<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100061" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM Canada strike forces U.S. layoffs.</title>
<headline>GM Canada strike forces U.S. layoffs.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The strike at General Motors Corp's Canadian operations will force the automaker to idle about 1,850 workers at U.S. engine and transmission plants by the end of the day, GM said on Monday.</p>
<p>GM Powertrain Division spokeswoman Christine D'Angela said 1,050 workers at the North Tonawanda, N.Y., engine plant had already been idled. The workers build 3.1-liter V-6 engines.</p>
<p>GM today will notify about 800 workers at its Ypsilanti, Mich., transmission plant not to report to work on Tuesday, D'Angela said.  </p>
<p>Both the North Tonawanda and the Ypsilanti facilities are only partially affected. North Tonawanda has a total of 4,216 hourly workers, while Ypsilanti has 5,692.</p>
<p>Both plants have been affected by the halt of production of GM's popular Chevrolet Lumina sedans at the strike-bound Oshawa, Ontario, assembly complex. The Lumina uses North Tonawanda's 3.1-liter V-6, and Ypsilanti's front-drive transmissions.  </p>
<p>GM spokesman Gerry Holmes said the automaker also had cancelled all overtime production in North America this week in order to conserve parts that may be in short supply.</p>
<p>As Monday began, about 5,690 workers at GM's St. Catharines, Ontario, components plants went on strike -- the second major step in the Canadian Auto Workers union's escalating strike strategy against the automaker.</p>
<p>The St. Catharines plants supply a broad range of components to U.S. vehicle models, including V-8 engines and suspension and axle components.</p>
<p>The rest of GM Canada's operations are expected to be struck by midnight Wednesday unless there is a settlement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
