<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100139" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: LOOP tanker loading halted but pipeline ops normal.</title>
<headline>LOOP tanker loading halted but pipeline ops normal.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Louisiana Offshore Oil Port Inc, (LOOP), which operates the Gulf of Mexico's only major deep-water oil port, has stopped loading oil tankers because of Tropical Storm Josephine but pipeline deliveries are normal, a company official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We still have our people on the rigs and our marine terminal is still in operation but we don't have any tankers loading because of the weather conditions,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We should be back to normal by tomorrow morning,&quot; he added. Meanwhile, pipeline operations and deliveries were unaffected, the official said.</p>
<p>The LOOP is the only deep-water port in U.S. waters and is about 20 miles south of Grand Isle, La.</p>
<p>According to the National Weather Center, at 0500 EDT/1000 GMT Tropical Storm Josephine had gusts of up to 50 miles per hour and was centered at latitude 25.8 north, longitude 88.4 west, or about 340 miles southwest of of Florida's coast. It was moving east/northeast at 15 mph and was expected to strengthen and reach land early Tuesday.</p>
<p>--New York Energy Desk 212-859-1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I74000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
