<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100172" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Disease treatment hopes spark Nobel medicine prize.</title>
<headline>Disease treatment hopes spark Nobel medicine prize.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two scientists, one Australian and the other Swiss, were on Monday awarded the Nobel Medicine Prize for a discovery 23 years ago that gives hope for treatment of such diseases as cancer, diabetes and AIDS.</p>
<p>Australian Peter Doherty, 55, and Swiss Rolf Zinkernagel, 52, received the prestigious award, worth $1.12 million, for joint work at the John Curtin School of Medical Research in Canberra, Australia, between 1973 and 1975.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a fantastic feeling...I'm still in a state of shock. It is a tremendous recognition,&quot; Doherty told Reuters from Memphis, Tennessee, where he works at a cancer hospital.</p>
<p>Zinkernagel, a graduate student at the time of the find, was delighted by the award but said it was only the first step.</p>
<p>&quot;We know so little still that there is enough work to keep me busy for the coming years and decades,&quot; said Zinkernagel, head of Zurich University's experimental immunology institute.</p>
<p>Zinkernagel and Doherty were chosen for the award after the Nobel Assembly at Stockholm's highly respected Karolinska Institute invited nominations for the prize.</p>
<p>On average 250 nominations are received each year and the Nobel Assembly of 50 of the institute's 150 professors decide.</p>
<p>Sten Grillner, chairman of the Nobel Medicine committee, said Zinkernagel and Doherty's discovery was ground-breaking.</p>
<p>The pair discovered how the immune system recognises and can then kill virus-infected cells, unlocking the mystery of how a vaccine needs to be composed.</p>
<p>They found mice infected with a virus able to cause meningitis developed killer T-lymphocytes that could destroy the virus-infected cells, but only in a specific animal.</p>
<p>&quot;Over time it has become more and more apparent how important this discovery was and continuation of this work has had a major impact on the whole field,&quot; Grillner told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Already it has led to successful vaccines for animals and if one has such a vaccine for animals, then it must not be far away before you can do the same with humans.&quot;</p>
<p>Grillner said the find related to both efforts to strengthen the immune response against invading microorganisms and certain forms of cancer and to lessen the effects of auto-immune reactions in inflammatory diseases like rheumatic conditions, multiple sclerosis and diabetes.</p>
<p>&quot;But essentially I cannot see why it could not also be imported for AIDS,&quot; Grillner said.</p>
<p>Doherty, now chairman of the Department of Immunology at St Jude Children's Research Hospital in Memphis and adjunct professor to the College of Medicine at Tennessee University, said the discovery brought about a new way of understanding how viruses should be controlled and how to make vaccines.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a major discovery,&quot; Doherty said.</p>
<p>&quot;It triggered a new direction in research. It targeted a whole new way of looking at the problem and this was not understood immediately.&quot;</p>
<p>The medicine award is one of six Nobel prizes awarded each year which since 1901 have been funded by a foundation set up by Swedish scientist, Alfred Nobel, who invented dynamite.</p>
<p>Polish poet Wislawa Szymborska won the Nobel Literature prize last Thursday. The winner of the economics prize will be announced on Tuesday, physics and chemistry on Wednesday, and the Nobel Peace Prize will be awarded in Oslo on Friday.</p>
<p>($1=6.60 crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
