<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100143" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton, Dole clash in first election debate.</title>
<headline>Clinton, Dole clash in first election debate.</headline>
<dateline>HARTFORD, Conn. 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton and Republican challenger Bob Dole clashed on Sunday in a debate that seemed unlikely to derail Clinton's drive for a second four-year term in the White House.</p>
<p>Dole attacked Clinton for having a weak foreign policy, raising taxes at home and failing to stop rising drug abuse, while the president defended his record, telling Americans they were better off than four years ago.</p>
<p>Opinion polls conducted immediately after the 90-minute debate showed that Clinton came out on top, though the public found Dole had performed better than expected.</p>
<p>Dole entered the debate facing the formidable task of denting Clinton's armour while promoting himself as a credible alternative. Clinton's job was simpler: protect his wide lead in the public opinion polls while avoiding gaffes.</p>
<p>&quot;There was nothing very big here. It was closer to a draw than anything else, and a draw helps Clinton,&quot; said David Birdsell, an expert on presidential debates with Baruch College in New York.</p>
<p>Dole did produce many of the better lines and showed a quick wit, but Clinton stuck doggedly to his message that he was the better man to lead America into the 21st century.</p>
<p>Dole responded: &quot;I want a bridge to the future but I also want a bridge to the truth. We have to tell the truth. And the truth is, there's a lot wrong in America. We need a strong economic package. We need a tax cut. We need a $5,000 child credit. We'll have that soon.&quot;</p>
<p>Standing side by side, the 73-year-old Dole, tanned but tense, contrasted with the clearly younger and perpetually smiling Clinton.</p>
<p>Both campaigns sent scores of aides to brief the press, each side arguing that their man was the victor. But snap polls by three TV networks all declared Clinton the winner.</p>
<p>An ABC poll showed that both candidates appeared to benefit modestly from their showing in the debate, with Clinton's support rising to 55 percent from 51 percent and Dole's backing inching to 41 percent from 40 percent.</p>
<p>Support for Reform Party candidate Ross Perot, who was excluded from the debate, dipped to two percent from five percent in the ABC poll.</p>
<p>The debate was the first of two the candidates will hold. The second is scheduled to be held in San Diego on Oct 16.</p>
<p>With neither Clinton nor Dole inflicting real damage in the first debate, the pressure is now on Dole to come up big in the second encounter if he is to narrow Clinton's lead.</p>
<p>Clinton quickly set the tone of the debate in his opening statement. &quot;Four years ago you took me on faith. Now there's a record...We are better off than we were four years ago. Let's keep it going,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>Dole, who looked nervous and rarely smiled, quickly shot back: &quot;Well, he's better off than he was four years ago,&quot; getting a laugh from the audience.</p>
<p>&quot;Well, I guess some may be better off,&quot; he added. &quot;(Iraqi leader) Saddam Hussein is probably better off.&quot;</p>
<p>The Republican candidate argued that Clinton's recent bombing in Iraq had failed to deter the Iraqi leader from establishing control over the north of his country, while demonstrating his failure to keep an international coalition together. He also attacked Clinton's record on Somalia, Haiti, Bosnia, Korea, Cuba, Ireland and the Middle East.</p>
<p>Moderator Jim Lehrer kept the candidates moving quickly through a broad array of subjects, from foreign policy to health, education, drugs, taxes and personal integrity.</p>
<p>One of the sharpest exchanges came when Clinton accused Dole of opposing his efforts to rein in tobacco companies.</p>
<p>&quot;It wasn't me who opposed what we tried to do to save the lives of children who were subject to tobacco and then went to the tobacco growers and bragged about standing up to the government when we tried to stop the advertising, marketing and sales of tobacco to children,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>Dole responded by touting his own anti-smoking record dating back to 1965. &quot;It wasn't until election year, Mr President, that you thought about stopping smoking. What about drugs that doubled in the last 44 months? Cocaine up 41 percent, marijuana, cocaine up 166 percent. It seems to me that you have a selective memory,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>Later, invited to comment about Clinton's personal integrity, Dole resisted the temptation, saying: &quot;The question is, would you buy a used election promise from my opponent?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTFORD, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
