<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100142" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Oct 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Oct 7.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil giants Texaco Inc, Shell Oil Co and a Saudi Arabian company are negotiating the merger of their U.S. refining and marketing businesses in a deal that would pool assets valued at more than $10 billion, the Wall Street Journal reported Monday.</p>
<p>Other top stories included:</p>
<p>* General Motors Corp laid off some workers and canceled or scaled back overtime as a result of the strike being held by the Canadian Automobile Worked union. Five thousand more workers joined the 15,000 who had walked off the job after labor talks broke down.</p>
<p>* U S West Inc is considering a boost in the cash portion of its $5.3 billion purchase of  Continental Cablevision in order to offset a 31 percent drop in the value of its Media stock.</p>
<p>* Oxford Health Plans Inc intends to set up a network of 1,000 holistic health care providers in an effort to penetrate alternative medicine sector.</p>
<p>* U.S. Federal Communications Commission Chairman Reed Hundt said he was concerned about Seagram's latest television advertizing campaign for liquor, saying it set a new precedent.</p>
<p>* U.S. prosecutors convicted GTECH Holdings Corp's former sales manager in a kickback scheme.</p>
<p>* U.S. prosecutors also charged six men, including a former lawyer for the Securities and Exchange Commission, with securities fraud.</p>
<p>* McKesson Corp agreed to acquire FoxMeyer Health Corp's drug distribution unit for about $80 million, plus debt assumption.</p>
<p>* Aluminum Co of America reported a near 70 percent fall in quarterly profit due to lower prices and a charge to cut jobs.</p>
<p>* Dickson Concepts has offered to buy  Barney's for about $350 million.</p>
<p>* Health coverage premiums edged 0.5 percent higher at 1,100 major employers from spring 1995 to spring 1996, the smalled increase since the 1960s, according to a study by Peat Marwick.</p>
<p>* The jobless rate increased to 5.2 percent in September from 5.1 percent in August and payroll employment fell by 40,000 jobs.</p>
<p>* The financial markets welcomed the unemployment figures, expecting the U.S. Federal Reserve not to tighten interest rates as a consequence.</p>
<p>* Skeptics believe that investors are overreacting about the jobless figures and the U.S. economy is not as weak as it might appear. But they are having more difficulty conveying their opinion to investors who are used to thinking of inflation as history.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
