<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100561" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - OCT 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - London Evening Standard - OCT 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>EVENING STANDARD</p>
<p>TORY BLITZ ON WELFARE BILL</p>
<p>The Conservatives will announce plans to massively expand &quot;Workfare' schemes, which compel the long-term unemployed to take part in community projects for 10 pounds stg more per week than they would get on benefit, at their conference this week. These plans, along with the introduction of the job seekers' allowance and limitations on housing benefit for under-25s, are aimed at reducing the welfare bill by billions.</p>
<p>STING FOR STERLING IN NEW TORY DEFECTION</p>
<p>The defection of prominent Conservative Lord McAlpine from the Tories to the Referendum party caused the pound stg to be &quot;soft&quot; in overnight trading according to financial markets consultancy IDEA.</p>
<p>EUROTUNNEL SET TO UNVEIL RESCUE PLAN</p>
<p>It is expected that Eurotunnel will today make public the rescue plan it has reached after consultation with its banks. The deal involves the banks agreeing to swap part of the nine billion pounds stg they are owed for shares in the company.</p>
<p>INDEPENDENT RAISES BID FOR NZ PUBLISHER   Independent Press</p>
<p>Communications, the Irish newspaper group, has increased its offer for the remaining shares in New Zealand newspaper publisher Wilson &amp; Horton to the equivalent of 4.86 pounds stg per share.</p>
<p>F&amp;C TRUST UPSETS HYPO MOVE ON FCM</p>
<p>Foreign &amp; Colonial Investment has decided that it wants to retain its 30.5 percent stake in Foreign &amp; Colonial Management, thereby putting a major obstacle in the way of Hypo Bank's planned takeover of FCM.</p>
<p>ICI OZ SHARES SOAR ON TALK OF BUYBACK</p>
<p>Shares in ICI's 73 percent-owned Australian subsidiary, ICI Australia, are soaring on expectations of a mop-up bid by the British company. --  For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC on -- BMC +44 71 377 1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
