<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100746" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Scientists study world's oldest amber in Lebanon.</title>
<headline>Scientists study world's oldest amber in Lebanon.</headline>
<byline>Zeina Soufan</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amber found in the mountains of Lebanon has been confirmed as the oldest in the world dating back 125 million years and insects trapped in it could lead to new scientific advances, a Lebanese scientist said on Monday.</p>
<p>The amber contains insects, some of them now extinct, and plants far older than those found in Baltic amber which dates back 35 million years, Professor Georges Tohme, head of Lebanon's National Council for Scientific Research told Reuters.</p>
<p>Amber is a hard yellowish to brownish translucent fossil resin valued throughout history for making ornaments such as beads and necklaces. It sometimes contains insects and plants trapped inside before the resin hardened millions of years ago.</p>
<p>Tohme said teams of Lebanese and French scientists had been set up to study the insects in the amber, whose age was confirmed by French scientists earlier this year.</p>
<p>Some remains of plants were also trapped in the amber. &quot;This might be the first thread to understanding the beginnings of plants with flowers,&quot; Tohme said.</p>
<p>A Lebanese university student named Dany Azar sparked the discovery when he collected thousands of tiny samples of Lebanese amber and took them with him when he went to study in Paris in 1989.</p>
<p>Azar's French professors took interest in the samples and they told Lebanese authorities earlier this year that studies at the Universite de Paris Sud in Orsay concluded that the amber dated back 125 million years.</p>
<p>&quot;Polish, Russian and Baltic amber were believed to be the most ancient insectified resin dating back to the Jurassic age some 35 million years ago. Now it has been established that the Lebanese, which is 125 million years old, is the oldest,&quot; Tohme said.</p>
<p>The insects trapped in Azar's amber are of &quot;exceptional freshness&quot; and belong to extinct species, Michel Solignac, a professor of genetics and evolution, told Tohme in a letter dated July 8, 1996.</p>
<p>Tohme declined to identify the site where the amber was found, saying it had to be protected.</p>
<p>Study of the insects could help lead to a new understanding of the history and evolution of insects, which make up 90 percent of all living beings, Tohme said.</p>
<p>The insects trapped inside offered scientists the chance to study ancient DNA which is essential to the science of genetical engineering. Study of the insects themselves could help taxonomy, the science of ranking living beings.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed to create two teams of eight members each. The French will study the ancient DNA in parasitical insects,&quot; Tohme said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would increase our understanding of biodiversity. It is important to understand how living beings have evolved, how one cell evolved into billions of diverse cells,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Lebanese team is hoping to establish that social insects existed 125 million years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been scientifically proved so far that ants, which are social insects, lived in the Jurassic age. The study was conducted by a Harvard professor in New Jersey,&quot; Tohme said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hoping to find scientific evidence that they existed much earlier than that,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
