<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="100717" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: TURKISH SHARES LEAP 2.3 PCT TO NEW ALL-TIME HIGH.</title>
<headline>TURKISH SHARES LEAP 2.3 PCT TO NEW ALL-TIME HIGH.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares at Istanbul's stock exchange continued a three-week-long uptrend amid selective activity and strong volume on Monday to hit a fresh record.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 closed at a new all-time high of 78,479.71, up 1,784.85 points, or 2.33 percent from Friday's 76,694.86, the previous record. But it eased from an afternoon high of 79,086 on profit-taking.</p>
<p>Daily trade volume soared to 25.79 trillion lira, including a 3.5 trillion lira block deal on the wholesale market, from Friday's 16.51 trillion.  </p>
<p>&quot;A down correction is awaited, but has not yet happened. It looks as though activity will continue this way,&quot; said Nazmi Sarikaya, securities manager at Disbank.</p>
<p>The index which surged 7.15 percent last week has gained 21.1 percent since mid-September when the medium-term uptrend began.</p>
<p>Brokers said activity was spearheaded by utilities and largely state owned firms which are highly capitalised and thus have major impact on the market index.</p>
<p>Of the 223 shares traded, gainers overwhelmed losers by 157 to 28 and 38 closed unchanged. The 85-share industrial index put on 2.3 percent to 84,425.27 and the 15-share financial index leapt 2.39 percent to 72,904.11.</p>
<p>Top actives were utilities Cukurova Elektrik, steady at 79,000 lira, Aktas Elektrik, up 4,000 lira at 66,000 and Kepez Elektrik which gained 1,000 lira to 79,000.</p>
<p>They were followed by largely state owned firms slated for privatisation -- flat steel giant Eregli, up 200 lira at 10,000 and petroleum refiner Tupras which jumped 2,000 lira to 17,500.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
