<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101016" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- BOTNAR'S 50 MILLION STG TAX DEAL MAY ALLOW RETURN TO UK</p>
<p>The head of Nissan UK, Octav Botnar, has agreed a 50 million stg tax settlement with the Inland Revenue which could allow him to re-enter Britain. The Revenue claimed that his company owed more than 250 million stg tax after fraudulently inflating freight payments. The agreement was reached ahead of an appeal, which the tax commissioners were due to start hearing this morning and which is expected to last six months. It appears the agreement was made reluctantly and Mr Botnar is expected to continue his attack on the Revenue.</p>
<p>-- BACKERS PUT PIZZALAND CHAIN'S OWNER UP FOR SALE</p>
<p>Brightreasons, the owner of the Pizzaland restaurant chain, has been put up for sale by its venture capital owners, despite hopes by Michael Guthrie, chief executive, that it can be floated on the stock market. Costs of a former floatation plan and poor trading, blamed on last year's hot summer, left the company with a 1.7 million stg loss. Mr Guthrie believes the company to be worth more than 100 million stg because of competition for restaurant chains, but accountants at Deloittes, who are handling the sale, started with lower expectations.</p>
<p>-- WILLIAMS BUY-OUT TEAM PLANS 300 MILLION STG DEAL</p>
<p>Venture capitalists are trying to put together a deal that would finance a 300 million stg management buy-out of some of Williams Holdings' UK building products, including household names such as Rawlplug and Swish curtain rails. Williams managers have drawn up a shortlist of potential venture capital backers. Williams has yet to take the formal decision to put the businesses up for sale but Roger Carr, chief executive, is known to regard many of the building products in Britain as non-core.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- PETROL GIANTS EXPLOIT SURGE IN PRICE OF CRUDE TO BOOST MARGINS</p>
<p>The surge in the price of crude oil is being used by oil companies to boost their margins at the petrol pumps, where prices have risen by about ten percent since July, by raising the price of unleaded and four-star petrol. Weaknesses in the spot price of gasoline has allowed the major oil companies and their supermarket rivals to claw back some of the profit lost in the petrol price war.</p>
<p>-- HUGE DILUTION FOR INVESTORS IN EUROTUNNEL</p>
<p>Due to the months of negotiations with banks over financial restructuring, Eurotunnel shareholders are set to be told today that their stake in the company is to be reduced to little more than a quarter. They are also set to be given a new target date for the first dividends payable on their investment. Advisors believe these will arrive by 2010. The most difficult task facing Eurotunnel is to sell the package to shareholders.</p>
<p>-- DMG CONSIDERS LEGAL ACTION ON AUDIT OF YOUNG FUNDS</p>
<p>Insiders believe Deutsche Morgan Grenfell is considering legal action against KPMG and General Accident, the auditors and trustees of the three European funds that were managed by the rogue trader Peter Young. The role of KPMG was to audit the accounts of the three funds, while General Accident, as trustee, was to ensure that the funds complied with regulatory rules and stated investment objectives. If sued KPMG and General Accident would argue that Mr Young presented them with incorrect information that made their jobs impossible.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- FORECAST CLEARS NEW LABOUR</p>
<p>Independent economists, as part of the Item Club, are using the Treasury's forecasting system to declare that there is no danger from New Labour. They believe that tax plans and the minimum wage would have no adverse effect on the economy, which would grow by 3.75 percent next year. Chief economist at the Item Club, Paul Droop, says the election poses the biggest short- term risk to economic health, predicting that the Conservatives will not be able to resist wooing voters with personal tax cuts, leaving the next government with excessive public borrowing.</p>
<p>-- NUCLEAR GENERATOR TO AXE 1,300 IN EFFORT TO KEEP DIVIDEND PROMISE</p>
<p>The newly privatised nuclear generator British Energy is set to unveil plans to axe 1,300 jobs in an attempt to shore up dividend promises make during the sell-off. The losses will be associated with Nuclear Electric, the English and Welsh operating arm of the company, and are to be followed by further and more politically sensitive job cuts by Scottish Nuclear. These job losses show that British Energy is desperate to cut costs to maintain its policy of paying growing dividends.</p>
<p>-- BA PLANS MORE PAY AND JOB CUTS</p>
<p>Reports have emerged which suggest that British Airways' regional cabin crew staff may have to accept a 30 percent reduction in wages to meet the company's objective of a 17.3 percent return on assets. Union leaders say they have been told by management that cuts among 1,000 cabin crew and engineering staff would extend to Heathrow. BA is considering further moves towards franchising-out operations, including baggage handling, engineering and cabin crew.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- OFT STEPS UP CHECK ON GROCERY GIANTS</p>
<p>The Office of Fair Trading is to review the increasing dominance of the country's big supermarket groups after growing complaints from smaller food retailers. The action follows figures from AGB, the market research group, which show that the big four supermarket chains, Tesco, Asda, Safeway and Sainsbury, increased their share of the packaged goods market by a percentage point between August and September. They now control almost two-thirds of the market between them. The OFT decided to widen the scope of its inquiry following a formal complaint from the National Association of Master Bakers.</p>
<p>-- REED AND BLENHEIM CLOSE TO AGREEMENT ON 450 MILLION STG BID</p>
<p>A 450 million stg bid from the Anglo-Dutch publishing giant Reed Elsevier for Blenheim, the exhibitions company, could be agreed this week. A source close to Blenheim cautioned that Reed was not the only bidder, it is believed Lord Hollick's United News and Media are still interested. Reed insiders accused Blenheim as being difficult to deal with and suggested a deal could be done quickly with more co-operation.</p>
<p>-- CURRENCIES TO TRADE ON INTERNET</p>
<p>A service launched by Currency Management Corporation, the London-based dealer, will allow investors to buy and sell foreign currencies on the Internet. CMC offers the Internet service and software at no charge, planning to make its money on the spread between its own buying and selling of foreign currencies. The service will operate under an interim permit from the Securities and Futures Authority.</p>
<p>BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
