<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101165" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Facts regarding Japan's new electoral system.</title>
<headline>Facts regarding Japan's new electoral system.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are details of Japan's new electoral system to be introduced in the October 20 general elections. Campaigning starts on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Five hundred members of the new Lower House are to be chosen in the polls, the first since July 1993 and the first electoral test for Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto.</p>
<p>LOWER HOUSE: The Lower House, or the House of Representatives, is the decisive chamber in Japan's parliament, which has power over the Upper House in naming the prime minister, ratifying treaties and passing state budget bills. The prime minister must be a member of the Lower House.</p>
<p>Under a revised law, the new Lower House will have 500 members, down from 512 in the outgoing chamber.</p>
<p>Members serve four years but the prime minister can dissolve the house anytime. The 252-member Upper House cannot be dissolved, and half of that chamber is elected every three years for fixed six-year terms.</p>
<p>NEW SYSTEM: As much as 60 percent of Japanese voters told a recent Yomiuri Shimbun poll they were not familiar with the new system, which combines 300 members elected in single-seat districts with 200 chosen through proportional representation in 11 regional blocs. At polling stations, voters are given two ballots, one for a candidate in the constituency and one for a party in the regional blocs.</p>
<p>SINGLE-SEAT CONSTITUENCIES: There are 300 new single-seat districts that replace the 129 multi-seat constituencies of the old system. The old system had been blamed as a root cause of corruption because candidates were required to spend lavishly on election campaigns, often against rivals from the same party. The aim of the new system is to lessen the financial burden on candidates and make it more of a contest between parties and their policies, rather than between candidates.</p>
<p>PROPORTIONAL REPRESENTATION: Two hundred other members are to be chosen through proportional representation in 11 regional blocs. Candidates running in any single-seat constituency can also be listed for proportional representation, meaning they might still be made Lower House members even if they fail in the first-past-the-post contest in the districts. Voters will cast ballots for a party.</p>
<p>Winners in the single seat constituencies will be automatically deleted from the proportional representation list.</p>
<p>SCHEDULE:</p>
<p>October 8: Start of official campaign. Parties to submit list of candidates, both in the constituencies and in proportional representation blocs. About 1,400 candidates are expected to run.</p>
<p>October 19: Last day of campaign.</p>
<p>October 20: Polls open at 7 a.m. (2200 GMT Saturday) and close at 6 p.m. (0900 GMT). The first exit polls are expected at that time with final results by about 2 a.m. on Monday (1700 GMT Sunday).</p>
<p>Depending on the outcome, the winning bloc, either a party or a coalition, would have between one and two weeks to nominate a candidate for prime minister at a Special Session of Parliament.</p>
<p>As soon as the winner is elected prime minister, he or she will form a cabinet, normally consisting of 20 members.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
