<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101116" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AWF lifts Australia wheat f'cast to 20.43 MT.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AWF lifts Australia wheat f'cast to 20.43 MT.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Wheat Forecasters Pty Ltd (AWF) has further raised its 1996/97 wheat crop forecast to 20.43 million tonnes from 19.80 million a month ago.</p>
<p>The forecast compares with 17.78 million tonnes produced in 1995/96 (April-March).</p>
<p>AWF said rain received late in September, when the more northern areas of the Australian wheat belt are normally drying off, would extend the growing season by another 10 to 14 days.</p>
<p>The forecast, AWF's seventh for 1996/97, is for the second highest wheat crop ever achieved in Australia, after the record crop of 22 million tonnes in 1983/84.  </p>
<p>The extra growing days would mean additional wheat yield.</p>
<p>&quot;In most areas the crops have not been stressed over the late winter/early spring period,&quot; AWF said.</p>
<p>The grain filling process was being assisted by cool weather in the early maturing areas of southern Queensland and northern and western New South Wales, the forecaster said.</p>
<p>The harvest has commenced already in Queensland and by the end of October the task would be well-advanced, it said.</p>
<p>The New South Wales crop would be later maturing and because of the size of the crop, would take longer for the growers and contractors to handle, AWF said.  </p>
<p>If silo queues developed at the central wheat receival facilities, this would further prolong the harvest operation.</p>
<p>AWF said the north west of New South Wales was a predominantly summer rainfall area, and the longer the harvest took, the greater the risk of unharvested grain being spoiled by a series of late spring, early summer rains.</p>
<p>The three monthly climate forecast was for above average rainfall, AWF said.</p>
<p>&quot;Of the six and a half million tonnes of wheat forecast for New South Wales, we expect two million tonnes will be feed grade by the time it is harvested,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Nevertheless the Queensland wheat and the first harvested New South Wales wheat should provide adequate supplies of the premium Australian Prime Hard and Prime Hard categories for the traditional premium wheat markets,&quot; AWF said.</p>
<p>There had been several frosts and some severe hail storms, but damage at this time was not significant and would allow for a 20.4 million tonnes wheat crop, the forecaster said.</p>
<p>&quot;Victoria, South Australia and the southern half of Western Australia were each important wheat areas that we sown late this season and therefore faced the prospect of shortened growing seasons,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>However, rain through September and also in the first week of October had allowed crops to make steady growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The soil moisture status indicates that the seasons will extend into summer by a few more days than is normal,&quot; AWF said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is important for yield and will make up for some of the lost early winter growth.&quot;  </p>
<p>			  Crop		  Area    Previous</p>
<p>			1995/96   1996/97  1996/97  Forecast</p>
<p>  Queensland	  0.58    2.20     0.95     2.10</p>
<p>  NSW		   4.73    6.60     2.90     6.35</p>
<p>  Victoria	    2.08    2.33     1.08     2.30</p>
<p>  S. Australia	2.97    2.80     1.55     2.70</p>
<p>  W. Australia	7.42    6.50     4.25     6.35</p>
<p>  TOTAL		17.78   20.43    10.73    19.80</p>
<p>(Units are million hectares and million tonnes)</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
