<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101264" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine property stocks seen taking a breather.</title>
<headline>Philippine property stocks seen taking a breather.</headline>
<byline>Lilian Karunungan</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine property stocks, long a market favourite, may have been battered in recent sessions but brokers said on Monday the sector's boom is far from over.</p>
<p>&quot;Our view is that fundamentals of the sector are firm but it's really sentiment-driven. The sentiment is really bad from the foreign side,&quot; Colbert Nocum, an analyst of ING Barings Securities, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Philippine Stock Exchange's property sub-index, which represents about 25 percent of total market capitalisation, reached a record high of 179.38 on July 5, a 50 percent jump from the start of this year.</p>
<p>It has corrected by almost 15 percent since then and closed at 152.69 on Monday, a further fall of 2.78 points.</p>
<p>Analysts are advising investors to buy on dips, or be selective on property stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;Our recommendation is to be selective. We're not bullish on the office sector but on the residential sector,&quot; said Barrie del Rosario, an analyst at DBP Daiwa Securities.  </p>
<p>ING Barings' Nocum said that, despite expectations of falling domestic interest rates, foreign investors will remain cautious over real estate since they have been hurt before in Thailand and Malaysia.</p>
<p>In both places, property prices had fallen following an oversupply in response to strong initial demand for real estate in the early 1990s, Nocum said.</p>
<p>Angping Securities was even more positive, saying in an advisory to clients: &quot;We would treat further corrections as opportunities for a 'screaming buy' position.&quot;</p>
<p>The brokerage added that property prices are not likely to have a huge correction even if the real estate market cools down.</p>
<p>ING Barings estimates the property sector is trading at 24 times forecast 1996 earnings versus the market's 17 to 18 times.</p>
<p>Francisco Licuanan, president of Ayala Land Inc, told Reuters land prices in the premiere financial district of Makati had gone up by 50 percent in the past year and a half.</p>
<p>He estimated that land along Ayala Avenue, the district's most prestigious street, is now fetching about 430,000 pesos per sq metre more more.</p>
<p>Real land prices have more than tripled in residential areas just outside Manila, such in Laguna, Batangas, Rizal and Bulacan, due to the high demand for housing, he said.</p>
<p>Despite the huge jump in real estate prices, Licuanan said he was optimistic for the future, as long as the economy keeps growing.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as the economy is strong, the medium term view is land will go up. All property prices were relatively low. They're only catching up now,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
