<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101315" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - Oct 7.</title>
<headline>INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - Oct 7.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Indonesian stocks on Monday:</p>
<p>** The Dow Jones industrial average rallied 60.01 points, or 1.01 percent, to a record closing high of 5,992.86 on Friday as a surprisingly weak September jobs report eased fears of an interest rate hike by the Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>** Indonesia's plywood exports to Japan saw an 11 percent increase in the first nine months of this year and are expected to continue rising until next year.</p>
<p>MARKETS:</p>
<p>** The Jakarta Composite Index fell 1.44 points to close at 588.35 points on Friday following some profit-taking in selected heavyweights and secondaries.</p>
<p>** On Monday, the Indonesian rupiah was at 2,323.20/23.40 in early trading against an opening of 2,322.50/23.50.</p>
<p>STOCKS TO WATCH</p>
<p>** Barito Pacific, Sumalindo Lestari, on reports that a number of timber firms were facing a shortage in raw material, and higher exports to Japan.</p>
<p>** Automotive parts manufacturer Prima Alloy on market talk of expected higher earnings in 1996 due to rising overseas demand.</p>
<p>** Glass manufacturer Mulia Industri on market talk of a possible private placement.</p>
<p>** Duta Pertiwi on market talk the property firm was likely to issue convertible bonds for further expansion.</p>
<p>** Duta Anggada Realty on fresh market talk that the property firm was in negotiations with another new foreign property firm on possible joint venture</p>
<p>** Sampoerna on reports of a $400-million loan for &quot;corporate development&quot;</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom + 6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
