<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101308" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Two islands activists rescued from sea - radio.</title>
<headline>Two islands activists rescued from sea - radio.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two activists demonstrating against Japan's claim to a group of East China Sea islands fell overboard their protest vessel on Monday and were rescued by colleagues, Hong Kong radio reported.</p>
<p>The accident happened as Taiwan and Hong Kong activists pierced a Japanese maritime cordon and planted the flags of China and Taiwan on one of the islands in a challenge to Japan's claim to sovereignty.</p>
<p>The action by 50 boats from Taiwan carrying about 300 activists from Taiwan, Hong Kong and Macau, was the latest in two months of escalating anti-Japanese protests.</p>
<p>Hong Kong radio said two activists went overboard as the protest flotilla became involved in a face-off with a Japanese force of about 30 vessels. The two were not named.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears they were rescued after a short time without serious injuries,&quot; the radio's correspondent on board one of the vessels reported.</p>
<p>In an earlier protest on September 26, a Hong Kong protest leader drowned after jumping off a ship near the islands northeast of Taiwan. Thousands of Hong Kong people turned out to mourn David Chan at his funeral on Sunday.</p>
<p>Japan has claimed what it calls the Senkaku islands since 1895, while China has claimed them for centuries under the name of the Diaoyu isles.</p>
<p>The latest dispute was sparked in July when Japanese rightists erected a lighthouse and planted flags on the uninhabited rocky outcrop.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
