<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101488" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks open stronger, record beckons.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks open stronger, record beckons.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian shares opened stronger on Monday after record highs reached in New York and London and firmer base metal prices on the London Metal Exchange.</p>
<p>After one hour of trade the All Ordinaries index was 18.2 points higher at 2,333.7, within striking range of its record high of 2350.1 set on February 3, 1994.</p>
<p>But trading was quiet due to the Labour Day holiday in New South Wales, Australian Capital Territory and South Australia.</p>
<p>Traders said the holiday was likely to subdue trading but the market was likely to hold its gains for the rest of the day.</p>
<p>&quot;It has had a good kick start to the day,&quot; said a Perth broker. &quot;Generally it should be pretty firm, in line with the experiences in New York and London on Friday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rises were across the board in both industrial and resource issues, with only the chemical sector going against the rising trend. Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about four-to-one.</p>
<p>CRA recorded the largest turnover, representing nearly A$100 million (US$79 million) or about 40 percent of the value of the first hour's total business.</p>
<p>The Anglo-Australian miner and fellow mining gaint BHP were the biggest risers among the blue chips in morning trade.</p>
<p>CRA was up 20 cents at A$19.45 while BHP was up 18 cents at A$16.62.</p>
<p>(A$=US$0.79)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
