<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101440" id="root" date="1996-10-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Accor names Espalioux chairman of mgmt board.</title>
<headline>Accor names Espalioux chairman of mgmt board.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Accor announced on Monday that it had appointed Jean-Marc Espalioux chairman of the company's new management board under a move to transform the leisure group into a public limited company.  </p>
<p>Espalioux is currently assistant managing director of French utility Generale des Eaux and joined Accor's board in January 1988. He had been widely tipped by the French press to be named chairman of the management board.</p>
<p>Accor co-chairmen Paul Dubrule and Gerard Pelisson, who founded the group, will remain chairmen of the supervisory board. They announced at the group's last annual meeting they would change the company's management structure.</p>
<p>An extraordinary general meeting of shareholders will be held on January 7, 1997 to entrench the planned changes. This meeting will decide on the change in statutes and will name the members of the supervisory board which will choose the chairman and the members of the management board of Accor.</p>
<p>&quot;Shareholders on the board of Accor who confided the task to Paul Dubrule and Gerard Pelisson of choosing their successor greeted their proposal with satisfaction,&quot; Accor said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Dubrule and Pelisson wanted their successor to come from outside Accor to facilitate an innovative approach...,&quot; the statement said. &quot;Jean-Marc Espalioux embodies the change sought by the co-chairmen,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The company, whose first-half results are expected on Monday, plans to hold a board meeting on October 29 to review the plans to change Accor into a public limited company.</p>
<p>As chairman of the supervisory board, Pelisson and Dubrule plan to &quot;exercise their statutory role of supervising the good functioning of the group and will be involved in decisions of a strategic nature.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452 pmc</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
