<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101695" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. 10-yr note draws moderate demand at auction.</title>
<headline>U.S. 10-yr note draws moderate demand at auction.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The $10 billion in new 10-year notes that the U.S. Treasury sold on Tuesday attracted a little less demand than expected as buyers showed themselves to be a bit wary of current price levels, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a bit weaker than what was expected,&quot; said Kevin Flanagan, first vice president and money market economist at Dean Witter Reynolds Inc.</p>
<p>The auction produced an average yield of 6.502 percent, the lowest for a 10-year auction since February 7, when the average yield was 5.649 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the high and average yields, known as the tail, was one basis point.</p>
<p>The bid-to-cover ratio, the value of bids received over the value of securities sold, was 2.34 to one.</p>
<p>That was stronger than the last 10-year note auction on August 7 when the bid-to-cover ratio was 2.22 to one, but less than the the bid-to-cover ratio of 2.66 to one at the last off-cycle 10-year note auction on July 9.</p>
<p>Non-competitive bids totaled a tepid $284 million, down from $385 million at each of the two previous 10-year note sales.  </p>
<p>Flanagan said the U.S. Treasury market had traded up going into the auction &quot;in response to the notion that there was good bidding here&quot; for the 10-year notes.</p>
<p>But demand did not quite live up to expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The cover was average, nothing to write home about. And the non-comp bid was the lowest since August 1986,&quot; Flanagan said. He said prices, now near the high end of their six-month ranges, may just have made investors feel a little wary.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had rallied since Friday and a lot of good news had been factored in,&quot; Flanagan said. &quot;Investors felt a little bit apprehensive about coming in at these levels.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Early today, people were saying (the average yield) was going to be 6.53 or 6.54,&quot; said Matthew Alexy, chief markets strategist at CS First Boston Corp. &quot;No one really got completely shut out, given that it traded well going into the one o'clock deadline.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, we're at levels here that make some sense given the (employment) data that we saw, but by the same token you have a lot of risk going into the next big event which of course is the inflation data,&quot; said Alexy.</p>
<p>Alexy said the risk is chiefly the September Consumer Price Index (CPI) due next Wednesday, October 16, rather than to the Producer Price Index (PPI) due this Friday, October 11.</p>
<p>&quot;I like the market here,&quot; said Alexy, &quot;but again, there's a lot of discussion.&quot;</p>
<p>The yield on the new Treasury 10-year notes was 6.5075 percent in when-issued, mid-afternoon trade.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
