<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101795" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARMENIA: SOCCER-INJURY-WEARY VOGTS WANTS WINTER BREAK SCRAPPED.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-INJURY-WEARY VOGTS WANTS WINTER BREAK SCRAPPED.</headline>
<dateline>YEREVAN, Armenia 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>German national trainer Berti Vogts, facing a World Cup qualifier in Armenia without seven core players, said on Tuesday that the German league should scrap its two-month winter break.</p>
<p>&quot;Since we've had the winter break we've had injury problems because we force the players to play every three or four days,&quot; Vogts told journalists on the eve of Wednesday's match, the first in Germany's campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is, the players get less and less time to regenerate,&quot; he said. &quot;That makes them more vulnerable to injury. We are the only major soccer federation that takes two breaks.&quot;</p>
<p>Vogts's predecessor as coach, Bayern Munich president Franz Beckenbauer, supported Vogts.</p>
<p>&quot;We just can't afford to have five months off altogether, and get the the players fit from scratch twice over,&quot; he told the sports agency SID, suggesting the break could be cut to just over a month.</p>
<p>Germany's league programme is anyway fairly compact compared to other major European leagues. An 18-team first division means a programme of just 34 league matches, coupled with a much less arduous Cup schedule than in, say, England.</p>
<p>For this reason many of Germany's league clubs have also begun to think the break from mid-December to mid-February, introduced in 1986/87, is counter-productive.</p>
<p>Among the most vociferous are those who have to play in European competitions at a time when the players may not have seen league action for several weeks.</p>
<p>But any shortening of the break would almost certainly prompt protests from less successful league clubs and braodcasters who benefit from traditional winter indoor tournaments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARMEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YEREVAN, Armenia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARMENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
