<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="101999" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Ontario Hydro says 1997 average rates unchanged.</title>
<headline>Ontario Hydro says 1997 average rates unchanged.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ontario Hydro, North America's biggest power utility, said on Tuesday that average power rates will remain frozen in 1997, the fourth consecutive year that rates have been left unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;This is in keeping with our commitment of no increase in average rates for the balance of the decade...,&quot; Ontario Hydro president Allan Kupcis said in a statement.</p>
<p>The government-owned power utility said it plans to change the wholesale price structure for municipal electric utilities and distributing companies. But these moves will not change the projected average cost for this customer class.  </p>
<p>Ontario Hydro's large industrial customers will be offered an expanded menu of pricing options which could substantially reduce their energy costs, the utility said.</p>
<p>The Municipal Electric Association (MEA) criticized the utility for ignoring recommendations from the Ontario Energy Board. The MEA said one rate option will give Ontario Hydro a competitive advantage in the future, while today's customers bear the cost of implementation.</p>
<p>Ontario Hydro has paid off about C$3.5 billion in debt since 1993. Kupcis said the utility plans to pay off another C$7 billion of its C$32 billion debt by the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610107">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
