<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102150" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Bosnian Serbs to get $60 million loan-news agency.</title>
<headline>Bosnian Serbs to get $60 million loan-news agency.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnian Serb finance minister Novak Kondic said the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank approved a $60 million loan to the Bosnian Serb Republic for &quot;emergency purchases&quot;, the Yugoslav news agency Tanjug reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The first $20 million tranche of the loan, to be secured by donors from throughout the world, will be made available as soon as the Bosnian Serb government determines priorities for emergency purchases,&quot; Tanjug quoted Kondic as saying.</p>
<p>According to Kondic, the Bosnian Serb Republic will only pay a service charge of under one percent for the 40-year interest-free loan.</p>
<p>Kondic, who attended the recent annual meeting of the World bank and the International Monetary Fund in Washington, said the international financial organisations had promised equal treatment of the two Bosnian entities -- the Bosnian Serb Republic and the Moslem Croat Federation -- in financing future projects.</p>
<p>The Bosnian Serbs have complained they were receiving &quot;only crumbs&quot; of the aid earmarked for Bosnia's reconstruction.</p>
<p>The international community has been reluctant to send aid to the Bosnian Serbs until they demonstrate their willingness to support the Dayton peace accord, and its promise of a unified Bosnia.</p>
<p>Before Tuesday's announcement, the World Bank's representative in Sarajevo said some 600 million dollars had been donated to Bosnia, although the Bosnian Serb Republic had received only around 1.5 percent of that ammount.</p>
<p>Kondic said a delegation of the two financial organisations was due to visit the Bosnian Serb Republic late this month to determine conditions for financing projects of small and medium firms, forestry and private sector. -- Beti Bilandzic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
