<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102259" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Bus plunges into ravine in Peruvian Andes, 44 dead.</title>
<headline>Bus plunges into ravine in Peruvian Andes, 44 dead.</headline>
<byline>Saul Hudson</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bus driving through fog and rain in the Peruvian Andes plunged into a ravine early on Tuesday after failing to make a turn, killing 44 and injuring 34 passengers, authorities said.</p>
<p>&quot;Forty-four is the final death-toll,&quot; Prospero Najarro, a doctor working at the local hospital receiving victims, said.</p>
<p>Four of the injured were in critical condition, according to Hernan Chique, director of the Feliz Mayorca Soto hospital, which had been handling the emergency after the bus crashed just after midnight at Carpatata, 200 miles (320 km) east of Lima.</p>
<p>The bus with about 80 passengers was driving through dense fog and rain up a winding mountain highway when it failed to make a bend in the road. As the driver tried to back up, the vehicle plummeted 300 feet (100 meters) down the mountain onto a lower part of the highway, local fire chief Luis Guevara said.</p>
<p>&quot;If it was not for the road below, the bus would have carried on falling right into the river and nobody would have gotten out alive,&quot; Najarro said.</p>
<p>The doctor said survivors claimed the driver had been at the wheel for about seven hours without handing over to his co-driver.</p>
<p>By mid-morning, hundreds of relatives had gathered at the hospital's morgue to identify the victims, who were predominantly locals doing small trade between highland villages, Chique said.</p>
<p>Transport officials said thay did not know exactly how many people were on board because the bus had picked up passengers as it snaked through the mountains from Satipo to Tarma in the department of Junin.</p>
<p>The frequency of road accidents in the Peruvian Andes, where most people travel along poorly maintained highways on buses that are often overloaded, has led opposition parties to call for stricter transport regulations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
