<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102279" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Menem says he'll lead anti-corruption crusade.</title>
<headline>Menem says he'll lead anti-corruption crusade.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's President Carlos Menem, who is expected to announce a major customs service crackdown later Tuesday, said he will personally lead a crusade against corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;I am going to put myself at the front of the whole fight against corruption in Argentina,&quot; Menem told Argentine reporters in the Uruguayan capital of Montevideo.</p>
<p>A government source told Reuters that Menem would announce in a special address to the nation later Tuesday that he is appointing a special administrator to take over and investigate the nation's corruption-ridden customs service.  </p>
<p>The government believes that corrupt customs officials have set up a &quot;parallel customs service&quot; to smuggle in goods worth around $10 billion -- costing the state $3 billion in lost duties.</p>
<p>Police have raided customs offices, supermarkets and banks in recent days, seizing goods and documents. Seven people have been arrested, including one customs official and six customs &quot;fixers&quot;, and 10 others are on the run from the police.  </p>
<p>The head of the powerful Argentine Industrial Union business lobby, Jorge Blanco Villegas, hailed Menem's moves, but sniped at former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo, whom he said was partly responsible for not limiting corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased by the decision by the government and the courts to investigate this fully,&quot; he told Telam.</p>
<p>But he added, &quot;Cavallo is a man who has done an enormous number of things which have benefitted the country, (but reforming the customs service) is one of the pending matters which did not receive the attention it deserved and that has caused great damage.&quot;  </p>
<p>Cavallo, the architect of Argentina's sweeping economic reforms since 1991, was sacked by Menem in July after over a year of political feuding.</p>
<p>-- Jason Webb, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
