<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102451" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore gas oil trades higher, jet fuel slips.</title>
<headline>Singapore gas oil trades higher, jet fuel slips.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore gas oil traded higher Tuesday and traders said it is poised to surpass jet fuel values which remained pressured by large supplies and poor demand.</p>
<p>They said a European major sold 150,000 barrels of gas oil to a Singapore trader at $29.80 a barrel for October 23-27 lifting fob Singapore. This was 10 cents over the last cargo sold by the same major last week, which was a five-year high.</p>
<p>Traders said while front month physical jet fuel was offered below gas oil at $29.50, the first time the regrade has gone into a discount ahead of winter, forward jet prices continued to be offered higher at $30.75 for early November lifting.  </p>
<p>Fuel oil prices were steady on healthy supplies despite firmer paper quotes, traders said.</p>
<p>Physical 180-centistoke cargoes for October were indicated at $122 per tonne but edged lower to $121. The same major oil companies emerged to offer October barrels. Chinese demand remained weak as current prices were too high, traders said. On the paper swaps, October was discussed at $120.25-$121.25 up from Monday's $119.50-$119.75.</p>
<p>Taiwan has awarded its tender to buy low sulphur fuel oil to a Japanese refiner at just under $142 per tonne for November to December delivery. --Singapore newsroom (65-870-3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
