<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102443" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Tenaga to focus on power distribution.</title>
<headline>Tenaga to focus on power distribution.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>State power firm Tenaga Nasional Bhd said on Tuesday the company's immediate focus is to increase distribution capacity in order to deliver power from the 2,400-megawatt capacity Bakun hydroelectric dam.</p>
<p>&quot;We are focussing on strengthening our capacity to deliver power over the next five years,&quot; Tenaga executive chairman Ahmad Tajuddin Ali told reporters. &quot;We want to be ready for Bakun.&quot;</p>
<p>The 13.6 billion ringgit Bakun Dam project in Malaysia's Borneo state of Sarawak is expected to start generating electricity in 2003.</p>
<p>Tenaga has agreed to buy a minimum of 10,950 gigawatt-hours (GWH) worth of electricity generated by the dam, and a maximum of 14,000 GWH at 16.5 sen per kilowatt-hour (KWH) for the first five years, and 17 sen per KWH for the rest of the 25-year concession period</p>
<p>Tenaga had earlier said that it would be spending roughly five billion ringgit by 1997 to upgrade and expand its distribution facilities.</p>
<p>On the shareholding structure of the Bakun dam project, Tajuddin said details were still being worked out. &quot;It is still being discussed at this point,&quot; he said in response to the possibility of Tenaga ending up with a much smaller stake in the project than had previously been announced.</p>
<p>The Asian Wall Street Journal reported on Tuesday that Tenaga's share of the project would be five percent, although it was announced in June that its stake would be 25 percent.</p>
<p>Malaysian Mining Corporation Bhd and the national pension plan, the Employees Provident Fund, would each own five percent, with the Sarawak state government holding 28 percent, the report said.</p>
<p>Lead contractor for the project, Ekran Bhd last week said it will hold a 32 percent stake. The remaining 25 percent is expected to be offered to the public.</p>
<p>Recently-introduced laws allow infrastructure projects to raise funds on the stock market with lower listing requirements.</p>
<p>Tenaga closed unchanged at 8.65 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201-4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
