<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102589" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Georgia indicators signal economic growth.</title>
<headline>Georgia indicators signal economic growth.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Georgia's composite index of leading economic indicators moved up in August for the second consecutive month, signaling a healthy though moderating post-Olympics economy, state Labor Commissioner David Poythress said in his monthly report.</p>
<p>August's leading indicators, which are designed to forecast economic activity three to six months ahead, rose 0.17 points to 143.31 on a 1988 index base of 100.</p>
<p>The state's Composite Index of Coincident Economic Indicators, which are designed to reflect current conditions, dropped as expected from an Olympics spending splurge. That index plunged 2.62 points to 144.68 on a 1987 base of 100.</p>
<p>Georgia has begun to wean itself from an estimated $4 billion economic boost provided over the last few years by preparations for the 1996 Summer Olympics and by the games themselves. Although a less dramatic rate of growth is in the making, the economy will remain strong, Poythress said.</p>
<p>Upward movement in the index of leading indicators for August was fueled by sharp increases in applications for residential building permits and new motor vehicle sales, increasing manufacturing activity and a decrease in the numbers of unemployment claims.</p>
<p>Local governments issued 6,826 residential building permits during the month, an increase of 5.23 percent over July. Some economicsts had anticpated construction activity would fall off sharply after the Olympics.</p>
<p>Georgia Department of Revenue received title applications for 41,909 new motor vehicles in August, an increae of 7.12 percent over July.</p>
<p>Georgia's average manufacturing workweek increased to 42.4 hours from 42.3 hours even though total manufacturing empoyment also rose to 589,200 from 588,500. Initial unemployment claims dropped to 29,112 in August from 30,227 in July.</p>
<p>State revenue collections rose to $886.2 million in August, an increase of 1.02 percent from July and 11.81 percent from August of last year.</p>
<p>Nonagricultural employment grew by 10,000 to 3.57 million in August despite the loss of Olympics-related jobs. Retail employement grew by 4,900 jobs to 680,500.</p>
<p>Georgia's unemployment rate rose to 4.4 percent in August from 4.3 percent in July. That was down from 5.1 percent a year ago.</p>
<p>--Jane Sutton, 305-374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E71">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
