<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102610" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: San Miguel sees higher Q3 income.</title>
<headline>San Miguel sees higher Q3 income.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>San Miguel Corp expects third quarter income to show some improvement over last year, Chief Financial Officer Delfin Gonzalez Jr. said on Tuesday at the Jardine Fleming Asia Conference in New York.</p>
<p>However, Gonzalez said, this would not compensate for the shortfall of the first half and the company &quot;expects to finish the year with net income slightly lower than last year.&quot;</p>
<p>The Philippine food and drink conglomerate reported a 19 percent net income drop in the first half to 2.4 billion Philippine pesos, down from three billion pesos last year.  </p>
<p>The company blamed the losses on weak demand from the agricultural sector, higher raw material costs and expansion costs.</p>
<p>Gonzalez said the company's fortunes were on the mend as the agricultural sector recovered, international operations picked up and the tie-up with Miller Brewing Co to sell and distribute Miller Genuine Draft beer began to have an impact.</p>
<p>He said that beer volume sales in the June to September period were fairly flat versus the year ago compared to a six percent decline in the first half.  </p>
<p>International brewing operations were another reason for optimism going forward, he said, especially in Indonesia and China where volume was expected to pick up. Gonzalez said that the company's China operations were expected to start making a profit in 1998.</p>
<p>However, he said, in view of start-up costs, &quot;international operations are expected to show a net loss this year and next.&quot;</p>
<p>He said margins were recovering at the company's soft drink arm, Coca-Cola Bottlers Philippines Inc. The benefit of the price rise implemented by the company in March 1996 was curtailed because of high sugar prices in the second quarter but, &quot;this half our margins are back on track.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
