<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102955" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Council agrees EU should sponsor global Internet conference.</title>
<headline>Council agrees EU should sponsor global Internet conference.</headline>
<byline>Suzanne Perry</byline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Industry Council agreed on Tuesday that Germany should host an international conference to discuss ways to prevent the misuse of the Internet and other information networks.</p>
<p>Germany had proposed to the ministers that the conference tackle issues such as privacy, licensing of services, intellectual property, pornography and security of information.</p>
<p>A text presented by German Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt said the EU should launch an international initiative to find &quot;a common understanding on means and conditions governing the use of global information networks&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We have decided that Germany will host an international conference on this subject next year,&quot; Irish Enterprises and Employment Minister Richard Bruton, who chaired the meeting, told a news conference.</p>
<p>The ministers backed the conference in a resolution they adopted on ways to promote the &quot;information society&quot;, or pan-European computer and telecommunications networks.</p>
<p>The European Commission also plans to endorse the conference in a paper it is close to adopting on ways to tackle &quot;illegal and harmful&quot; material on the Internet, Commission officials said.</p>
<p>That subject has drawn increasing attention in Europe in recent months because of a Belgian child-sex scandal that resulted in the deaths of four girls.</p>
<p>The Telecommunications Council agreed last month to expand a working group that is looking at ways to keep child pornography and other illegal material off the Internet and to report back before the Council's next meeting in November.</p>
<p>The Commission's paper, being drawn up by Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann, will deal with a range of illegal or harmful activities, for example copyright piracy and using the Internet to incite terrorism, the officials said.</p>
<p>It will highlight policy questions such as how much responsibility service providers should have to police illegal content, they said.</p>
<p>The resolution adopted by ministers does not propose many other concrete initiatives, but simply highlights some of the policy areas that need to be addressed.</p>
<p>For example, it says EU states and the Commission should analyse the problem of material on electronic networks &quot;adversely affecting public order and morality&quot;, as well as the need for measures to ensure that electronically transmitted documents are authentic.</p>
<p>It also restates existing EU goals such as liberalising telecommunications markets and improving the functioning of the big single market.</p>
<p>Bruton acknowledged that the text was general, but said it was important that industry ministers had come together to set an agenda for future work on the sector, noting that EU industry lagged behind its U.S. competitors.</p>
<p>&quot;In the U.S., 60 percent of companies use e-mail, whereas in many EU countries the figure is only half that. Recent figures show that nearly one third of the U.S. population had a (personal computer) at home, compared with one in 10 in the EU,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>The Council adopted the resolution after hearing presentations by Bangemann, Social Affairs Commissioner Padraig Flynn and Internal Market Commissioner Mario Monti on various recent initiatives the Commission has taken to promote the information society.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
