<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102916" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Asian states launch WTO shrimp case against U.S.</title>
<headline>Asian states launch WTO shrimp case against U.S.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four Asian countries on Tuesday launched a case against the United States in the World Trade Organisation over its ban on shrimp imports worth hundreds of millions of dollars, trade sources said.</p>
<p>India, Malaysia, Pakistan and Thailand sent a letter to the U.S. mission to the WTO asking for consultations on the issue, a major environmentalist cause in the United States, under the trade watchdog's dispute settlement procedure.</p>
<p>The ban came into force in May this year after the New York-based U.S. Court of International Trade found in favour of an environmental group that complained many imported shrimps were caught with methods that killed sea turtles.</p>
<p>The Court ruled that so-called wild shrimps caught at sea by ships not using devices or techniques to protect turtles, an endangered species, could not be imported.</p>
<p>Asian countries, which are more heavily engaged in marine shrimp fishing, have been especially badly hit by the decision, which they argue effectively seeks to impose U.S. environmental laws on other countries.</p>
<p>Most Latin American countries, also providers of shrimp to a U.S. market worth $2.34 billion annually, use an acquaculture system to produce their exports or catch them in cold waters where there are no turtles.</p>
<p>The U.S. National Fisheries Institute was reported to have estimated after the ban went into effect that it would block between $200 and $500 million worth of shrimps, or about 25 per cent of all imports into the country.</p>
<p>Thailand, which sold shrimps worth some $980 million to the United States in 1994 although only 10 per cent of these were wild, sent a senior-level delegation to Washington in the summer to try to resolve the problem.</p>
<p>The request for consultations by the four, acting jointly and with the support of other shrimp exporters, is the first step in the carefully-constructed dispute procedure in whose shaping Washington itself played a key role.</p>
<p>The United States has 10 days to reply, and has to begin the consultations within 30 days. If no solution has been agreed 30 days later, the four can ask for -- with the certainty of getting -- creation of a full dispute panel.</p>
<p>Under the procedure, the rules of which replace the much looser practices under the old General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT), if panel and appeals rulings go against Washington, it will have to lift the ban or pay compensation to the four for the value of lost trade.</p>
<p>In a similar case, a GATT panel found in 1994 that a U.S. ban on imports of tuna caught without adequate protection for dolphins was illegal under agreed international trade rules.</p>
<p>Under the GATT, however, any country could block approval of a panel decision by witholding its consensus and the United States was not obliged to withdraw the ban.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I03000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
