<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="102924" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Shamir criticises Weizman over Arafat meeting.</title>
<headline>Shamir criticises Weizman over Arafat meeting.</headline>
<byline>Bernard Edinger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli ex-premier Yitzhak Shamir criticised President Ezer Weizman on Tuesday for meeting Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat, saying he disagreed especially if Weizman wanted to put pressure on Israel's government.</p>
<p>Shamir, who turns 81 next month, also dismissed reports that he had been taken ill in the French capital last week. He only admitted grudgingly: &quot;Maybe I was a bit tired but that can happen to everyone.&quot;</p>
<p>Commenting on Tuesday's meeting between the Palestinian president and the left-leaning Weizman in the Mediterranean coastal resort of Caesarea, Shamir told reporters: &quot;I don't know the details but he (Weizman) should not have done this.</p>
<p>&quot;Some newspapers say Weizman wanted to put pressure on (Israel's right-wing) government to force it to come to an agreement with Arafat. I can't understand how an Israeli president can do such a thing and use such means,&quot; Shamir said.</p>
<p>&quot;I know Weizman well, I have esteem for him and like him but I disagree with what he did,&quot; said Shamir, the hardline prime minister of Israel from 1986 to 1992.</p>
<p>Visiting Weizman's private home, a beaming Arafat struck all the right chords, pledging that &quot;negotiations will be the tool to resolve our differences&quot;.</p>
<p>Shamir, on a European fund-raising tour for the Jewish National Fund (Keren Kayemet), was also critical, though more guardedly, of Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for having met Arafat on two separate occasions.</p>
<p>&quot;I think what was required could have been done without meeting Arafat but I don't want to criticIse him (Netanyahu). Now it is done and one can still correct a lot of mistakes.&quot;</p>
<p>Netanyahu is a successor to Shamir as head of the right-wing Likud party and began his political career under Shamir.</p>
<p>The former premier also said the Palestinian Intifada uprising in the occupied territories would have petered out had he remained in power.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last year of my government in 1992, it was already nearly liquidated.&quot; Asked how international opinion would have reacted, Shamir replied: &quot;The world accepts facts.&quot;</p>
<p>The former Jewish underground fighter and spymaster said the Oslo agreements between Israel and the Palestinians &quot;were solely aimed at turning over parts of the Land of Israel to our enemies.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Israel had been wrong to withdraw from major Arab centres in the West bank and Gaza Strip and should never leave the contested city of Hebron. &quot;It is a holy Jewish city and we should not turn it over to our enemies. I hope many Jews will go to live there,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
