<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103143" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. proposes 'open skies' air pact with Japan.</title>
<headline>U.S. proposes 'open skies' air pact with Japan.</headline>
<byline>Robert Trautman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States has proposed a free-market &quot;open skies&quot; aviation agreement with Japan in a move that could resolve their troubled aviation problems, the U.S. Transportation Department said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But spokesman William Mosley said Japan has not yet responded to the offer, made by Transportation Secretary Federico Pena in a letter on Sept. 25.</p>
<p>He said an agreement to end government restrictions on aviation between the two and allow the market place to dictate routes and frequencies would resolve the many U.S. and Japanese aviation problems now outstanding.</p>
<p>Talks on the dispute broke off last summer.</p>
<p>An end to restrictions was seen as helping U.S. carriers American Airlines, a unit AMR Corp. ; Delta Air Lines Inc. and Trans World Airlines Inc. to get into the big and growing Japanese market.</p>
<p>The U.S. carriers now controlling it are United Airlines, part of UAL Corp. and Northwest Airlines Corp..</p>
<p>U.S. officials said Pena proposed an accord that would end all restrictions on bilateral commercial aviation, allowing Japanese airlines to serve any U.S. cities they wished and American carriers to serve any Japanese city.</p>
<p>The United States already has such &quot;open skies&quot; agreements with Canada, Germany and a number of smaller European countries.</p>
<p>It has also been seeking a free market pact with Britain, but has been rebuffed by British reluctance to allow increased U.S. flights into London Heathrow airport, considered the key transfer point for travel beyond to continental Europe.</p>
<p>U.S.-Japan aviation relations have been clouded recently by what American officials say is Japan's refusal to abide by their existing accord to allow U.S. airlines to fly to Japan and then to Asian points beyond.</p>
<p>The disagreements cover extended flights by United and Northwest, as well additional flights to the United States by Japan Airlines and All Nippon Airways.</p>
<p>Other carriers have more limited access to Japan, and they have been pushing for a new accord to open the way for them to increase their services to Japan and Asia beyond.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
