<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103490" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Court jails Dutchman in Philippine child sex case.</title>
<headline>Court jails Dutchman in Philippine child sex case.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Kelly</byline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A court jailed a 43-year-old Dutchman for five years on Tuesday for sex offences committed against young girls while he was on holiday in the Philippines.</p>
<p>The district court in The Hague said computer specialist and father of two Johan van der Scheer treated the children, some as young as 12, as objects for his own sexual gratification.</p>
<p>&quot;The suspect treated his victims as objects to satisfy his sexual desires, he did so repeatedly and in an extraordinarily sickening manner,&quot; presiding judge Leendert Verheij said.</p>
<p>Van der Scheer is the first Dutch citizen to be tried for sex offences committed against minors in another country, though Australian and German courts have jailed men for similar crimes.</p>
<p>He was arrested in February after a photo laboratory tipped off police that films he had sent to be developed showed adults taking part in sex acts with children. A police search of his home in the mediaeval Dutch town of Delft led to the seizure of more photos and video recordings portraying similar scenes.</p>
<p>The court said Van der Scheer had admitted filming his exploits &quot;for kicks&quot;.</p>
<p>Judge Verheij said the defendant had remained indifferent and emotionless throughout the hearings, even when confronted in court with video recordings of his offences.</p>
<p>A psychiatric report said Van der Scheer was highly egocentric but was not mentally ill, adding there was a danger that he might commit similar offences again in the future.</p>
<p>Van der Scheer, dressed smartly and well groomed for his court appearance, appeared shocked as he heard the verdict.</p>
<p>He had admitted visiting young Philippine prostitutes but told the court he had thought they were 16 or older.</p>
<p>Defence lawyer Dirk van der Landen said the court's verdict was unreasonably severe and had pandered to public opinion, adding that he had advised his client to appeal.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a verdict for the public, a verdict which reflects the commotion about sexual abuse of children but which does not do justice in terms of the charges against my client,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year an Australian court jailed a man for six years for child sex crimes in the Philippines and a German court jailed a man for two years for similar offences in Thailand.</p>
<p>In both cases the men were arrested after being found in possession of pornographic video tapes featuring children.</p>
<p>Campaigners for children's rights have recently called on countries around the world to amend their laws if necessary to give their courts powers to prosecute &quot;sex tourists&quot;.</p>
<p>The U.N. Children's Fund estimates that each year one million children around the world are forced into prostitution, sold for sexual purposes or used in pornography.</p>
<p>The Philippines, long a favourite destination for paedophiles from wealthy countries, has recently launched a crackdown, handing down heavy jail sentences to offenders.</p>
<p>In May and July Philippine courts jailed an Australian and a Briton for up to 17 years each.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
