<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103422" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FORECAST-Britain to delay EMU decision - analysts.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Britain to delay EMU decision - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Pratima Desai</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>An expected victory for Labour in the UK general election may increase the chances of greater co-operation with Europe, but economists expect Britain to exclude itself for the start of EMU on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;The UK is heading to fail the budget deficit criterion, and even if they were to water down the (Maastricht Treaty) reference criteria the political will is not there,&quot; Alex Garrard, UK economist at UBS said.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not envisage the UK being amongst the first wave of countries to join European monetary union.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the economists who provided forecasts for Reuters quarterly poll of UK economic forecasts published on Tuesday do not expect Britain to aim at being among the first to join EMU.</p>
<p>Contributors to the survey were not specifically asked for their forecasts of the UK budget deficit as a percentage of GDP, but they were asked to predict the Public Sector Borrowing Requirement for the next two years.</p>
<p>The UK general government deficit is equivalent to the budget deficit as defined by the Maastricht criteria. An approximate definition is the PSBR minus privatisation receipts.</p>
<p>The mean of forecasts for PSBR for financial year 1996/97 was 27.9 billion stg and 24.5 billion stg for 1997/98 compared to government forecasts of 27 billion stg and 23 billion stg.</p>
<p>UBS forecasts the UK budget deficit at 5.1 percent of GDP at end-1997 -- the Maastricht criteria calls for three percent or less -- versus the 3.7 percent forecast by the European Commission in May.</p>
<p>A Labour government, now widely tipped to succeed the Conservatives in an election which must be held by next May, would be perceived as being more pro-European than a Conservative government, Stephen Hannah, chief economist at IBJ International, said.</p>
<p>&quot;But I can't see Labour wanting to be totally dominated by the European agenda. Education and unemployment will be seen as more pressing issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>IBJ forecasts the budget deficit at 3.7 percent of GDP for end-1997 and the PSBR for 1997/98 at 26.8 billion stg.</p>
<p>Hannah also noted that 1997 is not Labour's call as far as fiscal policy is concerned. &quot;Basically it's Clarke's budget.&quot;</p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke is due to present the final budget of this government on November 26.</p>
<p>Adrian Owens, European economist at Julius Baer Investments, expects no extra measures to bring the deficit down to three percent of GDP.</p>
<p>&quot;But if the government has a referendum, which decides that we will go for the first wave, I would have to factor in expenditure cuts and tax hikes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>EMU is expected to take place in two stages. The first stage to include Germany, France, Austria, Netherlands, Luxembourg and Belgium.</p>
<p>Many economists who took part in the poll think Labour will have to promise a referendum on joining a single currency before a decision is taken, as the Conservatives have done.</p>
<p>A poll by Gallup for the Daily Telegraph newspaper on Monday showed 56 percent of voters were against Britain joining a single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>Owens expects the UK budget deficit at 3.7 percent of GDP end-1997 and forecast the PSBR for financial year 1997/98 at 27 billion stg.</p>
<p>But it will be harder for the UK to meet the exchange rate criterion, which expects countries to have been a part of the European exchange rate mechanism (ERM) for two years prior to EMU. This would mean sterling would have to join by end-1996, which most of the analysts surveyed do not expect to happen.</p>
<p>&quot;But the government will in some way try and track the Euro, there will be some sort of regime imposed,&quot; UBS's Garrard said.</p>
<p>Forecasts provided for the quarterly survey show a mean for sterling at 2.3032 marks by end-1996, falling to 2.2750 marks by end of first quarter 1998.</p>
<p>The UK already meets the requirement that total debt as a percentage of GDP should be no more than 60 percent.</p>
<p>In 1994 this was 50.3 percent and for 1997 the EU Commision forecast is 56.2 percent.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 2737.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
