<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103524" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France denies plan to strip Eramet's mine assets.</title>
<headline>France denies plan to strip Eramet's mine assets.</headline>
<byline>Dominique Vidalon</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French government said on Tuesday it had no plans to strip part of the mining assets of nickel producer Eramet in New Caledonia as part of negotiations over mining reserves in the Pacific territory.</p>
<p>&quot;It formally denies the serious allegations that it might try to rob Eramet of part of its mining resources,&quot; the government said.</p>
<p>The statement helped calm worries of investors who propelled Eramet shares 14.8 francs higher to trade at 280.8 francs by early afternoon.</p>
<p>The shares, which have been losing ground over the last few days, plunged to a year-low of 247 francs earlier on Tuesday, amid concern the government might force Eramet, in which it owns a 55 percent stake, to sell part of its mining interests in New Caledonia.</p>
<p>Under a 1988 plan to quell separatist tensions in the French territory in the South Pacific, France agreed to help rebalance political, social and economic interests in favour of the local Kanak people against those of French settlers ahead of a vote on independence set for 1998.</p>
<p>France is widely expected to support a project by the pro-independence Kanak Socialist Liberation Front Party (FLNKS) and Canadian firm Falconbridge to build a nickel plant in northern New Caledonia.</p>
<p>The plan would deal a severe blow to Eramet's expansion strategy in New Caledonia as it might have to sell part or the totality of its mining reserves of Thiebaghi in order to supply the proposed new plant, analysts said.</p>
<p>Despite the government's pledge, investors, which include powerful British and U.S financial institutions, were still worried about the group's future in New Caledonia.</p>
<p>Analysts said there were concerns that Eramet's highly regarded chairman Yves Rambaud might be replaced as he opposes any plan that could curb Eramet's mining assets in the region.</p>
<p>Eramet board members were meeting to study a plan put forward by state-controlled holding group Erap to turn Eramet into a company with a supervisory and a management bord. If cleared, the proposal might mean management changes.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are furious that a government may use its 55 percent stake in a listed company to push through its political interests in New Caledonia,&quot; one analyst said,</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever happens, the damage is done. The share is dead on the stock market,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>The affair may also spell trouble for future privatisations if investors feel the government is ignoring them to push through its own political interests, analysts warned.</p>
<p>Eramet ranks third among world nickel producers. It plans to produce more than 60,000 tonnes of nickel by the year 2,000, up from expected 1996 output of 53,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The higher output was expected to come mostly from nickel facilities in New Caledonia, where Eramet recently decided to build a fith rotary kiln at its Doniambo smelter,</p>
<p>Eramet started to develop the Thiebaghi nickel deposit in early 1995 and hopes to reach a capacity of 24,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>One analyst suggested the state might offer to buy out minority shareholders particularly if the stock price remained low. But other analysts thought the scenario of a &quot;re-nationalisation&quot; was highly unlikely.</p>
<p>Plans to build a Kanak-Canadian plant in northern New Caledonia are bound to be controversial as the project would require huge investment and significant financial aid from an already cash-strapped French state, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NEWCAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
