<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103551" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Samsung tables Fokker rescue plan.</title>
<headline>Samsung tables Fokker rescue plan.</headline>
<byline>Lucas van Grinsven</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM, Netherlands</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's Samsung Aerospace made a concrete proposal for a relaunch of bankrupt planemaker Fokker Tuesday when it handed over a long-awaited business plan to the Dutch Economics Ministry.</p>
<p>A large delegation of Samsung officials and Fokker receivers arrived early in the afternoon in The Hague, where they presented their plan, a ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>Samsung is asking the government to take a minority stake in the new Fokker and to provide large sums of money in straight subsidies, but neither Fokker nor the Ministry would give any further details.</p>
<p>&quot;The plan has just arrived. We'll study it carefully and then formulate a reaction,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The planemaker collapsed under a mountain of debt and went bankrupt on March 15, two months after its German parent Daimler Benz Aerospace cut a vital cash lifeline.</p>
<p>The firm has since been kept alive artificially by its court-appointed receivers. It has even accepted orders for new aircraft to preserve the value of its assets. But a structural rescue is needed before the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;We told the (Fokker) workers on Friday that the deadline for a possible rescue is at the end of October,&quot; said Ben Knueppe, spokesman for the receivers.</p>
<p>A rescue hinges on whether the Dutch government is prepared to invest tax-payers' money in a relaunch. The Fokker receivers and Samsung have a common interest and have already settled most outstanding issues, said a source close to the negotiations.</p>
<p>A successful resuscitation depends on three factors -- the purchasing sum, the establishment of a new aircraft leasing company and, most importantly, loans to develop a new 125-seat aircraft, he said, quoting work documents for the business plan.</p>
<p>The South Koreans have put great emphasis on a new, larger aircraft, capable of carrying more passengers than Fokker's current line of 50-, 70- and 100-seat jets. Fokker's work documents estimate the development costs of a new 125-seat aircraft at roughly 700 million guilders ($409.1 million).</p>
<p>This amount could be increased by 500 million guilders ($292 million) if it were decided to revamp the F70 and F100 jetliners, extending their life cycle beyond 2010.</p>
<p>If Samsung and the Dutch government strike a deal before the end-October deadline, jobs at the F70 and F100 assembly lines will be safe for the remaining life of these planes.</p>
<p>Most of the design and engineering work on the new 125-seat jet will also be done in the Netherlands but it will be built in South Korea, the source said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
