<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103677" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: German jobless rise lifts Belgian bourse.</title>
<headline>German jobless rise lifts Belgian bourse.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strong rise in bonds on the back of higher-than-expected German jobless figures lifted Belgian shares just out of the red on Tuesday, setting the stage for a renewed rally, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market started weak, but in the afternoon bonds picked up strongly on the German unemployment figures and that led to the recovery,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is now waiting for direction, which we think will be up. If the Dow closes above 6,000 tonight we could go higher very strongly,&quot; he added. The Dow Jones Industrial Average  .DJI was 22.36 points up at 6,002.17.</p>
<p>Traders said Tuesday, as Monday, was typified by light profit-taking following last week's three successive record high closes on the Bel-20 share index  .BFX, culminating in an engineered, brief but significant, break above 1,800 points.</p>
<p>Share analysts have been talking of a long-term objective between 1,850 and 1,880. On Tuesday publicly-owned bank Credit Communal/Gemeentekrediet said in a study the Bel-20 could hit 2,000 by the end of next year.</p>
<p>Discount retailer Colruyt was Tuesday's star, adding 325 francs to 12,800 -- although it was still well down from its October 3 year high of 13,800.</p>
<p>Electrabel was the busiest share by value, adding 50 francs at 7,250 on turnover of 23,881 shares, followed by Tractebel which rose 25 francs to 14,725 francs on turnover of 12,317 shares.</p>
<p>But Powerfin was among the biggest percentage losers, down 2.1 percent to 4,600 francs.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index ended Tuesday up just 0.01 percent at 1,778.05. Total market volume was an above average 2.7 billion francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
