<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103700" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: FOCUS - VNU says Blenheim strategic buy.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - VNU says Blenheim strategic buy.</headline>
<dateline>HAARLEM, Netherlands 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch publisher VNU said on Tuesday its acquisition of a 14.99 percent stake in Britain's Blenheim Group was a strategic long-term investment.</p>
<p>&quot;A significant investment in such an exhibitions business is...in line with our long-term strategy of expanding in professional information markets,&quot; VNU chairman Bart Brentjens said in a statement.</p>
<p>Exhibitions and conference organising currently account for a scant one percent of VNU group turnover.</p>
<p>Subsidiaries active in this segment are Bill Communications of the U.S. and VNU Business Publications in Britain.</p>
<p>VNU announced earlier it had bought a 14.99 percent stake in Blenheim from institutional investors at a price of 500 pence per Blenheim share.</p>
<p>It said it was not weighing a short-term bid for all Blenheim shares outstanding, barring rival offers for the firm.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisition of this stake fits with our strategy to expand our spread of activities in other types of media and other geographical areas,&quot; VNU spokesman Maarten Schikker said.</p>
<p>Blenheim was a highly internationally-oriented company with attractive gross margins, he added.</p>
<p>The exhibitions organisor had a significant presence in France, the United States, Britain and Germany, covering 14 different market sectors. Its gross margin in 1995 was 21 percent, Schikker said.</p>
<p>Schikker declined to comment on how far VNU was prepared to build up its newly-acquired stake in Blenheim or whether it planned eventually to take over the company completely.</p>
<p>&quot;That's a difficult question to answer at this moment. We will consider our position in the near future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>VNU's bid for Blenheim shares represents a premium on their Monday closing price of 435-1/2 pence.</p>
<p>&quot;We think this is a full price,&quot; Schikker conceded, adding &quot;we are prepared to pay five pounds ($7.8) (per share) to secure a long-term holding in Blenheim. It is a fair price.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We believe this a very good deal,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Lien van der Leij, Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000 ($ = 0.640 British Pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAARLEM, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
