<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103882" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIAN EXOTICS - Falling output pressures Singapore dollar.</title>
<headline>ASIAN EXOTICS - Falling output pressures Singapore dollar.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>News of worse than expected Singapore industrial output figures put the local currency under renewed pressure on Tuesday, forcing it down to key support levels against the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>By 0430 GMT, the Singapore dollar had been pushed down to just above 1.4120, a barrier it has not broken for two months.</p>
<p>Singapore's Economic Development Board said on Monday evening the city-state's total manufacturing output fell an unexpected 7.6 percent year-on-year in August, far worse than analysts had forecast.</p>
<p>The data encouraged several economists to revise downwards their forecasts for the country's economic growth for the year, with some saying growth may be around 6.5 percent in 1996 from 8.8 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;This morning there was a knee-jerk reaction to the overnight data showing an industrial production decline,&quot; said a Singapore-based dealer. &quot;But the U.S. dollar was never able to challenge the 1.4120 level and the Sing kept bouncing back.&quot;</p>
<p>One dealer said some major players appeared to be trying to push the Singapore dollar down below 1.4120 to try to trigger stop-loss selling.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is some very big comercial buying at that level and the Sing looks well supported,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit was almost unchanged against its southern neighbour at 0.5642 Singapore dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;Manufacturing figures were down, so they were buying ringgit and selling the Sing,&quot; said a Kuala lumpur-based U.S. bank dealer.</p>
<p>Against the U.S. dollar, the ringgit was at 2.5010/20, almost unchanged from its local close on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;On dollar/ringgit, we saw some people trying to push it below the 2.50 level, but quite a lot of buying interest came into the market every time it got there,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>Dealers said the ringgit was likely to stay within a fairly narrow 2.4990-2.5040 range until the release sometime over the next two weeks of Malaysia's trade figures, widely expected to show a surplus.</p>
<p>The Indonesian rupiah was steady against the dollar in slow early trading.</p>
<p>One local bank dealer said some offshore operators were trying to push the dollar down at the opening but met strong support at the 2,321.25 level, which helped the dollar rebound to the 2,321.75/22.25 level.</p>
<p>Spot rupiah was traded at 2,321.30/1.80 at 0430 GMT against an opening of 2,322.50/23.00.</p>
<p>&quot;The pressure was short-lived. Somebody wanted to test the downside but support was strong for the dollar because of the central bank's floor rate,&quot; the local bank dealer said.</p>
<p>Bank Indonesia raised its intervention rate by one point to 2,318/2,510 and the conversion rate also by one point to 2,318/2,366 on Monday.</p>
<p>A dealer in Singapore said the bank was expected to raise soon the floor of its intervention rate further to 2,322.</p>
<p>The Thai baht edged up to 25.437-25.442 to the dollar by 0430 GMT, from 25.451-25.454 late on Monday but still appeared to be headed down.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears some foreign funds began to flow out after (the) recent sell-off in the stock market,&quot; said one currency dealer.</p>
<p>The Thai stock index has fallen by 14 percent over the past five trading sessions as foreign funds reduce their investment weight on Thai shares by selling off most blue-chip bank and finance stocks, analysts said.</p>
<p>Dealers said dollar buying in the early morning was also because the U.S. unit was believed to have reached its support level against other major currencies.</p>
<p>-- Reme Ahmad in Kuala Lumpur (603-230 8911), Mantik Kusjanto in Jakarta (6221-384-6364), Anuchit Nguyen in Bangkok (662-652-0642) and Chris Johnson in Singapore (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
