<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="103978" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: IMF asks Philippines to contribute to programme.</title>
<headline>IMF asks Philippines to contribute to programme.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Monetary Fund had asked the Philippines to help it in its initiatives to help low-income countries, Central Bank Governor Gabriel Singson said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reached a milestone in our relations with the IMF,&quot; Singson, who attended the IMF-World Bank meetings in Washington, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only because we no longer need to borrow from the IMF but also because we have been asked by the IMF to help subsidise its lending programme.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Philippines was asked to contribute to a fund that will provide interest rate subsidies to the Enhanced Structural Facility (ESAF), the concessional lending window of the IMF to support adjustment programmes in low-income countries including those heavily indebted, the statement said.</p>
<p>The recently concluded annual meetings focused on ways to finance the continuation of the ESAF and to help resolve the debt burden of the most heavily-indebted poor countries.</p>
<p>IMF officials also welcomed the intention of the Philippine government to end its status as a borrowing country in the IMF upon completion of a three-year Extended Fund Facility programme due to end in mid-1997, Singson said.</p>
<p>Compared to previous meetings, IMF officials had fewer concerns about the Philippine economy, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This time they urged completion of the remaining agenda of reforms in the fiscal sector, an increase in domestic savings rates and continued careful management of the financial system which they believe would secure further progress towards stronger and more sustained growth,&quot; Singson added.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom 63 2 841-8937 fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
