<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="104208" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Eurobourses weaker after Monday's records.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Eurobourses weaker after Monday's records.</headline>
<byline>Peter Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The main European stock exchanges were lower in early trading on Tuesday following a bullish Monday which saw no fewer than eight bourses hit new record highs.</p>
<p>Sentiment was blunted when Wall Street's recent rally faltered overnight with the Dow Industrial Average ending down 13 points.</p>
<p>But while Frankfurt and Paris merely faltered, London, Europe's biggest exchange, took a sharp dive after the government said shareholders would no longer be able to claim tax credits on share buybacks or special dividend payouts.</p>
<p>The surprise statement wiped almost 30 points off the blue chip FTSE 100 index, but it later recovered somewhat to trade about 18 points down.</p>
<p>Shares in Reuters Holdings Plc and other companies planning or likely to make share buybacks or special dividend payments showed the greatest losses.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt floor trading opened a few points down at the beginning of what dealers said looked like being a day of consolidation after the market's recent rise to record levels.</p>
<p>Sportswear maker ADIDAS rose sharply after it announced it will be an official sponsor for the 1998 soccer world cup.</p>
<p>And on the Paris bourse, shares also opened down and slipped further. Traders said the market was consolidating after its recent strong gains and some profit-taking among last week's risers was expected.</p>
<p>Debt-mired Eurotunnel was requoted down nine francs in heavy trading after Monday's details of its equity restructuring.</p>
<p>On the currency markets, the dollar was steadier after slipping lower against the mark in early European trade amid a bout of profit-taking from its September rally.</p>
<p>However, dealers said activity was light with the dollar likely to find strong support around the 1.52 mark area.</p>
<p>With no major U.S. economic data until Friday's producer prices and retail sales figures, dealers said the dollar will be susceptible to more profit-taking throughout the week.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the dollar was steady around 111.00 yen, its session lows.</p>
<p>Monday's comments from senior Japanese politicians about raising rates after this month's general election were taken lightly by the market but have still created an air of caution over aggressive yen sales, dealers said.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 0900 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.5258 marks and 111.05 yen comapred with 1.5299 marks and 111.22 yen late in Europe on Monday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0900 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was down 17.1 points at 4014.4.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was down 7.35 at 2,144.20.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was down 4.04 at 2698.6</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was firmer firmer in early Europe at $380.90 compared with $380.15 at the London close on Monday. Silver was little changed at $4.90.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
