<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="104232" id="root" date="1996-10-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - Updated classics are hot for holiday toys.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Updated classics are hot for holiday toys.</headline>
<byline>Judith Schoolman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tea sets, Mr. Potato Head and anything Barbie, Batman or Spiderman are expected to top children's holiday toy lists this year, as updated versions of classics push aside some recent movie tie-ins as the items most in demand.</p>
<p>&quot;It's different this year -- there's no big hit, no 'Power Rangers' or no one major toy brand out there&quot; that children will be clamouring for, said Christopher Byrne, editor of the trade journal Market Focus: Toys.</p>
<p>Rather, he said, parents may want to consider some tried and true oldies but goodies.</p>
<p>&quot;Play never really changes,&quot; he said. &quot;It's just how it gets expressed.&quot;</p>
<p>Parents will spend about $231 per child on toys this year, about the same they spent in 1995, Byrne said. &quot;There won't be an increase in spending, but parents will be spending smarter.&quot;</p>
<p>Adults may want to seek out toys that stress creativity and expression, especially when it comes to girls' toys, which have lacked ingenuity and variety in the past few years.</p>
<p>New toys of value this year aimed at girls include Kidsview's Tea Bunnies, colourful dolls which live inside decorated tea cups. Sets include Tea Bunnies Fancy Dessert Tea Party ($19.99) and Tea Bunnies Wedding Tea Party ($29.99).</p>
<p>Byrne also likes Tyco Toys' Kitchen Littles ($6.99 and up), with doll-sized food, pans and cooking utensils. For future shoppers, Melanie's Mall, by Cap Toys ($1.50 to $29.99), allows children to play-act in what may become a favourite teenage hangout.</p>
<p>Electronics are of continuing appeal to children, Byrne said, especially when high-tech meets classic. Some examples are the CD-Roms, Mr. Potato Head Saves Veggie Valley ($29.99) and the Barbie Design Maker Studio ($49.95).</p>
<p>Here, Mattel has extended the age of the typical Barbie doll player (ages 4 through 7) by introducing a computer programme for slightly older children, allowing them to design and &quot;manufacture&quot; Barbie's new outfits.</p>
<p>Electronic toys for toddlers are increasingly popular. Tyco's Tickle Me Elmo ($28) is a plush version of the 'Sesame Street' character. When a child tickles Elmo, he laughs and says &quot;that's funny.&quot;</p>
<p>A toy like this is &quot;interactive, which is what kids always want,&quot; Byrne said. &quot;Kids don't change.&quot;</p>
<p>What has changed, however, is children's love affair with some movie-tie ins. The popularity of toys based on &quot;The Lion King&quot;, &quot;Aladdin&quot; and &quot;The Little Mermaid&quot; has not been repeated in Disney's &quot;Hunchback of Notre Dame.&quot;</p>
<p>The latest Disney animated film does not inspire the same types of &quot;play patterns&quot; that the other Disney hits did, and, therefore, there is a wealth of &quot;Hunchback&quot; items lingering on toy store shelves across the country.</p>
<p>Byrne said the Disney animated film &quot;Toy Story&quot; is being released soon on home video, and parents might want to be aware of &quot;a lot of toys, and demand, related to that.&quot;</p>
<p>Also, Warner Brothers' &quot;Space Jam,&quot; starring basketball hero Michael Jordan and classic cartoon character Bugs Bunny is being released shortly. &quot;It should be a big hit,&quot; Byrne said, indicating that toy tie-ins may follow suit.</p>
<p>Toys relating to the alien battle film &quot;Independence Day&quot; are losing some of their steam.</p>
<p>However, still riding a wave of renewed popularity from the 1995 release on home video is the &quot;Star Wars&quot; trilogy.</p>
<p>Galoob's Star Wars Micro Machines ($9.99) will appeal to collectors, as will action figures from ever-popular Batman, Superman and Spawn.</p>
<p>Activity toys are going to be popular, Byrne said.</p>
<p>Examples of some valuable toys include Tyco's Sesame Street Activity Sets ($7.99 and up) and Grandma's Surprise: A Box in a Book ($29.99), which helps kids make one-of-a-kind banners. Homemade goodies can be made with Chocolate Holiday Moulding Kit ($19.99) and they can create designs with animal shapes with Topline Toys' You Can't Paint With That ($14.99).</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>You can write to Judith Schoolman at Reuters, 199 Water Street, 10th floor, New York, N.Y. 10038, or e-mail her at Judith.Schoolman(at)Reuters.com.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
