<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="104644" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PairGain slumps on profit taking.</title>
<headline>PairGain slumps on profit taking.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of communications innovator PairGain Technologies Inc lost over 10 percent on Wednesday on profit taking after strong earnings results.</p>
<p>PairGain tumbled 9 to 71-3/4 heading the Nasdaq loss leaders. On Tuesday PairGain reported third quarter profits of $0.25 a share on record revenues of $54.6 million versus a profit of $0.18 on sales of $29.6 million a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a reflection of anything really significant, primarily it is profit-taking,&quot; said Nikos Theodosopoulos, at UBS Securities. &quot;The stock has had a very big run recently and a lot of investors choose to sell after good results.&quot;</p>
<p>PairGain is the dominant comapny in digital subscriber line based systems that allow firms with private networks to send data, video and voice over ordinary copper telephone lines.</p>
<p>The company has strong relationships with the regional Bells which have used its products to speed the flow of information over copper phone lines rather than upgrade to more expensive fibre-optic lines. As use of the Internet mushrooms the need for these products grow.</p>
<p>Shares of PairGain have risen steadily this year from a year low of 13-7/8 to a high last week of 83-3/4.</p>
<p>Theodosopoulos said, based on revenues, PairGain's market is growing at a clip of about 100 percent annually, and while long-term sustainable growth may slow, the company can augment that with new products.</p>
<p>&quot;If (new) products are successful I suspect the stock will rise,&quot; he said. &quot;It is a nascent technology area and they are adding new products to it.&quot;</p>
<p>But some others felt PairGain's stock rose too quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock has appreciated very very rapidly,&quot; said Joe Noel at brokerage firm Hambrecht &amp; Quist. &quot;I think it got way ahead of itself.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there's enough upside in the quarter. They only beat (analyst's earnings estimates) by two cents, which is good ... but really not enough to sustain a stock price (over $80),&quot; Noel said.</p>
<p>Noel said that he estimates a fair valuation for the company's stock would be $75 a share adding that the company remains in a strong position for growth.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will still outperform the high technology sector ,&quot; he said. &quot;Fantastic fundamentals, fantastic company but the stock was just ahead of itself.&quot;</p>
<p>Paul Johnson, analyst at investment bank Robertson Stephens, said Wednesday's drop offered investors a buying opportunity and said the outlook for the company was &quot;outstanding.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is a buying opportunity,&quot; he said. &quot;We've taken the position that the stock is not overvalued.&quot;</p>
<p>Johnson raised his earnings estimates for fiscal 1996 to $0.90 a share from $0.84 and for 1997 to $1.18 from $1.05.</p>
<p>CS First Boston cut its recommendation on the stock to hold from buy. Analyst Mike Schmidt was not available for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
