<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="104776" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Southern buys stake in Asian utility for $2.7 billion.</title>
<headline>Southern buys stake in Asian utility for $2.7 billion.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA</dateline>
<text>
<p>Southern Co. said Wednesday its Southern Electric International unit has agreed to purchase a majority interest in Consolidated Electric Power Asia Ltd. in a deal worth $2.7 billion.</p>
<p>Consolidated Electric, one of Asia's largest independent power producers, is now 60.4 percent owned by Hong Kong-based Hopewell Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the agreement, CEPA (Consolidated Electric) shareholders will receive $2.1 billion from Southern and $600 million in dividends for 80 percent of the company. Hopewell will become the largest minority shareholder of CEPA,&quot; Southern said.</p>
<p>Company officials were not immediately available to explain how this transaction would be carried out.</p>
<p>&quot;Combining the assets of Southern Electric International and CEPA will create one of the world's largest independent power producers, supplying electricity to the heart of Asia -- including three of the world's most populated countries -- as well as Europe, North America and South America,&quot; said Southern Chief Executive Officer A.W. Dahlberg.</p>
<p>Consolidated Electric Asia owns and operates electric power generating plants in China and the Philippines with projects under development in Pakistan and Indonesia.</p>
<p>The company was established in 1993 as a holding company for Hopewell's electric power projects.</p>
<p>Atlanta-based Southern said the transaction was subject to approvals by the Stock Exchange of Hong Kong and CEPA shareholders.</p>
<p>Southern, the largest producer of electricity in the United States, is the parent of five Southeast electric utilities: Alabama Power, Georgia Power, Gulf Power, Mississippi Power and Savannah Electric. Southern stock was off 62.5 cents at $21.875 on the New York Stock Exchange in afternoon trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
