<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="104885" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian traders see GKO market yields down to 50%.</title>
<headline>Russian traders see GKO market yields down to 50%.</headline>
<byline>Anna Smirnova</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian treasury bill yields dived below 50 percent for the first time at auction on Wednesday and dealers said yields on the secondary market would fall to similar levels in Thursday trade.</p>
<p>Sergei Koshelenko of CS First Boston said prices would rise on Thursday as investors unable to buy at auction turned to the market.</p>
<p>&quot;There is enough money in the system to push prices of all issues up one to two points,&quot; he said, estimating that market yields would fall to an average 50 percent.</p>
<p>Average yields for all government bills, or GKOs, at close on Tuesday were 52.7 percent.</p>
<p>A flood of buyers scrambling for GKOs pushed the average yield on six-month bills to 49.63 percent at an auction of 10 trillion roubles of paper, which attracted bids of nearly 16 trillion roubles.</p>
<p>Central bank first deputy chairman Sergei Aleksashenko told Reuters that yields would fall further as non-residents continued to move into the market.</p>
<p>He said non-residents had made bids of several hundreds of millions of dollars at Wednesday.</p>
<p>For the first time since July the finance ministry, which repaid an earlier issue of bills at the same time as the auction, had cash left over after the transaction -- almost one trillion roubles.</p>
<p>&quot;The 50 percent yield was a big psychological barrier, but the finance ministry broke it with a wave of the hand, and no one doubted that it was worth buying at that level,&quot; said Oleg Surkov of MFK bank.</p>
<p>Russia's better than expected credit ratings, an uplift in the MinFin bond market, and the central bank's lowering of the guaranteed dollar yield on T-bills for non-residents to 16 percent from 19 percent from October 16 were catalysts for the market, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said prices on the T-bills could rise further, given Wednesday's announcement that the International Monetary Fund had released another $350 million tranche of a $10 billion loan.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank gave the signal that it would be tougher going (for investors seeking high yields) from now on. So everybody hurried to buy, even at 55. They didn't all succeed,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>-- Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
