<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105312" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan blue chips drive bourse higher.</title>
<headline>Moroccan blue chips drive bourse higher.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco's blue chip companies drove the Casablanca bourse higher on Wednesday, traders said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 429.76 points, up from 429.08 points on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The main stock to gain was that of Eqdom credit company which rose 31 dirhams to 1,070 dirhams from 1,039 dirhams on the previous session.</p>
<p>Eqdom announced on Monday it was to increase its capital to 166.6 million ($19.1 million) from 111.1 million dirhams. It said the capital would be increased via a stock split and rights issue.  </p>
<p>&quot;Despite stagnation of some of the largest market capitalisations like ONA Group, the bourse index continued its upward trend pushed up mainly by the banking sector,&quot; a stockbroker said.</p>
<p>ONA, Morocco's largest private group which holds stakes in more than 100 firms, remained stable at 460 dirhams.</p>
<p>Banque Commerciale du Maroc, the country's second largest bank, rose six dirhams to close at 676 dirhams.</p>
<p>In its audited balance published on Wednesday, BCM said turnover rose 5.8 percent to 1.289 billion dirhams ($148.1 million) in the first half of 1996 from a year earlier.</p>
<p>The bank also posted profit of 271.7 million dirhams in the first half of the year but gave no comparison with the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Brasseries du Maroc, a leading brewery, gained 20 dirhams to close at 1,400 dirhams.</p>
<p>The traded volume on the official market was 19.02 million dirhams, up from 13.9 million on the previous session, a bourse official said.</p>
<p>($1= 8.7 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom (212-7) 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
