<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105317" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli-Jordanian ties in crisis - ambassador.</title>
<headline>Israeli-Jordanian ties in crisis - ambassador.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan's ambassador to Israel Omar al-Rifai said on Wednesday relations between the countries were in crisis over the Jewish state's policies towards Palestinians.</p>
<p>Omar al-Rifai said in an interview with Israel's Arabic radio that Jordan had conveyed &quot;strong displeasure&quot; at Israel's failure to tell Amman it planned to open a controversial tunnel near Islamic holy sites in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>The opening of the tunnel sparked Israeli-Palestinian violence in which 59 Arabs and 15 Israelis died.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact of the matter is that the crisis is not only between Israel and Jordan, but also between Israel and all the Arab parties,&quot; Rifai said.</p>
<p>&quot;The reasons are what is happening in the occupied territories, from the return to the policy of building settlements, violation of the sanctity of holy places, the closure, depriving Palestinians from work and the refusal to implement what had been agreed upon...&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jordan's King Hussein, Israel's closest Arab friend since their 1994 peace treaty, said in an interview with the Arabic daily Asharq al-Awsat this week that a lack of progress in peace talks could lead to war.</p>
<p>Israeli-Arab relations began to deteriorate after right-wing Likud leader Benjamin Netanyahu was elected in May and rejected the return of occupied Arab land for peace. Relations deteriorated further with last month's violence.</p>
<p>Rifai said in opening the tunnel near Jerusalem's al-Aqsa mosque compound Israel ignored its treaty with Amman in which the Jewish state recognised Jordan's historic role in the holy city. He said Netanyahu's political advisor Dore Gold should have informed Jordan of Israeli plans.</p>
<p>&quot;Jordan has conveyed its strong displeasure at the failure to notify Jordan of the tunnel digging, especially since the Israeli envoy Dore Gold was in Amman one day before the tunnel was opened,&quot; Rifai said. &quot;He did not mention at all the Israeli government's decision to open the tunnel.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
