<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105658" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss stocks close slightly lower.</title>
<headline>Swiss stocks close slightly lower.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss shares ended a volatile session slightly lower on average volumes as midday gains were erased by a weaker Wall Street beginning.</p>
<p>&quot;All in all we had a good session since we could largely keep yesterday's high levels&quot;, a dealer said. &quot;If the Dow Jones closes stronger we are in for the next big jump&quot;.</p>
<p>Trade was concentrated in blue chips and particularly in Roche, UBS and Swiss Re which saw lively interest.</p>
<p>Blue-chip Swiss Market Index closed down 10.2 points, or 0.27 percent, at 3,807.9 and the all-share SPI fell 0.31 percent, or 7.56 points, to 2,435.29.</p>
<p>Union Bank of Switzerland (UBS), Roche and Swiss Re overcame several resistance levels during the course of the day and were likely to see more advances in the next few days, one dealer said.</p>
<p>UBS bearer shares and Swiss Re added around 0.4 percent each to end at 1,243 francs and 1,356 francs, respectively.</p>
<p>Roche certificates fell 15 francs to 9,580, down from an intraday high of 9,645.</p>
<p>CS Holding and Swiss Bank Corp both edged down around 0.8 percent. Ciba and Sandoz also lost ground.</p>
<p>Alusuisse fell 14 francs to 939 after U.S. aluminium firm Alcoa gave a profit warning. There were also rumours about an imminent broker downgrade of Alusuisse.</p>
<p>Elektrowatt, in which CS Holding has a stake of 45 percent, gave up 2.75 percent to end at 495 after Tuesday's big gains.</p>
<p>The shares soared on Tuesday on renewed speculation that CS Holding may announce a divestment of its stake.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
