<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105685" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Karachi bourse reverts to Islamic weekend.</title>
<headline>Karachi bourse reverts to Islamic weekend.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's main Karachi Stock Exchange (KSE) said on Wednesday it had decided to revert to the Friday-Saturday weekend, only a week after deciding to observe Sunday as weekly holiday instead of Friday.</p>
<p>The KSE said it had reversed last week's decision because of problems it faced on Friday while government offices and banks remained closed on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering problems due to closure of banks, financial insitutions and government offices on Friday, the KSE operations (on Friday) cannot be practical and meaningful,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>KSE had announced on October 2 that it would open on Friday and observe Saturday-Sunday as weekly holidays, following a decision by Pakistan's top busisness organisation to revert to Sunday as weekly holiday instead of Friday.</p>
<p>Businessmen and traders say holiday on Friday effectively cuts them off from markets in Europe and the U.S. where Saturday and Sunday are observed as weekly holidays.</p>
<p>But religious parties have strongly opposed the idea as Friday is considered to be a holy day for Moslems.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
