<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105763" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Yahoo! reports smaller-than expected loss.</title>
<headline>Yahoo! reports smaller-than expected loss.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA CLARA, Calif. 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Internet search firm Yahoo! Inc. Wednesday reported a smaller-than expected third quarter loss, reflecting sharply higher revenues.</p>
<p>The Santa Clara, Calif.-based company reported a loss of $1.2 million, or 4 cents a share, for the quarter ended in September compared with a loss of $371,000, or 2 cents a share, in the 1995 quarter.</p>
<p>Sales jumped to $5.2 million from $288,000.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected the company to lose around 7 cents a share in the quarter, according to First Call, which tracks earnings estimates.</p>
<p>Yahoo! had a loss of $1.4 million, or 5 cents a share, in the second quarter on sales of $3.3 million.</p>
<p>Yahoo!, started by two Stanford University students two years ago to help people navigate the World Wide Web, went public in March.</p>
<p>&quot;Our growth in both traffic and revenues is gratifying as we have and will continue to work hard to build a high level of interest and loyalty with Yahoo! users and advertisers alike,&quot; President Tim Koogle said.</p>
<p>Yahoo! said its advertiser base grew to 340 advertisers in the third quarter from 230 in the previous quarter.</p>
<p>Yahoo! also reported more than 1 billion &quot;hits&quot; in the quarter ended Sept. 30, giving the company an average of more than 14 million page views a day in September, up from an average of 9 million a day in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA CLARA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
