<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105772" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ford sets recall of nearly 680,000 vehicles.</title>
<headline>Ford sets recall of nearly 680,000 vehicles.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ford Motor Co said Wednesday it is recalling nearly 680,000 vehicles for various problems, including 419,180 1996-97 Taurus, Sable, Lincoln Continental and Windstar minivans for transmission inspections.  </p>
<p>Ford said the park mechanism may not prevent the vehicle from rolling even if the shift lever is placed in the park position INTERRUPTED  </p>
<p>Other recalls announced by Ford were: 5,950 1997 F-Super-Duty trucks with motorhome basic chassis, 89 of which are in Canada, because of battery cable insulation problems; 5,000 1996 Taurus SHO cars, 209 of which are in Canada, to replace fuel pressure regulators; and 1,300 1997 F-150 pickups, 73 of which are in Canada, for possible brake problems.</p>
<p>Ford spokeswoman Francine Romine-MacBride said the Probe repairs could take a full day. Other inspections and repairs are likely to take between one and two hours. Ford does not disclose the financial impacts of the recalls, she said.</p>
<p>There have been no reported accidents or injuries stemming from the transmission problems, Romine-MacBride said.  Of the 419,180 recalled, she said about 360,000 are Taurus and Sable cars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
