<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105783" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chip stocks rise after book-to-bill report.</title>
<headline>Chip stocks rise after book-to-bill report.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks of computer chip makers rallied Wednesday after the industry reported that a key gauge of demand for memory chips rose to the highest level of the year in September.</p>
<p>The Semiconductor Industry Association reported Tuesday that its book-to-bill ratio rose to 0.99 in September from 0.93 in August. The reading means chip manufacturers received $99 in new orders last month for every $100 in shipments.</p>
<p>The rise reflected a stronger-than-expected increase in new orders, which rose to $3.19 billion, up 9 percent from August. Shipments inched up to $3.22 billion, 2.1 percent above August's level.</p>
<p>The ratio, considered a key indicator of the industry's direction, has been improving, reflecting better demand from personal computer makers and more stable prices for memory chips.</p>
<p>&quot;People are buying PCs as if there's no tomorrow,&quot; analyst Dan Klesken at Robertson Stephens said after the report was issued. &quot;We're having a PC-led recovery in the chip industry.&quot;</p>
<p>The stocks of some chip makers jumped in after-hours trading on Tuesday, and some managed solid gains Wednesday despite weakness in other high-technology issues as well as the broader market.</p>
<p>Texas Instruments jumped $1.125 to $56.25 and National Semiconductor added 50 cents to $20.375, both on the New York Stock Exchange. Applied Materials, which makes fabrication equipment for chip producers, rose $1 to $29 on Nasdaq.</p>
<p>Prices of memory chips tumbled over the year to a fraction of what they were in January. But since mid-September, memory prices have risen 30 percent to 50 percent from their lows.</p>
<p>The September ratio marked the highest level since December of 1995, when the index hit 1.12. A year ago it stood at 1.16.</p>
<p>Micron Technology Inc., a key chip maker, said last week that its excessive inventories of memory chips had fallen to desirable levels.</p>
<p>Micron shares were up 25 cents at $32.375, also on the NYSE.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
