<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105717" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan Taleban shrug off rival talks, fighting.</title>
<headline>Afghan Taleban shrug off rival talks, fighting.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Wagstaff</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghanistan's new Taleban rulers shrugged off signs of growing military opposition on Wednesday, dismissing a clash involving their forces as a misunderstanding and saying a meeting of rival factions would yield nothing.</p>
<p>Acting deputy foreign minister Sher Mohammad Stanakzai told a news conference Tuesday's meeting between warlord General Abdul Rashid Dostum and ousted president Burhanuddin Rabbani in Mazar-i-Sharif would not produce agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;Rabbani is at the end of things. He is going to be finished very soon along with his forces so I don't think Dostum will get together with him at this stage,&quot; Stanakzai said.</p>
<p>Taleban sources in Pakistan had said on Tuesday that Stanakzai had been moved to the Ministry of Rehabilatation and Reconstruction as acting deputy minister but he was still at his foreign ministry post in Kabul on Wednesday. No immediate explanation was available.</p>
<p>Stanakzai, speaking before news of further clashes on Wednesday, also dismissed fighting on Tuesday south of the Salang Tunnel, entrance to Dostum's northern stronghold, in which forces of Rabbani's ousted military chief Ahmad Shah Masood attacked Taleban forces.</p>
<p>&quot;At the Salang tunnel yesterday there was a minor clash. I think what I heard was that there was a clash as a result of a misunderstanding between the frontline of their people and our people but what I heard was that the situation is calm,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Western aid workers said on Wednesday Masood had cut off a large Taleban force in the Salang pass and inflicted heavy casualties, stalling the Taleban's attempt to force a way into Masood's Panjsher Valley stronghold.</p>
<p>He said he did not know whether Taleban forces had clashed with those of Masood or Dostum. Taleban fighters in the area said on Tuesday they had clashed with those of Basir Solangi, Masood's commander in the pass around the Salang tunnel.</p>
<p>Military analysts said it appeared that the arrival of Rabbani in Mazar-i-Sharif, Dostum's headquarters of the northern provinces under his control, and signs of fighting around the Salang tunnel, could usher in another round of conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears we are entering a new phase of the war,&quot; one military analyst said.</p>
<p>Rabbani arrived in Mazar-i-Sharif on Tuesday, embracing Dostum, who split from Rabbani's government in 1994 after a dispute with Masood.</p>
<p>The two were due to hold talks on Wednesday, possibly including representatives of other non-Taleban factions.</p>
<p>The Taleban, an Islamic movement created on the country's southern border in 1994, swept into Kabul in late September.</p>
<p>The Taleban, apparently reluctant to fight on two fronts, have been keen to talk peace with Dostum while launching attacks on Masood's Panjsher valley stronghold to the east of the Salang tunnel.</p>
<p>After overrunning two hills at the entrance to the gorge the Taleban assault appeared to have stalled, as the two sides exchanged artillery, rocket and mortar fire but made little movement on the ground.</p>
<p>Stanakzai admitted the assault, which began on Saturday, had been delayed but said further gains had been made into the 150 km (100 mile) valley. Journalists were prevented from travelling to either the Salang or Panjsher areas on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Taleban's offer of talks to Dostum remained open despite Tuesday's meeting in Mazar-i-Sharif, Stanakzai said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment we have no problem with Dostum. We know already that he has announced his position that he was ready to meet with us and talk with us and solve with us all the problems through negotiations and we want the same thing and we hope that very soon there will be a solution between Dostum and the Taleban Islamic movement,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
