<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105963" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK grain export on fast track, but trade cautious.</title>
<headline>UK grain export on fast track, but trade cautious.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clelia Oziel</p>
<p>UK grain exports got off to a fast start this season but traders suspect the pace of sales may not keep up with a bumper harvest.</p>
<p>Recent trade estimates have put wheat (mainly feed) shipments at between 750,000-800,000 tonnes by the end of September -- virtually a month after the harvest began.</p>
<p>According to one analyst, wheat sales up to end-September could have even amounted to 900,000 tonnes, mostly to other European destinations.</p>
<p>This compares with 3.054 million tonnes exported in the whole of the 1995/96 season (July/June).</p>
<p>Traders said three big vessels of 25,000 tonnes each had been loaded with barley destined for Saudi Arabia and more was in the pipeline to cover part of a 1.4 million tonnes sale.</p>
<p>&quot;I think between October and November some 400,000 tonnes will have been shipped to Saudi Arabia,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Barley shipments reached only 1.32 million tonnes last season.</p>
<p>But the belief among traders that grain availability this year will outstrip demand somewhat takes the shine off the early export picture. &quot;The figures are fairly impressive but we're not getting over-excited,&quot; said one trader. &quot;At the end of the day, it's the end-year surplus that counts.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Union (EU) stepped up its export awards at weekly tenders, but traders say larger tonnages must be allowed to avoid a potential dip in prices.</p>
<p>The Home-Grown Cereals Authority (HGCA) has estimated the surplus wheat to be slated for export this this season at 4.5-5 million tonnes and barley at 2-2.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The HGCA's calculation was based on a projected wheat harvest of 15.75 million tonnes and barley of 7.8 million. It then set aside combined commercial stocks for wheat and barley of 2.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a pretty good start to exports,&quot; said Steve Thornhill, head of marketing and economics at the HGCA. &quot;But 4.5 million is massive. The pace of exports needs to keep going.&quot;</p>
<p>The most active destinations for UK wheat were Italy and Spain, which, despite a good harvest this year, continued to rely on imports while farmers sit on stocks in the hope that prices will recover.</p>
<p>Spain was a good buyer mainly because its lousy delivery system made it hard to compensate regional supply differences, traders said.</p>
<p>UK shippers also clinched deals this year with Poland, Germany, Tunisia and northern France.</p>
<p>But order books were beginning to dry up. One trader said orders &quot;were next to nothing&quot; from November onwards.</p>
<p>HGCA's Thornhill said UK exporters would need to maintain price competitiveness to prevent large surpluses.</p>
<p>As wheat prices decline towards intervention in other European countries, British prices would need to slide even further as there is no intervention on feed wheat in the UK.</p>
<p>&quot;This (exports) will largely depend on a continued flow of ex-farm sales onto the market, since although post-harvest marketings have been high, pre-harvest sales were well below those of the past seasons,&quot;the HGCA in its latest weekly report.</p>
<p>Supplies will be further inflated by large carryover stocks from last year. At end-June stocks of wheat are estimated at 750,000 tonnes while barley was up at 130,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>-- Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
