<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="105972" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - British Energy faces flak on cuts.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - British Energy faces flak on cuts.</headline>
<byline>Jo Winterbottom</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Privatised nuclear power generator British Energy Plc sparked criticism on Wednesday when it announced job cuts that failed to impress the stock market and angered unions.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this move transforms (British Energy's) prospects at all,&quot; said Philip Hollobone, utilities analyst at Williams de Broe.</p>
<p>British Energy said in a statement it aimed to cut 1,460 jobs in Scotland and Wales to make savings in staff costs of 50 million pounds ($78 million) within three years.</p>
<p>It said it would have a one-off restructuring charge of 100 million pounds which was already provided for.</p>
<p>Chief executive Robert Hawley said there could be more savings to come as cuts in office costs came through.</p>
<p>Union representatives slammed the move in a statement as &quot;a high risk strategy,&quot; warning that job cuts could &quot;reduce training, lower standards and threaten safety.&quot;</p>
<p>The Nuclear Installations Inspectorate (NII), part of Britain's Health and Safety Executive, said it would review the plans and take action if it felt safety would suffer.</p>
<p>&quot;If we think (the plans) are adverse (for safety), we will use regulatory powers to stop (British Energy) doing them,&quot; a spokesman for the NII said.</p>
<p>But Hawley maintained that &quot;safety is our bottom line, not profit.&quot;</p>
<p>British Energy's debut on the stock exchange in July was overshadowed by temporary closures of two of its eight reactors after cracks were discovered.</p>
<p>Shares kicked off below the partly-paid issue price of 105 pence to institutions and 100 pence to small investors and have rarely moved above those levels, mangaging just a half penny rise on the day on Wednesday to stand at 108 pence at 1130 GMT.</p>
<p>The ruling Conservative government pressed ahead with its privatisation despite the deep unpopularity of the deal and has been left with a stake of around 12 percent.</p>
<p>The opposition Labour Party also criticised the job cuts, which energy and industry spokesman John Battle said showed British Energy &quot;has not performed as they promised they would.&quot;</p>
<p>He called on the company to confirm its dividend policy which it has said is vulnerable to underperformance by nuclear power stations.</p>
<p>Although Hawley maintained the company's plans were aimed at making &quot;absolutely sure we are competitive in the market place,&quot; analysts expressed concern it faced stiff challenges and remained an unattractive investment.</p>
<p>&quot;They are under pressure,&quot; said Marshall Whiting of Societe Generale Strauss Turnbull (SGST).</p>
<p>Whiting said the crucial factor for British Energy was price of electricity in the so-called &quot;pool,&quot; or wholesale market.</p>
<p>&quot;Pressure on electricity prices is downward in the medium to long term. (British Energy) has to address operating costs to get profits to stand still,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hollobone said the cost cuts should make predictions for dividend growth more secure but added that these were still below market averages.</p>
<p>&quot;Dividend growth is one of the lowest in the sector and there is no sign of a special dividend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>British Energy said at its privatisation that the first interim dividend would be 4.6 pence a share and forecasts for final dividend are for 9.1 pence in 1996/97.</p>
<p>&quot;You can get better value elsewhere. Why invest in British Energy?&quot; Hollobone said. ($1=.6393 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
