<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="106106" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Defeated MP seeks cancellation of Lebanon poll.</title>
<headline>Defeated MP seeks cancellation of Lebanon poll.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>An opposition MP defeated in Lebanon's parliamentary elections last month appealed to the Constitutional Council to scrap the entire election on grounds that the law under which it was held was unconstitutional.</p>
<p>The Lebanese Association for the Democracy of the Elections (LADE), a private watchdog group that monitored the vote, echoed the deputy's remarks in a statement issued on Wednesday, saying the election law was inequitable.</p>
<p>Habib Sadeq, a prominent former leftist deputy from south Lebanon, repeated charges made by other defeated opposition candidates of vote-rigging and abuse by pro-government candidates in a vote in south Lebanon on September 8.</p>
<p>The conservative daily an-Nahar published extracts from Sadeq's 80-page appeal on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Unlike 13 other defeated candidates who have appealed to the constitutional council for cancellation of the results of their individual races, Sadeq said the election of all 128 parliamentary deputies should be scrapped because the vote was carried out under a flawed election law.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if they cancel the result of one of the winners in south Lebanon and declare me a winner, I will resign the next day because my position is an appeal against the whole election process in Lebanon,&quot; Sadeq told Reuters.</p>
<p>The 10-man constitutional council struck down the first version of the government's election law in August after appeals by 10 MPs of the outgoing parliament, including Sadeq, that it discriminated among Lebanese by setting up different-sized electoral areas.</p>
<p>The law diluted the strength of the Christian vote by dividing up the governorate of Mount Lebanon -- the Christian heartland -- into five districts while the rest of the country voted by governorates.</p>
<p>LADE's statment said the law was unconstitutional as &quot;it does not treat Lebanese equally through the administrative divisions it formed, by not putting a ceiling on spending on election campaigns whereby candidates have equal chances and by breaching the unity of legislation in the country.&quot;</p>
<p>After the law was struck down in July, the government rushed a slightly altered version through parliament that kept the controversial electoral divisions but defined them as a once-off exception, which is apparently permissible under the constitution.</p>
<p>Sadeq repeated charges in other appeals by defeated candidates that pro-government candidates and their supporters benefited from illegal voting in south Lebanon in the names of thousands of dead people, emigrants and resident Lebanese whose identity cards were fraudulently copied and used by others.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
