<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="106201" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electric futures settle up, erase early loss.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electric futures settle up, erase early loss.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures settled higher Tuesday in a late jump, erasing early losses tied to light profit-taking, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was just bouncing around,&quot; said a Houston trader, referring to the day's trading pattern.</p>
<p>He added physical prices in the western U.S. stayed firm today on still strong air-conditioning demand in the Southwest. &quot;They've been very supportive.&quot;</p>
<p>November California-Oregon Border (COB) futures finished at $17.97 a megawatt hour (MWh), up two cents after hitting a session low of $17.65.</p>
<p>December COB also settled up two cents at $19.10. Other COB months ended up 10 cents higher than Monday's settlment.</p>
<p>November Palo Verde (PV) finished at $17.39 a MWh, up 14 cents after moving in a 25 cent range.</p>
<p>December PV settled up nine cents at $17.89. Deferred PV contracts ended unchanged to 40 cents higher.</p>
<p>Participants expected the electricity complex would test Tuesday's highs again Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If there's anywhere to go, it'll go higher,&quot; the Houston trader said.</p>
<p>NYMEX estimated 302 COB and 142 PV contracts were sold Tuesday.</p>
<p>The latest forecasts indicated the West would experience warmer to much-warmer than normal autumn weather next week.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
