<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="106262" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Buchanan says Dole can catch up to President Clinton.</title>
<headline>Buchanan says Dole can catch up to President Clinton.</headline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Conservative commentator and former presidential candidate Pat Buchanan returned to the site of one of his most dramatic victories Tuesday to drum up support for Republican nominee Bob Dole.</p>
<p>At an evening rally, Buchanan admitted to differences with the more moderate Dole. &quot;I think that clearly a Republican president with a Republican Congress would be better for America than what we have in the White House right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dole could beat Clinton if he won over dissatisfied voters now giving lukewarm support to the incumbent, Buchanan said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe Dole is as far behind as CNN says,&quot; he said. &quot;It's definitely an uphill battle, but I don't think the race is over yet. This is a volatile election. It's a volatile country.&quot;</p>
<p>Buchanan said he was happy with the strict conservative Republican platform adopted for the party's presidential campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;The platform, in a lot of its aspects, adopted the ideas that we had advocated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The commentator declined to rule out another run for the presidency. &quot;You can't talk about four years from now until we know about four weeks from now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Buchanan's Alaska trip was scheduled in large part to boost the state Senate bid of Jerry Ward, a former member of the secessionist Alaskan Independence Party who is now running for the legislative seat as a Republican. Ward had headed Buchanan's Alaska campaign.</p>
<p>Last January, Buchanan won the state's non-binding straw poll while Steve Forbes finished a close second and Dole had been a distant third.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
