<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="106225" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US DOE to meet with industry on home heating oil.</title>
<headline>US DOE to meet with industry on home heating oil.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Energy Secretary Hazel O'Leary said Wednesday she planned to meet October 18 with members of the National Petroleum Council to discuss tight supplies and prices of home heating oil.</p>
<p>&quot;We have spoken to the head of our National Petroleum Council and asked him to put together an appropriate group,&quot; O'Leary told reporters after addressing an aluminum industry gathering.</p>
<p>She said she likely would respond in the meantime to proposals of several New England congressmen, who have pressed her for a plan to deal with short home heating oil stocks.  </p>
<p>O'Leary said her response to the lawmakers would be on an &quot;interim&quot; basis before the industry meeting, but she was committed to get back with them within 10 days of her meeting with them last week.</p>
<p>She said she likely would respond either by letter or a conference call.</p>
<p>Asked whether the department was seriously considering a proposal from Rep. Joe Kennedy, D-Massachusetts, to sell oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve to build heating oil reserves, O'Leary said, &quot;We'll give it the attention that it certainly deserves.&quot;</p>
<p>Energy Department officials have said they did not want to tamper with the market, and industry officials have said Kennedy's plan would be counter-productive.</p>
<p>O'Leary also reserved comment on the likelihood of finding more imported supplies of home heating oil after Luis Giusti, heard of  Petroleo de Venezuela SA, said last week he doubted Venezuela could come up with much heating oil to help U.S. consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's see where we are by the 18th,&quot; she said of prospects of obtaining more heating oil imports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
