<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="106550" id="root" date="1996-10-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British Business press - Oct 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British Business press - Oct 9.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- RENTOKIL COUNTERS CLARK'S CLAIM</p>
<p>Rentokil Initial have hit back at High Court claims of the former BET chairman John Clark, that his dismissal had rendered him unemployable. Andrew Hogarth QC, for Rentokil, said that had Mr Clark looked for employment, he would have found it. Hogarth added that every chief executive displaced by takeovers of large companies since 1990 had found employment within 3 months and that Mr Clark should seek work as a company chairman if he could not find work as a chief executive.</p>
<p>-- EUROTUNNEL SHARES FALL AS DEBT DEAL DISAPPOINTS</p>
<p>Eurotunnel shares have fallen as dealings resumed a day after the company revealed its refinancing proposals. The deal disappointed shareholders in France, where a 66 percent vote is required to approve it. The Association pour l'Action Eurotunnel, which speaks for 32 percent of the shares, said the conversion price was well below past rights issues which had been difficult for shareholders.</p>
<p>-- PEPSI KEEPS ROSY VIEW OF BLUE DESPITE SALES SLIDE</p>
<p>Pepsi have defended its 500 million stg &quot;blue&quot; relaunch, despite figures which show sales in Britain fell substantially over the summer. A spokesperson for Pepsi insisted the company's poorer performance was due to the fact that Coca-Cola spent three times more on marketing. He added that Pepsi's share of the cola market has grown since the relaunch and at a faster rate than Coke.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- BRITISH COMPANIES POUR MILLIONS INTO ELECTING DOLE</p>
<p>Major UK companies are spending millions of dollars to help Bob Dole reach the White House and the Republican Party to preserve its majority in Congress. Spending has totalled 3.35 million dollars during the current election round. UK companies are now spending more on supporting American political parties than they are on UK political donations. The companies which ended donations to the Conservative Party, such as Glaxo Wellcome, are the biggest donators.</p>
<p>-- CLARKE BLOCKS 613 MILLION STG PAYOUT BY REUTERS</p>
<p>The news agency and financial information group Reuters has been forced to suspend plans to give 613 million stg to its shareholders after the Treasury closed a legal loophole. Chancellor Kenneth Clarke announced that a provision would be included in the next Finance Bill, which will prevent the growing loss of tax through schemes involving companies buying their own shares or paying special dividends. The move will block planned cash payouts. Reuters will now ask shareholders to adjourn consideration of the special share issue.</p>
<p>-- GALLAHER SET FOR LONDON MARKET LISTING</p>
<p>Gallaher, Britain's leading tobacco company with brands such as Benson and Hedges, Silk Cut, Hamlet and Old Holborn, is to be quoted on the London stock market after American Brands, the US consumer conglomerate, announced it is spinning off its UK tobacco subsidiary. The quote will give the London market its second leading tobacco company following the flotation of Imperial Tobacco.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- FOUR THOUSAND NEW JOBS FOR SCOTLAND</p>
<p>Hyundai Electronics Europe is planning to build two semiconductor plants on a 150-acre site at Dunfermline, Scotland. The project is one of Europe's most lucrative overseas imports and will create up to 4,000 jobs for an area devastated by defence cuts and the decline of traditional industries. Shadow Chancellor Gordon Brown and MP for Dunfermline East interpreted Hyundai's selection of the UK as a production base for its new generation of Dynamic Random Access Memory semiconductors, as a plug for New Labour.</p>
<p>-- WATCHDOG MAY ACT ON NUCLEAR SAFETY</p>
<p>The Nuclear Industry Inspectorate, the nuclear safety watchdog, has warned that it could be forced to take action if plans by British Energy to axe more than 1,300 jobs compromise safety in the newly privatised industry. BE have confirmed it would be making a statement on job cuts today, and is expected to announce a 25 percent cut. Unions attacked the job cuts as a &quot;sop&quot; to shareholders and a clear bid to sustain the company's prospectus pledges on dividends.</p>
<p>-- RAIL BIDDERS MUST TILT TO DEMANDS FOR HIGH SPEED</p>
<p>Bidders for the rail route between London and Glasgow must agree to using new tilting trains in order to win the franchise. Roger Salmon, rail franchise director, and Bob Horton, Railtrack's chairman, hope to see the introduction of tilting trains as a way of significantly reducing journey times. Railtrack is committed to spending 1.3 billion stg on the route over the next ten years.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- STAGECOACH IN UNDERTAKING ON PREDATORY POLICY</p>
<p>The Government has accepted undertakings from bus operator Stagecoach which will curb its ability to mount predatory pricing policies against rivals in the North-east of England. John Taylor, the corporate and consumer affairs minister, announced the agreement, which comes after a year of negotiations with the DTI, in the wake of the collapse of the Darlington Bus Company. This prompted a Mergers and Monopolies Commission inquiry. The MMC demanded undertakings from both Stagecoach and Go-Ahead Group. The agreement commits Stagecoach not to raise prices or reduce bus services for three years on any route where its price controls have forced a rival to abandon a service.</p>
<p>-- UNITED WAGES SOAR AFTER BOSMAN</p>
<p>Manchester United have announced a surge in players' wage inflation, increasing its wage bill by five million stg a year. This follows the Bosman ruling and the Alan Shearer transfer from Blackpool to Newcastle. The club's chief executive Martin Edwards said the Bosman ruling, allowing the free transfer of players within the EU, had pushed the club to sign new longer-term deals with all of its new foreign imports. However, he added that the wage spiral &quot;could not continue&quot;.</p>
<p>-- DAWN RAID PUTS BLENHEIM AHEAD</p>
<p>The Dutch publishing giant VNU has mounted a dawn raid to scoop up 15 per cent of the exhibitions group Blenheim at 500 pence stg a share. In a statement to the Stock Exchange Blenheim said it would continue to talk to all parties and that an announcement would be made at the earliest opportunity. This has fuelled speculation that bid talks continued with the two original suitors for Blenheim, Reed Elsevier and United News and Media. VNU say they view the investment as a strategic one.</p>
<p>BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
