<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107092" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-ALLENBY SET TO DEFY INJURY TO COLLECT CASH BONUS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-ALLENBY SET TO DEFY INJURY TO COLLECT CASH BONUS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian golfer Robert Allenby is ready to defy a fractured breastbone and play just one shot in a forthcoming tournament so he can collect a bonus of 73,000 pounds sterling ($114,200.</p>
<p>Allenby is third in the European Tour money-winning list and has been told that to collect the bonus he must tee off in the season-ending Volvo Masters in Valderrama, Spain, starting on October 24.</p>
<p>He fractured his sternum in a car crash in Spain 12 days ago and originally planned to make his comeback in the Australian Open from November 21-24.</p>
<p>However, Allenby's manager Andrew Ramsey said on Thursday: &quot;I've now re-entered him (for the Volvo), even though I doubt whether he will be able to hit more than one shot.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's good for golf if someone prevents someone else from playing, then pulls out after one shot. But it's worth a lot of money and Robert says he must think of himself.</p>
<p>&quot;I spoke to (Tour executive director) Ken Schofield about it and was hoping that, in the extraordinary circumstances, Robert would be allowed to miss the event and still be eligible for the bonus. But the rules are in black and white, and Ken said his hands were tied.&quot;</p>
<p>Bonus money goes to the top 15 players in the Tour's final money-winning list providing they play at Valderrama. If Allenby drops to fourth he would collect 53,000 pounds ($82,880).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
