<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107105" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-FOUR SENT OFF AS CRUZEIRO LOSE LEAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FOUR SENT OFF AS CRUZEIRO LOSE LEAD.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-10-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four players were sent off as Cruzeiro were knocked off the top of the Brazilian championship on Wednesday after losing 2-0 to lowly Parana in a bad-tempered encounter.</p>
<p>Both teams were reduced to ten men by halftime as Parana defender Edinho and Cruzeiro midfielder Ailton were given their marching orders for violent fouls.</p>
<p>Cruzeiro midfielder Fabinho and Parana's Carlos Alberto Dias were shown the red card in the second half for the same offence.</p>
<p>Dias had put Parana in front in the 50th minute before he was sent off and the game was settled three minutes from the end when Alissio scored again.</p>
<p>Guarani, second at the start of the day, also lost, 1-0 away to Atletico Mineiro, allowing Palmeiras to return to the top of the table with a 2-1 win over bottom club Bragantino.</p>
<p>Striker Viola scored his first goal since joining Palmeiras from Spanish club Valencia as the unbeaten championship favourites came from behind.</p>
<p>For the second time in four days, Flamengo suffered the humiliation of seeing one of their former players score a hat-trick against them.</p>
<p>Paulo Nunes, who began his career with Flamengo, scored all the goals for Gremio as they beat the beleagured five-times Brazilian champions 3-1 to go back into the top eight.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Flamengo were beaten 4-1 by arch-rivals Vasco da Gama with Edmundo, who played for them last year, scoring three times. Flamengo also lost 4-1 to Sao Paulo last week and have now slumped to eleventh place.</p>
<p>The top eight of the 24 teams go into the quarter-final stage.</p>
<p>Santos, runners-up last year, were jeered off the field after losing 2-1 at home to Sport Recife.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
