<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107144" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: OLYMPICS-NAGANO UNDER PRESSURE AFTER CALAMITIES OF ATLANTA.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-NAGANO UNDER PRESSURE AFTER CALAMITIES OF ATLANTA.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>LAUSANNE, Switzerland 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Organisers of the next Olympics in Japan acknowledged on Thursday that they were under extra pressure to run a trouble-free event after the calamitous organisation of the Atlanta Games.</p>
<p>Officials from Nagano, which hosts the 1998 Winter Games, were warned by the International Olympic Committee (IOC) at a meeting to avoid the accreditation, transport and computer problems which caused problems for athletes, officials and the media in Atlanta.</p>
<p>Asked if there was more pressure after the Summer Games problems, Nagano director Makoto Kobayashi said: &quot;Yes, especially regarding transport and information.&quot;</p>
<p>In Atlanta competitors, officials and the journalists were often obliged to wait for hours at the airport to get their accreditation cards and were frustrated by the inefficient bus system taking them to venues.</p>
<p>The results computer also failed to work at the start of the Games and drew furious worldwide media criticism.</p>
<p>Nagano chiefs have already held talks with the multi-national computer firm IBM about the technological problems and are working to make sure athletes are not forced to wait for hours to get accredited after long flights to Japan.</p>
<p>Atlanta was also heavily criticised for commercial excesses. Some said the large number of city-backed private vendors allowed to clog the streets had made the Games look like a huge flea market.</p>
<p>This subject was not discussed when Japanese officials met the IOC executive board on Wednesday, but Kobayashi said: &quot;There is no way the city will set up such commercial ventures.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAUSANNE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
