<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107255" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Reuter Mfg sees Q3 gains continuing into Q4.</title>
<headline>Reuter Mfg sees Q3 gains continuing into Q4.</headline>
<dateline>HOPKINS, Minn. 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reuter Manufacturing Inc said Thursday it expects strong activity in the third quarter to continue into the fourth quarter which should include some modest volume increases from new medical device customers.</p>
<p>Reuter Manufacturing makes and assembles medical products and other precision manufactured parts on a contract basis.</p>
<p>Earlier today, the company reported income from continuing operations of $527,887 or $0.15 a share ($0.08 per share on a fully diluted basis) on revenues of about $4 million for the third quarter of 1996. This compares with a loss from continuing operations of $22O,485 or $0.07 a share on revenues of $2.7 million during the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased that the improvement in the second quarter carried over and expanded in the third quarter, and that our efforts toward a reconstituted product line are producing the results we expected,&quot; said James Taylor, president and chief executive officer, in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased that the improvement in the second quarter carried over and expanded in the third quarter, and that our efforts toward a reconstituted product line are producing the results we expected.&quot;</p>
<p>	     Chicago newsdesk 312 408 8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I92110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOPKINS, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
