<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107211" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X negotiates to resolve Busang dispute.</title>
<headline>Bre-X negotiates to resolve Busang dispute.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lawyers for Bre-X Resources Ltd are negotiating &quot;around the clock&quot; to resolve a dispute with one of the company's Indonesian partners, a Bre-X spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The best way to put it is we're sitting down with them to see if they have anything solid,&quot; said Steve McAnulty in a phone interview from Calgary.</p>
<p>The Indonesian partner has a 10 percent stake in Busang I, one section of Bre-X's spectacular gold discovery in Indonesia. The partner recently told Bre-X it believes it is entitled to a similar stake in Busang II and Busang III.  </p>
<p>While Bre-X said the claims have no merit, the company wants to discuss details with its partner to make sure, McAnulty said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're working diligently around the clock to come to a solution,&quot; McAnulty said. &quot;We're confident we'll come to a resolution on this thing in fairly short order.&quot;</p>
<p>The company's shares had fallen C$0.95 to C$24.10 in trading of 2.8 million shares by late afternoon after Indonesia's Mines and Energy Ministry told Reuters it would delay issuing a contract of work until the dispute was settled.  </p>
<p>Bre-X has applied for a contract of work for the Busang II and Busang III areas covering a huge gold deposit in Kalimantan.</p>
<p>Without the government contract, Bre-X will have trouble advancing its search for a partner to develop the property, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I imagine a lot of potential major partners want to make sure that underlying ownership issues are all resolved,&quot; said Chris Bradbrook at Loewen, Ondaatje, McCutcheon.</p>
<p>But Bre-X said the search for a partner will not be hurt by the contract delay.  </p>
<p>&quot;We don't consider this a significant thing in our lives,&quot; McAnulty said.</p>
<p>The dispute has prompted a re-evaluation of exploration in Indonesia, analyst Jim Taylor at Yorkton Securities said in an interview from London.</p>
<p>&quot;People are concerned there may be other skeletons in the closet in relation to other mineral exploration projects,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bre-X has said the resource calculation at Busang I stood at about three million ounces of gold. The resource in all three parts of Busang total about 47 million ounces so far.</p>
<p>New resource totals are expected out soon, McAnulty said.</p>
<p>-- Heather Scoffield, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8104</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
