<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107216" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian growth seen at 1.5 pct in 1996 - group.</title>
<headline>Canadian growth seen at 1.5 pct in 1996 - group.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's economy will grow by just 1.5 percent in 1996 but growth should pick up to 2.6 percent in 1997 as businesses rebuild inventories, a private research foundation said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In the autumn 1996 issue of its Canadian outlook, the Conference Board of Canada revised its growth forecast for 1996 down from 1.7 percent while keeping its 1997 forecast unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1.2 percent difference between growth in 1996 and 1997 is almost entirely due to the inventory swing,&quot; Jim Frank, the board's chief economist, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The research foundation said it revised its 1996 forecast mainly because of a sharp slowing in export growth and an inventory correction in the second quarter.</p>
<p>The Conference Board also forecast that Canadian interest rates would rise by 120 basis points in the next six months as the U.S. Federal Reserve begin to hike interest rates there.</p>
<p>Inflation due to an overheated U.S. economy, which would provoke a sharp runup in interest rates, and prolonged auto workers strike in either the United States or Canada were cited by the Conference Board as the two greatest risks to its growth forecasts.  </p>
<p>&quot;We also can't rule out the possibility of a mild recession in the U.S. next year, and this would substantially lower our export prospects in mid-1997,&quot; said Frank.</p>
<p>The Conference Board said the possibility of an industry-wide auto strike later this year cannot be ruled out.</p>
<p>&quot;A prolonged auto strike would substantially lower output and employment growth -- with Ontario being especially hard hit,&quot; said Frank.</p>
<p>Real consumer spending is forecast to grow by 1.9 percent this year and 2.2 percent in 1997, the Conference Board said.</p>
<p>The Conference board also noted in the report that the Canadian government has benefitted enormously from recent interest rate relief.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
