<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107598" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bildt calls for troops to stay in Bosnia till 1998.</title>
<headline>Bildt calls for troops to stay in Bosnia till 1998.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>International mediator Carl Bildt called on Thursday for foreign peacekeeping troops to stay in Bosnia until 1998 to give the country a chance of recovering from war.</p>
<p>Bildt also called on the European Union to work out a strong regional strategy to secure peace and stability in south-east Europe and thereby help avert future ethnic conflicts.</p>
<p>There are currently around 53,000 peacekeepers in Bosnia under a NATO-led command but their mandate expires on December 20 and no firm decision has been taken to keep troops in Bosnia after that date.</p>
<p>The first U.S. troops pulled out on Wednesday at the start of a large-scale withdrawal of American troops in line with U.S. President Bill Clinton's promise to pull them out by the end of IFOR peace implementation force's mandate.</p>
<p>NATO is pushing for a follow-on force of indeterminate size, with U.S. participation, to remain in Bosnia after December. Bildt called for enough troops to remain in 1997 and 1998 to deter medium-size conflicts.</p>
<p>&quot;This military presence would primarily be deterrent, to provide reassurance that there are no military options and no military threat, thus providing the conditions necessary for political reconciliation, re-integration and reconstruction,&quot; he said in a speech in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Without an outside deterrent force in the country such efforts could easily become destabilising whereas they could be a long-term investment in military restructuring and stability if such a force is in place,&quot; Bildt said.</p>
<p>In September, Bosnians elected a three-man presidency as well as national and regional assemblies. But these split down ethnic lines, hampering efforts to ensure the country's Serb, Moslem and Croat populations started reintegrating.</p>
<p>Bildt said he wanted a rapid reaction force concentrated in a few key place rather than the structure of the current NATO-led peace force, which is spread across the country.</p>
<p>&quot;The force itself would have to be on the ground. It might be obliged to do something very quickly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not talking about deterring a mass war, but there are people contemplating military action of battalion size. To deter such actions you have to be on the spot.&quot;</p>
<p>Bildt said he was reasonably pleased with efforts to rebuild Bosnia, despite the huge problems involved, but said the EU had to find a way of helping south-east Europe economically and politically if future ethnic wars were to be avoided.</p>
<p>&quot;It is only by making a massive turn towards integration and cooperation in Bosnia, in the area of former Yugoslavia and in the entire region south of Slovenia and north of Greece, that we can have any hope of avoiding being dragged into new conflicts in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The EU had to devise a regional strategy focused on creating a common economic space with good links to the rest of the world and which included a commitment to safeguard human rights.</p>
<p>But Bildt stressed there was very little time for the three new presidents of Bosnia to stop squabbling and to start building joint institutions to bind the country together.</p>
<p>&quot;Gradually I believe it will be possible to set up these common institutions, and gradually I believe it will be possible for them to start work.</p>
<p>&quot;But without the active involvement of the international community, they will almost certainly not be set up, and they are more than likely to go to pieces after having been set up.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
