<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107526" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British Conservatives rush to end divisions.</title>
<headline>British Conservatives rush to end divisions.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>BOURNEMOUTH, England 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Warring factions in Britain's ruling Conservative Party agreed a truce over Europe on Thursday as party leaders warned delegates the next general election would be lost unless peace was declared.</p>
<p>The willingness of right-wingers to end the internecine conflict over Europe was signalled by the standing ovation given to finance minister Kenneth Clarke at the party's last pre-election conference in the coastal resort of Bournemouth.</p>
<p>Clarke's staunch pro-Europeanism and refusal to promise a tax-slashing budget next month have made him the target of attacks by the party's Eurosceptic, minimal-tax wing.</p>
<p>But his appeal to delegates to &quot;spend the next six months uniting&quot; behind Prime Minister John Major's wait-and-see stance towards a single European currency and to concentrate their fire on the opposition Labour Party won him loud cheers.</p>
<p>To back up Clarke's message, echoed by numerous cabinet ministers over the past three day, Deputy Prime Minister Michael Heseltine attacked party members who generated press stories about disunity and damaged the party's re-election hopes.</p>
<p>&quot;By all means let us debate issues -- every party feeds on such debate,&quot; Heseltine said.</p>
<p>&quot;But what we should not tolerate is members of our party feeding the voracious appetite of a media anxious to headline any phrase, any whisper that harms our cause and serves our opponents...they deserve our utter contempt.&quot;</p>
<p>The clearest sign that right-wingers were burying the hatchet came from Defence Minister Michael Portillo, the cabinet's leading right-winger, who told delegates: &quot;In order to win, we need three extra policies --unity, unity and unity.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Above all we must present a united front to the electorate and stop this argument about Europe,&quot; said Lord Cecil Parkinson, a former cabinet minister and right-hand man of ex-premier Margaret Thatcher. Thatcher remains the standard-bearer of the Eurosceptics.</p>
<p>Labour is some 20 points ahead of the Conservatives in the opinion polls with an election at most seven months away.</p>
<p>But Clarke insisted the party could close the gap on the back of a booming economy and increasing personal prosperity.</p>
<p>He said a fifth consecutive electoral triumph would put Britain on course to create the most successful economy in Europe with a standard income tax rate of just 20 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If we fight on the economy, we will win... The big reason why we will win is because, out there in the country, there is now a growing feeling of economic well-being,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Clarke warned that voters would not be persuaded to return to the Conservatives by unjustified tax cuts in his budget.</p>
<p>&quot;To earn and keep the trust of the British people, we have to follow one Tory golden rule. We only cut taxes when we can afford to, and when it is good for the economy...</p>
<p>&quot;We must create the climate for continued Conservative success, over the next five years. And my budget in November must create the climate for an honest election campagn in which we play fair and straight with the public,&quot; Clarke said.</p>
<p>Labour has made huge political capital out of Major's failure to honour tax-cutting pledges he made at the 1992 election. His government had to raise taxes by the largest amount in peacetime to plug a budget hole caused by recession.</p>
<p>On the single European currency, Clarke strongly backed Major's line under which the Conservatives would decide after the election whether it was in Britain's interests to jettison the pound sterling in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;It is in Britain's interest to keep all our options open. We should decide when we have to, not before,&quot; Clarke said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOURNEMOUTH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
