<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107520" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil drops as speculators slice peak off rally.</title>
<headline>Oil drops as speculators slice peak off rally.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices dropped sharply on Thursday as speculators rushed to sell heating oil futures, severely denting the rally to five-year highs earlier in the week.</p>
<p>&quot;We're shaking out some of the top soil on this rally,&quot; said Peter Gignoux, head of the energy desk at brokers Smith Barney in London.</p>
<p>Brent crude oil futures on London's International Petroleum Exchange (IPE) closed 69 cents down at $23.58 a barrel.</p>
<p>Oil futures traded in London and New York turned tail as dealers pocketed profits but traders said the longer-term supply and demand fundamentals were still strong.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still too early from a fundamental point of view to say that this is the end of the (bull) market,&quot; said Alastair Harris of Mees Pierson in London. &quot;But we've had a severe reaction today.&quot;</p>
<p>Harris added that he thought some managed funds, which play across the financial markets, were taking their money out of oil having ridden the crest of a rally based on low stocks in Western markets.</p>
<p>The slide began with selling on IPE gas oil futures early in the London day which in turn sparked the steep tumble of the sister contract, heating oil futures on the New York Mercantile Exchange.</p>
<p>IPE gas oil futures for November were down a massive $13.75 a tonne at $224.50 at close of trade, a loss of nearly six percent in value over the day and a drop of around $25 from the heady peak of the rally.</p>
<p>But stocks of gas oil -- used mostly for heating -- remained historically low in Europe, echoing the same scenario in the United States, the world's biggest consumer of heating oil.</p>
<p>Stocks in the European Union, excluding Sweden, are running 33.47 million barrels lower than the same time last year, data released on Wednesday showed.</p>
<p>&quot;Distillates stocks (in Europe) are 20 million barrels short of comfort and crude 10 million barrels short. In the U.S. they are also 20 million barrels short of distillate,&quot; said Geoff Pyne, oil analyst at UBS.</p>
<p>The stocks cushion could be severely tested if a harsh winter hits the northern hemisphere, traders said.</p>
<p>After a short-lived jump in Brent futures, oil markets shrugged off reports from a Middle East Gulf source that the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries had no plans to raise its crude output quota from the current 25.033 million barrels per day ceiling at the group's next meeting in November.</p>
<p>&quot;The most likely option is an extension of the current ceiling,&quot; the Gulf source said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel,</p>
<p>						    Oct 10	  Oct 9</p>
<p>						   (close)	 (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $23.60	 $24.37</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Nov)	$23.58	 $24.27</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Nov)     $24.23	 $25.07</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
