<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107654" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITANIA: Mauritania -- bridge between Arab and black Africa.</title>
<headline>Mauritania -- bridge between Arab and black Africa.</headline>
<dateline>NOUAKCHOTT 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mauritania, which holds its second multi-party parliamentary election on Friday, is an impoverished mainly Moslem nation straddling Arab and black Africa at the Altantic fringe of the Sahara Desert.</p>
<p>Occasionally pilloried as one of the world's lingering bastions of slavery, a charge the government vigorously denies, it is a member of both the Arab League and the Organisation of African Unity.</p>
<p>Tension between black Mauritanians, resentful at what they call the Arabisation of the West African nation, and the dominant Moorish community have coloured politics since independence from France in 1960.</p>
<p>Tension with Morocco in the 1970s and early 1980s over the disputed former Spanish colony in the Western Sahara caused further strains, as did friction with neighbour Senegal from 1989 to 1991 over the demands of the black minority.</p>
<p>Senegal and Mauritania expelled each other's nationals after both experiencing riots which killed hundreds.</p>
<p>President Maaouya Ould Sid'Ahmed Taya, a French-trained army colonel, seized power in a bloodless coup in 1984. He launched a democratic transition in 1991 and won a six-year presidential term in a disputed 1992 election.</p>
<p>His supporters in the Democratic and Social Republican Party went on to win 67 of the national assembly's 79 seats in 1992, in an election boycotted by the main opposition.</p>
<p>Friday's poll is the first major test of the fledgling democracy in the nation of 2.2 million people since then.</p>
<p>Mauritanians irritated Western and Gulf Arab partners during the 1991 Gulf War that ended Iraq's occupation of Kuwait, by expressing sympathy with President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>Many prominent Mauritanians have links with the pan-Arab Baath political movement, which includes Iraq's ruling party. The government has since distanced itself from Iraq and mended fences with its erstwhile allies in the Gulf.</p>
<p>The economy is based on exports of fish products and minerals, notably iron ore. The goverment has hopes of gold production, like many other nations bordering the Sahara.</p>
<p>Mauritania strongly denies the existence of slavery, which it officially outlawed in 1980.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOUAKCHOTT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
