<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107645" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Province aims to bring abortion pill to Canada.</title>
<headline>Province aims to bring abortion pill to Canada.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER, British Columbia 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The province of British Columbia said on Thursday it wants to sponsor Canada's first clinical trial of the controversial RU 486 abortion pill to help get the drug approved.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the obvious benefits of this (drug) in terms of improving access and expanding the reproductive choices available to women, we are extremely disappointed with the lack of initiative from our own federal government on this issue,&quot; British Columbia Health Minister Joy MacPhail said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that medical abortions using RU 486 would not only be considerably more private and less intrusive for Canadian women, they would also be more cost-effective than the surgical alternative,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Canada's federal government must first give approval to an application from the manufacturer before trials can proceed. Anti-abortion groups immediately criticised the province's move and said they would seek to block trials.</p>
<p>RU 486, made by Roussel Uclaf Co. of France, can be taken to terminate an unwanted preganancy in the first nine weeks, the province said. It causes an abortion by inducing contractions.</p>
<p>The drug, also known as mifepristone, is already available in Britain, France and other countries.</p>
<p>The U.S. Food and Drug Administration last month deemed the drug safe and effective but has not yet given final approval for U.S. doctors to begin prescribing it.</p>
<p>Opponents of the drug claim it makes abortion available on demand. But abortion-rights groups have campaigned in favour of the pill as a way of ensuring the availability of abortions, especially in rural areas.</p>
<p>Because it can be administered in a doctor's office, the pill would make abortions more accessible and allow women seeking abortions to avoid the protestors that surround many abortion clinics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER, British Columbia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
