<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107691" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mandela cool on Christopher's African army plan.</title>
<headline>Mandela cool on Christopher's African army plan.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela responded cautiously to U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher's proposal for a Western-sponsored African intervention force, which they are due to discuss on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;Africa would like to feel that they are handling things themselves...not acting in response to suggestions that come from outside the continent,&quot; Mandela told Reuters on Thursday.</p>
<p>He confirmed that he would meet Christopher in Cape Town on Saturday, but said he would take any peacekeeping proposals to the Southern African Development Community (SADC), of which he is chairman.</p>
<p>&quot;It is only by working together through established organisations that we can solve problems. We will not hold back if we are asked by any of these organisations and we have the capacity to do so,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. officials said in Addis Ababa on Wednesday that nine African countries had so far endorsed the U.S. initiative to convene an African Crisis Response Force of up to 10,000 troops.</p>
<p>Briefing reporters ahead of the Ethiopian leg of Christopher's five-nation African tour, they named only Mali as a supporter of the plan.</p>
<p>The United States has undertaken to pay a quarter of the estimated $40 million cost of training a pan-African intervention force and has pledged an additional $10 million.</p>
<p>Canada, Britain, Ireland and Belgium have so far promised financial support for the project.</p>
<p>The Johannesburg Star newspaper said in an editorial on Thursday it was time for Mandela's post-apartheid government to lend active support to the search for peace on the continent.</p>
<p>&quot;We all suffer from the periodic man-made disasters that still plague Africa. The negative image of the continent that they create in the minds of foreign investors rubs off on us.</p>
<p>&quot;This may be South Africa's moment to step out of the wings and begin to play its proper role in Africa,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>Mandela has so far resisted both a unilateral diplomatic role in peacemaking initiatives or a military role for his country's defence force, which is still trying to merge the former apartheid army and the liberation forces it fought.</p>
<p>&quot;We are concerned not to appear to continue the policies of the previous government, which engaged in military and economic destabilisation of neighbouring states. We are trying to avoid that,&quot; he said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Mandela broke his own rule on Nigeria by getting ahead of other African leaders with a call for sanctions against the country's military government, which was ignored.</p>
<p>He joined neighbouring countries last year in a more successful diplomatic drive for peace in landlocked Lesotho.</p>
<p>But political sources close to Mandela said he was resisting pressure from Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe to endorse a regional force mandated to intervene in other countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Mugabe is pushing hard, in fact he can be quite irritating, but as long as Mandela is president, I think the current policy will hold,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>A U.S. diplomatic source said Christopher probably would put the drive for democracy in Nigeria and the search for a successor to Boutros Boutros-Ghali as secretary general of the United Nations ahead of the force in his talks with Mandela.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
