<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107662" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>MADAGASCAR: Five more candidates cleared for Madagascar poll.</title>
<headline>Five more candidates cleared for Madagascar poll.</headline>
<dateline>ANTANANARIVO 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A high court cleared five candidates on Thursday to stand in the November 3 presidential election on the Indian Ocean island of Madagascar, bringing the total to 15.</p>
<p>The high constitutional court said it approved applications from the five candidates including interim President Norbert Ratsirahonana and National Assembly President Richard Andrianmanjato.</p>
<p>Ten candidates approved on Tuesday included former president Albert Zafy, whose impeachment by parliament in July cleared the way for the election, and former president Didier Ratsiraka.</p>
<p>The court rejected applications to stand as candidates from a Malagasy now living in France, Max Fabien Andrianirina, and the leader of a workers' movement, Francois Randrianantoandro.</p>
<p>The deadline for registering ended on Friday and campaigning on the world's fourth largest island starts on October 13.</p>
<p>The race is expected to focus on five or six candidates.</p>
<p>Retired admiral Ratsiraka, 59, the father of Madagascar's 1975 socialist revolution, returned to his homeland for the race on September 29, ending 19 months of voluntary exile in France.</p>
<p>Zafy, 70, won Madagascar's multi-party elections in 1993 by defeating former military ruler Ratsiraka, ending his 17 years in power, after an unprecedented campaign of popular protest at his rule.</p>
<p>But Zafy's presidency was dogged by instability, culminating in his impeachment by parliament for violating the constitution.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANTANANARIVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MADAGASCAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
