<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107761" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: World Bank approves of Bulgaria reforms.</title>
<headline>World Bank approves of Bulgaria reforms.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>World Bank executive director Pieter Stek said on Thursday the bank approved of Bulgaria's stabilisation programme, said the official agency BTA.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulgaria's reforms are at a turning point...The measures are tough, but urgent,&quot; BTA quoted Stek as saying.</p>
<p>The World Bank and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) have delayed funding for Bulgaria until the government closes some 64 state lossmakers and speeds up privatisation.</p>
<p>Sofia pledged to complete the closures by end-October and sell off some 20 major state firms by year-end.</p>
<p>Stek, one of the World Bank's 24 executive directors, is responsible for the group of countries that include Bulgaria.</p>
<p>During his two-day visit to Sofia he met Prime Minister Zhan Videnov, Finance Minister Dimitar Kostov, the head of parliament's budget and finance committee Kiril Zhelev and the head of parliament's economy committee Nikola Koichev.</p>
<p>Grappling with an unprecedented bank crisis, the government last month placed under special supervision nine banks, effectively closing them and hiked central interest rates to a record 300 percent.</p>
<p>Stek takes office as a new director in November 1, said the agency. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
