<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107787" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugoslav airlines JAT plans to renew fleet.</title>
<headline>Yugoslav airlines JAT plans to renew fleet.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslav airlines JAT said it was negotiating with three world aircraft manufacturers to purchase new planes to rejuvenate its fleet.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very intensively discussing possibilities for renewing or replacing our old fleet,&quot; JAT general manager Zika Petrovic told a news conference.</p>
<p>JAT commercial manager Borivoje Kovacevic told Reuters the carrier planned to buy some seven to eight aircraft, but he was unwilling to be more specific.</p>
<p>Petrovic said two manufacturers from the U.S. and one from Europe &quot;are still equal in the game&quot; but that it was too early for more details.</p>
<p>Petrovic said a decision was expected by the end of the year or early in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope through this package to also resolve problems of running the current fleet and of financing a new fleet, while ensuring maximum employment of JAT capacities,&quot; Petrovic said.</p>
<p>Local papers earlier reported that JAT planned to invest around $1 billion by the year 2000 to rejuvenate its fleet and was negotiating with Airbus Industrie, Boeing Co and McDonnell Douglas Corp.</p>
<p>JAT is seeking favourable credit conditions and for part of the deals to be covered through barter with Yugoslav components manufacturers who supplied the aircraft industry before sanctions were imposed on rump Yugoslavia in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;Employment of existing JAT capacities and the Yugoslav industry will be one of the criteria when we make our decision,&quot; Petrovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the final stage of talks but at the moment all three producers are still on an equal footing,&quot; Petrovic said.</p>
<p>JAT's current fleet of some 30 aircraft includes mainly DC9s, Boeing 727s and 737s and ATR 72s. Several aircraft are on lease to foreign companies. -- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
