<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107841" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania Sept savings bank deposits rise, seen up.</title>
<headline>Romania Sept savings bank deposits rise, seen up.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deposits at Romania's  Casa de Economii si Consemnatiuni (CEC) bank rose by some 0.4 percent to 1.917 trillion lei at end-September and should hit 1.937 trillion at end-December, provisional data showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>The end-1996 forecast does not include the interest which the CEC would capitalise at the end of each year, triggering a further jump in its deposits figure.</p>
<p>CEC deposits were on the slide in the first months of this year as its deposit rates were almost half the yields offered by other commercial banks.</p>
<p>But the figure began to pick up in May. Economists said the rebound in CEC deposits was helped by a rise in interest rates and by its status which allows it to cover investors fully amid recent upsets in the country's fledging banking sector.</p>
<p>Two Romanian private banks --  Renasterea Creditului Romanesc Credit Bank SA and  Dacia Felix SA -- have faced trouble in the past year after reports of big losses and debts.</p>
<p>The central bank lodged their files with courts, which are expected to rule on their liquidation or reorganisation.</p>
<p>In August, Romania approved the creation of an insurance deposit system for small depositors in banks which covers up to 10 million lei in deposits. The CEC is not included in that scheme, retaining the advantage of offering full cover.</p>
<p>The CEC's interest rate stands currently at 40 percent for one-year deposits, while commercial banks' one-year deposit rates are between 42 percent and 62 percent.</p>
<p>CEC savings took some 27 percent of total household deposits in August, down from 45 percent last December and well below 80 percent at the end of 1993. Household deposits data for September were not available. ($=3,262 lei) -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
