<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="107914" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Investment in Nicaragua said on hold ahead of vote.</title>
<headline>Investment in Nicaragua said on hold ahead of vote.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA, Nicaragua 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nicaragua's top banker said on Thursday that new investment in Nicaragua has been put on hold ahead of its October 20 presidential elections.</p>
<p>&quot;At this moment, not only foreign investment, but internal investment as well, is paralyzed. Those that don't need to continue their projects are watching since the elections are only 10 days away,&quot; Central Bank President Jose Evenor Taboada said at a news conference.  </p>
<p>Taboada said investments already underway were continuing and bank deposits were stable, but the initiation of new investments were being put off until after the election.</p>
<p>Nicaragua's presidential election pits left-wing candidate Daniel Ortega of the Sandinista Front against front-runner Arnoldo Aleman of the right-wing Liberal Alliance.  </p>
<p>Taboada, who met with International Monetary Fund (IMF) officials in early October, said they assured him the IMF would honor its agreements with Nicaragua whichever party wins and expressed optimism over the country's economic future.  </p>
<p>&quot;We think that with Nicaragua's elections a few days away, the panorama that presents itself is one of stability and growth, a panorama in which the international community has reiterated its will to continue supporting our country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Managua bureau, (505) 266-3300</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA, Nicaragua"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
