<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108002" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil re-election push must wait for split allies.</title>
<headline>Brazil re-election push must wait for split allies.</headline>
<byline>William Schomberg</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brazilian government is in a hurry to approve a bill allowing President Fernando Henrique Cardoso to stand again, but it cannot rush two big political parties whose votes are key to its success, analysts said.</p>
<p>Leaders of parties who make up the government's fragile alliance in Congress decided on Wednesday to postpone until around October 22 the start of committee-level discussions of a constitutional amendment allowing re-election.  </p>
<p>The committee's first meeting had been expected next week, paving the way for a first vote on the floor of the Chamber of Deputies this year and a final, second vote before February's changeover in the presidency of the lower house.</p>
<p>The government wants to get the re-election issue through the volatile chamber before Luiz Eduardo Magalhaes, its pro- reform president, is replaced by an as yet unchosen successor.</p>
<p>But the committee's start was delayed by differences within the Brazilian Progressive Party (PPB) and the Brazilian Democratic Movement Party (PMDB), which are split on re-election.  </p>
<p>The parties, who total nearly 200 deputies, are essential to the government's chances of pulling off the two three-fifths majorities, each equivalent to 308 votes, needed for the approval of the amendment in the volatile Chamber of Deputies.</p>
<p>&quot;In the re-election race, the government has slowed down on the curve to win on the home stretch,&quot; columnist Tereza Cruvinel wrote in newspaper O Globo.</p>
<p>The delay in the start-up of the committee gave the Brazilian Progressive Party (PPB) time to hold a national convention to decide its position on the reform.  </p>
<p>The PPB is the party of outgoing Sao Paulo mayor Paulo Maluf whose declared presidential ambitions were bolstered by the strong performance of his would-be successor in last week's first round of municipal elections.</p>
<p>Maluf is considered the biggest single threat to re-election, but has failed consistently over the years to win elections for anything bigger than Sao Paulo town hall.</p>
<p>Some Brasilia-watchers sense he might settle for a deal under which he drops his hostile approach in return for government support of his possible candidacy for the Sao Paulo state governorship in 1998.  </p>
<p>&quot;Maluf wants to be president, but he knows that's a long shot,&quot; said Marcelo Cordeiro of consultants Santafe Ideais. &quot;His game plan might be to win more space for the PPB in the government and consolidate his own position in the party.&quot;</p>
<p>A pro-re-election PPB might be rewarded in a cabinet reshuffle expected some time early next year, bringing it closer to the kind of power enjoyed by the government's closest ally, the Liberal Front Party, Cordeiro said.  </p>
<p>The extra week was also seen as a concession to the Brazilian Democratic Movement Party (PMDB), whose anti-Cardoso, old-guard leadership has ordered pro-reform members to stay out of the re-election debate until 1997.</p>
<p>The government may choose to avoid destabilizing the already divided PMDB by delaying until January -- during a special session of Congress to run through the year-end recess -- the committee-level vote on the re-election bill, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
