<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108058" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Official complaints of racism soar in Australia.</title>
<headline>Official complaints of racism soar in Australia.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Official complaints of racism in Australia have more than doubled partly because of an ugly political row over immigration and aboriginal welfare, Australia's Human Rights Commission said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The country's human rights watchdog cited figures to Reuters showing complaints under the national Racial Hatred Act surging to 39 for the September quarter, compared with 18 in the previous three months.</p>
<p>The commission's race-discrimination commissioner, Zita Antonios, attributed part of the increase to an education campaign about the act, which came into force a year ago and outlaws comments aimed at inciting racial hatred.</p>
<p>But Antonios said there was no doubt that a current debate over the level of Asian immigration and aboriginal welfare was fuelling racist sentiment in the community.</p>
<p>&quot;There's definitely been an increase in feelings in the community,&quot; she told Reuters, noting eight racism complaints before her were against outspoken legislator Pauline Hanson.</p>
<p>Hanson, a fish-and-chip shop owner from socially and politically conservative Queensland state, said in her maiden parliamentary speech in Canberra a month ago that Asian immigrants were &quot;swamping&quot; Australia.</p>
<p>Asians make up about a quarter of the approximately 100,000 immigrants who arrive in Australia,</p>
<p>Hanson's comments appear to have struck a chord with some voters and are backed  by Australians Against Further Immigration, a political party campaigning for an October 19 by-election in Sydney.</p>
<p>An opinion poll in Tuesday's Sydney Morning Herald nespaper showed 48 percent of Australians backed Hanson's comments, compared with 38 percent who opposed her stance. Other polls have shown many Australians believe the country is accepting too many migrants from Asia.</p>
<p>Hanson has also criticised aboriginal welfare as excessive.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard this week strongly attacked racism but defied pressure to reject Hanson's widely reported remarks, which Canberra acknowledges as potentially damaging to Australia's booming trade with Asia.</p>
<p>Antonios called for strong leadership to curb the flare-up in racist sentiment and said the current conservative government was not as swift to condemn racist remarks as the previous administration.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that there was a swiftness on the part of the previous government that we have not necessarily seen recently and there may be different reasons for that,&quot; she said. She declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>Antonios, daughter of Lebanese immigrants, cited personal experience of people of Asian or other ethnic background being abused in public and said some people did not feel safe.</p>
<p>The problem appears to be prominent in Hanson's home state of Queensland, one of the most popular destinations for Japanese tourists to Australia, Antonios said</p>
<p>&quot;Some people are suffering from anxiety and they don't feel safe in going out in public for fear of being abused,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to overstate it but these are the things people have been contacting me about.&quot;</p>
<p>Her remarks were backed on Thursday at a news conference called by leaders of migrant, student, union and aboriginal groups to condemn sentiments expressed by Hanson.</p>
<p>Danny Kong, a member of the Victoria state government advisory body on ethnic affairs, said immigrants were being made scapegoats of high unemployment and economic uncertainty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
