<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108194" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: J.P. Morgan net fell 23 percent in 3rd quarter.</title>
<headline>J.P. Morgan net fell 23 percent in 3rd quarter.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>J.P. Morgan &amp; Co. Inc. said Thursday its earnings fell 23 percent in the third quarter, hurt by a one-time charge and a drop in income from stock market investments.</p>
<p>The results were below expectations on Wall Street and Morgan stock fell, though modestly.</p>
<p>Even without the $71 million charge for a previously announced technology alliance, net income would have still been 12 percent below that of the 1995 quarter, the nation's fourth-largest bank said.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said sluggish stock and bond markets in the quarter hurt results at Morgan, which is more like an investment bank than most of its commercial bank competitors.</p>
<p>However, some noted that the latest results offered convincing evidence that the firm was now a power among investment banks, with strong performance in underwriting and mergers and acquisitions advisory work.</p>
<p>&quot;It's phenomenal,&quot; said George Salem, analyst at Gerard Klauer Mattison. &quot;They've come from way down to being No. 4 in underwriting in the U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>For the third quarter of 1996, Securities Data Co. ranked J.P. Morgan as the fourth-largest underwriter of U.S. debt and equity issues, serving as lead manager on $19.2 billion in deals in the quarter. Securities Data also had J.P. Morgan ranked sixth in completed deals worldwide and fourth in pending transactions in the first nine months of 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Investment banking continues to show strong headway,&quot; said Salomon Brothers analyst Diane Glossman.</p>
<p>&quot;Year-to-date performance is well ahead of last year, although third-quarter results did not achieve the levels of the first two quarters,&quot; Chairman Douglas Warner III said in a statement. Earnings for the first nine months rose 24 percent.</p>
<p>The New York-based bank said net income fell to $276 million, or $1.32 a share, in the quarter ended Sept. 30, from $360 million, or $1.78 a share, in the 1995 period.</p>
<p>Revenues were flat at $1.55 billion.</p>
<p>Analysts had expected Morgan to earn $1.58 a share in the quarter, according to First Call, which tracks Wall Street earnings estimates. Excluding the charge, equal to 21 cents a share, Morgan's per share earnings of $1.53 were still below expectations.</p>
<p>Morgan's stock fell 12.5 cents to $85.875 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>While third-quarter results excluding the charge were below expectations, Morgan's &quot;underlying results weren't so bad,&quot; said Raphael Soifer, analyst at Brown Brothers Harriman.</p>
<p>He noted that the bank's investment banking revenues, up 19 percent to $233 million, set a record for Morgan. &quot;Trading was down (from the first two quarters) but that was to be expected given the markets,&quot; he said, referring to the stock and bond markets in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Trading revenue rose 28 percent to $510 million due to higher results in fixed income and foreign exchange, while investment management fees grew 9 percent, Morgan said.</p>
<p>Interest revenue fell 16 percent to $425 million.</p>
<p>Other revenue fell 52 percent to $69 million. Included were net gains on stock investments of $56 million vs. $91 million in the 1995 period.</p>
<p>Operating expenses grew 11 percent to $1.14 billion in the quarter, Morgan said.</p>
<p>For the nine months, earnings including the special charge rose to $1.16 billion, or $5.60 a share, from $930 million, or $4.62 a share, in the year-earlier period.</p>
<p>The firm is advising Gillette Co. on its planned $7 billion acquisition of Duracell International Inc. It is also advising American Home Products Corp. on the sale of an 80 percent stake in its food products unit, and is adviser to Service Corp. International in its hostile bid for Loewen Group Inc.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
