<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108240" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gore beat Kemp in debate, three polls say.</title>
<headline>Gore beat Kemp in debate, three polls say.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vice President Al Gore did a better job than Republican Jack Kemp in the second debate of the presidential campaign, according to post-debate polls.</p>
<p>In a CBS News poll taken after the Wednesday night debate, 48 percent said Gore did a better job, while 31 percent favoured Republican vice presidential nominee Kemp. Thirteen percent said they tied and 8 percent had no opinion.</p>
<p>The poll sampled 348 registered voters and had a margin of error of plus or minus six percentage points.</p>
<p>A CNN/USA Today/Gallup poll of 408 registered voters who watched the debate showed 57 percent thought Gore did a better job while 28 percent favoured Kemp. Thirteen percent saw the debate as a tie. This poll had a margin of error of plus or minus 5 percentage points.</p>
<p>In a third poll, ABC News found Gore won by a margin of 50 percent to 27 percent. Another 21 percent called it a tie. The poll of 534 registered voters had a margin of error of plus or minus five percentage points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
