<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108310" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida mother who fed HIV baby sues hospital.</title>
<headline>Florida mother who fed HIV baby sues hospital.</headline>
<dateline>FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla. 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new mother who mistakenly nursed the infant of an HIV-positive woman has sued a hospital on the grounds that the error deprived her of breast-feeding her own child, her lawyer said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The lawsuit claimed the mother, identified only by the pseudonym Jane Doe, was exposed to a risk of contracting HIV, the virus that causes AIDS, and stopped breast-feeding her own baby girl for fear of exposing the infant to the virus.</p>
<p>&quot;The damages alleged are fear and anxiety over possibly having contracted HIV,&quot; said her attorney, Kenneth Sobel. &quot;And because she feared that breast-feeding was a mode of transmission, she was denied the right to breast-feed her child.&quot;</p>
<p>The mother, who has so far tested negative for the HIV virus, delivered a baby at Broward General Hospital in mid-April and was sleeping when a nurse brought in a child for her to breast feed. When the mother awakened she began to nurse the child, only to notice a few moments later that it was not her baby.</p>
<p>A nurse's aide brought the correct baby to the mother, who was allowed to breast-feed several times -- even after the hospital realised its mistake, said the lawsuit, filed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The woman was not told until the next day that the baby she had nursed was born to an HIV-infected woman. Doctors told her there was virtually no chance the baby had passed the virus to her, but advised her to stop nursing her daughter to be safe.</p>
<p>A lawyer for the hospital told the Sun Sentinel of Fort Lauderdale that the lawsuit was frivilous because the mother and her daughter were not harmed.</p>
<p>Sobel said the case could break new legal ground in that the courts could decide that deprivation of a woman's right to breast-feed her child carried a significant emotional impact that deserved a damage award.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is that the Florida legislature has embraced (breast feeding) as part of public policy. The courts should therefore ... vigilantly protect the woman who has been deprived of that right,&quot; said Sobel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FORT LAUDERDALE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
