<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108308" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pastors seek to bar gays from Key West parade.</title>
<headline>Pastors seek to bar gays from Key West parade.</headline>
<dateline>KEY WEST, Fla 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Another Christmas parade battle involving Gay rights is shaping up in Key West as religious leaders said Thursday a predominantly homosexual church should not be allowed to participate.</p>
<p>&quot;We hate homosexuality. It's a sin. It's very clear in the Bible,&quot; said Randy Weisberg, president of the Lower Florida Keys Ministerial Association, a group of 15 conservative pastors who have sponsored the parade for more than a decade.</p>
<p>The city planned to grant a parade permit only if the organisers promised not to exclude anyone, including Key West's largely gay Metropolitan Community Church. Members of the pastors group have cried foul, saying their freedoms of speech and religion were at stake.</p>
<p>City officials said the matter might come to a vote at a meeting Wednesday, and members of the pastors group said they intended to be there.</p>
<p>&quot;Suppose one of the sexually oriented businesses wanted to go down the street with their dancers on a flat bed truck as part of our parade,&quot; asked Rev. Gary Redwine of the Big Coppitt First Baptist Church on Big Coppitt Key. Under the city's plan, that would have to be allowed, he said.</p>
<p>A controversy arose prior to last year's Christmas parade, when the sponsor refused to let Metropolitan Community Church participate despite outrage from the city's large gay community. The parade went ahead as scheduled amid protests and prayer vigils.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KEY WEST, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
