<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108313" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street's bull market marks 6th anniversary.</title>
<headline>Wall Street's bull market marks 6th anniversary.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street's record-breaking bull market celebrates its sixth anniversary on Friday and while historical cycles suggest a 1997 demise, the bulls are not retreating.</p>
<p>Interest rates are low, inflation is under control, the economy is growing and best of all, the record flow of cash into mutual funds shows no signs of abating.</p>
<p>While this bull market has had its fits and starts -- the technology stocks roller coaster, for instance -- the six-year period has few parallels in history.</p>
<p>The current bull market began on Oct. 11, 1990, just after a 21 percent decline that analysts attributed to Iraq's August 1990 invasion of Kuwait, and, according to some measures, it has become the biggest one ever.</p>
<p>At its peak last week, the bull market had the Dow above 6,000, up from 2,365, and the S&amp;P 500 above 700, up from 295.</p>
<p>&quot;To date, this bull market has generated a 153 percent advance, making this cycle the longest and best in post-World War II history,&quot; said Gail Dudack, chief investment strategist at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>Market historians measure bull markets by different criterion, though, and Birinyi Associates, a respected statistical research firm based in Greenwich, Conn., says this bull market is the second biggest ever.</p>
<p>Birinyi says the grandaddy of all bull markets occurred between June 1949 and December 1961 when the Dow Jones industrial average rose from 162 to 735, a gain of 355 percent over 12-1/2 years.</p>
<p>So how long can a bull market last?</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a record-setting bull. But the sixth anniversary means nothing,&quot; said Alfred Goldman, a technical analyst at A.G. Edwards and Sons. &quot;It's the action of the market that causes its eventual demise, not the length of it. There's little evidence this is close to needing a resuscitator.&quot;</p>
<p>One factor is the flow of cash into mutual funds.</p>
<p>According to the Investment Company Institute, the amount of cash going into stock mutual funds this year is on pace to nearly double the previous record year.</p>
<p>Baby Boomers seem steadfast in plans to fund long-term commitments -- like children's college education, houses and retirement -- through stock ownership.</p>
<p>&quot;Sticking to fundamentals, I don't see a selloff. We might have squalls that will be sector-related or broader but it will be short-lived. There is still a bias to the upside. (Mutual fund flow) won't abate as long as fundamentals are reliable,&quot; said Joseph Battipaglia, chief investment strategist at Gruntal &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Still, the ageing bull market has turned some bulls more cautious, fretting that the record inflow into mutual funds is not sustainable, inflation and higher rates are lurking around the corner and that corporate profit growth is slowing from its spectacular double-digit pace to single digits.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an aged bull market and an aged economic cycle,&quot; said UBS' Dudack, who has turned into a bear. &quot;It's going to be hard to make money over the next six months.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think the constant rush of mutual fund money started in 1990 and there are plenty of reasons to think equities is the place to be, but that idea is also six years old. Consumers have a very healthy serving of equities in their portfolios already,&quot; she said. &quot;A six-year bull market is long in the tooth.&quot;</p>
<p>But Yale Hirsch of the Hirsch Organisation, which publishes the Stock Trader's Almanac, said the last bull market ended in 1987, and the current bull market doesn't have similar characteristics.</p>
<p>&quot;What happened in 1987 is not like now. We had small stocks (and) Canadian stocks running wild in 1987. We haven't had the same speculation in garbage stocks participating in this leg,&quot; he said. He also noted interest rates were 10 percent and rising in 1987, while rates are now steady near seven percent.</p>
<p>William LeFevre, a senior market analyst at Ehrenkrantz King Nussbaum, concluded: &quot;It's a bull market. Relax and enjoy it.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wall Street desk 212 859 1721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
