<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108534" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's Juppe presses for more jobs, fewer hours.</title>
<headline>France's Juppe presses for more jobs, fewer hours.</headline>
<dateline>REIMS, France 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe, his popularity tumbling over rising unemployment and government austerity plans, urged French firms on Thursday to battle joblessness by hiring young people and cutting the working week.</p>
<p>&quot;In the next six months, either we succeed in integrating 300,000 young people into the economy -- and I believe this will radically improve the French people's morale -- or we fail and keep on talking about scepticism and gloom,&quot; Juppe told business leaders in the northeastern city of Reims.</p>
<p>&quot;We must act together, in a renewed partnership,&quot; Juppe told the group gathered at the Reims Chamber of Commerce and Industry.</p>
<p>National statistics institute INSEE said French household confidence slid again in September and fears for jobs rose despite a tax-cutting package put forward by the Juppe government to encourage consumer spending and boost the economy.</p>
<p>Economists said the survey had to be treated with scepticism because other data showed consumer spending was actually rising, but they said it proved in stark political terms how badly Juppe was faring in the public's eyes.</p>
<p>Juppe, in his plea to business leaders, recognised that some may be in a difficult situation. But &quot;if there is no growth, no orders, there will be no new jobs.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are on the eve of a resumption of growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The government has urged business leaders and labour unions to negotiate agreements aimed at shortening the working week. Few accords have been reached, though the unions and the government believe they will lead to the creation of new jobs.</p>
<p>Unemployment reached a record 12.6 percent in August, affecting 3.09 million people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REIMS, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
