<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108639" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Hindu nationalists fall short in big Indian state.</title>
<headline>Hindu nationalists fall short in big Indian state.</headline>
<byline>Sharat Pradhan</byline>
<dateline>LUCKNOW, India 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP) failed to clinch an outright majority in India's most populous state on Thursday in a setback to its drive to win national power.</p>
<p>&quot;We accept the defeat,&quot; BJP leader Atal Bihari Vajpayee told reporters after results showed the right-wing party leading in a three-way race but falling short of a majority.</p>
<p>With results declared in 376 of 425 races in the state assembly, the BJP had won 158. In the last state election in 1993, the BJP won 176 seats.</p>
<p>The partial returns showed Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's United Front coalition had won 115 seats, while an alliance between the Congress party and its low-caste partner, the Hindu Bahujan Samaj Party (BSP), had taken 93.</p>
<p>The BJP, which built its national foundations on a Hindu revivalist agenda in Uttar Pradesh in the late 1980s, had hoped to win control of the state that is India's biggest electoral prize.</p>
<p>Instead, the United Front and the Congress-BSP alliance were already jockeying to rule the sprawling state with 140 million people.</p>
<p>&quot;It is disappointing,&quot; state BJP chief Kalraj Misra said.</p>
<p>The polls had signficance for Deve Gowda's stability in New Delhi because his centre-left coalition there depends on the Congress to survive against a BJP challenge in parliament.</p>
<p>Congress has insisted that the United Front back its candidate for chief minister in Uttar Pradesh, BSP leader Mayawati.</p>
<p>&quot;We are committed to Mayawati,&quot; state Congress president Jitendra Prasada said.</p>
<p>But the United Front's main component in Uttar Pradesh, the Samajwadi Party, wants its leader and Deve Gowda's defence minister, Mulayam Singh Yadav, to lead the state.</p>
<p>The tensions in Uttar Pradesh have spilled over to New Delhi, where the Congress party's new chief Sitaram Kesri recently threatened to withdraw support for Deve Gowda unless his coalition backed the Congress-BSP alliance in the state.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason why they (United Front) shouldn't support Mayawati if they're truly anti-communal,&quot; State Congress leader Prasada said. The BJP's rivals call the Hindu nationalist party &quot;communal&quot; because they claim it alienates minority Moslems.</p>
<p>&quot;If they don't support her (Mayawati), we'll have to rethink,&quot; Prasada said.</p>
<p>The BJP appeared to be manoeuvering to try to draw Congress away from the United Front. &quot;We know we are far short of a majority and therefore we have to look for other options,&quot; BJP leader Pramod Mahajan said.</p>
<p>&quot;Let a government be formed with our support. Our doors are open.&quot;</p>
<p>Congress, however, rejected the possibility of allying with the BJP. &quot;We will have no direct or indirect truck with the BJP,&quot; Prasada said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUCKNOW, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
