<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108656" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Taleban's Afghan foes forge military pact.</title>
<headline>Taleban's Afghan foes forge military pact.</headline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foes of Afghanistan's new purist Islamic Taleban rulers signed a military pact on Thursday and agreed to unite against them unless fighting stopped, Western reporters said.</p>
<p>The agreement was signed by Uzbek chief Abdul Rashid Dostum, former government military chief Ahmad Shah Masood and Karim Khalilli, head of the Shia Moslem Hezb-i-Wahadat, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whoever does not cease to fight against one of the signatories, the other signatories will jointly fight against them,&quot; they quoted Dostum spokesman Mohammed Yusuf as saying.</p>
<p>Masood's forces, bottled up in his Panjsher valley fortress since Taleban took control of Kabul two weeks ago, have counter-attacked in the Salang Pass, which cuts through the Hindu Kush and divides northern and southern Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Masood's forces had forced Taleban back to near the town of Jabal-os-Saraj at the mouth of the pass, which carries the road from Kabul to Dostum's headquarters at Mazar-i-Sharif.</p>
<p>The reporters said the pact was signed at Khin Jan, halfway between Mazar-i-Sharif and the Salang Tunnel, the main choke point in the pass.</p>
<p>Masood flew in from the Panjsher by helicopter for the ceremony and returned soon afterwards, saying nothing. Dostum, by contrast, appeared ebullient, the reporters said.</p>
<p>The two men originally became allies after Dostum switched to the side of Islamic guerrillas shortly before the fall of a Moscow-backed government in Kabul in 1992.</p>
<p>They fell out two years later and Dostum retreated to the north, where he controls six of Afghanistan's provinces with a strong army and a small air force.</p>
<p>Taleban leaders in Kabul had no immediate reaction to news of the military pact, but there seemed little doubt that the alliance of Dostum and Masood spelled deep trouble for them.</p>
<p>Masood's control of the Panjsher valley begins near Jabal-os-Saraj, while Dostum moved men and armour south of the Salang Tunnel after Taleban took Kabul on September 27.</p>
<p>Khallili controls territory in Bamyan province to the west of Jabal-os-Saraj and their combined forces could be too much to allow the Taleban to keep the town.</p>
<p>Taleban has prepared no major defence lines between Kabul and Jabal-os-Saraj, travellers said, but had massed about 2,000 men near Charikar, about 30 minutes drive south of the town. REUTER  . .</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
