<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108627" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German sick pay talks break up, little progress.</title>
<headline>German sick pay talks break up, little progress.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Talks between Germany's largest union and the engineering employers' association on how to resolve a dispute over cuts in sick pay broke up after four hours on Thursday with apparently little progress made.</p>
<p>&quot;We are finished for today,&quot; Dieter Hundt, deputy president of the employer group Gesamtmetall, told reporters.</p>
<p>The group's president, Werner Stumpfe, added that the two sides were still vey far apart. &quot;There is no cause for optimism,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;Both parties have been confronted with very high expectations from their members.&quot;  </p>
<p>The union and employers are deadlocked over the implementation of a new law entitling employers to cut sick pay to 80 percent of the normal wage from 100 percent currently.</p>
<p>The union, which takes the view that it fought hard in the past to win such benefits now locked into most wage contracts, has staged huge demonstrations to make clear it will not accept cutbacks of this type lightly.</p>
<p>Stumpfe, exiting from the talks, told journalists he expected to know very soon after the weekend whether it even made sense for the two sides to talk further.</p>
<p>If a new meeting were to be agreed, this would be set for October 21, he said.</p>
<p>But he also made clear the employers still wanted to discuss the sick pay issue in the context of other labour costs. &quot;The whole package (for discussion) should include sick pay, holiday bonuses, employment clauses and 1997 wage increases.&quot;</p>
<p>Employment clauses would allow workers to be paid below the tariff rate in certain circumstances.</p>
<p>--Mark John, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
