<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108659" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan denies getting Chinese nuclear equipment.</title>
<headline>Pakistan denies getting Chinese nuclear equipment.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan on Thursday denied that it had recently bought nuclear weapons-related equipment from China and complained it had become a victim of inspired leaks in the United States.</p>
<p>The Washington Times reported on Wednesday that China had made a new sale of nuclear weapons-related equipment to Pakistan in a move which could increase pressure on the U.S. government to impose sanctions on Beijing.</p>
<p>&quot;We deny that there was any nuclear weapons-related transfer to Pakistan,&quot; a Pakistan Foreign Ministry spokesman told reporters at a news briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;I regret to say that we seem to be becoming the victims of a series of leaks, some of which are...simply motivated or inspired by the electoral fever in the United States and by their own internal shadow-boxing amongst themselves,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This unfortunate trend gives chances to those lobbies which are motivated against Pakistan to raise these issues. But as happened in earlier cases, I think this also will fade away.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. State Department on Wednesday also denied that China had violated a promise to the United States by selling nuclear weapons-related equipment to Pakistan.</p>
<p>But spokesman Nicholas Burns stopped short of denying that the transfer reported by the Washington Times had taken place.</p>
<p>The Times said China sold Pakistan the technology -- a special industrial furnace and high-tech diagnostic equipment -- last month in violation of a May 11 pledge not to repeat an earlier covert sale of other nuclear-related items.</p>
<p>But Burns said: &quot;Senior-level people in this government have looked at these specific charges and, based on the information available to us, we do not conclude that China has violated the commitments it made in its May 11 statement.&quot;</p>
<p>His remark left open the possibility that a transfer could have taken place before May 11. A senior State Department official, asked if this was the case, said: &quot;I can't confirm that, but that's a possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>At a news briefing, Burns also did not deny the authenticity of a Central Intelligence Agency memorandum cited in the Times report. Instead he denounced what he called &quot;another leak of a highly classified intelligence report&quot;.</p>
<p>According to the Times, the September 14 memorandum said the State Department sent Beijing a diplomatic note on August 30 protesting at the sale of the equipment to nuclear facilities in Pakistan not subject to international inspection.</p>
<p>It also said senior Chinese leaders probably approved the sale, the Times said. The newspaper quoted Chinese and Pakistani diplomats as denying that any illicit transfer had taken place.</p>
<p>China's pledge not to repeat sales of nuclear technology to Pakistan -- a &quot;threshold&quot; nuclear power which has not signed the nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty -- followed months of negotiations with U.S. officials.</p>
<p>The talks were sparked in part by a Washington Times report in February that China had sold Pakistan ring magnets, used in gas centrifuges which produce nuclear weapons fuel. The sale raised the threat of U.S. sanctions under American anti-proliferation laws.</p>
<p>Washington eventually agreed not to impose sanctions, accepting assurances by Chinese leaders that they were unaware of the sale carried out by a Chinese company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
