<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108618" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures settled weaker but well off the lows struck as the market took a breather from five successive days on the rise on Thursday, with little sign spend-happy sentiment was likely to abate, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in a market that's being driven by flows rather than fundamentals,&quot; said one futures trader at a large French bank.</p>
<p>The December bond future ended MATIF trading, down 0.12, at 126.42 after a last minute lift in slim volumes, following a dip in heavier morning volumes to as low at 126.18.</p>
<p>&quot;Five successive rises followed by a bit of consolidation is normal,&quot; said another trader. &quot;The market's still upward-bound.&quot;  </p>
<p>PIBOR interest rate futures slipped across the curve, with the December contract shedding five basis points in relatively moderate volume to settle just above a day low of 96.37 after the Bundesbank and Bank of France kept interest rates steady.</p>
<p>There had been some market talk of an outside chance that the Bundesbank would make a move but the majority had kept their bets on rates staying on hold.</p>
<p>The franc gave way marginally to less than 3.38 versus the mark for most of the day, standing at 3.3811/15 at 1503 GMT versus 3.3799/01 late in Europe on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>One trader said he could see the December bond future rising to 127 or 128 further out on the back of the current wave of enthusiasm from mainly domestic investors and that some were even talking of a figure of 130.</p>
<p>Earlier on Thursday, the treasury announced that it had sold 565 million Ecus of OATs and BTANs with a total bid cover ratio of 2.98.</p>
<p>In the cash market, yields on the 6.50 percent OAT due 2006 eased marginally to 5.92 from 5.91 late on Thursday but the spread against its German counterpart tightened further to minus eight basis points from minus seven basis points.  </p>
<p>The big U.S. inflation-guage statistics will come back into play on Friday with the release of the Producer Price Index data for September at 1230 GMT.</p>
<p>A Reuters poll produced a forecast consensus monthly rise of 0.3 percent, and a rise of 0.2 percent in the core rate which excludes volatile food and energy prices.</p>
<p>Economists say U.S. wholesale price inflation remains well under control and a modest increase on Friday is not likely to boost prospects of the Federal Reserve hiking interest rates in the short term. Labour costs are the main focal point as the Fed meeting of November 13 approaches, they say.  </p>
<p>In France, Friday brings provisional consumer price data for September at 0645 GMT.</p>
<p>Consumer prices fall for the third month running in August with a drop of 0.3-0.3 percent, prompting economists to declare inflation a &quot;back-burner&quot; issue in France.</p>
<p>One trader said euphoric debt market was more likely to be upset by political than purely economic problems, like problems for Prime Minister Alain Juppe or with the health of Russian President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>At the moment things looked calm on that front, he added.</p>
<p>-- Brian Love, Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
