<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108720" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Rao caught in legal tangles.</title>
<headline>India's Rao caught in legal tangles.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Indian prime minister P.V. Narasimha Rao, who was briefly arrested on forgery charges late on Wednesday and then immediately released on bail, has been named in several corruption cases.</p>
<p>Following are summaries of the three cases in which Rao, who served as prime minister from mid-1991 until last May, has either been charged or is under investigation.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>ST KITTS</p>
<p>The Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI), India's federal police, charged Rao and three others on September 26 in a forgery case involving an alleged attempt in 1989 to defame V.P. Singh, an opposition leader who later became prime minister.</p>
<p>The case involves the alleged falsification of bank documents to show that Singh's son, Ajeya Singh, had a secret bank account with $21 million on the Caribbean island of St Kitts.</p>
<p>At the time V.P. Singh, who had left the ruling Congress party for the opposition, was spearheading an anti-corruption campaign against the government.</p>
<p>V.P. Singh became prime minister at the end of 1989 after Congress lost general elections. Authorities later cleared Ajeya Singh of allegations that he had violated foreign exchange and anti-corruption laws.</p>
<p>The federal police agency said the four accused were charged with criminal conspiracy, forgery, giving false evidence and using forged documents. The charges carry a maximum sentence of seven years in jail.</p>
<p>On October 4, an Indian judge issued a warrant for Rao's arrest and scheduled a hearing for October 14. The Delhi High Court suspended the warrant pending a ruling on a request by Rao for legal protection against arrest.</p>
<p>On October 9, the Delhi High Court granted Rao the right to pay pre-emptive, or anticipatory, bail to prevent being taken into custody before the lower court hearing set for October 14. At that hearing he can request ordinary bail.</p>
<p>Late on October 9, federal police served the arrest warrant on Rao at his New Delhi home. He immediately paid a total of 50,000 rupees ($1,400) in bail and was freed.</p>
<p>Rao has not commented publicly on the case.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHEATING SCANDAL</p>
<p>An Indian expatriate businessman, Lakhubhai Pathak, alleges Rao and a Hindu guru named Chandraswami conspired to cheat him of $100,000 in 1983.</p>
<p>Pathak claims he paid money to Chandraswami in an unsuccessful attempt to win a state newsprint contract after Rao, then foreign minister, assured him at a meeting in a New York hotel that his &quot;work will be done&quot;.</p>
<p>In July, a Delhi judge summoned Rao to appear in court to face charges. Rao lost two appeals to have the summons overturned. A judge upheld the summons on September 21, and ordered Rao to appear in his court on September 30 to face charges.</p>
<p>The former prime minister, who quit as Congress party chief hours after the judge's ruling on September 21, was later denied legal protection against arrest.</p>
<p>On September 30, the Supreme Court exempted Rao from having to appear in court until it considers a police request for a change in venue from a local court to a more secure location. The Supreme Court has not yet ruled on the police request.</p>
<p>The lower court has scheduled a hearing for October 16 but must await the Supreme Court decision before selecting the venue.</p>
<p>The lower court was expected to charge Rao with criminal conspiracy to cheat, which carries a maximum penalty of seven years in jail.</p>
<p>If arrested and denied bail, he could be put under judicial or police custody pending trial. Newspapers said a local state-owned hospital was prepared to take in Rao, who has diabetes and heart problems.</p>
<p>The two other co-accused, Chandraswami and his personal assistant, are both under custody in New Delhi's Tihar jail pending trial.</p>
<p>Rao has said he is innocent and has denied he was in New York on the dates mentioned by Pathak.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>VOTE-BUYING SCANDAL</p>
<p>Lawmakers of the regional Jharkand Mukti Morcha party said they were paid $100,000 to vote against a 1993 no-confidence motion which Rao's Congress-led government survived by a wafer-thin margin.</p>
<p>Earlier this year the CBI filed a case accusing Rao and other Congress leaders of buying the votes. They have denied any wrongdoing. The case is still under investigation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
