<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="108735" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue-chip stocks end lower; await Friday's data.</title>
<headline>Blue-chip stocks end lower; await Friday's data.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks ended with modest losses Thursday as Wall Street awaited Friday's wholesale price and retail sales reports for September.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average fell 8.95 points to 5,921.67. In the broader market, declining issues led advances 1,244 to 1,080 on subdued volume of 394 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Friday's data on producer prices and the pace of retail sales could give the market a scare if they show signs of inflationary pressures, analysts said.</p>
<p>Economists in a Reuters survey said they expected retail sales to rise 0.2 percent overall and the Producer Price Index to rise 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Friday's session is likely to show a reaction to the Federal Reserve's interest-rate perspective,&quot; said Alan Ackerman, senior market strategist at Fahnestock &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Last month, the Fed decided to keep interest rates unchanged, but some on Wall Street were betting that the central bank might have been waiting for additional economic data before making up its mind on whether or not to tighten monetary policy.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the government will report the Consumer Price Index for September.</p>
<p>The stock market jumped last Friday on an unexpectedly weak employment report for September, but it has since backtracked, with the Dow Jones index unable to retain rallies through the 6,000-point milestone.</p>
<p>Adding to the market's overall indecision is the flood of third-quarter earnings, which are due to begin in earnest next week, with companies including Johnson &amp; Johnson, Coca-Cola Co., Citicorp and Time Warner Inc. due to post their results.</p>
<p>Wall Street bears, a dwindling breed, are saying that the Dow's inability to close above 6,000 barrier is a sign that stocks are losing momentum.</p>
<p>Overvalued stocks, shrinking profit margins and slowing earnings growth are factors that could be leading to a broad market pullback, said James Solloway, director of Research at Argus Research Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;Earnings could be a critical factor here in pushing the market over,&quot; Solloway said.</p>
<p>But bulls said they saw no major danger on the horizon.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see much in the way of downside here at all,&quot; said Ken Tower, technical analyst at UST Securities. He cited the recent drop in the long-term interest rate below 7 percent, and the likelihood it will stabilise at that level.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the 30-year Treasury was off 22/32 and its yield rose to 6.89 percent vs. 6.83 at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, large retail store chains reported mixed September sales, hurt by a blast of Indian summer heat and an accounting shift that left most of the Labour Day weekend out of September results this year.</p>
<p>Sears Roebuck rose 1/2 to 48-1/4, J.C. Penney Co. gained 1-3/8 to 53-7/8, while speciality retailer Limited Inc., was unchanged at 19.</p>
<p>Among individual stocks, Altera Corp. rallied 6-1/8 to 60 after posting strong quarterly results.</p>
<p>The stock of eyeware companies tumbled after Sunglass Hut International warned of a third-quarter earnings shortfall. Sunglass Hut lost 4-5/16 to 9-3/16, Oakley Inc. shed 7-5/8 to 37-1/2, and Gargoyles Inc. tumbled four to 15-3/4.</p>
<p>Olin Corp. surged 4-3/8 to 88-1/2 after announcing a broad corporate restructuring, a share buyback and a stock split.</p>
<p>Altera Corp. rallied 6-1/8 to 60 after posting strong quarterly results.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index fell 1.01 to 1,236.97.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks fell 2.13 to 694.61. The American Stock Exchange index slipped 0.11 to 579.99.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks fell 1.00 to 370.35. The average share was down 11 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 6,816.557 down 16.082 or 0.24 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
