<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109045" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's Clarke steals show at Tory conference.</title>
<headline>Britain's Clarke steals show at Tory conference.</headline>
<byline>Rosemary Bennett</byline>
<dateline>BOURNEMOUTH, England 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke became the unlikely darling of the Conservative Party Conference on Thursday even though he made no promise of sweeping pre-election tax cuts in his set-piece speech.</p>
<p>Party activists, many of whom had been previously muted in their support for Clarke, gave the Chancellor a five minute standing ovation, the longest applause in the week so far.</p>
<p>Clarke's supporters were clearly relieved. They had been concerned the conference would give the Chancellor a cool reception because of his stance on Europe and tax.</p>
<p>Close colleague Quentin Davies told Reuters Clarke's speech was &quot;the best of his life&quot; and Deputy Prime Minister Michael Heseltine called it &quot;fabulous&quot;.</p>
<p>Delegates leaving the conference hall were clearly converted.</p>
<p>&quot;It was so obviously a brilliant speech. He's proved his metal and people will find it more difficult to criticise him now,&quot; said Murray Case from Welwyn and Hatfield constituency party. He said he was not generally a strong supporter of Clarke and wanted to see bigger tax cuts than have so far been hinted at.</p>
<p>Peter O'Brian, from a neighbouring Hertfordshire constituency, said he was happy with the line Clarke had taken on tax cuts, that he would only make them if affordable.</p>
<p>&quot;I only want to see sustainable tax cuts, but I'm pretty confident we'll get something in November.&quot;</p>
<p>At last year's conference, Clarke teased the audience with the prospect of tax cut. He took a much harder line on Thursday.</p>
<p>Clarke repeated his claim that the public would not trust the Tories if they tried to buy the next election by unsustainable tax cuts. &quot;We will only cut taxes when we can afford to.&quot;</p>
<p>Some delegates said they were still concerned Clarke was more interested in meeting the Maastricht criterian on fiscal deficits than cutting taxes as much a possible, but they appeared relieved Clarke stuck firmly to the goverment's line on a single currency.</p>
<p>The party leadership said it will keep its options open on EMU and not commit Britain to anything until it had to.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a good policy and one the party can unite on. I'm pleased Clarke is keeping is sticking to it,&quot; said a delegate from Bolton.</p>
<p>Clarke sparked uproar last month and left right wingers baying for his dismissal when he sid it would be &quot;pathetic&quot; for Britain to dither over joining a single currency, then sign up at the last minute.</p>
<p>And some activists and party colleagues said on Thursday they still want to see the party leadership make a decision one way or another before they go to the polls. An election must be held by May 1997 at the latest.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to make a decision about what we think before the election,&quot; said David Heathcoat-Amory a leading Eurosceptic. &quot;Obviously the Chancellor's speech is not the place to do it and today we can celebrate a very good speech from a very good Chancellor.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOURNEMOUTH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
