<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109156" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Arafat says talks with Israel not fruitful.</title>
<headline>Arafat says talks with Israel not fruitful.</headline>
<dateline>RAMALLAH, West Bank 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat told lawmakers in the West Bank town of Ramallah on Thursday that talks with Israel have not achieved any results and called on Palestinians to be on alert.</p>
<p>&quot;Until yesterday night, the brothers returned from the meetings and they have not reached anything,&quot; Arafat told the Palestinian Legislative Council, referring to Israeli-PLO talks in Gaza. &quot;Thus, we must be fully prepared...to confront all possibilities.&quot;</p>
<p>Arafat did not elaborate on his call. But he referred to Israel's deployment of tanks and armoured vehicles around West Bank cities following fierce clashes between Palestinians and Israeli troops last month.</p>
<p>&quot;(Benjamin) Netanyahu must know that no one can threaten the Palestinian people. We welcome peace but not from one side,&quot; Arafat said, directing his words to the Israeli prime minister.</p>
<p>Israel has eased the movements of Palestinians in most parts of the West Bank in the past week but it continues to maintain a heavy military presence in the area.</p>
<p>Arafat flew to Ramallah on Thursday for his first visit to the West Bank since 60 Palestinians and 15 Israeli soldiers were killed in the clashes two weeks ago.</p>
<p>The violence was sparked by the Israel's opening of an entrance to a tunnel near Islamic holy sites in Arab East Jerusalem. It highlighted Palestinian frustrations at Israel's reluctance to carry out self-rule deals signed with the previous Israeli government.</p>
<p>Israeli and PLO negotiators have since Sunday been holding talks on Israeli troop redeployment from the West Bank town of Hebron, the last of six West Bank cities Israel agreed to hand over to the PLO under a 1995 self-rule deal.</p>
<p>Arafat said Israel was trying to change the Hebron accord, which calls for handing over most of the city to the PLO while keeping the rest under Israeli control.</p>
<p>&quot;We are against changing even a comma in the agreement. He who agrees to change a comma will agree to reopen the accord,&quot; Arafat told the council.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RAMALLAH, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
