<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109151" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Ten foreign tourists dead in Turkish bus plunge.</title>
<headline>Ten foreign tourists dead in Turkish bus plunge.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A coach carrying German and Dutch holidaymakers skidded off the road and plunged 30 metres (100 feet) down a ravine in southern Turkey on Thursday, killing 10 foreign tourists and a Turk, police said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been told by the travel agent's headquarters that we have nine Dutch dead, a German and a Turkish driver,&quot; a Dutch embassy spokesman said.</p>
<p>Nineteen people were injured in the crash near the popular Mediterranean resort of Antalya, hospital officials said.</p>
<p>Turkish television showed the battered bus perched awkwardly on its side part of the way down the ravine. A flattened car, apparently crushed by the bus, lay at the bottom of the gully with a corpse inside it.</p>
<p>The bus was carrying around 30 tourists, mostly German and Dutch, from Antalya to the inland town of Pamukkale. &quot;It was bad weather, raining,&quot; the embassy spokesman said.</p>
<p>Turkey has one of the worst road traffic death rates in the world. Almost 6,000 people lost their lives in traffic accidents last year.</p>
<p>Seven people died on Thursday in another bus crash near the western city of Konya that was almost identical to the tourist accident, Anatolian news agency said.</p>
<p>A bus skidded off a wet country road and tumbled down a sharp decline. Anatolian quoted some of the 25 injured passengers as saying the driver was asleep at the time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
