<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109268" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole hopes reunion with Kemp, Powell sparks campaign.</title>
<headline>Dole hopes reunion with Kemp, Powell sparks campaign.</headline>
<dateline>CINCINNATI, Ohio 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole on Thursday joins up with running mate Jack Kemp and Gulf War hero Colin Powell, hoping the reunion with his popular allies will spark his campaign as he starts a bus trip in Ohio.</p>
<p>Powell has long been rumoured to be Dole's pick for secretary of state if the former Kansas senator wins an upset victory against President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Dole fuelled that speculation late on Wednesday night by telling reporters in Chicago, &quot;Colin Powell is going to be one of the stars of our new administration.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole, Kemp and Powell will rendezvous in Cincinnati on Thursday morning, following Kemp's debate with Vice President Al Gore in Florida on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>As might be expected, Dole said he thought Kemp was the clear winner in that matchup, although the instant public opinion polls showed the audience thought Gore did better.</p>
<p>After the Cincinnati rally, Dole departs on a two day bus tour through Ohio, a state with 21 electoral votes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CINCINNATI, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
