<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109253" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. defense secretary to visit Russia.</title>
<headline>U.S. defense secretary to visit Russia.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Defence Secretary William Perry will visit Moscow next week to discuss closer U.S.-Russian military ties and urge Russia's legislature to approve the Start-2 strategic arms reduction treaty, the Pentagon said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In a three-day visit beginning on Wednesday, Perry will meet Russian Defence Minister Igor Rodionov and speak to Russia's State Duma, the lower house of Parliament, to press for passage of additional deep nuclear weapons cuts under the treaty signed in 1993.  </p>
<p>Perry will be accompanied by U.S. Senators Sam Nunn of Georgia, Richard Lugar of Indiana and Joseph Lieberman of Connecticut. Nunn and Lugar sponsored legislation that has provided millions of dollars to aid nuclear cuts in the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Start-2 would require the United States and Russia to slash their nuclear arsenals to between 3,000 and 3,500 long-range warheads each by the year 2003, a reduction of some two-thirds from Cold War levels.</p>
<p>The U.S. Senate ratified the treaty by an 87-4 vote last January 26 but objections have been raised in Russia, where the economy and military forces are in turmoil. Some legislators fear that major nuclear cuts could leave Moscow vulnerable to pressure from the West.</p>
<p>Perry and Army General Rodionov met last month at a gathering of NATO defence ministers in Bergen, Norway, and Rodionov promised to continue improving Russian military ties with the alliance despite Moscow's objections to NATO enlargement into Eastern Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
