<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109383" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU on tightrope between wheat sales and U.S. spat.</title>
<headline>EU on tightrope between wheat sales and U.S. spat.</headline>
<byline>Tim Hepher</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain traders made a slew of bids for subsidised European Union wheat exports on Thursday but left the EU limited room to grant aid without watering down pledges to the United States, analysts said.</p>
<p>Requests for subsidies at the EU's weekly grain export tender included French bids to export 591,250 tonnes of soft wheat to non-EU countries using refunds starting from 5.74 Ecus per tonne.</p>
<p>Traders said this lowest subsidy bid valued French export wheat at $170-171 per tonne for November, barely more than the price of competing soft red winter wheat in the United States.</p>
<p>Moreover, only a fraction of the bids were for the lowest refund. At the first rung where significant quantities of wheat were involved, 6.75 Ecus, the EU was in danger of undercutting U.S. prices and risking a subsidy spat, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks tight for wheat this week. I think only the lowest bids (for subsidies) have much chance of going through,&quot; a trade analyst said.</p>
<p>The EU, fending off U.S. concerns over recently restored wheat export subsidies, has vowed not to undercut U.S. wheat prices on the world market even when helping exporters.</p>
<p>According to a U.S. envoy sent to Brussels partly to protest about subsidies this week, EU officials repeated the same pledge in talks on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A Commission official said on Wednesday the EU did not want to flood the market or start a subsidy war.</p>
<p>Analysts and officials said subsidies were a particularly sensitive issue in the talks, even though the EU has made no secret of the fact it believes Washington's complaints are linked to presidential electioneering.</p>
<p>French traders, however, were confident of getting slightly higher export refunds of around seven Ecus per tonne at the export tender on Thursday.</p>
<p>The waiting game for EU export refunds is particularly tense for traders who recently sold French wheat to Egypt at prices between $164 and $167 per tonne, analysts said.</p>
<p>Without more EU relief, they cannot -- on paper -- meet their commitments without taking some loss. But nor can the EU cover the full difference between the deal's price and higher prices in France without ignoring its pledge to Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now it is politically impossible to cover the Egypt sale,&quot; an EU export source said this week. But he added there was time for market conditions to improve before deliveries.</p>
<p>Giving the EU a little more elbow room on Thursday was a mixed world wheat market. U.S. wheat futures were slightly lower in electronic trading while French wheat for export was comfortably supported. A wider gap between U.S. prices and higher levels in Europe would justify more aid.</p>
<p>December wheat eased three cents on the Chicago Board of Trade's electronic Project A system to find bids at 4.24-1/2 a bushel, equivalent to some $169 per exported tonne in November.</p>
<p>French Rouen-delivered wheat for November, recently traded at 870 francs per tonne (about $178.50 when export charges are included), was bid five francs or a dollar firmer on Thursday.</p>
<p>Other factors were little changed since the last EU tender when 300,000 tonnes of wheat was sold at refunds up to six Ecus. The dollar was a shade firmer at 5.1765 francs. -- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
