<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109428" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: IG Metall sets ultimatum to employers on sick pay.</title>
<headline>IG Metall sets ultimatum to employers on sick pay.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Klaus Zwickel, head of Germany's powerful IG Metall engineering union, on Thursday set employers a deadline of October 23 for resolving a dispute over planned cuts in sick pay.</p>
<p>Zwickel, arriving at a Frankfurt hotel for talks with the engineering employers' association Gesamtmetall, told reporters that the union would stage a day of mass protest on October 24 if the deadline were not met.  </p>
<p>Mass walk-outs by the union last week forced Gesamtmetall leader Werner Stumpfe to make an about-turn in his policy over the implementation of a new law allowing firms to cut sick pay to 80 percent from 100 percent of the normal wage.</p>
<p>Having initially called on firms to adopt the new law as soon as possible, Stumpfe reversed his recommendation and told firms to hold off on reducing sick pay until talks with the union had been continued.</p>
<p>The union in return agreed to halt its protests.</p>
<p>Zwickel said he did not expect a quick decision in today's talks, adding that the discussions today were aimed more at working out the position of the two sides.</p>
<p>The union was determined that full sick pay should remain, he added.</p>
<p>Stumpfe was also sceptical about a deal being reached soon.</p>
<p>&quot;If IG Metall does not want to discuss an overall package, then the top-level talks are over,&quot; he said before the meeting with IG Metall.</p>
<p>Gesamtmetall said earlier that it wanted to discuss sick-pay cuts as part of an overall negotiation on other worker benefits such as holiday and Christmas pay within wider talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
