<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109454" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy new car registrations seen down in 1996 - CSP.</title>
<headline>Italy new car registrations seen down in 1996 - CSP.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian new car registrations for the whole of 1996 are forecast to show a 4.0 percent year-on-year fall, car sector forecasting body Centro Studi Promotor (CSP) said following poor September figures out on Thursday.</p>
<p>Total new car registrations in Italy for September fell 8.55 percent to 116,000 units, the Transport Ministry said.</p>
<p>CSP director Gian Primo Quagliano said he had revised down a forecast made at the beginning of this year for a 1996 total of 1.73 million new car registrations, little changed from 1995 levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we are expecting a four percent fall to 1.67 million vehicles,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;The market was in a phase of stagnation until July and showed a clear downward trend in August and September,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>August registrations fell a year-on-year 7.5 percent.</p>
<p>CSP's latest monthly report showed that 49 percent of car dealers expect sales to fall in the next three to four months, while 42 percent of those polled expected no change. Only nine percent saw sales increasing.</p>
<p>--Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
