<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109401" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's Endesa says no concrete plans electric cos.</title>
<headline>Spain's Endesa says no concrete plans electric cos.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish electrical group Endesa told the Spanish bourse supervisory authority CNMV that it had no concrete plans tied to electrical group Fecsa or with Sevillana.</p>
<p>In a brief statement, the CNMV said that &quot;in relation to the press report published today Endesa has told the CNMV that it has no concrete plans nor has it taken any decision to raise its share stake in Fecsa and Sevillana.  </p>
<p>Bourse activity centred on Thursday on the sector after financial daily Expansion published a report saying the Industry Ministry had proposed that state-owned Endesa take over the majority of Sevillana and 100 percent of the Catalan electrical group Fecsa.</p>
<p>In response to a Reuter query, a spokesman for the Industry Ministry said, &quot;The Ministry hasn't proposed anything to Endesa.&quot;</p>
<p>Separately, a local news agency reported that Spanish Industry Minister Josep Pique said on Thursday in Barcelona that there had been contacts made to explore Endesa raising its 39.4 percent stake in Sevillana de Electricidad.</p>
<p>Pique said &quot;there had been contact&quot; with banking group Banco Bilbao Vizcaya, which holds 6.7 percent of Sevillana's capital, Europapress reported.</p>
<p>Nonethless, Pique said &quot;there has been contact with other entities that form part of the capital not only of Endesa, but also of other electrical companies.&quot;</p>
<p>In any case, he said no decision had been taken and the ministry had not &quot;given specific instructions.&quot;</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
