<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109611" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian General News.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>The Federal Government's failure to adequately address accusations of racial intolerance threatens to weaken its confidence at a time when it has yet to secure any of its major policy agenda.  Although big issues such as Telstra, industrial relations refom and bringing down the Budget have regularly made the headlines, a significant series of reforms, including telecommunications deregulation, shipping and port reforms and the second round of financial deregulation are still waiting to be implemented.  Page 1.  </p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to the main findings of a special auditor's report into ATSIC, outlined by Aboriginal Affairs Minister John Herron yesterday, 374 of the 1,300 organisations funded by the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Commission were either in serious brach of their grant conditions or could potentially be found to be &quot;not fit and proper&quot;. Page 2.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Only a day after the Federal Government announced sweeping changes to its native title legislation, native title has been officially recognised for the first time on the Australian mainland after the New South Wales Government and the Dunghutti people reahed an agreement on a small area of vacant Crown land at Crescent Head on the State's north coast. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Ending talks with Taiwan over its entry to the World Trade Organisation yesterday, Australia won a package of concessions on more than 800 trade items, including the scrapping of a tariff which limits Australian beef sales and the lifting of a ban on manyhorticultural products, such as apples and stone fruits.  Page 4.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Native Title Tribunal has resolved the first native title agreement since the High Court's historic Mabo decision, in a deal that sees the New South Wales Government paying an initial compensation package of A$738,000 to the Dunghutti people of Crescet Head on the New South Wales north coast.  The Dunghutti people have been recognised as native title holders to the Crown land at the centre of the claim and have sold it back to the the Government for housing.  Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Helping to launch the election campaign of the Australians Against Further Immigration for the Lindsay by-election yesterday, Independent MP Graeme Campbell blamed excessive Asian immigration for a tuberculosis outbreak at Melbourne's Dandenong Hospital, here about 150 nurses have tested positive for exposure to TB.  AAFI is advocating a complete stop to all immigration for at least five years and after that zero net immigration.  Page 1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Defence Minister Ian McLachlan has rejected cuts of 2000 to 3000 troops from the regular army, a key proposal of the Army 21 reform plan.  However, McLachlan and defence force chiefs are understood to be close to an announcement on the future of the army,which includes a new unit structure, a bigger combat force, a more effective general reserve and equipment purchases of up to A$5 billion.  Page 1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Although Civil Aviation Safety Authority board members made no move to respond to calls by Transport Minister John Sharp to resign, the CASA responded to the damning report on the Seaview air disaster by grounding the Sydney-based airline KentiaLink, which is associated with former Seaview operator John Green, and suspending a maintenance company at Coffs Harbour associated with Green and two CASA employees the report named as &quot;lacking diligence&quot;.  Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD  </p>
<p>Tobacco retailers and manufacturers warned yesterday that they could be forced to sell tobacco only in unmarked packaging or keep it under the counter after a landmark ruling in the New South Wales Supreme Court ruled that the inside of a Sydney tobacco store was a public place, where under current legislation tobacco advertising is not permitted.  The ruling followed a crackdown by the Health Department on small retailers under the Tobacco Advertising Prohibition and Regulation Act. Page 1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Although controversial Independent MP Pauline Hanson was unable to attend the Australians Against Further Immigration party's campaign launch for the Lindsay by-election yesterday, fellow Independent MP Graeme Campbell gave the keynote speech, in which heblamed migrants for driving up unemployment and spreading diseases such as hepatitis and tuberculosis. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Dunghutti people of Kempsey, New South Wales, yesterday won the first successful native title land claim on mainland Australia, after State Lands Minister Kim Yeadon signed an agreement with Aboriginal elder Mary-Lou Buck recognising native title over12.4 hectares at Crescent Head.  Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Facing his third Senate censure motion since becoming a Minister, Aboriginal Affairs Minister John Herron yesterday tried to deflect criticism of how he managed his portfolio by revealing details of a Government-ordered audit into ATSIC, claiming the audit had so far found that 19 per cent of all organisations funded by ATSIC were in serious breach of grant conditions. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE  </p>
<p>Admitting that the Victorian Government's Tuberculosis Advisory Committee had failed to tell them that more than 150 nurses at Dandenong Hospital had tested positive to TB exposure, State Health Department officials have ordered an urgent review of hospitl screening procedures for tuberculosis. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian Education Minister Phil Gude is soon expected to announce an offer of voluntary redundancies for 600 of the State's teachers as part of a bid to make up for a A$60 million budget overrun.  About 200 administrative staff jobs are also expected togo and small schools will be urged to merge or close.  </p>
<p>Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following a meeting of 500 power workers, nurses and orderlies at Morwell yesterday, unions have threatened to strike for 24 hours if Victorian Health Minister Rob Knowles fails to respond within seven days to calls for the reinstatement of intensive carebeds and other critical services to the La Trobe Valley region. Page A1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Victorian police have formed a taskforce consisting of a specialist squad of 40 detectives from the police force's drug and Asian squads as well as district detectives and covert intelligence operatives to tackle Melbourne's heroin trade, which police admt is out of control.  The taskforce is expected to begin operations near the end of the month and will focus on about 10 known heroin dealers.  Page A1.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
