<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109604" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Cr Lyonnais needs even more cash - chairman.</title>
<headline>Cr Lyonnais needs even more cash - chairman.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Troubled state-owned French bank Credit Lyonnais will need a bigger than expected injection of government cash, chairman Jean Peyrelevade told Britain's Financial Times.</p>
<p>Peyrelevade told the newspaper in an interview that the bank would need a cash injection of 12 billion francs to strengthen its balance sheet. Last week he said eight to nine billion francs would be needed.  </p>
<p>Peyrelevade said the cash injection would help prepare the bank for privatisation or a trade sale to international investors.</p>
<p>But he said this would not occur until mid-1998 at the earliest -- later than expected. He had previously said the sell-off might take place within 18 months.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the bigger cash injection would help the bank cover losses it will have to book on the sale of Credit Lyonnais's European banking network.</p>
<p>Peyrelevade also warned there would be additional provisions for rationalising the domestic retail business.  </p>
<p>Provisions of 1.3 billion francs in the first half would cover two-thirds of rationalisation costs, but a further charge would be required in the second half. This would cover cost cutting until 1998, Peyrelevade said in the interview.</p>
<p>About 200 domestic branches -- some 10 percent of the network -- would be closed by the end of 1998 and there would be a further 5,000 job losses. Peyrelevade said he aimed to cut costs by between one percent and two percent a year.</p>
<p>The bigger cash injection would raise the bank's tier-one capital ratio to six percent from 4.5 percent. Last week Peyrelevade said he wanted to raise the ratio to 5.5 percent. --London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
