<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109600" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Liberty forms new subsidiary with Hermes.</title>
<headline>Liberty forms new subsidiary with Hermes.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liberty International Holdings Plc said on Thursday it had formed a strategic alliance with Hermes Investment Management Limited, creating a new subsidiary called Hermes Liberty International Pensions Ltd (HLIP).</p>
<p>This will offer &quot;specialised investment services to the UK pensions industry, with Hermes acting as fund manager&quot;, Liberty and Hermes said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>The BT Pension Scheme, which owns Hermes, will transfer 1.5 billion stg of its assets into new funds offered by HLIP, it added.  </p>
<p>&quot;Initially HLIP will offer a UK index tracking fund and an actively enhanced UK index fund...It is anticipated that HLIP will be operational by the second quarter of 1997 once regulatory approvals have been obtained,&quot; the groups said.</p>
<p>The products on offer would be particularly suitable for occupational pension schemes and represent specific areas of specialisation for Hermes, one of the UK's largest pension fund management groups, they added.</p>
<p>BT Pension Scheme's transfer of assets is &quot;believed to be the largest single premium ever written in the UK pensions industry&quot;, Liberty and Hermes said.  </p>
<p>A new specialist pensions company called Liberty International Pensions Ltd is also being established. BT Pension Scheme will pay 5.0 million stg for 10 percent of the equity while Liberty International Holdings will retain the balance of the initial capital of 50 million stg.</p>
<p>The company will meet the specific needs of money purchase pension schemes and offer personal pensions to retail customers.</p>
<p>Sir James Spooner, the chairman of BT Pension Scheme, said its investment in a Hermes Liberty International Pensions policy represented no effective change in the way the assets were being managed or their security.  </p>
<p>Liberty International Pensions will be launched later this year once it has received Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) authorisation, which is expected shortly, the groups said.</p>
<p>The new company will target visitors to Liberty International's regional shopping centres, which are held through its 72 percent owned subsidiary Capital Shopping Centres . These have more than 150 million customer visits a year, Liberty said.</p>
<p>Liberty International is the international subsidiary of South African life insurance company Liberty Life Association of Africa.</p>
<p>-- Alexander Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7719</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
