<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109711" id="root" date="1996-10-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China securities chief praises stock markets.</title>
<headline>China securities chief praises stock markets.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's top securities policy maker has re-affirmed support for the nation's fledging stock markets, saying they are beneficial to economic development, the China Securities newspaper said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Zhou Zhengqing, chairman of the policy-making Securities Commission under the State Council, China's cabinet, said the stock markets helped the economy in a variety of ways, including giving firms a means of raising funds.</p>
<p>&quot;More than six years of experience prove that the securities market can undoubtedly serve the socialist market economy,&quot; Zhou was quoted by the newspaper as saying. &quot;It is necessary to further recognise this and let the markets play their role.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the speech was a key indication of Beijing's support for the stock markets, which until earlier this year were regularly referred to as being in an experimental stage.</p>
<p>Authorities have taken a series of measures this year to boost the markets in Shanghai and Shenzhen, particularly to make them more competitive in the run-up to the Chinese takeover of Hong Kong in July, 1997, they said.</p>
<p>The policy support has triggered a bull run on Chinese domestic A share markets. The Shanghai A index is up more than 60 percent since April while the Shenzhen market has surged more than 150 percent.</p>
<p>Zhou said the most important function of the securities markets was to give Chinese firms a means to raise money.</p>
<p>By end-July this year, stock listings had enabled the firms to raise 120 billion yuan (US$14.5 billion), Zhou said.</p>
<p>About half of the amount, 60 billion yuan, was raised in foreign currency through Hong Kong-listed H shares and foreign-exchange B shares listed on domestic markets, he said.</p>
<p>The stock market has helped Chinese companies to improve their debt-equity ratio, Zhou said.</p>
<p>Listed companies as a whole have performed better than state-run enterprises with a debt-equity ratio of less than 50 percent and only 4.8 percent of them have been loss-making.</p>
<p>Zhou did not give comparative figures but earlier official figures showed that China's state-run enterprises as a whole had a debt-equity ratio of 85 percent and more than half of all state firms were loss-making.</p>
<p>The stock market also helps key Chinese firms in energy, transportation, raw materials and high technology areas to develop more effectively, Zhou said. It helps attract foreign investment and promote knowledge of finance among China's citizens, he added.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Shanghai's A share index hit another 1996 high of 946.122 points in the morning session, mainly due to Zhou's speech, analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
