<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109931" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-ENGLISH CLUBS TAUNTED BY CASTAIGNEDE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ENGLISH CLUBS TAUNTED BY CASTAIGNEDE.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>French international Thomas Castaignede has thrown down a challenge to England's top sides as they prepare to put some expensive reputations on the line in this season's expanded European Cup.</p>
<p>English clubs sat out last year's inaugural venture and are still arguing over the future format of a competition which is designed to match the impressive Super 12 tournament in the southern hemisphere.</p>
<p>But Toulouse fly-half Casteignede, whose side will be defending the title they won in Cardiff in January last year, is looking forward to watching how the English clubs tackle their new environment.</p>
<p>&quot;To win the European Cup a second time will be fine. To do so by beating the English is even better,&quot; said Castaignede.</p>
<p>&quot;They look down on the rest of us...you need to beg to get anything, as the Five Nations championship fuss showed. I hope they resent missing the first European Cup. Now it's up to them to prove they deserve to win it.&quot;</p>
<p>Toulouse sit out the opening weekend of matches, starting their campaign in Milan on Wednesday but Castaignede revealed this week that the champions have based their entire season's planning around the tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;Toulouse have prepared especially for it, the more so as we know that the level of play is going to be higher. Last season we were not so much surprised technically as physically, even though all the matches were very clean which came as a real surprise.</p>
<p>&quot;This year, we feel it may be a little bit harder in every sense.&quot;</p>
<p>Twenty teams from six countries will be involved, with Toulouse's pool D looking the most competitive. Cardiff, Milan, Munster and Wasps are all tough opponents boasting numerous internationals.</p>
<p>Wasps, who take on Cardiff on Sunday, will welcome back Va'aiga Tuigamala from injury and Toulouse coach Guy Noves is already expecting a tough visit to London later this month.</p>
<p>&quot;Wasps are a rigorous side, very precise and efficient. They will play at home and it's going to be hard,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His Wasps counterpart Rob Smith believes the tournament will determine just how good England's leading clubs are against the best in Europe.</p>
<p>Injuries are already a serious problem for some teams. Brive, who host Welsh champions Neath, must do without David Venditti, Romuald Paillat, Loic Van der Linden, Gilles Duclos and above all flyhalf Christophe Lamaison, who are all injured.</p>
<p>&quot;It is all the more unfortunate as we absolutely need to win this first match,&quot; said Brive coach, former international prop Laurent Seigne. The two sides shared a bitter encounter seven years ago which ended at half-time when Neath, claiming Brive intimidation and weak refereeing, walked off in protest.</p>
<p>Dax, who start their campaign in Italy against Benetton Treviso, are in no doubt about the huge potential of European club rugby.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll be a fine opportunity to test the real potential of our team,&quot; said captain Olivier Roumat.</p>
<p>&quot;This way, our young players will be allowed to make comparisons and realise the amount of work they still need to reach the top.&quot;</p>
<p>English champions Bath, winners of 16 major domestic titles since 1984, have made their intentions clear by dropping England wing Jon Sleightholme and Scottish forwards Dave Hilton and Eric Peters for their home game against Edinburgh.</p>
<p>There should also be no shortage of incentive for the 24 sides playing in the unheralded and unsponsored European Conference, running alongside the main tournament.</p>
<p>France's Agen, who can call on Abdel Benazzi and Philippe Benetton, are among those hopeful of playing a more pivotal role in next year's European action, whatever form that may take.</p>
<p>&quot;We must go all the way to the final as the European competitions will be more important next season and may even become a league,&quot; said former national coach Daniel Dubroca, now with Agen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
