<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="109901" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-HOLDERS SCOTLAND STUNNED BY INDIA.</title>
<headline>GOLF-HOLDERS SCOTLAND STUNNED BY INDIA.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>ST ANDREWS, Scotland 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 1,000-1 outsiders India inflicted a shock 2-1 defeat on holders Scotland as the Scots surrendered their Alfred Dunhill Cup title on Friday.</p>
<p>World number two Colin Montgomerie, crowned European number one last Sunday for the fourth year in succession, lost his second match in two days, this time to a player ranked 696th in the world.</p>
<p>Gaurav Ghei beat him 78-79 on the windblown Old Course at St Andrews, and with Jeev Singh, also ranked 696th, beating Andrew Coltart on the first hole of a playoff, the Indians kept alive their outside chance of advancing to Sunday's playoffs.</p>
<p>They must beat Sweden 3-0 in Saturday's final round robin group match to win their group and reach the semifinals.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel great. We got used to the cold and windy weather and we fought well,&quot; Singh said.</p>
<p>&quot;Colin did not have a very good day, and when that happens to a good player anything is possible,&quot; Ghei, the Asian Masters champion, said. &quot;I kept the pressure on him.&quot;</p>
<p>Montgomerie's round began to go wrong at the sixth when his ball hit a rake and bounded into a bunker up against the lip. He took a triple-bogey seven to fall behind and never fully recovered.</p>
<p>&quot;Ghei played very well and holed out well. When he birdied the first, I knew I was in a match,&quot; said Montgomerie, who lost to Swede Jarmo Sandelin on Thursday.</p>
<p>Scotland's defeat brought back the painful memory of their loss to another unfancied team, Paraguay, in the 1993 event.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST ANDREWS, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
