<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110074" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Intel shares said up on rising estimates.</title>
<headline>Intel shares said up on rising estimates.</headline>
<dateline>PALO ALTO, Calif. 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intel Corp shares closed up 5-1/2 to 105-3/8 amid speculation that the world's biggest chip maker will report better-than-expected earnings on Monday.</p>
<p>The stock was the third most active in U.S. markets on trading of 11.1 million shares.</p>
<p>No on at Intel could be reached for comment.  </p>
<p>The company is scheduled to report its earnings after the close of the market on Monday. Wall Street analysts expect Intel to earn $1.25 a share, according to a recent survey by First Call. In recent days, however, some analysts have said Intel could easily surpass that.</p>
<p>&quot;Business is extremely good,&quot; said Mark Edelstone, an analyst at Prudential Securities Research in San Francisco. Intel's gross margins -- the amount of money left over from revenues when cost of goods are subtracted -- clearly improved in the third quarter, which should boost earnings beyond the strong sales, Edelstone said.  </p>
<p>John Marren, an analyst at Morgan Stanley raised his rating on Intel to &quot;strong buy&quot; from &quot;outperform&quot; on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident in Intel's ability to meet or exceed our new EPS estimate of $1.31,&quot; Marren wrote in a research report released today. He wasn't immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Marren also expects two new line of microprocessors, the central computing chip in a PC, to &quot;provide the stimulus for a year of tremendous growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Intel's stock could reach $130 in the next 12 month, Marren said.</p>
<p>&quot;People know that the business is turning up, personal computer sales are rising,&quot; said Tom Kurlak, an analyst at Merrill Lynch in New York. &quot;People want to be in this stock group.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALO ALTO, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
