<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110266" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products-gas oil, some fuel up, others not.</title>
<headline>Med oil products-gas oil, some fuel up, others not.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were mixed on Friday, with some gainers and others losers.</p>
<p>Gasoline was steady, failing to follow the fall in NYMEX futures or the rebound in NWE physical prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The Med is fundamentally a weaker market...Demand is very thin, except perhaps for higher octane grades,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Naphtha also held steady despite the bearish tone created by the reopening of the Skikda terminal.</p>
<p>Traders said one delayed cargo was headed for Brazil, while two others in the hands of a trading house were earmarked for the U.S.  </p>
<p>Traders pegged the market at around cif quotes high +$3/$4 a tonne cif Med.</p>
<p>Gas oil rose about $2.00 in line with Nov IPE futures, but most trade in the Mediterranean was on floating prices.</p>
<p>Heating oil was still under some pressure, partly due to thin activity on both sides, but diesel premiums rose sharply after a cargo was talked above Nov IPE +$30 cif France.</p>
<p>A Russian cargo was sold at quotes high +75 cents cif Genoa.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel took sustenance from Romanian demand which lurks in the background as a pillar of support. A second trade was talked, but not confirmed.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's very hard to pin down exactly what is happening,&quot; said one trader at a major. Prices in the Med were assessed marginally under $120 fob Med, but this could well be broken next week.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cracked cargoes were slightly weaker with a late deal done out of Scandinavia on a 50:50 fixed/floating basis, fixed at $132 cif NWE cif Milazzo. The trade was the fourth purchase by the main Med buyer at increasingly lower numbers.</p>
<p>But, despite the softer prices, most traders said the market was fundamentally still firm.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
