<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110270" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dated Brent edges down on difficult U.S. arbitrage.</title>
<headline>Dated Brent edges down on difficult U.S. arbitrage.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea values for most grades were steady on Friday in slim business, but benchmark Dated Brent edged lower again.</p>
<p>October 28-30 cargoes sold at Nov -5 and -6 cents after trading at parity on Thursday and +10 cents on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said a difficult arbitrage to the U.S. was keeping the pressure on Dated premiums but that the seller was again keen to take advantage of operational tolerance on a maximum Brent sale.</p>
<p>Five of six end-October Brent cargoes were kept voluntarily on Friday.  </p>
<p>CFD values for next week slipped about 10 cents to sell at Nov -9 cents.</p>
<p>Transatlantic traders were examining VLCC economics for U.S. Gulf sales but remained reluctant to commit, given a sub-Brent/WTI spread below $1.</p>
<p>Other North Sea grades were slow ahead of next week's November programmes, with most grades expected to be announced on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A couple each of October Oseberg and Ekofisk probably still had to find homes.  </p>
<p>Early November sales on Friday appeared limited to a pair of DUCs, done at 10-11 cent premiums over Brent.</p>
<p>Nigerian prices remained difficult to pin down ahead of next week's NNPC term pricing release.</p>
<p>Contract holders were keen to keep rising differentials under wraps but Forcados was indicated at around Dated Brent +80 cents, Bonny Light at +70 cents.</p>
<p>Med Urals values were helped by the prospect of maintenance at Novorossiisk and assessed closer to Brent -60 cents cif Med than -70 cents.</p>
<p>--Richard Mably, London newsroom +44 171 542 8060</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
