<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110386" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Prempharm rises on Adcock merger.</title>
<headline>Prempharm rises on Adcock merger.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Premier Pharmaceutical Company Ltd shares rose on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange on Friday on news that it had been bought by competitor Adcock Ingram.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts welcomed the news saying the merger of the two operations would provide the new company with the necessary critical mass in the pharmaceutical industry.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is taking well the idea of building a pharmaceutical giant,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>An analyst who declined to be identified said: &quot;I think they both needed (the deal) to sustain future earnings growth.&quot;</p>
<p>By the close Prempharm shares had jumped 80 cents or 4.17 percent to 24.80 after a volume of 38,300 shares valued at just over a million rand changed hands. Shares earlier touched a best level of 25 rand but had slipped on profit-taking, dealers said.</p>
<p>Adcock Ingram announced on Thursday it had bought 100 percent of the Prempharm Company with effect from May 1, 1996 -- thereby merging the two operations.</p>
<p>Analysts said Prempharm shareholders would stand to benefit more from the merger than Adcock shareholders.</p>
<p>&quot;It is positive in the longer term, those who will gain are Prempharm shareholders,&quot; said Melanie da Costa, pharmaceutical analyst at Investec Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect Adcock shares to trade sideways for a while,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Adcock shares ended the day 20 cents firmer at 19.40 rand in thin volume trade.</p>
<p>-- Charles Phahlane, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
