<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110319" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Yachting: Peter Campbell's Rhumblin Column.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Yachting: Peter Campbell's Rhumblin Column.</headline>
<text>
<p>By Peter Campbell*</p>
<p>A GLORIOUS MORNING IN HOBART</p>
<p>Although the Cruising Yacht Club of Australia revealed this week that Sydney-to-Hobart sponsors Telstra have upped the ante to $300,000 for the first yacht to break Kialoa's 21-year-old race record, the list of overseas challengers is far from clear.</p>
<p>Applications for entry into the 630-nautical mile blue water classic do not close until November 1, with final entries a month later, and to date only a dozen or so yachts have applied.</p>
<p>It now seems that LARRY ELLISON, boss of the huge Oracle computer software company in the U.S., will not be bringing his ILC maxi, Sayonara, back to Australia in a bid to repeat last year's line honours win.</p>
<p>In ELLISON's place, however, will be another computer company chief, HASSO PLATTNER, co-founder of Germany's SAP. PLATTNER's record-breaking 82-footer, Fancourt's Morning Glory, is on its way by ship from San Francisco to New Zealand to have a new mast stepped.</p>
<p>Morning Glory is a REICHEL/PUGH design and was built in Sydney early last year by JOHN McCONAGHY, who has built our recent America's Cup challengers as well as many ocean racers.</p>
<p>In her first major race, Morning Glory took line honours in record time and was first on International Measurement System (IMS) in the 1995 Cape Town to Rio Race.</p>
<p>She looked the major threat to the supremacy of Sayonara among the maxi boats at the recent Kenwood Cup in Hawaii until she broke her mast in the fourth race.</p>
<p>With the mast repaired she contested the Big Boat Series in San Francisco, but again snapped the top section of her rig. Hence a brand a new mast will be waiting for her in New Zealand.</p>
<p>- - - - - - -</p>
<p>RECORD PRIZE MONEY FOR WEST COASTER</p>
<p>The Ocean Racing Club of Victoria (ORCV) has announced that a prize of $25,000 will paid to the first boat to finish this year's 25th Melbourne-to-Hobart race around Tasmania's west coast -- if it breaks the 470-nautical mile race record.</p>
<p>The ORCV is predicting a fleet of some 60 yachts to compete in this anniversary regatta, and the appropriate prize money has been put up by a group of Melbourne companies.</p>
<p>In addition, Sir DONALD TRESCOWTHICK, chairman of the Harris/Scarfe group and one of the early supporters of the West Coaster race, has also put up $25,000 for the handicap winners and placegetters.</p>
<p>The race record is held by the Steinmann-52, Flying Colours, which roared home before a 60 knot gale in the 1992 race, at times reaching speeds of 26 knots off southern Tasmania.</p>
<p>Flying Colours overtook Animal Farm just a few miles from the Derwent Sailing Squadron's finish line, lowering the record by five minutes to set a new time of 2 days 15 minutes 7 seconds.</p>
<p>- - - - - - -</p>
<p>CORPORATE VISITORS TAKE TO THE HARBOUR</p>
<p>Sydney Harbour yacht charter company East Sail has a huge exercise on its hands over the next four days, hosting more than 1,200 international visitors for sailing days on the harbour.</p>
<p>The visitors are all high achievers from the American computer giant, Sun Micro Systems, and come from countries such as the U.S., Venezuela, China, South Korea and several European countries.</p>
<p>Tour organisers offered the sailing experience as a unique opportunity to see Sydney from the water while at the same time injecting a competitive element in a team building excercise.</p>
<p>- - - - - - -</p>
<p>AN EPIC VENTURE AT SEA</p>
<p>When ROD SKELLETT bought the remarkably successful ROBERT HICKS-designed 26-footer, Joint Venture, and changed the name to Epic Venture, he didn t realise how prophetic the name would be.</p>
<p>Last weekend SKELLETT, who is head of the equity derivatives division of Ord Minnett, joined the offshore fleet for Royal Sydney Yacht Squadron's Spring Offshore Regatta.</p>
<p>After placing second in the Friday night race from Sydney to Bird Island and back to Pittwater, and winning the second race, the little sloop was looking well-placed in the third race when the crew's epic venture began.</p>
<p>Off Long Reef, as she beat to windward in a 20 knot nor'easter, the yacht smashed into a submerged object, ripping off the keel.</p>
<p>&quot;We capsized in seconds, with the boat turning turtle, leaving the four of us floundering in the water,&quot; Skellett recalled this week.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't have time to grab a flare and we were in the water for around 30 minutes, hanging on to the upturned hull, until another competing yacht, Shoshana, saw our plight and picked us up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Epic Venture was towed ashore by the Water Police but during the beaching process the rig was broken and the hull damaged beyond repair. And so ends the remarkable sailing career of Australia's smallest IMS racing yacht.</p>
<p>Nor was it a good sailing weekend for SKELLETT's boss at Ord Minnett, CHRIS GORMAN, who was sailing with jeweller JULIAN FARREN-PRICE aboard Invincible when she was dismasted off North Head.</p>
<p>Apart from losing the rig, the outcome was less dramatic.</p>
<p>- - - - - -</p>
<p>ON THE RAZOR'S EDGE</p>
<p>Middle Harbour yachtsman RAY STONE had a resounding win with his new Mount Gay 30, Razor's Edge, in the Performance Handicap division of last weekend's race to Bird Island.</p>
<p>The 30-footer, designed by SCOTT JUTSON, outsailed most of the 40-footers and finished only 21 minutes astern of Kenwood Cup team yacht Quest, which took out the IMS handicap.</p>
<p>&quot;The boat performs brilliantly. In a breeze of 18-20 knots we have been hitting speeds of 17 knots on a square run,&quot; says the enthusiastic STONE, who previously skippered the IMS 36-footer Kings Cross-Sydney with great success.</p>
<p>STONE is planning a strong campaign this summer, including the Bruce &amp; Walsh Regatta in late November and the Telstra Cup offshore regatta in December, in which he hopes other Mount Gay 30s will compete.</p>
<p>Among them will be a new JUTSON-designed boat ordered by Dr JIM HUNT of the United States, who is flying out with his crew to contest the Telstra Cup before shipping the yacht back to the States.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SAILOR'S DRINK BACKS 18-FOOTER</p>
<p>Rum has historically been the sailor's drink and one of the most popular mixers favoured by Aussie yachtsmen is a Dark &amp; Stormy, a combination of Bundaberg dark rum and Bundaberg ginger beer.</p>
<p>The liquid for the launching toasts was obvious yesterday when former world champion 18-footer sailor and ocean racing yachtsman MICHAEL SPIES unveiled his new sponsors for the Grand Prix Circuit -- Bundaberg Rum/Dark &amp; Stormy.</p>
<p>The skiff is not new, but is a totally refurbished version of the JULIAN BETHWAITE-designed boat which SPIES campaigned last year as Winfield Racing.</p>
<p>Obviously that sponsorship had to come to an end.</p>
<p>SPIES' crew this summer will include former 12-foot skiff sailor MICHAEL SHASIN and the champion young sailor EUAN McNICOL, a graduate of the Cruising Yacht Club of Australia's (CYCA) Youth Sailing Academy.</p>
<p>The boat will be registered with the Sydney Flying Squadron and also with the CYCA -- probably the first skiff to be listed on its register along with maxi ocean racing yachts such as Brindabella.</p>
<p>SPIES' summer sailing will also include some offshore racing aboard Skilled 2KY, the JUTSON NSX-36 owned by BOB MULKEARNS which he will skipper the yacht in the Telstra Sydney-to-Hobart -- his 20th race to Hobart.</p>
<p>*Peter Campbell is editor of Offshore Yachting magazine</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
