<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110453" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian experts barred from freighter crash site.</title>
<headline>Russian experts barred from freighter crash site.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian authorities have prevented Russian investigators from working at the site where a Russian Antonov-124 freighter crashed near Turin last Tuesday, an aviation official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Russian experts were denied access to the debris of the aircraft and they could not take pictures or work with documents because the Turin prosecution objected,&quot; said an official of the Interstate Aviation Committee who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>He told Reuters that Italian police had removed all documents from the plane.</p>
<p>&quot;Our experts have not seen them yet but time has been lost and it will make the investigation more difficult,&quot; the official added.</p>
<p>The head of the Russian team, Mikhail Tereshenko, sent a letter on Friday to Russian aviation organisations and to the Foreign Ministry to ask for their help in the case.</p>
<p>The giant An-124 crashed on Tuesday near Turin airport after its crew failed in their first landing attempt.</p>
<p>Earlier this week a chief executive of Aeroflot -Russian International Airlines, Marshal Evgeny Shaposhnikov, called the crash inexplicable.</p>
<p>&quot;The crew (of the plane) met an inexplicable situation and it is not known why they could not get out of it. All the pilots were very experienced,&quot; Shaposhnikov said.</p>
<p>The cargo jet had two crews of six pilots each on board and a further 11 officials from Ayaks cargo company which owned the plane. Aeroflot provided its crews to Ayaks, which owns an additional An-124 freighter but does not have the right to operate it.</p>
<p>The Russian pilot and co-pilot were killed and two villagers died when they were buried in rubble after the plane sliced into the village of San Francesco al Campo on a flight from Moscow.</p>
<p>--Viktor Anoshkin, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 85 20</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
