<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110400" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius leading stocks and volume continue fall.</title>
<headline>Mauritius leading stocks and volume continue fall.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks of leading companies continued to fall on the Mauritian bourse on Friday with the market index Semdex losing 2.33 points to 311.54, reflecting a drop in prices of several listed shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>Transactions totalled 7.61 million rupees on 527,642 shares from 9.07 million rupees on 561,316 shares on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Mauritian bourse trades on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays. The Semdex drop reflected a fall in leading share prices as well as those of several other listed companies.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are keeping their wait and see attitude and are hesitant to buy unless things clear up on the political front, especially after the EIU report. There is no price support to counteract those who are selling,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Last week, the EIU (Economist Intelligence Unit) painted a subdued picture for the Mauritian economic future with growth forecast of 4.0 percent in 1997 from 5.0 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>The EIU report criticised the Mauritian government that came into power last December, for losing &quot;opportunities to introduce a range of solid measures to revive economic growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Mauritius Commercial Bank was unchanged at 70 rupees on 31,985 shares and State Bank of Mauritius remained stable at 8.40 rupees on 21,300 shares. Construction company Gamma Civic lost 20 cents to 16.50 rupees on 5,950 shares and Mauritius Oil Refineries fell by 20 cents to 9.30 rupees on 6,400 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
