<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110500" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Explosions hit Moslem housing in northern Bosnia.</title>
<headline>Explosions hit Moslem housing in northern Bosnia.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>International officials expressed grave concern on Friday after explosions destroyed a number of houses in Serb-held parts of northern Bosnia.</p>
<p>The International Police Task Force, charged with helping to implement the Bosnian peace process, said the blasts occurred on Thursday in the demilitarised Zone of Separation along the old wartime frontline.</p>
<p>There were no reports of casualties, but the incidents were seen as major setback in efforts to resettle Moslems in their homes in Serb-held areas.</p>
<p>United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees spokesman Kris Janowski said one of the houses destroyed was being rebuilt by his agency as part of an agreement signed with the Bosnian Serb authorities. &quot;We are quite concerned about it. It is a threat to our agreement and the return (of Moslems) to the Zone of Separation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Janowski said Serb propaganda had spoken of Moslems &quot;occupying&quot; Serb villages in the area. &quot;It's not a huge jump to the conclusion that it was a way of disinviting the Moslems to that area,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>In the first incident, four explosions destroyed six houses in the abandoned village of Mumbasic, smashing windows in a nearby inhabited village, whose angry inhabitants staged a protest threatening retaliation against the Serbs.</p>
<p>An IPTF spokesman said the crowd had later dispersed and the IPTF was carrying out an investigation.</p>
<p>In the second incident a house being rebuilt by UNHCR in the village of Stanic Rijeka was hit by an explosion, but it occurred after workmen had left the site for the night.</p>
<p>Earlier, five explosions were reported at the village of Kardoni, near the Serb-held town of Zvornik, but there was no immediate explanation for this incident.</p>
<p>The blasts come at a time of tension in northern Bosnia, with Moslems moving into homes in some villages in Serb-held territory.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serb police, in a joint patrol of the village of Dugi Dio with the IPTF and NATO peacekeeping troops on Wednesday, found two rifles, two hand grenades and some ammunition in the house of a Moslem man.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
