<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110741" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Unilever unit plans $160 mln Asian expansion.</title>
<headline>Unilever unit plans $160 mln Asian expansion.</headline>
<byline>Angela Tan</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>DiverseyLever, a global unit of Anglo-Dutch consumer products giant Unilever Plc, plans further inroads in Asia, regional director Ray Jones said on Friday.</p>
<p>Jones told Reuters in an interview that DiverseyLever, which provides cleaning products and services, would spend $160 million in Asia-Pacific over the next five years to upgrade facilities, and on investments in new areas and people.</p>
<p>&quot;We have budgeted $10 million for next year in refurbishing new factories,&quot; Jones said, adding that amount was a net sum after deducting proceeds from sales of factories.</p>
<p>He said the company, which is fast becoming a top performer among Unilever's business units, invested in new premises in India and the Philippines.</p>
<p>It was also upgrading plants in Thailand and Japan as well as investing in a new facility in Indonesia.</p>
<p>Jones said India, China and Indonesia have the greatest growth potential for the company in Asia.</p>
<p>Providing cleaning services to the hotel sector as well as food processing are the company's two core business.</p>
<p>The company is involved in the laundry business for major hotels in the region as well as cleaning services for commercial buildings, Jones said.</p>
<p>He said the contribution from this sector is expected to grow at an average 20 percent a year in Asia.</p>
<p>On the group's food processing business, Jones said it is expected to grow at 15 percent a year. Currently, food contributes about 45 percent of its turnover in Asia Pacific.</p>
<p>In India and China, the group plans to use the network and expertise of its respective joint-venture partners to make further inroads into these vast markets, Jones said.</p>
<p>The company is seeking opportunities in Vietnam.</p>
<p>Jones said it was possible to have a wholly-owned company in Vietnam but the company was considering a joint venture because &quot;doing business would be much better&quot;. It already has  a distributor in Vietnam.</p>
<p>DiverseyLever was formed after the merger in April of Diversey and Lever Industrial International, Unilever's industrial and institutional cleaning business group.</p>
<p>It has an annual turnover of US$2 billion and is the world's second largest producer of cleaning and hygiene products and services.</p>
<p>Jones said the company was still in the process of streamlining its operations after the merger. This included merging the factories in Thailand and the Philippines as well as reducing third party manufacturing.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a plan in Asia Pacific to harmonise all our business units by August 1997,&quot; Jones said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
