<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110713" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian crudes edge back, Oman trades, Tapis rises.</title>
<headline>Asian crudes edge back, Oman trades, Tapis rises.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices in Asia were slightly weaker on Friday with a few more cargos of Oman being mopped up, although the Tapis premium climbed further.</p>
<p>Traders said they added a further three Oman sales to their tally for November trading but at prices no higher than MPM plus one cent.</p>
<p>They said a Chinese state trader sold one cargo to a Thai refinery at MPM flat and a second to a Singapore refiner at half a cent premium to MPM.</p>
<p>A third Oman was was traded between majors at MPM plus one cent, they said.  </p>
<p>Traders estimated that two or three cargos of Oman were still left on the November shelf -- lagging other Gulf grades which are mostly sold with the exception of a Lower Zakum and possibly a Murban.</p>
<p>A 300,000 barrel cargo of early November Tapis was sold fob to a Japanese trader for supplying into Burma on a delivered basis.</p>
<p>The premium reached $1.40, surpassing the previous November deal into Korea by 20 cents. But traders said the price alone was not necessarily a strong indication of the price because of the risk premium being associated with trading into Burma.  </p>
<p>Taiwan decided not to opt out of its term contract purchases for West African grades from Elf, despite the wide Brent/Dubai.</p>
<p>CPC will take two November VLCCs, shared three parts Forcados, one part Angolan Palance in one, and three Forcados and one Odudu in the second, traders said.</p>
<p>Paper Tapis also retreated. November was assessed at $24.20/$24.50, down 15 cents. A Wall Street trader and a trader exchanged December paper at $23.85.</p>
<p>Traders said Minas has traded as high as a premium of 24 cents above the ICP after China bought 500,000 barrels from two equity producers between 21 and 24 cents over.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
