<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110796" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish decree sets out bank sell-off plan.</title>
<headline>Turkish decree sets out bank sell-off plan.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Turkish government paved the way for the privatisation of state-owned Etibank on Friday with the publication of a decree in the Official Gazette setting out a plan to divide the bank into three.</p>
<p>Anatolian news agency said the decree provided for the creation of two new banks, to be known as Anadolu Bank and Denizbank, alongside part of the existing Etibank.</p>
<p>The privatisation of Etibank had been targeted by the government as a key aspect of its revenue-raising plans.  </p>
<p>The publication of the decree indicated the government had answered President Suleyman Demirel's concerns about certain aspects of the privatisation, including the creation of the two new banks, according to privatisation sources.</p>
<p>Turkey's decade-old privatisation programme has been stalled repeatedly by legal challenges and political opposition.</p>
<p>The three-month old coalition government of Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan has targeted privatisation as vital to a planned $10 billion resource package. Turkey is in desperate need of fresh revenues to combat gaping deficits.</p>
<p>The sell-off programme has so far raised around $3.1 billion, with annual revenues repeatedly well below government targets, analysts say.</p>
<p>Etibank, expected by some analysts to raise around $100-150 million, was given priority by Erbakan ahead of other major privatisation projects.</p>
<p>-- Ankara Newsroom, +90-312-446 2940</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
