<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110736" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia reacts negatively to Nobel peace prize.</title>
<headline>Indonesia reacts negatively to Nobel peace prize.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia reacted negatively on Friday to the award of the 1996 Nobel Peace Prize to two men born in the troubled territory of East Timor, saying that one of them was a &quot;political opportunist&quot; and avoiding comment on the other.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the right of the committee with its own criteria to award the Nobel Peace Prize. However we regret that a political opportunist has received the prize,&quot; Foreign Ministry spokesman Ghaffar Fadyl told Reuters, referring to East Timor independence movement leader Jose Ramos-Horta.  </p>
<p>The Nobel Committee said Ramos-Horta and East Timor Bishop Carlos Belo were jointly awarded the prize for their work towards a just and peaceful solution to the conflict in East Timor. The territory was annexed by Indonesia 20 years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not know the basis on which they have given the prize,&quot; Fadyl said, declining to comment on Belo's award.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quite a surprise and quite regrettable that such a reputable institution has decided to give this prize to a person like Ramos-Horta, who has quite clearly been involved in the manipulation of the people of East Timor for his own interests,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;He has incited the people of East Timor to separate from the unitary Republic of Indonesia.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
