<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110808" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Controversial study links abortion, cancer.</title>
<headline>Controversial study links abortion, cancer.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Wulfhorst</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A study released on Friday of existing research showed that abortion increases a woman's risk of developing breast cancer by one-third, sparking controversy among researchers and abortion activists.</p>
<p>The study, a statistical analysis of 23 earlier studies of a total of nearly 26,000 women with breast cancer and nearly 35,000 cancer-free women, was in the October issue of the Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health, published by the British Medical Association.</p>
<p>Written by researchers from Penn State University's Hershey Medical Center in Hershey, Pennsylvania, and Baruch College in New York City, the study said the link was underpublicized and women should be warned of the risk.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's a moral imperative,&quot; said Dr. Joan Summy-Long, co-author and pharmacologist at Hershey. &quot;We were aware certainly of the political and emotional ramifications of this study ... We used all the data we could find.&quot;</p>
<p>But some researchers questioned the study's credibility, saying it used earlier research with little quality control.</p>
<p>&quot;They have summed up and averaged a group of studies, some bad and some good, and drawn a conclusion that there is a cause and effect because they found a statistical association, and it makes no sense,&quot; said Dr. Lynn Rosenberg, an epidemiologist at Boston University.</p>
<p>The National Cancer Institute said last week that recent scientific reviews concluded data on a link between abortion and cancer &quot;are inconsistent and inconclusive.&quot;</p>
<p>The authors of this study estimated abortions accounted for about 5,000 cases of breast cancer in the United States every year and could reach 25,000 by the mid-21st century.</p>
<p>They said the trigger for the increased risk was the buildup of estrogen during pregnancy.</p>
<p>Women who had early miscarriages -- before estrogen levels rise sharply -- did not experience a similar risk, they said.</p>
<p>In women who carried pregnancies to term, hormones secreted later modified the growth and vulnerability of breast cells and resulted in a lower cancer risk, they said.</p>
<p>The National Cancer Institute said a weakness in any such study is accuracy. Other studies show women without cancer under-report having abortions and women with cancer are more forthcoming, possibly skewing results, it said.</p>
<p>In January, a study of 16,000 U.S. women published in the Journal of the American Medical Association showed those who had a miscarriage or an abortion had a 12 percent higher risk of breast cancer than those who never terminated a pregnancy.</p>
<p>That study showed the risk was unrelated to whether the abortion was induced or due to a miscarriage. The AMA journal said in an editorial that several studies conflicted and legislation proposed in several states to require women be warned of potential risks of abortion was premature.</p>
<p>The question of a link between abortion and breast cancer stirs heated response on all sides of the abortion debate. Pro-choice activists say findings are overblown or misused; anti-abortion actitivts say they are purposely downplayed.</p>
<p>Pro-choice activists noted one of this study's authors, Dr. Joel Brind of New York, was a known opponent of abortion whose work has appeared in the National Right-to-Life newsletter. But co-author Summy-Long defended the work as bias-free, saying that another author was pro-choice.</p>
<p>Washington-based National Right to Life accused abortion advocates of failing to acknowledge a link between abortion and cancer.</p>
<p>Vickie Saporta of the Washington-based National Abortion Federation responded by saying: &quot;They are scaring women needlessly with a statement that cannot be backed up in scientific literature.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
