<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="110900" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end mostly lower on pork spillover.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end mostly lower on pork spillover.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spillover weakness from the skid in pork complex futures weighed on CME live cattle futures, pulling cattle values to mostly lower closes, traders said. Feeders also slipped to close mixed despite sharply lower corn futures, they noted.</p>
<p>Short covering linked to an oversold condition and expectations cash beef prices will start to firm provided early strength in live cattle before values were pulled down by hog and belly values in neighboring pits.</p>
<p>But lower grain futures, a pickup in cattle slaughter late in the week and strong financial markets curbed declines, traders said.</p>
<p>Ideas cash beef prices will start to firm when retailers switch promotions and advertising dollars to beef from pork, added to gains, they said.</p>
<p>Boxed beef values recently slipped to lowest levels since late September and retailers will likely feature beef early in November after featuring pork during October, which some retailers have dubbed National Pork Month, they said.</p>
<p>An increase in cattle slaughter late this week to boost kills above week-ago levels, also underpinned values, as it indicated packers want cattle.  </p>
<p>&quot;Kill levels are up and that means they are making money and will want cattle,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>In live cattle options, activity increased with February 66/68 call spreading cited. The February 64 stradle was active, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle advanced early on falling corn futures. Lower feed costs prompted ideas there will be increased interest to place feeders in feedlots, especially with many feedyards sporting empty pens, they said.</p>
<p>But prices slipped late as weakness in other livestock pits and cash concerns weighed on futures, they said.</p>
<p>Demand for feeders Friday was less than anticipated in some areas, especially in Texas direct trade where prices were lower. This should result in the CME feeder cattle index being quoted lower early next week, floor sources added.</p>
<p>USDA quoted feeder cattle prices at Dodge City, Kan. down $1 to $3 Thursday and values at Lexington, Ky were steady. Feeders at Amarillo, Tx. were quoted $2 to $4 lower Wednesday.</p>
<p>Live cattle ended up 0.075 cent to down 0.200 with only October up and December off 0.100 at 65.625 cents. Feeder cattle ended down 0.250 to up 0.400 with Nov off most at 63.700 cents.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
