<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111044" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN puts off clearing Baghdad on dangerous arms.</title>
<headline>UN puts off clearing Baghdad on dangerous arms.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>After five years of scrapping weapons of mass destruction, Iraq may still be hiding small but significant quantities of banned arms, the United Nations said on Friday.</p>
<p>In a major half-year report to the Security Council, the U.N. Special Commission in charge of Iraqi disarmament accused Baghdad of systematically concealing weapons despite periods of substantial cooperation.</p>
<p>A clean bill of health by the commission is a key requirement by the U.N. Security Council before the embargo on Iraqi oil exports can be lifted entirely. Iraq has been under U.N. sanctions since its invasion of Kuwait in August 1990.</p>
<p>The commission, the report said, &quot;continues to believe that limited, but highly significant quantities (of arms) may remain, as Iraq has not been able to account for a number of proscribed missiles and certain high-quality chemical and biological warfare agents.&quot;</p>
<p>It said that the &quot;policies and actions of concealment practiced by the Iraqi authorities have been obstacles in the way of rapid completion of the implementation tasks.&quot;</p>
<p>The report, prepared by commission chairman Rolf Ekeus, evaluated chemical, biological and ballistic weapons. Nuclear arms are covered separately by the Vienna-based International Atomic Energy Agency which has not reported any new finds.</p>
<p>On biological weapons, Ekeus harshly criticized Iraq's six purported final declarations submitted to date. &quot;Major sections are incomplete, inaccurate or unsubstantiated. Materials acquired for proscribed activities are understated,&quot; he said, adding that he had not yet received a full account of &quot;weapons produced and destroyed unilaterally.&quot;</p>
<p>Iraq had filled missiles and bombs with biological agents for deployment during the 1991 Gulf War but there was no evidence they were used. Last June, Ekeus' inspectors destroyed a huge plant at al-Hakam that had been used to manufacture botulism, anthrax and other germ warfare agents.</p>
<p>Et Iraqi charges that Ekeus was deliberately holding back certification on political grounds by gi of the inspectors' work to date.</p>
<p>On Oct 2, Foreign Minister Mohammed Saeed al-Sahaf lashed out at the commission ech to the U.N. General Assembly, saying it was influenced by American and British intelligence. He noted it had sen3 inspection teams with 3,574 inspectors to Iraq over more than five years.</p>
<p>&quot;What has this huge army of inspectors been doing for all this long period of time? They did not come to Iraq for a vacation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On chemical weapons, Ekhe destruction took place between June 1992 and May 1994 when the U.N. helped dispose of more than 126,800 gallons (480,000 litres)  of live chemical agents, 28,000 chemical munitions and about 475,500 gallons (1.8 million litres) of 45 nt precursor chemicals.</p>
<p>He said inspectors now had a &quot;fundamental understanding&quot; of Iraq's tactical chemical arms but &quot;the most technologically advanced programs remain unaccounted for.&quot;</p>
<p>On ballistic missiles, the commission destroyeds, 14 conventional warheads, ssix mobile missile launchers and other equipment. Ekeus said he believed that most missiles had been uncovered but he said Iraq's accounting was not yet complete.</p>
<p>He did not say how many missiles remained, although last year he said there were 6 to 15 Scud-type missiles in Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
