<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111033" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gold use in coinage up 32 pct in 95-Gold Institute.</title>
<headline>Gold use in coinage up 32 pct in 95-Gold Institute.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Worldwide use of gold in coinage rose 32 percent in 1995 to more than 3.3 million ounces, up from 2.5 million ounces in 1994, according to a report published annually by The Gold Institute.</p>
<p>Austria and Iran topped the list of gold users last year followed by Australia, the United States and Canada.</p>
<p>Austria's use of gold rose sharply to 793,015 - up 164 percent from the 1994 level of 300,226 ounces.  </p>
<p>The Vienna Philharmoniker bullion coin was credited for this increase, due to strong domestic sales fueled by low interest rates and economic uncertainty, according to Gold Fields Mineral Services.</p>
<p>Primarily for economic reasons, Iran expanded its Azadi coin program, consuming 776,827 ounces of gold in 1995.  This is the largest amount of gold used by Iran for coinage since 1986.</p>
<p>While Australia ranked third in 1995 as a user of gold in coinage, its demand for gold dropped by about 45 percent from the 1994 level of 827,230 ounces to 456,977 ounces.  </p>
<p>The decline was reportedly due to decreased coin exports, especially to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>In the U.S., sales of the coins commemorating the Centennial Olympic Games coupled with a 21 percent increase in gold used in American Eagle Bullion Coins helped push gold coinage demand up by 10 percent to 442,933 ounces.</p>
<p>Overall, gold used to mint commemorative coins exceeded the amount used in minting bullion coins last year by 449,194 ounces.</p>
<p>Of the countries producing bullion coins, only Austria, the United States and the United Kingdom posted increases in gold usage.  </p>
<p>The gold used in Austria's Philharmoniker was more than double that of any other bullion coin.</p>
<p>The report, &quot;Modern Gold Coinage 1995&quot;, documents the 416 coins issued last year by 64 countries throughout the world.</p>
<p>The Gold Institute, which published the report, is a nonprofit international association of miners, refiners, bullion suppliers and manufacturers of gold products.</p>
<p>			GOLD USED IN BULLION COINS</p>
<p>					    (Ounces)</p>
<p>					    1994	 1995</p>
<p>    American Eagle		  291,634    297,750</p>
<p>    Australian Kangaroo	   342,529	 N/A</p>
<p>    Austrian Philharmoniker     287,546    747,024</p>
<p>    Canadian Maple Leaf	   304,877    245,492</p>
<p>    Centenario			 69,813     17,362</p>
<p>    South African Kruggerand    155,747    118,457</p>
<p>    United Kingdom Britannia     11,815     12,424</p>
<p>	TOTAL			 1,463,961  1,438,509</p>
<p>--New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
