<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111089" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Negotiations still possible on German sick pay.</title>
<headline>Negotiations still possible on German sick pay.</headline>
<byline>Mark John</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Signs appeared on Friday that regional leaders of the IG Metall trade union backed further talks between their central board and employers on planned sick pay cuts, keeping alive some hope of an end to the dispute.</p>
<p>A spokesman for IG Metall in the state of Hesse said on Friday that its regional committee had voted to allow union negotiators to continue talks with metal employers' federation Gesamtmetall.</p>
<p>Earlier, the chief negotiator for IG Metall in the state of North Rhine Westphalia, a key metalworking region, said he would also be recommending that its committee there also back further top-level talks with Gesamtmetall in a vote on Monday.</p>
<p>Talks between union and employer representatives had broken up on Thursday with neither side able to say whether the issue could be determined at the national level at all. IG Metall said afterwards it would consult its regions on the matter.</p>
<p>The dispute follows a federal law passed last month aimed at allowing employers to cut sick pay allowances from the current 100 percent of salary to 80 percent, a move designed to shave some 12 billion marks off German industry's labour costs.</p>
<p>But employers such as Daimler-Benz AG which sought to implement the law on top of existing wage contracts were forced earlier this week to back down after protests in the engineering sector involving more than 100,000 workers.</p>
<p>They said they would leave sick payments unchanged pending agreement with unions and in return for a promise of no more industrial action.</p>
<p>Employers' demands that the sick pay issue be linked to the overall discussions about the 1997 pay round has forced IG Metall to consult its regions to gain permission to handle the pay claim as well at the top level.</p>
<p>Pay discussions are normally held in the regions.</p>
<p>IG Metall's Schartau also told a news briefing on Friday that he backed the inclusion of talks on sick pay allowances in overall negotiations on the 1997 wage round and other benefits such as holiday and Christmas pay.</p>
<p>Negotiations that included sick pay in wider wage talks were described by Geasamtmetall president Werner Stumpfe on Thursday as an &quot;absolute pre-condition&quot; for central talks continuing.</p>
<p>But despite initial indications that talks between the union and employers may yet continue, the two sides still appear as far apart as ever on whether the cuts should go ahead.</p>
<p>IG Metall reaffirmed on Friday an ultimatum given to employers earlier this week that they should by October 23 back down on their insistence that they would ultimately still seek to implement the cuts.</p>
<p>If they do not, IG Metall says it will go ahead with a second series of nationwide protests orginally planned for the day after.</p>
<p>Gesamtmetall insists not only that the sick pay cuts go through but they be accompanied by reductions in holiday and Christmas benefits necessary to lower labour costs.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
