<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111016" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Freeport Copper gets RTZ-CRA payment.</title>
<headline>Freeport Copper gets RTZ-CRA payment.</headline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Freeport-McMoRan Copper &amp; Gold Inc said the RTZ-CRA mining group has made a $184 million payment for exploration and expansion spending under joint venture programs announced in 1995.</p>
<p>Freeport said the definitive documentation for those programs was signed Friday, resulting in the payment to Freeport Copper and 82 percent owned P.T. Freeport Indonesia Co.</p>
<p>The two companies will use the funds to reduce bank debt, Freeport said.  </p>
<p>With the completion of definitive documentation, RTZ-CRA has fully funded its $100 million exploration commitment, reimbursed P.T. Freeport Indonesia for expansion capital spending incurred, begun funding future expansion costs, and become a 40 percent partner in the current Indonesian expansion above 118,000 metric tonnes per day, Freeport said.</p>
<p>Also, RTZ-CRA can now elect to participate in Freeport Copper's future development projects in Indonesia.</p>
<p>As previously announced, Freeport and RTZ-CRA have established the economic justification for an expansion of the Indonesian facilities, subject to certain approvals.  </p>
<p>Freeport said engineering activities have begun on an expansion above the current throughput rate of about 125,000 tonnes daily. The optimum rate of this &quot;fourth concentrator mill expansion&quot; is expected to be at least 190,000 to 200,000 MTPD and completion is expected in the second half of 1998.</p>
<p>The company said costs for this expansion to achieve optimum throughput rates is expected to be some $960 million, including about $300 million to construct a coal-fired power plant and related facilities.  </p>
<p>The new power plant will not only provide power for the expanded operations but also improve the profitability of existing operations which use power generated by higher cost diesel-fueled facilities.</p>
<p>With the definitive documentation signed and the payment made, RTZ-CRA has fulfilled its commitment under the joint venture agreement, Freeeport noted. Once this amount has been spent, it said, exploration expenditures will be shared 60 percent by Freeport subsidiaries and 40 percent by RTZ-CRA.</p>
<p>In addition to funding its 40 percent share of expansion costs, Freeport said, RTZ-CRA will loan up to $450 million on a nonrecourse basis for P.T. Freeport Indonesia's share of costs for expansion activities above 118,000 tonnes of ore per day in the Block A area, where operations are underway.</p>
<p>Once the expansion is completed, RTZ-CRA will receive 100 percent of incremental cash flows from the expanded operations until it RTZ-CRA recoups the amount loaned, Freeport noted.</p>
<p>Subsequently, cash flows from the expanded operations will be shared 60 percent by PT-FI and 40 percent by RTZ-CRA. Freeport Copper will retain 100 percent of the production and cash flows associated with mill throughput up to the current capacity. -- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
