<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111036" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WHX strike could last several months - USW.</title>
<headline>WHX strike could last several months - USW.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Steelworkers union is bracing itself for a protractive fight with WHX Corp and its current strike against the company, now in its eleventh day, could continue for several months, union officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to keep this going as long as we have to until we feel we get what we deserve,&quot; Mickey Forte, president of Local 1187, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Some 4,500 steelworkers walked off the job October 1 after their former contract expired and negotiations failed to produce a new one. The strike has idled eight steel plants in three states.  </p>
<p>Forte said pensions remain the major divisive issue. The union wants WHX to establish a defined benefit plan, which guarantees funding regardless of hours worked.</p>
<p>WHX currently has a defined contribution plan, which is funded based on age and hours worked and is cheaper to fund than a defined benefit plan.</p>
<p>A bankruptcy court ruling barred the company from offering a defined benefit plan until this year. WHX has maintained it cannot afford such a plan and needs its $406 million of cash-in-hand for debt and interest payments and capital expenditures.  </p>
<p>&quot;A defined benefit plan forces the company to put a lot of money up front and that's risky,&quot; company spokesman Gregg Warren said. &quot;(Steel) is a cyclical business. It's hard to make those kinds of commitments when you don't know what will happen in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Forte said WHX should put some of its cash-in-hand into a pension plan. &quot;It would take $95 million of ($406 million) to fund the first three years of a defined benefit plan.&quot;</p>
<p>The strike has halted WHX's steel production but inventories that were built up prior to the strike will allow the company to ship product for 60-90 days, Forte said.  </p>
<p>But he said striking workers are asking truck drivers not to take steel from the plants and some drivers have complied.</p>
<p>The company during negotiations offered to enhance its defined contribution plan. WHX said it would provide monthly benefits of $1,600 per month for workers with 44 years of service or more; $1,500 per month for service of 41-43 years; $1,400 per month for service of 36-40 years; $1,300 per month for service of 31-35 years; and $1,200 per month for service of 30 years or less.  </p>
<p>But Forte said that proposal increases contributions only for employees over 50 years of age. Plus, the proposal is good only for the life of a contract, he said. &quot;If we chose not to renew the contract, we would have to renegotiate the whole plan,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Forte said union members also are upset because WHX is the only integrated steelmaker in the country that does not have a defined benefit plan, but Warren said such plans are a thing of the past.</p>
<p>&quot;They may be the way in the steel industry, but their not the way in industry as a whole,&quot; he said. &quot;Defined benefit plans are dinosaurs.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
