<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111082" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Portugal's island voters could boost government.</title>
<headline>Portugal's island voters could boost government.</headline>
<byline>Richard Waddington</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Voters in the Azores Islands could this weekend give Portugal's minority Socialist government a timely boost as it prepares for looming political battles, particularly over a tough budget package.</p>
<p>For the first time in two decades, opinion polls suggest the Socialist Party has a chance of winning when the windswept mid-Atlantic islands vote on Sunday in local elections.</p>
<p>The votes for regional governments in the Azores and in Madeira, a sub-tropical archipelago off the coast of north Africa, have no direct impact on parliament in Lisbon.</p>
<p>But the islands have long been political fiefdoms of the conservative Social Democrats (PSD) whom the Socialists ousted from national government in a general election a year ago.</p>
<p>A win in the Azores for the Socialists of Prime Minister Antonio Guterres would underline his ascendency on the national scene and deal a blow to the Social Democrats just as they seemed to be emerging from the political lethargy into which they slumped after their 1995 defeat, political analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a political plus for the government, no doubt about it,&quot; said one European diplomat in Lisbon.</p>
<p>The tension surrounding the campaign was reflected in a fierce row that erupted over air fares to the distant islands after state airline TAP announced a month-long promotion campaign of cut-priced tickets for residents.</p>
<p>The Socialists' opponents accused the government of abusing its power by trying to use the state company as a vote-winner. TAP denied that there was any political interference, saying that it was a usual off-season offer to win passengers.</p>
<p>Opinion polls in Madeira suggest that local PSD leader Alberto Joao Jardim, a rumbustious and colourful politician, will be comfortably returned for his sixth four-year stint as head of the regional government.</p>
<p>But in the Azores, a third of the way across the Atlantic towards North America, polls give the Socialists a slight lead over the PSD in the run-up to Sunday's vote.</p>
<p>The Socialists' chance came when long-time PSD boss, Joao Mota Amaral, stepped down as head of the local government in 1995 and moved to the mainland in what was seen as an -- ultimately unsuccessful -- bid to win the national party leadership, then up for grabs.</p>
<p>Voter loyalty is as much to people as parties in the volcanic islands, still reliant economically on remittances of emigrants to the mainland and North America, and Mota Amaral's electorate does not seem to have all gone over to his successor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
