<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111054" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: East Timor autonomy leaders win Nobel Peace Prize.</title>
<headline>East Timor autonomy leaders win Nobel Peace Prize.</headline>
<byline>Rolf Soderlind</byline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two leaders of East Timor's movement for independence from Indonesia won the 1996 Nobel Peace Prize on Friday in Norwegian Nobel Committee decision that drew international praise but chilly reaction in Jakarta.</p>
<p>East Timor's Roman Catholic Bishop Carlos Belo and exiled resistance leader Jose Ramos-Horta, who lives in Australia, shared the prestigious prize for their efforts to solve a conflict triggered when Indonesia invaded the territory in 1975.</p>
<p>They shared the $1.12 million distinction &quot;for their work toward a just and peaceful solution to the conflict in East Timor&quot;, Committee Chairman Francis Sejersted said.</p>
<p>Praise from around the world from the European Union to the Vatican for the choice of Belo and Ramos-Horta mixed with disbelief in Jakarta.</p>
<p>Indonesian Foreign Minister Ali Alatas, visiting the German port of Hamburg, said on Friday he was &quot;astounded&quot; that Ramos-Horta had won. &quot;We think he is a political adventurist, for a while representing a very small minority but...(now) repudiated by the majority of the people of East Timor,&quot; he told Reuters Television.</p>
<p>Portugal, the former colonial power in East Timor, reacted with delight, saying it could push Indonesia into easing its iron grip over the territory.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded the former Portuguese colony just after Portugal pulled out, and annexed the territory a year later. The annexation has never been recognised by the United Nations, which still regards Lisbon as the administering power.</p>
<p>Friday's announcement of the peace prize, the only one of the Nobels to be made in Oslo, concluded this year's awards. The Nobel physics, chemistry, medicine, economics and literature awards were announced in Stockholm over the past eight days.</p>
<p>But the Nobel series ended on a tragic note with news of the death in Boston of William Vickrey, who was a co-winner of the Nobel Prize for Economics just three days ago. He died on Friday after suffering a heart attack at the wheel of his car, a Columbia University spokeswoman in New York said.</p>
<p>The 1996 awards are to be presented on December 10.</p>
<p>The Committee, which openly accused Indonesia of oppressing East Timor's population, said in a statement it honoured Belo and Ramos-Horta for &quot;their sustained and self-sacrificing contributions for a small but oppressed people&quot;.</p>
<p>Sejersted told reporters: &quot;We want to put the spotlight on this conflict. I hope this situation will strengthen their negotiating basis and also protect them personally.&quot;</p>
<p>Indonesia is participating in tripartite talks with Portugal and the United Nations to seek a solution to the issue. They met in Geneva in June and the next round is due in December after the U.N. General Assembly session.</p>
<p>&quot;Belo...has been the foremost representative of the people of East Timor. At the risk of his own life, he has tried to protect his people from infringements by those in power,&quot; the committee said.</p>
<p>Belo, 50, East Timor's outspoken and often fiery bishop, was saying Mass at a school in the territory's capital Dili when the award was announced. Reached later, he said of the award: &quot;I see it as a victory for East Timorese...and all Indonesians.&quot;</p>
<p>Belo said there was hard work ahead in the peace and reconciliation process. &quot;Peace can be achieved through non-violent means,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta, 46, an exiled Timorese leader based in Sydney, Australia, said he hoped the Peace Prize would send a message to Indonesia &quot;that the people of East Timor have suffered long enough and that there must be serious dialogue under United Nations auspices to resolve the problem&quot;.</p>
<p>He was happy but also sad at the award because his jailed leader Xanana Gusmao should have won. Celebrating the award at his mother's home in the suburbs of Sydney, the resistance spokesman said: &quot;I would feel much happier if instead of my name, his was selected.&quot;</p>
<p>Gusmao has been in prison in Jakarta since 1992 when he was captured by Indonesian security forces and sentenced to 20 years in jail.</p>
<p>Diplomats, political analysts and local residents say two decades of Indonesian rule -- mainly through the armed forces -- has failed to win many hearts and minds among the 800,000 East Timorese despite major development efforts by Jakarta.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
