<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111062" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greece set to join EMU by 2000, minister says.</title>
<headline>Greece set to join EMU by 2000, minister says.</headline>
<byline>Costas Paris</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Decreased state spending, a strict currency policy and increased growth should enable Greece to join the European Monetary Union by the year 2000, Economy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Greece is committed to its target of participating in the EMU not later than the year 2000 and this is why it will continue the effort to meet the targets of the convergence plan,&quot; he told parliament in a debate on a confidence motion.</p>
<p>Papandoniou, the Greek economy's &quot;Czar&quot; in the newly-elected government of Socialist Prime Minister Costas Simitis, said targets for 1997 included cutting the inflation rate by two percent and cutting the government deficit to 3.4 percent of Gross Domestic Product.</p>
<p>The general government deficit was expected to be 7.6 percent of GDP at the end of 1996, compared with a requirement for participation in EMU of three percent of GDP.</p>
<p>The inflation rate was running at 8.5 percent in September, more than three times the European Union average. EMU criteria call for an inflation rate of no more than two points above the three best EU performers.</p>
<p>Papandoniou said an acceleration of public and private investments would boost GDP growth by three to 3.5 percent next year, compared with 2.6 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>He said the government would introduce new laws before presenting the 1997 budget at the end of November to freeze public hirings and abolish tax breaks introduced by the previous Socialist government.</p>
<p>Government officials say they expect to raise $1.8 billion in 1997 from public spending cuts and the abolition of tax breaks.</p>
<p>Papandoniou, speaking in the debate before a guaranteed government victory in the confidence vote late on Saturday, stressed he would maintain a strict monetary policy to curb inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The current foreign exchange policy is the cornerstone of our fight against inflation and can't be changed. This must be understood by the business community and the markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He called for small-scale privatisations of three state banks and a 10 percent flotation of the Public Petroleum Corporation on the Athens Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
