<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111121" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German parliament to shrink in bid for efficiency.</title>
<headline>German parliament to shrink in bid for efficiency.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German parliament, swollen to more than 650 seats with the country's unification in 1990, voted on Friday to reduce its size in six years' time in a drive to cut costs and improve efficiency.</p>
<p>The lower house, the Bundestag, passed legislation that will cut the number of regular seats to 598 after elections scheduled for the year 2002 from the current number of 656 seats.</p>
<p>Critics of the Bundestag's size have pointed out that Germany has more elected representatives than the U.S. Congress even though the population of the United States is three times larger than united Germany.</p>
<p>Earlier proposals to make even deeper cuts in the number of Bundestag seats were discarded but the legislation passed on Friday had widespread backing in Bonn even though opposition parties voted against for technical reasons.</p>
<p>Before unification in 1990, the West German Bundestag had 496 seats. The number of parliamentarians grew to more than 650 when more than 150 deputies from former communist eastern Germany took seats in Bonn in 1990.</p>
<p>There are currently a record 672 seats in parliament, partly because of so-called &quot;excess mandates&quot;.</p>
<p>Germans can cast two votes in general elections -- a general one for a party list of candidates and direct one for a specific candidate.</p>
<p>The excess mandates are awarded under a complicated formula to &quot;top up&quot; the strength of a party which has received a disproportionately low number of seats compared to the number of direct votes for its candidates.</p>
<p>The parliament, with votes from the coalition of Chancellor Helmut Kohl's conservative Christian Democrats (CDU/CSU) and the centrist Free Democrats (FDP), also voted to reduce the number of electoral districts to 299 from the current 328.</p>
<p>The opposition Social Democrats and the environmentalist Greens were unsuccessful in their bid to change the election law on the &quot;excess mandates&quot; that helped Kohl in the 1994 election.</p>
<p>The CDU/CSU had 12 &quot;excess mandates&quot; in 1994 compared to just four for the SPD.</p>
<p>Kohl's coalition currently enjoys a 10-seat majority over the opposition, an advantage that would have been cut to just two seats without the &quot;excess mandates&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
