<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111160" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Ousted Afghan chief hits Taleban behind lines.</title>
<headline>Ousted Afghan chief hits Taleban behind lines.</headline>
<byline>Michael Battye</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ousted Afghan military chief Ahmad Shah Masood attacked the Taleban militia on Friday, using the guerrilla tactics he successfully employed against the Soviet Army in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Masood engaged a large force of the purist Islamic faction in one spot and orchestrated hit-and-run strikes behind the enemy's lines, travellers said, quoting local people along the road from Jabal os-Siraj.</p>
<p>Masood sent envoys to local commanders urging them to hit the Taleban, local people told the travellers. The commanders struck at the Taleban at least half a dozen times and inflicted significant casualties on the militia, which took Kabul two weeks ago, the witnesses said.</p>
<p>The latest attack took place at Saray Khoeja, some 15 km (nine miles) south of Bagram where the government has its main air base.</p>
<p>Fleeing villagers said local fighters hit the Taleban around 9 a.m. (0530 GMT) and the fighting was still going on more than 30 minutes later, Reuters photographer Patrick de Noirmont reported.</p>
<p>He said the sound of automatic rifles and rocket-propelled grenades filled the air as people fled, many of them carrying children. Trucks laden with goods for towns further north turned back towards Kabul.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the Taleban were gathering fighters about 15 km (nine miles) to the south of Saray Khoeja for an apparent counter-attack and that two tanks headed from Kabul at high speed trailed by a convoy of pick-up trucks carrying heavily armed Taleban fighters.</p>
<p>Villagers said the attack began after a Masood envoy arrived to talk to the local commander.</p>
<p>The travellers said that would follow the pattern of other reports of hit-and-run attacks behind the lines.</p>
<p>The tactics were the same as Masood followed against the Soviet army when when Moscow backed a communist government in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>When not fighting in the valley, Masood,  dubbed the &quot;Lion of Panjsher,&quot; would strike in the Salang, a major Soviet supply line, draw in Soviet troops and keep them jumpy with attacks in the pass and on their rear lines.</p>
<p>They said the Taleban-occupied governor's house just outside Charikar, a 30-minute drive south of Jabal-os-Siraj, was hit on Thursday and two other strikes were launched against the militia between Charikar and the Bagram air base.</p>
<p>Further north, the travellers reported a serious attack at Mataq bridge, just south of Jabal os-Siraj and near a military base.</p>
<p>They quoted villagers as saying they saw several jeeps loaded with dead or wounded Taleban fighters being driven away after Thursday's attack.</p>
<p>In the Salang Pass, they said the Taleban had pushed their front line back, at least along the winding road, towards the place it stood before Masood commander Basir Solangi launched a major attack on Tuesday.</p>
<p>But they said Solangi's forces were launching regular attacks on the Taleban from the hillsides.</p>
<p>The pass which connects the north and south is open to civilian traffic during lulls in the fighting. When the fighting starts, heavily laden buses, trucks and cars halt and wait patiently for the next lull before continuing their journey.</p>
<p>Solangi's attack forced the Taleban to break off attempts to force their way through the gorge into the Panjsher and switch their men to the Salang front.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
