<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111174" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan government forces fightback against Taleban.</title>
<headline>Afghan government forces fightback against Taleban.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SALANG PASS, Afghanistan 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forces loyal to ousted government military head Ahmad Shah Masood pursued their counter-offensive against the Taleban militia, fighting for control of a vital highway north of Kabul.</p>
<p>Guerrilla attacks, apparently orchestrated by Masood, have hit the Taleban well behind their front lines.</p>
<p>Village commanders have turned on the Taleban, cutting some units off north of the capital, and fighters loyal to Masood have shelled Bagram airbase, 50 km (30 miles) north of Kabul.</p>
<p>&quot;Taleban hold some parts of the road between here and Kabul and we hold some,&quot; said Masood commander Abdul Bashir Salanghi in Olang, just south of the strategic Salang pass, on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still fighting in Jabal-os-Saray and Charikar. Perhaps we will take them today or tonight...our troops are fighting and there are some civilians fighting there too.&quot;</p>
<p>The Salang pass links the capital Kabul with northern Afghanistan, including territories controlled by the Uzbek warlord Abdul Rashid Dostum.</p>
<p>The fightback against the fundamentalist Islamic Taleban seems to have stemmed from a meeting of anti-Taleban leaders north of the Salang pass on Thursday.</p>
<p>Dostum, Masood and Karim Khalilli of the Shia Moslem Hezb-i-Wahadat were reported to have held a war council.</p>
<p>But while Masood's men are fighting in the valley, trying to regain the initiative against Taleban forces which drove them and the rest of the government out of Kabul two weeks ago, Dostum's soldiers are staying out of the battle.</p>
<p>Dostum's men have preferred to cement control of the Salang.</p>
<p>Hundreds of Dostum soldiers in winter clothes were guarding all the main ridges along the rugged route and large numbers of tanks, rocket launchers and big guns were dug in along the way.</p>
<p>&quot;If General Dostum gives the order we will attack to the south (along with Masood). For the moment we are holding here,&quot; said General Abdul Majid Ruzi, a Dostum commander.</p>
<p>Asked how Masood was making so much progess Ruzi said: &quot;The Taleban were so cruel ordinary people have begun to fight.&quot;</p>
<p>Taleban forces, who practice an ultra-conservative form of Islam, have imposed strict controls on Kabul, banning women from the workplace, forcing them to wear the veil and insisting men pray in the mosque, rather than at home.</p>
<p>Afghan-watchers in Kabul said Masood appeared to have reverted to the tactics he used against the Soviet army in the 1980s when Moscow backed a communist Afghan government.</p>
<p>His ethnic Tajiks survived a series of assaults on his Panjsher valley redoubt and often hit back in the Salang Pass. Then they would stage hit-and-run raids in the Soviet rear.</p>
<p>Masood's success may depend on the extent of the help he receives from Dostum.</p>
<p>The two charismatic commanders were fighting each other in the Salang earlier this year. With that memory still fresh the Taleban threat has sparked only tacit operation between the two rather than the active alliance some had forecast and hoped for.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALANG PASS, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
