<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111239" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-European bourses climb on benign US data.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-European bourses climb on benign US data.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses climbed on Friday, given a boost by figures showing restrained inflation in the United States, the world's most powerful economy.</p>
<p>London, Frankfurt and Paris drew strength from the U.S. Labor department data saying moderate increases in food and energy prices helped to subdue the overall rate of wholesale inflation.</p>
<p>On the currency markets, the dollar shrugged off the figures and remained at the levels seen earlier in the day, up slightly. Sterling surged against the mark on other factors, touching 20-month highs.</p>
<p>London, Europe biggest bourse, perked up strongly on the U.S. data which traders said confirmed a benign U.S. inflation scenario with the prospects of subdued interest rates.</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 share index, which edged up slightly in nervous trading earlier, climbed 0.75 percent after the U.S. figures made for a strong opening on Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no great expectations now of a U.S. rate rise and... we should hold these levels or push on by the end of the day,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Frankfurt and Paris also showed gains after all European bourses registered losses on Thursday.</p>
<p>The poor performance followed a record-breaking pace by European bourses earlier this week which largely mirrored the bull market on Wall Street, driven by rapid growth and low inflation.</p>
<p>European investors closely follow the state of the U.S. economy because any downturn there would quickly be felt on this side of the Atlantic -- hence the focus on Friday's data.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, floor trading ended in modest gains before the American inflation figures were issued, but transaction on the computerised IBIS DAX index climbed 0.4 percent on their release.</p>
<p>Dealers said Wall Street's performance on Friday would provide direction for Frankfurt early next week. &quot;The tone for next week will be set by how the U.S. reacts to this data,&quot; said one dealer. In Paris, French shares made gains on the U.S. figures.</p>
<p>The dollar took the price figures in its stride, as well as the data on retail sales which posted a surprisingly strong rise in September, largely because of a surge in new car sales.</p>
<p>Total retail sales increased by 0.7 percent but excluding the automobile business, September retail sales were up a more modest 0.4 percent, indicating that economic activity was slowing.</p>
<p>&quot;All-in-all, its still obvious that consumer spending has slowed considerably from the first half of 1996 and will probably come in near one percent in the second half,&quot; said Cheryl Katz, senior economist at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>In mid-afternoon the dollar was at 1.5311 marks and 111.60 yen, up slightly on Thursday's figures.</p>
<p>Among European currencies, sterling surged against the mark on the back of British finance minister Kenneth Clarke's upbeat speech at the ruling Conservative party conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>The pound broke through 2.40 marks in early business and pushed on to 2.4105 by mid-afternoon, compared with 2.3943 late Thursday in Europe. It also rose strongly against the dollar to $1.5747, compared with $1.5656.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.5311 marks and 111.60 yen compared with 1.5300 marks and 111.26 yen late in Europe on Thursday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1430 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was up 24.2 points at 4018.9.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was up 9.26 at 2,144.89.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt closed up 5.28 at 2686.03.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold was fixed in the afternoon at $380.75, compared with Thursday's close of $381.95. Silver was at $5.02, up one cent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
