<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111463" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FROM THE FLIGHTDECK - The Air Cargo Week In Review.</title>
<headline>FROM THE FLIGHTDECK - The Air Cargo Week In Review.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is Reuters' look back at the major developments in the global air cargo industry in the week October 4 - October 11.</p>
<p>**OCTOBER 4**</p>
<p>ZURICH - Swissair says cargo shipments transported in the first eight months of 1996 totalled 1.05 billion FTKs, up 6.4 percent on the same period 1995.</p>
<p>NAPLES - Prime minister Romano Prodi says he had asked France to help Italy's bid to join the Airbus consortium.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Hong Kong's civil aviation department says it turning down applications from airlines seeking an average of 150 extra flights a week in and out of the territory's Kai Tak airport.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - Officials says the EC is planning to allow airlines to buy and sell their landing and take-off slots at EU airports but will not introduce wholesale auctions of all slots.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - EVA Air says that its air cargo market share on the new Hong Kong to Taipei route &quot;has been as high as 20 percent&quot;.</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Koninklijke PTT Netherland says it would cooperate with an Australian investigation into possible insider trading of TNT options, but did not expect any of its employees to have been involved.</p>
<p>LONDON - BA says it welcomed the prospect of European backing for the legalised, commercial trade of airport take-off and landing slots.</p>
<p>TORONTO - Air Canada and SAS says they agreed to develop a comprehensive air travel alliance that may include code-sharing.</p>
<p>PARIS - Le Monde reported the French government wants to create an airline by bringing together privately-owned Euralair and AOM and buying up the insolvent Air Liberte, to keep out BA.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - AEA says global freight traffic carried by West European airlines in August 1996 was up seven percent on the same month last year at 1.87 billion FTKs'.</p>
<p>* AEA says global freight traffic carried by West European airlines in the first eight months of 1996 up was 4.1 percent against the same period 1995.</p>
<p>PARIS - Tunis Air says it plans to launch a four-time weekly Boeing 737-200 freighter service between Paris and Tunis later this month or early November in partnership with Air France.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Airport authority figures show global cargo traffic handled at Zurich airport in the first eight months of 1996 totalled 287,616 tonnes, a decreased of 1.4 percent on the same period last year.</p>
<p>HANOVER - A senior AEA executive says regional airlines face the possible loss of airport slots, addition costs and increased passenger liability under proposed EU transport rules.</p>
<p>* The European Regional Airlines Association (ERA) says it has decided to change its name to the European Regions Airlines Association.</p>
<p>LONDON - BA public relations manager Michael Blunt says it welcomed the prospect of European backing for the legalised, commercial trade of airport take-off and landing slots.</p>
<p>MADRID - Portuguese airport authority ANA says cargo traffic at Lisbon airport rose 1.9 percent in September to 8,405 tonnes.</p>
<p>SEATTLE - Boeing says it delivered 54 commercial jet airlines in the third quarter ended September 30.</p>
<p>ABIDJAN - A company official says troubled price-cutting French charter company Air Liberte is to suspend its flights from France to Ivory Coast from October 5.</p>
<p>LONDON - BA says it has asked Europe's transport and competition commissioners to block &quot;with utmost urgency&quot; a bid by French regional airline AOM to buy its competitor Air Liberte, which is in receivership.</p>
<p>LONG BEACH - A report published by McDonnell Douglas Corp says the world's passenger jet fleet will need to double in the coming years, adding 13,600 aircraft worth an estimated $5.1 trillion.</p>
<p>LONDON - Emirates says it will be launching new services to Kuala Lumpur and Sanaa on October 27 and 28 respectively.</p>
<p>* Emirates says it will increase weekly flights to Nairobi and Jakarta from October 27, when the airline commences its winter schedule.</p>
<p>PARIS - The national pilots union SNPL says pilots at BA's French associate airline TAT, ended their strike.</p>
<p>ATLANTA - ValuJet says it had sold 15 surplus DC-9 and MD-80 aircraft and five engines, enabling the company to retire $46.6 million of aircraft bank debt.</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The U.S. transportation department says it tentatively approved a carrier agreement waiving a liability limit for passengers and their families in the event of death or injury on international flights.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
