<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111745" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Friday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Friday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Friday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Patrick Child briefed on the Ecofin Council that will take place on Monday in Luxembourg. He said discussions would focus on the new guarantee system for loans to third countries where the Commission is expecting a political agreement, on the financial situation of Georgia and Armenia and on the new VAT programme adopted by the Commission on July 10th. On this issue, Child announced a conference to be held beginning of November.</p>
<p>Child also said the EU ministers would meet with the European Free Trade Association (EFTA) representatives during to lunchtime discuss the economic situation, social dialogue and structural reforms procedure.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas said the prospects of unblocking the trans-European networks file were not very good.</p>
<p>He added that whereas this file was part of the confidence pact for jobs, the pact would go on without it since there were many other actions to be developed.</p>
<p>Van der Pas said Commission President Jacques Santer would not make an alternative proposal in this field.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, Child said there would be an informal debate on article 109 J.3. This a formal requirement to do with the issue of whether will be a majority of member states able at the end of 1997 to join the European single currency union.</p>
<p>Spokesman Jochen Kubosch briefed on the meeting that took place in Paris on Thursday between Commissioners Martin Bangemann and Edith Cresson, the telecommunication ministers from the member states and about 30 industrials from the sector of communication by satellite (see separate story).</p>
<p>Spokesman Constantin Verros said Commissioner Christos Papoutsis would leave on an official visit to China on Sunday to promote and support cooperation in the field of energy. Verros said he would be joined by members of the European Parliament, the European Investment Bank, the European Energy Agency and industrialists from the energy sector.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/96/894: Financing for developing countries in Asia and Latin America - Projects totalling ECU 186 million.</p>
<p>- IP/96/910: Commission decides that no aid is involved in the sale of British Coal Enterprise.</p>
<p>- IP/96/913: Romanian post-privatisation fund to be financed by EBRD and European Community.</p>
<p>- IP/96/914: Communication per satellite: towards a European strategy.</p>
<p>- High-level group on public-private partnership financing of TEN transport projects (background note).</p>
<p>-Speech/96/244: Address by Commissioner Papoutsis on &quot;Improving the market penetration for new energy technologies: prospects for pre-competitive support&quot;.</p>
<p>- ME96/11.10: Midday express</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
