<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111730" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Neste write-off well received by analysts.</title>
<headline>Neste write-off well received by analysts.</headline>
<byline>Roland Moller</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A surprise write-off of trading losses on crude oil derivatives by Finnish oil group Neste Oy made its January-August results look very weak but the &quot;macho&quot; move ended uncertainty and was good news, analysts said.</p>
<p>The 495 million markka loss Neste reported on Friday sent analysts to their spreadsheets to downgrade 1996 forecasts, but did nothing to trouble a broadly positive outlook further ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;From the stock market's point of view, it is much more important that the desk has been cleared for next year,&quot; AG Pankkiiriliike chief analyst Jussi Hyoty said.</p>
<p>Neste had already spoken of a 285 million markka 1996 trading loss, which analysts' had for Jan-Aug put between 200 million and 300 million. But none had expected as much as 495 million, which Neste later said was the ceiling of its exposure.</p>
<p>Neste's 26 million markka January-August loss before extraordinary items was a sharp contrast to analysts' forecast profit from 123-550 million markka.</p>
<p>But stockbrokers said the fact Neste took the loss on the chin was a &quot;manly deed&quot;, and Neste's share even nudged up one markka to 93.00 after the announcement.</p>
<p>Merita Bank analyst Antti Pietarinen -- having expected a 285 million markka trading loss and earlier forecast full-year 1996 profit at 575 million -- now said the trading loss and some other revisions would bring this nearer to 300 million markka.</p>
<p>&quot;The benefit is that the risk regarding the whole company is smaller... from the shareholder perspective, the risk is smaller,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Neste CEO Jaakko Ihamuotila said 495 million markka was the ceiling for the losses and that if oil prices developed favourably for Neste, the loss could even fall.</p>
<p>However, analysts noted that the cost of contracts Neste had concluded to eliminate the risk was not yet known; some said it could be substantial.</p>
<p>Ihamuotila also said the group's total oil market position now meant if crude prices still rose, Neste would benefit as its open positions are smaller than the volume of its own output.</p>
<p>In production, analysts saw significant potential for Neste in the long run.</p>
<p>In the Norwegian Asgard field is output capacity which could raise Neste's production by some 10,000 barrels per day from the current 33,000, Neste executive vice president Bo Lindfors told Reuters.</p>
<p>Including other potential increases, Neste's output of oil and gas may rise to the equivalent of 50,000 or 55,000 barrels per day by 2001, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;An independent study has shown that Neste's direct per-barrel production costs in Norway are the lowest in the industry,&quot; Neste said in its report.</p>
<p>Analysts noted other negative news in Neste's report -- like depressed chemicals and petrochemicals -- but on the whole their conclusions were on the optimistic side.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a positive view on Neste,&quot; said Merita's Pietarinen.</p>
<p>He said Neste's stock was justifiably recovering since much uncertainty had been removed; seeing some extra upside when Neste finds an buyer for Borealis.</p>
<p>&quot;Although most of that is probably discounted, I think once the deal is announced, there will be a positive reaction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 0 - 680 50 242</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
