<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111897" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 11.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared for Reuters by The Broadcast Monitoring Company</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- BZW CHIEF TO COLLECT 2.9 MILLION STG IN SIX MONTHS</p>
<p>The recently appointed chief executive of BZW, the investment banking arm of Barclays, Bill Harrison, will earn 2.9 million stg in his first six months in the role. His total package will be inflated by payments linked to the future performance of the Barclays group and he will receive a guaranteed minimum bonus of 1.25 million stg at the end of March. Mr Harrison was also appointed a director of Barclays and attended his first board meeting.</p>
<p>-- RETAILERS' PRICE HIKES POSE THREAT TO INFLATION</p>
<p>Official figures show that retailers are taking advantage of the rising levels of consumer confidence and sales to push up key prices to repair margins. Price statistics pointed to threats to low inflation and interest rates on the day Chancellor Kenneth Clarke presented low inflation as one of his greatest achievements at the Conservative Party conference. The Confederation of British Industry's latest distributive trades survey shows retail sales growth slowed last month, but there is no sign of weakening consumer confidence as shop stocks continue to dwindle.</p>
<p>-- BET PROFIT FIGURES AT TAKEOVER QUESTIONED</p>
<p>Rentokil lawyers have questioned profit figures supplied by BET at the time of its takeover earlier this year. The matter arose during the High Court hearing of former BET chief executive John Clark. Andrew Hogarth, defence council, said that during cross-examination of Rentokil finance director Christopher Pearce, BET had reported pre-tax profits of 122 million stg in its 1995 annual report but later published a figure of 111 million stg in a document issued during the takeover battle.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- JARDINE FLEMING DROPPED FROM ASIA UMBRELLA FUND</p>
<p>The Hong Kong investment bank Jardine Fleming has been dropped as a leading fund manager in Portfolio Fund Management, a new UK unit trust launch. The fund managers' watchdog Imro found that one of its most senior traders, Colin Armstrong, was making secret deals to benefit himself and to the detriment of clients. It was fined 700,000 stg, paid 12 million stg in compensation and sacked the trader.</p>
<p>-- NATWEST BUYS HAMBRO MAGAN</p>
<p>The investment banking arm of NatWest has acquired JO Hambro Magan, the successful corporate finance boutique. More than 100 senior City executives are set to become millionaires. NatWest Markets have refused to disclose the cost of buying Hambro, but market analysts believe that a basic 20 million stg price could reach 150 million stg. Some of the new contracts are said to be worth as much as two million stg for the best performers.</p>
<p>-- LLOYD'S NAMES FACE FLURRY OF WRITS</p>
<p>The first step by Lloyd's of London towards recovering 500 million stg in outstanding debts has led to the issuing of 240 writs against non-paying Names. The law firm acting for Lloyd's, Dibb Lupton Alsop, has the power to seize homes and assets of Names who refuse demands for payment. Leading Lloyd's personalities to be singled out include Tony Gooda, Sir William Piggot-Brown, Robin Kingsley, Sally Noel and Rupert Galliers-Pratt.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- INSURANCE SWITCH IN DOUBT</p>
<p>The resignation of Paul Smee, the head of life business for the Association of British Insurers and senior executive handling the issue of handing over large parts of health, pensions and long-term care insurance to the private sector, has thrown government plans into doubt. He admitted there had been problems drawing up a plan for action over the Government's programme. But he denied any confrontation with the ABI's members, which include companies such as Prudential, Norwich Union and Royal Sun Alliance.</p>
<p>-- BRITISH GAS APOLOGISES FOR THREATS</p>
<p>British Gas have publically apologised for wrongly demanding payments from 400 customers in southwest England and industry watchdog Clare Spottiswoode has demanded a detailed report from the company into the incident. BG have promised to consider compensating the 150 customers sent incorrect letters so far and admitted it would take several weeks to resolve problems with its computerised billing system.</p>
<p>-- LEESON BOSS CLAIMS HALF A MILLION STG FROM BARINGS</p>
<p>A former Barings Brothers executive and former boss of Nick Leeson, Mary Walz, is claiming half a million stg from the bank for &quot;unpaid bonuses&quot;. She is to take her case to the Stratford industrial tribunal in London's East End. She says the money is owed for work she did before the bank's collapse. It is thought that Ms Walz's claimed bonus is based in part on the huge profits supposedly generated by Mr Leeson's activities.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- REED -ELSEVEIR AND VNU CONSIDER BLENHEIM DEAL</p>
<p>The Dutch publishing group VNU is in talks with Reed-Elseveir over the future of the exhibitions company at the centre of a takeover battle, Blenheim. VNU has discussed various options aimed at resolving the situation with executives from Elseveir. Reed is willing to discuss ways of providing VNU with some of Blenheim's assets in return for the Dutch company's support for an offer for Blenheim from Reed. Such an offer would require the support of Blenheim directors.</p>
<p>-- WARNING ISSUED ON INTERNET BANKING</p>
<p>The Bank of England have issued a warning to depositors to be careful about using an Antiguan bank which has been promoting itself over the Internet using the name of Lord Mancroft, an English peer. He was called in by the Bank to explain the Antiguan bank's operations. The Bank's concern about Internet banking is a result of fears that the new means of communication will put large numbers of banking transactions beyond the reach of supervisors and make it easier to launder money.</p>
<p>-- CHEMICAL FIRMS SET UP MORE JOINT VENTURES</p>
<p>Three of Europe's biggest chemical groups, Shell, BASF, and Hoechst, have announced two new joint ventures with the intention of restructuring the European chemical industry. The moves are part of a general move in the chemical industry to adapt in the face of swings in prices over the last few years and looming over-capacity problems in the years ahead. Tony Cox of Kleinwort Benson Securities said the companies were trying to position themselves and &quot;de-fragment&quot; ahead of a downturn in prices which could come in 1998.</p>
<p>BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
