<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111906" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - European bourses up in hesitant trading.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - European bourses up in hesitant trading.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>European stocks edged upwards in early trade on Friday but the mood was hesitant ahead of U.S. inflation figues due later which will give pointers on interest rates.</p>
<p>But the dollar was unchanged from Thursday's levels with currency dealers reluctant to stick their necks out before the 1230 GMT release of U.S. producer price and retail sales data.</p>
<p>London, Europe's biggest bourse made a healthy start, climbing 0.25 percent on the FTSE index but traders saw only limited gains until the American data was out of the way.</p>
<p>&quot;I think people are going to use the figures as an excuse not to do anything,&quot; said one trader. &quot;If the figures are good, we may well rally. This market is resilient,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>Frankfurt and Paris also showed small gains after all European bourses registered losses on Thursday, unsettled by healthier U.S. employment figures which reignited inflation fears.</p>
<p>The poor performance followed a record-breaking pace by European bourses earlier this week wich largely mirrored the bull market on Wall Street, hitherto driven by rapid growth and low inflation.</p>
<p>European investors closely follow the state of the U.S. economy, the world biggest, because any downturn would quickly be felt on this side of the Atlantic -- hence the focus on Friday's data.</p>
<p>Wall Street itself made losses on Thursday because of jitters over inflation. Economists in a Reuters survey said they expected September's retail sales to rise by 0.2 percent overall and the Producer Price Index to rise by 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, shares climbed modestly in early dealings but were expected to tread water. &quot;This is one of those 'let's wait for the Americans' kind of days,&quot; said a Frankfurt dealer.</p>
<p>Opinion was divided as to whether the DAX index, hovering at the 2,685 level, was taking a breather after its recent spate of record highs or heading for a more dramatic downward correction.</p>
<p>Some dealers said the DAX needed to fall back as low as 2,630 to 2,650 to spark new buying interest.</p>
<p>French shares made the biggest gains, climbing 0.5 percent on the CAC index but trading was thin. &quot;The market is very cautious ahead of the U.S. data, you can see that in the volumes,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The dollar was stuck at late Thursday's levels at the start of dealings characterised by the same caution afflicting the equity markets.</p>
<p>Analysts said Friday's data is likely to indicate little inflation pressure in the U.S. economy. &quot;The overheating fears of the U.S. economy are misplaced,&quot; said Gerard Lyons, chief economist at DKB International.</p>
<p>Data showing inflation growing could hit the U.S. bond market which in turn could hurt the U.S. currency but Lyons saw the dollar's overall uptrend still intact.</p>
<p>There was no noticeable inflationary pressure in Germany or in Europe as a whole, according to Bundesbank council member Ernst Welteke in a speech made Thursday.</p>
<p>Among European currencies, sterling surged against the mark, touching fresh 20-month highs largely on the back of British finance minister Kenneth Clarke's upbeat speech at the ruling Conservative party conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>The pound broke through 2.40 marks in early business and pushed on at 0815 GMT to 2.4081, compared with 2.3943 late Thursday in Europe. It also rose strongly against the dollar to $1.5733, compared with $1.5656.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 0920 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was at 1.5302 marks and 111.32 yen compared with 1.5300 marks and 111.26 yen late in Europe on Thursday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0920 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was up 8.5 points at 4003.2.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was up 7.17 at 2,142.80.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was up 4.08 at 2684.83.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold opened at $382.00 an ounce, compared with Thursday's close of $381.95. Silver began at $5.05, up four cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
