<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="111980" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ takes leap into unknown with new voting system.</title>
<headline>NZ takes leap into unknown with new voting system.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are key facts about New Zealand and the new voting system it is adopting for Saturday's general election.</p>
<p>* GOVERNMENT - Conservative National Party-led coalition</p>
<p>* PARLIAMENT - Single chamber House of Representatives</p>
<p>* PRIME MINISTER - Jim Bolger</p>
<p>* ELECTION - October 12, 1996, polls open 9 a.m. (2000 GMT) and close at 7 p.m. (0600 GMT).</p>
<p>* ELECTION RESULTS - First results shortly after polls close; final official result in 10 days after counting of special votes (those filed by New Zealanders overseas or away from home on polling day).</p>
<p>* NEW VOTING SYSTEM - New Zealand voted in a referendum in 1993 for a Mixed Member Proportional (MMP) system to replace the British-style First Past the Post (FPP) system. Germany is the only other country that uses MMP, in place there since 1949.</p>
<p>Voters get two votes -- one for a party to determine the overall proportion of seats a party will get and the other for a candidate in the voter's geographic constituency.</p>
<p>The total number of MPs in parliament from each party will depend on its share of the party votes. However, a party must win at least five percent of the party vote or at least one constituency seat to receive a proportional allocation of seats in parliament.</p>
<p>The new parliament will usually have 120 MPs (99 under the old system) with 55 list seats, 60 general constituency seats and five Maori constituency seats. More than 120 seats may be allocated if any parties win more constituency seats than the percentage of seats they are entitled to under the list vote.</p>
<p>Twenty-two parties will contest the election.</p>
<p>* MAIN PARTIES -</p>
<p>NATIONAL</p>
<p>Leader: Prime Minister Jim Bolger</p>
<p>Campaigning on its economic record of strong growth, low inflation, budget surpluses and falling unemployment; says it offers economic stability.</p>
<p>LABOUR</p>
<p>Leader: Helen Clark</p>
<p>Campaigning on promise to share more evenly the benefits of 10 years of economic reform. Stresses extra spending on health and education.</p>
<p>ALLIANCE</p>
<p>Leader: Jim Anderton</p>
<p>Advocates free publicly funded-health and education system. Plans to radically alter economy with more steeply progressive tax scale, lifting top income rate to 49 percent from 33 percent and company tax to 40 percent from 33 percent. Expected to back Labour but will not join formal coalition.</p>
<p>NEW ZEALAND FIRST</p>
<p>Leader: Winston Peters</p>
<p>Adopted &quot;Putting New Zealanders First&quot; slogan to reflect its desire to restrict foreign ownership and immigration. Opposed to state asset sales. Wants more social spending but relatively conservative fiscally. Yet to say whether it would go into coalition with Labour or National.</p>
<p>ACT NEW ZEALAND</p>
<p>Leader: Richard Prebble</p>
<p>Wants to reduce government to bare essentials. Plans compulsory health insurance, voucher education, and a flat tax rate at 19.5 percent. Would sell all remaining government-owned businesses and privatise prisons. Will back the National Party.</p>
<p>CHRISTIAN COALITION</p>
<p>Joint leaders: Graeme Lee of Christian Democrats and Graham Capill of Christian Heritage.</p>
<p>Moral-based programme based on family values. Opposes abortion. Would crack down on drugs, pornography, gambling and TV violence.</p>
<p>UNITED</p>
<p>Leader: Clive Matthewson</p>
<p>Formed by seven MPs who switched from National and Labour. Centrist party which supports current economic direction.</p>
<p>* LATEST POLLS - These suggest the three main parties of the centre-left -- Labour, NZ First and the Alliance -- will win more seats than the ruling conservative National Party supported by minor parties Act NZ, United and the Christian Coalition.</p>
<p>An average of the last three polls puts support at (percent): National 32.3, Labour 26.5, NZ First 14.7, Alliance 14.2, Act NZ 5.6, Christian Coalition 3.3, United 0.6. However, United is expected to win a constituency seat entitling it to one MP even if it fails to reach the five percent threshold of votes nationwide.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
