<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112040" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Five people die in attacks on Indonesian churches.</title>
<headline>Five people die in attacks on Indonesian churches.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Five people died when a mob burned nine churches, four Christian schools and a convent in the Indonesian town of Situbondo, a policeman in the town said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true the churches were burnt&quot; on Thursday, the policeman told Reuters by telephone from the town on Java island 800 km (500 miles) east of the capital Jakarta. &quot;The five died inside a church,&quot; he said before the phone was cut off.</p>
<p>He said the crowd also destroyed a court building and cars and caused other damage during the violence around 1 p.m. on Thursday.</p>
<p>Indonesia's nearly 200 million population on the archipelago of 17,500 islands is more than 85 percent Moslem, but the state ideology preaches religious tolerance and recognises the five main religions.</p>
<p>Situbondo is about 160 km (100 miles) east of Indonesia's second city, Surabaya, where a number of attacks on churches were reported in June. The reason for these attacks was not clear.</p>
<p>The policeman said it was yet known what had caused the Situbondo riot or whether it had been organised. A number of people had been detained and investigations were continuing, he added.</p>
<p>A Surabaya-based journalist who went to Situbondo said the riot apparently broke out after a hearing in the court into a case of alleged blasphemy against Islam.</p>
<p>He said several thousand people outside the court during the third hearing into the case called for the accused to be sentenced immediately or handed over to the crowd.</p>
<p>He said another church was burnt in the neighbouring town of Panarukan.</p>
<p>A hall being used by Roman Catholics as a church in a village in east Jakarta was burned down in mid-September. Catholics in the area attributed the attack to religious antagonism towards their presence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
