<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112221" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Siemens, Mosel in $1.7 bln deal.</title>
<headline>Siemens, Mosel in $1.7 bln deal.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's Mosel Vitalic Inc said on Friday it will formally sign a contract with German electronics giant Siemens AG on November 7 to set up a US$1.7 billion venture to produce advanced dynamic random access memory, or DRAM, chips in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Siemens in late September announced a decision to form a venture with Mosel, but mentioned few details.  </p>
<p>&quot;In fact, we already have signed the deal, but a formal signing ceremony with Siemens will be held on November 7,&quot; Mosel vice-president William Chen told Reuters.</p>
<p>The new venture, ProMOS Technologies Inc, will be in Hsinchu, outside Taipei. Mosel will hold 62 percent and Siemens 38 percent.</p>
<p>The venture will operate a chip factory already being constructed by Mosel and set up a joint research and development centre for DRAMs, Chen said.</p>
<p>The venture will produce 64 megabit and 256 megabit DRAMs, he said.  </p>
<p>Both sides will invest $1.7 billion in two stages, with the first stage -- costing $1 billion -- expected to start production in mid-1997, and the second stage -- costing $700 million -- seen to begin production in late 1998, Chen said.</p>
<p>The venture's monthly production capacity will reach 20,000 eight-inch wafers of DRAMs by the end of 1997, and 40,000 wafers by end-1998, Chen said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the recent oversupply situation in the semiconductor industry, keeping on expansion is our long-term development strategy,&quot; Chen said. Mosel is one of the island's leading DRAM chip makers. -- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302019">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
