<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112257" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: EU considering suspension of Burma trade benefits.</title>
<headline>EU considering suspension of Burma trade benefits.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union is considering suspending trade benefits accorded to Burma because of human rights abuses in the Southeast Asian country, according to the EU's Irish presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;The European Union is giving active consideration to further possible restrictions in relation to Burma,&quot; Irish Foreign Minister Dick Spring said in a statement released late on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said the EU Commission was completing an inquiry into possible future suspension of trade benefits available to Burma under the generalised system of preferences.</p>
<p>Spring said he deplored &quot;the practice of torture, summary and arbitrary executions, forced labour, abuse of women, political arrests, forced displacements of the population and restrictions on the fundamental rights of freedom, of speech, movement and assembly which have been reported in the recent past.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU recently adopted a declaration deploring wide-scale detentions of supporters of Burma's National League for Democracy and the blockading of access to the residence of its leader, Aung San Suu Kyi.</p>
<p>&quot;The European Union called for the immediate and unconditional release of all those who have been detained and to allow for the resumption of normal activties by the National League for Democracy,&quot; Spring said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
