<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112274" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Neste new contracts clear derivs risks.</title>
<headline>Neste new contracts clear derivs risks.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish oil and energy group Neste Oy, reporting on Friday a January-August loss partly on crude oil derivatives trading, said it now had contracts to eliminate risks on contracts due by end-year.</p>
<p>&quot;Neste has concluded new contracts in order to eliminate risks associated with the complex derivatives due by the end of 1996 and cancelled instruments of similar nature due in 1997 and 1998,&quot; Neste said in a statement.</p>
<p>It earlier revealed a 495 million markka &quot;sales margin deficit&quot; on crude derivatives to end-August 1997.</p>
<p>It warned on July 25 this would be around 285 million to end-1996 at that day's prices.  </p>
<p>Neste said the sale agreed this week of its shareholding in Swedish Sands Petroleum AB -- to be completed on October 18 -- would generate a capital gain of around 60 million markka.</p>
<p>Despite falling to a January-August loss, Neste said in the statement with its results that its solidity had improved during the review period.</p>
<p>Interest-bearing debt fell by 2.2 billion markka to 10.75 billion, its equity-to-assets ratio rose to 39 percent from 37 percent and gearing fell to 76 percent from 77 percent.</p>
<p>Neste said its own industrial performance had improved.  </p>
<p>Its result was mainly pressured by the crude trading loss and a poorer performance from  Borealis which it owns 50-50 markka fall in gains on fixed asset sales.</p>
<p>Neste booked a 131 million markka operating loss on associated companies, which include Borealis, against a 477 million profit in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>But Neste said its exploration and production division doubled operating profit to 245 million from 121 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The value of Neste's oil and gas reserves has also increased substantially,&quot; Neste noted.</p>
<p>It said its proven oil and gas reserves had increased, mainly due to the Asgard field in Norway which gained a development licence from the start of summer.</p>
<p>Oil production in January-August averaged 33,000 barrels a day and associated gas sales were 600 barrels a day equivalent, Neste said.</p>
<p>&quot;Neste's oil and gas production rose 17 percent on the comparable period in 1995, corresponding to an annual production of about 1.7 million tonnes,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>In oil, which booked an 81 million markka operating loss in January-August down from a 535 million profit, Neste said its crude oil refining margin had picked up slightly in September after shrinking &quot;clearly below the long-term average&quot; in summer.</p>
<p>Its energy division, which includeds gas, improved operating profit to 245 million markka from 227 million.</p>
<p>Natural gas sales totalled 22.7 Terawatt-hours, up eight percent on the previous year and LPG (liquefied petroleum gas) and heat sales also improved, Neste said.</p>
<p>Neste also said it has started trading actively on Finland's new electricity exchange which started operations in August, buying some of the power for its refineries on the exchange.</p>
<p>In chemicals, which saw operating profit more than halve to 223 million markka from 549 million, Neste said demand for oxo products in coatings and plasticisers had weakened.</p>
<p>But demand for adhesive resins continued extremely strong in North America, although the market was still gloomy in Europe.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +35 80 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
