<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112323" id="root" date="1996-10-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SMH rejects negative study on Smart Car.</title>
<headline>SMH rejects negative study on Smart Car.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>SMH chairman Nicolas Hayek rejected a Standard &amp; Poor's study warning that automobile project Smart Car posed risks not yet reflected in the watchmaker's share price.</p>
<p>Hayek told Reuters risks were low and profit margins were high in the joint venture between Suisse Microelectronique et d'Horologerie (SMH) and Mercedes-Benz.</p>
<p>Hayek said he did not accept S&amp;P Marketscope's finding that Smart Car sales targets may be wildly optimistic.</p>
<p>He also noted that SMH holds a 49 percent stake in Smart Car maker Micro Compact Car (MCC), spreading risks with Mercedes.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if true, any low sales would only come in 1998, not in 1996 or 1997. They would have no effect on our results for now,&quot; Hayek said after a regular meeting of the MCC board, which combines top SMH and Mercedes executives.</p>
<p>&quot;SMH and Mercedes and all other bodies that have studied the project say the risks are low and the profit margin is large,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Hayek said SMH shares were moving up again on Friday after losing 2.9 percent on Thursday on news of the S&amp;P study, which concluded that the risks of losses were much greater than generally appreciated.</p>
<p>SMH bearer shares, which are traditionally among the most volatile on the Swiss Exchange, added about four francs in morning trade but at midday were back around the Thursday close of 822.</p>
<p>Hayek said the S&amp;P study was unreliable because it was based on speculation about a new product, the colourful two-seater city car, rather than any existing type of automobile.</p>
<p>&quot;All speculation from high to low (about Smart Car sales) are wrong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have made our own studies and the results are very different from those of S&amp;P,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>MCC plans to launch the Smart Car in early 1998 and aims to sell about 200,000 units a year by 2000.</p>
<p>Hayek, whose watchmaking group is home of major brands including Swatch, said he was used to people predicting problems for his new ventures.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not new. In my life I have launched many new products and people always say something is not possible,&quot; he said, pointing to the success of Swatch in reviving world demand for low priced Swiss watches rather than just luxury pieces.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Newsroom, +41-1-631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
