<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112456" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-JUVENTUS COACH LIPPI SET TO EXTEND CONTRACT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JUVENTUS COACH LIPPI SET TO EXTEND CONTRACT.</headline>
<dateline>TURIN, Italy 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Juventus coach Marcello Lippi, who steered the Turin team to European Cup victory last season, is set to stay at the Italian club after his current contract expires at the end of the season.</p>
<p>Umberto Agnelli, the club's honorary president, told reporters on Saturday that Juventus and Lippi had agreed that he would sign a new deal.</p>
<p>&quot;We will fix the details after Wednesday,&quot; said Agnelli, without revealing any figures. Juventus play a European Cup Champions' League match against Rapid Vienna in Austria on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lippi has been mentioned as a possible successor to beleaguered Italian national coach Arrigo Sacchi, whose position looks increasingly doomed after poor recent results.</p>
<p>An opinion poll for RAI radio on Saturday showed that 54 percent of Italians wanted Sacchi out. Some 23 percent had no preference and the remainder were pro-Sacchi.</p>
<p>Under-21 coach Cesare Maldini was the top choice as a replacement, followed by Lazio president Dino Zoff, Lippi, Real Madrid coach Fabio Capello and Bayern Munich's Giovanni Trapattoni.</p>
<p>However both Agnelli and Lippi appeared to dampen any speculation linking the Juventus coach with Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;The national team can have no bearing on the negotiations between Juventus and Lippi,&quot; said Agnelli.</p>
<p>Lippi said he believed the ideal position was to renew a contract from year to year &quot;because if you win you have more power over your contract and if you don't get the results it is not right to stay on under a cloud.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But the case of a great club like Juventus is a little different,&quot; he added, hinting at a long-term renewal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TURIN, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
