<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112448" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: GOLF-RIVAL CAPTAINS SET UP MADRID SHOOT-OUT.</title>
<headline>GOLF-RIVAL CAPTAINS SET UP MADRID SHOOT-OUT.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tom Kite, who chipped in five times for a 64, and Seve Ballesteros, who twice holed out from over 80 yards for a 69, were in line on Saturday for a Ryder Cup captain's shoot-out in the final round of the Oki Pro-Am.</p>
<p>But Argentinian Angel Cabrera, who shot a course-record 62 to take the outright lead on 202, 14 under par, and David Gilford, who scored 66 to take third place on 206, may have different views.</p>
<p>Kite is lying second on 203, just one shot behind Cabrera while Ballesteros is back in fourth place on 207 but both these outstanding golfers believe they can take the title on Sunday.</p>
<p>Kite is in Spain to photograph Valderrama, where next year's Ryder Cup match will be played, but said: &quot;I'm really surprised not to be in the lead. You can hardly believe that I could shoot 64 and lose ground. But this guy Cabrere must have played awfully well.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the fact I've had a poor year in the States I'm not surprised I'm playing well. Hell, I always think I'm going to play well. That's the only way to succeed.&quot;</p>
<p>Ballesteros had one of his old-time rounds where he was never quite sure where he was going next.</p>
<p>He went out of bounds for a double-bogey six at the second, holed out with a sand wedge from 80 yards for an eagle two at the third, went into the water for a bogey five at the fifth and holed a wedge from 150 yards for another eagle two at the 14th.</p>
<p>&quot;I had to fight at every hole,&quot; said the Spanish maestro. &quot;This is the first time I have signed a card with two eagles at par fours on my card but I never really found my rhythm. But tomorrow is another day and I can still win.&quot;</p>
<p>Cabrera, who had two eagle threes, at the 11th and 16th, in an inward half of 29 and six birdies also on his card, is in his first season on the European Tour. But he said he would not be nervous on Sunday playing with Kite and Gilford instead of Ballesteros.</p>
<p>Gilford, who has been having a quiet year, had a seven-birdie round and said: &quot;It's nice to be in contention again.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
