<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112421" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-OGRIN USES HOME FIELD ADVANTAGE TO TAKE TEXAS OPEN LEAD.</title>
<headline>GOLF-OGRIN USES HOME FIELD ADVANTAGE TO TAKE TEXAS OPEN LEAD.</headline>
<dateline>SAN ANTONIO, Texas 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>David Ogrin took advantage of his home field advantage to secure a one-stroke lead after the second round of the $1.2 million Texas Open golf tournament on Friday.</p>
<p>Ogrin, who lives nearby and has played the LaCantera course some 50 times, used his intimate knowledge of the 7,001-yard layout to compile nine birdies in a seven-under-par 65 round.</p>
<p>The Texan heads into weekend play at nine-under 135, one stroke ahead of Jay Haas, who fired a 66. Bob Tway (67), budding superstar Tiger Woods (68), and overnight co-leader John Huston (71) were two shots back at 137.</p>
<p>Ogrin put together two impressive streaks, reeling off five successive birdies from the fifth hole, and four in a row beginning at the 12th.</p>
<p>&quot;Those two runs made the 65,&quot; said Ogrin, 38, who has not won since joining the PGA Tour in 1983.</p>
<p>&quot;It didn't surprise me at all that I did this, although 65 is by far my best round on the course.&quot;</p>
<p>Haas, a two-time Texas Open winner at its previous venue of Oak Hill, also feels at home at the event's new site.</p>
<p>Starting his round at the 10th hole, Haas made only one birdie on the back nine, before charging home with five on the front side.</p>
<p>Woods, in contrast, blistered the back nine after a sluggish front nine. He dropped two shots on the outward half, primarily as a result of four-putting the sixth green, where he rushed because his group was being timed for slow play.</p>
<p>Woods negotiated the back nine in 30 strokes, thanks to six birdies and three pars, to move into the hunt for his second consecutive victory.</p>
<p>&quot;Going into the weekend you want to be in with a chance to win,&quot; said Woods, the three-time U.S. Amateur champion who won last week's Las Vegas Invitational in only his fifth start since turning professional.</p>
<p>Defending champion Duffy Waldorf bogeyed his final hole to miss by one stroke the cut, which fell at one-over 145.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN ANTONIO, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
