<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112519" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Fifty villagers killed in attacks in eastern Zaire.</title>
<headline>Fifty villagers killed in attacks in eastern Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean gunmen killed at least 50 villagers in attacks this week in the Goma region of eastern Zaire, forcing an estimated 9,000 people to flee, aid officials said on Saturday.</p>
<p>They said violence in Goma, already destabilised by some 700,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees, followed ethnic conflict to the south which was also threatening a new humanitarian disaster.</p>
<p>Aid workers in Goma and Nairobi said between 50 and 60 people were killed in a series of attacks on Bambu village and other settlements from Wednesday night by members of Ingilima, an armed group of indigenous Zaireans in North Kivu province.</p>
<p>They said the raids prompted some 9,000 Hutu villagers to flee for more than 50 km (30 miles) on foot to Rutshuru town, where on Saturday they were camping around a soccer pitch.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the Hutus are farmers who have been here for generations but some of the people attacked were 1994 refugees from Rwanda, including Interahamwe (Hutu militiamen), living outside camps,&quot; an aid worker said by telephone from Goma.</p>
<p>The Ingilima are opposed to all Banyarwanda, majority Hutus and minority Tutsis originally from what are now neighbouring Rwanda and Burundi. Banyarwanda are the majority in Goma region.</p>
<p>Fearing they will lose political power and land following the influx of Rwandan Hutu refugees in 1994, Ingilima have waged an increasingly militant campaign to force the Banyarwanda out.</p>
<p>A U.N. report released on Friday warned of a looming disaster in North Kivu because of the mounting ethnic conflict and partly blamed the crisis on incitement by Zairean officials.</p>
<p>The report, by Chilean human rights investigator Robert Garreto, said hundreds and perhaps thousands had died in attacks on peoples who have moved into north Kivu in the last century.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghjali said this week the situation had recently deteriorated and remained explosive with dozens of people killed and the refugee problem unresolved.</p>
<p>An aid source said Goma was calm but Tutsis, the bulk of the Banyarwanda in the town, had left fearing for their safety.</p>
<p>He said tension rose after a senior Zairean armed forces officer visiting from the capital Kinshasa last week appeared on television in Goma city and made an anti-Banyarwanda speech.</p>
<p>Aid sources reported Uvira town calm on Saturday but said some armed local residents patrolled overnight trying to protect property from Zairean soldiers who were sporadically looting.</p>
<p>The conflict in South Kivu including Uvira is between Zairean troops, indigenous Zairean tribes and the Banyamulenge, ethnic Tutsis who left what is now Rwanda up to 200 years ago.</p>
<p>An aid worker in radio contact with Uvira said soldiers were on their worst behaviour in town when returning from fighting Banyamulenge in the hills about 70 km (40 miles) from the town.</p>
<p>&quot;They are pretty wild when they get back, particularly if they have lost some men in the fighting,&quot; the aid worker said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, a Reuters Television cameraman filmed an estimated 750 Zairean youths roaming the streets of Uvira armed with spears, machineguns, rifles, knives and good luck charms.</p>
<p>Zairean antipathy towards the Banyamulenge started a witch hunt this week after authorities on Tuesday gave the estimated 300,000 ethnic Tutsis a week to leave their high plateau home.</p>
<p>Some Uvira residents cited economic reasons for the official crusade against the Tutsis and said Banyamulenge fighters were more than a match for the notoriously badly-disciplined army.</p>
<p>&quot;The Zairean army is a joke. They are not prepared to fight a real war and when the first bullet whistles past they will all just run away,&quot; one foreign businessman in Uvira told Reuters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
