<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112582" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia rights body links government to riots.</title>
<headline>Indonesia rights body links government to riots.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's official human rights watchdog on Saturday linked the authorities to the start of a riot which rocked Jakarta in July and said five people died and 149 were injured in the violence.</p>
<p>In its final official report on the July 27 incident, it said 23 people were still missing and called on the authorities to continue to search for them and determine whether they were alive or dead.</p>
<p>It said there were two phases to the events: a factional assault backed by the security forces on the headquarters of the minority Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI, and subsequent rioting which it said was influenced by the violent takeover of the PDI building.</p>
<p>The assault on the headquarters followed a rebel PDI congress financed by the government in the north Sumatran city of Medan in June in which Megawati Sukarnoputri was ousted as part leader by parliamentary deputy speaker Surjadi.</p>
<p>&quot;The takeover of the (PDI) secretariat on July 27 was an action that was carried out violently by the executive board of the Medan congress and a group of its supporters, together with the security forces,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;This was the result of the creation of open conflict in the PDI, where the government had involved itself excessively and in a biased way out of proportion to its function as a manager of politics and security.</p>
<p>&quot;The social disturbances that broke out and spread... were influenced by the use of violence in the takeover of the secretariat,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Political analysts have said the government backed the ousting of Megawati, daughter of Indonesia's late founding president Sukarno, over concern that she might draw votes from the ruling Golkar party in general elections next year.</p>
<p>The commission reaffirmed its findings of a preliminary report in August which said five people had died and 149 were injured in the riots, the worst in Jakarta in more than two decades which caused $43 million damage.</p>
<p>The government had challenged the body, set up by presidential decree in 1993, to prove its findings after the military said there were only four deaths and nobody missing in the riots.</p>
<p>The commission revised down its earlier total of 74 people missing to 23 and said that as of Saturday, 136 people remained in custody.</p>
<p>&quot;The term missing means they have not yet returned home to their address of origin, they cannot be contacted, they are travelling and/or they are possibly dead,&quot; secretary-general Baharuddin Lopa said reading the six-page report.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission recommends... the government through its authorised agencies look for those people who are lost and the possibility that people have died still needs to be checked.&quot;</p>
<p>The report named the dead as Asmayadi Soleh, 19, Slamet, 52, Suganda Siagian, 21, Uju bin Asep, 31, and Sariwan, 40.</p>
<p>It said doctors' reports or autopsies showed the first two died of wounds from blunt instruments, the third received fatal burns, the fourth had a heart attack and the fifth was shot. It was not known who had shot him.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday 64 of 124 people arrested in and around the party headquarters went on trial. Lawyers say all are members or supporters of Megawati's faction of the PDI.</p>
<p>The commission called on the government not to discriminate and to take legal action against the 200 Surjadi supporters who attacked the office.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
