<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112533" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnian local elections seen &quot;at risk&quot;.</title>
<headline>Bosnian local elections seen &quot;at risk&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>SARAEJVO 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Security fears in Bosnia mean plans to hold municipal elections next month are &quot;substantially at risk&quot;, the international body supervising postwar polls in the former Yugoslav republic said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), facing threats from the Bosnian Serbs to pull out of the municipal elections set for November 23 and 24, issued an urgent appeal, saying: &quot;All sides must cool it.&quot;</p>
<p>OSCE spokesman David Foley said decisions on whether to proceed, with the polls rapidly approaching, must be taken immediately. &quot;The time is now,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Postponement of the municipal elections, which follow September 14 elections for a presidency and parliament, would be a major blow to the Bosnian peace process and to the prestige of the international community.</p>
<p>The OSCE mission head in Bosnia, Robert Frowick of the United States, has been holding urgent talks with the Bosnian Serb leadership to try to persuade them to take a full part in the electoral process.</p>
<p>U.S. Assistant Secretary of State John Kornblum was on Friday having last ditch talks with Bosnian Serb President Biljana Plavsic.</p>
<p>Plavsic said earlier this week that the Serbs might hold their own local elections without OSCE supervision.</p>
<p>Then on Friday she said a security crisis surrounding the resettlement of Moslems in Serb areas made it &quot;almost impossible&quot; for the Serbs to participate in the elections.</p>
<p>The resettlement of Moslem villagers in Serb areas of northern Bosnia has stoked up tension, with Serbs arresting Moslems for possession of arms and Moslems accusing Serbs of blowing up houses they want to occupy.</p>
<p>Foley called for an end to &quot;gamesmanship and brinkmanship&quot;, saying the elections were a crucial part of the Bosnian peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;There are significant fears that if the current security situation were to continue from now to the municipal elections, they would be put substantially at risk,&quot; he said, adding: &quot;Decisions must be made immediately.&quot;</p>
<p>Putting off the elections would pose a major security headache. NATO is set to begin a rapid withdrawal of its 58,000 peacekeepers after the November polling date, with the drawdown expected to be complete in January.</p>
<p>The international community has been putting intense pressure on the Bosnian Serbs to fall into line and participate in the elections, threatening to exclude them from finaical aid for post-war reconstruction.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAEJVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
