<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112615" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan approves record low China investments.</title>
<headline>Taiwan approves record low China investments.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan said on Saturday it approved the lowest number of investment projects ever in China for a single month in September, indicating local companies were heeding government advice to slow their mainland businesses.</p>
<p>The economics ministry said in a statement it approved 16 indirect Taiwanese investment projects in China worth US$46.4 million in September, down from 31 worth $122 million in August.</p>
<p>The government, fearing that the island's economy would become overdependent on China's market, has been urging businesses to cool their pace of investment in the mainland.</p>
<p>&quot;The (record low number of cases) shows the government's current investment policy towards the mainland has received the cooperation of our enterprises,&quot; the ministry said in the statement.</p>
<p>From January to September, the ministry said it approved investment of $956 million in 285 projects to China, down 90 cases but up $127.53 million from the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;This shows that our investments to China are becoming larger-scale projects,&quot; the ministry said.</p>
<p>Taiwan has banned direct investments to China since the two separated after a civil war in 1949. All projects must be routed through a third territory, mostly Hong Kong.</p>
<p>The ministry added it approved $345.7 million foreign investments in Taiwan in September, up $145.97 million from August.</p>
<p>It attributed the rise to foreign firms applying to set up ventures in Taiwan's newly-opened mobile phone industry -- including a $123.6 million project by U.S.-based SBC Communications Inc.</p>
<p>The government part-liberalised the telecommunications industry in January, opening up some areas for private and foreign investments.</p>
<p>The ministry approved $156.26 million in 32 cases of Taiwan's overseas investments in countries other than China, down nine cases but up $46.835 million in value from August.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
