<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112669" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole reluctant to press Clinton character issue.</title>
<headline>Dole reluctant to press Clinton character issue.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>For months, the so-called character issue has loomed as Republican Bob Dole's ultimate election campaign weapon against President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>Now, with time running out before the November 5 vote, it looks as if Dole may never use it.</p>
<p>In this week's vice presidential debate, Dole's running mate, Jack Kemp, made it even harder for the Republican nominee to attack Clinton on ethical or moral grounds.</p>
<p>&quot;It is beneath Bob Dole to go after anyone personally,&quot; Kemp said, striking a high moral tone that Dole will now violate at his own risk.</p>
<p>Before the campaign got going, Republican strategists salivated at the prospect of exploiting Clinton's alleged womanizing, as well as the Arkansas investment and banking tangle known as Whitewater.</p>
<p>The Clintons are still under congressional and independent counsel investigation on Whitewater issues, and some of their Arkansas associates have been convicted on bank fraud charges.</p>
<p>But Dole has refused to touch Whitewater -- and even though polls show voters do not rate Clinton high on moral character, they do not seem to care.</p>
<p>Dole's last real chance to attack the president's ethics and morals may come in the second and final presidential debate in San Diego, California, next Wednesday.</p>
<p>Trailing in the polls with Election Day three-and-a-half weeks away, Dole is being urged by some Republicans to go for broke. But that would be both difficult and dangerous.</p>
<p>&quot;Dole is facing the most difficult decision of his campaign,&quot; said Democratic political consultant Bob Beckel.</p>
<p>&quot;The only chance he has now, barring some unforeseen event, is that he's going to have to go after Clinton and it's going to have to be on character. There ain't no room for 'soft-and-fuzzy' left for Bob Dole,&quot; said Beckel.</p>
<p>The Republican candidate himself seems torn. In an interview with the Chicago Tribune this week, he said he was walking &quot;a very fine line, because there's a myth out there that Bob Dole is mean.&quot; At the same time, Dole promised &quot;a few surprises&quot; in San Diego.</p>
<p>He has had many opportunities to go after Clinton's character, but has ducked them all, most recently in the first presidential debate last Sunday.</p>
<p>Asked in an ABC Nightline interview on Thursday whether he would rather lose as a gentleman or win rough, Dole said: &quot;I like to win but there are certain limits. I can't see myself getting into the mud here the last three weeks ... Whatever happens, I want to be at peace with myself when it's over.&quot;</p>
<p>He has preferred to attack Clinton's record, portraying the president as a man who breaks his promises. &quot;It's about trust, trust, trust, trust, trust,&quot; he said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Some of Dole's allies are losing patience with this approach. Former Education Secretary William Bennett, compiler of the best-selling &quot;Book of Virtues,&quot; told reporters on Friday he thought the Dole campaign was going easy on Clinton.</p>
<p>Bennett, who was campaigning with Dole, said he and other Dole surrogates would start raising Whitewater and other scandals in public appearances starting next week.</p>
<p>In a subsequent interview with CBS-TV's &quot;CBS Evening News,&quot; Bennett said he would not be surprised if Clinton was indicted after the election.</p>
<p>&quot;I am saying that there are so many serious questions, the possibility of indictment is very real,&quot; he said. &quot;I think all of these things are going to come to roost, and the American people are going to experience tremendous regret about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole may calculate he has more to lose by personally going on the offensive. He clearly does not want to be remembered as a candidate who not only lost but lost gracelessly.</p>
<p>&quot;The character issue has become the nuclear weapon of the campaign. You can't use it without blowing yourself up as well,&quot; said John Geer, a political scientist at Vanderbilt University in Nashville, Tennessee.</p>
<p>&quot;Dole especially is badly placed to attack Clinton because of his own reputation as a hatchet man,&quot; Geer said.</p>
<p>Throughout the campaign, Dole has been fighting to rid himself of a harsh image which, fairly or unfairly, has clung to him since he went aggressively after Democrat Walter Mondale in a vice presidential debate back in 1976.</p>
<p>Voters this year have made it clear they hate personal attacks and seem ready to severely punish the first candidate to go negative.</p>
<p>This week, Dole took considerable criticism just for referring to Clinton as &quot;Bozo,&quot; in responding to a well-wisher in a handshake line who had urged him to go after &quot;Bozo.&quot;</p>
<p>Even if Dole did decide to go negative, the San Diego debate format will make that hard to do. The encounter is set up as a &quot;town hall meeting&quot; with undecided voters providing the audience and asking the questions.</p>
<p>The betting is that he will decide to keep the tone civilised and leave the character issue alone.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
