<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112797" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Sacked Bangladesh army chief wants job back.</title>
<headline>Sacked Bangladesh army chief wants job back.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dismissed Bangladesh army chief Lieutenant-General Abu Saleh Mohammad Nasim has asked Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to reinstate him in his previous job, the Banglabazar Patrika said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Dhaka-based daily said Nasim had written to Hasina saying then president Abdur Rahman Biswas, who retired on Tuesday, had no legal or constitutional authority to fire him.</p>
<p>&quot;The president's act was non-judice, motivated and incompatiable to law,&quot; the newspaper quoted Nasim's letter as saying.</p>
<p>The newspaper report could not be confirmed by the prime minister's office. Nasim was also not available for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;Legally I am still on the job... and I want it to be practically restored to me,&quot; the newspaper quoted Nasim as saying.</p>
<p>Biswas was also the acting defence minister after prime minister Begum Khaleda Zia's government resigned in March following a long-running campaign of opposition-sponsored strikes.</p>
<p>He fired Nasim on May 20 for for not obeying orders to retire two senior army officers.</p>
<p>Shahabuddin Ahmed, a former chief justice, took over as Bangladesh's new president last week.</p>
<p>Nasim apparently decided to wait until the departure of Biswas to take up his case with the new government, but political analysts believe it unlikely he would get back his old job.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be too dangerous... and upset the delicate balance in the armed forces,&quot; one analyst said on Saturday, without elaborating.</p>
<p>But Nasim could be formally retired with all benefits and privileges. A sacked officer is denied these.</p>
<p>Nasim's dismissal provoked a near mutiny by his followers in garrisons outside the capital city.</p>
<p>They returned to their barracks after troops loyal to the president secured Dhaka with tanks and detained Nasim and six other officers.</p>
<p>They were freed on June 14, two days after Hasina's Awami League won paarliamentary elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
