<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112711" id="root" date="1996-10-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German gunman frees hostages after volley of shots.</title>
<headline>German gunman frees hostages after volley of shots.</headline>
<byline>Michael Able</byline>
<dateline>NEUENSTEIN, Germany 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A convicted criminal described as a &quot;psychopathic&quot; by German police held six hostages at gunpoint for 14 tense hours in a small town bank office in southwestern Germany before surrendering on Saturday.</p>
<p>The 25-year-old man was armed with three pistols and had threatened to kill the six hostages if his ransom demands of five million marks ($3 million) and a getaway car were not met.</p>
<p>The all-night ordeal, which started after an attempted robbery went wrong, came to a bloodless end at dawn when the gunman surrendered peacefully moments after firing a salvo of shots into the bank's ceiling.</p>
<p>None of the three men and three women seized was hurt during the standoff in the small rural town of Neuenstein, which is about 50 km (30 miles) east of Heidelberg.</p>
<p>Police did not name the man but said he had previous convictions for various crimes, including attempted extortion. He had been released from prison in July.</p>
<p>&quot;This man developed almost neurotic, pyschopathic tendencies,&quot; local prosecutor Roland Kleinschroth told a news conference, adding the man said he loved the hostages one minute but would then fire a shot into the ceiling the next.</p>
<p>&quot;He said at one point 'I have to motivate myself for this now',&quot; Kleinschroth said. &quot;He kept telling the hostages he didn't want to hurt them and that he cared for them. He was very obliging.&quot;</p>
<p>But on the other hand, police said, the man would not let his captives -- four bank employees, a customer and a cleaner -- use the bank's toilets.</p>
<p>Some of the hostages were tied up during the night and all were given sedatives by the hostage-taker, who police said had apparently planned the robbery a few days in advance.</p>
<p>The drama began late on Friday afternoon just before the bank was due to close. Police believe the man had been trying to rob the bank and took the when the hold-up went wrong.</p>
<p>A car filled with the ransom money was brought to the scene in the early hours of Saturday morning.</p>
<p>The talks began to make progress once the man's lawyer and social worker were brought in, police said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strategy was to try to solve this situation on the spot,&quot; said Rudolf Thoma, the police officer in charge of the operation. &quot;We managed to achieve that.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He made demands without really wanting what he was asking for and then changing his demands or combining the next demand with the previous demand,&quot; he said. &quot;That cost the negotiation process a lot of time and patience.&quot;</p>
<p>The man originally set a deadline of 10 p.m. (2000 GMT) on Friday night for his demands to be met but later cancelled the ultimatum, police said.</p>
<p>He had threatened to shoot hostages if anyone approached the building, police said, and repeated his threats in telephone to calls to local media organisations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEUENSTEIN, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
