<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112866" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-YANKEES BEAT ORIOLES TO REACH WORLD SERIES.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-YANKEES BEAT ORIOLES TO REACH WORLD SERIES.</headline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Yankees powered their way to their first World Series in 15 years, using three homers for six runs in the third inning on the way to a 6-4 victory over the Baltimore Orioles.</p>
<p>The home runs -- by Jim Leyritz, Cecil Fielder and Darryl Strawberry -- were more than enough for Andy Pettitte (1-0), who pitched eight strong innings as the Yankees closed out the American League Championship Series, four games to one.</p>
<p>Including this series, the Yankees were an amazing 9-0 at Baltimore's Camden Yards.</p>
<p>Pettitte, the leading candidate for the AL Cy Young Award as the league's best pitcher with 21 games this season, allowed just three hits, including solo homers to Todd Zeile in the sixth and Eddie Murray in the eighth.</p>
<p>The Orioles made it close in the ninth when John Wetteland allowed a leadoff walk to Zeile and Bobby Bonilla hit a two-run homer with two outs. But Cal Ripken grounded to short and the long throw from Derek Jeter beat a diving Ripken at first base for the final out.</p>
<p>The Yankees, baseball's most storied franchise, will appear in their record 34th World Series when they host either Atlanta or St. Louis in Game One of the 1996 Series next Saturday night. The Yankees' last appearance was in 1981 when they lost to the Los Angeles Dodgers in six games.</p>
<p>The man who waited the longest for a trip to baseball's showcase was Yankees manager Joe Torre, who has participated in 4,272 games as a player and manager and will now be part of his first World Series.</p>
<p>It has been a difficult season for Torre, who endured the death of one brother and another brother desperately awaits a heart transplant in a New York hospital.</p>
<p>All three homers were allowed by Scott Erickson, who became the first pitcher in ALCS history to surrender three homers in an inning. But Erickson might have escaped serious damage if not for a key error by second baseman Roberto Alomar, who won his sixth straight Gold Glove as the leagues best defensive player last week.</p>
<p>Leyritz homered to right on a 3-2 pitch to open the third and Jeter singled to centre with one out. Wade Boggs reached on an infield single before Bernie Williams hit a grounder that went through Alomar's legs, allowing Jeter to score. Boggs was thrown out at home on a fielder's choice grounder.</p>
<p>Fielder then unloaded a three-run homer to left. He was just 3-for-18 in the series but drove in eight runs.</p>
<p>Strawberry followed with a mammoth homer to centre field on a 2-2 pitch. It was his third homer in two games.</p>
<p>Erickson lasted five innings, allowing seven hits.</p>
<p>The Orioles set a major-league record with 257 homers this season. But the Yankees won the long-ball battle this series. The Yankees hit the third-lowest number of homers in the AL this season (162) before going deep 10 times in the series.</p>
<p>Baltimore hit nine homers in the series.</p>
<p>The Yankees won the series opener controversially, when Jeter was allowed a home run after a fan interfered with the ball. But New York left little doubt as to its superiority by winning the final three games of the series at Camden Yards. The Yankees won all nine games in Baltimore this season.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
