<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112988" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: St Andrew relics draw Romanian crowds, politicians.</title>
<headline>St Andrew relics draw Romanian crowds, politicians.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Huge crowds and campaigning politicians descended on Romania's northeast city of Iasi on Sunday in a pilgrimage to remains believed to be those of St Andrew.</p>
<p>Romanian Orthodox Church leaders had the relics of Andrew, who is said to have spread the gospel among ancient Romanians 2,000 years ago, flown from Patras shrine in Greece to Iasi on Saturday for week-long ceremonies marking a local saint's day.</p>
<p>Romanian state television showed left-wing President Ion Iliescu among crowds packing the Iasi metropolitan cathedral on Sunday. Iliescu was ending a tour of northeast Romania, once his electoral stronghold, on his campaign for November 3 polls.</p>
<p>Six of Iliescu's challengers, including his two main rivals, opposition Democratic Convention bloc leader Emil Constantinescu and ex-Prime Minister Petre Roman, are expected to visit Andrew's relics on Monday.</p>
<p>A skull said to be that of Andrew was displayed in a silver casket before thousands of worshippers outside Iasi cathedral, along with relics of the city's patron saint Paraschiva.</p>
<p>Andrew, one of the 12 Apostles whom Christ sent to preach the gospel, is believed to have travelled northward, across what is now Romania's Black Sea coast, around the year A.D. 70.</p>
<p>Official census data show that more than 86 percent of Romanians belong to the mainstream Orthodox church, which has a centuries-old tradition of cooperation with state authorities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
