<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112927" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Intel, other earnings.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/Intel, other earnings.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The bellwether of bellwethers, Intel Corp, reports net on Monday and kicks off the main part of the third quarter earnings season.</p>
<p>Intel is the highlight as far as technology stocks are concerned but companies as diverse as Compaq Computer Corp, Coca-Cola and Chase Manhattan Corp are due to report this week.  </p>
<p>Also reporting net this week will be the Big Three Detroit automakers -- Chrysler Corp, General Motors Corp and Ford Motor Co.</p>
<p>Some analysts say the peak in earnings momentum has passed and that the techs have gone too far to be influenced even by higher than expected net. Others expect an earnings season which will compare favorably with the second quarter.  </p>
<p>&quot;Given the fact that Nasdaq made a new high, it will be difficult for the techs to celebrate nine ways from Sunday even if they report good earnings,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, analyst at Prudential Securities. &quot;The questions are will you hit the estimate and, if you do, is it good enough.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that with some high techs trading at 80 times earnings, investors expect net to be up to par with &quot;whisper&quot; expectations, an informal target which is higher than official estimates on the Street.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you don't hit this whisper number, they will take you down on that. You live by momentum and you die by momentum,&quot; Wachtel said.</p>
<p>Michael Metz, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said that earnings momentum would indeed slow as the best of the earnings for a while were behind us.</p>
<p>&quot;The peak of earnings momentum is behind us,&quot; he said. &quot;Momentum will slow and we'll see pressure on corporate profit margins. Wages will increase, the benefits of downsizing are behind us and the strong dollar will have a negative impact on the translation of profits from multinationals.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
