<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112919" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: CROWN TO FOLLOW FUNDAMENTALS, NOT ERM - DEALERS.</title>
<headline>CROWN TO FOLLOW FUNDAMENTALS, NOT ERM - DEALERS.</headline>
<byline>Simon Haydon</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Swedish crown is likely to obey bullish economic fundamentals in trading on Monday rather than take fright at there being one less currency outside the EU's Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM), analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Stockholm-based Treasury heads said there was a possibility the crown and long bonds could come under pressure for a day or two on a sentiment of uncertainty over Swedish commitment to ERM or European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>But they said consistently bright macro-economic news from Sweden in recent months would govern trade.</p>
<p>Carl B. Hamilton, the influential Chief Economist of Sweden's Handelsbanken, said Swedish political credibility had been damaged by the Finnish decision to adhere to ERM.</p>
<p>&quot;Swedish hesitation towards European monetary union presents the market with a sharp contrast to Finland's clear and decisive move to enter ERM as well as EMU from the start in 1999,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>But several Stockholm treasury heads rejected Hamilton's views, saying that markets were looking at strong Swedish fundamentals and investing accordingly.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been trading Sweden up on fiscal improvements. The government seems to be coming up with some new budget savings regularly,&quot; said the head of treasury of an international bank.</p>
<p>Sweden's minority Social Democratic Party (SDP) government -- whose Prime Minister Goran Persson is a personal supporter of European monetary union -- is having to moderate its enthusiasm because of hostility from rank and file SDP members.</p>
<p>The government has called for a broad public debate on ERM and EMU membership and in the meantime the government has declared that ERM adhesion is not on the agenda.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Erik Asbrink repeated those sentiments after Finland's decision was announced on Saturday.</p>
<p>Stockholm traders said trading trends for the crown would be set in Asian trade in Sydney and Singapore on Sunday evening European time, when markka-mark trading would set the trend for crown trade.</p>
<p>&quot;You could see a dip but it will only last for a day or two at the most and I would expect buyers to return in quickly and in depth,&quot; said another Stockholm currency trader.</p>
<p>A chief dealer said: &quot;I cannot see that this (Finnish) news should influence the crown very much. The Finnish desire to adhere to ERM was well-known, just as Sweden's stance that it is not on the agenda at the moment is well-known.</p>
<p>&quot;We may have some nervousness on Monday morning but it should have much effect in the longer term,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The crown traded late on Friday in New York at 4.3130-60 versus the mark compared to 4.3155 at 1400 GMT in Stockholm.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom (46 8 753 6189)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
