<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="112938" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Water firms group says progress made on leak cuts.</title>
<headline>Water firms group says progress made on leak cuts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>British regional water companies which have suffered most from lack of rainfall have made the most progress in cutting leaks, according to the Water Services Association (WSA).</p>
<p>In a statement, the group said North West Water, Severn Trent Water, South West Water and Yorkshire Water were between them saving nearly 64 million gallons of water per day compared with a year ago.</p>
<p>Last year, the water companies were slammed by the opposition Labour party for leaks, which it said lost 826 million gallons a day from company pipes.</p>
<p>The WSA admitted that leakage reduction programmes were still &quot;very much in the early stages.&quot;</p>
<p>It said five main factors contributed to cuts in leakage: faster response times, more detection and repair teams, more sophisticated monitoring equipment, more widespread introduction of advanced pressure management and free or low cost help lines.</p>
<p>But the WSA said &quot;no water distribution system in the world is leak-proof, nor would it be sensible to strive for one.&quot;</p>
<p>It said water firms did not believe that leakage control and conservation through more efficient water usage would be enough to meet future demands and new resources would need to be found.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
