<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113044" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FOCUS - NZ markets rally despite murky poll result.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - NZ markets rally despite murky poll result.</headline>
<byline>Simon Louisson</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand markets rallied on Monday immediately after Saturday's inconclusive election.</p>
<p>The strongest to react was the New Zealand dollar which jumped nearly half a U.S. cent to US$0.6981/91 and the currency's Trade-Weighted Index rose to 66.61 from 66.05 on Friday.</p>
<p>The share market rallied 18.72 points, 0.8 percent, to 2,268.27 after two hours and was just shy of a 2-1/2 year high.</p>
<p>Long bond yields fell 10 basis points to 7.94 percent while 90-day bank bills fell six points to 9.86 percent.  </p>
<p>Dealers said the key positive out of the election, which was largely in line with poll predictions, was the poor performance of the left-wing Alliance Party.</p>
<p>The election result gave 53 seats to the conservative National Party and its two allies, United and Act, against 50 for the two left-wing parties, Labour and the Alliance, leaving the nationalist NZ First with 17 seats to determine who becomes the government.  </p>
<p>&quot;There shouldn't be any shocks. There were no surprises about this result. If people hadn't put this result into their calculations then I don't know what they were doing,&quot; said Bankers Trust foreign exchange dealer Philip Lindberg.</p>
<p>National Bank chief dealer Stu Nattrass said the market had taken heart from the poor showing of the left-wing Alliance, which only won 11 percent of the vote for 13 seats.</p>
<p>&quot;The positive thing was that the Alliance, which was the only party which could really cause damage, were taken out of play.&quot;  </p>
<p>Nattrass said he was surprised at the strength of dollar and doubted it would be sustained, particularly if New Zealand First opted to go with Labour, as was most likely.</p>
<p>Lindberg said the foreign exchange market was prepared to live with uncertainty for up to six weeks.</p>
<p>Westpac Head of Financial Markets Chris Rand said the market had acted with relief and was anticipating a return of the offshore interest via eurokiwi and samurai issuance.</p>
<p>He agreed the market's main election fear had been the Alliance party -- that it would have been in a position to extract large concessions from the more moderate Labour Party.  </p>
<p>&quot;They really don't have that same sort of leverage and that certainly makes the market feel more comfortable,&quot; Rand said.</p>
<p>&quot;The basic economic policy of NZ First isn't too far removed from either Labour or National,&quot; Rand said.</p>
<p>County NatWest sharebroker Neville Todd said the equities market had also feared the potential power of the Alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;They are the ones who would likely inflict the most damage to a market-led economy and their influence is obviously going to be much less than we perhaps would have thought,&quot; Todd said.</p>
<p>International credit rating agency Standard &amp; Poor's soothed markets by saying it was comfortable with the election result.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is broadly consistent with what we have been saying, which is we did not think if there was going to be a change of government that it would necessarily portend a substantial deviation from existing policy settings,&quot; Sovereign Risk Managing Director David Beers told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on the numbers, it seemed to us that if you tally up all the distribution, there is a majority in the new parliament advocating something like the stance of economic policies by both Labour and National governments for over a decade now.&quot;</p>
<p>Beers said he believed the majority of the voters had expressed their economic policy preferences pretty clearly.  </p>
<p>&quot;Those are ones that seem to us to be broadly consistent with the ratings we've got on New Zealand right now.&quot;</p>
<p>S&amp;P rates New Zealand's sovereign risk at AA plus.</p>
<p>&quot;Broadly speaking, we are comfortable with the types of scenarios that we can perceive going forward,&quot; Beers said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
