<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113061" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Wide rate gaps to slow Seoul market opening - radio.</title>
<headline>Wide rate gaps to slow Seoul market opening - radio.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea plans to slow the opening of some financial markets until interest rate gaps with advanced nations narrow to two to three percentage points, state radio quoted the country's top economic minister as saying on Sunday.</p>
<p>The KBS radio quoted Finance and Economy Minister Han Seung-soo as saying the government was seeking to delay opening the domestic bond market until the gaps narrow.</p>
<p>The report could not independently be confirmed and it was not clear whether the remarks would affect previously scheduled openings.</p>
<p>South Korea has said it will allow foreign investment in unsecured corporate bonds issued by domestic small to medium-sized firms from late 1998.</p>
<p>Han was also quoted as saying that opening capital markets too hastily could trigger confusion by causing an influx of foreign funds taking advantage of interest rate gaps.</p>
<p>Currently, key long-term interest rates hover at more than 12 percent in South Korea, compared with three percent to six percent in many industrialised nations, analysts say.  </p>
<p>Han's remarks came amid criticism that entry into the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) could trigger chaos in local financial markets.</p>
<p>The Paris-based group of industrialised nations on Friday voted to invite South Korea into the group as the 29th member, with a formal agreement due to be signed on October 25.</p>
<p>South Korea would be the second Asian nation after Japan to become an OECD member.</p>
<p>Han also reaffirmed a plan to cut the reserve requirement for banks by about two percentage points from an average of 7.4 percent now, KBS said. But he did not give the date.</p>
<p>The cut in the reserve requirement -- the proportion of deposits banks must place as reserves with the central bank -- will likely be followed swiftly by cuts in bank lending rates.</p>
<p>In April, South Korea trimmed the reserve requirement to an average of 7.4 percent from 9.4 percent.</p>
<p>-- Seoul Newsroom (822) 727-5646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
