<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113122" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel-PLO talks held off for one day - official.</title>
<headline>Israel-PLO talks held off for one day - official.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Burston</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli-PLO talks on a long-postponed redeployment from the West Bank town of Hebron, set to resume in Egypt's Red Sea resort of Taba on Monday, will be delayed by a day, U.S. and Israeli officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>But a PLO official said Palestinian negotiators were not notified of the delay, made at the suggestion of U.S. peace envoy Dennis Ross, mediator of the talks that began last week.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been delayed by a day,&quot; said spokesman Moshe Fogel.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an American suggestion to let the parties keep talking in the way they've been talking, more one-on-one,&quot; Fogel said, referring to informal negotiations between the sides.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not been informed of any change in the plans,&quot; Palestinian negotiator Hassan Asfour told Reuters. &quot;As far as we are concerned the talks start tomorrow in Taba,&quot;</p>
<p>Ross said in a statement the one-day delay &quot;will give the ongoing discussions an opportunity to develop further and create a stronger basis for making progress when the Taba/Eilat talks convene.&quot;</p>
<p>Recent talks between the parties had proved &quot;very useful&quot;, Ross said, adding that both sides had agreed to the delay.</p>
<p>The parties decided on the negotiations at an emergency Washington summit after fierce Palestinian-Israeli clashes last month in which 60 Arabs and 15 Jews were killed.</p>
<p>Formal negotiating sessions were held in Israeli and Palestinian controlled areas of the Gaza Strip last week.</p>
<p>This week talks were to be held for two days in Taba beginning on Monday, and then for two days in the nearby Israeli resort of Eilat. Since the last formal session on Thursday informal talks have been continuing, officials said.</p>
<p>Israeli officials said the delay was intended to afford time for progress in the informal talks.</p>
<p>Senior Israeli negotiator Dan Shomron said the informal negotiations had spurred a narrowing of gaps between the sides. &quot;It would be a shame to halt the momentum,&quot; he told army radio.</p>
<p>However PLO negotiator Saeb Erakat said talks with Netanyahu's government had failed to yield &quot;one inch of progress.&quot;</p>
<p>Erekat called on Israel's main ally Washington to push the Jewish state to honour the Hebron deal, signed with the Labour government ousted by Netanyahu in May elections.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat pointedly hosted Israeli opposition leader Shimon Peres on Sunday in self-ruled Nablus, the only West Bank town still under an Israeli blockade imposed after last month's bloodshed.</p>
<p>Israel's Channel Two television said Israeli General Shaul Mufaz had been holding &quot;secret talks&quot; with senior Palestinian security officials Jibril Rajoub and Mohammed Dahlan and that those talks were making progress.</p>
<p>The television said civil affairs issues were now the stumbling block. Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu hoped to placate Jewish settlers in Hebron -- who strongly oppose the redeployment -- by providing them more municipal powers, it said.</p>
<p>PLO officials confirmed that joint security and civilian committees were meeting. They said the outcome of the committee sessions would determine the direction of the formal talks.</p>
<p>Israel's state-run Channel One Television said Netanyahu objected to the choice of the Taba, Egypt site. In recent weeks relations between Netanyahu and Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak have been severely strained.</p>
<p>Mubarak said on Saturday he would refuse to meet Netanyahu until Israel settled the Hebron issue with the Palestinians.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
