<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113116" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: WEEK AHEAD - HK stocks seen pausing, resilient.</title>
<headline>WEEK AHEAD - HK stocks seen pausing, resilient.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The stellar performance by Hong Kong stocks is expected to be followed by some consolidation around newly gained ground in the week ahead, but prices could resume the rally at any time, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is really a matter of trying to judge whether the market needs a breather or consolidation,&quot; said Howard Gorges, director at South China Brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there is a lot of downside but we could see 100 to 200 points. It would not be surprising if it suddenly spurted up so I think it is evenly balanced,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng blue chip index ended last week at 12,218.40 points, down 24.07 points on Friday but up 312.89 points, or 2.63 percent, on the week.</p>
<p>Last Wednesday, the blue chip index registered a record closing high of 12,250.57, beating the previous best of 12,201.09 on January 4, 1994.</p>
<p>Higher levels of liquidity in the market have fuelled the Hang Seng's rise and analysts said continued flows should support the market through any pullback.</p>
<p>&quot;So far the market really does not seem to have encountered overwhelming selling pressure,&quot; said Gorges. He saw a possible upside for the Hang Seng index at 12,400 to 12,500 points.</p>
<p>Kelvin Tang, analyst at ImPac Asset Management, said the market could drift lower in the week ahead but find support around 12,000 points.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market really needs to take a rest. In the short-term, we could be in a trading range or see a mild pullback unless there is a strong inflow of liquidity from overseas,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;At this level I think people will be more cautious about the market,&quot; Tang said, adding however that &quot;it all depends on the liquidity&quot;.</p>
<p>Analysts said Hong Kong stocks needed new incentives to push them higher after a weak U.S. September jobs report gave them an early fillip last week.</p>
<p>&quot;That could come in the form of local factors like developments in the local property market, further signs of economic stimulus on the mainland or again developments in the U.S. with regard to inflation numbers and employment figures,&quot; said Andrew Fernow, director of research at Vickers Ballas.</p>
<p>&quot;We may see further funds flow in the coming week which will support the market so there will be room for the market to move higher but I think we are in the middle of a trading range and we could settle down a couple of hundred points or we could be up a couple of hundred points,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
