<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113279" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algerian forces kill 12 gunmen - report.</title>
<headline>Algerian forces kill 12 gunmen - report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algerian security forces killed 12 Moslem guerrillas in Algiers after a nearly eight-hour gunbattle around a villa being used as a hideout, an Algerian newspaper reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>And Moslem guerrillas struck again in the southern Algerian Laghouat province killing two people, four days after they slaughtered more than 30 passengers in the same area at a fake road block they erected, al Khabar newspaper said.</p>
<p>Two gunmen, thought to be Moslem rebels, shot dead a homeless man on Saturday at Algiers Place des Martyrs main square, the Algerian newspaper el Watan reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>Security forces, using &quot;heavy means&quot;, late on Friday surrounded a villa in the southeastern Algiers' district of el Harrach where 12 rebels took refuge, Le Matin newspaper said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gunfire from automatics did not stop throughout the operation,&quot; said Le Matin adding that the encounter lasted about eight hours.</p>
<p>Troops, paramilitary gendarmes and police took part in the combined operation against the 12 guerrillas armed with &quot;heavy weapons&quot;, it added.</p>
<p>Al Khabar newspaper said on Sunday that an armed group broke on Thursday night into a Moslem prayer room in Kourdane town in Laghouat province, 340 km (210 miles) south of Algiers.</p>
<p>They killed two people and tortured a third and then damaged the room by setting off a canister gas bomb, al Khabar added.</p>
<p>The prayer room is controlled by Sheikh Ahmed Amar Tidjani, grandson of the widely respected chief of the Tidjani Moslem brotherhood which has thousands of followers in several countries, including Senegal.</p>
<p>An estimated 50,000 people have been killed in Algeria's violence since early 1992 when the authorities cancelled a general election in which radical Islamists had taken a huge lead.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
