<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113204" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. machine tool demand reported strong in August.</title>
<headline>U.S. machine tool demand reported strong in August.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Demand for machine tools was strong in August, estimated at $667 million, the American Machine Tool Distributors' Association and the Association for Manufacturing Technology said Sunday in a joint report.</p>
<p>For the first eight months of 1996, demand was estimated at $5.56 billion, the report said.</p>
<p>The report, the third U.S. Machine Tool Consumption report issued by the two associations, replaces monthly data on U.S. machine tool orders, shipments and exports that had been issued by the Association for Manufacturing Technology.</p>
<p>&quot;Customer plant vacation shutdowns in August tend to make order levels for the month one of the lowest in any year,&quot; AMT President Albert Moore said. &quot;Relative to August in each of the past two years, this month's orders were very strong.&quot;</p>
<p>Year-ago comparisons were not provided in the report. But machine tool orders in July were estimated at $744.4 million, an American Machine Tool Distributors' Association spokesman said.</p>
<p>Machine tools are used to shape metal in making everything from golf clubs to aircraft. Demand for these tools can provide a leading indicator of the pace of manufacturing.</p>
<p>Eli Lustgarten, an analyst with Schroder Wartheim in New York, estimated that August orders looked to be &quot;up 15 to 20 percent&quot; from a year earlier due to premarketing of new products before the September international machine tool show.</p>
<p>But Lustgarten added that he was still expecting a modest decline in the machine tool business over the next 12 months.</p>
<p>The report said 2,890 machine tool units were ordered in August, up from 2,693 in July. January-to-August units totaled 24,096.</p>
<p>By region, the report said, the Midwest accounted for 37.2 percent of national demand, followed by 16.6 percent in the West.</p>
<p>The Central and South regions each accounted for 15.7 percent of demand, while the Northeast accounted for 14.8 percent, it said.</p>
<p>Export orders placed with U.S. builders totaled 139 units in August, down from 207 in July. In the first eight months of this year, export orders were 1,795 units, the report said.</p>
<p>The groups said they based their latest estimates on a survey of over 400 machine tool manufacturers and distributors representing 64 percent of market share, and then projected the remaining 36 percent of the manufacturers' and distributors' business.</p>
<p>Distributors' business includes orders for imported machine tools.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
