<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113238" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Galliano bids Givenchy farewell, readies for Dior.</title>
<headline>Galliano bids Givenchy farewell, readies for Dior.</headline>
<byline>Lee Yanowitch</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>In one of the finest moments of the Spring Summer fashion season, John Galliano produced a breathtaking farewell collection for the house of Givenchy.</p>
<p>Free of theatrical tricks and costume ball dresses, it cemented his reputation as a brilliant craftsman and fervently imaginative designer as he prepares to take the helm at the more prestigious fashion house of Christian Dior.</p>
<p>LVMH Moet Hennessy Louis Vuitton, the luxury goods firm that owns both houses, is set to make his appointment at Christian Dior official and name his successor at Givenchy on Monday.</p>
<p>The collection on Sunday night was a masterpiece: djellaba braid swirls across a black Victorian jacket, high-waisted gowns with tiny puffed sleeves of silk patterned like Wedgewood china, and the romance of a primrose-strewn blouse, its ruffles tumbling down the shoulders of a diminutive Kate Moss.</p>
<p>It was fantasy that translates into real-life: satin bellhop suits with red ribbon trim, curvy 1940s-style dress in tiny polka dotted fabrics and wing-sleeved jacket of absinthe brocade on a leopard chiffon gown.</p>
<p>During his short-lived tenure at Givenchy, Galliano has transformed the house's strait-laced image into one of romance and drama, propelling the label back to fashion's sharp edge.</p>
<p>The nay-sayers who had predicted Galliano's wild ways and fragile artistic temperment would not hold up under the high- pressure demands of a major label have swallowed their words.</p>
<p>Fashion industry bible Women's Wear Daily reported earlier in the fashion week, which ends later on Monday, that another British designer, Alexander McQueen, had signed a contract with Givenchy last Thursday in Paris. Givenchy officials would neither confirm nor deny the report.</p>
<p>Earlier, the lightly dancing silhouette of Valentino's floral chiffon dresses, the ruffles cascading down his jacket necklines and a lace strip inserted at the waist of an evening gown heralded glamour's return to the catwalk.</p>
<p>The skilled work of Valentino's Rome atelier was evident in the shiver of fishscale sequined sheaths or the draping of a diaphonous, shade-graded chiffon strewn with tulips and poppies.</p>
<p>The designer created a soft, sweet kind of feminity with lace as an edging for slip dresses, as tops under pinstriped suits or as an underpinning for sheer dresses.</p>
<p>Buyers agreed it was one of the most elegant and wearable collections of the Spring summer season.</p>
<p>&quot;It was quite beautiful and elegant. I loved the way he handled the mixing of lace with the suiting and spectacular evening wear,&quot; said Dawn Mello, president of Bergdorf Goodman.</p>
<p>Rosemarie Bravo, president of Saks Fifth Avenue, called it a &quot;beautiful evening wear collection&quot; that her store will carry.</p>
<p>Jean-Paul Gaultier scored a hit with all-in-one trompe l'oeil three-piece suits (neckties included) that models took off with a simple slide of a zipper, string bikinis peeking out from low-cut dress backs and tatoo bodystockings.</p>
<p>The layering was all topsy turvy, in stride with Gaultier's witty take on reversing the most basic rules of dress -- fishnet stockings over bright green knee-socks, bikini bottoms over denim shorts, and bras on the outside of dresses.</p>
<p>In the midst of the madness were beautifully cut pinstriped suits with knee pants or wide-legged fluid trousers -- sometimes edged with Indian motifs -- snappy sailor jumpsuits, liquid halter dresses and perfect little shantung jackets.</p>
<p>In an eyebrow raising finale, the bride, all virginal white in front, wore a backless dress with a bouquet of lilies on her bottom in place of a G-string.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it was sensational.  I loved the suiting, I loved the new prints and the mixes,&quot; said Nicole Fischelis of Saks Fifth Avenue. &quot;I loved all the cross culture influences, the jumpsuits and sailor items.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFAS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
