<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113263" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German publisher of Stern magazine dies.</title>
<headline>German publisher of Stern magazine dies.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-10-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Henri Nannen, founder and long-time publisher of Germany's biggest-selling magazine Stern, died on Sunday after a long battle with cancer, a spokesman for the magazine said. He was 82.</p>
<p>One of the country's most influential journalists and a noted art collector, Nannen launched the weekly illustrated Stern amid the rubble of post-war Germany in 1948.</p>
<p>Its colourful focus on issues that affected ordinary people helped it to become at one point the magazine with the largest circulation in Europe.</p>
<p>Whether publishing articles critical of the government or church, Stern tapped the mood of nation and often triggered national discussions with its cover stories.</p>
<p>It also sometimes drew the ire of the occupying Western Allies in Germany, which on several occasions confiscated issues of the magazine in the 1940s and 1950s.</p>
<p>The magazine's reputation was badly tarnished in 1983, three years after Nannen retired as editor-in-chief, when it published what turned out to be the bogus &quot;Hitler Diaries&quot;.</p>
<p>Nannen, who was a member of the magazine's board of directors at the time, accepted blame for the fiasco even though he was no longer running the magazine.</p>
<p>The scandal cost the magazine much of its credibility and eroded its circulation for several years.</p>
<p>&quot;I will always have to live with the fact that I failed here politically and journalistically,&quot; Nannen said.</p>
<p>A Stern reporter was duped by a Stuttgart forger named Konrad Kujau in 1983 into believing he had &quot;found&quot; dozens of diaries secretly written by Nazi leader Adolf Hitler.</p>
<p>But shortly after the magazine published what it called &quot;the biggest journalistic coup of the post-war era&quot; they were proved to be forgeries. Several Stern editors resigned in disgrace.</p>
<p>Stern reporter Gerd Heidemann and the forger Kujau were each sentenced to prison terms of more than four years.</p>
<p>Nannen was born on December 25, 1913 in Emden, north Germany. He studied art history at the University of Munich and worked briefly in 1938 as a journalist for an art magazine known as &quot;Art in a Germany renewed by the Fuehrer.&quot;</p>
<p>But he was dismissed after writing an article about a Jewish author. During World War Two Nannen served as an officer in the Luftwaffe.</p>
<p>After the war, he started a newspaper in 1946 in Hanover before launching Stern, first known as &quot;Zickzack&quot;, in 1948.</p>
<p>After retiring as editor-in-chief of Stern, Nannen turned his focus to art. He opened an art gallery in Emden in 1986.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
