<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113297" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Unocol Corp. undeterred by Afghan turmoil.</title>
<headline>Unocol Corp. undeterred by Afghan turmoil.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD, Pakistan</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unocal Corp. of California remains determined to build oil and gas pipelines from Turkmenistan across Afghanistan into Pakistan, despit the turmoil in Afghanistan, a company executive said Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hopeful that this is a temporary situation,&quot; Richard Keller, president and general manager of Unocal Pakistan Ltd, said, referring to the war raging between the Islamist Taleban militia and government forces ousted from Kabul last month.</p>
<p>&quot;We are waiting to see what happens in Afghanistan,&quot; he said. &quot;Hopefully, things will improve, but we don't know what to believe. Everything seems so confusing at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Unocal, which is based in El Segundo, Calif., wants to build a natural gas pipeline with a capacity of about two billion cubic feet a day from Turkmenistan's Dauletabad field to feed power plants in Pakistan.</p>
<p>It also hopes to construct a pipeline to carry a million barrels a day of crude oil from Chardzhou oil field to a proposed export terminal on Pakistan's Arabian Sea coast.</p>
<p>Keller's remarks Sunday contrasted with optimism expressed by a Unocal executive immediately after Taleban guerrillas captured Kabul.</p>
<p>Chris Taggart, executive vice president of Unocal International Energy Ventures Ltd, said on Oct. 1 that the Taleban's dominance could prove to be a positive development.</p>
<p>&quot;I understand Pakistan has already recognised the (Taleban) government. If the U.S. follows, it will lead the way to international lending agencies coming in,&quot; Taggart said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Taleban leads to stability and international recognition, then it's positive,&quot; he said, adding that the prospects for the two projects, whose routes pass entirely through Taleban-controlled territory, had improved.</p>
<p>Pakistan, which denies charges that it has sponsored the fiercely fundamentalist Taleban, says it will deal with any government in Kabul and plans to reopen its embassy there.</p>
<p>The United States initially said it would send diplomats to meet the new Taleban rulers, but has put this plan on hold amid mounting international criticism of Taleban edicts imposing harsh Islamic Sharia law and placing curbs on women.</p>
<p>Washington backed a decision by a U.N. General Assembly committee last week to defer a decision on the credentials of Afghanistan's U.N. delegation.</p>
<p>That left President Burhanuddin Rabbani's representatives in place, to the chagrin of the Taleban leadership.</p>
<p>Keller said Unocal, which has teamed up with Delta Oil Co. of Saudi Arabia for the trans-Afghan pipeline project, was refining cost estimates, planning optimal routes with the help of satellite imagery and holding discussions with concerned governments, the World Bank and interested companies.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of work is going on, but we'll just have to see how this thing plays out,&quot; he said of the rapidly-changing military map of Afghanistan. &quot;Obviously, there has to be a government acceptable to the Afghans and the outside world.&quot;</p>
<p>The Taleban, fired with Islamic zeal, swept into Kabul on Sept. 27, but have since suffered reverses in their drive to crush former government forces led by Ahmad Shah Masood.</p>
<p>Keller said estimates of the cost of the two pipelines had dropped significantly as a result of detailed studies.</p>
<p>The gas pipeline was now expected to cost about $2 billion, down from $3 billion previously estimated, while the tab for the oil pipeline was now put at $2.6 billion, down from $5 billion.</p>
<p>Keller also said all Afghan factions, including the Taleban and those groups in the ousted coalition government led by Rabbani, had expressed support for the project.</p>
<p>But he said no detailed proposals had been made about how Afghans would share transit fees or other benefits.</p>
<p>The company has had no contacts with the Taleban since their conquest of Kabul, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURKM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
