<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113202" id="root" date="1996-10-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: College football player dies before game.</title>
<headline>College football player dies before game.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Fordham University football player collapsed during warmups and died on the field minutes before the school's homecoming game was to start, a school official said Saturday.</p>
<p>Bill Tierney, a junior defensive back, collapsed minutes before the scheduled 1 p.m. kickoff and was treated on the field by paramedics and a team doctor. He was rushed to St. Barnabas Hospital in The Bronx, N.Y., but efforts to revive him were unsuccssful.</p>
<p>The 20-year-old from New Jersey was a junior majoring in economics.</p>
<p>Among those in the packed stands at the university's Bronx campus was the student's parents and sister. Brian Byrne, university vice president for administration, said the sister had been scheduled to lead everyone in singing the National Anthem.</p>
<p>&quot;His death is unexplained at this time. It may have been a heart attack. An autopsy is to be performed to determine cause of death,&quot; Byrne said.</p>
<p>The game against Pennsylvania's Lafayette College at Fordham's Jack Coffey Field was postponed. Homecoming activities were cancelled, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
