<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113488" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chrysler rises, lifting auto sector.</title>
<headline>Chrysler rises, lifting auto sector.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chrysler Corp surged after the automaker posted surprisingly strong third-quarter earnings on Monday, pointing to a rich product mix and robust production, which came in 17,000 vehicles higher than the firm's own forecasts.</p>
<p>Chrysler shares jumped 1-1/8 to 32-7/8 after the release of its quarterly profits of $1 a share excluding extraordinary items, blowing past Wall Street estimates of $0.71 a share, according to First Call Corp.</p>
<p>Ford Motor Co shares rose 1/2 to 32-5/8 and General Motor Shares rose 1-1/2 to 51-5/8.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think it was all in the sales mix,&quot; Burnham Securities analyst David Healy said of Chrysler's strong performance. &quot;They've raised prices and the mix has shifted to trucks. They're selling not so many Neons and a lot more Jeep Grand Cherokees and Town &amp; Country minivans.&quot;</p>
<p>Dean Witter Reynolds Inc auto analyst Kenneth Blaschke agreed: &quot;It was a solid quarter because of the higher production and a strong mix. The company's selling more fully loaded and higher end vehicles.&quot;</p>
<p>Blaschke said the earnings surprise and statements by Chrysler executives that fourth quarter incentives will remain flat with the third quarter level of $685 per vehicle, led Dean Witter to raise its 1996 full year earnings estimate for Chrysler to $5.14 from $4.74.</p>
<p>He also said Dean Witter's 1997 Chrysler estimate was raised to $5 from $4.25 because the automaker disclosed that it will add 190,000 units worth of truck production capacity next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
