<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113442" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FULL TEXT - Intel Corp Q3 results.</title>
<headline>FULL TEXT - Intel Corp Q3 results.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Intel Corp Monday reported financial results for the third quarter. The following is a copy of the company's news release.</p>
<p>--------------- PRESS RELEASE ------------------------</p>
<p>SANTA CLARA, Calif.--(BUSINESS WIRE)--Oct. 14, 1996--Intel Corporation's third quarter revenue and earnings per share set new records, rising 23 percent to $5.14 billion and 41 percent to $1.48 from the year earlier period, respectively, the company said today. The third quarter of 1996 marks the first time in the company's history that quarterly revenue surpassed $5 billion.</p>
<p>Third quarter revenue rose 11 percent from $4.62 billion in the second quarter of 1996.  Net income rose to $1.31 billion, up from $1.04 billion in the second quarter of 1996. Earnings per share rose 26 percent from $1.17 in this year's second quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;We are delighted with the excellent acceptance of Pentium(R) and Pentium(R) Pro processor-based PCs and servers, which has produced a stronger third quarter than we had originally expected,&quot; said Dr. Andrew S. Grove, president and chief executive officer.</p>
<p>Revenue for the first nine months of 1996 rose 24 percent to $14.41 billion from $11.62 billion a year ago, and net income grew 20 percent to $3.25 billion from $2.70 billion. Earnings per share increased 20 percent to $3.67 from $3.06.</p>
<p>In the third quarter, the company repurchased a total of 8 million shares of common stock at a cost of $598 million under an ongoing program.  The company has repurchased 82.2 million shares at a total cost of $3.1 billion since the program began in 1990.</p>
<p>During the quarter the company announced its regular quarterly cash dividend of $0.05 per share.  The dividend is payable on December 1, 1996 to stockholders of record on November 1, 1996.  Upon payment of this dividend, Intel will have paid a dividend for seventeen consecutive quarters.</p>
<p>BUSINESS OUTLOOK</p>
<p>Effective as of this date, except as required by law, the company is indefinitely ceasing the publication of forward-looking statements in its filings with the Securities and Exchange Commission, in press releases and in other public communications.  The company has instituted this new policy on the publication of forward-looking statements due to the company's substantial concerns about the possible adoption, and effect, of a proposed California ballot initiative.</p>
<p>On November 5 the voters of California will be asked to vote on Proposition 211: &quot;Attorney-Client Fee Arrangements, Securities Fraud, Initiative Statute.&quot;  If passed, this measure could significantly increase the exposure to frivolous stockholder law suits for all companies with a California presence.  This measure would render useless the federal securities law &quot;safe harbor&quot; for forward-looking statements, and the federal securities class action reforms, adopted into law in 1995.  Moreover, Proposition 211 would increase securities litigation liability of corporations substantially beyond the pre-reform liability.  Although passage of this measure is uncertain, Intel does not intend to assume the risk of making forward-looking statements concerning the company's business outlook. Accordingly, Intel will not include such statements in the company's communications with stockholders and the financial community except as required by law.</p>
<p>The company expects to review this policy in the event that Proposition 211 is defeated at the polls on November 5, 1996. SEPTEMBER 1996 QUARTER BUSINESS REVIEW</p>
<p>-- The company's book-to-bill ratio exceeded 1.0 for the third quarter.  Orders during the third quarter set a new record.</p>
<p>-- Unit shipments of microprocessors and chipsets set new records during the quarter.  Flash memory, embedded processors and microcontrollers were slightly down in unit volumes from the second quarter and strong downward pricing pressure continued throughout the quarter.</p>
<p>-- Third quarter gross margin percentage was positively affected by favorable product mix.  There were no unusual inventory write-offs and no unusually high royalties during the quarter.  The percentage of motherboards to microprocessors declined in the third quarter from the second quarter.</p>
<p>-- The company continued to see high levels of orders for immediate delivery (&quot;turns&quot;) during the third quarter.</p>
<p>-- Intel's revenue breakdown by major geographic regions is summarized below: -0-</p>
<p>				    Q3 95	    Q2 96	   Q3 96</p>
<p>Percent of revenue</p>
<p>by geographic area</p>
<p>     Americas			51		40		42</p>
<p>     Europe			  27		30		26</p>
<p>     Asia-Pacific		  11		18		21</p>
<p>     Japan			   11		12		11</p>
<p>-- In comparison to second quarter levels, Asia-Pacific and the Americas experienced strong growth in revenue during the third quarter; Japan and Europe were sequentially flat in revenue.  Growth was highest in the Asia-Pacific region, where local consumption continued to increase rapidly.</p>
<p>-- Employment in the third quarter was 46,000, up from 40,000 in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>Processor Products</p>
<p>Key Q3 1996 developments in the company's processor products business included the following:</p>
<p>-- The Pentium Pro processor continued to gain rapid market acceptance by offering &quot;cost of ownership&quot; advantages and outstanding performance on today's advanced operating environments such as Windows NT and Windows 95 running 32-bit applications.  A wide range of servers featuring multiple Pentium Pro processors are achieving performance levels previously only associated with proprietary RISC technologies.</p>
<p>A Compaq server recently achieved record cost/performance in benchmark measurements compiled by the Transaction Processing and Performance Council.  These benchmarks demonstrate the capabilities of Pentium Pro-based servers for very high volume Intranet/Internet Web site solutions.</p>
<p>-- The company began shipping its highest performance processor for mobile computers, the 150-MHz Pentium processor.</p>
<p>This new processor enables manufacturers to deliver notebooks with high-resolution color screens, CD-ROM drives, full motion video, and stereo sound at approximately the same battery life as previous Pentium processor-based notebooks.</p>
<p>Internet &amp; Communications Products</p>
<p>-- During the &quot;Wired for Management&quot; symposium in New York City, the company unveiled a broad initiative comprising new Intel hardware and software products, joint work with other companies, industry standards efforts, and other programs to reduce the total cost of ownership of business computing, including costs for system management and support.  During the quarter, the company announced:</p>
<p>-- a new LANDesk technology, to be introduced later this year as LANDesk(R) Configuration Manager, that enables the remote configuration of operating systems and other software for new PC installations and upgrades;</p>
<p>-- LANDesk Support Center, a new management product for PC help desks;</p>
<p>-- a series of Pentium Pro processor-based server platforms with built-in management capabilities;</p>
<p>-- the availability of a hardware monitoring chip to track PC health;</p>
<p>-- During the quarter, Intel hosted the Internet Media Symposium, where a vision was revealed for delivering rich multimedia experiences to PC users over the Internet using compelling &quot;hybrid&quot; applications, which combine the performance, versatility, and local storage capability of the high-performance connected PC with the interactivity of the Internet.</p>
<p>-- The newest addition to Intel's NetportExpress PRO print server line, the 10/100Mbps NetportExpress(TM) PRO/100 Print Server, was introduced. The PRO/100 model allows workgroups easily and affordably to connect and manage printers at 10Mbps Ethernet or 100Mbps Fast Ethernet.</p>
<p>Semiconductor Products</p>
<p>--Intel's flash memory-based Miniature Card products, digital media that stores image, text and voice data in consumer electronic devices, began shipping to worldwide customers.</p>
<p>Manufacturing Review</p>
<p>-- The company's factories continued to ramp the 0.35 micron process, achieving excellent performance during the quarter by manufacturing high speed Pentium and Pentium Pro processors to meet higher than expected demand.</p>
<p>FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Income Statement</p>
<p>Q3 1996 net revenue was up 23 percent from Q3 1995, driven primarily by higher revenue from sales of Pentium and Pentium Pro processors and related board-level products.</p>
<p>Cost of sales increased 10 percent from Q3 1995 primarily as a result of increased sales of microprocessors and related board-level products.</p>
<p>Gross margin percentage in the third quarter increased to 57.2 percent from 53.5 percent in the second quarter due primarily to better overall mix between higher and lower margin products.</p>
<p>Q3 1996 total expenses (R&amp;D and MG&amp;A) increased 31 percent from Q3 1995 due to strategic investments in products and process technology, higher cooperative marketing costs, profit dependent related expenses and more employees.  Expenses were 19.7 percent of revenues in Q3 1996 versus 20.7 percent in Q2 1996.</p>
<p>During the quarter, interest and other income was $91 million, down from $94 million in Q3 1995.  Q3 1995 interest and other income included an approximately $37 million pretax gain on the sale of an equity investment.</p>
<p>Shares and equivalents used in the calculation of earnings per share are summarized below:</p>
<p>(millions of shares)</p>
<p>					 Q3 95     Q2 96     Q3 96</p>
<p>     Average Outstanding	  822	 824	 822</p>
<p>     Equivalents		     67	  64	  63</p>
<p>     Total			    889	 888	 885</p>
<p>(Note: Q3 1996 equivalents include 20 million equivalent shares for the 1998 Step-Up Warrants.)</p>
<p>Balance Sheet</p>
<p>Intel's net cash position (short- and long-term investments less short- and long-term debt) increased by $714 million in Q3 1996 to $6.12 billion.</p>
<p>Significant components of the changes in cash for Q3 1996 and year-to-date are summarized below:</p>
<p>Increase/(Decrease) (in millions)</p>
<p>							  Nine Months ended</p>
<p>					   Q3 1996	 Sept. 28, 1996</p>
<p>Net income				    $1,312	     $3,247</p>
<p>Depreciation				     496		1,369</p>
<p>Capital spending			     (630)	    (2,234)</p>
<p>Working capital and other, net		29		1,064</p>
<p>Put warrant proceeds, net		     20		   56</p>
<p>Stock repurchase program		   (598)		(967)</p>
<p>Sales of shares to employees,</p>
<p> including tax benefit			 126		  323</p>
<p>Dividends paid				  (41)		(107)</p>
<p>    Total change			    $  714	     $2,751</p>
<p>Inventories (in millions)</p>
<p>					June 29, 1996    Sept. 28, 1996</p>
<p>Raw material				  $  382	     $  320</p>
<p>Work in process				  693		  712</p>
<p>Finished goods				   404		  338</p>
<p>    Total net inventories		 $1,479	     $1,370</p>
<p>Capital spending was $630 million and depreciation was $496 million in Q3 1996.  Accounts receivable increased by $588 million in the quarter.  The company's average days-sales-outstanding was 50, an increase of 3 days from the second quarter.</p>
<p>During Q3 1996, the company repurchased 8 million shares of common stock at a cost of $598 million under an ongoing program.  As of September 28, 1996 the company's potential put warrant obligation was $547 million to buy back 8.5 million shares of common stock.  Of the total 110 million shares authorized for repurchase, approximately 82.2 million shares have been repurchased and 19.3 million shares of common stock remain available for repurchase under the stock repurchase program, after reserving shares to cover outstanding put warrants.</p>
<p>Activity during the quarter related to put warrants and stock buybacks is as follows:</p>
<p>Increase/(Decrease) (millions of shares)</p>
<p>							 (Less)</p>
<p>			   Available For    Allocated To	Net</p>
<p>			   Stock Buybacks   Put Warrants   available</p>
<p>June 29, 1996		    35.8	     11.7	    24.1</p>
<p>Put warrant sales				   3.0	    (3.0)</p>
<p>Put warrant expirations	  --	     (6.2)	    6.2</p>
<p>Stock buybacks		   (8.0)	     --	    (8.0)</p>
<p>September 28, 1996	     27.8		8.5	    19.3</p>
<p>Stockholders' equity increased by $1,080 million in Q3 1996.</p>
<p>Changes in equity for Q3 1996 and year-to-date are summarized as follows:</p>
<p>Increase/(Decrease)</p>
<p>(in millions)					  Nine Months ended</p>
<p>					  Q3 1996	   Sept. 28, 1996</p>
<p>Net income				$1,312		  $3,247</p>
<p>Put warrant proceeds			20			56</p>
<p>Reclass of put warrant</p>
<p> obligation, net			   203			70</p>
<p>Repurchase of stock		     (598)		   (859)</p>
<p>Dividends declared			 (41)		   (115)</p>
<p>Sales of shares to employees,</p>
<p> plus tax benefit and other	    184		     425</p>
<p>    Total increase		    $1,080		  $2,824</p>
<p>Intel, the world's largest chip maker, is also a leading manufacturer of personal computer, networking, and communications products.  Through innovative technologies, Intel is committed to improving the Internet experience for PC consumers.</p>
<p>				    INTEL CORPORATION</p>
<p>		     CONSOLIDATED SUMMARY FINANCIAL STATEMENTS</p>
<p>			  (Millions, except per share amounts)</p>
<p>INCOME			  3 Months Ended	  9 Months Ended</p>
<p>			  Sept. 28,  Sept. 30,  Sept. 28,  Sept. 30,</p>
<p>				1996	 1995	 1996	  1995</p>
<p>NET REVENUE	     $ 5,142    $ 4,171    $14,407    $11,622</p>
<p>Cost of sales	     2,201	2,008	6,772	5,422</p>
<p>Research and development</p>
<p>				  449	  334	1,288	  944</p>
<p>Marketing, general and</p>
<p> administrative	     565	  440	1,600	1,274</p>
<p>Operating costs and</p>
<p> expenses		   3,215	2,782	9,660	7,640</p>
<p>OPERATING INCOME	  1,927	1,389	4,747	3,982</p>
<p>Interest and other	   91	   94	  248	  316</p>
<p>INCOME BEFORE TAXES     2,018	1,483	4,995	4,298</p>
<p>Income taxes		  706	  552	1,748	1,599</p>
<p>NET INCOME		$ 1,312    $   931    $ 3,247    $ 2,699</p>
<p>EARNINGS PER SHARE    $  1.48    $  1.05    $  3.67    $  3.06</p>
<p>COMMON SHARES AND</p>
<p> EQUIVALENTS		  885	  889	  884	  883</p>
<p>BALANCE SHEET</p>
<p>						 At	     At</p>
<p>					     Sept. 28,    Dec. 30,</p>
<p>						1996	   1995</p>
<p>CURRENT ASSETS</p>
<p>Cash and short-term investments    $ 5,820	$ 2,458</p>
<p>Accounts receivable			3,488	  3,116</p>
<p>Inventories				   1,370	  2,004</p>
<p>Deferred tax assets and other	     537	    519</p>
<p>  Total current assets		   11,215	  8,097</p>
<p>Property, plant and equipment, net</p>
<p>						  8,258	  7,471</p>
<p>Long-term investments		     1,407	  1,653</p>
<p>Other assets				    192	    283</p>
<p>  TOTAL ASSETS			    $21,072	$17,504</p>
<p>CURRENT LIABILITIES</p>
<p>Short-term debt			   $   409	$   346</p>
<p>Accounts payable and accrued liabilities</p>
<p>						  2,452	  2,168</p>
<p>Deferred income on shipments to distributors</p>
<p>						    342	    304</p>
<p>Income taxes payable			  803	    801</p>
<p>  Total current liabilities	     4,006	  3,619</p>
<p>LONG-TERM DEBT				  702	    400</p>
<p>DEFERRED TAX LIABILITIES		    853	    620</p>
<p>PUT WARRANTS				    547	    725</p>
<p>STOCKHOLDERS' EQUITY</p>
<p>Common Stock and capital in excess of par value</p>
<p>						  2,830	  2,583</p>
<p>Retained earnings			  12,134	  9,557</p>
<p>    Total stockholders' equity	  14,964	 12,140</p>
<p>TOTAL LIABILITIES AND STOCKHOLDERS' EQUITY</p>
<p>						 $21,072	$17,504</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
