<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113538" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Miami airport bond suit set for trial in November.</title>
<headline>Miami airport bond suit set for trial in November.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new trial date of Nov 12 has been set in the lawsuit that five airlines filed against Florida's Dade County over the bond financing formula for a new American Airlines terminal at Miami International Airport, an attorney in the case said Monday.</p>
<p>Trial had been set to begin Tuesday but was delayed due to scheduling conflicts, said Barry Davidson, an attorney for the plaintiffs.</p>
<p>The plaintiffs are Air Canada, Delta Air Lines, Trans World Airlines Inc, United Airlines a unit of UAL Corp and USAir Group Inc.</p>
<p>They filed suit against the county, which runs Miami International, in September 1995, saying they would be unfairly forced to pay higher rents to cover debt service on the bonds, but would not be allowed to use the American terminal. They want the project funded entirely with American revenues.</p>
<p>Attorneys for the county and for American, a unit of AMR Corp said the American terminal is part of a 10-year, $3.6 billion expansion that would include a new terminal for the other carriers, plus a new runway and added cargo space.</p>
<p>They said American will help pay for the other carriers' facilities and that the funding formula, wich is pro rated according to the number of flights each carrier operates, has long been the norm at Miami and other airports.</p>
<p>The bulk of the bonds for the project have not yet been issued, although $25 million from a $292 million issue in February was earmarked for engineering and design work on the American terminal.</p>
<p>Davidson said the parties are still meeting in an attempt to settle the lawsuit out of court.</p>
<p>&quot;There are some discussions going on,&quot; Davidson said. &quot;I wouldn't say I'm optimistic but I wouldn't say I'm pessimistic.&quot;</p>
<p>--Jane Sutton, 305-374-5013</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
