<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113638" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BOBSLEIGH-TOUT RECEIVES LIFE BAN FOR STEROID OFFENCE.</title>
<headline>BOBSLEIGH-TOUT RECEIVES LIFE BAN FOR STEROID OFFENCE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Olympic bobsledder Mark Tout has been banned for life after failing a random drugs test, the British Bobsleigh Association said on Monday.</p>
<p>Tout, a competitor at the last four Winter Games, admitted the offence after testing positive for an anabolic steroid last month.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a culmination of things and the main thing is that I have been carrying an injury for the last four years,&quot; Tout told BBC radio.</p>
<p>&quot;That in itself has its frustrations. I've had treatment with no success and then speaking to various people, taking some advice, I felt that maybe taking drugs would help the problem. That was one reason why I tried it. It certainly helped the injury.</p>
<p>&quot;When you are training hard and the injury keeps breaking down, it speeds up the healing. I completely regret doing it. I have seen what's happened to other people and their careers.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't think I would be caught, otherwise I wouldn't have done it.&quot;</p>
<p>The British Bobsleigh Association said: &quot;The life ban was imposed by the disciplinary committee of the British Bobsleigh Association and subsequently ratified by the sport's governing board.</p>
<p>&quot;It is understood that the athlete, who has apologised, does not intend to appeal against the decision.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
