<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113725" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-AC MILAN COULD BE STOCK MARKET WINNER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-AC MILAN COULD BE STOCK MARKET WINNER.</headline>
<byline>Jude Webber</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Champions AC Milan could prove winners on the stock market in soccer-mad Italy if they go ahead with a flotation tentatively planned for next year but market players said investors would need to study the sums carefully.</p>
<p>&quot;Assuming people are happy with the books, I'd say it would be a success,&quot; said one Milan-based share dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the kind of stock that would appeal to the Italian public. But I'm not sure it would appeal in the cold light of day to a UK pension fund.&quot;</p>
<p>AC Milan, owned by billionaire media mogul and former prime minister Silvio Berlusconi who is on trial for corruption charges related to his Fininvest empire, would be the first Italian club to seek a stock market listing.</p>
<p>But experts noted that a classy track record and big fan base were not enough to guarantee success as soccer shares tended to be volatile and to react emotionally to match results.</p>
<p>Worse still, clubs which splash out millions of dollars on top-notch players can no longer collect transfer fees when they move on after their contracts expire under the so-called Bosman Ruling which blew the European transfer market wide open.</p>
<p>Alan Sugar, chairman of quoted British club Tottenham Hotspur , last week called it &quot;a devastating blow to the football industry&quot; and said spendthrift clubs could face ruin.</p>
<p>AC Milan is lucky to be backed by Berlusconi's deep pockets but there could one day be a conflict of interest with his commercial TV stations over the rights to screen soccer matches, now owned by state broadcaster RAI and pay-TV operator Telepiu.</p>
<p>But analysts said the leisure sector was a hot prospect for investors and that an AC Milan launch could be thrilling.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a massively interesting proposition for a club of its stature in the European context,&quot; said one British-based broker specialising in soccer shares. &quot;It would be huge.&quot;</p>
<p>Managing director Adriano Galliani was quoted at the weekend as saying that the club aimed to float in 1997 and may consider a foreign listing if red tape frustrated its efforts at home.</p>
<p>Neither he nor U.S. investment bank Lehman Brothers, reported to be organising the valuation with British merchant bank Rothschild, could immediately be reached for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;For top clubs, it's quite a sensible way of raising capital and raising their profile,&quot; said Richard Baldwin, a partner specialising in soccer at chartered accountants Deloitte, Touche, Tohmatsu International in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Properly handled, (Italian clubs) could have more potential than British clubs because they have a much bigger visibility and fan base...But you're exposing clubs to public scrutiny. You've got to run the business for investors.&quot;</p>
<p>AC Milan made a loss in 1994-95, its last published accounts, of 4.44 billion lire ($3 million), slightly below the previous year's 4.58 billion. Galliani told Corriere della Sera newspaper that the 1995-96 accounts, due for approval on October 28, would show the club &quot;in the red, heavily in the red&quot;.</p>
<p>Under Milan bourse rules, a company must be able to boast three straight years of profit before being allowed to list.</p>
<p>The club, which won Italy's Serie A championship last year and is currently sixth, one point behind leaders Internazionale, owns the Milanello training ground and sought-after stars including world player of the year George Weah of Liberia.</p>
<p>The club is believed to be worth at least 400 billion lire.</p>
<p>The Italian government last month opened the way for soccer clubs to list on the stock exchange by passing a decree law allowing them to become profit-making corporations.</p>
<p>AC Milan's local rivals Internazionale, owned by the oil-rich Moratti family, Juventus, which belongs to the Agnelli family of Fiat cars fame, Bologna, Napoli and second division Salernitana have all said they are keen to float.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
