<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113792" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Ex-Irish PM Reynolds sues British newspaper.</title>
<headline>Ex-Irish PM Reynolds sues British newspaper.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A court on Monday began hearing a libel action brought by former Irish prime minister Albert Reynolds against Britain's Sunday Times newspaper over accusations that he lied to Ireland's parliament.</p>
<p>Lawyers for Reynolds, 63, told a court the Sunday Times was wrong when it accused him of lying to the parliament when he publicly backed former attorney-general Harry Whelehan as suitable for the post of President of the High Court.</p>
<p>Reynolds lost the premiership in November 1994 when his ruling coalition collapsed after attacks on the promotion of Whelehan after he delayed the extradition of a paedophile priest.</p>
<p>The court heard that Reynolds, who did much to promote the peace process in Northern Ireland, relied on legal advice when he initially backed Whelihan, who he later said had misled him.</p>
<p>&quot;The Sunday Times said that Albert Reynolds had lied to the Dail -- he hadn't. That there was confusion, he will not dispute. That there was inefficiency, he will not deny,&quot; Reynolds' lawyer told the court.</p>
<p>&quot;He will deny and deny and deny again that he told lies to the Dail (parliament).&quot;</p>
<p>The priest, Father Brendan Smyth, was jailed for 24 years for child sex abuse in June 1994 after he voluntarily returned to Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>The newspaper denies libel and says it will defend itself vigorously in the case, which is expected to last four weeks.</p>
<p>Reynolds sued the Sunday Times once before, in 1993, in a case that settled out of court with damages paid to the Irish politician.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
