<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113832" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices surge with renewed Kurdish fighting.</title>
<headline>Oil prices surge with renewed Kurdish fighting.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil markets jumped back in the saddle and rode higher again on Monday, shrugging off last week's heavy price fall amid renewed concerns over winter heating oil supplies and tensions in the Middle East.</p>
<p>London November futures for bellwether North Sea Brent crude were up 40 cents by 1430 GMT at $24.40 a barrel, not far off their recent post-Gulf War high of $24.60.</p>
<p>Rival Kurdish factions in northern Iraqi Kurdistan resumed hostilities over the weekend, reminding oil traders of the missing crude supplies previously expected under the U.N.'s postponed oil-for-food exchange with Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraqi oil exports under U.N. resolution 986 this year are now impossibly remote, and in the light of recent developments in the Kurdish areas of Iraq, they may well not begin until the second half of 1997 -- if at all,&quot; said the Centre for Global Energy Studies (CGES) in London.</p>
<p>The U.N. deal, signed in May, was put on hold at the end of August after Baghdad sent troops to intervene on behalf of the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) against its rival, the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>U.N. officials said on Monday that the anti-Baghdad PUK had regained control of part of the territory lost, including the region's largest city, Sulaimaniya. The KDP accused Iran of sending troops and arms to lead PUK attacks over the weekend, but Tehran denied any involvement.</p>
<p>&quot;The threat of a domino effect in the oil-rich Middle East is a real worry to oil traders,&quot; said energy desk head Peter Gignoux at brokerage Smith Barney. Analysts said the renewed fighting underlined how difficult it would be for the U.N. to guarantee the safety of aid distribution monitors in northern Iraq any time soon.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Western oil markets are still suffering a chronic shortage of winter heating oil and diesel supplies.</p>
<p>Oil fell sharply on Friday as traders took profits from prices at five-and-a-half year highs.</p>
<p>But buyers stepped back in for heating oil on Monday as forecasts emerged for colder than normal weather in the U.S. northeast, the world's biggest heating oil market.</p>
<p>&quot;With oil sales from Iraq almost certainly out of the question...the oil market looks set to remain tight through the coming winter -- whatever the weather,&quot; said the CGES.</p>
<p>Oil cartel OPEC looks unlikely to respond to strong demand for its crude by raising its output ceiling when it meets again at the end of November.</p>
<p>OPEC, including linchpin member Saudi Arabia, has no plans to raise output for fear of rocking the boat and undermining a market which is providing windfall extra revenues, Middle East Gulf sources said last week.</p>
<p>&quot;If Iraqi oil is unlikely to materialise and Saudi Arabia, along with its Gulf allies, is reluctant to open the taps because of subsequent reveneue losses, only a mild winter is capable of taking the heat out of the oil market,&quot; said the CGES.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Oct 14	 Oct 11</p>
<p>						  (1430 GMT)     (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $24.35	 $23.95</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Nov)	$24.40	 $24.00</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Nov)     $24.95	 $24.61</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
