<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113897" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi bourse index falls in moderate trading.</title>
<headline>Nairobi bourse index falls in moderate trading.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi bourse 20-share index fell on Monday, dragged down by falling prices in most leading counters due to a supply in excess of demand, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange 20-share index was down 14.94 points to stand at 3020.38. Turnover was posted at 8.343 million shillings on 236,334 shares compared to 7.538 million shillings on 220,919 shares on Friday.</p>
<p>A bourse official described Monday's trading as moderate. &quot;There were no big lots dealt from the special board, just the usual many small deals.&quot;</p>
<p>A broker said following increased rates on government treasury bills, investors had diverted their funds from the secondary market to treasury bills.</p>
<p>But the broker added that there was also reduced interest from investors because most companies had already announced their results and there appeared nothing sigificant to stir the market.</p>
<p>As a primary issue of Kenya Commercial Bank closes on Tuesday, a floor dealer described purchases of the bank's shares as &quot;furious&quot;, with institutional investors worried they might not get their full allotments.</p>
<p>Brokers said the continued demand was boosted by 's announcement of its interim results.</p>
<p>Kenya Commercial Bank traded 35,245 shares at a steady 58 from 59, Standard Chartered Bank fell to 45.25 from 45.75 while Barclays Bank eased to 98 from 98.50.</p>
<p>Among plantations, Brooke Bond fell 2.0 shillings to 177, Rea Vipingo eased to 10.75 from 10.95. An official said that foreign investors dealt 9,000 shares of Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee at 52.50 from 50.</p>
<p>Kenya Airways traded 56,7545 shares at 9.70 from 9.85, Uchumi Supermarket eased to 46.50 from 57.50.</p>
<p>Oil concern Total Kenya fell to 70 from 71.50.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
