<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113873" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGER: Niger opposition leader arrested, family says.</title>
<headline>Niger opposition leader arrested, family says.</headline>
<dateline>NIAMEY 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leader of one of Niger's opposition parties was arrested by police shortly after accusing the government of the West African state of dictatorship, his family said on Monday.</p>
<p>Family members said Bello Tiousso Garba, leader of the Union for Democracy and Progress (UDP), was arrested on Sunday night. There was no immediate police comment.</p>
<p>UDP is one of eight parties who formed the Front for the Restoration of Democracy. The Front challenges last July's presidential elections won by coupmaker General Ibrahim Bare Mainassara who toppled an elected government in January.</p>
<p>Garba held a news conference on Sunday to counter a statement by Mainassara's spokesman accusing the opposition of blocking moves towards democracy.</p>
<p>He accused the government of corruption and said it was not in a position to lecture the opposition on democracy after Mainassara's January 27 coup.</p>
<p>Mainassara began cracking down on opponents when opposition parties cried foul after he suspended the independent electoral commission part way through the July 7-8 presidential election.</p>
<p>On the second day of voting he put all his four rivals under house arrest, freeing them on July 22. A handpicked electoral commission declared him elected.</p>
<p>The opposition have threatened to boycott twice-postponed parliamentary elections, now rescheduled for November 23. Mainassara recalled the independent electoral committe after the mediation of a council of wise men, but the opposition say it is now packed with the president's supporters.</p>
<p>Mainassara seized power, saying he wanted to end a showdown between the elected president and the prime minister that was paralysing the government of the impoverished country.</p>
<p>He called early elections following Western pressure. But he pushed through a constitution giving greater powers to the president, before standing for the post himself.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NIAMEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGER"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
