<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113827" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Amnesty calls for permanent international court.</title>
<headline>Amnesty calls for permanent international court.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amnesty International launched a worldwide appeal on Monday to establish a permanent international criminal court.</p>
<p>The London-based human rights group wants the court to be created by the year 2000 and have jurisdiction over genocide as well as other serious crimes against humanity.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the United Nations was set up, millions of people have been detained in concentration camps, tortured, raped, bombarded in undefended villages...or been victims of extrajudicial executions or mass exterminations,&quot; Amnesty secretary-general Pierre Sane said in a statement.</p>
<p>Sane said the Nuremberg and Tokyo war crimes tribunals were set up at the end of World War Two to ensure that victims of international crimes would see those responsible brought to justice.</p>
<p>&quot;The tribunals were temporary but the human rights abuses have continued,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Amnesty wants the court's prosecutor to be independent, not subject to a UN Security Council veto and have the powers to investigate cases and present indictments to the court on his or her own initiative.</p>
<p>Sane believes the court should be funded by long-term, secure financing by the United Nations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
