<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="113848" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Burundi rules out talks while sanctions in place.</title>
<headline>Burundi rules out talks while sanctions in place.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Kotch</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundi said on Monday it would refuse to negotiate with Hutu rebels until crippling regional economic and transport sanctions are lifted.</p>
<p>The defiant stand by the tiny central African country's Tutsi military junta was announced to diplomats and foreign correspondents by Prime Minister Pascal Firmin Ndimira at a meeting in the Burundi capital.</p>
<p>Regional analysts in the Kenyan capital Nairobi told Reuters the latest stand was likely to antagonise the leaders of Kenya, Tanzania, Rwanda, Ethiopia, Zaire and Zambia who agreed on Saturday to maintain the embargo to force Burundi to negotiate with the rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;So long as the embargo is not lifted, it is out of the question for Burundi to negotiate with armed factions,&quot; said Ndimira.</p>
<p>&quot;The government of Burundi announces again its willingness to enter into negotiations with the armed groups. However, it considers that the blockade is an obstacle and the government cannot dialogue until it is lifted,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>At a regional heads of state summit in the northern Tanzanian town of Arusha on Saturday, African leaders told Burundi's military ruler Pierre Buyoya on Saturday to open unconditional talks with Hutu rebels within a month or face further sanctions.</p>
<p>Defying a U.S. suggestion to ease the embargo, now more than two months old, the regional leaders said they would send a team to Burundi to check on Buyoya's commitment to unconditional negotiations stated in a letter from him to the Arusha summit meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The summit reiterated that the objective of the sanctions is to serve as an effective means of securing a negotiated settlement between all parties to the conflict,&quot; they said after nearly six hours of talks.</p>
<p>Ethnic war between Burundi's Tutsi-dominated army and Hutu rebels is killing up to 1,000 people monthly and regional leaders fear the country could go down the same path as Rwanda where up to a million people were killed in genocide in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
