<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114053" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Oct 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Oct 14.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Monday. Prepared for Reuters by the Cooperation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- The conservative parties of Latvia and Estonia, Tevzemei un Brivibai and Isamaaliit, concluded an agreement on co-operation last Saturday in the border town of Valga.</p>
<p>- Yesterday several hundred people held a rally near the Victory monument, on the bank of the Daugava river, to commemorate the 52nd anniversary of Riga's liberation from German troops by the Red Army at the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>- The defence ministers of Latvia, Estonia and Lithuania held a regular meeting in Riga. They signed a joint declaration on the further development of the Baltic battalion. For unknown reasons they did not sign the declaration on the creation of joint navy forces nor a declaration on joint air space control.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- The EBRD and the World Bank take an interest in the possibility of buying shares in the Latvian Savings bank.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Valdis Birkavs will leave for a working visit to Iceland. One of the questions scheduled for discussion is the abolition of visa regulations between Latvia and Iceland.</p>
<p>- A Catholic convent was opened in Daugavpils yesterday. It was built with financial support from the Dutch Christian mission.</p>
<p>BIZNES &amp; BALTIYA</p>
<p>- The conflict between the National Radio and Television council and the TV company IGE continues. IGE asks that parliament form a special commission to investigate the activities of the council.</p>
<p>- At the meeting of the Latvian and Lithuanian prime ministers last Friday in Palanga the two sides failed once again to reach any agreement on the delimitation of the maritime border. Lithuania rejected the proposal of being given 50 percent of oil, if any, put forward by the Latvian side.</p>
<p>DIENAS BIZNESS</p>
<p>- Minister of Transport Vilis Krishtopans will accompany President Guntis Ulmanis on his trip to London in November in order to discuss the further privatisation of Lattelekom with Cable&amp;Wireless, the major foreign partner in the Latvian telecommunications monopoly.</p>
<p>- Debts accumulated by the bankrupt national air company Latavio are keeping Air Baltic from flying any routes to Russia. The former airline owes some $3 million to the Russian authorities.</p>
<p>- A German group, Nordorf, will start extracting Latvian peat.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
