<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114257" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Wall Street rally boosts Hong Kong, Australia shares.</title>
<headline>Wall Street rally boosts Hong Kong, Australia shares.</headline>
<byline>Brian Rhoads</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>It was a day of record highs and lows for several Asian markets on Monday.</p>
<p>Lingering sentiment from Wall Street's rally on Friday helped push Hong Kong and Australia markets to record highs.</p>
<p>But Thai shares fell to a 39-month low and Singapore swung to an 18-month low on domestic concerns. Tokyo finished slightly up and most other Asian markets were mixed.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's market took its lead from Friday's rise in U.S. stocks and bonds and investors continued to look for gains.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index closed 111.95 points or 0.92 percent higher at 12,330.35. The previous record close was set last Wednesday at 12,250.57.</p>
<p>&quot;It confirms a breakout,&quot; said Robin Hammond, Hong Kong research director at Asia Equity. &quot;Everything opened strongly. Futures opened at a premium which sucked the market up, with principally property stocks and banking stocks as the gainers.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The market is just following the U.S. last Friday,&quot; said Edwin Cheung, dealing director at Taiwan Securities.</p>
<p>The Dow rose 48 points on Friday to 5,969 on good news about September wholesale prices and retail sales.</p>
<p>The U.S. rally also helped the Australian share market climb to a record close. The key All Ordinaries index ended 26.5 points or 1.13 percent higher at 2,363.3, three points lower than the all-time high of 2,366.3 set in afternoon trade.</p>
<p>Tokyo stocks managed to claw back into positive territory by the close but turnover tumbled to a new low for the year, brokers said, adding that it reflected the cautious trade. They said most investors were inactive ahead of October 20 elections.</p>
<p>The benchmark Nikkei 225 closed 61.09 points or 0.29 percent higher at 21,029.25.</p>
<p>Singapore's key Straits Times Industrial index fell 31.07 points or 1.5 percent to end at an 18-month low of 2,045.58 points, up slightly from an intra-day low of 2,039.16.</p>
<p>&quot;The decline was in response to news that a (recent) government land sale attracted only two low bids and also due to revisions for third quarter growth,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>A recent Business Times poll said economists expected third quarter growth to be an average of 3.4 percent, 1.2 percentage points lower than their forecasts in September.</p>
<p>Despite late local mutual fund buying, Thai stocks ended at a 39-month low after investors sold shares on worries over bank earnings and concern that some property firms may have cash problems, brokers said.</p>
<p>The SET index ended off 14.56 points or 1.56 percent at 918.30. It was the lowest close since July 28, 1993, when the index finished at 908.36. Total turnover was 2.9 billion baht.</p>
<p>Manila shares also ended in negative territory, falling 37.73 points, or 1.27 percent, to 2,935.86 as an early technical rally induced local investors to resort to profit taking, traders said.</p>
<p>Malaysia's blue-chip Composite Index ended up 8.11 points or 0.71 percent to 1,148.85 while Seoul shares closed up 1.48 points or 0.18 percent higher at a provisional 842.28.</p>
<p>Taiwan share prices closed virtually unchanged.</p>
<p>SIMEX Brent futures traded higher late in the day with the market excited by news that anti-Baghdad Kurdish rebels have regained two more towns from pro-Baghdad rivals, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The news from Iraq as well as technical factors are helping to support the market,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>November last traded at $24.25 per barrel, up 27 cents from its last IPE close on Friday at $23.98. Brokers said the resistant level for November is $24.50.</p>
<p>The dollar was steady in late Tokyo against both the yen and the mark as activity waned ahead of a holiday in New York, dealers said. At 1030 GMT, the dollar traded at 111.73/1.78 yen and 1.5305/10 marks.</p>
<p>Hong Kong bullion ended at US$381.10-US$381.50 an ounce against New York's close of US$381.00/50 on Friday, and Saturday's close in Hong Kong of $381.25/75.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
