<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114277" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil products firmer on strong crude.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil products firmer on strong crude.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil products rose on strong crude prices following news that anti-Saddam Kurdish rebels have regained three Kurdish cities in northern Iraq from pro-Baghdad rivals, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>Swaps November gas oil gained 40 cents from Friday and was quoted at $29.85/$29.95 a barrel. Physical gas oil was offered by a major at $$30.20 for end-October/early November lifting fob, 20 cents over last Friday's offer. A bid was seen at $29.70. China's buying interest was limited to $232 a tonne c+f southern China, with sellers indicating $233-$234. A deal was heard done recently over $230 c+f.  </p>
<p>Traders said northern Chinese refineries have gas oil to sell but Chinese buyers might prefer to buy from international market because of easier access.</p>
<p>Nepal's diesel and kerosene purchase tenders for November delivery will be awarded later this evening.</p>
<p>Around 13 offers were received with the lowest for gas oil below $232.90 a tonne and kerosene at $249.50 c+f Indian east coast.</p>
<p>Traders said a Europan major sold 100,000 barrels of jet fuel to a Singapore trader at $30.20 a barrel for Oct 29-Nov 2 lifting fob. The major started its offers at $30.60.  </p>
<p>Naphtha also rose with November/December swaps gaining 40-60 cents a barrel. Traders said physical naphtha is strong on healthy fundamentals underpinned by the return of north Asian petrochemical plants from shutdowns and bullish sentiment in anticipation of imports from India's Reliance. A Singapore major has a mid-November naphtha cargo which it has not yet offered.</p>
<p>But fuel oil bucked the trend to end lower. Traders said prices were dragged down by high stocks in Singapore. The weak undertone offset earlier price gains on higher crude values. At close a 20,000t, 180-cst cargo was sold by a major to a local trader at $120 a tonne.--Singapore newsroom (65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
