<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114307" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt says it has pledges, no progress on Hebron.</title>
<headline>Egypt says it has pledges, no progress on Hebron.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Wright</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt said on Monday it had assurances Israel would carry out old agreements with the Palestinians but on the Israeli-Palestinian side there was no sign of a breakthrough over the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak said he had the assurances from visiting Israeli President Ezer Weizman, who flew to Cairo on Monday to try to mend fences with a powerful neighbour.</p>
<p>&quot;The president (Weizman) assured me that they are honouring the agreements and it is going to be implemented,&quot; Mubarak told a joint news conference with the Israeli head of state.</p>
<p>But Mubarak again refused to see Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu until Israel satisfies the Palestinians on arrangements for an Israeli troop redeployment in Hebron.</p>
<p>&quot;Whenever they reach a solution to that I am ready to meet with him (Netanyahu) and I told him this in my last contact on the phone (on October 4),&quot; Mubarak said.</p>
<p>But Weizman did not give any assurances in public and PLO officials said U.S. peace envoy Dennis Ross had yet to bridge wide gaps on the long-delayed redeployment, which for Arabs has become the litmus test for Netanyahu's attitude to peace.</p>
<p>The PLO officials said Palestinian President Yasser Arafat had rejected a Netanyahu proposal that they hold a summit if Arafat agreed to change the Hebron deal, signed a year ago by Israel's previous government, and give Israel powers in areas previously assigned to the PLO.</p>
<p>The Israeli prime minister told reporters at parliament: &quot;We are in a very sensitive stage of negotiations.&quot;</p>
<p>Chief PLO negotiator Saeb Erekat told Reuters: &quot;They want powers in H1. This is impossible. President Arafat's instructions are not to reopen the agreement.&quot; &quot;H1&quot; is the area to be handed to Palestinian rule under the signed deal.</p>
<p>A PLO official speaking on condition of anonymity said Arafat, in the West Bank town of Nablus, had rejected the Netanyahu proposal brought by Ross on Sunday night. Arafat left Nablus on Monday for Jordan to meet with King Hussein.</p>
<p>Arafat specifically turned down a proposal to deploy the Israeli army on hills overlooking the heart of Hebron, he said.</p>
<p>The hills overlook the area of Hebron where most of some 400 Jewish settlers living amidst 100,000 Palestinians stay in fortified enclaves.</p>
<p>In Cairo Weizman, whose role in Israeli politics is largely ceremonial, struck a conciliatory tone but did not back up the assurance Mubarak attributed to him.</p>
<p>Pressed on Netanyahu's attitude, he said: &quot;We have had security problems in the past, we hope that we will be over it and we have to be very careful of what we do in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;So therefore the government is not going back. The government perhaps has slowed down but I'm sure, as I've said to President Mubarak, that the government of Israel will continue to do all its best to achieve peace with the Palestinians.&quot;</p>
<p>In Amman, Arafat briefed King Hussein on the latest talks over the Hebron redeployment. Jordanian officials said the two leaders held one-on-one talks and were due to be joined by delegations including Jordanian Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti and chief PLO negotiator Saeb Erekat.</p>
<p>&quot;We are here to meet King Hussein to discuss our concerns and difficulties about the lack of implementing the accords, which we all signed,&quot; Arafat told reporters as he crossed into Jordan from the West Bank at the Allenby Bridge.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still delay and procrastination,&quot; Arafat said, adding that special Israeli-Palestinian committees discussing security, civilian and economic issues had made no progress.</p>
<p>Arabs continued to attack Netanyahu, who come to power in June on a platform opposed to territorial concessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Netanyahu's policies are threatening both peace and security... The international community should move to put an end to this aggressive policy,&quot; the central leadership of the National Progressive Front in Syria said in a statement following a meeting on Sunday night.</p>
<p>The front, a coalition of parties led by the Baath party, renewed Syria's commitment to make peace with Israel.</p>
<p>But it stressed that any settlement of the conflict with the Jewish state should be based on the land-for-peace principle, a formula rejected by Netanyahu's government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
