<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114330" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shares shed early gains to close down.</title>
<headline>Israeli shares shed early gains to close down.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed lower in volatile trading on Monday as investors remained indifferent to a cabinet decision to postpone voting on a key part of a capital market reform package, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares fell 0.27 percent, or 0.49 points, to 178.70 on low turnover of 60 million shekels against 52 million on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 blue chip index lost 0.44 percent to 187.58.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to say why the market fell today. Trading opened with nice gains but later the trend changed. The reason might be that the market was affected by a similar change in trend in the options market,&quot; said Danniella Finn, head of sales at Batucha Securities and Investments.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision on the Brodett report (the capital market reform) did not affect trading today and investors are waiting to see what the government decides in two weeks,&quot; Finn said.</p>
<p>The cabinet adopted on Monday morning only part of the Finance Ministry's reform package recommended by a panel, headed by the ministry's director general, David Brodett. Measures concerning savings, including a politically sensitive tax on savings of less than 10 years, will be voted on in two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is really sick and nothing is happening in it. Without the tax on savings the (Brodett) report is meaningless,&quot; said Amir Eyal at Epsilon Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will never tax saving plans. I see no reason for a change in the market in the near future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The most active shares were Bank Leumi, which fell 2.0 percent to 346 on volume of 3.9 million shekels; Israel Corp, which lost 1.0 percent to 17,265 on turnover of 3.3 million shekels; and Teva Pharmaceutical Industries, which gained 0.25 percent to 135,734 on volume of 3.0 million shekels.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.19 shekels)</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
