<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114450" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton extends lead over Dole in Reuters poll.</title>
<headline>Clinton extends lead over Dole in Reuters poll.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton led Republican Bob Dole by 14.8 percentage points on Monday in the Reuters daily tracking poll and appeared to hold a commanding position two days before the final presidential debate.</p>
<p>The poll, conducted by John Zogby Group International, tracks about 900 likely voters over a three-day period. The latest result, with a 3.3 percentage point margin of error, reflects polling on Friday through Sunday.</p>
<p>Clinton had 47.7 percent, ahead of Dole's 32.9 percent. Reform Party candidate Ross Perot trailed with 4.6 percent and 12.1 percent of respondents were still undecided.</p>
<p>Until recently, Clinton's strength was not being passed on to Democratic congressional candidates, but that has changed in the past three days, raising the possibility that the Democrats could recapture at least one house of Congress.</p>
<p>Asked whom they would support in their local congressional district, 39.4 percent said Democrats and 33.9 percent said Republicans. Some analysts now give the Democrats a 50-50 chance of regaining the majority in the House of Representatives only two years after losing it to Republicans.</p>
<p>Clinton and Dole meet in their second and last debate on Wednesday in San Diego. With Election Day only three weeks away, the poll suggested the president had little to fear.</p>
<p>Dole has not exceeded 39 percent in any Reuters poll since August, while Clinton has not fallen below 43 percent. He now leads Dole in every region of the country, although the race has tightened in the Republican stronghold of the South.</p>
<p>He also leads among every age group, every ethnic group and every income group.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the sixth straight day that Clinton's lead has increased. In one week it has gone from 5.3 percent to today's 14.8 percent,&quot; pollster John Zogby said. &quot;Time is running out for Dole and it is not surprising that he and his advisers have decided on the risky option of attacking Clinton's character. Nothing else has worked to date.&quot;</p>
<p>Significantly, Clinton was gaining 23 percent of the vote among those describing themselves as &quot;very conservative&quot; and 29 percent of those who say they are &quot;conservative.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole has the support of only 71 percent of Republicans while Clinton has 87 percent of Democratic votes. Clinton leads among independents by 19 percentage points. He leads by five points among men and 23 points among women.</p>
<p>				Table 1</p>
<p>If the election for president were held today, for whom would you vote, Clinton, Dole, or Perot?</p>
<p>				Reuters Tracking</p>
<p>	     Oc14 Oc13 Oc12 Oc11 Oc10 10/9 10/8 10/7 10/6</p>
<p> Clinton   47.7 45.5 44.5 43.8 44.2 44.7 43.8 44.4 47.3</p>
<p> Dole	32.9 32.9 34.3 34.1 35.7 36.6 38.5 35.1 31.9</p>
<p> Perot	4.6  7.0  8.3  8.7  6.1  4.4  4.5  5.8  5.3</p>
<p> Other	2.7  2.1  1.3  1.2  2.3  2.1  1.9  1.6  2.0</p>
<p> Undecided 12.1 12.6 11.6 12.3 11.7 12.2 11.3 13.0 13.4</p>
<p>Note: Columns may not add to 100 % due to rounding</p>
<p>Which party's candidate do you intend to vote</p>
<p>for in your congressional district?</p>
<p> Democrat   39.4 38.6 38.6 36.0 35.3 36.1 36.7 37.9 36.1</p>
<p>Rebublican 33.5 33.8 35.1 35.1 36.3 36.4 36.8 35.6 35.3</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
