<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114499" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN panel sees no change on Iraq oil deal delays.</title>
<headline>UN panel sees no change on Iraq oil deal delays.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The UN Security Council Sanctions Committee on Iraq was told Monday implementation of the oil-for-food plan continued to be delayed due to security concerns in the northern Kurdish regions of the country.</p>
<p>A U.S. official on the panel told reporters there were no major actions taken by the panel during Monday's meeting.</p>
<p>The offical reiterated that nothing has changed since last week when top UN officials said conditions to implement the limited sales deal remained untenable.</p>
<p>Implementation of the limited oil plan has been delayed since September 1.  </p>
<p>At that time, UN Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali delayed deployment of UN staff meant to monitor oil sales and aid distribution under the plan.</p>
<p>The U.S. official also said the committee once again deferred a decision on a Turkish request to buy Iraqi oil as an exception to the oil-for-plan.</p>
<p>The official said the Turkish request would be dealt with after the oil plan was implemented.  </p>
<p>Also on Monday's agenda were requests by Iraq for what the U.S. official termed &quot;non-humanitarian aid,&quot; notably an $18 million request for the oil industry to repair equipment, as well as a request to increase funds from the oil plan to pay for crude production and trasportation costs.</p>
<p>The U.S. official said no action was taken on these requests, and noted the oil-for-plan does not include provisions for infrastructure and transportation expenditures.  </p>
<p>The oil-for-food accord would allow $2 billion in oil sales every six months to be as humanitarian relief for the Iraqi populace suffering under UN-imposed sanction after Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>-- Patrick Connole, United Nations +1 212 859 1828</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
