<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114491" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FOCUS - Calm end to Finnish markets' first ERM day.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Calm end to Finnish markets' first ERM day.</headline>
<byline>Roland Moller</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish financial markets responded calmly to the markka's link to Europe's Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM) on Monday, with the markka steady, bonds firmer and shares mixed amid some doubts on prospects for exporters.</p>
<p>The markka was steady as a rock despite overnight attempts in Singapore to head down towards its 3.04 central parity rate against the German mark. It held a range between 2.9850 and 2.9880 per mark, to close unchanged on Friday at 2.9860.</p>
<p>Finnish bonds outperformed German Bunds, narrowing the 10-year yield spread between the two by nine points lower to 39, but with scant volume.</p>
<p>Stocks were becalmed, at a loss for direction as the link, which could be bearish for forestries, came days before interim results from the sector due on Thursday.</p>
<p>The HEX added 0.23 percent to 2,189.95 with volume in official hours a very thin 242 million markka. The forest industry sub-index fell early on but regained some ground to end down almost one percent with Kymmene off one markka at 93.50.</p>
<p>The Bank of Finland said it was pleased with the markets' response and the government said it had expected calm.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been very pleased with the exchange rate level and stability (today) because it is fully market driven,&quot; Bank of Finland governor Sirkka Hamalainen said in an interview with Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>Her remarks followed early talk of intervention at levels above 2.98 per German mark, but this was rapidly doused by some dealers and petered out.</p>
<p>Operators said they expected the Bank of Finland to stick to a fluctuation band of two to four percent for the markka rather than the ERM's official 15 percent margins either way.</p>
<p>They said bonds were poised to gain more as long as EMU seems on track and Finland remains a single currency candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the (2006) gap over Germany to fall to 25 basis points...in a month or so,&quot; said Henrik Alsoe, economist at Danish Unibank.</p>
<p>However, he added this was based on a bullish scenario for German and U.S. bond markets -- a more stable international trend would make the narrowing process much slower.</p>
<p>Foreign exchange market operators also agreed to extend trading hours to 1415 GMT, after the Bank of Finland noted that its responsibility was to keep the markka steady between 0700 and 1500 GMT, which dealers said increased pressure to bring bond market hours more in line with international times.</p>
<p>In stocks, analysts saw scope for Finnish valuations to rise to converge over time with other European markets. But even in an upbeat economic scenario they said Helsinki would generally retain a discount to other European markets.</p>
<p>&quot;If confidence in the Euro remains strong -- which is the scenario we currently believe  -- I see this as a positive thing,&quot; said Elina Timonen, chief analyst at Merita Bank.</p>
<p>Analysts were calm even though nerves about the competitiveness of Finnish forestry companies -- potentially exposed to competitive devaluation by Sweden if the economic situation worsened -- dented forestry shares early on.</p>
<p>The forestry sector accounted for over half Finland's 1995 exports.</p>
<p>&quot;I actually believe that even though it seems pessimistic now, there is more will in Sweden (to join EMU and link the crown to the ERM) than is shown,&quot; said Timonen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
