<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114592" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German police comb countryside for kidnap victim.</title>
<headline>German police comb countryside for kidnap victim.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>German police with helicopters and tracker dogs scoured the countryside north of Frankfurt on Monday for clues to the whereabouts of kidnapped multi-millionaire Jakub Fiszmann, police said.</p>
<p>The 40-year-old businessman was abducted at the start of October. Fiszmann's brother Georg paid over a four-million-mark ($2.6 million) ransom on October 10 for his release, but his kidnappers failed to free him as promised the following day.</p>
<p>Hundreds of police searched the area of forest and fields, near the town of Idstein, after an anonymous phone call said cars had been seen in the locality.</p>
<p>Police thought the cars might have been involved in the kidnapping. They were also on the lookout for possible dug-outs in the earth which could be used to hide Fiszmann.</p>
<p>The last confirmation that Fiszmann was still alive came on October 2, one day after the kidnap during which he was injured in a scuffle.</p>
<p>Fiszmann telephoned a contact person, believed to be his girlfriend, saying he was being held by kidnappers in a cellar.</p>
<p>A ransom of 3.5 million marks ($2.3 million) was set, later raised to four million marks.</p>
<p>Fiszmann needs medication to treat specific food allergies so police are watching out for sales of the drugs Zyrtec, Lenen, Pulmicortnasal and Beconase in hopes of picking up a clue to where the abductors are located.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
