<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114532" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Britain puts &quot;quota hoppers&quot; before fish cuts.</title>
<headline>Britain puts &quot;quota hoppers&quot; before fish cuts.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>British fisheries minister Tony Baldry, dismissing a clash with his Spanish counterpart, said on Monday Britain would not implement further fleet cuts until the issue of &quot;quota hoppers&quot; is settled.</p>
<p>He added Britain would not boycott proceedings and would take an active part in negotiations on measures to protect fish stocks and ensure a long term future for the fishing industry.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not prepared to contemplate any further substantial reductions in the UK fishing fleet until this whole issue of quota hopping is resolved,&quot; Baldry told a news briefing during a meeting of European Union fisheries ministers.</p>
<p>Baldry said that some 20 percent of the British catch quota is taken by &quot;quota hoppers&quot; -- mainly Spanish vessels who register under the British flag.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a crazy situation that can't continue,&quot; he said, noting that Prime Minister John Major had raised the issue at a recent EU summit in Dublin reviewing the EU treaty.</p>
<p>Asked about an intervention by Spanish Fisheries Minister Loyola de Palacio objecting about Baldry's alleged description of Spanish fishermen as &quot;looters,&quot; Baldry said he couldn't be held responsible for the Spanish translation.</p>
<p>Nor could he be responsible for the Spanish minister's &quot;somewhat sensitive&quot; reaction to the term &quot;quota hoppers,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>De Palacio was quoted by officials as objecting to the term &quot;quota hoppers,&quot; which implied in Spanish some form of piracy. Spanish vessels, she said, were legally flying the British flag.</p>
<p>The European Court of Justice recently sanctioned Britain for its action against &quot;quota hoppers,&quot; the minister noted, a reference to its judgement last March that Britain erred in restricting the operations of foreign-owned vessels in its waters.</p>
<p>The Spanish minister stressed that free movement of labour and capital was one of the principles of the EU's single market and that &quot;quota hoppers&quot; were being discussed separately in an ongoing conference on the EU treaty.</p>
<p>Baldry said that national fish quotas meant there was no effective free market in fish.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I03000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
