<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114631" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEPAL: Nepal PM opens joint venture bank with Sri Lanka.</title>
<headline>Nepal PM opens joint venture bank with Sri Lanka.</headline>
<dateline>KATHMANDU 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nepali Prime Minister Sher Bahadur Deuba on Monday inaugurated a joint venture bank between Sri Lanka and Nepali investors, a local news agency said.</p>
<p>The state-owned Bank of Ceylon of Sri Lanka would subscribe 40 percent shares in the Nepal-Bank of Ceylon Limited which has a paid up capital of 500 million rupees ($8.8 million), the Rashtriya Samachar Samiti (RSS) said.</p>
<p>Nepal's N.B. group along with three local investors would hold 30 percent of equity and the rest would be open for public subscription, the news agency reported.</p>
<p>It would be the Himalayan kingdom's 11th bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Nepal has embraced open and liberal economic policy to attract foreign investment in the banking and industrial sectors,&quot; Deuba said at the inauguration of a bank at Siddharthanagar, 350-kms (218 miles) west of Kathmandu.</p>
<p>Lumbini, where Lord Buddha is believed to have been born, is located near Siddharthanagar.</p>
<p>&quot;Our priority is to help the rural sector which is why we thought we will start from the birthplace of Lord Buddha,&quot; the new bank's managing director D V K Jayasuriya told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bank officials said the Sri Lankan bank will buy additional five percent of the equity in the bank from the Nepali promoters at a later stage.</p>
<p>Nepal liberalised its economy in 1992 to attract foreign investment to lift its sagging economy and has privatised 11 state-owned enterprises in the past four years.</p>
<p>Nepal-Bank of Ceylon Limited is the ninth joint venture commercial bank in Nepal. There are two other  two government owned banks in Nepal. Nepal does not allow foreign banks to open branches.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KATHMANDU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEPAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
