<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="114982" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Markka makes sound ERM debut, bourses mixed.</title>
<headline>Markka makes sound ERM debut, bourses mixed.</headline>
<byline>Roger Jeal</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Finnish markka made a sound debut in the European Union's currency grid on Monday, while major European stock markets paused for breath at the start of a new week.</p>
<p>In the latest step on the path towards a single European Union currency, Finland agreed at the weekend to put the markka into the Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM), which limits the fluctuations of a majority of EU currencies against each other.</p>
<p>One of the Maastricht treaty's criteria for membership of European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) in 1999 is at least two years of membership of the ERM.</p>
<p>The markka traded around 2.9890 to the German mark in early trading, little changed from Friday's Helsinki close and compared with its ERM central rate of 3.04. Its entry into the mechanism had been widely signalled but its central rate was 1.7 percent weaker than the previous spot market level.</p>
<p>With European currency news taking the spotlight, the dollar held its ground and currency dealers said it could receive support from fallout from the Finnish move.</p>
<p>&quot;To the extent that Finland's move underlines the EMU process, then it should keep the mark under pressure and the dollar supported,&quot; said Joe Prendergast, foreign exchange strategist at Merrill Lynch in London.</p>
<p>But he added that the U.S. currency seemed to lack the fuel for a strong push higher. Traders said many U.S. dealers could be missing for the Columbus Day holiday on Monday, limiting trading activity in currencies.</p>
<p>The New Zealand dollar strengthened as Saturday's election, while inconclusive, recorded relatively weak support for left-wing parties. It was quoted around 69.95 U.S. cents versus 69.20 at the New Zealand opening earlier.</p>
<p>The pound, meanwhile, hit 2.4192 marks in early trade, its highest since January 1995, and held most of its gains after news of a slightly higher-than expected 0.4 percent rise in British output prices last month.</p>
<p>European bourses had been in buoyant mood on Friday, rising on figures which suggested that inflation in the United States, the world's biggest economy, was being kept in check. But they consolidated their gains on Monday.</p>
<p>The London stock market, Europe's biggest, showed a marginal loss by mid-morning. Traders said the key FTSE 100 index, which ended just 19 points below its all-time high on Friday, was vulnerable to political jitters with an election due by May.</p>
<p>&quot;Politics is now high on the agenda,&quot; one trader said. &quot;People are questioning whether this government has the ability to get to the end of its term.&quot;</p>
<p>French stocks opened lower in thin trading, amid nervousness ahead of a public sector strike on Thursday, but the Frankfurt bourse made moderate gains.</p>
<p>U.S. stocks and bonds rallied on Friday after news that producer prices rose only moderately last month, calming inflation jitters. The Dow Jones industrial average rose 47.71 points to 5,969.38 but was down on the week.</p>
<p>Wall Street will open as usual on Monday although U.S. bond markets will stay shut for the Columbus Day holiday. No major U.S. economic statistics are scheduled for release.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted around 1.5305 marks and 111.66 yen, compared with 1.5307 and 111.67 in late European business on Friday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 0930 GMT</p>
<p>The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was down 0.2 point at 4,027.9.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was 10.30 lower at 2,136.82.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was up 7.73 at 2,693.76.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold traded around $381.30 an ounce in early European trading, compared with Friday's London close of $381.35. Silver edged up to $5.04 from $5.02.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
