<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115019" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan delays 150,000 T wheat tender to Oct 17.</title>
<headline>Jordan delays 150,000 T wheat tender to Oct 17.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan has postponed a snap tender to buy 150,000 tonnes of U.S. red hard winter or spring wheat or equivalent origin to October 17 due to a U.S. holiday, traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>Jordan originally set October 15 as a deadline for bids, but postponed it due to the U.S. Columbus Day holiday, traders said.  </p>
<p>An annex to the tender announced on Monday said that offers for U.S. origin wheat are to be covered under a $40 million credit guarantee for gain purchases granted to Jordan last September to be made available under the GSM-102 programme.</p>
<p>The shipment is to be delivered in three lots of 50,000 tonnes each in November, December and January.</p>
<p>Officials said the government may lower bread prices in Jordan if offer levels are attractive enough.</p>
<p>Jordan is considering a reduction in bread prices prompted by recent cheaper wheat purchases.</p>
<p>The decision to almost double bread prices in August in line with IMF-agreed economic reforms led to the worst civil unrest since riots in 1989, also sparked by government price rises.</p>
<p>Since August Jordan has bought 140,000 tonnes of wheat at prices ranging from $191-206 per tonne, a drop of nearly 25 percent from a high of $275 per tonne in May.</p>
<p>Bread is a staple food for Jordan's 4.2 million people, who have a per capita gross domestic product of about $1,500 a year.</p>
<p>--Amman Newsroom +9626-623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
