<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115012" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BAHRAIN: GCC chief tries to persuade Bahrain to attend summit.</title>
<headline>GCC chief tries to persuade Bahrain to attend summit.</headline>
<dateline>MANAMA 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the Gulf Cooperation Council (GCC) arrived in Bahrain on Monday in an apparent attempt to convince the island state's ruler to attend the next Gulf Arab summit.</p>
<p>The official Gulf News Agency said GCC Secretary-General Jameel Hujilan met Bahrain's Emir Sheikh Isa bin Sulman al-Khalifa immediately after his arrival. Crown Prince Sheikh Hamad bin Isa al-Khalifa also attended the meeting.</p>
<p>The agency gave no details, but sources at the Riyadh-based GCC said Hujilan's visit was aimed at trying to convince Bahrain to attend a Gulf Arab summit in the Qatari capital Doha in December.</p>
<p>They said the visit was at the request of Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>Bahrain and Qatar are locked in a territorial dispute over a cluster of barren reefs and islands which are potentially rich in oil and gas. They include Hawar islands, which have been controlled by Bahrain since the 1930s.</p>
<p>Bahrain has threatened to boycott the summit in protest against Qatar's failure to withdraw a case it has taken to the International Court of Justice to settle the dispute.</p>
<p>Qatar said it would only withdraw the case from the world court in the Hague if Saudi Arabia's mediation succeeded in settling the long-standing border row.</p>
<p>Qatar asked the court in 1991 to settle the problem. The court decided in January it had jurisdiction and is expected to produce a verdict by the end of this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BAHRAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
