<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115145" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian shares end up, ignore Euro-sceptic poll.</title>
<headline>Austrian shares end up, ignore Euro-sceptic poll.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares closed slightly higher on Monday, boosted by European markets.</p>
<p>European parliament elections on Sunday which pushed the country's far right to a historic high, appeared to have no impact on the market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was no evident effect from the polls in the market, although we might see something over the next few days,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The ATX index of 21 blue-chips climbed 0.48 points or 0.04 percent to 1,081.81. Among its constituents were 14 gainers, five losers and two shares unchanged.</p>
<p>Traders said the market had been subdued amid meagre turnover. The index could push higher to 1,100 in the week ahead but looked likely to consolidate recent gains first, they added.</p>
<p>October ATX futures rose 8.1 schillings to 1,084.1.</p>
<p>Insurer Wiener Staedtische was the leading gainer, jumping 13 schillings to 988.</p>
<p>The leading decliner was card board maker Mayr-Melnhof, shedding 10 schillings to 533.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna Bourse index added 0.02 points to 413.24. -- Vienna newsroom, +431 531 12257</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
