<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115219" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French VAT may be cut in next 5 years - Lamassoure.</title>
<headline>French VAT may be cut in next 5 years - Lamassoure.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>French budget minister Alain Lamassoure said in an interview published on Monday that the government might cut Value Added Tax (VAT) in the next five years if the economy grew more than 2.5 percent per year.</p>
<p>&quot;A cut in VAT will be possible in the five years ahead if the rate of growth exceeds 2.5 percent because then we will have extra room to manoeuvre and the taxes that were raised in mid-1995, like VAT, can be reduced,&quot; Lamassoure said in an interview with afternoon daily Le Monde.</p>
<p>&quot;The cut in VAT is therefore not ruled out but it is not for 1997 in the budget bill because it must be done as and when returning growth allows,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The UDF party, junior ruling coalition member, has said it would like to lower VAT from 1997. VAT was raised by two percentage points to 20.6 percent in August 1995.</p>
<p>When asked about the possibility of eliminating a planned rise in petrol duties from the 1997 budget, Lamassoure said it was not out of the question but could be allowed only if a substitute source of revenues were found.</p>
<p>&quot;If the UDF believes the rise is too much, we are not necessarily closed to discussion, but on two very precise conditions: the cut in income taxes cannot be affected and the deputies must propose another revenue source of the same size,&quot; Lamassoure said.</p>
<p>The government has decided to cut income taxes by 25 billion francs next year and 75 billion over the coming five years.</p>
<p>Lamassoure said the government believed it had only a little room to negotiate on raising civil servants' pay and he refused to name a sum the government was willing to offer.</p>
<p>He said the government would meet its 1996 budget targets and cautioned not to read too much into monthly budget results for the end of August due to be published shortly.</p>
<p>&quot;They will seem disappointing, whereas we know, today, that reality is different,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had, this autumn, tax revenues on corporations far higher than our expectations and good revenues from income tax. We will hit the target we set for ourselves by deciding that the 1996 budget deficit would not exceed 288 billion francs,&quot; Lamassoure told Le Monde.</p>
<p>The government has pledged to keep the budget deficit capped at 288 billion francs this year and lower it to 284 billion francs next year as part of its efforts to meet criteria for joining a single European currency.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
