<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115280" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: utch Sport7 channel gets poor reception.</title>
<headline>utch Sport7 channel gets poor reception.</headline>
<byline>Philip Blenkinsop</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sport7, a Dutch television channel aimed at giving the country's sports fans access to live soccer matches and sporting events, has been dealt a double blow only three months after going live.</p>
<p>Investment bank ING Barings has estimated Sport7 will make a loss of 102 million guilders ($60 million) for the 1996/97 financial year, saying the channel is suffering from poor audience ratings and large start-up costs.</p>
<p>And the Dutch soccer association (KNVB), which has a 10 percent stake in Sport7, has criticised the channel as being packaged for Amsterdam viewers in a bundle which includes a soft pornography channel.</p>
<p>Sport7 began broadcasting in August and most Dutch viewers can receive it for the standard cable TV fee, but, in and around Amsterdam, it forms part of a supplementary pay-TV package.</p>
<p>ING Barings said Sport7 needed to link up with other commercial channels to form a powerful pay-TV package, but that it would be two years before sophisticated pay-TV decoders allowed this.</p>
<p>Recent Dutch audience research figures showed Sport7 gained a four percent share of the national TV audience in its first full month of operation.</p>
<p>The top nine television audiences in The Netherlands last year were all for soccer matches featuring the then European champions Ajax Amsterdam or the Dutch national side.</p>
<p>In an interview with NRC Handelsblad newspaper on Saturday, Jos Staatsen, president of the KNVB, said he was unhappy with the way the Amsterdam cable-TV firm A2000 had packaged Sport7 with other channels.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I'm concerned Sport7 should pull out of that package as soon as possible. It's a revolting package. Sport7 is being used to shoe-horn the other channels in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The KNVB has sold exclusive rights for Dutch league soccer to Sport7 in a billion-guilder, seven-year deal and also took a 10 percent stake in the channel.</p>
<p>A2000, which pipes television to households in and around the Dutch capital, is a cable joint venture between Philips Electronics NV and US West.</p>
<p>Its pay-TV package groups Sport7 with a Chinese-language channel (CNE) and The Adult Channel which features soft-porn.</p>
<p>Sport7 has taken a battering from the Dutch media since its start in August, but Staatsen was unwilling to write the channel off yet.</p>
<p>&quot;Sport7 has not been on the air for two months yet. Some parts of the media have already sounded its death knell. But the public has not yet had the chance to decide. The stakeholders still have complete faith in the venture,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The key shareholders in Sport7 are PTT Nederland, ING, Philips and Dutch TV production firm Endemol, each with 19.5 percent, the KNVB, and publisher De Telegraaf, with five percent. ($1=1.717 Guilder)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
