<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115340" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: No immediate Goldman comment on Sumitomo report.</title>
<headline>No immediate Goldman comment on Sumitomo report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Goldman Sachs International said it had no immediate comment on a British newspaper report that Sumitomo Corp had assigned the US investment bank the the task of unwinding huge holdings of copper.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no comment we can make at the moment,&quot; said a London spokesperson at Goldman Sachs International, a subsidiary of Goldman Sachs Group. Sumitomo said in June it had lost $1.8 billion - later raised to $2.6 billion - on what it alleges was unauthorised trading by Yasuo Hamanaka. The trader built a big long position in copper.</p>
<p>The Guardian said on Monday that Goldman was in June handed perhaps the most sensitive job in the history of metals trading -- disposing of the copper holding. It quoted sources with a close knowledge of Sumitomo's position as saying that Goldman had completely unwound the stockpile although it added that other traders disagreed.</p>
<p>The Guardian said there was no suggestion of impropriety on Goldman's part but that the assignment &quot;seems to have led&quot; it into conflict with regulatory and police agencies.</p>
<p>They are investigating the Hamanaka affair. The Guardian said they might now regard Goldman as a source of information whilst it had had to instruct lawyers in relation to business carried out by its commodity dealing arm J. Aron and Co.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
