<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115344" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British opposition calls for tougher sleaze probe.</title>
<headline>British opposition calls for tougher sleaze probe.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's main opposition parties increased pressure on the government on Monday for an independent inquiry into allegations of parliamentary sleaze involving a former minister.</p>
<p>Labour and the minority Liberal Democrats claim a parliamentary watchdog set up after a wave of sleaze scandals does not have sufficient powers for an in-depth inquiry.</p>
<p>They are also concerned about allegations that ruling Conservative party managers sought to influence a key committee which governs the conduct of members of parliament.</p>
<p>The move, which comes the day parliament resumes after the summer break, was designed to keep up pressure on the government in the run-up to an election now no more than seven months away.</p>
<p>It was given extra weight by the weekend decision of a Conservative rebel MP, Peter Thurnham, to join the Liberal Democrats in protest at Prime Minister John Major's handling of the sleaze row.</p>
<p>Donald Dewar, Labour's senior parliamentary manager, said: &quot;What we're trying to do here...is to get a comprehensive examination which is designed to allay public fears.&quot;</p>
<p>But senior Conservative MPs were outraged by the move, which they said was motivated by a desire to score political points off the government and not a concern for ethics.</p>
<p>Conservative MP Paul Marland told the BBC: &quot;I'm astonished that the Labour party and the Liberals are actually taking this issue up again...It doesn't do parliament any good.</p>
<p>The new outbreak of conflict follow successful annual party conferences for both Labour and the Conservatives.</p>
<p>Major managed to pull his party together and give an image of unity at his conference last week, portraying himself as an honest, down-to-earth leader.</p>
<p>But Labour, whose disciplined party conference boosted their already huge opinion poll lead, believes the ruling party is vulnerable to charges of sleaze after 17 years in office.</p>
<p>Major has a parliamentary majority of just two. Although it is unlikely Major could be brought down over the current argument, a call for a vote of no confidence could be damaging.</p>
<p>Labour leader Tony Blair, on a tour of South Africa, on Sunday left the option open. &quot;We will have to wait and see how the debate progresses. I don't rule anything out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The latest case involves allegations that former trade minister Neil Hamilton accepted cash in return for asking parliamentary questions in breaches of House of Commons rules.</p>
<p>Hamilton has denied the charges. But two weeks ago he dropped a libel action against the Guardian newspaper which broke the story. Hamilton said he could not afford the legal fees, but the Guardian responded by printing fresh allegations.</p>
<p>The new allegations are to be investigated by Sir Gordon Downey, the so-called Parliamentary Commissioner for Standards -- a post set up after a full-scale inquiry last year sparked by the original charges which led to a tightening up of rules.</p>
<p>But Dewar said he believed Downey's current powers would not allow him to investigate all the new allegations.</p>
<p>They also want him to investigate charges a Conservative party manager, David Willetts, wrote to ruling party MPs on the key House of Commons privileges committee suggesting they use their majority to ensure Hamilton was cleared.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
