<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115429" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: PM says no racism debate raging in Australia. [CORRECTED 05:50 GMT]</title>
<headline>PM says no racism debate raging in Australia. [CORRECTED 05:50 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Jane Nelson</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard on Monday denied that anti-Asian remarks by a maverick politician had set off a &quot;raging&quot; national debate on racism and said Australians should be proud of their history of immigration.</p>
<p>Howard, who has resisted pressure to openly condemn independent member of parliament Pauline Hanson for her views, accused the media of inflaming the whole racism issue.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the claims that have been made by many people in recent days about a racism debate in the Australian community are superficial and juvenile,&quot; Howard told state radio.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there's a raging racist debate in the Australian community at all.&quot;</p>
<p>Howard was commenting on a newspaper interview on Sunday in which Hanson warned that Australia faced a Bosnia-style civil war if migrants and Aborigines continued to get special treatment.</p>
<p>(Corrects to make clear warning came in an interview, not a speech)</p>
<p>Hanson, a fish and chip shop owner from conservative Queensland state, has dominated Australian headlines since her maiden parliamentary speech last month.</p>
<p>She used that speech to criticise the government over the number of Asians in the country, warned of an Asian invasion threat, and even took a swipe at indigenous Aborgines.</p>
<p>An opinion poll in The Sydney Morning Herald newspaper last week found 48 percent of respondents backed Hanson, while only 38 percent disagreed with her views.</p>
<p>Australian agricultural and trade officials have expressed concern that the row could harm the country's burgeoning trade ties with its neighbours in Asia. Asians make up around one-third of the 100,000 immigrants into Australia every year.</p>
<p>But Howard said on Monday he believed the majority of Australians were not racist.</p>
<p>&quot;Most Australians are very tolerant,&quot; he said. &quot;... in reality, the great majority of Australians have demonstrated a capacity to absorb people from all around the world the like of which few other countries have achieved since the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;That should be a source of pride -- it should not be a source of defensiveness.&quot;</p>
<p>Aware of the poll findings and with a parliamentary by-election due next weekend, both government and opposition have been stepping gingerly around Hanson and the racism row.</p>
<p>But opposition leader Kim Beazley, who has been increasingly critical of the MP, said on Monday she was an &quot;unguided missile&quot; that had to be shot back at.</p>
<p>&quot;She's come out and said that we've got some equivalent Bosnian situation developing here and that is a load of cobblers (nonsense),&quot; Beazley said in a radio interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that what we've got here is a pretty unguided missile launched into the Australian community and we are just going to have, to every now and then, pepper it with a bit of counter-battery fire.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
