<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115513" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper ends sharply down on LME losses.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper ends sharply down on LME losses.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended sharply down with later-maturing contracts hitting a 1996 low on Monday due to last Friday's losses on the London Metal Exchange, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active January 1997 contract ended at 19,420 yuan ($2,340) per tonne, losing 240 yuan. It opened at an intra-day high of 19,600 and hit a low of 19,350.</p>
<p>October fell 280 to 19,320 yuan, November 300 to 19,300, December 270 to 19,350, February 210 to 19,450, March 150 to 19,500 and April 250 to 19,550.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 73,890 tonnes from 63,900.  </p>
<p>Copper opened lower and fell further for most of the session with the most active January and February contracts breaching the key 19,500 support level.</p>
<p>Traders said speculative and hedging selling emerged at high levels due to last Friday's LME losses and over-surplus of domestic spot copper.</p>
<p>&quot;The poor market sentiment did not change and many investors built short positions at high levels today,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Copper is likely to find further support at low levels in the short term,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Traders said futures prices faced heavy pressure with domestic spot price dropping step by step.</p>
<p>&quot;Falls of spot prices indicated domestic spot demand has not improved at all despite a booming consumer season,&quot; a second trader said. Prices of spot copper in Shanghai has fallen to about 20,000 yuan per tonne from 20,100 two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Traders expect copper to test the 19,000 yuan key support level in the next few days on weak market sentiment.</p>
<p>Aluminium ended down. October fell 120 to 13,580, November 40 to 13,600, December 150 to 13,400 and January 200 to 13,300.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 1,410 tonnes from 800.</p>
<p>($1=8.2990 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
