<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115633" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: FEATURE - Credit card war heats up in Taiwan.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Credit card war heats up in Taiwan.</headline>
<byline>Nailene Chou Wiest</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Free airline mileage, travel irons, water purifiers, toasters, lucky number draws and many other prizes are yours -- if you pay by credit card in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Banks are wooing with increasing intensity the growing number of rich  customers on this prosperous island who are only now acquiring the habit of plunking down plastic rather than cash at payment counters.</p>
<p>And, they are using a dizzying array of gimmicks to carve out a slice of the potentially lucrative market.</p>
<p>Experts say the winners will be banks that achieve economies of scale due to the labour-intensive nature of the business.</p>
<p>&quot;You need volume to make money,&quot; said Albert Hsiung, head of clearinghouse VISA International Service Association in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Since international cards debuted in Taiwan in 1989, the number of cardholders has rocketed by over 50 percent a year and show no signs of slowing down, Hsiung said.</p>
<p>In 1996, Taiwan card holders are expected to charge T$270 billion to T$280 billion (US$9.8 billion to US$10.2 billion) -- a mere five percent of total personal spending.</p>
<p>By contrast, people in Hong Kong and Singapore -- similarly wealthy and largely Chinese communities -- ring up 10-12 percent of their spending on plastic. Americans charge nearly 20 percent, he said.</p>
<p>By western standards, Taiwan's 21 million people could be expected to pack 100 million credit cards in their pockets.</p>
<p>But fewer than five million cards are now in circulation.</p>
<p>&quot;The market penetration is still very low,&quot; Hsiung said.</p>
<p>Neck-and-neck in the early lead with more than one million cards each are ChinaTrust Commercial Bank, a top private bank, and the local unit of Citibank.</p>
<p>&quot;Some 20 years ago, we envisaged a different payment system from cash-based transactions,&quot; said ChinaTrust marketing vice president Peter Ziang.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a long process to change people's spending habits.&quot;</p>
<p>Faced with stiffening foreign and local competition, Ziang said ChinaTrust cannot afford to take customer loyalty for granted, although competition not yet hurt ChinaTrust.</p>
<p>&quot;Our competitors introduce more people to the use of credit cards, and that's positive for us as well,&quot; he said. &quot;It's not as if the others must grow at our expense.&quot;</p>
<p>Citibank, with its upscale client base and dazzling technology, celebrated its million-cards-in-force milestone in August with considerable marketing fanfare.</p>
<p>Staking a claim to market leadership, Citibank spokeswoman Pat Lin said the U.S. giant measured &quot;cards in force&quot; -- those in active use -- as opposed to the &quot;cards in circulation&quot;, which includes idle accounts.</p>
<p>Tougher screening ensures Citibank does not take on customers who won't or shouldn't buy on credit, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are more selective in issuing cards,&quot; she said, noting that only 70-80 percent of applicants pass credit checks.</p>
<p>Both ChinaTrust and Citibank hold the line on annual fees, which run T$1,200 (US$44) for a regular card and T$2,400 (US$88) for a gold card.</p>
<p>Some smaller banks waive fees as a sign-on incentive.</p>
<p>But even the aloof Citibank is drawn into the fray when it comes to luring customers with an array of freebies.</p>
<p>&quot;Citibank is forced into it,&quot; said Peregrine Securities analyst Jason Tuan. &quot;That shows the extent of the competition.&quot;</p>
<p>Faced with sluggish loan business, banks are eager to expand into new services, he said, adding that resolve to stay in the game is more important than deep pockets or high technology.</p>
<p>&quot;Almost everyone wants a piece of the pie, but few can do it,&quot; Tuan said.</p>
<p>Taishin International Bank -- a distant fourth in the credit card race with 190,000 in circulation after ChinaTrust, Citibank and Standard Chartered's 210,000 -- regards itself as a David determined to take on the Goliaths.</p>
<p>Taishin card manager Daniel Tsai takes pride in &quot;innovative product design&quot; -- cards loaded with bells and whistles.</p>
<p>Taishin launched its cards in 1993 with free term life insurance to cardholders and was first to allow cash advances.</p>
<p>A &quot;Rose Card&quot; catering to a growing sector of financially independent women showcases Taishin's marketing flair.</p>
<p>&quot;Our lady customers love it,&quot; Tsai said.</p>
<p>Half of Taishin's cards are held by women, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are a leader in serving to mass customers,&quot; Tsai said. &quot;We have many imitators.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
