<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115612" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Finnish markka sees scant interest in Asian trade.</title>
<headline>Finnish markka sees scant interest in Asian trade.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Finnish markka was on softer ground against the mark but saw scant interest during Asian trade on Monday after Finland's move to join the European exchange rate mechanism (ERM) at the weekend.</p>
<p>Forex dealers in Singapore said the markka had stayed between 3.0020 and 3.0070 per mark most of the morning, after closing at 2.9860 in Europe on Friday.</p>
<p>The European Union (EU)'s monetary committee brought the markka into the ERM currency grid at a central rate of 3.04 to the German mark on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is talk about interest to buy below 2.9800/9900 but the Far East doesn't actually know what to do with it,&quot; said a European bank dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody's just waiting for Europe to come in and see what the corporates are going to do because this cross is very customer-driven.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the markka showed potential to weaken to around 3.0400/3.0600 against the mark, after reaching a low of 3.0050 in the morning.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of flows on the Finnish markka, we're pretty weak in that area,&quot; said another European bank dealer.</p>
<p>But he said the Italian lira could see more interest on expectations that Finland's entry into the ERM at the weekend could increase the pressure on Italy to follow suit.</p>
<p>The Italian lira, Swedish crown, sterling and Greek drachma are the only four EU currencies still remaining outside the ERM.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65-8703080)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
