<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115760" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: UPM down three pct after Finland-ERM link.</title>
<headline>UPM down three pct after Finland-ERM link.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finland's biggest forestry UPM-Kymmene Oy fell sharply in cautious Monday morning trade as some investors saw the markka's weekend link to the ERM hitting Finnish forest industry's competitiveness, brokers said.</p>
<p>In its first trade, the stock fell 3.00 markka or 3.2 percent to 91.50 but with only 2,000 shares traded.  </p>
<p>Bids for the stock were slightly higher and it later traded at 93.00, off 1.50 markka or 1.59 percent but volumes were almost piecemeal and the market hesitant.</p>
<p>At 1100/0800 GMT, the forest industry sub-index was down 1.6 percent, off its earlier lows, as Enso also edged back from early weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;Many players had decided to sell forestries if Finland joins the ERM and Sweden stays out,&quot; one broker said; but added that weakness was likely to be a temporary knee-jerk reaction with bargain-hunters set to sniff out opportunities.</p>
<p>Metsa-Serla B share traded at 28.00 markka, down 0.60 markka or more than two percent, and Enso R share was at 34.30 markka, down 0.80 markka or just over two percent, also in thin trade.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom +35 89 6805 0247</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
