<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115729" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German call money starts steady at 3.00/3.05 pct.</title>
<headline>German call money starts steady at 3.00/3.05 pct.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>German call money rates began the week on a steady note trading at 3.00/3.05 percent on Monday, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading is very, very quiet as rates are still mostly unchanged,&quot; said a Frankfurt dealer.</p>
<p>On Monday the bulk of overnight funds traded between 3.00/3.05 percent, virtually unchanged from Friday's level, dealers said. Looking ahead traders did not expect rates to move sharply higher or lower any time soon as the Bundesbank is likely to keep liquidity conditions mostly unchanged this week, preventing any swings of rates.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the Bundesbank will more or less replace the repo pact that is expiring this week ensuring that liquidity conditions remain more or less balanced this week,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>A repo pact for 67.5 billion marks expires on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said banks' holdings at the central bank were not excessive but sufficient to prevent rates from drifting off into either direction in the next sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Reserve holdings are adequate and will not move the market into one or the other direction and they should climb during the week,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Banks held 38.2 billion marks at the Bundesbank on Friday with average monthly holdings registering at 37.8 billion marks on Sunday.</p>
<p>Lombard borrowing totalled 100 million marks on Friday.</p>
<p>The daily Frankfurt Interbank Offered Rate was set at 3.05383 percent on Monday compared with 3.05242 a day earlier.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
