<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115790" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - October 14.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of stories reported in the Irish press on Monday.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- The Irish Republican Army was warned by Loyalist guerrillas to to expect a violent backlash if it carries out a further bomb attack anywhere.</p>
<p>- Irish police are investigating an outbreak of so-called mad cow disease amid deep suspicions that it may have been deliberately introduced.  </p>
<p>- The European Commission this week unveils tough new economic rules for countries joining the so-called &quot;Euro'. The long-awaited rules will also outline a code to govern relations between countries inside the new money area from January 1, 1999, and those like the UK which intend continuing outside the Euro-zone.</p>
<p>- Bula Resources on Sunday played down a UK newspaper report that it would be raising some 70 million Irish pounds to fund development of its Salymskoye oilfield in Western Siberia, following encouraging flow tests from its first development well there.  </p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- A message from Ulster Volunteer Force guerrilla group calling for stringent security measures against the IRA in the Republic of Ireland is due to be delivered to the Irish government today.</p>
<p>- Charlie McCreevy, spokesman on finance for the main opposition party, Fianna Fail, on Sunday accused the Department of Finance of publishing &quot;untrue and misleading&quot; information on payments to former Irish government ministers.  </p>
<p>- Bertie Ahern, leader of the main opposition party, Fianna Fail, has outlined a four-point plan to break the current impasse in the peace process. He suggested a &quot;stairway of consensus&quot; so all sides in the Northern conflict could &quot;climb to a level of agreement&quot; where everyone's traditions would be protected.</p>
<p>- The planned leasing of part of the Electricity Supply Board's generating station at Moneypoint, on the Shannon estuary, to a consortium of U.S. banks would not involve the sale of any assets, a spokesman for the company has said.</p>
<p>- The success of the Dublin's International Financial Services Centre has been underscored by a report that assets in Dublin funds have soared by 65 percent over the past year. They now total $33.1 billion.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 660 3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
