<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115791" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Air France, Continental in alliance talks - paper.</title>
<headline>Air France, Continental in alliance talks - paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>French state-owned airline Air France and Continental Airlines are in advanced stages of discussions towards signing an alliance deal, the Les Echos financial newspaper said on Monday.</p>
<p>It quoted Continental chairman Gordon Bethune as telling U.S. specialised publication Aviation Daily that the talks were in their final stages but that no deal had been signed yet.  </p>
<p>Les Echos said that Air France declined comment on the talks.</p>
<p>The paper said industry sources indicated that the French airline was talking to more than one airline about alliances, trying to find a good geographical spread to counter other airline alliances.</p>
<p>Les Echos said Air France talked to both Continental and USAir in the past few months.</p>
<p>Air France and Continental signed a commercial accord back in 1993 but it has never been implemented due to changes in top management at both companies.</p>
<p>The paper added that the U.S. aviation authorities were squaring up for another power struggle with France over &quot;open skies&quot; and were preparing to refuse their authorisation of Air France's winter timetable and would also use any alliance deal as a lever to push the French to further open up the domestic market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
