<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115818" id="root" date="1996-10-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ government takes flexible stance on coalition.</title>
<headline>NZ government takes flexible stance on coalition.</headline>
<byline>Mark Trevelyan</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand's caretaker government reassured investors on Monday after an inconclusive general election and signalled it would be flexible in coalition talks with populist Maori leader Winston Peters.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Bill Birch said a widening of the central bank's target range for inflation may well be on the agenda for coalition talks, which could drag on for weeks or months.</p>
<p>He said the conservative National Party government, in power since 1990, wanted to maintain the &quot;broad mix&quot; of policies which have produced the strongest economic growth in a generation.</p>
<p>&quot;That's not to say there would not be some tweaking of those policies. We've never claimed that they're perfect, and indeed during the campaign we argued ourselves that they needed to be built on as we look ahead,&quot; Birch said in an interview to Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>National and its allies won 53 seats, while the Labour Party and left-wing Alliance gained 50. Peters' New Zealand First Party was left holding the balance of power with 17.</p>
<p>Peters has refused to say if he will embrace National or Labour, which campaigned on promises to share the fruits of economic recovery with more funding for health and education.</p>
<p>While Peters avoided the media, his deputy Tau Henare retracted a pre-election comment that he personally could not work with National unless it dumped Prime Minister Jim Bolger, Birch and Health Minister Jenny Shipley.</p>
<p>Henare said the remark had been a &quot;bungle&quot; and he would be ruled by the decision of the party deputies, but added he would find it &quot;very, very, very difficult&quot; to work with National's leaders.</p>
<p>Financial markets took the uncertainty in their stride, with the New Zealand dollar, shares and bonds all firming. Traders said there was relief at the poor showing of the Alliance, which favours higher tariffs and a big increase in taxes and spending.</p>
<p>National's Bolger and Labour leader Helen Clark have both said they aim to stitch together a coalition, and Peters said on Sunday he expected a &quot;bidding war&quot; over policy.</p>
<p>Peters favours limiting foreign stakes in &quot;strategic&quot; New Zealand assets to 25 percent and wants to reverse the recent NZ$2 billion (US$1.4 billion) sale of state-owned Forestry Corporation, something neither National nor Labour could accept.</p>
<p>But markets drew some encouragement from his election-night comments on the need to maintain stability, run budget surpluses and repay foreign debt.</p>
<p>New Zealand First and Labour both favour a widening of the central bank's zero to two percent inflation target, although their prescriptions differ.</p>
<p>Birch's comments were the first sign the government may at least discuss changes to the mandate of the Reserve Bank, which has narrowly failed to keep inflation in the target band this year but still commands huge respect in financial markets.</p>
<p>Asked about the possibility of prolonged political stalemate, Birch said: &quot;I can understand the market's apprehension about that, but I think the election result indicated strong support for the direction in which the economy is going.&quot;</p>
<p>($1 = NZ$1.43)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
