<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="115912" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FOCUS - API data shows heat stocks tighter than ever.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - API data shows heat stocks tighter than ever.</headline>
<byline>Oliver Ludwig</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The American Petroleum Institute's (API) weekly inventory report Tuesday evening showed heating oil stocks in the Northeast are growing tighter even as the winter approaches, traders said.</p>
<p>The API said total distillate stocks rose by a below-expectation 673,000 barrels to 114.3 million, but more significantly said stocks fell in the Northeast, the biggest heating oil market in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Look for some support for heating oil. Stocks are still low,&quot; said Steve Platt, analyst with Dean Witter in Chicago.  </p>
<p>Platt and others said the report, which also showed drops in gasoline and crude stocks, and a sharp drop in refinery utilization rates, was bullish but not terribly so.</p>
<p>Heating oil led the after-hour gains on ACCESS, with the November heat contract rising nearly 0.50 cent to about 73.55 cents a gallon. That trimmed about half its losses from Tuesday's NYMEX session, which was marked by profit taking.</p>
<p>The API data showed heating oil stocks on the East Coast of 24.3 million barrels or 43 percent below year-ago levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports are showing up in the numbers,&quot; one trader said, noting a million barrel build would have tempered bullishness.  </p>
<p>Failure to build distillate stocks, let alone maintain them, put a 2.2 percent drop in refinery utilization rates into even sharper focus, traders said. The drop, beyond most expectations, brought runs to 92.7 percent of capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;It's evidence of turnarounds,&quot; said Gerald Samuels, a trader and managing director of ARB Oil, noting some refiners may have also voluntarily scaled back gasoline production last week due to poor refinery profit margins recently.</p>
<p>Gasoline inventories meanwhile fell by 509,000 barrels to 195.8 million barrels amid low imports and what appeared to be somewhat disappointing demand, traders and analysts said.  </p>
<p>But stocks of reformulated gasoline rose on the East Coast by 1.9 million barrels to 18.1 million, which helped keep the November unleaded contract's gains on ACCESS to 67.25 cents a gallon, about 0.25 cent over the day-session close.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a 417,000 barrel drop in crude that brought inventories to 301.9 million was seen as neutral and fueled, as predicted, by relatively light imports of about 7.2 million barrels per day (bpd), or about 600,000 bpd below last week.</p>
<p>November crude prices on ACCESS were up about six cents to $25.48 a barrel.</p>
<p>-- Oliver Ludwig, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
