<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116298" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: RALLYING - MCRAE ESCAPES DELUGE, STRENGTHENS LEAD.</title>
<headline>RALLYING - MCRAE ESCAPES DELUGE, STRENGTHENS LEAD.</headline>
<dateline>LA ROSA, Italy 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colin McRae escaped a cloudburst in the San Remo Rally on Tuesday and his good fortune boosted his victory chances.</p>
<p>The former world champion shot through the ninth stage near Volterra in central Italy in light rain before the deluge left his rivals ploughing through flooded roads.</p>
<p>Spain's Carlos Sainz, who finished the second day in second place, 32 seconds behind McRae, said: &quot;Five minutes before we started the stage we could not even see.</p>
<p>&quot;It was incredible -- like a lake,&quot; the Ford Escort driver added.</p>
<p>McRae momentarily lost control of his Subaru on the day's last stage. &quot;I'm disappointed that I spun on the last one. Now it depends how the Ford goes on tarmac.  We'll be OK if it's dry, but if it's wet there's no margin for error,&quot; McRae said.</p>
<p>McRae's team mate Piero Liatti of Italy shadowed Sainz in third place with Sweden's Kenneth Eriksson fourth in another Subaru.</p>
<p>Frenchman Didier Auriol dropped out of contention because his Mitsubishi was stuck in two-wheel drive for most of the day.</p>
<p>Drivers face another 130 km of flat out driving on asphalt on Wednesday before the rally ends in San Remo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LA ROSA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
