<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116368" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: ZIMBABWE'S MUGABE DEFENDS MALAYSIA POWER DEAL.</title>
<headline>ZIMBABWE'S MUGABE DEFENDS MALAYSIA POWER DEAL.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe has defended a widely-criticised privatisation deal with Malaysia, saying he wanted players other than Europeans to invest in his country's economy.</p>
<p>Mugabe said critics of the deal -- under which Malaysian power producer YTL Corp Bhd would invest Z$6 billion (U.S.$570 million) in the privatisation of Hwange Thermal Power Station -- were losers who wanted to buy the station themselves and were opposed to Malaysia's entry into the country's economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The criticism has been made by those who wanted Hwange and didn't get it and you are not going to be answering each and every question (when) you know what you are doing,&quot; he told the Financial Times of London in an interview, a transcript of which was made available to Reuters.</p>
<p>The Malaysian deal has drawn widespread criticism from black empowerment groups, economic analysts and the former board of the state-owned Zimbabwe Electricity Supply Authority (ZESA) as well as some Western countries who have queried the manner in which it was handled.</p>
<p>Mugabe sacked the entire 10-member ZESA board last month for opposing the deal and pressing the government to rescind the letter of intent it signed with the Malaysian company under which YTL would control 51 percent of the equity in a joint venture company to be established for the Hwange project.</p>
<p>The sacked board, which was chaired by Harare mayor Solomon Tawengwa, said the agreement was contrary to the country's programme to economically empower the majority blacks and was also a departure from the government's tender system.</p>
<p>Before the signing of the letter of intent, ZESA had already invited bids and six foreign companies had been shortlisted, top of them a British firm, while YTL was at the bottom of the list.</p>
<p>Mugabe told the Financial Times that if anyone was eager to set up another thermal power plant in the southern African country, they were free to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;But in some cases we will just take an official position obviously and say it's a parastatal property belonging to the state, say we prefer the Japanese to go partners with us and no-one should cry foul,&quot; he said, adding: &quot;Why should they, because that is the preference we have.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The area of operation where this privatisation is going to occur is a very narrow one, most of the country having been privatised in the past, and so no one should ever think that the remaining area should go West, should go to America or to Europe alone, we would want to bring in other contenders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the Hwange shares that would be sold to YTL could be used to set up a national investment fund the government was planning to advance its black economic empowerment programme.</p>
<p>-- Harare newsroom, +2634 731-757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
