<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116331" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NHL-RANGERS BEAT FLAMES, OILERS, BRUINS WIN.</title>
<headline>NHL-RANGERS BEAT FLAMES, OILERS, BRUINS WIN.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mark Messier, Wayne Gretzky and rookie Daniel Goneau all scored third-period goals to lift the New York Rangers to their first victory of the season, a 5-4 defeat of the Calgary Flames Monday.</p>
<p>The Rangers took their first lead just 22 seconds into the third period. Messier took a pass from Brian Leetch just behind centre ice and skated down the right side before blasting the puck under Trevor Kidd's left arm for his first goal of the season, giving New York a 3-2 lead.</p>
<p>After Calgary's Dave Gagner tied the score 72 seconds later, the Rangers regained the lead with just over nine minutes left when Wayne Gretzky took a pass from Bruce Driver and tipped the puck into an open net for his second goal.</p>
<p>&quot;Teams respect us and fear us, but they dislike us and want to beat us,&quot; said Gretzky. &quot;We can't look at it like we have turned anything around.&quot;</p>
<p>Mike Richter made 23 saves for the Rangers, who are 1-3-2.</p>
<p>In Phoenix, Jason Arnott had two goals and two assists and Dean McAmmond added two goals and one assist, leading the Edmonton Oilers to a 6-3 victory over the Coyotes and spoiling Jeremy Roenick's Phoenix debut.</p>
<p>Arnott's first goal of the game with eight minutes left in the second period snapped a 2-2 tie and gave Edmonton the lead for good.</p>
<p>Roenick made his Coyotes' debut just hours after ending his holdout and agreeing to a mulit-year contract.</p>
<p>In Vancouver, Rick Tocchet's goal with 15 seconds left in overtime lifted the Boston Bruins to a 5-4 victory over the Vancouver Canucks for their second straight win on a four-game road trip.</p>
<p>With time running out, Adam Oates won a draw in the right circle and chipped a pass to Tocchet high in the slot. Tocchet snapped the puck past an unscreened Kirk McLean for his third goal.</p>
<p>&quot;Oates was winning draws all night. With only 18 seconds left, you're not going to get much except a shot at the net,&quot; said Tocchet. &quot;He is really good on the draw.&quot;</p>
<p>Steve Heinze added a pair of goals and Jeff Odgers scored in his third straight game for Boston, which picked up the win despite being outshot, 43-19.</p>
<p>Bruins goalie Bill Ranford made 39 saves.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
