<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116358" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA PLANS RESCUE BID FOR BANKRUPT COUNCILS.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA PLANS RESCUE BID FOR BANKRUPT COUNCILS.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African government has implemented a package to rescue town councils pushed into the red by costs of the transition to democracy and politically motivated boycotts dating from the apartheid years.</p>
<p>Provincial Affairs Minister Mohammed Valli Moosa told parliament that councils were owed a total of 5.6 billion rand ($1.23 billion) in service charges at the end of June.</p>
<p>He said Gauteng, which includes the industrial region around Johannesburg, was worst off with bad debts of 2.9 billion rand, followed by KwaZulu-Natal with 826 million rand outstanding.</p>
<p>The department said in a report to parliament's provincial affairs committee that Eskom, the state-owned power utility, was owed 938 million rand.</p>
<p>&quot;Effectively, local authorities are starting to use Eskom as an overdraft facility,&quot; the department said, adding that 48 of the country's 800 municipalities did not have cash reserves to pay their electricity bills.</p>
<p>&quot;Some 95 local authorities were identified with insufficient cash to cover one month's manpower bill,&quot; the department said.</p>
<p>The report said some councils were structurally able to bill fewer than 75 percent of their clients, adding: &quot;Only 69 percent of all accounts rendered are paid on a regular basis.&quot;</p>
<p>The backlog arises partly out of an apartheid-era rent and service charge boycott endorsed by the African national Congress as a weapon against white rule.</p>
<p>After several years of not paying, clients are resisting efforts by the ANC, now in power for over two and half years, to re-establish a culture of payment.</p>
<p>Even some elected ANC councillors and one deputy minister are behind in their service payments to local authorities.</p>
<p>The department's report stressed the need for councillors to help establish payment discipline in their areas.</p>
<p>&quot;Major progress has been made in the transition to local democracy,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;There have, however, been significant costs associated with the transition and many local authorities have inherited new areas which were in a state of virtual financial collapse.&quot;</p>
<p>The department said &quot;Project Liquidity&quot; was instituted to assess the scale of the problem and to set up mechanisms to help councils unable to pay their debts.</p>
<p>Officials were unable to give any immediate estimate of the cost of the project and the scheme to keep ailing municipalities afloat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
