<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116388" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: GOVERNMENTS TO BACK NORWEGIAN GAS SALES TO POLAND.</title>
<headline>GOVERNMENTS TO BACK NORWEGIAN GAS SALES TO POLAND.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Warsaw and Oslo governments want companies to clinch contracts for long-term supplies of Norwegian gas to Poland, partly to ensure it has varied sources apart from Russia, their foreign ministers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are interested in supplies of Norwegian natural gas and in long-term cooperation. The decisions rest with companies, but they have our encouragement,&quot; Polish minister Dariusz Rosati said after talks with Norway's Bjoern Tore Godal.</p>
<p>Last month Poland clinched a long-awaited 25-year agreement with Russia's giant state-owned gas supplier Gazprom for the supply of 250 billion cubic metres of natural gas.</p>
<p>&quot;Although Poland has signed an agreement on gas from Russia it was never our intention that this should cover 100 percent of demand for natural gas,&quot; Rosati told reporters, saying it was strategically important to have several sources.</p>
<p>Godal said they had not discussed details of any future gas deals, which would be worked out, on the basis of commercial considerations, by Norway's gas negotiating committee grouping major energy companies including state-owned Statoil.</p>
<p>&quot;We do support politically the diversification of the energy markets in Europe and see the value of a diverse situation not only in Poland, but in other countries of Central and Eastern Europe,&quot; Godal added.</p>
<p>&quot;But we do not direct contents of negotiations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether Norway was disappointed over the Russian deal Godal said Oslo backed whatever Poland felt was in its interests.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that we have an increase of European gas markets will be to the benefit of both Norway and Russia,&quot; said Godal, who was accompanying Norway's King Harald on a three-day state visit to Poland, Norway's largest trade partner in the region.</p>
<p>The Russian gas imports, through a pipeline from the Yamal Siberian peninsula, should cover between 30 and 40 percent of Poland's needs in the 1997 to 2010 period, estimated at 22 to 27 billion cubic metres per year.</p>
<p>Norway's ship-borne gas exports to Poland are small although it is a major source of Poland's oil and related products.</p>
<p>These make up 63 percent of Poland's imports from the country and ensure the balance of their trade, which totalled $536 million in 1995, consistently favours Oslo which showed a $244 million surplus last year.</p>
<p>Among other issues, Rosati asked Godal to promote Norwegian investment in Poland's shipyards and support a increasing Poland's investment rating to encourage Norwegian banks extending credits for investment and trade.</p>
<p>Norway agreed that Poland could devote three million Norwegian crowns of its debt to Norway for its Ekofund which promotes ecological investments and Rosati said the sum, though a small part of the debt, might be increased in future. -- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
