<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116440" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N Sea offshore loading crudes rise with freight.</title>
<headline>N Sea offshore loading crudes rise with freight.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crudes which load offshore jumped in value on Tuesday as freight rates soared during the day, traders said.</p>
<p>Statfjord, valued in the low dated Brent +40 cents early in the day, traded later at dated +51 cents and some thought a cargo moved as high as dated Brent +60 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;World scale has gone mad. You can't get ships. World scale for the October 23-28 time range shot up over lunch today. A cargo fixed on Monday at 115 would cost you 135 today,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>November IPE Brent dipped 22 cents by 1738 GMT to $24.64.  </p>
<p>Offshore loading crudes Statfjord, Draugen and Gullfaks have freight rates for set destinations set at the beginning of the year and thus do not fluctuate with movements on worldscale.</p>
<p>The November Brent crude oil loading programme was expected to be released overnight.</p>
<p>Other physical North Sea deals included two October Brent cargoes - at November -8 and -5 cents, a Nov 9-11 Troll at dated +60 cents, November 6-10 Draugen at dated +50 cents and a Urals at dated -55 cents cif NWE (Nov 1-5 delivery).</p>
<p>Talk of an October 31-02 Forties at dated Brent +48 cents could not be confirmed, but was thought around market level.  </p>
<p>The ULCC fixed to load some five Brent cargoes around October 25 for the U.S. Gulf took all the remaining October barrels out of the market, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has tightened things up but whether the dated Brent value will rise above the current level (Nov -5 cents) I don't know. It doesn't feel like it will fall,&quot; one producer said.</p>
<p>Urals supply/demand in the north and the Mediterranean was balanced, traders said.</p>
<p>In the North delays of 1-2 days continued but buying was subdued and assessed around dated Brent -52/55 cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
