<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116486" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME copper fails to sustain upward move.</title>
<headline>LME copper fails to sustain upward move.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>LME copper ended Tuesday with muted gains after strength to attack overhead barriers evaporated.</p>
<p>As prices approached the key $1,970 per tonne level on the first afternoon ring, selling came in, stalling the advance at $1,968, as profit-taking and producer selling overwhelmed buyers, dealers said.</p>
<p>It was disappointing that the market could not even stay above the $1,950 level, ending only $11 higher at $1,945, they added.</p>
<p>The market has been wary of the recent LME stocks falls, including Tuesday's 10,950-tonne decline, since many believe tonnage is not destined for end users. Many say it is ending up in bonded Chinese warehouses, where is liable to be re-expored.</p>
<p>&quot;Switching stock from one hand to another by sleight of hand, however, deftly done, unfortunately does not make it disappear,&quot; said Nick Moore of Flemings Global Mining Group.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to counsel a risk averse stance towards copper, preferring exposure to aluminium, nickel and zinc,&quot; he added in a commentary.</p>
<p>Aluminium broke through several layers of resistance as influential short-covering hit the market, but eased off its afternoon high of $1,363.</p>
<p>Last business on the kerb was at $1,356, a healthy $30 gain from Monday.</p>
<p>But some technical analysts have been cautious, saying a bounce was expected after the market dived into oversold territory when touching $1,305 recently, adding that charts look vulnerable to a solid test of the $1,300 level in the near future.</p>
<p>Lead recovered from its slide to seven-month lows of $735 on Monday, ending the kerb at $750, up $12. Resistance is pegged at $760/1.</p>
<p>Tin also finished the day stronger at $6,000, up from $5,975 on Monday, but off its high of $6,015.</p>
<p>Nickel ended unchanged at $7,120 after exploring within a range of $7,155 to $7,100.</p>
<p>Zinc gained $7 to $1,022, just on the cusp of resistance.</p>
<p>Alloy closed $30 higher after Monday's $1,200.</p>
<p>--Eric Onstad, London Newsroom +542 8065</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
