<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116550" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire polls to cost $253 million, seeks 60 percent.</title>
<headline>Zaire polls to cost $253 million, seeks 60 percent.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's National Electoral Commission has estimated the budget for the country's long-awaited elections at $253 million, parliamentary sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>About 60 percent of the budget, presented to parliament for approval, is expected to be financed by foreign donors, with the government making up the remainder.</p>
<p>Zaire has been in talks with U.N. agencies for assistance with presidential and parliamentary elections due by next May, the country's first multi-party polls for more than 30 years.</p>
<p>Although approval of the budget would be a symbolic step forward in Zaire's transition to democracy now more than five years behind, the holding of elections is by no means certain.</p>
<p>Strongman President Mobutu Sese Seko, who has ruled Zaire since seizing power in 1965, is convalescing in Europe after surgery in August.</p>
<p>He says he will seek re-election and it is a foregone conclusion in Zaire that elections cannot be held behind his back. It is not clear when he will be back on his feet.</p>
<p>Parliament, which adopted a new federalist constitution this month further complicating election logistics in the vast country, has yet to enact an elctoral law.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still waiting for the electoral law, and the president who is convalescing from surgery in Switzerland, should assure people,&quot; said a diplomat in the capital.</p>
<p>Many Zaireans doubt elections can be held while violence spirals uncontrollably in eastern regions suffering from a spillover of bloodshed in neighbouring Rwanda and Burundi.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
