<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116576" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa releases conservative welfare blueprint.</title>
<headline>S.Africa releases conservative welfare blueprint.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa on Tuesday published a welfare policy blueprint designed to balance the racially skewed apartheid-era benefit spread without significantly increasing the welfare budget.</p>
<p>The 140-page policy white paper confirms the state's role as a provider of last resort for the destitute, but dashes any notion of a European-style welfare safety net.</p>
<p>There will be no change for the 2.8 million people who depend on subsistance-level grants of various kinds, but the government plans to reduce its contribution to institutional care focussed mainly on whites.</p>
<p>The document sketches the inequalities inherited in 1994 from apartheid, which offered social security almost exclusively to whites, coloureds and Asians.</p>
<p>More than half the country's children live in poverty while 10 percent of the population earns more than half the national income. Almost eight million of the estimated 41 million population live in households dependent on a grant.</p>
<p>&quot;The policies of the past have resulted in social disintegration...social welfare services could contribute significantly to enhancing social integration,&quot; the white paper says.</p>
<p>University of Stellenbosch economist Servaas van den Berg, a Welfare Ministry consultant, told Reuters the proposals could add about one billion rand ($220 million) to the current 13.9 billion rand welfare budget over the next five years.</p>
<p>He said the policy paper proposed changes mainly in welfare services, which absorbed only eight percent of the welfare budget, and proposed no change to the child, family and pension benefit systems, which absorb 88 percent of the budget.</p>
<p>&quot;The model envisaged for social welfare services is not a cost-intensive one. It's saying deploy, it's saying reach into the rural areas, but close down institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;One is talking about less than a doubling of the welfare services portion, which means adding up to eight percent to the present costs over five years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see welfare's overall bite of the national budget increasing significantly. We could even see a marginal decline in the 8.7 percent share of the total.&quot;</p>
<p>Van den Berg said South Africa would have to look again at creating a social security system in the long term, but that it was too soon for a major shake-up of the infrastructure inherited from the previous white government.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going through a period where we have already had too much institutional change and we can't manage all of it so I would say that where a system works reasonably well we should just look at those that aren't working and change those.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a system in place that reaches most of the people it should reach - about 80 percent. When you've got a system that works reasonably well, one should not try to change that.&quot;</p>
<p>$=4.54 rand</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
