<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116513" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE Dec Brent expected to follow Nov's path higher.</title>
<headline>IPE Dec Brent expected to follow Nov's path higher.</headline>
<byline>John Hanley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE December Brent crude futures are expected to follow in the footsteps of the November contract to post-Gulf War highs once it becomes the spot contract after Wednesday.</p>
<p>November Brent on Tuesday rose to a nearly six-year high for the spot contract at $25.06 a barrel, and with the December contract about 50 cents cheaper it has room to capitalize on the unrest in Iraq as the focus turns to the winter weather, traders said.</p>
<p>But sustained gains above $25 may have to be fueled by unexpectedly cold weather heading into November, they warned.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market has just got a mind of its own and wants to go higher,&quot; said David Oxley, an oil broker at Credit Lyonnais Rouse. &quot;We're breaking into new territory and you can't fight it.&quot;</p>
<p>Brent has grabbed the baton from gas oil and New York crude futures, with the WTI/Brent spread for the November contracts nearly cut in half the last three weeks, traders noted.</p>
<p>&quot;The supply concerns are more on the crude than the products at this time,&quot; said Charles Gray, energy analyst at Prudential Bache Futures. &quot;I think you have to say the uptrend is still intact on the spot continuation chart.&quot;</p>
<p>Last month the Oct contract expired at $24.12 and the next session the spot Nov contract started trading at $22.52. Nov closed that gap during a rally that has continued to this day.</p>
<p>An uptrend off that low from mid-September crosses today just below $24 on the spot continuation chart, Gray said.</p>
<p>Weather forecasts for Europe may prove in great demand over the next few weeks but traders said supplies were still tight enough to push up gas oil prices, which would help Brent.</p>
<p>A German heating oil supplier said last week that private household stocks of heating fuel in Germany stood at 65 percent of capacity at the end of September, compared to an historical average of 71 percent.</p>
<p>Total middle distillate stocks in Europe, according to Euroilstock, were 283.35 million at the end of September, down from 316.82 million a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;From a fundamental picture I think it's going to be weather dominated now and if we get cold snaps it will just add fuel to the fire,&quot; Oxley said.</p>
<p>&quot;We still have end-user demand out there...I think it has to be demand-led and once cold hits in and the consumer starts requiring and demand gas oil we could get the next big spike,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the loss of Iraqi crude many counted on this quarter has been punctuated by renewed unrest in Iraq this week.</p>
<p>Pro-Baghdad Iraqi Kurdish militiamen launched a counter-attack on Tuesday to retake a key town from a rival guerrilla group pushing through northern Iraq.</p>
<p>This comes on top of news on Monday that the United Nations Security Council Sanctions Committee on Iraq was told that implemenation of the oil-for-food plan continued to be delayed due to security concerns in the northern Kurdish regions.</p>
<p>The plan to allow Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months was shelved on September 1 when U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali delayed deployment of U.N. staff meant to monitor the sales.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
