<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116651" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania to continue Ukraine iron ore project.</title>
<headline>Romania to continue Ukraine iron ore project.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's parliament has approved a government plan to complete construction of a $867 million iron ore processing plant in Ukraine, which will supply Romania with 31 million tonnes of ore over the next decade.</p>
<p>A parliament statement said the bill had passed through the lower chamber with a majority of votes.</p>
<p>Under an agreement signed in Kiev two years ago, the Romanian side is expected to complete the Krivy Rih plant, 240 km south of Kiev, by the end of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, Romania has carried out 81 percent of its share of construction at the Krivy Rih plant,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>It added that Bucharest had to invest a further 181 million &quot;transferable roubles&quot; -- a now-defunct currency for settling trade deals between countries of the former communist bloc.</p>
<p>When operational, the plant, where work started in 1986 following an accord between Romania and the former Soviet Union, is to produce iron ore pellets with iron content of 63 percent, an industry ministry source said.</p>
<p>The remaining 37 percent would consist of materials used in metallurgical technologies, the source said.</p>
<p>Ukraine would supply Romania with 31 million tonnes of iron ore pellets at a rate of some three million tonnes per year over the next decade.</p>
<p>The main recipient of the Krivy Rih plant's output will be the giant steel plant at Galati, on the River Danube and near Romania's border with Ukraine. -- Adrian Dascalu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22470">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
