<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116761" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria unemployment edges up to 10.5 pct in Sept.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria unemployment edges up to 10.5 pct in Sept.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of people unemployed in Bulgaria rose to 401,634 or 10.5 percent of the workforce, in September from 396,155 the month before, the National Labour Exchange (NLE) said.  </p>
<p> BULGARIAN UNEMPLOYMENT    SEPT	 AUG	 SEPT'95</p>
<p> monthly total		401,635    396,155    400,688</p>
<p> pct of workforce	    10.5	 10.4	 10.5</p>
<p>&quot;The rise was mainly due to the inflow of people from non-industrial sectors to the labour market as some 2,800 teachers lost their jobs in September,&quot; Milcho Dimitrov, deputy social care minister and NLE chairman, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Dimitrov said closures of state firms slated for liquidation by the government did not have a considerable impact on unemployment last month due to the slow pace of liquidation.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the closures are expected to boost unemployment in October by 5,000 to 8,000 people following government pledges to international lenders to speed up liquidation of debt-ridden firms,&quot; Dimitrov said.</p>
<p>Last month the International Monetary Fund again postponed a second $115 million tranche of funding to Bulgaria until the Socialist cabinet completes closures of 64 state loss-makers under a funding agreement sealed in July. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
