<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="116996" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: LSI Logic Corp sees Asian revenue jumping.</title>
<headline>LSI Logic Corp sees Asian revenue jumping.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S.-based semiconductor firm LSI Logic Corp said on Tuesday Asian revenue would rise to about 35 percent of its worldwide total by 2000, prompting it to open a regional headquarters in Singapore.</p>
<p>LSI, a pioneer in developing custom-made high-performance semiconductors that serve as the electronic brain of products like video games, now gets 25 percent of its total revenue from Asia.</p>
<p>Total global revenues of LSI in calendar 1995 reached US$1.27 billion. Net earnings last year reached $238 million.</p>
<p>&quot;By the year 2000, we expect revenues in Asia to contribute probably 35 percent (of the world total),&quot; W. Richard Marz, LSI executive vice-president of geographic markets, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;As our total corporate revenue would transcend $3 billion, then Asia would be $1 billion. It's simple math,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Marz said the estimate of potential earnings the company may reap from Asia may be on the low side.</p>
<p>&quot;As we develop a presence here, we may find that those numbers may be conservative. We're just understanding the market opportunities here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Along with establishing its regional headquarters in Singapore, LSI would put up a design centre here focusing on sales, marketing and engineering of its products, a company statement said.</p>
<p>LSI already has offices in Japan, South Korea, Taiwan and Hong Kong. Company officials said the Singapore office would also support expansion of the company in the rest of Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;With such tremendous growth in consumer products, especially in Asia, it makes strong business sense to widen our scope and tap into market opportunities in China, India and Singapore,&quot; said Norman Chanoski, a senior vice-president and general manager for Pan-Asian operations.</p>
<p>&quot;There (are) tremendous growth opportunities in China and India particularly as these economies prosper and consumer products proliferate,&quot; said Dipak Raval, director of business development for Pan-Asia operations. He will head the Singapore regional office.</p>
<p>Marz said the company expected revenues in 1996 would probably take a beating because of a slump in the electronics industry.</p>
<p>&quot;This year, the semiconductor industry itself is relatively flat (compared) to 1995 revenues,&quot; he said, adding that the industry should recover easily and &quot;start its progression back to a more historic growth of between 15-20 percent&quot; a year.</p>
<p>The company recently launched a one-chip decoder designed specifically for digital video disc players. The chip integrates nine separate chips on a single silicon chip.</p>
<p>LSI's business focus is shifting from its traditional reliance on computers, which accounted for 70 percent of sales in 1990, to consumer products.</p>
<p>By 2000, consumer products like satellite television set-top boxes, digital video cameras and video games would account for 35 percent of total global sales, the company said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
