<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117075" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Court puts key parts of FCC phone rules on hold.</title>
<headline>Court puts key parts of FCC phone rules on hold.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. court on Tuesday put on hold key provisions of a landmark federal rule designed to break open the nation's local phone monopolies to competition while it considers a court challenge to the measure.</p>
<p>Attorneys and analysts said the action by the appeals court here could delay the introduction of widespread competition in the $100 billion local phone market now controlled by the regional Baby Bell phone companies.</p>
<p>It also represented a major setback to the Federal Communications Commission and long-distance companies such as AT&amp;T Corp. and others wanting to break into the local phone business.</p>
<p>FCC Chairman Reed Hundt said it &quot;throws a monkey wrench into the carefully designed congressional machinery for introducing competition&quot; into the local market.</p>
<p>His agency will ask the U.S. Supreme Court to lift the &quot;partial stay&quot; imposed by the three-judge appeals court panel.</p>
<p>The Baby Bells, GTE Corp. and other local carriers and state regualtors challenging the FCC rule welcomed the order.</p>
<p>The three-judge panel suspended the all-important pricing components of the agency's &quot;interconnection&quot; rule, aimed at opening the local phone market to long-distance carriers, cable-television operators and others. The judges said they had &quot;serious doubts&quot; over the FCC's authority to impose its pricing policies.</p>
<p>The FCC rule, among other things, would require the Baby Bells and other local carriers to lease their phone lines to new competitors at steep discounts of up to 25 percent.</p>
<p>The stay -- which also covers the so-called &quot;pick and choose&quot; elements of the rule -- will remain in effect until the appeals court rules some time in 1997 on the challenge.</p>
<p>Oral arguments in the case are scheduled for January. The court had issued a temporary stay of the interconnection order last month while it considered granting a longer stay.</p>
<p>&quot;Congress' vision of a level playing field is being restored, while the FCC's effort to stack the deck against the local phone companies has been rebuffed,&quot; said GTE General Counsel William Barr.</p>
<p>The three-judge panel said the parties challenging the rule would be &quot;irreparably harmed&quot; if a stay was not granted.</p>
<p>The court suggested the FCC overstepped its authority and usurped the power of state regulators to make pricing policy.</p>
<p>It said it had &quot;serious doubts&quot; over the FCC's interpretation of the recently enacted  telecommunications law, from which the sweeping interconnection rule stems.</p>
<p>Barr said the court's action &quot;validates our view of a key point: in the Telecommunications Act itself, Congress explicitly gave the states -- not the FCC -- responsibility for these pricing matters.&quot;</p>
<p>The FCC rule would require local carriers to lease their local lines in bulk to competitors at discounts of 17 percent to 25 percent from retail prices. The new entrants to the local market could then resell the service to residential and business customers.</p>
<p>The agency also ordered local carriers to &quot;unbundle&quot; their local networks into seven pieces that new rivals can lease to complete their own phone networks. The pieces include call-switching devices and operator and directory assistance.</p>
<p>These &quot;unbundled elements&quot; were to be priced at competitive levels based on the cost of new and more-efficient facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a significant setback for the FCC for two reasons,&quot; said attorney Alfred Mamlet of Steptoe &amp; Johnson.</p>
<p>He said the appeals court &quot;concluded there is potential significant merit to the challenge to the pricing portions of the order. And second, this is going to slow down the implementation of local competition.&quot;</p>
<p>Barr argued that the granting of the stay &quot;facilitates the introduction of competition in local phone markets.&quot;</p>
<p>He said it will permit state regulators to &quot;go ahead and work out these issues without the dictates of the FCC.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
