<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117017" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks surge on Wall Street, election hopes.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks surge on Wall Street, election hopes.</headline>
<byline>Masako Iijima</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stock prices surged on Tuesday, propelled by record highs on Wall Street and expectations that the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) could win an outright majority in Japan's general election this weekend.</p>
<p>The key Nikkei 225 share index jumped 400.68 points, or 1.91 percent, to close at 21,429.93.</p>
<p>&quot;The Dow closed at over 6,000 and the domestic political picture is finally coming into focus with the LDP seen as the nucleus,&quot; said Tadahiro Kamogawa, general manager of Yamaichi Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;Both factors propelled the stagnant market into action.&quot; Brokers said investors, mostly institutional ones, started the day by buying back issues they had sold off in the past few weeks, encouraged by gains in the Dow and NASDAQ indexes on Monday.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials closed above the psychologically important 6,000 level for the first time ever on Monday, ending 40.99 points higher at 6,010. The Nasdaq Composite, which is studded with high-technology shares, also set a new record, closing up 8.09 points at 1,256.36.</p>
<p>Referring to Tokyo shares, Haruo Nakaharu, director of Toyo Securities, said: &quot;Buy-backs accounted for about half of the rise today and the other half was buying in anticipation of the upcoming election.&quot;</p>
<p>Market sources said the buying ignited by the U.S. markets was sustained by media reports saying the conservative LDP could win an outright majority in Japan's election on Sunday.</p>
<p>A weekend poll of 150,000 voters conducted by the business daily Nihon Keizai Shimbun showed the LDP was likely to have a simple majority of 251 seats, and possibly more, in the 500-seat Lower House of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a feeling of relief in the market that the political scene is beginning to take shape, which means that policies to prop up the economy have a chance of being carried out relatively smoothly,&quot; Yamaichi's Kamogawa said. &quot;It didn't have to be the LDP, it could have been any of the parties,&quot; Kamogawa added. &quot;The market was satisfied just to know that the political situation is showing signs of stabilising with the emergence of at least one dominant party.&quot;</p>
<p>The market also showed renewed vigour, with turnover almost doubling to 347 million shares after hitting a yearly low of 187 million on Monday.</p>
<p>Real estate shares benefited most from speculation about an LDP win. Brokers said investors hope the land taxation system will be revised smoothly under the party's supervision.</p>
<p>&quot;The sector's shares will rocket if the LDP does come to power,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Estate gained 30 yen ($0.26) to 1,480 yen ($13). Tokyu Land Corp closed up 18 yen ($0.16) at 578 yen ($5) and Sumitomo Realty &amp; Development Co Ltd was up 11 yen ($0.9) at 858 yen ($7).</p>
<p>Market sources said the bullish market mood would probably continue until the election.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know what will happen on Monday,&quot; said an official at one of Japan's &quot;Big Four&quot; securities houses.</p>
<p>&quot;If the LDP does indeed win a majority, the bright sentiment will continue, but if it doesn't, those who bought on speculation will be sorely disappointed.&quot; ($1=112 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
