<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117188" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tailgating leads to slaying in Orlando.</title>
<headline>Tailgating leads to slaying in Orlando.</headline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Fla 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A woman who was beaten during an argument between two couples over a tailgating incident died Tuesday and her alleged assailant was charged with murder, police said.</p>
<p>The argument erupted on a busy Orlando highway Saturday evening between a couple who followed too closely behind another couple's car, investigators said.</p>
<p>But when the drivers pulled to the side of the road to settle the dispute, the passenger in one car beat the passenger from the other on the head with what appeared to be a baseball bat, witnesses told police.</p>
<p>Georgetta Eaves, 44, a food service worker at Disney-MGM Studios, lapsed into a coma from which she never recovered and was pronounced dead Tuesday.</p>
<p>Joseph Holden, 25, a city maintenence worker who had no prior criminal record, was charged with second-degree murder and was held without bond, said Orange County Sheriff's spokesman Steve Jones.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not unusual for people to get into heated arguments. They get mad, next thing you know you're yelling back and forth, it goes to horn honking, fist shaking,&quot; he said. &quot;It's pretty common around the U.S. But not for somebody to be dead.&quot;</p>
<p>Investigators were still looking for the weapon used in the beating, police said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
