<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117443" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Justice says continuing probe of ADM officials.</title>
<headline>US Justice says continuing probe of ADM officials.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Justice Department officials said Tuesday that evidence is still being gathered on two top officials of the giant agribuiness concern Archer Daniels Midland Co and that &quot;they remain available for prosecution.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking at a press conference with senior Justice Department officials including Attorney General Janet Reno, Deputy Assistant Attorney General Gary Spratling said the agency is gathering evidence on ADM Vice Chairman Michael Andreas, and Terrance Wilson, Group Vice President in charge of ADM's corn refining division.  </p>
<p>ADM announced Monday it agreed to plead guilty to federal charges related to price-fixing and pay fines totalling $100 million, the largest criminal antitrust fine in history.</p>
<p>The agreement settles the Justice Department's almost four-year investigation of price-fixing of feed additive lysine and citric acid.</p>
<p>Attorney General Reno said the settlement should send a message worldwide to corporations that if they engage in collusive behavior that hurts U.S. consumers, &quot;there will be vigorous investigation and tough, tough penalties.</p>
<p>ADM will pay a fine of $70 million in connection with its plea in lysine, a feed additive used in poultry and swine feed, and $30 million in connection with citric acid, an organic acid used in various foods, beverages and other products.</p>
<p>U.S. Attorney James Burns of the northern district of Illinois, said that under the agreement ADM officials are required to cooperate with the Justice Department in its ongoing investigation.</p>
<p>&quot;You should stay tuned,&quot; said Burns. &quot;There will be more to come.</p>
<p>Speculation has been that Michael Andreas, son of ADM Chairman Dwayne Andreas and Wilson will eventually be criminally indicted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
