<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117590" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission to adopt two papers on Internet.</title>
<headline>Commission to adopt two papers on Internet.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission on Wednesday will take a first stab at one of the hottest potatoes on its political agenda -- how to prevent paedophiles and other criminals from misusing the Internet.</p>
<p>But the Commission, reacting to a Belgian child-sex and murder scandal which threw the spotlight onto the worldwide phenomenon of paedophilia, will fall short of proposing concrete, legally-binding measures, EU officials say.</p>
<p>Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann will instead outline in a communication a series of policy options that in the short term could help keep child pornography and other illegal material off the Internet, EU officials said.</p>
<p>They include strengthened cooperation between member states to apply existing rules, self-regulation by associations of Internet service providers, and extended use of filtering software and rating systems allowing users to block access to listed messages.</p>
<p>But encouragement, recommendation and examination will be the keywords rather than regulation, the officials said.</p>
<p>Keyword searches of the World Wide Web, after the bodies of four girls - alleged victims of convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux were found in Belgium -- showed thousands of messages about paedophiles and paedophilia. The Internet, where anonymity can be ensured, is almost impossible to police.</p>
<p>The Commission will argue on Wednesday that while misuse of the Internet is limited compared with its social, educational and cultural benefits, it is too wide to be ignored.</p>
<p>However, it believes the Internet's technical features, worldwide nature and unlimited accessibility mean that new legislation might not be the best way to fight crime.</p>
<p>The Commission will endorse a plan agreed by the Industry Council last week to have Germany host a global conference on ways to prevent misuse of the Internet and other information networks.</p>
<p>It will also set up a site on the World Wide Web including information about technical, legal and other solutions to the problem, officials said.</p>
<p>Culture Commissioner Marcelino Oreja will present a complementary green paper aimed at examining medium and long-term ideas for protecting minors and human dignity on a whole range of new audiovisual services, which he says include online services.</p>
<p>Oreja has opted for a softly-softly approach, saying he fears too-impulsive action could hinder the public benefits of the Internet and hinder freedom of expression.</p>
<p>His consultations with industry, government and family groups will focus on regulation versus self-regulation, parental control systems and improving international cooperation, officials said.</p>
<p>Interested parties will have until next February to answer a list of nine questions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
