<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117561" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French group says has the capital for Air Liberte.</title>
<headline>French group says has the capital for Air Liberte.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jacques Maillot, chairman of travel group Nouvelles Frontieres and airline Corsair, said on Tuesday a consortium he was heading &quot;had the capital it needs&quot; for succeeding in obtaining control over ailing airline Air Liberte.</p>
<p>Maillot is heading a French/Moroccan grouping who made an offer to the commercial court at Creteil, southeast of Paris, to acquire Air Liberte on Monday.</p>
<p>The main other bidder is British Airways Plc, through its French TAT unit, which has put 25 million francs on the table.</p>
<p>&quot;The big difference between us and BA is that BA has drawn up a disposal plan while we have made a continuity plan,&quot; Maillot told Reuters in an interview, explaining he believed British Airways aimed to strip Air Liberte's assets -- mainly a quarter of the slots at Orly Paris airport.</p>
<p>BA said on Monday it wanted to merge Air Liberte with TAT and safeguard 1,250 jobs out of 1,400. Maillot declined to give details on jobs, flights and debts.</p>
<p>&quot;Another difference is that we will negotiate with the creditors. We will not assume the debts but talk with the creditors,&quot; Maillot said.</p>
<p>The consortium of Maillot includes companies run by French industrialist Vincent Bollore, an investment vehicle of Club Mediterranee and Moroccan airline Royal Air Maroc.</p>
<p>Bollore's Groupe Rivaud and Club Med were also in the share capital of Air Liberte before it went into receivership on September 26. It made a nine month loss of 650 million francs and has debts of about 1.5 billion francs.</p>
<p>A third bidder, pilot Fernand Denan of airline AOM, made a 120 million francs offer for Air Liberte but has not yet finalised the financing.</p>
<p>Richard Branson's Virgin Express has not made an offer to the commercial court but it has expressed an interest in the matter.</p>
<p>Maillot confirmed to Reuters that he also wanted to bid for AOM, an airline put on sale by the Consortium de Realisation (CDR) state vehicle which is charged with selling assets formerly of bank Credit Lyonnais.</p>
<p>He said that the consortium for AOM would be &quot;an enlarged group&quot; compared to the Air Liberte bid. He added that mainly some French investors would join the team.</p>
<p>Maillot said AOM and Air Liberte could be merger into a strong French domestic airline.</p>
<p>Air Liberte made losses and ran up its debt after a rapid expansion during the year to fully exploit the opening up of a number of domestic routes after a virtual monopoly by Air Inter, a unit of Air France. All French air routes will be open to competition in 1997 in line with European liberalisation of the sector.</p>
<p>&quot;The management of Air Liberte just did all kinds of things. They invested too much too quickly,&quot; Maillot said, noting his Corsair was making money and AOM, while loss-making, was less affected than Air Liberte by the price war on French routes.</p>
<p>The Creteil commercial court is expected to unveil its deicsion next week at the earliest. The offer from British Airways is valid until October 30.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
