<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117534" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks close at year high with Dow support.</title>
<headline>French stocks close at year high with Dow support.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares closed at a closing high for the year but off their best levels on Tuesday, after a rally on the back of Wall Street's bull run, traders said.</p>
<p>Alcatel fell sharply in late trading on market talk it had won the bidding for electronics group Thomson but the missiles activities were being sold to Lagardere, traders said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed up 24.66 points or 1.15 percent at 2,168.28 while the CAC-40 futures contract was up at 2,172.5 from a settle of 2,149 on Monday.</p>
<p>The year high hit today by the CAC-40 index is 2,176.45.</p>
<p>The life high of the CAC-40 stands at 2,360.98 since February 1994.</p>
<p>Share volume today was 6.65 billion francs.</p>
<p>Turnover in Alcatel was 240 million francs, making it one of the biggest volumes. It was down 2.22 percent at 444.90.</p>
<p>Lagardere rose 2.94 percent to 133.10. The books-to-missiles conglomerate wants to merge its Matra unit with Thomson-CSF if it won Thomson SA.</p>
<p>Cie Generale des Eaux firmed 5.08 percent to 620 francs and had higher highest volume of 804 million francs, following an analysts meeting on Monday's first-half results</p>
<p>Its SGE construction unit ended up 14.74 percent at 102 francs, buoyed by restructuring plans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
