<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117658" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Congress leader wants minimum tax withdrawn.</title>
<headline>India Congress leader wants minimum tax withdrawn.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior leader of India's Congress party, which gives make-or-break support to Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's coalition, was quoted on Tuesday as saying the government must roll back a minimum corporate tax.</p>
<p>The Associated Chambers of Commerce and Industry (Assocham) quoted Pranab Mukherjee, a leading economic strategist of the Congress party, as saying at a seminar that the minimum alternate tax (MAT) must be withdrawn to boost savings and investment.</p>
<p>Finance Minister P.Chidambaram imposed in his budget last July the controversial 12.9 percent MAT on firms that in the past evaded corporate taxation by using a loophole that exempted tax payments on profits ploughed back into business.</p>
<p>The MAT was one of the key factors that caused a subsequent decline in Indian stock markets.</p>
<p>Mukherjee who has in the past held the jobs of the Finance Minister and Foreign Minister, also called for a reduction in interest rates as inflation based on wholesale prices was below 7 percent compared to a historical average of 8.5 to 9.0 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
