<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117620" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - October 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - October 15.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Tel:3326806, 3326813, 3326849  Fax:+91-11-3351006 E-mail:</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>DOMESTIC INDUSTRY TO BE PROTECTED</p>
<p>Industry Minister Murasoli Maran said the government's first duty would be to protect domestic industry. Now that government had achieved considerable progress in foreign investment policy, the industry ministry plans to shift its focus to small-scale industry and the public sector, Maran said. The minister's statement came in the wake of contrary signals from various ministries on policy and dissent raised against the government's pro-foreign investment policy by the domestic industry.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>BOMBAY BOURSE INDEX DOWN 98 POINTS</p>
<p>Stock hammering continued for the second day on Monday. The Bombay and National Stock exchanges (BSE &amp; NSE) saw their respective indices battered. The 30-share BSE sensitive index (SENSEX) touched an intra-day low of 2,939 during the mid-trading session but bounced back 62 points towards the end on profit-taking. The Sensex finally closed at 3002.86, down 98.41 points from the previous close. The NSE-50 lost 30.12 points from the previous close of 904.12.</p>
<p>GDRS PLUNGE TO NEW LOWS</p>
<p>Prices of global depository receipts (GDR) of Indian corporates plunged to new lows on Monday in tandem with trends in the domestic market. The Skindia GDR Index touched a new low of 59.22 on October 4, down from a record low of 61.18 on September 27. It had perked up to a high of 90 last April 4.</p>
<p>UNIT TRUST COLLECTIONS AT 12 BLN RUPEES</p>
<p>The Unit Trust of India (UTI) collected 12 billion rupees under various schemes offered by it during the quarter ended in September. Its sales target for the current financial year is pegged at 100 billion rupees. UTI's collection figures indicate it may not be able to meet its target this fiscal year. Given poor market conditions, the going may get tougher for UTI.  </p>
<p>CENTRAL BANK SEEN EASING LIQUIDITY</p>
<p>The central bank is likely to further ease liquidity, sparking a fall in interest rates and boosting depressed equity markets, bankers said. Currently, interest rates for top rated borrowers range from 15.5 percent per annum, charged by nationalised banks, to 18.5/19 percent by private and foreign banks. Most bankers feel liquidity may tighten in the coming months and this is keeping interest rate high. The problem can be solved by a cut in the cash reserve ratio for banks, they said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SUGAR INDUSTRY INCURRING LOSSES</p>
<p>The sugar industry, facing a severe glut, is incurring losses due to rising production and lagging consumption. In 1995/96 (April-March), sugar output totalled 16.4 million tonne, up from 14.16 million tonne in 1994/95. In fiscal 1996/97, looking at crop conditions, production is expected to touch 16 million tonnes. However, consumption is likely to reach only 14 million tonnes in 1996/97.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>ASEA BROWN BOVERI TO INVEST $1 BLN IN INDIA</p>
<p>The $35 billion Swiss Swedish conglomerate, Asea Brown Boveri (ABB), outlined a strategy for India to become the largest private sector electrical engineering company by 2000. This includes becoming an important partner in infrastructure, development of the industrial sector, build export business by 20 to 25 percent of the total ABB India production and become partners in third country projects. This would increase ABB India's turnover to $3.5 billion by 2000.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>SIEMENS TO TURN INDIAN ARM INTO FIVE BLN RUPEE GIANT</p>
<p>Siemens Nixdorf Information Systems India (SNI) is planning a $15 million investment in the next four years. The company is scouting for partners to establish itself in the manufacture of personal computers and telecommunication. SNI, a 51:49 joint venture between Siemens Nixdorf Informationsystemme AG and Siemens India, claims it will become a five billion rupee outfit by the year 2000.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>EXTERNAL COMMERCIAL BORROWINGS' CEILING RAISED</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has raised the year's external commercial borrowings (ECB) ceiling to $7.9 billion. The increase of $900 million over the the $7 billion cap set earlier is to meet the requirements of corporates which had received clearance last year but could not raise capital. Last fiscal, the government had cleared proposals worth $6.3 billion out of which only $5.4 billion was actually raised. The $900 million sum which could not be raised last year has been added to this year's annual ECB limit.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>LOW DEBT COMPONENT MOOTED FOR POWER UNITS</p>
<p>The Confederation of Indian Industry (CII) has suggested to the government that equity investment during construction of a power project be treated as subordinated debt. It has advised a change in the debt equity norm from 80:20 to 70:30. This, CII said would ensure that the burden of debt servicing did not unduly affect tariffs. It also recommended a 20 year income tax holiday for these projects. The suggested changes in financing pattern of power projects are part of CII's recently compiled Task Force Report on Private Power Development.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>NINETEEN MINING SECTOR PROJECTS CLEARED</p>
<p>The government may soon open up the mining sector to the foreign investors. The Foreign Investment Promotion Board has cleared 19 proposals for exploration, exploitation and technical consultancy of the minerals sector by foreign firms. Seven Australian mining companies were among the firms whose proposals were cleared. Two of the seven Australian companies have been granted 100 percent equity. Strait Resources is investing A$40 million. CRA Australia is investing A$150,000 along with an Indian subsidiary on technical consultancy.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
