<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117636" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India sees fiscal deficit cut to 4 pct in 2/3 yrs.</title>
<headline>India sees fiscal deficit cut to 4 pct in 2/3 yrs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's fiscal deficit would be brought down to four percent of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) in the next two to three years, Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This year, we have estimated the fiscal deficit at 5.0 percent and it may take two to three years to bring it down to below 4.0 percent,&quot; a Finance Ministry statement quoted Chidambaram saying at a meeting of state ministers.</p>
<p>India's fiscal deficit in 1995/96 (April-March) stood at 5.9 percent.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said that the first task of the government was to contain fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>He said financing of deficits through borrowing would raise inflation and keep interest rates at high levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The high cost of borrowing is also reflected in the central government's fiscal deficit,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>He said that the level of subsidies in the economy was high and urged for a more prudent approach on that front.</p>
<p>The government has promised to prepare a comprehensive paper on subsidies, both open and hidden, and submit it to parliament in the next session.</p>
<p>Chidambaram ruled out further government guarantees to private power producers to ensure payment obligations of state-run electricity boards who would buy power from private generation companies.</p>
<p>&quot;I also believe that we can get at least $ 7.0 billion over the next five years if we can introduce reforms in the power sector including state electricity boards (and) distribution,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--New Delhi newsroom +91-11-301-2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
