<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117855" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Coca-Cola Q3 up 22 pct, volume gains solid.</title>
<headline>Coca-Cola Q3 up 22 pct, volume gains solid.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coca-Cola Co reported Tuesday that third-quarter earnings per share increased 22 percent to $0.39 and said the gain came on solid global unit case volume increases.</p>
<p>&quot;While our business continued its strong performance, exceeding our publicly stated long-term goal for earnings per share growth, we prudently designated reserves and took charges aimed entirely at further strengthening our system and our company, both operationally and financially, chief executive Roberto C. Goizueta said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Consequently, we concluded the quarter on an even more sound footing than was the case three short months ago.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;All these actions, as well as the solid performance we foresee for our business over both the short and long term, position us well to continue to deliver the reliable earnings growth we have had over the past 15 years.&quot;</p>
<p>In the North America Group, the company said third-quarter unit case volume growth was four percent, including five percent growth in the United States. The growth rate in the company's bottle/can business was higher than the company's overall five percent growth rate in the United States during the quarter.  </p>
<p>Coke said the volume gains came one increases in unit sales of its core brands, which benefited from execution by bottlers and effective broad-based marketing plans which included leveraging the power of Olympic related promotions.</p>
<p>Once again, it said, Sprite was the fastest growing major soft drink brand in the United States producing double digit volume gains. Volume also rose from sales of products such as Barq's, POWERaDE, and Nestea.</p>
<p>&quot;Our U.S. business keeps on producing strong, profitable volume growth and share increases continuing the momentum we achieved in the first half of the year,&quot; Goizueta said.  </p>
<p>Unit case volume in North America has grown six percent for the year to date, including six percent growth in the United States, Coke said.</p>
<p>North American gallon shipments increased four percent for the quarter, including growth of four percent in the United States.  For the year to date, North American gallon shipments have risen seven percent, including a seven percent increase in the United States.</p>
<p>In the Latin America Group, unit case volume grew 10 percent in the third quarter following a five percent increase in the third quarter of 1995.  </p>
<p>The increase in volume was led by gains of 20 percent in Chile, 11 percent in Argentina and 10 percent in Mexico.</p>
<p>It said gallon shipments in the Latin America Group increased 11 percent in the third quarter of 1996.  For the year to date, unit case volume has risen six percent and gallon shipments have grown seven percent in Latin America.</p>
<p>Unit case volume in the Middle and Far East Group grew nine percent in the third quarter. The volume gain was led by increases of 29 percent in China, 17 percent in India and 16 percent in the Philippines. Gallon shipments in the Middle and Far East Group declined four percent in the third quarter.  </p>
<p>For the first nine months of the year, unit case volume has grown 10 percent and gallon shipments rose four percent.</p>
<p>In the Africa Group, third-quarter unit case volume was even.  Unit case volume increased two percent in the Southern Africa Division and declined two percent in the Northern Africa Division due to a difficult economic environment in Nigeria. Africa Group gallon shipments declined 13 percent.</p>
<p>Nine month unit case volume increased one percent and gallon shipments declined eight percent in the Africa Group.</p>
<p>In the Greater Europe Group, third-quarter unit case volume increased one percent.  </p>
<p>On a year-to-date basis, unit case volume rose seven percent.  An unseasonably cold and rainy summer negatively impacted volume in the third quarter.  Several key countries were hit by the poor weather, including Germany and Great Britain, where unit case volume fell 10 and 17 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>However, Coke said it continued to build on its leadership position in Eastern Europe with unit case volume increasing 18 percent in the third quarter. Gallon shipments in the Greater Europe Group fell four percent in the third quarter. For the year to date, gallon shipments rose eight percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, it was a tough third quarter for our Greater Europe Group, trying to top some challenging comparisons in a time when the weather hurt us.  But the outlook for the year and for the future remains very bright,&quot; said Goizueta.</p>
<p>Worldwide gallon shipments were up one percent in the third quarter and six percent for the year to date. Worldwide unit case volume increased six percent in the quarter and seven percent for the first nine months of the year.</p>
<p>At Minute Maid Co, formerly known as Coca-Cola Foods, unit volume increased 11 percent in the third quarter due to marketing initiatives, including new advertising.  </p>
<p>As previously announced, several non-recurring items resulted in after-tax gains for Coke in the third quarter.</p>
<p>These included $320 million as a result of a U.S. tax settlement and bottler transactions that added $190 million from issuing of additional equity by Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd, and by its Eastern German bottling operations as part of merger.</p>
<p>Concurrent with the gains posted in the third quarter, and as already announced, the company has taken steps to strengthen its operating system and provisions for these actions were recorded in the third quarter, it said.</p>
<p>Coke said it reduced concentrate inventory levels held by certain bottlers by curtailing concentrate shipments. As a result, concentrate gallon sales increased only one percent during the third quarter. This one-time reduction had an approximate $200 million after-tax impact in the quarter.</p>
<p>The cash infusion to the bottler system will be directed to sales-generating equipment and production expansion.</p>
<p>In connection with Project Infinity, the company recorded a provision of about $55 million.</p>
<p>The company said it also has taken various provisions totaling some $200 million after-tax arising from structural changes, mainly at Minute Maid Co.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
