<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="117852" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. manufacturing chief sees slowing economy.</title>
<headline>U.S. manufacturing chief sees slowing economy.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the National Association of Manufacturers said Tuesday that he sees economic growth slowing in the fourth quarter and in 1997, and urged the Federal Reserve to hold interest rates steady to see if that occurs.</p>
<p>&quot;We would encourage them (the Fed) to continue to wait,&quot; NAM Chairman Warren Batts told a news conference.  </p>
<p>Batts, who is also chairman of Tupperware Corp and Premark International, said he expects growth next year in the range of 2 to 2-1/2 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We think 1997 will probably be a good year,&quot; he said. But, he added, &quot;it will be a year not quite as strong as this year.&quot;</p>
<p>Batts said U.S. interest rates remain &quot;on a relative basis fairly high,&quot; and consumers are very heavily in debt.</p>
<p>Growth overseas remains lackluster, especially in Europe, he added.  </p>
<p>Batts said labor costs are beginning to rise, but only very slightly. &quot;I do not see a rapid escalation in labor costs right now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said companies continue to face difficulties in raising prices, partly due to stiff foreign competition. &quot;The closer we are to the consumer, the more difficult it is to raise prices,&quot; Batts said.</p>
<p>He said he did not see any sign of recession next year.  </p>
<p>Batts said, though, that the economy will remain saddled with slow growth of about two percent per year for the next few years if the government fails to take action to put its finances in better shape and reform entitlement spending.</p>
<p>NAM on Tuesday launched a national campaign calling for enactment of Social Security reform and a schedule for its implementation before the end of 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;The Social Security retirement system is approaching both financial and political crisis,&quot; Batts said.</p>
<p>NAM called for the appointment of a high-level bipartisan commission to recommend fundamental changes in Social Security. The association wants to transform a portion of the pension program to an individual retirement savings plan which would give people a choice of investment opportunities.</p>
<p>Batts said some of the measures that the bipartisan panel would need to look at would include an increase in the retirement age, a change in the calculation of cost-of-living increases in pension benefits away from reliance on the Consumer Price Index, and possibly some adjustment to taxes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
