<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118073" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ABU DHABI: Oman aims to export fertiliser to India from 2000. [corrected 15:57 gmt]</title>
<headline>Oman aims to export fertiliser to India from 2000. [corrected 15:57 gmt]</headline>
<dateline>ABU DHABI 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Omani-Indian joint venture fertiliser plant to export urea to increasingly import-dependent Indian fertiliser firms will start up in early 2000, Paul Weber, commercial development manager at Oman Oil Co said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>State-owned Oman Oil Co and India's Krish Bharati Cooperative Limited and Rashtriya Chemicals and Fertilisers Limited are behind the $1 billion project which would export 1.45 million tonnes a year of urea to India, Weber told delegates at a Middle East gas conference in Abu Dhabi.</p>
<p>The fertiliser plant is being developed to diversify the Gulf Arab state's oil-dominated economy by utilising the sultanate's proven gas reserves of 11 trillion cubic feet.</p>
<p>India is facing a growing supply-demand gap in urea supplies over the next ten years because of limited local gas output.</p>
<p>Omani and Indian government officials agreed to go-ahead with the project in August, despite the subsequent collapse of a project to export Omani natural gas to India by pipeline and doubts over a joint-venture oil refinery in India.</p>
<p>An offtake agreement between the parties is in its final drafting while contractors' bids to construct the plant are being evaluated. A final joint venture agreement is expected to be signed imminently.</p>
<p>Oman Oil Co will initially hold 50 percent equity in the firm while the Indian partners will each hold 25 percent.</p>
<p>The Oman plant, to be built at Sur south-east of the capital Muscat, will use 45 million cubic feet a year of gas from Omani fields to supply two 2,200 tonnes a day (corrects from tonnes a year) urea trains.</p>
<p>It will also have two ammonia trains each with a capacity of 1,750 tonnes a day, allowing exports of some 315,000 tonnes a year to the international market.</p>
<p>Some 3.5 million barrels a year of condensate or light oil will also be produced from the project.</p>
<p>&quot;Indian fertiliser companies will take 100 percent of the urea at the greater of market prices or a floor price set to achieve a minimum project return,&quot; Webber said.</p>
<p>&quot;Future market prices for urea will be set by incremental production exported at Yuzhnyy in the Ukraine. Cash costs fob Yuzhnyy are increasing with gas price increases throughout the former Soviet Union,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The floor price is around $115 a tonne.</p>
<p>Oman is reserving most of its gas reserves for a $6 billion liquefied natural gas (LNG) project -- expected to come into production in the year 2000 -- for industrial projects including a $2.4 billion aluminium smelter and a petrochemical plant.</p>
<p>-- Steven Swindells, Dubai Newsroom, +971 2 328000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
