<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118165" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Utah suing federal government over wilderness move.</title>
<headline>Utah suing federal government over wilderness move.</headline>
<dateline>SALT LAKE CITY 1996-10-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The state of Utah on Monday sued the (U.S.) Interior Department, claiming the federal government wants to set aside more areas for wilderness protection without adequate public consultation.</p>
<p>The state joined with county commissioners in filing the lawsuit in U.S. District Court in Salt Lake City.</p>
<p>The lawsuit claims Interior Secretary Bruce Babbitt is surveying areas in Utah for wilderness designation without following the procedures outlined in a 1979 law passed by Congress, said Vicki Varela, spokeswoman for Republican Gov. Mike Leavitt.</p>
<p>When areas are set aside as wilderness, road building and other development are strictly limited.</p>
<p>Some of the state's leading politicians -- Utah Republicans Sen. Orrin Hatch, Bob Bennett, Representative Jim Hansen as well as Democratic Representative Bill Orton -- held a news conference on Monday to announce the lawsuit.</p>
<p>&quot;What the Interior Department is doing now doesn't make sense and we want to have our day in court,&quot; Leavitt said. &quot;I want to create more wilderness (areas). It's a question of the process.&quot;</p>
<p>Utah politicians felt left out of the process when President Bill Clinton last month announced he was creating the Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument, which covers 1.7 million acres (688,000 hectares) in southern Utah.</p>
<p>The governor is concerned that Utah school trust lands are in jeopardy because of the Interior Department's interest in those lands for wilderness designation.</p>
<p>In some Western states such lands have been set aside for the benefit of school districts, with funds from development of those lands going toward education.</p>
<p>Varela said the governor's motivation for filing the lawsuit was in part to assure that the federal government &quot;can't take that land from the school children of Utah.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALT LAKE CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
