<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118193" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Opel Eisenach plant a litmus test for car industry.</title>
<headline>Opel Eisenach plant a litmus test for car industry.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German carmaker Adam Opel AG will tout the triumph of its job-creating Eisenach plant this week when production tops 500,000 vehicles at the gleaming facility it built on the ruins of a former East German factory.</p>
<p>For Europe's largest carmakers, which dream of fleeing costly countries like Germany to reap the benefits of cheaper labour markets and innovative Japanese production techniques, the plant is a proof that change can bring success at home.</p>
<p>Opel on Tuesday said it will celebrate the milestone output with a ceremony on Thursday at the plant, located about 200 kilometers northwest of Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The success at home has prompted Opel, a unit of General Motors Corp., to use the Eisenach plant as a model for new plants in emerging markets like Asia and eastern Europe.</p>
<p>A new plant in Gliwice, Poland, will produce 72,000 low-cost passenger cars annually from 1998, while a new $750 million plant announced for Thailand will be modelled on Eisenach.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to make improvements in productivity in Europe because of the restrictive labour laws,&quot; said Philip Ayton, an industry analyst at BZW in London.</p>
<p>&quot;They are all trying to do it within Europe. But when you start with an overmanned workforce, it is difficult,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Opel pounced as East Germany began crumbling after the Berlin Wall came down, signing a deal to build the plant in Eisenach during the last week of Communist rule in March 1990.</p>
<p>The carmaker poured a billion marks into Eisenach and created for the first time a European plant belonging to a western company that used Japanese standards. The deal is still the largest completed industrial investment in east Germany.</p>
<p>Gone was the tense relationship between management and labour as titles disappeared. Workers from the plant manager down to cleaners wear gray and white uniforms and are organised into teams of six to ten people, with each team responsible for a production stage.</p>
<p>The Opel plant uses Japanese ideas such as just-in-time stock control, continuous improvement meetings and systems to allow workers themselves to report and correct problems.</p>
<p>About 2,000 jobs have been created at the plant along with 1,000 more jobs at local supplier companies, creating work in a beleaguered area with double-digit unemployment. Wages are below western standards but have been catching up.</p>
<p>The absence rate -- a sore topic in Germany  particularly after Bonn approved a controversial law to cut sick pay -- is a low three to four percent. Employees who do not take any sick time can participate in a lottery for a Corsa.</p>
<p>Opel was also able to raise efficiency by swiftly introducing computer-controlled production, a move difficult in the west since carmakers often find themselves embroiled in disputes with powerful unions over changes to production.</p>
<p>The results during the last four years are evident.</p>
<p>The Eisenach plant increased productivity even further in the first half of 1996 by cutting the amount of time needed to make a Corsa vehicle to under 17 hours and down from almost 20 hours in 1995. Opel says 32 Corsas now roll off the production line each hour during three-shift days.</p>
<p>For the second year running, the plant was the most productive in Europe, ahead of Fiat's Melfi facilty and Japanese plants in Europe, although industry analysts say Honda and Toyota have not yet reached their full potential.</p>
<p>The Economist Intelligence Unit raised its output ratio for Opel during 1995 to 71.9 vehicles per employee, up from 59 in 1994. Fiat was second at 64.3 vehicles per employee.</p>
<p>The Opel plant is considered a major test for Europe's auto industry, and several carmakers -- including Ford, Mercedes, BMW and Porsche -- have visited the plant seeking ideas.</p>
<p>In only a few more years the European Community will lift barriers againt the full blast of Japanese competition amid fears they will invade like they did in North America.</p>
<p>European carmakers have a long way to catch the Japanese, even during a period of an overall drop in output. Mitsubishi's Mizushima facilty produces 117 cars per employees, while Toyota's Takaoka plant is second at 109.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
