<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118279" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Dresdner to run Eurobond operation in London - paper.</title>
<headline>Dresdner to run Eurobond operation in London - paper.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Dresdner Bank AG plans to concentrate its Eurobond operations in London, taking over a team from a London-based Eurobond firm, to form the centre of its operations there, a German newspaper reported.</p>
<p>The Boersen-Zeiting said in Tuesday's edition Dresdner planned to buy the firm Luthy Baillie Dowsett &amp; Pethick Ltd (LBDP). Peter Luthy and his future deputy Jan Pethick would take over global responsibility for Dresdner's Eurobond business in all major currencies, the paper said.</p>
<p>No comment was immediately available from Dresdner Bank's headquarters in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The Boersen-Zeitung said Gerhard Abel, who runs Dresdner's primary business in Frankfurt, and Kluas Roehricht, responsible for Eurobond trading, would also then report to London beginning in November.</p>
<p>Top level responsibility would remain in Frankfurt however, it said. Luthy would thus report to Erich Pohl and Leonhard Fischer, the joint heads of the Global Markets Division, the paper reported.</p>
<p>Responsibility for government and German domestic issues would also remain in Frankfurt, it said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
