<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118251" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss food giants want gene soybeans separated.</title>
<headline>Swiss food giants want gene soybeans separated.</headline>
<byline>Marcus Kabel</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Switzerland's two biggest food retailers, which control 43 percent of the Swiss market, are demanding that U.S. soybean producers separate new genetically altered beans from the conventional crop.</p>
<p>Migros, the largest Swiss retailer with 24 percent market share, said on Tuesday genetically engineered soybeans and derivative products must be clearly labelled because consumers want to know what is in their food.</p>
<p>Migros joined a call by number two retailer Coop Schweiz on Monday for European food producers to stand up against plans by U.S. suppliers to mix the new soybeans with shipments of conventional soybeans.</p>
<p>&quot;We too want the soybeans marketed separately and labelled because 80 percent of our consumers say they want clear labelling and freedom of choice,&quot; Migros managing board member Monika Weber told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not against genetic technology, but you have to respect the consumers' wishes,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Europe is due for its first shipments of genetically altered soybeans later this year, when the new U.S. harvest will include Roundup Ready beans developed by U.S. chemicals group Monsanto Co. to withstand its Roundup herbicide.</p>
<p>Soybeans, soyoil and derivatives are used in some 30,000 food products such as confectionery and margarine.</p>
<p>&quot;We are urging our suppliers to push for a separation (of genetically altered soybeans),&quot; Weber said.</p>
<p>Migros and Coop spoke out three weeks after EuroCommerce, representing food retailers and wholesalers in 20 European countries, warned that European consumers could shun the 1996 U.S. soybean harvest unless gene-modified strains were labelled.</p>
<p>But Migros' Weber said there was little chance of widespread consumer boycotts of the kind that affected the European beef industry after this year's &quot;mad cow&quot; scare.</p>
<p>&quot;With beef, it was one product, but with soy now it is in all kinds of produce,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The U.S. grain industry says it would be costly and impractical to try to separately handle crops that are indistinguishable from traditional varieties.</p>
<p>U.S. and European Union (EU) health and safety checks have approved the use of Roundup Ready beans, but approval by non-EU member Switzerland is still pending.</p>
<p>Consumer and environmental groups including Greenpeace are petitioning the Swiss government to bar any imports of genetically engineered foodstuffs.</p>
<p>Simonetta Sommaruga from the Swiss Foundation for Consumer Protection said the arrival of the Roundup Ready beans would give a boost to already popular organically grown produce at big grocery chains and smaller shops.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
