<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118407" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Outlook &quot;positive&quot; for gold demand --GFMS.</title>
<headline>Outlook &quot;positive&quot; for gold demand --GFMS.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The many influences which will decide gold demand as the market moves into its five months of peak consumption are &quot;fairly benign and possibly even positive&quot;, according to the chief executive of Gold Fields Minerals Service.</p>
<p>In remarks prepared for his Overview of the Gold Market at the International Gold Markets Conference in Istanbul, Turkey, Stewart Murray noted on Tuesday that a key factor would be supply from above-ground stocks.</p>
<p>The market had to wait for further policy indicators from the offical sector and see if recent buying back by producers represented a &quot;sea-change&quot; in their policy or a pause before they resumed forward selling.</p>
<p>Murray outlined in detail the changing consumption and supply patterns in the market. Since 1990, physical demand for gold has oustripped mine production by just under 500 tonnes per year.</p>
<p>The gap has been filled by scrap and by drawing on bullion stocks held above ground. Since 1990, central banks have sold on average 277 tonnes of gold a year. A further 214 tonnes has come into the market annually from producer hedging.  </p>
<p>However, to balance the first half of 1996 an &quot;implied disinvestment&quot; -- a gap between supply and demand -- of 160 tonnes would be needed in Europe and North America.</p>
<p>&quot;Our gut feeling about this amount is that it is probably too large,&quot; Murray said. &quot;It would be smaller if we over-estimated physical demand.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We feel that a more likely source of revision is the estimate for offical sector net sales. If it turns out that our estimate is on the low side, then the implied net disinvestment number will fall correspondingly.&quot;</p>
<p>During the first half of this year producers buying back earlier forward sales resulted in a net zero addition to supply from producer hedging programmes.</p>
<p>The Belgian Central Bank was the leading seller from the official sector with 207 tonnes during first half 1996, although Murray noted that not all of this came on to the market (being sent to other central banks) and some of it was sold forward into the market the previous year.  </p>
<p>Such disinvestment as was seen resulted in laying off in the London market the large decline in open interest on Japan's Tocom and New York's Comex futures exchanges, as well as the much larger change in the less transparent over-the-counter markets, Murray said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
