<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118556" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIA passenger growth seen offsetting fuel costs.</title>
<headline>SIA passenger growth seen offsetting fuel costs.</headline>
<byline>Doreen Siow</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong passenger traffic growth should partly offset higher jet fuel prices for Singapore Airlines (SIA), which is due to release its first half results on October 27, aviation analysts said on Tuesday. The consensus forecast of analysts polled in the October edition of The Estimate Directory is for SIA's net earnings to rise 14 percent to S$1.17 billion (US$830 million) for the full year ending March 1997.</p>
<p>The national airline has seen an earnings downgrade by some analysts in recent months due to rising jet fuel prices.</p>
<p>But the impact is seen cushioned by better-than-expected passenger traffic growth since the start of SIA's financial year in April.</p>
<p>The airline achieved passenger traffic growth of 12.8 percent for the first five months (April-August), outstripping capacity growth of 7.9 percent, said Sim Chey Hoon, investment analyst with Merrill Lynch in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;The August load factor numbers were quite healthy,&quot; said Sim, who expects the airline to post net profit of S$550 million to S$600 million for the first half.</p>
<p>Declan Magee, regional aviation analyst with HG Asia in Hong Kong, agreed. &quot;The interims should be quite good. The passenger business has been quite strong,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Passenger revenues in the first half should be better than the previous corresponding half when traffic from the Philippines and Japan was depressed by a controversy over the hanging of a Filipino maid in Singapore and the Kobe earthquake.</p>
<p>However, Magee, who had forecast full-year earnings of S$1.20 billion for SIA, said higher oil prices would impact on first-half earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;Roughly speaking, every one percent increase in oil prices on a full-year basis would reduce earnings per share by about 0.7 percent for SIA,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sim said she expected high jet fuel prices to shave about S$120 million off SIA's 1997 earnings, assuming prices stayed high until after the winter.</p>
<p>She said much of the impact of higher fuel prices would be felt in the second half by SIA, despite some hedging activities by the airline.</p>
<p>SIA's cargo business, which accounts for about 20 percent of revenue, is expected to continue to be depressed by global overcapacity and keen competition.</p>
<p>Magee said he saw no relief for that sector as SIA also would be affected by declining volumes of computer-related manufactured goods freighted out of Singapore.</p>
<p>Sim noted SIA's cargo traffic growth to date of 13.6 percent continued to lag capacity expansion of 16.2 percent, resulting in a further deterioration in load factor to 66.9 percent.</p>
<p>However, she expected the downtrend in load factor to bottom as SIA's aggressive capacity expansion tapered off.</p>
<p>US$1 = S$1.41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
