<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118527" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: ASIAN EXOTICS - Baht unmoved by Bodi departure.</title>
<headline>ASIAN EXOTICS - Baht unmoved by Bodi departure.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Thai baht held its own in both the spot and forward markets on Tuesday, remaining unfazed by the resignation of Finance Minister Bodi Chunnananda ahead of a general election on November 17.</p>
<p>Bodi submitted his resignation to Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa on Monday. He did not state the reasons for his sudden resignation, which takes effect today.</p>
<p>&quot;It was more or less expected because everyone knows the Finance Minister was part of Banharn's camp. And if Banharn goes, his people have to go,&quot; said a European bank dealer in Singapore.</p>
<p>Dealers said the baht was not likely to be affected as no major policy changes were expected from Bodi's replacement, who would serve as a caretaker minister until after the election.</p>
<p>The baht was quoted at 25.459-25.464 to the dollar at 0415 GMT from 25.464-25.467 late on Monday, but demand for dollars persisted due to low baht short-term interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The demand for the dollar this morning has nothing to do with the Finance Minister's resignation,&quot; said a Bangkok dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;People continue to buy the U.S. unit because short-term baht interest rates remain very low...,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, the rupiah was on firm ground and short-dated swaps remained expensive, but the dollar found some support on market fears of a higher fixing by Bank Indonesia.</p>
<p>Still, pressure on the central bank's downside limit pushed spot dollar/rupiah through support at 2,321.0 to 2,320.8/21.2 at 0415 GMT, compared with an early high of 2,321.75.</p>
<p>Dealers in Jakarta said the dollar-rupiah rate also fell briefly below the intervention rate on Monday, but apparently the amount of dollars absorbed by the central bank was not large enough to impact money market liquidity.</p>
<p>A local bank dealer said the central bank might have to absorb a large amount of dollars if it raised the intervention rate by one point later on Tuesday as offshore players were trying to test the downside.</p>
<p>&quot;The amount of dollars to be absorbed by the central bank could be larger, thus inducing additional rupiah in the market which may help ease swap premiums,&quot; another said.</p>
<p>The central bank kept its intervention rate unchanged at 2,320/2,512 and the conversion rate at 2,320/2,368 on Monday.</p>
<p>The Malaysian ringgit stayed within a narrow range but gained ground on fund buying and speculation of a positive trade figure for August.</p>
<p>&quot;The rumour is still going around that August will be a (trade) surplus month. That is pushing down dollar/ringgit,&quot; said a dealer with a Malaysian bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been opening 10 pips lower every day since Friday. This could take dollar/ringgit down to 2.50,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the offshore market was still long dollars and funds continued to flow in from Thailand.</p>
<p>Across the border, the Singapore dollar was mildly dented by its neighbour's positive tone, as ringgit/Sing buying pushed it below the psychological 1.41 level against its U.S. counterpart.</p>
<p>&quot;The Singapore stock market is looking very sick,&quot; said a European bank dealer. &quot;Between the ringgit and Sing, the Sing has to be weaker given the lower projected economic growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said dollar/Sing was likely to trade between 1.4090 and 1.4115/20. It was quoted at 1.4098/108 at 0410 GMT.</p>
<p>Singapore shares recovered some ground on Tuesday after the key Straits Times Industrials Index ended at an 18-month low of 2,045.58 on Monday on expectations of poor third quarter growth.</p>
<p>-- Madhav Reddy in Kuala Lumpur (603-230 8911), Mantik Kusjanto in Jakarta (6221-384-6364), Anuchit Nguyen in Bangkok (662-652-0642) and Sonali Desai in Singapore (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
