<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118513" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-RESEARCH ALERT-Lend Lease seen a buy.</title>
<headline>RTRS-RESEARCH ALERT-Lend Lease seen a buy.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brisbane-based broking house Morgan Stockbroking Ltd was recommending Lend Lease Corp Ltd as a buy, saying all indications were that the group's buoyant performance would continue.</p>
<p>&quot;Recommendation is buy. (There is) an improved property workload, increasing financial services business and opportunities to use its expertise in Asia and related areas,&quot; Morgan analyst Greg Cathro said in a research report.</p>
<p>&quot;These are all indications that the above-average performance of the company will continue,&quot; Cathro said.  </p>
<p>Cathro said the net profit result of A$280 million in the year ended June 30, 1996 was marginally below expectations but included some conservative one-off items which, on balance, tended to understate the performance.</p>
<p>Cathro forecast Lend Lease's net profit rising to $325 million in the current 1996/97 year with total fully-franked dividends of 96 cents a share compared to the 90 cents in 1995/96.  </p>
<p>&quot;The company is expanding into Asia, has formed a joint venture with IBM to provide information out-sourcing services in Australasia and is seeking ways to use its skills in new infrastructure projects,&quot; Cathro said.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for the company remains positive,&quot; he said. Financial services operations were forecast to achieve double-digit growth over the next three years with gains arising in a competitive environment from a planned 40 percent reduction in costs over the period, Cathro said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The company has established itself as a consistent growth investment with a conservative financial position,&quot; Cathro said. &quot;It deserves to sell at a premium to sharemarket average valuation ratios,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
