<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118653" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Communists could spring surprise in Japan election.</title>
<headline>Communists could spring surprise in Japan election.</headline>
<byline>Teruaki Ueno</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's topsy-turvy politics could throw up another surprise in next Sunday's general election if, as seems increasingly possible, the Communist Party emerges as a key player.</p>
<p>Analysts say the Communists, whose very survival seemed threatened by the demise of the Soviet Union in 1991, could capitalise on voter discontent and increase their seats, setting off a rush by conservative groups to unify.</p>
<p>With less radical left-wing parties like the Social Democrats in disarray and some polls forecasting a coalition as the most likely election result, the Japan Communist Party (JCP) may well be poised for a new and enhanced role.</p>
<p>The Social Democrats, formerly the Socialists, have shared power in a bizarre left-right coalition with the pro-business Liberal Democratic Party since 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Communist Party wins more seats, Japan's politics will be plunged into a new form of instability,&quot; said political analyst Minoru Morita.</p>
<p>&quot;It would spark fear among all the non-Communist parties and prompt them to form an awkward unified front against the Communists,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Some analysts predict the JCP, which is fielding 321 candidates, could win 50 seats in the new 500-seat Lower House.</p>
<p>It had 15 seats in the 511-seat Lower House dissolved this month. The most it has ever held was the 41 seats won in 1979.</p>
<p>They said voters disenchanted with the main parties and unhappy with the status quo could vote for the Communists, who have at least been consistent in their policies during the past three years of turbulence in Japanese politics.</p>
<p>&quot;The general public is not allergic to the Communist Party any more since the collapse of the Soviet Union,&quot; said Rei Shiratori of Tokai University in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Senior JCP official Kazuo Shii said his party planned to woo &quot;disaffected&quot; and &quot;undecided&quot; voters who polls indicate number more than half of Japan's 98 million voters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeking cooperation from both reformists and conservatives who have no allegiance to any political party,&quot; he told a recent news conference.</p>
<p>Japan's oldest political party was hit hard by the collapse of the Soviet Union, losing support in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>But it bounced back this year to win mayoral elections in two Tokyo suburbs in what could be a pointer to Sunday's polls.</p>
<p>In its election platform, the JCP promises to force U.S. troops out of Japan, scrap the Japan-U.S. Security Treaty and nullify a planned sales tax rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The government the general public really needs is one in which citizens, not business circles or the United States, play the leading role,&quot; said JCP Chairman Tetsuzo Fuwa.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan must have true freedom by being independent of foreign countries,&quot; Fuwa said in a recent campaign speech.</p>
<p>The rape of a schoolgirl by three U.S. servicemen on Okinawa last year ignited strong resentment at the presence of 47,000 U.S. troops in Japan -- an issue the JCP has exploited.</p>
<p>A national survey by the Tokyo Shimbun newspaper last week showed 46 percent of voters support scrapping all U.S. bases.</p>
<p>While vaguely advocating the consolidation and reduction of U.S. military bases in Japan, other parties basically support the Japan-U.S. military alliance.</p>
<p>Japan's Communists broke with the leading Communist powers -- Moscow and Beijing -- in the 1960s, saying their principal ideological soul mate was the Vietnam of Ho Chi Minh.</p>
<p>Founded in 1922, the JCP was repeatedly suppressed by the authorities in the years up to World War Two, only to be revived by its few remaining members after the war.</p>
<p>The JCP, which refuses to accept campaign funds from the government or donations from business, is financed mainly by sales of the party newspaper Akahata or &quot;Red Flag&quot;.</p>
<p>The paper's circulation, a good indicator of the party's popularity, has remained at 2.5 million for the past few years after reaching a peak of 3.5 million in 1980.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
