<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118911" id="root" date="1996-10-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Global trade triangle gaining popularity.</title>
<headline>Global trade triangle gaining popularity.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A global trade triangle featuring Europe, the United States and Asia is gaining currency as a precursor to a next round of international market liberalisation, analysts say.</p>
<p>Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong referred to the &quot;triad&quot; during an adress to Belgium's Royal Institute of International Affairs on Monday, saying a complete trade triangle was essential for global economic harmony.</p>
<p>His comments were seen by some analysts as confirming Asian perceptions that Europe -- or more particularly the European Union -- had ground to make up following years of ignoring Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;While transatlantic ties between Europe and North America and transpacific ties between North America and East Asia were strong, institutional linkages between Europe and Asia were absent,&quot; Goh said.</p>
<p>He added, however, that ASEM (the Asia-Europe Meeting started this year which groups the 15 EU states with 10 Asian bations) was a great step towards completing the triangle.</p>
<p>&quot;The world will benefit in many ways from this strengthened partnership,&quot; he said. &quot;It will create a strong triangular relationship among the three regions of economic power... (provide) potential for synergy between Asia and Europe...and make a joint contribution to global peace and stability in the new century.&quot;</p>
<p>A seminar last week in Brussels on European relations with the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) focussed on the idea of building a global trade pyramid around APEC, ASEM and the New Transatlantic Agenda, which groups the EU and United States.</p>
<p>But Ernest Preeg, an expert from the Washington-based Centre fort Strategic and International Studies, called the triad &quot;unequal&quot; and warned that the world economy was in danger of being split into two or three adversarial trade blocs.</p>
<p>While the ideal way to prevent polarisation would be through multilateral agreements under the World Trade Organisation, Preeg said: &quot;Another way is to build cooperative linkages among the three regional groupings which has only begun to take shape recently.&quot;</p>
<p>While many analysts are united in believing a triangle is the shape of the world's trade future, few agree on whether this triangle will have sides of equal length.</p>
<p>Peeg said few people in Washington had heard of ASEM, while Jacques Pelkmans -- an analyst at the European Institute for Asian Studies -- said APEC's &quot;actual or potential meaning to Europe is ill-understood if not routinely ignored&quot;.</p>
<p>Few experts, on the other hand, dispute Asia's grasp of the transatlantic axis. Asian leaders have frequently accused the EU and U.S. of ganging up against them -- particularly on issues such as labour rights -- in order to dull their competitive edge.</p>
<p>In his speech on Monday, Goh urged Europe to have a closer look at strengthening relations by first understanding how Asia works.</p>
<p>He cited the 16th-century European Jesuit missionary Matteo Ricci as a model for cooperation.</p>
<p>The Jesuits, said Goh, &quot;creatively and wisely adapted themselves to local circumstance by adopting Chinese dress, names and language, thus making themselves acceptable to their host before imparting their knowledge.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, Asian businessmen are copying the Jesuits, by donning Western dress, speaking Western languages and -- for some -- even adopting Western names in order to do business.</p>
<p>Goh neglected to mention, however, that while Ricci's tactics succeeded in gaining him entry to Beijing, where he died in 1610, scores of his colleagues were killed in their mission, villified as foreign devils bent on corrupting Asian values.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
