<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118965" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Cameco Corp sees strong pre-tax earnings.</title>
<headline>Cameco Corp sees strong pre-tax earnings.</headline>
<dateline>SASKATOON, Saskatchewan 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cameco Corp said on Wednesday it expected continued strength in cash flow and earnings before tax in coming years.</p>
<p>&quot;Cameco anticipates the trend of strong pre-tax earnings and cash flow will continue in future years,&quot; Bernard Michel, Cameco chairman, president and chief executive said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company repeated that starting in 1997, recording deferred income taxes would lower net earnings, but that it did not expect to have to pay significant cash taxes until after the year 2000.  </p>
<p>Cameco said its revenue sensitivity to the uranium spot price was such that a change of US$1 a pound U308 for the rest of the year would impact sales by C$2 million.</p>
<p>In the third quarter, the uranium spot price averaged US$16.26 per pound U308 versus US$16.34 in the second quarter and US$11.79 per pound in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>The lower spot price relative to the second quarter was due to market demand being met by adequate supply.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the long-term uranium market fundamentals remain favorable, with excess inventories being drawn down as uranium demand continues to outpace production,&quot; Michel said.  </p>
<p>Cameco earned C$38.03 million or C$0.72 per share in the third quarter versus C$24.12 million or C$0.45 a share in the prior-year period.</p>
<p>Sales rose by more than 70 percent to C$457 million from the 1995 nine months' earnings of C$268 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvement in net earnings and revenues was due primarily to increases in uranium concentrate sales volumes and average selling prices,&quot; Cameco said.</p>
<p>Uranium sales volumes rose 60 percent from last year's levels while the average selling price increased by 17 percent.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SASKATOON, Saskatchewan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
