<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118979" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bank of Canada cuts bank rate.</title>
<headline>Bank of Canada cuts bank rate.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Canada cut its key Bank Rate by 25 basis points to 3.75 percent by conducting special purchase and resale operations at 3.75 percent, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The move lowers the central bank's target range for the overnight lending rate to 3.25-3.75 percent from 3.50-4.0 percent, money market traders said.</p>
<p>The Bank Rate is the top of the central bank's target range for the overnight rate, at which it lends to financial institutions in its role as lender of last resort.</p>
<p>A basis point is one-hundredth of a percentage point.  </p>
<p>In a news release after the cut, the Bank of Canada said the rate cut was designed to keep monetary conditions from tightening.</p>
<p>&quot;Given a stronger Canadian dollar, this action was designed to keep overall monetary conditions from tightening,&quot; the Bank said.</p>
<p>The Bank said the rate cut also ratified the recent decline in short-term market interest rates.  </p>
<p>The Bank of Canada rate cut prompted several of Canada's major chartered banks to lower their prime lending rates to 5.25 percent from 5.50 percent.</p>
<p>The Canadian dollar, T-bills and bonds were stronger after the rate cut, with the yield on Canada's three-month when-issued T-bill firming to yield 3.38 percent from 3.41 percent at the close of trading on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It was the ninth rate cut by the Bank of Canada this year and the eighth done independent of an easing by the U.S. Federal Reserve. The Bank of Canada has now eased by 450 basis points since May 1995.  </p>
<p>Dealers said prime rates in Canada are now at their lowest levels since 1959.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
