<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="118974" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X falls on ownership doubt.</title>
<headline>Bre-X falls on ownership doubt.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Bre-X Minerals Ltd fell sharply on Wednesday as questions grew about the ownership of the company's spectacular Indonesian gold discovery.</p>
<p>&quot;I think these (ownership) claims are just the tip of the iceberg,&quot; gold analyst John Ing of Maison Placements Canada said in an interview.</p>
<p>Bre-X shares lost almost 16 percent of their value in early trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange, falling 3.60 to 19.35 in brisk turnover of more than 5.7 million shares.  </p>
<p>The stock has fallen C$7.55 since October 4, when disputes about the ownership of the deposit became public.</p>
<p>&quot;There are so many theories, different scenarios, permutations, combinations,&quot; said Ing, who has just returned from a visit to Indonesia.</p>
<p>He thinks the slide in the stock had just begun.</p>
<p>&quot;We're telling our clients that the cake is not yet baked.&quot;</p>
<p>Indonesian businessman Jusuf Merukh told Reuters in Indonesia on Wednesday that he was entitled to a 40 percent stake of the rich Busang gold find through two of his firms.  </p>
<p>Merukh also said he signed a technical assistance agreement this year with Golden Valley Mines NL of Australia.</p>
<p>The Australian company publicized details of its agreement with Merukh's PT Krueng Gasui last weekend, prompting Bre-X to challenge its claims to the Busang deposit.</p>
<p>&quot;We've asked the Australian Stock Exchange to ask the company to back up its allegations,&quot; Bre-X spokesman Steve McAnulty said today in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We've asked for documentation to support the claims and nothing has been forthcoming.&quot;  </p>
<p>Placer Dome Inc, which said it had its eye on Bre-X, was not worried about the ownership claims, Placer Dome spokesman Hugh Leggatt said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a factor for us. It still remains an attractive deposit.&quot;</p>
<p>The company, while interested in the property, had not yet put in a bid, he said.</p>
<p>A bid for part of Bre-X could include a requirement that the ownership dispute be resolved, Leggatt said.</p>
<p>The Busang discovery has estimated resources of at least 50 million ounces of gold. Exploration is ongoing.</p>
<p>Most of the world's major gold producers are said to be interested in buying a piece of Bre-X.</p>
<p>-- Heather Scoffield, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8104</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
