<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119163" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. stock index futures close up after late spurt.</title>
<headline>U.S. stock index futures close up after late spurt.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stock futures finished stronger after spurting upwards late in the session.</p>
<p>Traders said they saw heavy technical buying once December S&amp;Ps went above 708.50. The contract set fresh session highs in the last half-hour of trade after a lackluster morning.</p>
<p>&quot;This last push up past 708.50 is really, really bullish,&quot; one trader said. &quot;We're poised for a move further, at least to 710.00 or 710.65.  Unless there's some problem with the bonds, with rates in general, I think we'll see a move towards 712.50, the contract high.&quot;  </p>
<p>That level, and the Oct 8 high of 710.65, has created the head and shoulder of a head-and-shoulder pattern, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that 710.65 level should be in the bag and we'll probably push past that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Marc Chandgie, trading desk manager at Atlantic Coast Futures, agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;Really short-term, I think you've got a retest of the highs you made on Tuesday,&quot; he said, referring to the 712.50 level. However, after that, he expects to see a pull-back through the rest of the month, probably into the &quot;low 690s.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;As soon as you move into November, you should take off again. I am looking for a top that should be far more significant than the one we're making now,&quot; he said, citing 725.00 and 730.00 as possible targets.</p>
<p>Traders noted a liquidity gap between 704.40 and 704.60, which they termed a swing area. Below that, the contract would have to fall to 697.50 before it would meet substantial support, one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;But right now, the way things are going, the money is flowing in on the buy side so a blow-off rally past 712.50 in a day or two is within the realm of possiblity,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Beyond that level, stops could be seen, he added.</p>
<p>Decemember S&amp;P futures weakened early on local and dealer selling, but some traders and analysts said the move was a typical consolidation within a bull market.</p>
<p>In the afternoon, local short-covering and dealer buying pushed December S&amp;Ps into positive territory. The contract set its daily high at 708.40.</p>
<p>At settlement, December S&amp;Ps were up 1.95 points at 708.60, Value-line was up 1.75 at 652.30, Russell gained 0.10 to 351.0, the Nikkei was down 100.0 at 21530.0, Midcap 400s lost 0.20 to 246.85, and Nasdaq 100 eased 5.20 to 776.00. -Derivatives Desk(312)408-8750/E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
