<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119223" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: McNeil ends deceptive advertising dispute.</title>
<headline>McNeil ends deceptive advertising dispute.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Attorney General said on Wednesday that Johnson &amp; Johnson unit McNeil Consumer Products and the Arthritis Foundation voluntarily agreed to stop alleged deceptive advertising of pain relief products.</p>
<p>Under the settlement, McNeil will pay $250,000 to the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases, an agency of the National Institute of Health. It would pay another $90,000 to each of the 19 states for costs of the investigation, the attorney general said.</p>
<p>In a separate statement, McNeil said the settlement was not an admission of guilt.  </p>
<p>N.Y. Attorney General Dennis Vacco and Pennsylvania Attorney General Tom Corbett said that in a multi-state settlement, McNeil and the Arthritis Foundation agreed to stop claiming that four pain relief products were new or that the Arthritis Foundation helped create them.</p>
<p>McNeil said the settlement did not find McNeil or the Arthritis Foundation violated any state or federal laws or regulations in marketing the products.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision to settle was made solely to avoid an expensive and protracted legal battle for a line of products we no longer market,&quot; McNeil President Brian Perkins said.</p>
<p>Perkins said the marketing agreement with the Arthritis Foundation was developed with high ethical standards and resulted in significant benefits for people with arthritis. They had introduced the products to the market in 1994.</p>
<p>Vacco said the so-called Arthritis Foundation Pain Reliever product line is no more effective than other over-the-counter oral pain releivers.</p>
<p>&quot;By using the Arthritis Foundation name and marketing the product as 'new', McNeil led people to believe that the products were better than other products on the market,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
