<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119252" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ADR REPORT - Latam ADRs sag in New York market.</title>
<headline>ADR REPORT - Latam ADRs sag in New York market.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Latin American companies largely sagged in New York on Wednesday, weighed by concerns about the weakened Mexican peso and the lower U.S. market, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Weakness in Mexico and in New York means weakness all around Latin America,&quot; said Curtis Butler, a senior analyst for emerging markets at Lazard Freres.</p>
<p>In early afternoon 99 of the 441 American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) had recorded advances and 173 had noted declines.  Volume was almost 40 million shares.  </p>
<p>Telefonos de Mexico SA was among the most heavily traded ADRs, falling 3/8 to 30-7/8 on volume of two million shares.  Grupo Televisa also was off 3/8, to 26, on volume of 924,600 shares.</p>
<p>Mexico's peso has been battered recently and economists have said it could fall further against the dollar in the next few weeks before recovering a bit by year's end.</p>
<p>Telecommunications companies Telefonica de Argentina and Telecom Argentina both fell after UBS Securities reduced 1996 earnings per ADR forecasts for them.  </p>
<p>Telefonica was off 1-1/4 to 23-3/8 and Telecom Argentina fell 1-7/8 to 38.</p>
<p>Among European ADRs, Hanson Plc was up 3/8 to seven on volume of 2.05 million shares, boosted by recent positive comments in London's Financial Times newspaper.  The conglomerate is undergoing a demerger.</p>
<p>&quot;Hanson is finally beginning to act like a little bit of a star here after being driven down to pretty low levels,&quot; said Michel Hanigan, head of the global equities desk at SBC Warburg.  </p>
<p>Italian optical giant Luxottica was off 3-5/8 to 63-1/4 on volume of 34,300 shares. Traders said the fall might have been caused by Sunglass Hut International Inc's recent warning of disappointing third-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>-- Ian Simpson, Wall Street desk, (212) 859-1730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
