<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119398" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Harrah's Q3 hurt by competition.</title>
<headline>Harrah's Q3 hurt by competition.</headline>
<dateline>MEMPHIS 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Harrah's Entertainment said on Wednesday its 1996 results were hurt by increasingly competitive markets and construction disruptions.</p>
<p>The casino entertainment company reported third quarter 1996 earnings of $0.41, including a $0.02 per share charge related to the reorganization of a project, against $0.50 per share in the third quarter 1995.</p>
<p>Harrah said its third quarter 1996 operating income was slightly below last year in northern Nevada and that operating income declined 21 percent in southern Nevada.  </p>
<p>Revenues and operating income at Harrah's Lake Tahoe each declined about five percent, the company said.</p>
<p>Results also declined at Harrah's Laughlin due to the overall weak market, it said.</p>
<p>Construction hurt Harrah's Las Vegas, Harrah said. The company said the property was being redone and would be nearly complete by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>Harrah's Atlantic City posted record revenues, although operating income declined 11.1 percent due to increased marketing expenses to combat the competitive market, it said.  </p>
<p>The company said it expected the competitive conditions to continue for the next six to nine months.</p>
<p>Operating income at Harrah's Riverboat Casino division fell 31.9 percent in the third quarter 1996, the company said. Most markets in the area were hurt by increased competition, it said. Harrah's Joliet fell 45.1 percent, partly due a 95 percent increase in the number of slot machines and a 70 percent increase in teh number of table games in the region.</p>
<p>Chicagoland market wide revenues grew 38 percent in the quarter, but the company said this was not enough to offset the increased competition.  </p>
<p>But Harrah's said third quarter 1996 results were helped by the lack of operating losses and interest expense from Harrah's New Orleans, which hurt the third quarter 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strategy of being early to market and pioneering new casinos in riverboat gaming has proven to be a very profitable strategy and value creator for our shareholders,&quot; President and Chief Executive Philip Satre said. &quot;We are now seeing a long-anticipated increase in supply and new competiton converging over the past six months which is putting pressure on our revenues and margins.&quot;</p>
<p>To counter competitive pressures, the company said it was working on product improvement and cost cutting.</p>
<p>Satre said the company was experiencing &quot;growing pains&quot; at its Las Vegas and Atlantic City casinos as it added hotel rooms, restaurants and other amenities.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEMPHIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
