<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119372" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wachovia card charge-offs at 3.22 pct in Q3.</title>
<headline>Wachovia card charge-offs at 3.22 pct in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>WINSTON-SALEM, N.C. 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wachovia Corp's loss rate on its managed credit card portfolio rose to 3.22 percent in the third quarter from 3.15 percent in the second quarter and 2.37 percent in the third quarter of 1995, the bank's chief financial officer said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Wachovia did not break out the credit card loss ratios in its third-quarter earnings release Wednesday,  but Robert McCoy, its chief financial officer, provided the figures in response to a question.  </p>
<p>He also noted that the receivables total was considerably smaller than some of the larger banks.</p>
<p>Citicorp, for example, had $44 billion in managed receivables in its U.S. card business at the end of the 1996 third quarter.</p>
<p>In its earnings release, Wachovia said net loan losses reached $40.7 million, or 0.53 percent of average loans for the 1996 third quarter, compared with $23.1 million, or 0.33 percent, in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>The provision for loan losses was $40.7 million for the quarter, 75.7 percent higher than in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>Wachovia reported net income per fully diluted share of $0.97 for the third quarter, an increase of 11.5 percent from $.87 in the year-earlier period. Net income rose 8.8 percent to $164.6 million from $151.3 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINSTON-SALEM, N.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
