<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119429" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GenRad sees 1996 EPS of at least $1.00.</title>
<headline>GenRad sees 1996 EPS of at least $1.00.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>GenRad Inc chief executive officer James Lyons told analysts in a conference call Wednesday he expected to keep his promise to shareholders of earnings per share of &quot;$1.00 a share or more&quot; in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We have come a long way from the fall of 1993,&quot; when the Concord, Mass.,-based company, was losing money, Lyons said. &quot;We will earn $1.00 a share or more in 1996...Our net worth has turned positive to the tune of $336,000.&quot;</p>
<p>GenRad, which acquired Mitron Corp, Test Technology Associates and Field Oriented Engineering AG (TRACS) in 1996, expects to continue making acquisitions, Lyons said.  </p>
<p>Genrad's vice president of strategic planning, Sarah Lucas, said, &quot;We are actively, agressively looking for acquisitions.&quot; Lyons said he expected the acquisitions would be in the &quot;transaction range of $3 million to $4 million to $5 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of these transactions will be whenever possible pooling, using stock.  Some will be for cash,&quot; Lyons said. &quot;There will be little, if any, dilution to speak of.&quot;</p>
<p>Lyons estimated that earnings per share in 1997 would be no less than $1.25 per share.  </p>
<p>First Call said it had only two analysts' projections for GenRad in 1996 with a consensus of $0.88 a share. Its single projection for 1997 EPS was $1.15.</p>
<p>Lyons said with the positive net worth -- the first time since 1991 GenRad has been in that position -- &quot;We have concluded the financial turnaround&quot; and now GenRad is in the midst of a strategic turnaround.</p>
<p>GenRad, which has 1,150 employees world wide, provides software, systems and services to makers of electronic products.  It has seen a shift in its major customers to telecommunications and contract manufacturers during 1996.</p>
<p>Lyons said International Business Machines Corp has replaced the U.S. Marine Corp as GenRad's third largest customer.</p>
<p>--Leslie Gevirtz, 617-367-4142</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
