<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119446" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sonoco Brazilian consolidation going slower.</title>
<headline>Sonoco Brazilian consolidation going slower.</headline>
<dateline>HARTSVILLE, S.C.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sonoco Products Co said on Wednesday that it was on track to meet its earnings goal of $250 million by the year 2000, but that the consolidation of its Brazilian operations was going slower than expected.</p>
<p>While Sonoco said it was optimistic for the long-term prospects in Brazil, it said the general economy there remained soft.</p>
<p>The company, which announced flat fully-diluted third quarter 1996 earnings of $0.41 per share, said earnings were hurt by costs due to Sonoco's recent initiatives, including closing seven paper converting plants and expanding 20 others.  </p>
<p>Sonoco said it expected positive contributions from these initiatives starting in the fourth quarter 1995.</p>
<p>Internationally, Sonoco said its third quarter was also hurt by the cost of upgrading a recently acquired paper mill in Shanghai, China.</p>
<p>In the consumer packaging unit, the company said it was continuing to integrate and consolidate its label business. Costs associated with this consolidation included a plant closing, severance costs, and inefficiencies resulting from transferring volume among plants.</p>
<p>The company also said it continued to have costs related to installing and starting two new rotogravure presses in its flexible packaging operations and a new press at the carton unit.</p>
<p>But Sonoco said it was on track to double sales and earnings from its 1994 base by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Chairman and Chief Executive Officer C.W. Coker said, &quot;Sonoco's plans for achieving these goals include four key drivers -- globalization of Sonoco's technology, increases in productivity, growth of our U.S. businesses and the continued building of a strong team around a solid culture and value structure.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTSVILLE, S.C."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
