<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119511" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-PGA OF AMERICA NOWS SAYS TIGER BEEN EARNING RYDER POINTS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-PGA OF AMERICA NOWS SAYS TIGER BEEN EARNING RYDER POINTS.</headline>
<dateline>LAKE BUENA VISTA, Florida 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tiger Woods is already on his way to challenging for a berth on the next U.S. Ryder Cup team as the PGA of America said Wednesday it had mis-stated its own rules last week.</p>
<p>Woods's victory in the Las Vegas Invitational on October 6 in his fifth start as a professional boosted the 20-year-old three-time U.S. Amateur champion into 21st place in the Ryder Cup standings.</p>
<p>Last week, the PGA said Woods would not receive Ryder Cup points for the Las Vegas event, stating that he only became eligible for points after becoming a member of the tour, which he officially joined following Las Vegas.</p>
<p>PGA of America media director Julius Mason admitted Wednesday that the PGA had erred, and said a rule had been in place since 1991 to award points to any player joining the tour during a season, retroactive to his first event as a pro.</p>
<p>Mason said Justin Leonard had been helped by the rule in 1994, receiving 60 points retroactively.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't had a phenomenon like Tiger climb the ladder so quickly. He caught us by surprise,&quot; Mason said. &quot;This policy has been in place since '91. It didn't just happen because of Tiger.&quot;</p>
<p>The top 10 finishers at each official PGA Tour event receive Ryder Cup points on a sliding scale.</p>
<p>Woods therefore collects points for the Las Vegas Invitational (first), Texas Open (third), B.C. Open (equal third) and Quad Cities Classic (equal fifth).</p>
<p>He has 125 points. Mark Brooks heads the U.S. standings with 519.75 points.</p>
<p>The leading 10 players after the PGA Championship next August automatically make the U.S. team, while captain Tom Kite selects two others.</p>
<p>Europe will defend the Ryder Cup at Valderrama, Spain, next September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAKE BUENA VISTA, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
