<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119522" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-ITALIAN STRIKER GIVES UP FOR ART'S SAKE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ITALIAN STRIKER GIVES UP FOR ART'S SAKE.</headline>
<dateline>PIACENZA, Italy 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian professional Pierpaolo Curti, a striker for serie C club Fiorenzuola, said on Wednesday he was giving up full-time soccer because it was cramping his style as an aspiring artist.</p>
<p>&quot;My lifetime's ambition was to play as a professional. I have achieved that dream but it has been a rude awakening,&quot; he said. &quot;I realised that a part of me had been wiped out. Too much soccer was stifling my creativity as an artist.&quot;</p>
<p>Club sources said Curti, who wanted to go back to being an amateur soccer player, had held several exhibitions of his paintings and was known in local artistic circles.</p>
<p>&quot;Pierpaolo has made his decision and we can do nothing to change it,&quot; said Fiorenzuola manager Riccardo Francani. &quot;It's a shame because we had great hopes for him.</p>
<p>&quot;He was our bet on the transfer market, having scored 36 goals last season with Soresinese in the amateur league. In the third division he was already showing his quality.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PIACENZA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
