<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119559" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-HOLYFIELD'S SPIRIT AND HEART ARE READY FOR TYSON.</title>
<headline>BOXING-HOLYFIELD'S SPIRIT AND HEART ARE READY FOR TYSON.</headline>
<byline>John Phillips</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Evander Holyfield's recipe for beating Mike Tyson sounds so simple -- inspirational, really -- a combination of a Sunday morning Bible-thumping sermon and a father's classic advice for taking down a schoolyard bully.</p>
<p>The gist of it is, don't let anything anybody says about you shake your spirit. And hit him first.</p>
<p>It is a given that Holyfield will follow the gospel according to Holyfield the warrior and Holyfield the spiritual man against Tyson on November 9.</p>
<p>Holyfield the warrior never met a brawl he didn't like. And Holyfield the Believer genuinely thinks no fighter is better than him, and &quot;I don't let nothing that no one says get into my spirit,&quot; said Holyfield in a telephone conference call from Houston Wednesday.</p>
<p>It is exactly those attributes, plus a monk-like devotion to physical conditioning, that allowed him to take his modest physical gifts as a fighter to the heavyweight championship of the world, twice.</p>
<p>It follows, then, that Holyfield, 33, certainly will be a much more competitive opponent for Tyson than the four assorted humorists he has fought since his parole in March 1995 from prison where he served three years for rape.</p>
<p>But Tyson, 30, is still probably the hardest-punching heavyweight around, and Holyfield has never been the most difficult fighter to hit. Those seem to be reasons enough why he is a longshot to take away Tyson's World Boxing Association title at the MGM Grand in Las Vegas.</p>
<p>How is Holyfield (32-3) going to respond when Tyson likely will rush across the ring at him from the opening bell?</p>
<p>&quot;The big part of anything is your chance is greater to win if you land the first lick,&quot; said Holyfield, who originally was scheduled to fight Tyson in 1991.</p>
<p>But many people believe Holyfield's best chance against Tyson (46-1) is to try to out-box him and take him into the later rounds of their scheduled 12-round fight. Holyfield, though, dismisses any suggestions and comes as close as his gentle, respectful nature will allow to ridiculing them.</p>
<p>Looking to get Tyson into the later rounds &quot;is a losing mentality,&quot; he said. Against Tyson, &quot;most people don't get into the later rounds.&quot;</p>
<p>People who suggest he stay away from Tyson are &quot;not fighting, I'm fighting. They just assume he's the hardest puncher. I'm not gonna let no one that never fought .... judge what my abilities are in the ring. You can't just look at me and tell me what my abilities are,&quot; he said. &quot;You fight your fight.&quot;</p>
<p>Putting aside all of that, &quot;the most important thing is I believe in Christ, and there's just no way he can beat me,&quot; said Holyfield, who was forced by the Nevada State Athletic Commission to pass a rigorous physical examination before they would license him to fight again.</p>
<p>Questions arose about Holyfield's health after he lost two of three grueling fights with Riddick Bowe.</p>
<p>Holyfield refused to demean Tyson the way the champion's camp has attempted to do to Holyfield by saying he had disrespected Tyson. &quot;Team Tyson&quot; insists Holyfield said he would never fight a convicted rapist.</p>
<p>Holyfield matter of factly denied he said that, adding: &quot;I try to respect everybody. If I did (say that) I didn't do it on purpose.&quot;</p>
<p>At a recent news conference, one of Tyson's advisors said, among a string of typically distasteful remarks, &quot;the only rape was gonna be November 9.&quot;</p>
<p>In his usual understated style, Holyfield said, &quot;the game of boxing can use better judgment than&quot; those remarks. The verbal bullying tactics were efforts &quot;to win the fight then and there.&quot;</p>
<p>But Holyfield said he surprised the Tyson camp by reminding them that Tyson still had to show up and fight.</p>
<p>Holyfield said even if the remarks were part of trying to sell tickets to the fight, &quot;you don't have to hype a fight when you have the two best guys there.&quot;</p>
<p>In a reference to Tyson, which also seemed to stand for advice against most bullies, Holyfield said: &quot;We're all people. We respond to pain. It's easy to respond when there's no pressure or any problem ... They love to apply pressure but they can't take it themselves.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
