<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119525" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: RALLYING-SAINZ CLOSES IN ON MCRAE AS SAN REMO RALLY NEARS END.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-SAINZ CLOSES IN ON MCRAE AS SAN REMO RALLY NEARS END.</headline>
<dateline>SAN REMO, Italy 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spaniard Carlos Sainz was closing in on Scot Colin McRae as the San Remo Rally, eighth round of the world championship, entered its final stages on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Subaru driver McRae, 32 seconds ahead of his Spanish rival on Tuesday, held off Sainz on Wednesday's first stage, losing just four seconds on the daunting, 40-km stretch over Monte Ceppo.</p>
<p>Ford driver Sainz was slowed by brake problems for the last four kms but turned the tables to make up 10 seconds on the next stage and reduce the gap behind McRae to 18 seconds with just 80 kms to run.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe I'm getting more used to the car,&quot; suggested Sainz, who had not previously raced the Ford on asphalt.</p>
<p>McRae must finish to guarantee Subaru the lead in the world manufacturers' championship and tyre choice could prove decisive in damp, treacherous conditions.</p>
<p>Subaru's position was weakened when third-placed Italian Piero Liatti's engine failed to restart on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>Swede Kenneth Eriksson was lying third in his Subaru, ahead of Belgian Ford driver Bruno Thiry who lost ground with a poor tyre choice.</p>
<p>The 1,950-km rally was due to finish later on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN REMO, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
