<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119579" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-HAMBURG EXPLOIT SPARTAK MOSCOW'S WEAKNESS IN THE AIR.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HAMBURG EXPLOIT SPARTAK MOSCOW'S WEAKNESS IN THE AIR.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hamburg exploited Spartak Moscow's weakness in the air at the back to clinch an impressive 3-0 victory in their UEFA Cup second round, first leg on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Goals from Andre Breitenreiter, Karsten Baeron and Marijan Kovacevic in the eighth, 39th and 58th minutes helped the Germans take a confident step towards the third round.</p>
<p>Felix Magath's team took the initiative early on when Breitenreiter made a late run into the box to head home a cross from the right.</p>
<p>Six minutes before halftime Baeron extended their lead with a clever chip over the Spartak goalkeeper after a well-worked counter-attack down the right. Kovacevic rose at a corner to head Hamburg's third.</p>
<p>Hamburg are seeking their first triumph in Europe since they won the European Cup in 1983, Magath scoring the only goal in the victory over Juventus.</p>
<p>&quot;We knew they might have a weakness in the air and we managed to take advantage of it,&quot; Magath said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
