<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119589" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-TROUBLED ZAMORANO WANTS TO STAY AT INTER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-TROUBLED ZAMORANO WANTS TO STAY AT INTER.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile international Ivan Zamorano, signed amid much fanfare from Real Madrid this year, said on Wednesday he wanted to stay at Inter despite criticism of his poor form.</p>
<p>The striker, who boasted when he arrived that he had goalscoring in his blood, has yet to find the net in an official match this season and was substituted during Inter's 1-0 UEFA Cup win over Austria's Casino Graz on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Nicknamed &quot;The Terrible&quot;, Zamorano has proved far from terrifying for serie A defenders so far.</p>
<p>The Italian media have speculated that Zamorano, who has played just seven official matches for the club, could return to Spain. Sevilla have been reported to be interested.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to stay at Inter,&quot; Zamorano told reporters at the Inter training ground north of Milan. &quot;I made a difficult decision this summer but I have not changed my mind.</p>
<p>&quot;Many teams wanted me but I chose Inter...It's a difficult time for me, although everyone is behind me...(president Massimo) Moratti, (coach Roy) Hodgson, the team and fans.&quot;</p>
<p>Zamorano, clearly furious at being substituted after just seven minutes of the second half, said he had no complaints about Hodgson and was really angry with himself.</p>
<p>He said his commitments to the Chilean national team, seeking to qualify for the 1998 World Cup finals in France, had weighed heavily on his form because of repeated travelling between Europe and South America.</p>
<p>&quot;I just have to train and play,&quot; he said. &quot;I know people have faith in me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
