<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119627" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: DROSED SETS ISSUE PRICE AT PLN 50.</title>
<headline>DROSED SETS ISSUE PRICE AT PLN 50.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish poultry producer Drosed Siedleckie Zaklady Drobiarskie SA (Drosed) set the price of its forthcoming issue of 150,000 to 300,000 shares at 50 zlotys each, an official from the brokerage offering the shares said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Drosed's) board of directors set the issue price of the 150,000 to 300,000 shares at 50 zlotys -- one price for both of the issue's tranches,&quot; Piotr Kowalczewski of BIG brokerage told a news conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Drosed is offering large investors 110,000 to 250,000 shares and small investors up to 50,000 shares in a public offering from October 21 to 25.</p>
<p>Kowalczewski also said Drosed had signed an agreement with the issue's underwriting consortium stating that consortium member Societe Generale SA would not underwrite shares at the price fixed by the board.</p>
<p>But he said Bank Inicjatyw Gospodarczych SA (BIG) would keep its pledge to underwrite 150,000 shares. At least 160,000 shares must be bought for the issue to be valid.</p>
<p>Previously Societe Generale, BIG and BIG brokerage said they would seek investors and underwrite all 300,000 shares.</p>
<p>Drosed Presdent Ryszard Pietkiewicz said he expected the 150,000 shares not underwritten to be taken up by investors.</p>
<p>Pietkiewicz also said he expected his firm to make a net profit of 5.8 million zlotys this year on sales of 140 million.</p>
<p>Drosed netted 6.1 million zlotys last year.</p>
<p>The company has said this year's profit would be lower because of the modernisation of a plant in Torun, northern Poland, and that its 1997 net would reach 8.6 million zlotys.</p>
<p>Drosed currently has 1.54 million shares outstanding.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41230">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
