<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119617" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - SLOVAKIA - OCT 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SLOVAKIA - OCT 16.</headline>
<text>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - President Michal Kovac leaves for a two day visit to Belgium. On Thursday Kovac will meet with European Commission President Jacques Santer, Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene, European Parliament Chairman Klaus Haensch and NATO Secretary General Javier Solana.</p>
<p>- Parliament Chairman Ivan Gasparovic has convened the next regular parliamentary session for October 22. The preliminary agenda includes a non-confidence vote in Education Minister Eva Slavkovska and six laws returned by President Michal Kovac for revision.</p>
<p>- The government has agreed to create a special pro-export fund to start its activities at the beginning of next year with an initial capital of one billion crowns. About 500 million will be compulsory contributions from all Slovak export-import companies and the other half will be provided by the state.</p>
<p>- Slovak agricultural firms are suffering from a lack of fodder cereals. The association of cereals traders has asked the state market regulation fund to release part of its reserves to cover the current shortage.</p>
<p>- Production of Slovakia's textile and clothing industry has decreased by some 60 percent from the volumes before the collapse of communism in 1989. At present, imports account for about 40 percent of the Slovak textile and clothing market.</p>
<p>- Representatives of construction firm PS Nitra will leave on Thursday for the Russian ethnic region of Ingushetia to resolve the problem of three PS employees kidnapped there. PS officials will meet with Ingush President Ruslan Aushev and Prime Minister Muharbek Didikov.</p>
<p>PRAVDA - Steel producer VSZ plans commercial cooperation with Belgium's Cockerill Sambre Group. Both companies export most of their production to EU countries, and under the cooperation agreement the two firms will establish a joint strategy for selling their products on these markets.</p>
<p>- Germany's Deutsche Bank forecast Slovakia's GDP would grow 5.5 percent in 1996 and 1997. The bank sees inflation at 6.0 percent this year and at 5.5 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - The state-run public transport company SAD s.p., accounting for about 80 percent of the country's passenger transport network, should get 2.5 billion crowns from the next year state budget to help the company restructure before planned privatisation.</p>
<p>- In 1995, Slovakia's sole operating nuclear power plant at Jaslovske Bohunice accounted for 50 percent of the country's electricity production, thermal power stations produced 27.4 percent and hydro-electric plants the remaining 22.6 percent.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-563-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
