<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119671" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - OCT 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - OCT 16.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--Budget: Drastic cutbacks in public expenditures and 13 percent increase in revenues. The government's economic team is facing serious obstacles to drafting the 1997 budget due to differing opinions in the government. The government has yet to decide on basic axes of the economic policy such as new wage scales, the extent of the cutbacks in tax exemptions and restrictions on public expenditures.</p>
<p>--The Iberian model: Spain and Portugal go ahead with impressive privatisation programmes while the Greek government still hesitates, confining moves to selling 10 percent of the State Fuel Organisation (DEP), three banks and a little more of the telecommunications organisation, OTE.</p>
<p>--Bank of Greece to unveil new 200-drachma note to the public tomorrow.</p>
<p>--A six percent increase in building materials index in first quarter 1996 over the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>--Alpha Credit Bank reveals new business loans and increase in share capital in the first quarter of 1997. The tendency at the moment is for larger banking units, president says, predicting that Greece's five large banks will - through mergers - become three.</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--Greece will be obliged in 1998 to submit a &quot;baby-Maastricht&quot; two-year crash convergence programme - in addition to the one currently being followed - to be able to participate in the third phase of Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>-- Twenty-one planned roadworks projects worth 180 billion drachmas will give a boost to the construction industry.</p>
<p>--Development ministry revokes two operating licences for insurance companies for not meeting legal prerequisites.</p>
<p>--Telecommunications organisation, OTE, to decide on up to 11 percent increases in tariffs next week.</p>
<p>--Concern in Athens over rising price of fuel on international markets. Government worried about effect on inflation as domestic prices rise.</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--How to cover the debts of the state? Committee managing the public deficit decides on bond auction next week and issue of T-bills at end of the month to meet needs for the coming month. Three billion drachmas needed by the end of the year.</p>
<p>--National Bank drops interest rate on deferred payments by 2.5 percent.</p>
<p>EXPRESS</p>
<p>--Finance ministry changes objective tax criteria provisions for fairer deal.</p>
<p>--Government to soon take initiatives to tap private investment participation in works subsidised by the Community Support Framework.</p>
<p>--OTE to take decision on mobile phone contract tomorrow. Nine bids on the shortlist.</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--European Commission asks Greece for an additional short-term covergence programme for 1998. European support for the drachma if EMU if public deficit down to 3.0 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
