<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119702" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Details of British government action on guns.</title>
<headline>Details of British government action on guns.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British government on Wednesday announced it was banning almost all handguns after an inquiry into the massacre of 16 Scottish schoolchildren and their teacher by a crazed gunman in March.</p>
<p>The government's response to the inquiry by the senior judge, Lord Douglas Cullen, included the following moves:</p>
<p>- The government will ban all handguns of more than .22 calibre. This will mean that at least 160,000 guns -- 80 percent of those legally held now -- will be destroyed.</p>
<p>- All handguns will be banned from people's homes. Low calibre handguns used for target shooting -- an Olympic sport -- will have to be used and kept in clubs.</p>
<p>- Clubs will have to be licensed after meeting tough, new security limits. &quot;Some handgun clubs may never be able to achieve an adequate level of security. If so they will have to close,&quot; Home Secretary Michael Howard said.</p>
<p>- As &quot;few, if any, existing gun clubs will be able to meet these requirements&quot;, all owners of low calibre handguns will have to hand them in to police for safekeeping until they can find a licensed club which they can join.</p>
<p>- Possessing a low calibre handgun outside a licensed club will carry a maximum penalty of 10 years' imprisonment.</p>
<p>- Mail order selling of guns will be banned. It will also be an offence to sell or destroy a gun without notifying police.</p>
<p>- &quot;Expanding&quot; -- or dum-dum -- ammunition, used in the Dunblane massacre, will be banned except for tightly controlled deer hunting.</p>
<p>- The government will tighten requirements for firearms certificates, including limiting the grounds for appeal, and make it easier for police to revoke a certificate.</p>
<p>- School security will be tightened. The government will introduce grants to help schools pay for this.</p>
<p>- Voluntary youth organisations will be able to check the suitability of leaders and workers, including the possibility of access to criminal records and other police information.</p>
<p>Thomas Hamilton, responsible for the massacre, was an ex-scout leader who ran keep-fit classes and camps for young boys.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
