<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119706" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BAe says Thomson link &quot;good news&quot;.</title>
<headline>BAe says Thomson link &quot;good news&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Aerospace Plc said on Wednesday that the possible inclusion of French electronics giant Thomson SA  in its planned missile joint venture with Matra is &quot;good news.&quot;</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters Financial Television to be broadcast on Thursday, BAe Defence chief executive John Weston said, &quot;this opens up some exciting new possibilities for us to further build on the development of European defence industry consolidation.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier the French government said it would sell Thomson to Matra parent Lagardere Groupe, creating a major new force in the world defence industry and speeding up the process of European consolidation.</p>
<p>The creation of Matra BAe Dynamics, which Weston said should be &quot;fully operational&quot; before the end of the year, would already create Europe's biggest missile maker with annual sales of around $1.5 billion.</p>
<p>Although he declined to forecast sales for an enlarged venture including Thomson, Weston said it would result in &quot;something that is comparable in size to a U.S. company that is similar in size to Raytheon Hughes,&quot; the joint venture between Raytheon Co and Hughes Electronics Corp.</p>
<p>Uncertainty remains over the impact of the Thomson acquisition on BAe's stake in Matra BAe Dynamics. Analysts believe that BAE will either have to cut its 50/50 stake in the joint venture or pay an additional dowry to reflect the greater value of the French side.</p>
<p>&quot;The arrangement we've got with Matra is a 50/50 deal and that won't change,&quot; Weston said. &quot;What would change if they bring extra guided weapons business in on the French side is that we'd have slightly more of the activity in France,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>BAe said it accepted that in the short-term the acquisition of Thomson by Lagardere would give leadership in the missile business to the French, but it did not accept this would be the case in the longer term.</p>
<p>Weston said he expected consolidation in the European industry to continue over the next five to six years as it moved to catch up with giant companies recently created in the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously Germany is an important component in the overall European scene and we would hope that we'd find a way in due course to also form some of the necessary links in Germany,&quot; Weston said.</p>
<p>--Jonathan Birt, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
