<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119787" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Soccer: Australia coach quits for Hiroshima job.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Soccer: Australia coach quits for Hiroshima job.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia coach Eddie Thomson has quit to take up a job as head coach with Japanese J-League soccer side Sanfrecce Hiroshima, the sport's ruling body Soccer Australia said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Thomson, who has been the manager of the national team since June, 1990, will serve three months' notice before leaving on December 31 to take up his new post early in 1997, Soccer Australia said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been an exciting challenge and leaving has been the hardest decision of my life,&quot; Thomson said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is a wonderful career opportunity and my contract with Soccer Australia was up in 1998, anyway,&quot; Thomson said.</p>
<p>Raul Blanco, the coach of Australia's Olympic soccer team will take over as acting national coach while the search is underway for Thomson's successor, Soccer Australia said.</p>
<p>Soccer Australia chairman David Hill said in a statement Thomson had made a &quot;huge&quot; contribution to Australian soccer.</p>
<p>&quot;No time is a good time to lose the national coach in the lead-up to the (1998) World Cup, but the timing is the least damaging because we don't have any World Cup qualifiers until mid next year,&quot; Hill said.</p>
<p>Australia narrowly missed reaching the quarter-finals at the Atlanta Olympics in July, with Spain winning their group match 3-2 after Australia had been ahead 2-1.</p>
<p>Known as &quot;the Socceroos&quot;, Australia have qualified for the World Cup only once, in 1974.</p>
<p>Australian media reported over the past fortnight that Thomson was considering leaving the job to take up a post worth up to A$500,000 (US$395,000) a season with a rich J-League club.</p>
<p>Thomson was cleared in June last year of corruption by a parliamentary inquiry into overseas transfers of Australian players.</p>
<p>The inquiry came after an internal report by the then Australian Soccer Federation which recommended Thomson be sacked for misconduct.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
