<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119839" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe wins IMF support for reforms - minister.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe wins IMF support for reforms - minister.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe has won crucial support from the International Monetary Fund (IMF) for a new reform programme due to be launched later this year, Finance Minister Herbert Murerwa said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>According to the official news agency, ZIANA, Murerwa said IMF managing director Michel Camdessus pledged support for the plan when they met a week ago in Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF has agreed to support us. It would be unusual if they didn't because it would mean we have a strong disagreement,&quot; Murerwa said.</p>
<p>He and finance ministry officials as well as IMF resident representative Robert Franco were unavailable for further comment.</p>
<p>Prospects of Western donor funding for the southern African country's economic reforms were thrown into uncertainty last year when the IMF and the World Bank withheld some aid for its first programme which ended in 1995 after the government failed to meet some cost-saving targets.</p>
<p>This year, the IMF said substantive negotiations for fresh aid for the second phase of reforms would only start later this month after the two international lending bodies had studied Zimbabwe's 1996/97 budget presented in July.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Murerwa told ZIANA: &quot;I met with Michel Camdessus...and World Bank vice-president responsible for Africa (Alisto) Madavo and they were favourable of the framework that was presented. There was a lot of goodwill in all our discusions&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the amount of funding for the new programme -- renamed the Zimbabwe Programme for Economic and Social Transformation (ZIMPREST) from the Economic Structrual Adjustment Programme (Esap) -- was still being worked out.</p>
<p>He said teams from the IMF and the World Bank were expected in the country at the end of the month for further negotiations.</p>
<p>----Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
