<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119835" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerians plan seminar to attract investment.</title>
<headline>Nigerians plan seminar to attract investment.</headline>
<byline>James Jukwey</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Nigerian bank said on Wednesday it was organising workshops in the country next week aimed at aggressively attracting foreign investment into the country.</p>
<p>Nigeria's military government last year backed up its trumpeted opening up of the economy to foreigners with decrees allowing foreign investors unlimited stock in businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of new foreign direct investment is not commensurate with the very positive efforts made so far,&quot; Pascal Dozie, chairman of Diamond Bank told a news conference.</p>
<p>The wholly Nigerian-owned bank is working in conjunction with the Multilateral Investment Guarantee Agency (MIGA), to organise the workshops in Lagos on Monday and Abuja on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Lagos seminar would be attended by MIGA executives and key players in the Nigerian economy while the one in the capital Abuja would attract ministers and public officials.</p>
<p>&quot;The workshop is for Nigerian businesses and the government to know about MIGA and to tap it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>MIGA is a World Bank agency that provides political risk insurance guarantee for foreign investors.</p>
<p>Dozie said since 1991, the agency had issued about $190 million in coverage for over $1.2 billion of foreign investment in nine African nations and was active in 30 countries but that Nigeria was not one of them.</p>
<p>Nigeria's economy, one of Africa's biggest, has been hard hit by political instability, foreign debt of more than $32 billion and long term falling income from its main export, crude oil.</p>
<p>The oil industry is currently operated by multinational oil companies in joint ventures with state-run Nigerian National Petroleum Corp.</p>
<p>Dozie said apart from the oil sector, direct foreign investment in Nigeria was little.</p>
<p>With the oil boom dead, Nigeria has begun wooing foreign investors but so far few have shown interest.</p>
<p>Key measures so far taken include legalisation of the autonomous foreign exchange market where the naira currency freely trades while dividends or profits from foreign investments can now be transferred abroad.</p>
<p>Dozie said the planned privatisation of state-owned power and telecommunications firms would attract foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;When Ghana privatised Ashanti Goldmines it shook the world. We have such projects and that is what will happen if the oil refineries, the electricity and telecommunications companies are floated,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nigeria has been in turmoil since June 1993 when the military annulled a presidential election.</p>
<p>--Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
