<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119936" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's 97 budget deficit non-negotiable - minister.</title>
<headline>Russia's 97 budget deficit non-negotiable - minister.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economy Minister Yevgeny Yasin, responding to parliament's rejection of the 1997 draft budget, said on Wednesday that he would change the budget, but would not increase the budget deficit.</p>
<p>&quot;Under no circumstances is it possible to increase the budget deficit,&quot; he told reporters after the Duma lower house of parliament rejected the draft and asked for changes to key figures. &quot;I don't see any room for concession on this issue.</p>
<p>&quot;Stepping up borrowing would disrupt the entire process of resuming economic growth and restoring Russia's economy.&quot;</p>
<p>The draft had spending of 524.34 trillion roubles, revenues of 433.64 trillion roubles and a deficit of 90.70 trillion, or 3.3 percent of the gross domestic product.</p>
<p>&quot;We have very little room for manoeuvering with regard to reducing key budget parameters,&quot; Yasin said, adding that projected revenues and spending could both be cut.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Alexander Livshits had said earlier that he would re-submit a tighter budget.</p>
<p>&quot;We will reduce incomes, spending and maybe the deficit. We are being asked to meet the president's budget outline and that has a deficit of three percent (of GDP), while we have 3.3 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Julie Tolkacheva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
