<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119922" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Shares in Czech SPT telecom tumble at midday.</title>
<headline>Shares in Czech SPT telecom tumble at midday.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in SPT Telecom, the most heavily capitalised share on the Prague bourse, took a nose dive on Wednesday morning with dealers saying the situation on the over-the-counter (OTC) market was even worse.</p>
<p>At 1220 local time (1020 GMT) SPT was down 80 crowns to 3,010 on the Reuters RPIX index of continuously traded Czech shares. One month ago the issue was 350 crowns, 11.6 percent, higher at 3,360.</p>
<p>&quot;On the OTC market it even went below the 3,000 level shortly before 1100 (local time); just now it's bouncing back a little bit,&quot; said Petr Koblic, a trader at Zivnostenska Banka in Prague.</p>
<p>The decline in SPT Telecom's share price is seen by analysts and traders as reflecting the general decline in interest in the Czech equity market rather than company fundamentals.</p>
<p>The Czech capital markets are routinely criticised, especially by foreign investors, for their lack of transparency and the absence of adequate protection of minority shareholders' rights.</p>
<p>Koblic said it was difficult to predict which way SPT would go the rest of this week but he doubted whether the small recovery on the OTC market seen after the fall below 3,000 crowns a share was anything other than a small upward correction.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people are saying right now that SPT is going to go up but somebody had better prove it. I don't believe it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Robin Shepherd, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
