<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="119958" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian shares edge down, seen up after breather.</title>
<headline>Russian shares edge down, seen up after breather.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Russian shares edged down on Wednesday as local brokers took profits and foreign buyers stayed out of the market, but some traders said prices would rise after a few days' breather.</p>
<p>The Russian Trading System index of 24 shares fell by 2.03 percent to 186.14 on $22.57 million in volume.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices have been falling all day,&quot; said Alexei Genkin, manager of international sales at IK Alfa-Capital.</p>
<p>&quot;There were practically no international buyers. Russian brokers understood that they had nothing else to wait for and started taking profits.&quot;</p>
<p>Nick Mokhoff of Alliance-Menatep said prices would fluctuate in a two to three percent range over the next few days.</p>
<p>Dealers said western investors had cheered news that President Boris Yeltsin would undergo a heart operation in mid-November, earlier than some estimates.</p>
<p>Genkin predicted that an American Depositary Share issue for natural gas monopoly Gazprom, due shortly, would be oversubscribed and drive the market up.</p>
<p>Gazprom plans to make an ADRs issue and its lead managers said last week that the preliminary price for the international offering will be between $14.00 and $16.00. One ADS covers ten ordinary shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Real investors will continue holding Russian shares,&quot; Genkin said.</p>
<p>&quot;They believe in Russia and for them there is no sense to leave the market now.&quot;</p>
<p>Truck maker KamAZ was among the losers of the day after the government decided to start bankruptcy cases against the company for alleged tax evasion, he added.</p>
<p>KamAZ fell to $1.23 from $1.30 at Tuesday's close, LUKoil edged down to $10.26 from $10.47, Rostelekom dropped to $2.66 after 2.73, UES fell to $0.0823 from $0.0837 and Norilsk Nickel ticked down to $6.25 after $6.26.</p>
<p>--Julie Tolkacheva, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
