<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120053" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Oct 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Oct 16.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Wednesday morning's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- Police have arrested Klement Kolaneci, the son-in-law of late communist dictator Enver Hoxha, and have questioned him about his alleged links with a suspected extremist group.</p>
<p>- Five opposition parties, including the key Socialists, have written to President Sali Berisha insisting that voting in Sunday's local elections should end at 6 p.m. (16:00 GMT) instead of 9 p.m. (1900 GMT).</p>
<p>- Socialist International vice president Nicola Zingaretti has confirmed the group's support for the opposition Socialist Party in Sunday's local polls.</p>
<p>- Victor Ruffy, the head of the Council of Europe delegation that will coordinate the monitoring of Albania's local polls, says the elections and the preceding campaign are a test of the country's commitment to democracy.</p>
<p>- An opposition member of the Central Elections Commission says the chairman has blocked the commission by not allowing a vote on several issues.</p>
<p>- The World Trade Organisation (WTO) has told Albania it must liberalise its trade according to WTO principles before it can become a member of the organisation.</p>
<p>- Tirana district court has ruled that 13 suspects should stay in jail during an investigation into the killing of the general director of prisons and two bank robberies.</p>
<p>- Villagers living near a cement factory in Fushe-Kruje have blocked the use of pesticides by the plant.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- Albania will not allow observers from the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe's main monitor body, the Office of Democratic Institutions and Human Rights, to oversee Sunday's local polls. An OSCE spokesman said Albania considered the organisation's list of monitors unacceptable.</p>
<p>- Albania's local polls will be watched by 535 foreign observers.</p>
<p>- The paper says members of an alleged terrorist band accused of killing the general director of prisons are also suspected of planting a bomb that killed four and wounded 27 in central Tirana last year.</p>
<p>- Albania's national soccer team coach, Neptun Bajko, has resigned after last week's 3-0 loss to Portugal in a World Cup qualifier.</p>
<p>RILINDJA DEMOKRATIKE</p>
<p>- Albanian President Sali Berisha says local polls on October 20 will be a proof of the country's adherence to western standards.</p>
<p>ZERI I POPULLIT</p>
<p>- Albania's jailed Socialist Party leader, Fatos Nano, says a victory for the Socialist Party or the progressive opposition in Sunday's local polls would be a step towards solving the political stalemate after controversial general elections in May and June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
