<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120032" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: FORECAST - Hungary think-tank sees rising GDP.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Hungary think-tank sees rising GDP.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eighteen months of economic stabilisation efforts is likely to help Hungary achieve quicker growth rates from the end of 1996, the economic think-tank GKI Gazdasagkutato Rt said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Hungary has improved imbalances of its current account and state budget and won the confidence of international investors but other conditions of sustainable growth are still missing, GKI General Director Andras Vertes told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Certain conditions of economic growth have appeared but others have not or hardly,&quot; GKI said in a statement.</p>
<p>Economic policies still do not provide sufficient encouragement for domestic companies to invest in development and the budget reforms are slow, it added.</p>
<p>GKI forecast that the gross domestic product (GDP) is likely to increase by a maximum of 0.5 percent this year, but the growth rate will be 2.5 percent in 1997 even without any special economic policy measures.</p>
<p>The think-tank expects consumption of the population to drop three percent in 1996 but to rise one percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Businesses and individuals already see an improving economic climate which will help investment to increase by two percent this year and 10 percent in 1997, GKI said.</p>
<p>Industrial output is likely to rise by three percent this year and five to six percent next year, GKI said.</p>
<p>However, increasing domestic demand may worsen the 1997 current account and its deficit may even rise over GKI's forecast of up to $2 billion, compared with the government projection of $1.5 billion, Vertes said.</p>
<p>This year the current account deficit will be probably smaller than the government expected, at $1.6 billion to $1.8 billion from last year's $2.5 billion, he added.</p>
<p>However, the general government deficit may reach 4.5 percent of GDP in 1996, Vertes said, which would be above the four percent rate agreed with the International Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>The country has gone very far in reducing consumption in the past 18 months and the 4.5 percent rate is approximately average for the European Union, Vertes said.</p>
<p>GKI said the 1997 general government deficit should be between 4.5 and five percent but if economic policies ahead of the 1998 elections softened, the rate could increase.</p>
<p>The think-tank added the 1997 budget revenue target could be questionable as the planned wider base of social security contributions may drive more employees into the black economy.</p>
<p>GKI said inflation was likely to drop to 20 percent next year, compared with the 18 percent government target, from 23.5 to 24 percent this year.</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
