<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120007" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Council of Europe official voices concern in Belarus.</title>
<headline>Council of Europe official voices concern in Belarus.</headline>
<byline>Yuri Svirko</byline>
<dateline>MINSK 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Council of Europe official Leni Fischer warned President Alexander Lukashenko on Wednesday that his plans to increase his own powers might divide the former Soviet republic of Belarus.</p>
<p>And Parliamentary Speaker Semyon Sharetsky told Fischer that violence might break out during pro- and anti-Lukashenko rallies this weekend.</p>
<p>Fischer, head of the Council of Europe's parliamentary assembly, was in Belarus to discuss its application to join the 39-nation body which promotes democracy and human rights.</p>
<p>She told parliament, at loggerheads with Lukashenko over a referendum to extend his term, that there was &quot;serious concern&quot; in the Council at the constitutional crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;I call on the leadership of your country to try again to find a compromise and not to confuse the nation,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;Any attempt to bypass a parliament should be avoided because this can split a nation. I hope that your constitution will be faithfully respected and followed,&quot; Fischer said.</p>
<p>Lukashenko has served half the five-year term he is allowed by the constitution but is seeking another five years without elections in a referendum he wants to hold on November 7.</p>
<p>The 41-year-old leader was in Moscow on Wednesday, meeting President Boris Yeltsin and discussing integration with Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;The presidents said they favoured a consolidation of society on the basis of compromise, corresponding to the demands of a legitimate, democratic path of development,&quot; Yeltsin's press service said.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, elected on a platform of fighting corruption and re-building ties with Russia, has drawn criticism from parliament and nationalists for signing a pact to create a &quot;community&quot; with Russia.</p>
<p>Up to 200 people were given short jail terms after mass rallies last spring led to clashes with police.</p>
<p>Another major demonstration is expected on Saturday to coincide with an &quot;All-Belarus&quot; congress being held by Lukashenko to garner support for his referendum.</p>
<p>Speaker Sharetsky, the country's second highest political figure, met Fischer and told her Lukashenko was running a dictatorship.</p>
<p>&quot;I await with fear the events of October 18 and 19. Yesterday my deputy said he expected bloodshed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Deputies, who according to the constitution must approve the date of any referendum, have twice rejected Lukashenko's plan to hold the vote on a new draft constitution on November 7.</p>
<p>Lukashenko is also seeking authority to appoint one-third of the members of a new upper house of parliament. Deputies have instead called a vote for November 24 -- on a constitution abolishing the post of president.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
