<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120170" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil proposes corporate income tax overhaul.</title>
<headline>Brazil proposes corporate income tax overhaul.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Finance Minister Pedro Malan presented a new corporate income tax bill which he said would make life easier for taxpayers and harder for tax dodgers.</p>
<p>The new bill, which is part of a general overhaul of the tax system and will be sent to Congress later on Wednesday, should not alter current tax pressure on companies but is designed to increase the tax base.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim of the bill is to make life easier for tax payers and harder for tax dodgers,&quot; Malan said in a news conference in which he introduced the new bill.  </p>
<p>The new bill also includes measures to close a loophole in Brazil's tax legislation that allowed foreign companies to alter prices they pay for imported and exported goods and pay less tax.</p>
<p>The biggest change for Brazilian companies is a move to make corporate tax payable on a quarterly basis as opposed to the existing monthly system.</p>
<p>National tax Secretary Everardo Maciel outlined several measures to help in identification and prosecution of corporate tax dodgers.</p>
<p>&quot;These are tough rules which we will use on the most skillful tax dodgers,&quot; Maciel said.</p>
<p>-- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom 5561 223 0358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
