<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120199" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Another Australian minister has share problem.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Another Australian minister has share problem.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Finance Minister John Fahey may have misled the parliament and Prime Minister John Howard regarding his shareholding in a private firm, according to media reports on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Australian Financial Review newspaper reported that Fahey had declared a 50 percent stake in Tunboa Pty Ltd to the New South Wales state parliament in 1995 as well as in nine earlier annual registrations of his interests lodged after 1986.</p>
<p>But Fahey told both Howard and parliament on Wednesday that he sold his stake in August 1986.  </p>
<p>Fahey said the buyer had failed to register the transfer. The latest share controversy arose after it was revealed on Wednesday that Fahey had failed to declare the Tunboa holding in the Lower House's pecuniary interest records.</p>
<p>&quot;In defence of his failure to list the Tunboa interest in his House of Representatives pecuniary interest records, Mr Fahey said he had disposed of his shareholding, although Australian Securities Commission records showed he still owned half the company,&quot; the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Fahey later put the discrepancy down to &quot;an oversight&quot; on the minister's part.  </p>
<p>&quot;Having been recorded there (on the NSW register) initially, it remained there and he continued to sign it throughout,&quot; the spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Two junior members of the government resigned earlier this week, saying they had taken ministerial decisions regarding companies in which they held shares.</p>
<p>Those incidents were regarded as a breach of Howard's ministerial guidelines, under which government members are required to divest any investments that could conflict with their portfolio area.  </p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Tim Fischer is under fire regarding shares he owned until last week which may have conflicted with his trade portfolio, while Industry Minister John Moore is defending himself over his stock in a venture capital company.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
