<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120146" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine president says Cavallo's graft charges lies.</title>
<headline>Argentine president says Cavallo's graft charges lies.</headline>
<byline>David Haskel</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine President Carlos Menem on Wednesday dismissed as lies charges by former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo that two cabinet ministers covered up corruption and manipulated judges.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course that's a lie,&quot; he told foreign correspondents.</p>
<p>Cavallo, who first denounced &quot;mafias&quot; in ruling Peronist Party circles a year ago, on Tuesday said Interior Minister Carlos Corach had tried to remove a judge from investigating a gold-export fraud case and replace him with another magistrate &quot;who failed to find any crime committed by gold exporters.&quot;</p>
<p>Both Corach and Justice Minister Elias Jassan were manipulating judges and state prosecutors, alleged Cavallo, the architect of Argentina's economic reform plan.</p>
<p>But Menem, who last July sacked his &quot;superminister&quot; after one too many brawls over his austerity policies, told reporters: &quot;Let's not get confused, for God's sake. Cavallo is no longer in the government. He is now in the opposition.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are no mafias in the government,&quot; Menem said.</p>
<p>Cavallo, who last week announced he will run for Congress in 1997, but not for Menem's Peronist Party, said the two ministers had made self-incriminating comments but he had no tape recordings or documentation on the alleged conversations.</p>
<p>&quot;It's my word against those of the two ministers,&quot; Cavallo said at a dinner at New York University, where he is teaching economics. &quot;It's a question of credibility -- do the people believe in what I say or in what they say?&quot;</p>
<p>Local Argentine bonds fell early on Wednesday on worries about the political consequences of the attacks. But Menem brushed aside those concerns, saying, &quot;Markets fell everywhere in the world. I don't think it is because of Cavallo.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement issued on Tuesday, Corach rejected the charges, calling them &quot;totally irresponsible and reflecting (Cavallo's) state of emotional imbalance.&quot; He also said he would take legal action.</p>
<p>Federal Judge Adolfo Bagnasco challenged Cavallo to come forth with a napkin on which he claims Corach once wrote the names of several judges and state prosecutors and bragged, &quot;These do as I say.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;All else is heresay, resembling more a Mexican soap opera than any other thing,&quot; the judge said.</p>
<p>Menem also dismissed as mere electioneering charges by another former aide, former Interior Minister Gustavo Beliz, who said this week that many Argentines saw Menem &quot;almost&quot; as the head of alleged mafias infiltrating the government.</p>
<p>&quot;These two ministers (Cavallo and Beliz) are referring to totally non-existent mafias,&quot; said Menem, who did not rule out legal action against Beliz.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
