<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120184" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: AMP Investments NZ returns 2.7 pct in Sept qtr.</title>
<headline>AMP Investments NZ returns 2.7 pct in Sept qtr.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>AMP Investments NZ said on Thursday it had a 2.7 percent gross return in the September quarter for its balanced medium-risk fund against 5.0 percent in the year ago quarter.</p>
<p>Return for the low risk fund was 3.0 percent and the high risk was 2.1 percent.</p>
<p>For the year to September the low, medium and high risk funds returned 10.8 percent, 10.3 percent and 10.4 percent respectively. June year returns were 11.8, 12.8 and 15.3 percent respectively.  </p>
<p>High cash balances have been key to AMP funds maintaining returns above 10 percent for the year to September, AMP Investments managing director Roger Greville said.</p>
<p>Greville said the cornerstone of AMP's investment strategy was to retain higher than normal cash exposure to take advantage of the historically high short-term interest rates seen during the past year.</p>
<p>&quot;Maintaining high cash balances gives us the best of both worlds -- extremely attractive interest rates for little risk in the immediate future and the flexibility to move money very quickly into markets or investment segments where attractive investment opportunities exist,&quot; Greville said.</p>
<p>AMP is the country's largest private investor with around NZ$6 billion under management, 75 percent of that invested in New Zealand assets.</p>
<p>Greville said the company remained optimistic that better-than-average returns were available from New Zealand assets so long as sound fiscal and monetary policies remained in place.</p>
<p>New Zealand property had given AMP's clients a 14.7 percent return over the year and the outlook for commercial property remained sound.  </p>
<p>Despite the sharemarket's recent rally, stocks were also not overpriced, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, since 30 September and before the election, AMP Investments increased its exposure to New Zealand equities by taking some four percent out of its cash deposits. Since that move the New Zealand sharemarket has risen by around 4.5 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Greville said the gross fund returns were about 2.5 percent better than would have been achieved through passive management.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
