<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120216" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Oct 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Oct 17.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>A Nihon Keizai Shimbun survey of companies in the United States, Europe, Japan and Hong Kong shows more than 90 percent of these companies' Hong Kong units are considering either maintaining or expanding their business in Hong Kong and China after the colony reverts to Chinese sovereignty next year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Mitsui &amp; Co Ltd has signed a contract with U.S. network National Broadcasting Co (NBC) to sell advertising time on NBC satellite and cable television. Mitsui will handle all Japanese corporate advertising placed on NBC's 24-hour news service and other programmes broadcast to 75 countries. Mitsui is expected to spend about 500 million yen in the first year, and this is expected to jump to more than 10 billion yen within five years.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Daishowa Paper Manufacturing Co Ltd is expected to have increased its parent current profit by 2.5 times from a year ago to 10 billion yen in the half-year ended September 30, helped by a fall in the price of raw materials.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Semiconductor companies and major users of 16-megabit dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chips have agreed with suppliers to a price range of 980 to 1,100 yen per microchip for October shipments, which is about the same level as last month's.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Itoham Foods Inc plans to start a large-scale hog farm in the United States next year in a joint venture with trading firm Marubeni Corp. Itoham aims to start shipping 100,000 hogs annually, expanding this number to 600,000 by the end of 2000. It hopes to initially sell the pork in the U.S. market, and to later ship processed pork back to Japan. Total investment will be more than eight billion yen.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
