<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120248" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Only five foreign firms quality for S$ listing -TV.</title>
<headline>Only five foreign firms quality for S$ listing -TV.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Just five of the 40 foreign firms trading on the Stock Exchange of Singapore would qualify to list their shares in Singapore dollars under new rules announced this week, state television said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Richard Hu said on Tuesday foreign firms would be able to convert their shares, which must currently be quoted in foreign currencies, into Singapore-dollar denominated stocks, provided they met a series of conditions.</p>
<p>The conditions included having an operating track record in Singapore of at least two years and having the senior management of the company located in Singapore.  </p>
<p>But state televison quoted analysts as saying most companies failed to meet another key condition: that 35 percent of their revenue, profits or expenses should be attributable to their Singapore operations.</p>
<p>Only five cmpanies would currently meet all the conditions, it said.</p>
<p>These were: Acer Computer International Ltd, Clipsal Industries Holdings Ltd, Datacraft Asia Ltd, Elec &amp; Eltek International Co Ltd and GP Batteries International Ltd.  </p>
<p>State televison said the most likely contender for conversion to Singapore dollars was Datacraft. However, it quoted Datacraft's managing director Des Althorp as saying the company might keep its shares in U.S. dollars.</p>
<p>The company was trading successfully in U.S. dollars and Datacraft's investors, mostly institutional, indicated they prefered to trade in that currency, he said.</p>
<p>State television quoted analysts as saying the 35 percent criterion may be eased in future. This would encourage more foreign companies to have initial public offerings in Singapore, it added.  </p>
<p>Hu announced the measures in a move designed to boost Singapore's role as a regional centre for securities trading.</p>
<p>Foreign companies have complained in the past that their non-Singapore dollar stocks have received only limited attention from Singapore domestic investors because of fears of potential foreign exchange risks.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703199)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34320">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
