<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120434" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: China bans U.S. poultry imports from 10 states.</title>
<headline>China bans U.S. poultry imports from 10 states.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has banned imports of poultry from 10 U.S. states because of fears the birds carry a fowl plague, the U.S. Agriculture Department said Wednesday.</p>
<p>The ban threatens an export market worth about $500 million a year.</p>
<p>&quot;Effective yesterday, China has banned imports of live poultry and poultry meat from 10 states,&quot; said John Reddington, director of the department's Dairy, Livestock and Poultry division.</p>
<p>The states affected are Arkansas, Florida, Maryland, Minnesota, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Texas, Utah and Wisconsin.</p>
<p>Chinese authorities had voiced fears the poultry products carried a virus called highly pathogenic avian influenza, or HPAI.</p>
<p>Reddington said the department was sending a technical team to Beijing to try to clear up apparent confusion on the part of China over the difference between HPAI and avian influenza, or AI.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe there's some confusion by the Chinese over the type of avian influenza that China has allegedly discovered,&quot; Reddington said.</p>
<p>Reddington said there had been no cases of HPAI in the United States since the early 1980s.</p>
<p>A U.S. quarantine official based in China told Reuters last week that the virus could not be transmitted to people who ate the meat of infected birds.</p>
<p>China is the second-biggest market in the world, after Russia, for U.S. poultry products. It is the only market for U.S. chicken feet.</p>
<p>U.S. poultry exports to China in 1995 totalled 330,000 tons transshipped through Hong Kong alone, worth $445 million, according to the U.S. Poultry and Egg Export Council.</p>
<p>Every day thirty 23-ton containers of U.S. chicken feet crossed the border from Hong Kong into China, according to the council's spokeswoman, Sarah Li.</p>
<p>An official at the U.S. embassy in Beijing said the AI virus was common worldwide, particularly in wild fowl, but was not present in commercial poultry flocks in the United States.</p>
<p>Another U.S. official said the AI virus may have been detected in ostriches imported from the United States as breeding stock on Chinese ostrich farms.</p>
<p>&quot;Ostrich raising in China has become very popular and a lot of the breeding stock is brought in from the U.S.,&quot; the marketing official said.</p>
<p>Officials of China's Administration of Animal and Plant Quarantine and the U.S. Embassy in Beijing met Tuesday in an effort to resolve the issue, the embassy official said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a frank, candid and open meeting -- they listened to us and agreed that we should talk more about it, which we will as soon as possible,&quot; the official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41230">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
