<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120546" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conn. says new Mohegun Sun casino exceeds forecast.</title>
<headline>Conn. says new Mohegun Sun casino exceeds forecast.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Connecticut on Wednesday said that gamblers at the new Mohegun Sun casino, which opened over the weekend in the southeastern part of the state, pumped more than twice as much cash into slot machines as expected.</p>
<p>While cautioning the results from the casino's first two days were incomplete and this was too short a period to judge the resort's performance, the Connecticut official said that if they continued, the state would benefit handsomely.</p>
<p>&quot;In terms of what we had estimated for the Moheguns, this could literally double the revenue estimates,&quot; said the official, who declined to be named. He also pointed out that the number of people who came to the casino likely was inflated by the three-day U.S. Colombus Day holiday.</p>
<p>Connecticut had been figuring that its second casino, which opened on October 12 and is located only 10 miles from the older and bigger Mashantucket Pequot Foxwood Resort, would produce around $750,000 a day.</p>
<p>Instead, the new slot machines collected $1.45 million in change on October 12, the day the Mohegun Sun casino opened, and $1.68 million the next day. These totals are expected to rise because they do not include the amount of money gamblers spent using bills instead of small change.</p>
<p>Further, the state said that the Foxwoods casino's earings were not dented by the new competition, as it attracted a record number of customers. Its slot machines collected $2.9 million in change on Saturday, the only day for which its preliminary data were available.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody did extremely well,&quot; the state official concluded.</p>
<p>For the state's 1996 fiscal year, Connecticut estimates that the Mohegun casino will produce a net win of $210 million, sending the state $57 million. The term net win is defined as how much the casino keeps as a percentage of the total amount that is bet.</p>
<p>And the four-year old Foxwoods is projected to generate a net win of almost $555 million, sending nearly $139 million to the state.</p>
<p>Foxwood's revenues declined in September, as is typical after the summer ends, with the resort's producing almost $50.5 million, down from $63.5 million in the previous month, the state official said.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
