<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120765" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Nationwide French strike starts on railways.</title>
<headline>Nationwide French strike starts on railways.</headline>
<byline>Brian Love</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>French railwayworkers began a partial strike late on Wednesday, kicking off nationwide stoppages expected throughout Thursday in schools, hospitals, trains and other services.</p>
<p>The rail strike, which began at 1800 GMT on Wednesday and was due to run until 0600 GMT on Friday, was expected to curb between 30 and 60 percent of train services.</p>
<p>The London-Paris Eurostar train under the English Channel was however due to provide full service.</p>
<p>The strikes are against government cutbacks and record unemployment and are the first big wave of labour unrest since crippling strikes in late 1995.</p>
<p>Government offices and agencies face disruption or closure for the day and workers at the state-owned gas and electricity companies will also stop work, but power cuts are not expected.</p>
<p>Postal workers will also join the action.</p>
<p>The 24-hour strike is spearheaded by civil servants fighting government plans to trim their numbers by nearly 6,000 next year as part of a wider drive to get French finances in order so as to qualify for monetary union and a single European currency.</p>
<p>Teachers will bear the brunt of the austerity drive, with a loss of 2,300 permanent jobs and the layoff of some 15,000 short-term contract staff.</p>
<p>The other motive is frustration over record 12.6 percent unemployment, with more than three million jobless despite President Jacques Chirac's May 1995 election pledge to make employment his top priority.</p>
<p>A poll due to appear in Thursday's Parisien daily shows 64 percent of those polled support or sympathise with the strike.</p>
<p>Opposition Socialist leader Lionel Jospin backed the strikes on Wednesday, accusing Prime Minister Alain Juppe's conservative coalition of a &quot;social and economic error which is dragging France into a tailspin&quot;.</p>
<p>While the CFDT, the largest trade union, and other labour leaders have yet to discuss plans beyond Thursday's strikes and demonstrations, the Communist-led CGT is already trying to muster support for follow-up action.</p>
<p>Labour Minister Jacques Barrot pleaded with civil servants to avoid any action that could damage the French economy -- clearly mindful of the public sector strikes which crippled France for 24 days last November and December.</p>
<p>&quot;I cannot believe they do not feel, at the bottom of their hearts, their loyalty to the rest of the country,&quot; Barrot said. He asked civil servants to &quot;know just where to stop, when the French economy would hurt too much&quot;.</p>
<p>The seven main civil service unions have organised a march in central Paris on Thursday from the Place de la Republique.</p>
<p>Jospin urged Socialist party members to join the demonstrations which will be led by Nicole Notat, head of the CFDT, Marc Blondel, vociferous government critic and head of the Force Ouvriere union, and CGT leader Louis Viannet.</p>
<p>Viannet called for a halt to job-cutting by French firms, said he would do everything to forge a solid front among the unions and warned of future action. &quot;It's clear the month of November will bring new developments,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A strike by air traffic controllers and staff at airlines Air France and Air Inter Europe is expected to cause serious disruption, mainly for medium-haul flights.</p>
<p>Air Inter alone will cut its total flights from 500 to 110, while a skeleton service by air traffic controllers will hit international flights and delay flights through French airspace. British Airways is cutting flights from Paris to four from the usual 46.</p>
<p>Doctors will also protest for 24 hours on Thursday over government health care reforms.</p>
<p>Some disruption is also expected on Paris buses, the Metro underground rail service and the suburban RER commuter lines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
