<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="120780" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac to address Palestinian council, revive port.</title>
<headline>Chirac to address Palestinian council, revive port.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac will become the first foreign leader to address the Palestinian Legislative Council next week during a six-day tour of the tense Middle East region, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Seeking to assert a greater French and European role in the region, Chirac will address the 88-strong elected assembly in the West Bank town of Ramallah next Wednesday.</p>
<p>French officials said the gesture would symbolise support for Palestinian aspirations to statehood despite Israeli opposition, but also backing for parliamentary democracy against any &quot;autocratic temptation&quot;.</p>
<p>Chirac will fly with Palestinian President Yasser Arafat to the Gaza Strip, visit a refugee camp and lay a foundation stone for a disputed Gaza sea port project, they said.</p>
<p>The French president will be the second European leader to lay a stone for the uncertain $60 million project on the Gaza coastline, stymied by Israeli security objections.</p>
<p>Dutch Prime Minister Wim Kok laid the first stone in January. The Netherlands is the biggest donor in the project with $25 million to France's $20 million. Germany will donate the remaining $15 million.</p>
<p>Palestinian and Israeli sources said that although the port was agreed in Israeli-PLO accords, the Israelis object to it on security grounds, since it would give the Palestinians uncontrolled access to the sea.</p>
<p>The sources say Israel may also have economic and political motives for blocking the port, since Palestinan goods are currently forced to transit through Israel's port of Ashdod, giving the Jewish state valuable control.</p>
<p>A hasty attempt by Arafat's Palestinian Authority to build a marina for Gaza fishermen in 1994 foundered shortly after Arafat returned from exile, wrecked by winter storms. A mangled, rusting pier near his beachfront office is all that remains.</p>
<p>Chirac will spend a day in the Palestinian self-rule areas after visiting Syria on Saturday and Sunday for talks with President Hafez al-Assad, and Israel on Monday and Tuesday, where he will meet Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and make a major speech on French Middle East policy in the city of Haifa.</p>
<p>A French diplomat called Chirac's trip the most difficult of his 18 months in office. He aims seek a political role for the European Union in Middle East peacemaking despite U.S. and Israeli objections.</p>
<p>The Europeans were excluded from this month's emergency Arab-Israeli summit in Washington and U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher wrote to EU leaders urging them to stay out of the Israeli-Palestinian negotiations, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The French argue that the EU is the main financial sponsor of the peace process and can offer useful proposals and good offices without supplanting Washington as mediator. Many Arab leaders see the EU as more even-handed than the United States.</p>
<p>To avoid a clash with hardline Netanyahu, neither Chirac nor Foreign Minister Herve de Charette will visit Orient House in Arab East Jerusalem, the PLO's unofficial headquarters in the city, which Israel has vowed to close, the sources said.</p>
<p>However Chirac will visit Christian and Moslem holy places in the Arab Old City without the Israeli mayor of Jerusalem, Ehud Olmert, underlining the fact that France does not recognise Israeli sovereignty over the eastern half of the city, annexed after it was captured from Jordan in 1967.</p>
<p>After the Palestinian territories, Chirac will make brief visits to Jordan, Lebanon and Egypt on October 24-25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
