<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121038" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian union says GM ready to recognize outsourcing limits.</title>
<headline>Canadian union says GM ready to recognize outsourcing limits.</headline>
<byline>Paul Casciato</byline>
<dateline>OSHAWA, Ontario 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp. is prepared for the first time to recognise limits on the amount of work which can be contracted out, or outsourced, Canadian Auto Workers union President Buzz Hargrove said Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;They are now prepared to recognise that they are going to leave this bargaining table with limits (on outsourcing),&quot; Hargrove told about 160 striking workers occupying a GM fabrication plant in Oshawa, about 30 miles (50 km) east of Toronto.</p>
<p>The Canadian union leader said the compromise emerged from a closed-door meeting he had with GM Chief Executive Jack Smith at a hotel near Toronto's airport this morning.</p>
<p>In return, Hargrove said, the union is ready to agree that GM is in a different financial position than that of the other two big North American automakers, Ford Motor Co. and Chrysler Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;The union is prepared to recognise that they (GM) are different,&quot; Hargrove said.</p>
<p>Talks between the two sides have foundered since the strike began around midnight Oct 2. GM had refused to agree to the outsourcing limits laid out in the pattern contract reached by Chrysler and the CAW in September.</p>
<p>Reporters inside the Oshawa plant where workers were holding a sit-in to prevent GM from moving out key machinery used in component production heard Hargrove promise that negotiations with GM would be resumed at local levels almost immediately. High-level negotiations are to resume Friday.</p>
<p>The workers occupied the plant earlier Wednesday after learning that GM Canada was seeking a court injunction to move the machinery in an effort to maintain supply to customers in the United States.</p>
<p>Hargrove said GM had now agreed to drop the injunction if the strikers leave the plant.</p>
<p>GM Canada spokesman Stew Low confirmed that an agreement had been reached to drop the injuction.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not go forward with the injunction if the workers leave the plant,&quot; said Low. He declined to comment on any possible limits to outsourcing but confirmed things were looking &quot;a little more positive.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly I would have to say there is a renewed commitment from both sides to put together an agreement that's going to work for everybody,&quot; said Low. &quot;So a little bit of a positive tenor here, and we'll have to see how things go.&quot;</p>
<p>Hargrove said the two sides were going to go back to serious talks with the goal of brokering a deal by noon EDT Monday.</p>
<p>The union leader has said about 72 hours were needed to hammer out a tentative agreement once talks start again in earnest.</p>
<p>Hundreds of workers gathered outside the Oshawa plant as Hargrove spoke to about 160 workers inside, on the roof and in the periphery. The strikers chanted and waved banners in support of the union leader.</p>
<p>In its  agreement with Chrysler, the union won unprecendented say in future outsourcing decisions made by the automaker. The pact prevents Chrysler Canada from outsourcing work as long as workers are producing a quality product at a reasonable cost and the company is making a reasonable profit.</p>
<p>GM had argued it needed an agreement that was tailored to fit GM's business plan.</p>
<p>Also at issue is GM's decision to sell or close its trim and fabrication plants and outsource other work at a total cost of about 5,500 jobs.</p>
<p>Hargrove said Tuesday the union's most recent position on the bargaining table &quot;would have allowed for the sale of the plants&quot; in return for protection of some jobs.</p>
<p>About 26,000 Canadian workers are on strike. The ripple effect of the walkout has idled about 10,000 GM workers in the United States and Mexico.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSHAWA, Ontario"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
