<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121065" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Consumer prices move up 0.3 percent in September.</title>
<headline>Consumer prices move up 0.3 percent in September.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consumer prices rose moderately in September, the Labour Department said on Wednesday, continuing a pattern of relatively contained inflation despite the strength of the economy.</p>
<p>The department said the Consumer Price Index rose 0.3 percent last month, following an increase 0.1 percent in the prior month.</p>
<p>Excluding the usually volatile food and energy components, the department said, this &quot;core&quot; rate also rose 0.3 percent after rising 0.1 percent in August.</p>
<p>The September report matched Wall Street estimates of an increase of 0.3 percent for both the overall and core rate.</p>
<p>&quot;When you look at the details, everything came in as expected,&quot; said Wadlo Best, senior economist at BZW Government Securities Inc. &quot;All of these things were expected. There's really no surprise.&quot;</p>
<p>The new data on inflation follows last week's report showing wholesale prices advanced modestly in September.</p>
<p>The inflation numbers have been closely watched by the inflation-sensitive bond market and the high-flying stock market, which this week pushed over the 6,000 mark as measured by the Dow Jones Industrial Average for the first time in history.</p>
<p>Economists have become increasingly concerned that rising labour costs in a tightening job market could lead to a pickup in inflation in the months ahead.</p>
<p>But the CPI data suggested that so far businesses have been cautious about passing along higher labour costs in the form of large price increases.</p>
<p>&quot;That 0.3 percent is an upside miss on the CPI and we're all right on the inflation front. These numbers are fine,&quot; said Matthew Alexy, chief market strategist at CS First Boston Corp.</p>
<p>The department said food and beverage prices rose 0.5 percent while housing edged up 0.2 percent.</p>
<p>Energy prices were unchanged following a decline of 0.6 percent in August with gasoline (petrol) showing a decline of 0.4 percent.</p>
<p>New vehicle prices jumped 0.6 percent, posting the biggest rise since January 1991, when it was up an identical amount.</p>
<p>Apparel and its upkeep rose 0.5 percent after being down 1.4 percent in the prior month.</p>
<p>Airline fares rose 2.9 percent while overall transportation costs were up 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>Medical care cost continued their a pattern of modest increases, going up 0.2 percent, identical with August.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
