<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121017" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Russia,Middle East demands firm India rice prices.</title>
<headline>Russia,Middle East demands firm India rice prices.</headline>
<byline>Sambit Mohanty</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Growing demand from Russia and the Middle East countries has pushed up price of rice exports from India, which expects a good winter crop, traders and analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Firm demand from Russia and Middle East countries had pushed up Indian higher grades (five percent broken) rice export prices by nearly $10,&quot; said Prem Garg, a leading Delhi foodgrains exporter.</p>
<p>Garg said the export price of this quality rice had risen to $300 per tonne from $290 a week ago.</p>
<p>Traders said the price of Indian rice was on par with the price quoted for a similar variety in Vietnam, a leading rice exporter.</p>
<p>&quot;But Russia has more than $10 dollars freight advantage if it buys from India than Vietnam,&quot; Garg said.</p>
<p>He said the Middle East countries too had a freight advantage on purchases from India.</p>
<p>Analysts said rice imports by the Middle East countries increase at this time of the year due to seasonal factors.</p>
<p>Garg did not say what quantities had been contracted with Russia or the Middle East countries.</p>
<p>Analysts said India's winter output was expected to be nearly 72 million tonnes, marginally up from last year's level of 71 million tonnes. The winter harvest began in early October.</p>
<p>Government officials had estimated India's winter rice production at a record 75 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The Centre for Monitoring Indian Economy (CMIE), an independent think-tank, has estimated the winter rice output at 71.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;Less output is expected than the earlier anticipated due the marginal damage to the rice crop in Andhra Pradesh and Karnataka,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>The southern state of Andhra Pradesh and Karnataka contribute nearly 15 percent of the country's total rice output.</p>
<p>India produced around 81 million tonnes of rice in 1995/96 (June-July) crop year.</p>
<p>India's winter harvest starts in early October and continues till late in November. India annually produces two rice crops, getting the bulk of its output from the winter crop.</p>
<p>Traders said Indian five percent broken non-Basmati rice was currently quoted at $300 per tonne F.O.B, 10 percent broken at $280, 15 percent at $255 and 25 percent at $240.</p>
<p>Garg said nearly 100,000 tonnes of rice from the new crop had started arriving daily in the markets.</p>
<p>&quot;According to trade sources traders have signed deals to export nearly half a million tonnes of rice in November,&quot; an official in a leading Delhi foodgrains export firm told Reuters.</p>
<p>India exported nearly 5.5 million tonnes of rice in 1995/96 (April-March), against a target of three million. It emerged as the biggest exporter of rice after Thailand.</p>
<p>Industry officials feel India's rice exports in 1996/97 would dip to about three million tonnes due to a fall in international demand and uncompetitive prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
