<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121287" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FORESTRY JITTERS KEEP HELSINKI FROM TESTING HIGHS.</title>
<headline>FORESTRY JITTERS KEEP HELSINKI FROM TESTING HIGHS.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>* Shares near year-highs on Wedneday but fail to test</p>
<p>stronger ground as forestries slip ahead of key results on</p>
<p>Thursday. Merita rallies on buy recommendations.</p>
<p>* HEX -0.08 pct at 2,222.17 adv-decl 43-40, 19 unch</p>
<p>* Vol FIM 420 mln, 22 pct in Nokia, 14 pct in Merita</p>
<p>------------------------ (Oct 16) ----------------------------</p>
<p>Shares remained close to</p>
<p>year-highs but ended lively Wednesday session a shade lower as</p>
<p>forestries slipped ahead of UPM's and Metsa-Serla's eight-month</p>
<p>reports, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;It depends on the UPM data whether forestries continue to</p>
<p>slide,&quot; one broker said. Shares in Europe's biggest forestry</p>
<p>group UPM-Kymmene lost 1.20 markka at 92.90 in cautious trade.</p>
<p>Merita advanced to 14.00 markka -- its highest since July</p>
<p>12, 1995 -- up 0.50 in brisk demand after buy recommendations.</p>
<p>Its competitor Okobank closed fair trade at 47.50 markka -- up</p>
<p>0.70 -- where it last traded on January 18, 1995.</p>
<p>The HEX set its calendar year-high 2,226.6 on October 8.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals wholesaler Tamro gained 0.50 markka to 32.50</p>
<p>ahead of eight-month data due on Thursday with volume boosted by</p>
<p>a 40 million markka in-house deal by Protos Stockbrokers. Protos</p>
<p>declined comment on the deal, and Tamro said it did not know who</p>
<p>traded the stock.</p>
<p>Engineering groups Rauma and Tampella also gained slightly</p>
<p>in moderate trade ahead of January-August reports.</p>
<p>Cargo shipping firm Finnlines rose 2.50 markka to 108.00,</p>
<p>its highest close since November 1995, as analysts said its</p>
<p>chance to up its BTL stake may justify a yet higher valuation.</p>
<p>Food and chemicals group Raisio returned to sharp gains,</p>
<p>ending up 16.00 markka at 279.00 after solid dealings ahead of</p>
<p>the group's update on its cholesterol-reducing Benecol margarine</p>
<p>on October 24.</p>
<p>-- Ilkka Virtanen, Helsinki newsroom +358-9-6805 0248</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
