<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121368" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Pound profits from fundamentals, Euro-jitters.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Pound profits from fundamentals, Euro-jitters.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Steele</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sterling, benefiting from its detachment from the intense debate raging over European monetary union, caught its breath on Wednesday after a nearly a week of headlong gains across the board.</p>
<p>The pause came despite a slew of British figures released on Wednesday which were seen as positive for the pound.</p>
<p>Analysts said sentiment was still very bullish but the speed of the gains was now expected to slow.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has been incredibly positive but I think there will be a bit of consolidation around this level,&quot; said Ian Amstad, economist with Bankers Trust in London.</p>
<p>&quot;We are already seeing quite a bit of short-term profit-taking at these levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sterling sentiment was expected to remain upbeat thanks to its relative isolation from the growing debate over European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Economists fear that the nascent euro will be a softer currency than at first envisaged because of an increasing number of countries bidding to be founder members. Britain is almost certain to remain outside the single currency club upon its introduction in 1999.</p>
<p>Wednesday's British data was perceived as positive for sterling, showing a greater-than-expected September fall in unemployment of 35,600 for a jobless rate of 7.4 percent.</p>
<p>August average earnings rose an underlying 4.0 percent, and the September public sector borrowing requirement was a heftier-than-expected 3.41 billion sterling ($5.40 billion).</p>
<p>&quot;The UK data are stronger than expected and should underpin the rise in the pound,&quot; said Jeremy Hawkins, chief economic adviser at Bank of America in London.</p>
<p>&quot;(They) highlight the relative outperformance of the UK economy versus continental Europe and will add to speculation that the next move in rates is up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the data provided little scope for any easing in fiscal or monetary policy, and employment minister Eric Forth said although the figures were on the high side, the government saw no signs of economic overheating.</p>
<p>Sterling started its inexorable rise last Thursday, shortly after Chancellor Kenneth Clarke promised a fiscally responsible budget next month, allaying fears that he would go for a tax-cutting giveaway to boost his party's flagging fortunes.</p>
<p>The most dramatic gains were posted on Tuesday when sterling rose more than two pfennigs against the mark.</p>
<p>The pound was trading at 2.4435 marks at Wednesday's European midsession, easing back after an early climb to a 21-month high of 2.4475. It was trading at $1.5860 compared with Tuesday's close of around $1.5827. Sterling's trade-weighted index against a basket of currencies stood at 88.8 against its previous close of 88.6, a rise of 5.7 percent since the start of August.</p>
<p>In the past week alone, sterling's rise against its trade-weighted basket has been a remarkable 1.8 percent.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said sterling's recent leap was not yet over and medium-term targets were now moving into focus.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to go quite some way to find resistance...the first resistance level I'm focusing on is 2.45 (marks), which we have already been testing,&quot; said Geert-Jan Nikken, technical analyst at ABN AMRO in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>($1=.6317 Sterling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
