<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121350" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE cocoa edges higher but may hit resistance.</title>
<headline>LIFFE cocoa edges higher but may hit resistance.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>London cocoa futures recorded small gains on Wednesday in a corrective move from the lows.</p>
<p>But the near term picture looked bleak with a possibly heavy flow of West African supplies about to hit the ports, traders said.</p>
<p>Persistently strong sterling against other European currencies continued to attract a small daily dose of origin sales.</p>
<p>But eyes were transfixed on the first arrivals from Ivory Coast and Ghana, expected anytime this week or next week, which may give clues to gauge the extent of the crop.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be interesting to see the first Ivorian arrivals,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The season was set to open on Tuesday but the Ivorian government has yet to announce farm-gate prices and fix the freight rates with the shippers.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ivory Coast's Caistab (marketing body) has called on all domestic cocoa and coffee traders to renew their licences, which is usually a sign that the opening of the new season is close at hand,&quot; said brokers GNI on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The benchmark March contract opened marginally higher and by midday had clawed back seven stg to stand at a session high of 999 stg a tonne. Spot December was up four stg at 969 stg.</p>
<p>Turnover totalled a meagre 1,035 lots which included some AA deals. The Dec/March spread traded at a steady 28-29 stg.</p>
<p>Technical analysts expect resistance at 1,000 stg on March to hold, but they said the selling pressure was diminishing.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the U.S. Agriculture Department forecast world cocoa bean production for the 1996/97 season at 2.66 million tonnes, down from 2.88 million last season.</p>
<p>In a report that mainly confirmed traders' forecasts, the USDA pegged the Ivorian crop at 1.05 million tonnes, down from last season's record 1.20 million.</p>
<p>-- Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
