<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121433" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares firm 0.5 pct ahead of censure vote.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares firm 0.5 pct ahead of censure vote.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares rose slightly in quiet and selective trade on Wednesday as the Turkish parliament began debating an opposition censure motion aimed at toppling Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100  .ISEC closed 417.54 points, or 0.54 percent higher at 77,829.69, but down from an early high of 78,339 on profit-taking. Daily volume leapt to 16.4 trillion lira from Tuesday's 13.8 trillion.</p>
<p>&quot;Activity was share-based today without an overall rise, as seen in the last few days. The censure motion is expected to be rejected,&quot; said Sarper Ozten, general manager of Oncu securities.</p>
<p>The index brushed a low of 77,082 in late afternoon selling prompted by the resignation of an MP from the coalition's junior conservative partner DYP ahead of the vote on the motion. But the drop was followed by selective reaction buys, brokers said.</p>
<p>The market index had leapt 2.4 percent on Monday on political optimism that the Islamist-led government would survive the vote, but declined 0.8 percent on Tuesday as the index failed to pierce firm resistance at 78,500 for the second day in a row.</p>
<p>Brokers who await support at 76,000 said the market could continue its uptrend towards 80,000 if the motion is rejected. They expect nine-month company profit expectations and downward t-bill yields to fuel selective demand.</p>
<p>The market dived 4.2 percent on Thursday and Friday last week after soaring 22.7 percent from September 13 to last Wednesday's sixth consecutive all-time high close of 79,511.82 in a strong uptrend.</p>
<p>Turkish t-bill yields, on a downtrend since record bid and sale at last Tuesday's 238-day bill auction, were little changed today after state minister Ufuk Soylemez said no t-bill auctions were planned in the next two weeks because the Treasury was not in a short-term cash need.</p>
<p>Of the 223 shares traded, 113 rose, 58 fell and 52 were unchanged. The 85-share industrial index  .ISEI firmed 0.92 percent to 83,980.40 and the 15-share financial index .ISEF eased 0.35 percent to 71,785.39.</p>
<p>Actives were led by cement pipe and brick producer Dogusan, down 4,000 lira at 66,000, iron and steel firm Metas, up 1,300 lira at 8,300, largely state-owned flat steel giant Eregli, up 100 lira at 9,700 and utility Aktas Elektrik, up 2,000 lira at 63,000.</p>
<p>-- Aydan Eksin, Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
