<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121540" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU's treads political minefield with KEDO links.</title>
<headline>EU's treads political minefield with KEDO links.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union companies will be able to compete for millions of dollars in contracts for two North Korean power plants if the EU wins a place on the executive of the scheme's board, its director said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Stephen Bosworth, executive director of the Korean Peninsula Energy Development Organisation (KEDO), told Reuters the EU's contribution of $100 million would make European companies eligible to bid for contracts &quot;worth millions more&quot;.</p>
<p>But Bosworth warned the EU will have to tread carefully through the political minefield that surrounds Korean peninsula relations -- highlighted by Pyongyang's bloody submarine incursion into southern waters last month.</p>
<p>&quot;It is obvious we are not operating in a political vaccuum,&quot; Bosworth said. &quot;The group constantly has to be aware of all the sensitivities that have characterised relations in the area.&quot;</p>
<p>Bosworth is in Brussels to negotiate the EU's entry to KEDO after the 15-nation bloc's foreign ministers earlier this month gave its executive -- the European Commission -- a mandate to pursue membership.</p>
<p>KEDO was formed by the United States, Japan and South Korea to help North Korea develop its nuclear energy industry while at the same time ensuring its reactors are not diverted to non-energy activities.</p>
<p>In exchange for building two light water reactors by 2003 and supplying Pyongyang with 500,000 tonnes of heavy fuel oil a year until then, North Korea will dismantle two partially-built heavy water reactors.</p>
<p>Seoul's Korea Electric Power Corp will be the main contractor for the nuclear steam supply system part of the $5 billion project, but European Companies will be able to bid for much of the rest, Bosworth said.</p>
<p>The KEDO board was particularly anxious to secure EU funding in order to maintain its fuel-supply side of the bargain and the EU contribution will primarily be used to buy the oil on the open market.</p>
<p>The KEDO founders make up the board's executive, but Bosworth said the EU was likely to also win a place &quot;in keeping with its financial and political status&quot;.</p>
<p>Bosworth said last month's submarine incident had delayed the start of the project &quot;for a few weeks&quot;.</p>
<p>Seoul said a submarine, bent on infiltration, landed 26 North Koreans on an east coast beach of South Korea. One of them was captured, 22 killed and the rest are believed to be still at large. North Korea said the submarine washed ashore after suffering engine trouble.</p>
<p>The incident highlighted the tense atmosphere in the region, where North and South Korea are still technically at war following the 1950-53 conflict that divided the peninsula.</p>
<p>KEDO -- recognised by the United Nations as an international body -- is currently negotiating with Pyongyang for de facto diplomatic status for what is likely to be a substantial South Korean workforce needed for the project.</p>
<p>Australia, New Zealand, Canada, Chile, Indonesia and Finland are general members of KEDO without a voice on the executive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
