<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121604" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>VATICAN: Convalescing Pope marks election anniversary.</title>
<headline>Convalescing Pope marks election anniversary.</headline>
<byline>Philip Pullella</byline>
<dateline>VATICAN CITY 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pope John Paul on Wednesday marked the 18th anniversary of his election resting after an appendix operation which his doctors hope will be followed by a slower phase of his papacy.</p>
<p>The Pope waved briefly from his window overlooking St Peter's Square just before noon to acknowledge the cheers of several thousand Polish countrymen but did not address them. He normally holds general audiences on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It was in the same square on October 16, 1978, that a cardinal stepped out of a conclave to tell a stunned world that a man named Karol Wojtyla had been elected to succeed the late John Paul I.</p>
<p>The cardinals had elected the world's first Polish Pope and the first non-Italian in 455 years. Now there few people in the world who would not recognise John Paul II's name or face.</p>
<p>After a breathless 18 years of travel that has taken him the equivalent of 25 times around the world, the Pope has been told by his doctors to slow down and try doing what he likes least -- taking it easy.</p>
<p>&quot;We told him he had to rest,&quot; Professor Francesco Crucitti, the surgeon who operated on the Pope, said on Tuesday night as the 76-year-old Pontiff ended a 10-day stay at the Gemelli hospital in Rome.</p>
<p>Asked if he believed the Pope would obey, Crucitti smiled and said: &quot;Ah now, that remains to be seen.&quot;</p>
<p>But this time, Vatican sources say, the Pope may well listen -- at least more than he has in the past.</p>
<p>The Pope who witnessed the rise and fall of communism in Eastern Europe is determined to lead Christians into the third millennium.</p>
<p>His aides have been telling him that he will have to slow down if he wants to reach the milestone year 2000.</p>
<p>In the past 18 years, the Pope has made 74 overseas journeys and 127 trips in Italy, travelled more than a million kilometres (600,000 miles) and spent the equivalent of nearly two full years outside the Vatican.</p>
<p>He has visited 114 of the world's 191 countries and read nearly 2,500 speeches.</p>
<p>Vatican sources say doctors and top aides have made it clear to the Pope that he cannot keep up this pace if he wants to conserve his energy for major events.</p>
<p>The Pontiff's next public appearance is scheduled for Sunday, when he is due to address pilgrims and tourists in St Peter's Square.</p>
<p>It is still not clear when the Pope will resume weekly general audiences or take part in long liturgical services.</p>
<p>As his health has waned in recent years following a series of operations, the Pope has been delegating his secretary of state, Cardinal Angelo Sodano, to lead religious ceremonies that could fatigue him.</p>
<p>One health issue the Vatican has not addressed publicly is what is causing the Pope's left hand to tremble, sometimes uncontrollably. The Vatican has not denied media reports that the Pope is suffering from Parkinson's disease or a related neurological disorder.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VATICAN CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VATICAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
