<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121612" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek shares end down, no hints of rally.</title>
<headline>Greek shares end down, no hints of rally.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek equities fell 0.42 percent, with the market suffering from a lack of funds and no hints of a rally ahead of next month's 1997 budget, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly the market is suffering from a lack of funds. We don't see any funds coming into the market,&quot; Nick Stathopoulos of N.Devletoglou Securities said.</p>
<p>The market was waiting to see how National Economy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou faced the 1997 draft budget, due by the end of November.</p>
<p>He has a number of tough choices. Several brokers noted the tide was now running against the economy with the lower dollar and higher oil prices putting pressure on inflation.</p>
<p>Brokers said money coming in to Greece appeared to be going to the money markets and shunning equities and few could offer reasons to expect a rally over the next six weeks.</p>
<p>The Athens general share index closed down 0.42 percent, or 4.00 points at 937.70 from Tuesday's 941.70 close after opening at 940.05 points.</p>
<p>Turnover was at 6.47 billion drachmas on volume of 4.11 million shares boosted by a block trade of 36,470 shares in OTE and 50,000 shares in Papastratos.</p>
<p>Gainers traced decliners 91 to 104 with 31 issues unchanged on 226 traded. Banks fell 0.36 percent, industrials down 0.90 percent and construction ended lower 0.30 percent. Small-caps fell 0.06 percent.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch call spread warrant on OTE with a strike price of 3,800 drachmas was quoted at 539-557 at the close. Shares of OTE telecom, the underlying, was unchanged at 4,055 drachmas.</p>
<p>The Merrill Lynch stock index call warrant based on a basket of 23 shares was at 178.60-188.00 drachmas. It expires on January 9 1998 with a strike price of 1000. It was in the money at 1025.9.</p>
<p>The recently launched ING Baring Financial Products American style call warrant based on a basket of six banking stocks was quoted at $10.77-$11.77. The strike price was at $99.6.</p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley Hellenic Blue Chip Warrant, which has a strike price of 100 marks, was quoted at 4,159-4,427 drachmas at the close. --Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
