<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121714" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Europe line may harden in gene-soya row with U.S..</title>
<headline>Europe line may harden in gene-soya row with U.S..</headline>
<byline>Vera Eckert</byline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crushers and traders in Europe were rethinking their line on genetically-altered soybeans which American farmers will start supplying in a few weeks.</p>
<p>They were reacting to a multi-country protest organised by environmentalist group Greenpeace, which seeks to force food companies to boycott the products, or provide clear labels.</p>
<p>&quot;General indifference seems to have made way to a belief that labelling of soya products or of entire U.S. soybean cargos would be the best response to quell public concerns and to avoid a harmful boycott,&quot; a leading seeds broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still unclear whether this will die down or if it will blow up into a major food industry war with consumers.&quot;</p>
<p>Operators initially were indiffent or inclined to believe U.S. assurances the new products were safe, a segregation impossible, and Europe too dependent on the U.S. to argue.</p>
<p>Europe's oilseeds crusher lobby FEDIOL was not in principle against labelling, director general Pascale Cogels said from Brussels.</p>
<p>&quot;Greenpeace wants labelling and what the EU Commission should give them is a compromise, maybe the scare is legitimate after all the health scares we've had over the past years.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Let people reflect on that, give them a choice, and maybe they won't care anymore as they see the products are safe.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Authorities should be told they should be careful about these products and do their duty in assessing them.&quot;</p>
<p>Greenpeace activists attached banners on buildings of leading soya products processor, food manufacturer Unilever demanding consumers be given more choice.</p>
<p>Consumers cannot avoid soya, which is included in some form in 60 percent of food products here, and therefore would have to eat genetically-altered food unknowingly, they said.</p>
<p>Developed by Monsanto Co, the new products which have been made resistant to a weed-killer, have been declared safe by health authorities in the U.S., Europe and Japan.</p>
<p>But Greenpeace says dangers of allergic reactions cannot be ruled out and the impact on the environment unknown.</p>
<p>A European Parliament conciliation committee later today will seek to qualify an EU Commission stance only &quot;substantial&quot; changes to a foodstuff should appear on a label.</p>
<p>Left-wing parties think while this would apply to modified whole beans only, the use, or non-use, of raw materials derived from gene-altered organisms should also be indicated.</p>
<p>&quot;Labelling must be significant and practicable,&quot; said Cogels.</p>
<p>&quot;For example, oil heated during crushing of traditional beans is identical with oil made from genetically-altered beans as the minute traces of modified protein are destroyed.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If you label these products separately you won't be able to check -- you'd give rise to fraud and market distortions.&quot;</p>
<p>As soy oil has lost favour since the row erupted, domestic rapeseed oil has risen to an untypical premium, currently five guilders per 100 kilos, over soy oil in Rotterdam markets.</p>
<p>Traders said radical market participants saw Latin American soybeans replacing U.S. supplies and palm oil and sunseed oil making up for soy oil shortages if it came to a boycott.</p>
<p>Soymeal in animal feeding could be replaced by feed grain.</p>
<p>But the EU could lose crucial third country export markets for the soy oil it crushes partly from U.S. beans. On the other hand, most thought there was no alternative to U.S. supplies.</p>
<p>-- Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
