<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121727" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil price rally resumes on more supply shortfalls.</title>
<headline>Oil price rally resumes on more supply shortfalls.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A rally which swept world oil prices to another post-Gulf War high on Tuesday picked up steam on Wednesday morning amid further indications that heating fuel stocks are low heading into winter.</p>
<p>At 1115 GMT, November Brent crude oil futures on London's International Petroleum Exchange stood at $25.00 a barrel, 27 cents up on the day and not far from Tuesday's high of $25.06 which was Brent's highest level since 1991.</p>
<p>Late selling took oil prices at Tuesday's close down some 15-20 cents on the day as traders took their profits from the earlier gains.</p>
<p>Traders attributed Wednesday's early strength to bullish reaction to an American Petroleum Instiutute (API) report that inventories of distillate including heating oil in the U.S. Northeast, the world's largest heating fuel consumer, fell last week to a shocking 43 percent below 1995 levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The low stock situation in the U.S. Northeast is a cause of concern on the oil market as winter approaches,&quot; said Peter Gignoux, head of the London energy desk at Smith, Barney.</p>
<p>Adding to Wednesday's bullishness was news that supplies of North Sea benchmark Brent would be lower in November by about 2.26 million barrels.</p>
<p>&quot;Any signs of supply shortfalls will rally this market. I would look to buy any dips,&quot; said Bo Van Wijk, vice president of energy derivatives at Swiss bank UBS in Zurich.</p>
<p>Brent stands a massive $9 above this time last year and has added $7 in value since mid-June, driven by concern over tensions in the oil-rich Middle East and persistently low stocks of heating oil in key markets in the United States and Europe where stocks are about 10 percent down on last year's already slim levels.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Oct 16	 Oct 15</p>
<p>						   (1115 GMT)    (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $24.95	 $24.76</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Nov)	$25.00	 $24.73</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Nov)     $25.53	 $25.52</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
