<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121725" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: ANALYSTS BRACE FOR Q3 PHILIPS PROVISION.</title>
<headline>ANALYSTS BRACE FOR Q3 PHILIPS PROVISION.</headline>
<dateline>EINDHOVEN, Netherlands 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share analysts are bracing themselves for a big reorganisation charge when Philips Electronics NV announces third quarter results on October 24, with the gloomiest on Wednesday seeing a billion guilder hit.</p>
<p>Philips on Monday issued a warning that second half operating profit was unlikely, as it had previously predicted, to show an improvement and said it would be necessary to acclerate planned actions for recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;With no sign of what it is they're going to do who knows? A billion guilder charge? We have no idea where this acceleration is going to be,&quot; said one analyst, declining to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm throwing out a number. We don't know at this stage whether this is going to be some wholesale something or other, or whether it's just tweaking at the edges. I could imagine that it could be a billion or more but to amount to that it would have to be something significant,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>Philips watchers believe the company's profit warning this week was preparing investors for some harsh medicine and said the recent transition of Cor Boonstra to new Philips chairman could prove the springboard for a fresh round of reorganisation.</p>
<p>Susan Anthony at Schroders in London said markets had already discounted moves to tighten up Philips from Boonstra.</p>
<p>Anthony declined to speculate on the size of any possible restructuring charge but said action to get to grips with Philips' problems could be on the cards at the third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;In a sense I'm not sure that it matters very much as long as we have firm details of what it is he plans to do. I suppose it's more likely it could happen at the third quarter because he (Boonstra) would want to show speed,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Dutch unions earlier this week said they feared as many as 5,000 jobs could go at Philips, on top of the 6,000 job cuts announced by the company earlier this year at the Sound and Vision unit of its consumer products division.</p>
<p>Some said the net 760 million guilder extraordinary charge it took in the second quarter, following news in February of a 300 million extraordinary loss to cover a restructuring at German unit Grundig, might make a further charge unlikely.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if we would see a restructuring provision announced at the third quarter,&quot; said Steven Vrolijk, at ING Barings. &quot;A big restructuring charge is always possible but we've already heard quite a bit about restructuring projects.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For Sound and Vision and for Grundig there have already been provisions. We never know though because it's the first time Mr. Boonstra is in the chair,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will probably see some extraordinary charges taken at the third quarter. It's difficult to put a figure down,&quot; said another analyst who declined to be named. &quot;If  it's only 5,000 job cuts as the unions are suggesting you could do with a size of let's say 500 million guilders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be higher than that, as to how big that would be foolish to try to put a figure to it, but it could be higher than a billion for instance,&quot; the analyst added.</p>
<p>Analysts said that should the axe fall on jobs at Philips on October 24, cuts might come in areas traditionally seen as healthy if unexciting, such as lighting.</p>
<p>Frits de Vries of Theodoor Gilissen saw a third quarter extraordinary charge and further actions such as Tuesday's announcement of a reorganisation at Philips' Eindhoven corporate headquarters, during which jobs are set to go.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect one because I think the reorganisation they announced at the second quarter of Sound and Vision was insufficient. I think in some parts of the organisation they need to cut back on personnel costs. They announced they would cut back the Eindhoven headquarters, they need to do that in more parts of the organistion,&quot; he said. -- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EINDHOVEN, Netherlands"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
