<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121888" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Timorese asylum bid in French mission said rebuffed.</title>
<headline>Timorese asylum bid in French mission said rebuffed.</headline>
<byline>Jim Della-Giacoma</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French embassy in Jakarta apparently rebuffed a bid for political asylum by three East Timorese men who broke into the mission on Wednesday, East Timorese sources said.</p>
<p>The sources said the three men, who slipped past security guards at the embassy in the early hours of the day in a bid for political asylum in Portugal, had been evicted from the mission.</p>
<p>An embassy spokesman said: &quot;There are no East Timorese in the French embassy.&quot; He refused to elaborate.</p>
<p>The spokesman said he could not add to his statement when asked if the three men had broken into the embassy.</p>
<p>A Reuters reporter saw the three men in the forecourt of the embassy shortly before dawn.</p>
<p>They identified themselves by name and said they had scaled the embassy fence to seek political asylum in Portugal in protest against Indonesia's 1976 annexation of East Timor, a former Portuguese colony.</p>
<p>Some hours later, East Timorese sources told Reuters security guards in the embassy had evicted the three men from the mission. They said two of the three were injured while being forced out.</p>
<p>It was not known where they had gone and the embassy spokesman declined to comment on the report.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeking political asylum in Portugal. We feel that our homeland has been taken over by the Indonesian military,&quot; one of the men, who identified himself as Sabino D'Arujo, 26, told Reuters shortly after the break-in.</p>
<p>&quot;In East Timor we are always chased by the troops of the Suharto regime,&quot; said a second man who identified himself as Alberto Da Silva, 23. The third man was named by his colleagues as Anatolio Francesco Arujo, 21.</p>
<p>The embassy break-in came a day after Indonesia's President Suharto visited East Timor for only the third time since he took power three decades ago.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded East Timor in 1975 and annexed the territory the following year in a move not recognised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Da Silva read out a statement calling for greater United Nations involvement in the troubled territory.</p>
<p>The men made no mention of East Timorese Bishop Carlos Belo or self-exiled resistance leader Jose Ramos-Horta who jointly won the 1996 Nobel Peace Prize last Friday.</p>
<p>The statement asked for permanent presence of the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) in three East Timor towns. At present the ICRC has only an office in the territory's capital of Dili.</p>
<p>Da Silva said he and his colleagues wanted the United Nations to supervise a referendum on the future of East Timor, to include jailed resistance leader Xanana Gusmao in any international talks on East Timor, and to investigate all deaths in the territory since 1975.</p>
<p>He said they would ask the French ambassador to urge Paris to support the demands.</p>
<p>It was the seventh such break-in at the French embassy since November last year.</p>
<p>The spiked iron fence around the embassy was raised by a metre (three feet) after the last break-in, but the men said they still managed to scale it.</p>
<p>A total of 89 East Timorese have been granted asylum in Portugal since September 1995 after breaking into foreign embassies in Jakarta. The number includes 25 who broke into the French embassy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
