<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="121918" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks close down, profit-taking pares record.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks close down, profit-taking pares record.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended Wednesday's session sharply lower, after a morning surge to a new intra-day record high prompted investors to take profits during the afternoon, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index closed 94.52 points lower at 12,396.18, well off the intra-day record of 12,602.34 hit earlier.</p>
<p>The previous all-time intra-day high was 12,599.23 hit on January 4, 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure that what we have seen here is just a profit-taking session,&quot; said Miles Remington, sales trader at Crosby Securities.</p>
<p>Some brokers said rumours that First Pacific Co Ltd would place shares at a discount to its current market price sparked the profit-taking. First Pacific denied the rumours.</p>
<p>&quot;The market obviously has risen very strongly over the last few days and needed to have a consolidation.  The trigger of the consolidation was the rumour in the market of a possible placement of First Pacific.  People used that as an excuse to top slice,&quot; said Remington.</p>
<p>Turnover soared to HK$9.142 billion, significantly higher than Tuesday's HK$8.41 billion. The total was lifted by a turnover in market favourite HSBC of HK$709.29 million, more than the share's average daily turnover.</p>
<p>HSBC closed unchanged at HK$151.50, after trading at a new all time high of HK$153.50.</p>
<p>Brokers said turnover was also enlarged by overseas brokers selling baskets of shares.</p>
<p>The market's correction is overdue, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is only a temporary top,&quot; said Alex Wong,</p>
<p>&quot;Over the next three to four days, we could see a 250 to 500-point retracement back to the 12,200 to 12,250 level,&quot; Wong said. &quot;Daily indicators are still bullish but on the hourly chart indicators look very overbought.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the blue chips, properties took the greatest beating, followed by the commercial and industrial sector. Finance issues traded sideways, thus leading the market.</p>
<p>HSBC subsidiary Hang Seng Bank which has leaped ahead in active trading in recent days, shed only HK$0.25 to HK$92.50, after hitting a new high of HK$94.75.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
