<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122083" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan, US say can't confirm N.Korea missile report.</title>
<headline>Japan, US say can't confirm N.Korea missile report.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan and U.S. military authorities in Tokyo said on Wednesday they could not confirm reports that North Korea was preparing to test-fire a long-range ballistic missile into seas just off the Japanese coast.</p>
<p>Quoting unnamed U.S. officials, NHK public television and Jiji news agency said North Korea was planning to test-fire its Rodong-1 long-range ballistic missile into the Sea of Japan.</p>
<p>The missile had been moved to a launching place near the east coast of the communist country, the reports said.</p>
<p>The Rodong 1 is based on the Soviet Scud design used by Iraq in the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>Jiji said a military delegation from the Middle East, apparently from Iran, had also arrived at the launching site.</p>
<p>North Korea planned the test-firing as part of a demonstration aimed at selling missiles to Iran, Jiji said.</p>
<p>Officials from Japan's Defence and Foreign ministries and U.S. forces in Japan would not confirm the reports.</p>
<p>In May 1993, North Korea shocked Japan by test-firing its Rodong-1 ballistic missile into waters just off the coast of the Noto peninsula in the Sea of Japan.</p>
<p>U.S. spy satellites caught the launch and tracked its trajectory, but Japan was caught off guard.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
