<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122244" id="root" date="1996-10-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FIJI: Fiji's sugar industry threatened by land lease row.</title>
<headline>Fiji's sugar industry threatened by land lease row.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SUVA, Fiji 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fiji's sugar industry, the backbone of this South Pacific nation's economy, faces its biggest threat for a generation over the issue of native land leases.</p>
<p>The majority of the nation's sugar farms are on native land leased to Indian Fijians for 30 years, but these leases start to expire from early 1997.</p>
<p>Nationalistic politicans have called for leases not to be renewed and land returned to &quot;its true owners&quot;. Leaders of the Indian community have called on sugar farmers, most of whom are Indian, to abandon the land if new leases are not satisfactory.</p>
<p>The government has yet to announce new native land lease laws, leaving farmers anxious about their future and reluctant to invest in the sugar industry, according to farming and industry officials.</p>
<p>&quot;The viability of the sugar industry is at stake,&quot; said Mahendra Chaudhry, leader of the Fiji Labor Party, which represents Indian Fijians.</p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult for the farming community to pin its future on this kind of insecurity. We have to know whether the land will be avaiable and at reasonable conditions to all the farming community,&quot; Chaudhry told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;If that assurance is not forthcoming then farmers will look elsewhere for a living and leave the land. We cannot continue to go from generation to generation with this kind of bondage.&quot;</p>
<p>A draft report on the leases, presented to the government, said the &quot;long-term survival of agriculture, sugar, exports&quot; and Fiji's &quot;sustainable growth&quot; were at stake.</p>
<p>&quot;One must not seek to promote the short-term interests of the landowner nor for the tenant, at the expense of the other,&quot; said the review by the ministry of agriculture. &quot;Each is dependent on the other for their mutual long-term survival.&quot;</p>
<p>While the Sugar Commission of Fiji concedes the land lease issue is a risk to the sugar industry, it remains optimistic.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident that the majority of leases will be issued again. There will be some land that the landowners will want for their own requirements and that is understandable,&quot; said Commission chairman Gerald Barrack.</p>
<p>But while nationalists call for a return of sugar farm land to native Fijians, there is little experience in sugar farming in the indigenous population.</p>
<p>Native Fijians make up only 25 percent of the 22,000 sugar farmers, the rest are Indian Fijians, descendants of Indians brought here at the turn of the century to work the cane.</p>
<p>Simmering beneath the land issue is the politics of race.</p>
<p>In 1987 Fiji was rocked by a military coup which ousted the then Indian-dominated government. Prime Minister Sitiveni Rabuka, then coup leader, said at the time that Fijians were losing control of their country to Indians, who make up about 46 percent of the 750,000 population.</p>
<p>Rabuka later introduced a racially-biased constitution guaranteeing indigenous Fijians a majority in parliament.</p>
<p>But the sugar commission believes the government will treat the land leases issue on its merits and not be hijacked by racial politics, citing the fact that the sugar industry supports the livelihood of one third of the Fijian population.</p>
<p>(F$1=US$0.78)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIJI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SUVA, Fiji"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FIJI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
