<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122263" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Oct 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Oct 17.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are leading domestic stories in Portuguese newspapers.</p>
<p>DIARIO ECONOMICO</p>
<p>- French car company Renault will transfer some production from France to its factory at Cacia in Portugal.</p>
<p>- Banco Comercial Portugues, Portugal's largest private-sector bank, is to be quoted on the London stock exchange.</p>
<p>- Murteira Nabo, president of Portugal Telecom, will announce to senior company officials today details about the restructuring plan for the group.</p>
<p>PUBLICO</p>
<p>- A European study reveals Portuguese doctors prescribe more medicines per consultation than their colleagues in the European Union. They often prescribe unsuitable medication, the study found.</p>
<p>- The trial of former broker Pedro Caldeira on sleaze charges has been postponed to January 1997. The judge told Caldeira to stop talking to the media, otherwise he could return to preventive custody.</p>
<p>DIARIO DE NOTICIAS</p>
<p>- Pensions are expected to rise by three percent for most retirees and by 3.5 percent for the poorest pensioners in 1997, a source in the social security ministry told the paper.</p>
<p>- Cabovisao, a private cable TV operator, sold 20 percent of its capital to Banco Portugues de Investimento.</p>
<p>--Lisbon bureau 3511-3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
