<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122747" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mirage Monte Carlo posts $23.4 mln EBITDA.</title>
<headline>Mirage Monte Carlo posts $23.4 mln EBITDA.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mirage Resorts Inc said its 50-percent owned hotel in Las Vegas, the Monte Carlo, generated $70.1 million in revenues and and $23.4 in earnings before interest and taxes depreciation and amortization in the third quarter, the hotel's first full quarter of operation.</p>
<p>Monte Carlo is a joint venture between Mirage and Circus Circus Enterprises Inc.</p>
<p>Earlier, Mirage reported third quarter earnings of $0.25 a share versus $0.23 one year ago, adjusted for a two-for-one stock split in June. Analysts had expected the company to earn $0.28 a share, according to First Call.  </p>
<p>Analysts attributed the fall off in earnings from the company's flagship hotel/casino, The Mirage, in Las Vegas.</p>
<p>&quot;When you pick it apart, it was primarily due to luck,&quot; said Jim Murren, analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell Inc. &quot;We knew they'd played poorly in July, and it looks like they played poorly in September at The Mirage.&quot;</p>
<p>Cash flow at The Mirage fell 12 percent to $55 million from $63 million in the prior year's third quarter.</p>
<p>Total revenues dropped to $194 million from $201 million last year. Of the total, casino revenues were flat except on Baccarat tables where they fell. Non-casino revenues rose nine percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;The big issue was the level of play at Baccarat..(The) drop was down about $35 million in the quarter,&quot; said Jason Ader, analyst at Bear Stearns.</p>
<p>He attributed much of the slowdown to the lack of popularity of Mike Tyson's heavyweight boxing matches, which have declined since his first return bout in last year's third quarter which increased casino traffic, brought large numbers of high-rollers to Baccarat tables, and Mirage played lucky.</p>
<p>This year, the fight generated much less enthusiasm in Las Vegas.  </p>
<p>&quot;The economic impact of these Tyson fights was misunderstood to a large extent,&quot; Ader said.</p>
<p>At other resorts in Las Vegas, the company's properties performed well, analysts said.</p>
<p>Cash flow at The Monte Carlo was on target or slightly above analyst's expectations.</p>
<p>Revenue at Treasure Island hotel/casino rose four percent to $104 million from $100 million last year, and operating cash flow increased to $30.6 million from $28.4 million. Analysts had been concerned about how Monte Carlo and another new hotel/casino, Stratosphere, would effect Treasure Island.</p>
<p>Also, the Golden Nugget, in downtown Las Vegas, generated $52.1 million in revenue versus $50.2 million last year, and operating cash flow rose to $11.5 million from $10.3 million.</p>
<p>In Laughlin, Nev., however, the Mirage's relatively small Golden Nugget hotel/casino posted revenue of $13.6 million compared to $15.2 million last year and operating cash flow of $1.5 million versus $2.9 million last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
