<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122841" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-STRICKER OVERCOMES INFERIORITY COMPLEX.</title>
<headline>GOLF-STRICKER OVERCOMES INFERIORITY COMPLEX.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>WENTWORTH, England 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>In his own eyes, Steve Stricker's long game is inadequate and his iron play sub-standard.</p>
<p>And he even considers himself inferior as a golfer to team mates Phil Mickelson and Mark O'Meara in the team who won the Alfred Dunhill Cup team at St Andrews on Sunday.</p>
<p>So Stricker surprised himself as much as anyone by going unbeaten through five matches on his first visit to the Old Course, while his team mates each lost twice.</p>
<p>On Thursday the fair-haired 29-year-old American begins the second stage of a British odyssey when he takes on Australian Steve Elkington in the first round of the World Matchplay championship at Wentworth.</p>
<p>Mickelson and O'Meara are also in action as the 650,000 pounds sterling ($1.03 million) event begins, against Vijay Singh of Fiji and Japan's Nobuo Serizawa respectively.</p>
<p>The fourth match is an All-British clash between Colin Montgomerie and Ian Woosnam, first and second on the European Order of Merit this year.</p>
<p>The leading four seeds, defending champion Ernie Els and the American winners of three major titles this year, British Open champion Tom Lehman, U.S. Open champion Steve Jones and PGA winner Mark Brooks, each have byes to the second round.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I have weaknesses,&quot; Stricker said on Wednesday after his last practice round in the pro-am. &quot;I think my long game isn't as good as it should be and my iron play in general isn't as strong as I think it could be.</p>
<p>&quot;But these are things I am constantly trying to improve.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Phil and Mick hit their shots a little more consistently and they've done well in the major tournaments, a step I'm trying to improve on to become a top player in the world.</p>
<p>&quot;I am trying to get to the level of those players and I believe they are a notch above where I am, maybe two or three notches.</p>
<p>&quot;I need to get to those levels and will keep working hard to get there.</p>
<p>&quot;But I was a little surprised to win all five last week. With Mark playing the best from the other side each time and me playing second, I felt the pressure was on me to win.&quot;</p>
<p>Stricker has kept improving since turning professional in 1990, finishing 50th and 40th on the U.S. money list in 1994 and 1995.</p>
<p>This year after victories in the Kemper and Western Opens he holds fifth place on the money list.</p>
<p>One thing Stricker is certain he has got right is his choice of caddy. Wife Nicky began caddying for him several years ago when she was his girlfriend.</p>
<p>&quot;She travelled with me, we finally married and we decided we shouldn't change what we'd been doing, her caddying for me,&quot; Stricker said.</p>
<p>&quot;We took a bit of grief about it, people talking about my wife caddying and how I'd never win with my wife on the bag.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a tough thing for other people but for us it was never a problem. She was the right person for the job.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;She knows me, she knows the game of golf and she's a good player herself, about a five or six handicapper.</p>
<p>&quot;We played the nine-hole course yesterday and she beat me, she shot even par, I was one over.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WENTWORTH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
