<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122805" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: SOCCER-RELATIVES BLAME DISORGANIZATION FOR SOCCER DISASTER.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-RELATIVES BLAME DISORGANIZATION FOR SOCCER DISASTER.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poor organisation and greed that enabled thousands of fans with bogus tickets to barge into an overcrowded soccer stadium caused up to 82 people to be crushed to death, relatives charged on Thursday.</p>
<p>The victims were killed in an avalanche of bodies at the Guatemalan stadium after fans without proper tickets charged in to see a World Cup soccer qualifying game between Costa Rica and Guatemala on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a tragedy that should have been prevented. It was corruption that let this happen because of all the forged tickets,&quot; said a grieving boy at the city morgue on Thursday.</p>
<p>The boy, who refused to give his name, said he and his friends who died in the disaster had all been sold fake tickets by scalpers before the match. His story was echoed by other relatives and local media, who all spoke of a flood of forged tickets circulating in the city ahead of the game.</p>
<p>Capt. Julio Roberto Rodriguez, owner of the private security company that was responsible for the match, admitted on Thursday there was overcrowding and fake ticket sales but blamed crowd misbehaviour for the disaster.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a brawl caused by the people who were already inside,&quot; he said. &quot;At no time was the door broken down.&quot;</p>
<p>The exact death toll from the tragedy was still unclear on Thursday. The municipal fire department estimated &quot;82 or 83 dead&quot; but Mario Rene Guerra, a forensic doctor at the morgue, said he had 78 bodies. Either way, it was the worst stadium disaster in World Cup history.</p>
<p>&quot;Fans' faces were turning blue and purple,&quot; eyewitness Kimberly White, a Reuters photographer, said. &quot;They couldn't breathe. I heard people screaming and screaming.&quot;</p>
<p>Guatemalan President Alvaro Arzu, who rushed onto the field with tears in his eyes to call off the match, declared three days of national mourning for the victims.</p>
<p>A Reuters correspondent counted 79 dead, including two children, lying on the field of the Mateo Flores stadium after the tragedy, dubbed the &quot;black night&quot; by local media. After the initial death toll early on Thursday, emergency workers reported that up to four more had died in local hospitals.</p>
<p>Bodies were taken to a morgue near Guatemala City's main cemetery on Thursday for relatives, mostly poor Indians, to identify. Sad, resentful and angry by turns, the family members wept, sobbed and held on to each other as they filed in. Outside the building, 20 black hearses waited to carry away the cheap tin coffins for burial.</p>
<p>Jorge Mario Boche, the cousin of a victim, said: &quot;The authorities are not capable of staging a soccer event like this. And they're not even capable of finding the people responsible for this terrible tragedy, either.&quot;</p>
<p>Guatemalan officials said the stadium was packed well beyond its 45,800 capacity an hour before kickoff, with some estimating that up to 60,000 were in the facility, close to the centre of Guatemala City. The stadium is a concrete 1940s bowl that serves as both the national stadium and the venue of the capital's leading soccer clubs.</p>
<p>In a preliminary report submitted by a match commissioner who attended the game, FIFA, world soccer's governing body in Zurich, Switzerland, said forged tickets may have triggered the stampede. It said angry fans kicked down an entrance door to the south stands causing spectators inside to cascade down to the lower levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The proper number of tickets was issued, 45,800, but we are going to investigate,&quot; Guatamalan soccer chief Rolando Pineda Lam told reporters.</p>
<p>Witnesses said gate-crashers pushing into the cheap stands from the street at the south end of the stadium overwhelmed fans below, causing a mass of people to tumble down on top of each other toward the playing field about half an hour before the game's scheduled start at 8 p.m. (0200 GMT on Thursday).</p>
<p>The south end entrance is at street level, with the playing field and lower stands below ground. Many died crushed against the chainlink fence separating the stands from the playing field. Emergency workers opened the fence to relieve the pressure but too late to save those who had suffocated.</p>
<p>Alberto Chamale, a 46-year-old construction worker, limping and disorientated, told Reuters he had lost four brothers and a niece in the crush. &quot;There was no room for more people but more and more came in. There were too many people. They pushed us forward,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Choking back tears, he said emergency workers told him his relatives were among the bodies laid out on the field.</p>
<p>Guatemala's attorney general, solicitor general and health minister all made public calls for a thorough investigation to determine who was responsible for the overcrowding. If found guilty of negligence in the disaster, the Guatemala Football Association could face possible FIFA sanctions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
