<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122821" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SOCCER-FORGED TICKETS MAY HAVE TRIGGERED TRAGEDY - FIFA REPORT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FORGED TICKETS MAY HAVE TRIGGERED TRAGEDY - FIFA REPORT.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forged tickets may have triggered the stampede that claimed at least 79 lives at a World Cup qualifying match in Guatemala, world soccer's governing body FIFA said on Thursday.</p>
<p>According to an early report submitted by FIFA match commissioner Arnoldo Levinson of Mexico, who attended Wednesday's CONCACAF (North, South and Central America and Caribbean) preliminary group one game between Guatemala and Costa Rica, forged tickets were apparently sold prior to the start of the match.</p>
<p>The report said angry fans kicked down an entrance door to the south stands causing spectators, who had already entered the ground, to cascade down to the lower levels.</p>
<p>The report noted that security forces released emergency gates to the pitch but could not relieve the crush.</p>
<p>In addition to the deaths, more than 150 people were injured. The game was immediatly suspended.</p>
<p>The exact cause of the disaster will be investigated by Guatemalan goverment authorities, which FIFA (the International Football Federation) said were responsible for safety inside and outside the stadium.</p>
<p>FIFA spokesman Andreas Herren would not confirm that FIFA would conduct its own investigation, saying only &quot;that these are matters I cannot discuss but the media can draw their obvious conclusions&quot;.</p>
<p>If found guilty of negligence in the disaster the Guatemala Football Association could face possible FIFA sanctions.</p>
<p>The match has been postponed until further notice.</p>
<p>&quot;With the current situation that is not the main concern at the moment,&quot; said Herren. &quot;We must first respect the victims of this tragedy.&quot;</p>
<p>In a prepared statement, FIFA said: &quot;The international football community are devastated at the news of this latest stadium disaster and have sent the football association of Guatemala and families of the victims their deepest sympathy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
