<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122850" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: SOCCER-HERMOSILLO GIVES MEXICO IMPORTANT QUALIFYING WIN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HERMOSILLO GIVES MEXICO IMPORTANT QUALIFYING WIN.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico recovered from last month's shock World Cup qualifying defeat against Honduras to beat Jamaica 2-1 in a crucial match on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Striker Carlos Hermosillo, who has been left in the cold by his country despite a prolific scoring record in domestic soccer, scored the winner in the CONCACAF semifinal group three match the Mexicans could not afford to lose.</p>
<p>The result put Mexico level on points and goal difference with Jamaica, who won their first two games, with Honduras trailing the two on goal difference.</p>
<p>Jamaica has never qualified for a soccer World Cup before.</p>
<p>Coach Bora Milutinovic, who led Mexico to the World Cup quarter-finals when the country hosted the tournament in 1986, recalled midfielder Benjamin Galindo and Brazilian-born striker Zague in the wake of the Honduras defeat.</p>
<p>Striker Luis Garcia, an automatic choice for years, was relegated to the substitute's bench.</p>
<p>The changes paid off with Galindo pulling the strings in midfielder and Zague firing Mexico in front with a well-taken goal in the 41st minute following a move involving Galindo and Hermosillo.</p>
<p>Galindo set up a chance that was wasted by Pavel Pardo at the start of the second half before supplying the corner from which Hermosillo headed Mexico's second goal in the 53rd minute to the delight of a 100,000 crowd at Aztec stadium.</p>
<p>Hermosillo had not been picked before the Honduras games, despite being top scorer in the Mexican championship for the last three seasons with Cruz Azul.</p>
<p>His goal proved the winner because in the 79th minute Jamaican striker Walter Boyd pounced on a defensive mistake by Duilio Davino to pull a goal back with a powerful shot from outside the penalty area.</p>
<p>Mexico had to survive some worrying moments before claiming the points.</p>
<p>The top two in the group go into the final CONCACAF qualifying round.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
