<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122992" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE coffee ends mostly weaker as origins sell.</title>
<headline>LIFFE coffee ends mostly weaker as origins sell.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Robusta coffee futures stayed weighed down by origin selling on Thursday although roaster price fixing supported the London market against an overspill of bearish New York sentiment, traders said.</p>
<p>Overall volume was modest at 2,710 lots by the close and the Nov/Jan switch was the only real feature of interest, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;You've got a lot of origin selling...I certainly think there's a lot more above the market as well,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;People are quite happy to keep short whilst they know there's going to be a cap on the market with selling above.&quot;</p>
<p>Indonesia, Ivory Coast, Vietnam and Madagascar were named as active origins on the sell side but traders voiced concern about the grading of some origins, saying much of the better qualities were destined to go directly to industry buyers.</p>
<p>Traders said the overhead pressure of origins could dwindle if the New York arabicas market staged a strong rally.</p>
<p>At the close, November stood $5 higher at $1,521 after touching a low of $1,505. But all other positions ended weaker, with the second-month January contract down $10 at $1,424.</p>
<p>&quot;The only interesting thing is the Nov/Jan which has widened out again today, which is fairly surprising when you hear about all this coffee around,&quot; the trader said, adding that some players with short positions were rolling forward into January.</p>
<p>The truck drivers' strike in Colombia is continuing and has halted coffee shipments.</p>
<p>Market sources said the strike showed no sign of ending as yet but the market was unlikely to be affected.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it will go on for much longer. At the end of the day these people need the money to support their families,&quot; said the trader.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
