<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122906" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: PRESS DIGEST - ANGOLA - OCT 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - ANGOLA - OCT 17.</headline>
<dateline>LUANDA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories reported in the Angolan press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JORNAL DE ANGOLA</p>
<p>- The United nations began demobilising the second group of underaged soldiers at Negage assembly camp in the northern Uige province where UNITA soldiers have been disarmed under the terms of a 1994 peace accord with the government. More than 571 child soldiers will be deombilised at the camp.</p>
<p>- Angola's national airline TAAG (Transportadora Aerea Angolana) will begin as of next year flying directly to Houston, Texas, where many of the U.S. oil companies operating in Angola are based. </p>
<p>- The Angolan parliament has started evaluating plans for the creation of the first urban project south of the capital Luanda. The state organ who will oversee the plan said it will not build houses in the area, but will prepare basic infrastructures for people to construct their own houses.</p>
<p>- The head of the International Monetary Fund, Michel Camdessus, concluded a visit to Abngola and appealed for peace.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
