<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="122957" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lebed dismissal jolts markets but West stays calm.</title>
<headline>Lebed dismissal jolts markets but West stays calm.</headline>
<byline>James Flannery</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin's dismissal of security chief Alexander Lebed jolted world markets on Thursday, but Western leaders reacted calmly.</p>
<p>The United States said the sacking did not appear to be &quot;a fundamental turning point&quot; and that the Russian government was stable.</p>
<p>The muted political reaction from the big powers contrasted with markets responding nervously.</p>
<p>Some commentators expressed concern about the future in Chechnya where Lebed had brought peace. And many diplomats believe the Kremlin power struggle may persist.</p>
<p>The dollar jumped higher against the German mark and prompted European stock markets to retreat. It leapt half a pfennig as concern about political instability in Moscow pressured the German currency and Swiss franc.</p>
<p>Share markets in both Germany and France also pared gains after the news from Moscow.</p>
<p>Following an increasingly rancorous struggle in the Kremlin between Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov and Lebed, Yeltsin appeared on television to announce he had sacked his security chief.</p>
<p>Lebed had been accused of plotting to seize power while Yeltsin awaits heart surgery.</p>
<p>&quot;This is disturbing news for European assets given the potential for increased political instability in Russia,&quot; said Keith Edmonds, chief analyst at IBJ International in London.</p>
<p>Russian financial markets had already spent a jumpy day that saw sharp falls in shares and bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;There was panic in the morning,&quot; said a trader at the Troika-Dialog bank in Moscow. &quot;The market is very sensitive to political news and it causes panicky movements from both brokers and investors.&quot;</p>
<p>Echoing other Western allies, State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said it was not appropriate for Washington to comment on what was an internal decision.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;I don't think the American public needs to worry that this is some fundamental turning point.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is dramatic. It's important,&quot; he said. &quot;We're not exactly sure where it's going to lead in the future but the (U.S.-Russian) relationship is stable and this is what matters ultimately to the American people.&quot;</p>
<p>Burns and White House spokesman Mike McCurry, travelling with President Bill Clinton in California, said Yeltsin was acting within his constitutional powers.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry, visiting Moscow, said Lebed's sacking would not change the deepening security relationship between Washington and Moscow.</p>
<p>In other capitals spokesmen insisted this was a political matter for the Russians.</p>
<p>On money markets, interest rates for Russian debt jumped but investors said any short term uncertainty would give way to optimism on a perception that Yeltsin's firm hand had reinforced the reformist camp.</p>
<p>&quot;Yeltsin's action lanced the boil,&quot; said Robin Hubbard, senior emerging market economist at Chase Manhattan in London.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not know what Lebed will do now,&quot; said a Russian equity trader at a major European bank in London, &quot;But this does show that Yeltsin is backing Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin and reformer Anatoly Chubais, which is good for the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Some investors believe that if Lebed had not been pushed, he would have been forced to jump.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebed was the hostage of Yeltsin, not the other way round and Lebed was very short on options. He had the choice to get out or stay in and become compromised,&quot; said Mark Cooke a fund manager at Brunswick Capital Management in London.</p>
<p>The country is on the verge of a Eurobond issue of up to $500 million and RAO Gazprom, the world's largest natural gas producer, is looking for $460 million via the issue of shares listed in London.</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel said he believed there was no need no over-dramatise Yeltsin's decision.</p>
<p>But a leading German analyst of Russian affairs took a different view, saying Lebed's departure could endanger the fragile peace in Chechnya.</p>
<p>&quot;This whole peace process was connected with the personality of Lebed,&quot; Alexander Rahr of the German Society for Foreign Policy told Reuters. &quot;The danger is now that the situation could return to how it was before -- war.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain said it hoped the sacking would not hurt the peace process in breakaway Chechnya, but the Foreign Office declined further comment &quot;on internal Russian politics.&quot;</p>
<p>NATO Secretary-General Javier Solana declined to comment. But one senior diplomat in Brussels said: &quot;This is the Russians sorting out their own leadership problems. You can even argue that Yeltsin taking action is better than allowing the power struggle to keep going on.&quot;</p>
<p>In Finland, which shares an 800-mile (1,300 km) border with Russia, Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen said on television the sacking need not badly shake Russia's situation but the government was following developments closely.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
