<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123003" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BAe scores over GEC in Thomson sale.</title>
<headline>BAe scores over GEC in Thomson sale.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The sale of French group Thomson SA to Lagardere will open up a big new area in the European defence industry's search for cross-border mergers and gives British Aerospace a head start over General Electric in the race to lead the industry consolidation.</p>
<p>But analysts warn that a marathon lies ahead with many political and commercial obstacles to negotiate before European firms find the strength in combination they want to take on the might of U.S. titans such as Lockheed Martin.  </p>
<p>Consequently they said GEC will still have everything to play for and yesterday's decision by the French government to sell Thomson to Lagardere instead of GEC's own partner Alcatel Alsthom was not going to push GEC into seeking new merger talks with BAe instead.</p>
<p>&quot;GEC's defence businesses are easily strong enough for it to stand on its own two feet for as long as it wants...There's no question of anybody pushing anybody else,&quot; said Chris Avery, London-based industry analyst at Paribas Capital Markets.</p>
<p>There have been on-off talks dating back to the 1980s. The last attempt was abandoned three years ago.  </p>
<p>BAe denied last month it was about to get back into talks now that former BAe deputy chairman George Simpson has taken over the helm at GEC but declined to rule out the idea in the longer term.</p>
<p>Had Alcatel won the bid for Thomson there was a strong expectation it would have joined Thomson's defence businesses with GEC's own radar to warships defence group GEC-Marconi.</p>
<p>Instead the government picked BAe's partner Lagardere which has said it plans to merge Thomson CSF with its own defence business Matra and invite other European firms to join in creating pan-European defence groups.  </p>
<p>&quot;Both for BAe and GEC this move represents a step for European defence industry consolidation,&quot; said Avery.</p>
<p>&quot;It still has many many miles to run but on this particular occasion it's leaving BAe more favourably placed than GEC.&quot;</p>
<p>Avery and other analysts say there is little doubt GEC will still be included in the consolidation, not least in radar where Thomson and Marconi are Europe's two biggest concerns, and in satellites where GEC partners Matra as Matra Marconi Space.</p>
<p>But having Alcatel as Thomson's new owner would have given GEC a much stronger hand to play in Europe's consolidation.  </p>
<p>&quot;GEC would have got the whole lot,&quot; said another analyst who declined to be named. &quot;Now they might get little bits.&quot;</p>
<p>BAe and Lagardere have already said their budding joint venture Matra BAe Dynamics plans to take over Thomson's guided missile business, something BAe tried to do several years ago.</p>
<p>And BAe is also likely to start coveting other parts of the Thomson defence empire now that the French government has effectively pushed GEC back in the queue.</p>
<p>&quot;GEC would have been keen to have an opportunity to ally itself with various bits of Thomson's business but it now has to take second seat at the table to BAe,&quot; said Avery.  </p>
<p>He believes BAe could be interested in Thomson's naval business where it is prime contractor for Lafayette frigates.</p>
<p>As defence budgets get cut and military technology grows more complex, an increasing number of governments are turning to -- be they warships, aircraft or tanks.</p>
<p>Last year BAe lost its bid for British shipbuilder VSEL to GEC, causing a severe setback to its ambitions to extend its prime contracting skills in naval work.</p>
<p>GEC has long coveted a merger of GEC and BAe's defence interests to produce a single national champion, able to compete at home and abroad as prime contractor.</p>
<p>Privately BAe executives have said they are not averse to the idea but the priority now is to look for consolidation across national boundaries in Europe, and this may or may not involve bringing GEC and BAe together.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
