<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123078" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Menengitis epidemic in Burundi kills 73.</title>
<headline>Menengitis epidemic in Burundi kills 73.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>BUJUMBURA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aid workers, hard pressed by regional sanctions, said on Thursday they were struggling to control a meningitis outbreak that has killed up to 37 people in three weeks in Burundi's northern Kirundo region.</p>
<p>Meantime, Burundi's Brarudi brewery, a chief source of government revenue, said it had suspended distribution and could stop its operations because of a lack of fuel and spare parts.</p>
<p>Revenue from Brarudi pays civil service salaries.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't get enough fuel we will have to close altogether. It's as simple as that,&quot; said Koos Woltjes, spokesman for Heineken m.v., which owns 60 percent of Brarudi.</p>
<p>But Woltjes gave no date for such a closure.</p>
<p>The World Health Organisation delivered 15,000 doses of vaccine to Kirundo on Wednesday as part of a campaign to control the menengitis outbreak and doctors said an early response by the health ministry averted a crisis on a much larger scale.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an epidemic of meningitis in Kirundo. It started on 24 September and since then 37 people have died,&quot; Annick Hamel, Burundi director of MSF-France (Doctors Without Borders) told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment this is a meningitis alert...but there is a danger that if we do nothing it will grow especially with the onset of the dry season,&quot; Hamel said.</p>
<p>Regional states imposed a trade and transport embargo on landlocked Burundi on July 31 in response to a coup by the army that ousted president Sylvestre Ntibantunganya, a Hutu, and installed Buyoya of the minority Tutsi tribe, which dominates the military.</p>
<p>At a summit last Saturday regional leaders rejected a suggestion by U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher to ease the embargo and gave Burundi one month to enter negotiations with Hutu rebels or face further sanctions.</p>
<p>They also decided to send a ministerial committee to Burundi to review a stated commitment by Buyoya to unconditional talks.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the African ministers cancelled a peace mission to Burundi because Buyoya refuses to negotiate with Hutu rebels.</p>
<p>The cancellation reflected a growing rift between Buyoya's isolated government and regional heads of state demanding a return to constitutional legality in Burundi where ethnic war has killed 150,000 people in three years.</p>
<p>The blockade has been somewhat relaxed to allow the entry of essential medicines and limited flights, fuel and supplies for humanitarian agencies and diplomats.</p>
<p>But Burundi's mainly Tutsi capital has remained defiant despite sanctions. Food prices have stabilised and a steady supply of black market fuel has brought prices down.</p>
<p>&quot;There is fuel now and prices have come down from 1,000 Bfrs ($3.1) per litre to 300 Bfrs per litre,&quot; a tax driver said.</p>
<p>Beer distribution was suspended last month after four Brarudi staff died in two separate ambushes on beer trucks, Woltjes said in a telephone interview from the Netherlands.</p>
<p>Production of Amstel beer has stopped because it was impossible to import new labels for bottling, he added.</p>
<p>He said Brarudi, which employs 1350 workers, would rather stop production than break sanctions to import fuel or parts.</p>
<p>($1=316.48 Burundi francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUJUMBURA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
