<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123042" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada bonds end mixed on curve flattening trades.</title>
<headline>Canada bonds end mixed on curve flattening trades.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed mixed on Thursday, with some spreads to U.S. bonds reaching 11-year lows, as longer-term bonds benefitted from curve-flattening trades, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The curve was too steep. It was due for a bit of a correction,&quot; said Jeoff Hall, market analyst with Technical Data. &quot;It's a natural progression to unwind positions in the short end where there's less bang for the buck.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond rose C$1.15 to C$109.30 to yield 7.208 percent compared to the U.S. 30-year benchmark which rose 24/32 to yield 6.80 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the benchmark bonds narrowed to an 11-year low of 41 basis points from 44 points at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>The Canadian yield curve steepened yesterday when the Bank of Canada surprised many in the market by cutting its key bank rate to 3.75 percent, bringing the bank's target range for the overnight lending rate down to 3.25-3.75 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;I think investors are believing that this may be near the end of the rate-easing cycle and they're moving out the yield curve to take advantage of the higher yields,&quot; said one trader. &quot;I think it's a correction in a steepening trend.&quot;  </p>
<p>In new issue news, the Bank of Canada said that on October 23 it will auction C$1.5 billion of 8.0 percent bonds due June 1, 2027. The bank will buy at least 10 percent of the bonds.</p>
<p>Yesterday, the Bank of Canada said it may increase the pace of its bond purchases in order to reduce its involvement in treasury bill tenders. The central bank said it is considering acquiring at auction 15 percent of bonds maturing beyond the three-year benchmark beginning in November.</p>
<p>In other prices, the Government of Canada 7.0 percent of 2006 rose C$0.30 to C$103.25 to yield 6.554 percent. The U.S. 10-year benchmark rose 13/32 to yield 6.51 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread narrowed to four basis points from seven basis points on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The three-month cash bill traded at 3.39 percent against the U.S. three-month bill at 5.10 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
