<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123167" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin takes big risk in ousting security chief.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin takes big risk in ousting security chief.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin took a calculated risk on Thursday by dismissing security tsar Alexander Lebed, perhaps turning Russia's most charismatic politician into its most powerful opposition leader.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who sacked Lebed after Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov accused him of plotting to set up his own military force in a bid to seize power, also put the fate of peace in breakaway Chechnya on the line.</p>
<p>Lebed negotiated and signed the deal that doused fighting in Chechnya on August 31 and he was regarded by separatist leaders as the one Kremlin official they trusted.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's ability to control Lebed was limited because he is out of the Kremlin awaiting heart surgery. His choice in the end came down to whether the reserve general was a greater liability in the Kremlin or out of it.</p>
<p>&quot;There has to be a united team; the team should pull together, work like a fist,&quot; Yeltsin said in a nationwide television address in which he accused Lebed of running a presidential campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;But now we have a situation whereby Lebed is splitting the team apart and is carrying out a number of moves which he did not agree with the president. This is totally unacceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>Perhaps calculating that troops loyal to Lebed might rise up, the interior ministry had already ordered tightened security across the country before Yeltsin's announcement.</p>
<p>It was a dramatic fall from grace for Russia's fastest-rising political star.</p>
<p>In four months as Yeltsin's national security adviser and secretary of his influential Security Council, the 46-year-old former paratroop commander looked like a man on a mission to become president in the shortest possible time.</p>
<p>That made him many enemies in the Kremlin and clearly worried Yeltsin, forcing him to abandon his plan to use Lebed as a counterweight to any other politicians in his team with presidential ambitions.</p>
<p>But it is unlikely to be the end of Lebed's political career. His potential as an opposition leader is clear. A recent opinion poll in the Sevodnya newspaper showed that Lebed was more trusted by Russians than any other politican.</p>
<p>&quot;Lebed's best chances of becoming a major opposition figure are if he can show that Yeltsin has put him down and that he really wants to wash his hands of the Kremlin bureaucracy,&quot; political analyst Andrei Kortunov told Reuters recently.</p>
<p>Some analyst interpret his actions in the Kremlin as designed to force his own dismissal to distance himself from the leadership and portrasy himself as a victim.</p>
<p>Another analyst said Lebed's departure would be a &quot;Christmas gift come early&quot; for the opposition.</p>
<p>Whether Lebed can unite the bitterly divided opposition is open to question, particularly as he has no record of working in a political team and has been an outspoken critic of the main opposition party, the communists.</p>
<p>He may choose to lead his own party and fight on his own. Whether he can exploit widespread discontent over unpaid wages and hardships under tough economic reforms for his own political purposes remains to be seen.</p>
<p>He would first have to win back a seat in parliament after resigning his own to take up his Kremlin post.</p>
<p>Separatist leaders in Chechnya were in no doubt that Lebed's departure represented a setback and could encourage hardliners in Moscow who want the conflict to resume.</p>
<p>&quot;If they get rid of Lebed, we will have to prepare for war because you can expect anything from people like Kulikov,&quot; separatist chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov told Reuters before Yeltsin's announcement.</p>
<p>One sign of hope for the peacemakers is that Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin and Yeltsin have committed themselves to the agreement signed by Lebed, despite criticism by rivals in Moscow who say it amounts to capitulation.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Russian troops are pulling out.</p>
<p>&quot;Chernomyrdin is committed to peace in Chechnya and I think he will push hard to maintain the peace,&quot; said Andrei Piontkowski of the independent Centre for Strategic Studies.</p>
<p>&quot;The danger is that Kulikov will see this as a victory for himself and the party of war which he represents.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
