<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123176" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria chemical company raises export revenue.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria chemical company raises export revenue.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Himko chemical company, which is offered for partial privatisation, raised revenue from export sales for the first nine months of 1996 by $10 million to $107 million over the same period last year, an official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In lev terms, pre-tax profit doubled to 7.3 billion levs for the same period but the currency has fallen from 70 to the dollar at the beginning of the year to about 216 now. Himko exports 92 percent of its products.</p>
<p>Himko's net profit for 1994 was 60 million levs.</p>
<p>A senior official, who declined to be named, said Himko produced some 400 tonnes of ammonia, more than 580 tonnes of carbamide, some 9,000 tonnes of carbon sulphide and more than two million metres of argon.</p>
<p>The Privatisation Agency wants to sell 60 percent of Himko which is Bulgaria's second largest chemical producer after calcinated soda maker Sodi-Devnya.</p>
<p>Himko is among 20 major state enterprises which the government hopes to sell by year-end to raise desperately needed cash.</p>
<p>Earlier this year Himko set up a joint venture with Frankfurt-based Messer Grieshelm GmbH, a subsidiary of Germany's Hoechst, to distribute industrial gases. Himko has 49 percent and the Germans have the remaining stake.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
