<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123266" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia's Lebed has few allies in power struggle.</title>
<headline>Russia's Lebed has few allies in power struggle.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The row between Russian security tsar Alexander Lebed and Interior Minister Anatoly Kulikov has highlighted the infighting under way as President Boris Yeltsin is out of the Kremlin awaiting heart surgery.</p>
<p>The following brief portraits of the leaders involved in the rivalries outline the sides they have taken.</p>
<p>ALEXANDER LEBED, 46. National security adviser and secretary of president's Security Council. Has no clear allies in Kremlin and has won enemies by making outspoken comments and signing a controversial peace deal to end fighting in Chechnya. He is in open conflict with Kulikov over the peace deal but Yeltsin, who sees Lebed as a counterweight to other forces in the Kremlin, has praised his peace moves. Lebed's main presidential rival is Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin but they have avoided open hostilities.</p>
<p>ANATOLY KULIKOV, 50. Interior Minister. Has played major role in Chechnya conflict since appointment in July 1995. He is accused by Lebed of deliberately dragging out fighting in Chechnya. Kulikov hit back at Lebed by saying his rival was planning to take power by force. Has no presidential ambitions but is widely depicted as pawn representing interests of groups who want to undermine Lebed. Chernomyrdin's presidential hopes might benefit from any blow struck against Lebed, but he has distanced himself from Kulikov's attacks on the Chechnya peace plan and from the minister's allegations that Lebed planned to seize power.</p>
<p>VIKTOR CHERNOMYRDIN, 58. Prime Minister. Stolid, pro-reform leader who will take over Yeltsin's duties temporarily when the Kremlin leader undergoes surgery. Has presented image of calm and kept his options open in the power struggle by avoiding open warfare with Lebed, although they could be presidential rivals. Has good relationship with Kremlin chief of staff Anatoly Chubais and both want Yeltsin to stay in office as long as possible because Chernomyrdin is not thought likely to beat Lebed in an early presidential election.</p>
<p>YURI LUZHKOV, 60. Moscow Mayor. Won landslide re-election last June. Says he has no immediate presidential ambitions but attacked his potential rivals in a recent newspaper interview. Sides with Kulikov over the Chechnya peace plan and, at least for now, seems to oppose Lebed. But he is keeping his options open for possible alliance-forming if presidential election is called early. Has good relationship with Yeltsin and smooth relations with Chernomyrdin, but history of feuding with Chubais.</p>
<p>GENNADY ZYUGANOV, 52. Communist Party leader. Was second to Yeltsin in presidential election last July but says he could win if the president stepped down now. Has recently forged wider alliance with other leftist and nationalist groups to strengthen the left's bid for power. His presidential ambitions are hampered by limited access to mass media, lack of charisma and few financial resources. Has criticised elements of Lebed's Chechnya peace plan but also blasted the policy long pursued by Kulikov. Russian media have speculated over whether he and Lebed might join forces if the security chief were sacked or quit.</p>
<p>ANATOLY CHUBAIS, 41. Head of presidential administration. Unlikely presidential challenger, at least for some years, but his post as Yeltsin's chief-of-staff gives him huge influence and makes him a potential kingmaker. Regarded as a master of behind-the-scenes intrigues who is widely thought anxious to clip Lebed's wings. Many commentators say he encouraged recent public attacks on former Yeltsin bodyguard Alexander Korzhakov who has formed a liaison with Lebed. Has long alliance with Chernomyrdin and is fierce critic of Zyuganov.</p>
<p>TATYANA DYACHENKO, 36. Yeltsin's daughter. She has no formal Kremlin post but helped organise her father's successful reelection campaign and is thought to have big influence on him. Independent Russian political analysts suggest she and Chubais share similar views in the power struggle, particularly over keeping Lebed in check. The analysts suggest she still has a powerful role behind the scenes but the extent of her influence remains unclear.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
