<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123293" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Oct 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Latvia - Oct 17.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the main stories in Latvian newspapers on Thursday. Prepared for Reuters by the Cooperation Fund. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Russia's biggest nuclear-powered aircraft carrier, Piotr Velikii, as well as two other warships, one of them a guided missile destroyer, entered Latvia's economic zone in the afternoon of October 15, only 23 nautical miles off the Latvian coast. Yesterday a Swedish reconnaissance aircraft, a J 37 Viggen, which flew at 200-700 metres from the warships, crashed into the sea. Some witnesses say the Swedish aircraft exploded in the air. Its pilot has still not been found.</p>
<p>- The Latvian foreign ministry expressed its serious concern over the Russian warships being in Latvia's economic zone without informing Latvia. The ministry asked Russian ambassador Alexander Rannikh for explanations.</p>
<p>- Deputy Prime Minister Ziedonis Chevers was examined yesterday by the Riga District Court as a witness in the case of an alleged leader of organised crime, Ivan Kharitonov.</p>
<p>- President Guntis Ulmanis met the commander of the Home guard, Juris Eihmanis, to hear his opinion on the failed arms deal with the Slovak company, Katrim Stella.</p>
<p>- State foreign ministry secretary Maris Riekstinsh said that although Latvia is not rejecting Lithuania's proposal to define the disputed sea border area, its size and the possibility of fixing its legal status are still being discussed by the two sides.</p>
<p>DIENA</p>
<p>- The largest ruling parties deny plotting against the government. They say they discussed the possibility of declaring a moratorium on any changes in the cabinet.</p>
<p>NEATKARIGA RITA AVIZE</p>
<p>- The culture ministry the culture workers trade union have agreed to cancel the strike of culture workers and to solve all disputes by means of negotiations.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
