<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123250" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Russian warships cause furore in Latvia.</title>
<headline>Russian warships cause furore in Latvia.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Latvia, sensitive to any sign of military activity by Russia, sought explanations on Thursday about the entry of three Russian warships into its waters, one of which witnessed the crash of a Swedish jet.</p>
<p>The nuclear warship Pyotr Veliky narrowly missed being hit by a Swedish air force reconnaissance jet, which crashed 200 metres (yards) from the vessel as it was scouting the area.</p>
<p>Latvia regained its independence from the former Soviet Union five years ago but suspicion of Russia, which ruled it for most of the last 200 years, still runs deep.</p>
<p>&quot;We expressed our concern about the long stay of Russian navy units not far from our territorial waters,&quot; Aivar Vovers, Foreign Ministry ambassador at large, told Reuters, saying the Russians did not inform Latvia of the ships' presence.</p>
<p>The Russians said Latvia's claims were baseless, he added.</p>
<p>The warships entered Latvia's economic zone of interest, 25 km (15 miles) from the coast, en route from St Petersburg to the Russian enclave of Kaliningrad, but did not enter its territorial waters, up to 12 km (7.5 miles) from the coast.</p>
<p>President Guntis Ulmanis said on television on Wednesday night that the incident showed Russia was not as friendly as it sometimes seemed, the news agency Baltic News Service (BNS) said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
