<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123359" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Accel units mull acquisitions.</title>
<headline>Accel units mull acquisitions.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Accel SA de CV, a Mexican holding company with interests in warehousing, clothing and contract manufacturing, is considering an expansion, a top official said Thursday.</p>
<p>Optimistic about growth prospects for all of Accel's businesses in 1997, Jesus Alvarez Morodo said Elamex SA de CV, the contract manufacturing unit, was in a sound economic position to make acquisitions, form partnerships or invest in new space.  </p>
<p>&quot;Elamex has a very strong economic capacity and we could take advantage to make acquisitions,&quot; he said in an interview this week.</p>
<p>He stressed that for Elamex, and for the firm's Florida-based clothing division, Tropical Sportswear Inc, purchases were being considered alongside other alternatives.</p>
<p>But the door was clearly open to expansion.</p>
<p>Asked about a possible stock issue by Tropical Sportswear International Inc, Morodo said no decision had been taken.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we followed that route -- and it's only an if -- it would be to give (Tropical) a much more accelerated growth capacity; it would enable us to think about buying competitors and change the scale and size of the company,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Elamex's readiness to grow was underpinned by a stock issue in early 1996 that virtually eliminated its debt.  The company, with plants on the U.S. border and in central Mexico, assembles goods under contract from firms like Nintendo Co Ltd. It earns dollars and has benefited from Mexico's December 1994 peso devaluation.</p>
<p>The other units were also seen picking up steam.  </p>
<p>&quot;In the first quarter (Tropical) was slow, but it had a very important (55 percent) recovery in the second quarter (versus Q1), and we have sufficient information to know that the third quarter was good,&quot; Alvarez Morodo said.</p>
<p>Referring to the warehousing unit in Mexico, he said it was still not seeing much pick-up in business, despite the rebound in Mexico's macroeconomic statistics.  Warehousing traditionally lags during an economic recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that perspectives for 1997 will be much better than they have been in 1995 and 1996...it depends how fast the Mexican economy grows,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Henry Tricks, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9560</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
