<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123358" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil deficit pressured by states' finances.</title>
<headline>Brazil deficit pressured by states' finances.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's operational public sector deficit will end the year at 3.5 percent of gross domestic product because of the worse-than-expected finances of the states and lower-than-foreseen revenue, an official said.</p>
<p>Murilo Portugal, head of the National Treasury, confirmed to reporters the government had raised its operational deficit forecast from an original 2.5 percent of GDP.  </p>
<p>He said the states were contributing to a bleaker fiscal situation because the Treasury was having to loan them money to pay off salary arrears and for advance outlays on voluntary redundancy programmes.</p>
<p>He added, &quot;(Tax) revenue has not evolved as we had hoped in the second half of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>Portugal said revenue, which had been expected to pick up along with the economic recovery, had actually decreased.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a decrease which we did not predict,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Finance Minister Pedro Malan last Friday first confirmed the government had raised its forecast of the 1996 operational deficit to 3.5 percent of GDP, bringing the official view more in line with market estimates.</p>
<p>At the beginning of the year, the government had pledged to halve last year's 5.0 percent of GDP operational deficit.</p>
<p>Portugal, reiterating Malan's expectation that a cost-cutting and revenue-raising package announced last Friday would improve the fiscal accounts next year, said 1997 should see an operational deficit of 2.5 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
