<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123369" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine govt. on defensive against graft charges.</title>
<headline>Argentine govt. on defensive against graft charges.</headline>
<byline>Gary Regenstreif</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina's ruling party rallied to defend the government against charges of corruption in the Cabinet on Thursday while President Carlos Menem moved to demonstrate his determination to stamp out graft.</p>
<p>Former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo's allegations this week that two ministers covered up corruption and manipulated judges put the opposition on the offensive and unsettled financial markets.</p>
<p>A Menem aide said &quot;not one word&quot; about the accusations was discussed in Thursday's Cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;There was an agenda and this was not important enough for the president,&quot; the aide, who requested anonymity, said in an interview. &quot;We cannot let this be an impediment for us to carry on with our policies.&quot;</p>
<p>Cavallo, who first denounced &quot;mafias&quot; in public services a year ago, said on Tuesday Interior Minister Carlos Corach tried to remove a judge from investigating a gold-export fraud case and replace him with another who found no evidence of crime.</p>
<p>Cavallo, whom Menem sacked nearly three months ago after a running battle between himself and the Peronist old guard, also said both Corach and Justice Minister Elias Jassan were manipulating judges and state prosecutors.</p>
<p>Argentina's Senate late on Wednesday rejected a motion filed by the opposition Radical Party to question the ministers after the Peronist caucus, which has an absolute Senate majority, turned it down after a long debate.</p>
<p>Menem, who has sought to take the initiative on corruption to boost his poor standings in the polls, on Thursday visited an Air Force hangar where smuggled goods seized at a customs office were displayed to the media.</p>
<p>&quot;Those responsible will go to prison,&quot; Menem told reporters. &quot;It was critical to strike a blow as we have to break up these kinds of activities.&quot;</p>
<p>Since making his accusations, Cavallo has said he has no documentation or other proof. Menem dismissed them as &quot;lies.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He says he has no proof,&quot; said Jorge Matzkin, leader of the Peronist bloc in the lower house of Congress. &quot;Get serious.&quot;</p>
<p>But many Argentines appear to believe Cavallo.</p>
<p>Eighty-one percent of respondents to a poll by pollsters Ricardo Rouvier, published in the daily El Cronista Thursday, said they thought the allegations were probably true.</p>
<p>Early on Thursday, Corach said he would make good on his earlier threat and launch a lawsuit against Cavallo on Friday.</p>
<p>Late on Wednesday, Cavallo gave his support to the president. &quot;I have always supported President Menem. Now that he will face the mafias I will help him even more.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
