<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123499" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Withdrawal of Indonesian editor's licence slammed.</title>
<headline>Withdrawal of Indonesian editor's licence slammed.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's Alliance of Independent Journalists (AJI) said on Thursday the country's official journalists' union was helping authorities restrict media freedom by withdrawing a magazine editor's licence.</p>
<p>The government-backed Indonesian Journalists' Association (PWI) said on Wednesday it had withdrawn the editing licence of Goesti Emran, editor-in-chief of the weekly Detektip &amp; Romantiak (D&amp;R) magazine, because he employed members of the unrecognised AJI.</p>
<p>The removal of the licence could lead to the magazine closing down, because under Indonesia's strict press laws such official approval is needed for before a publication can go to print.</p>
<p>&quot;We are critical of the actions of a journalists' organisation which constricts the creative opportunities for all journalists,&quot; Santoso, head of the AJI presidium, said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Moreover, it puts that journalists' organisation in a position which is subordinated to authority. Humiliatingly, (the PWI) has let itself become an instrument for the restriction of the freedom of the press in our country.&quot;</p>
<p>On Thursday, AJI members went to the official National Commission on Human Rights to complain about the PWI decision.</p>
<p>AJI was formed in reaction to the banning of three outspoken weekly publications -- Tempo, Editor and DeTik -- by the government in June 1994.</p>
<p>A number of its members have been removed from their jobs since its formation in what media watchers say is a result of government pressure on editors.</p>
<p>Three people associated with a former publication of AJI were jailed last year for spreading hatred against the president.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
