<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123497" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Borrowing big in Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Borrowing big in Hong Kong.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian debt markets offered more evidence on Thursday that Hong Kong banks and companies are looking to borrow big before year-end.</p>
<p>Market sources said Bank of East Asia may issue a three-year HK$1.8 billion floating rate certificates of deposit issue before the end of 1996.</p>
<p>The sources said they expect the bank will apply to the Hong Kong Monetary Authority to accept the issue as eligible for its Liquidity Adjustment Facility (LAF), or discount window.</p>
<p>Eligibility for LAF makes an issue more attractive to banks because holders of the qualifying debt can engage in repurchase agreements with the monetary authority, increasing liquidity.</p>
<p>Bank of East Asia is rated A3 by Moody's Investors Service.</p>
<p>Sources said Bank of East Asia is close to awarding a mandate. Company officials could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>In February, the bank completed a HK$2 billion three-year LAF FRCD that paid an all-in return of 48 basis points over the three-month Hong Kong Interbank Offered Rate.</p>
<p>Other bank issues also are expected.</p>
<p>Most bankers predict that Dao Heng Bank will launch a LAF-eligible deal before year-end, while some are betting that Dah Sing Bank will come to market as well.</p>
<p>Wing Lung Bank reportedly is seeking a HK$500 million deal. The bank privately placed a HK$200 million FRCD last month.</p>
<p>Schroders Asia is tipped to have won the mandate to arrange a HK$600 million FRCD for Shanghai Commercial Bank.</p>
<p>Details on the fee structure for the US$500 million funding for Chinese Estates' guaranteed Good Top emerged on Thursday.</p>
<p>The financing combines an FRN tranche and a term loan/revolving credit tranche. Lenders may participate in the FRN and/or the loan tranches, although those participating in the loan tranche must commit 35 percent to the term loan and 65 percent to the revolving credit.</p>
<p>The facility can be put by the lenders at the end of three years and can be called by Chinese Estates annually.</p>
<p>The interest margin for both the FRN and the loan tranches is set at 165 basis points for years one through three and 190 basis points for year four and five.</p>
<p>Bankers said fees are 72.5 basis points for co-arrangers taking US$25 million, 67.5 basis points for co-arrangers taking US$20 million, 55 basis points for lead managers taking US$11-15 million, 47.5 basis points for senior managers taking US$6-10 million and 40 basis points for managers taking US$3-5 million.</p>
<p>Chase Manhattan Asia, China Development Finance Co HK, Citicorp International, Deutsche Bank Hong Kong, Hua Chiao Commercial Bank, Peregrine Fixed Income, American Express Bank and BA Asia are arrangers.</p>
<p>On the loan side, bankers said consortium members are still reviewing bids for the HK$6.4 billion financing for Hong Kong's Belcher Gardens. Bids were based on the percentage of the guarantee provided by the most highly regarded consortium member, Sun Hung Kai Properties.</p>
<p>Bankers also are bidding on a loan to finance phase two of the Tai Kok Tsui development project.</p>
<p>Chevalier is looking for about HK$1.3 billion for a private sector participation scheme (PSPS) property development project. The deal is reported to have a tenor of 2.5 or three years. It may be completed as a club deal, bankers said.</p>
<p>In other news, one of South Korea's newest merchant banks, Kumho, launched a US$50 million, five-year final, three-year put FRCD. It pays an all-in of 81 basis points.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371 fax (852) 2845-0636</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
