<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123496" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Euroyen firm in late trade on revised data.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Euroyen firm in late trade on revised data.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen futures were firmer in late trade on Thursday on the back of the stronger yen and revised industrial production data, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said trading was light with market participants reluctant to take fresh positions ahead of the Japanese elections next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The Euroyen was supported by the strong yen in the afternoon and also the revised industrial production data for August which showed more weakness,&quot; said a dealer with an Asian futures firm.  </p>
<p>August industrial production was revised down to -2.3 percent from the preliminary release of -1.9 percent.</p>
<p>The dealer said there was no clear direction for Euroyen, which seems to be consolidating around current levels.</p>
<p>The new lead Euroyen futures contract, June 1997, settled at 99.13 against a CME close at 99.09 while March was at 99.30 against 99.27. Turnover for both months combined was more than 9,000 contracts.</p>
<p>Japanese goverment bond futures were also firmer with December contracts at 122.81 in late trade against an open at 122.45.  </p>
<p>Eurodollar futures were little changed in late trade. Activity was light and trading was confined to within a two-tick range.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market needed fresh leads after the September consumer price data overnight came in within market expections.</p>
<p>A dealer said the lead March contract would see support at 94.25 on the downside.</p>
<p>March Eurodollars settled at 94.27 unchanged from their IMM close of 94.27 while December was 94.35, against a 94.36 previous close.  </p>
<p>-- Doreen Siow 65-87030892</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
