<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123561" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Middle East negotiators struggle to save peace.</title>
<headline>Middle East negotiators struggle to save peace.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>TABA, Egypt 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian negotiators struggled on Thursday to break a deadlock in talks on a long-promised Israeli troop pullback in the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, speaking to the London-based Arabic newspaer al-Hayat, said of the negotiations: &quot;I do not expect they will be easy.&quot;</p>
<p>In tension-packed Hebron itself, Israeli police pulled down a fence that Jewish settlers had begun erecting around an Arab-owned hilltop.</p>
<p>The settlers hammered spikes around the sparsely planted hilltop and began extending barbed wire, sparking a row with Palestinian landowners, witnesses said. Police separated the two sides and ordered the settlers to halt the work.</p>
<p>In Taba, in Egypt next to the Israeli border, negotiators meeting for a second day said U.S. peace envoy Dennis Ross had detailed points of understandings which could become the basis for a Hebron deal.</p>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian negotiators were meeting elsewhere -- away from media scrutiny -- to hammer out a deal, officials said. But in Taba the differences appeared to run deep.</p>
<p>Palestinian negotiators said they had offered Israel a &quot;road map&quot; or &quot;protocol&quot; for carrying out the 1995 peace deal that includes Hebron and other issues.</p>
<p>Israeli chief negotiator Dan Shomron countered: &quot;We want to focus on the Hebron issue. This is our priority. And then we can speak about other issues.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel has held up a troop pullback from Hebron, citing security concerns for the 400 Jews who live and study in enclaves among 100,000 Arabs. The city is sacred to Moslems and Jews as the burial place of the biblical Abraham.</p>
<p>The deployment, due to have taken place in March, was delayed by Islamic suicide bombings in Israel and was later put off by Israel's right-wing government elected in May.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not pessimistic,&quot; Ross told reporters when he met Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat in Gaza. &quot;We are all determined to do all we can to produce results as soon as possible.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEAST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TABA, Egypt"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
