<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123592" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares jump 2.4 pct to new record.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares jump 2.4 pct to new record.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The market index at Istanbul's stock exchange leapt 2.43 percent in selective activity to a new record on Thursday in positive mood after a censure motion against the government was rejected on Wednesday, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 rose 1,889.56 points from Wednesday to close at an all-time high of 79,719.25, compared to a previous high of 79,511.82 last Wednesday.</p>
<p>Trade volume soared to 24.2 trillion lira ($255 million) from Wednesday's 16.4 trillion ($173 million) with the help of limited cash entry, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market showed a tendency to ease in the second session. But such fluctuations will continue tomorrow and early next week as the market targets the 80,000 level with share-based buying,&quot; said Haldun Sertel from Can securities.</p>
<p>Selective demand was based mainly on nine-month profit expectations.</p>
<p>Brokers said easier Treasury-bill yields and statements that the Treasury would not borrow from domestic markets until November could divert some more cash to the bourse.</p>
<p>The index had lost 2 2 percent in a week-long correction to Wednesday after surging 22.7 percent from September 13 to last Wednesday's sixth consequtive record close of 79,511.82.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
