<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123589" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: U.S. envoy to meet Iraqi Kurd leader in Turkey.</title>
<headline>U.S. envoy to meet Iraqi Kurd leader in Turkey.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior U.S. diplomat is to hold talks in Turkey this week with pro-Baghdad Iraqi Kurdish leader Massoud Barzani, a Turkish foreign ministry official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) leader Barzani has threatened to again ask Baghdad for help against a rival militia, in a blow to U.S. mediation efforts to a Kurdish conflict in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;Assistant Secretary of State Robert Pelletreau will come to Turkey tomorrow. He will meet us, and Massoud Barzani,&quot; the Turkish official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Washington announced on Wednesday that Pelletreau would visit the Middle East to meet separately with Barzani and Jalal Talabani, head of the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>The United States fears Iraq and Iran may benfit from the latest Kurdish fighting, which broke out again late last week when Talabani's forces started to retake territory lost last month in fighting.</p>
<p>The Turkish official declined to say where in Turkey the Barzani meeting would take place but diplomatic sources said it could be in a town near the Iraqi-Turkish border.</p>
<p>Barzani told a news conference on Thursday that he may ask Baghdad for backing against Talabani's advancing forces.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Kurdish people are under hard pressure of the PUK, we will ask for help from Iraq,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Iraqi troops and tanks helped Barzani take the key city of Arbil in late August in an alliance that prompted U.S. missile trikes on targets in southern Iraq.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
