<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123633" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chrysler hit with new car ban in California.</title>
<headline>Chrysler hit with new car ban in California.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>In a blow to Chrysler Corp., California's Department of Motor Vehicles Thursday banned the automaker from supplying new vehicles to dealers in the state for 45 days.</p>
<p>The decision, which stems from alleged &quot;Lemon Law&quot; violations, would prevent Chrysler from shipping new cars and trucks into the nation's largest car market. However, the ban, which would take effect on Nov. 25, would not prevent dealers from selling cars that are already on their lots or servicing vehicles.</p>
<p>Chrysler, which has steadfastly denied any wrongdoing, said it plans to appeal.</p>
<p>In May, an administrative law judge found Chrysler guilty of 116 violations of the state's Lemon Law, citing the automaker's failure to notify used car customers that the vehicles they were buying were returned by their original owners because they were lemons.</p>
<p>At the time, Judge Keith Levy had recommended a 60-day suspension but the agency reduced it to 45 days after dealers complained the penalty would seriously hurt their business.</p>
<p>&quot;The action taken today is taken against Chrysler Corporation, not corporation dealerships in California,&quot; Department of Motor Vehicles Director Sally Reed said. &quot;Prohibiting the restocking of vehicles for 45 days, coupled with other sanctions, sends the strongest message to Chrysler Corporation, but should have less effect on innocent parties.&quot;</p>
<p>The agency banned Chrysler from re-selling so-called &quot;Lemon Law&quot; buybacks and re-selling good-will repurchases within the state for three years and put the No. 3 U.S. automaker on probation for three years.</p>
<p>Under the state's lemon law, an automaker must buy back a car from a first owner if it spends 30 days in a repair shop during first year of ownership, or if specific problem hasn't been fixed after 3 attempts.</p>
<p>Consumer advocates quickly praised the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the equivalent of putting a corporation behind bars by taking them off the street,&quot; said Clarence Ditlow, a longtime consumer advocate and executive director of the Centre for Auto Safety in Washington, D.C. &quot;It's a landmark day for consumers.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that the DMV's penalty was the first action tough enough to deter so-called lemon laundering.</p>
<p>&quot;The only way to stop lemon laundering is to suspend a corporation from doing business. If you fine them, they ignore it, they consider it a cost of doing business and they continue laundering lemons,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a statement, Chrysler said it planned to appeal the decision to the state's New Motor Vehicle Board, an independent body set up to review regulatory decisions on cars and trucks in California.</p>
<p>Chrysler said the decision will not become effective, if at all, until the appeals process is exhausted.</p>
<p>&quot;Unlike the DMV, the board is set up to provide an impartial review of regulatory actions,&quot; the company said. &quot;The DMV had asked the administrative law judge to review the economic impact of his earlier decision. California dealers presented substantial, unrefuted evidence of economic harm to their dealerships and California consumers.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The DMV has essentially ignored this evidence of harm to California citizens, just as it ignored evidence of Chrysler's compliance with California law.&quot;</p>
<p>Chrysler spokesman James Crawford said the appeals process could take a long time to complete, and the matter could eventually wind up in a civil courtroom.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't expect them to ignore all the evidence that they apparently did, but i don't think anyone's surprised by it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The vehicles in question were sold in 1992. Chrysler contends the cars were sold to dealers at auctions and the automaker supplied a disclosure notice and unlimited 12-month warranty with every vehicle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
