<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123758" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US grain rail and truck transport running smoothly.</title>
<headline>US grain rail and truck transport running smoothly.</headline>
<byline>Anna Driver</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the early stages of this year's delayed harvest in the U.S. Midwest, rail and barge traffic is slow but running smoothly, merchants and grain transportation officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've had thousands and thousands of cars sitting around waiting for something to put in them,&quot; said Ed Trandahl, with Union Pacific Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;We're poised to handle a lot of grain, but there's a lot out there that hasn't been harvested,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Railcar grain loadings for the week ended October 12 were 32 percent above the previous week's, but 9.5 percent below year-ago levels, according to data from the Association of American Railroads.</p>
<p>Cash grain merchants throughout the Midwest said no major problems have cropped up yet, partly because farmers have plenty left to harvest and many are storing rather than selling grain.</p>
<p>One grain transportation manager for a Missouri cooperative said that the new car programs that Union Pacific and Burlington Northern Santa Fe Corp put in place this year &quot;should also smooth things out.&quot;  </p>
<p>In anticipation of a busy year, Union Pacific increased total locomotive capacity by 15 percent and added 3,300 grain cars that carry larger amounts of grain, Trandahl said.</p>
<p>Most of this harvest season's barge traffic has been soybean movement, because the Midwest's wet spring delayed planting of both corn and soybeans, said Morris Larson, executive vice president of the St. Louis Merchant's Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;It's late, and if the weather holds, we'll have a harvest with a long tail,&quot; Larson said. &quot;We could see heavy harvest movement as late as mid-November.&quot;  </p>
<p>The U.S. Agriculture Department reported Tuesday that the U.S. soybean harvest was 40 percent complete as of Sunday, behind a five-year average of 52 percent. The corn harvest was 20 percent done, which lagged the average pace of 34 percent.</p>
<p>Larson said he expected a busy barge traffic season based on increased soybean and corn production estimates as well as higher-than-earlier-expected yields for the U.S. crops.</p>
<p>He noted that water levels in the mid- and upper-Mississippi River were currently low, which could cause problems with ice if the harvest was delayed significantly.</p>
<p>Some transportation managers reported rail car delays for shipments of fertilizer to Midwestern farmers.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just too many consumers wanting the product (fertilizer),&quot; said Dan Weber, with Indianapolis-based Countrymark Cooperative Inc..</p>
<p>Typically, farmers buy fertilizer in August. But prices in August were not attractive, so many waited until three weeks ago to buy, Weber said. The resulting surge in demand has created a rail car bottleneck, he added.</p>
<p>At this time of year, producers use fertilzer for winter wheat planting and preparation of corn fields for next spring, Weber said.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408 8720</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
