<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123771" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. would support arms embargo on Afghanistan.</title>
<headline>U.S. would support arms embargo on Afghanistan.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said Thursday it would be willing to support an international arms embargo on Afghanistan in a bid to end the long civil war there.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said the demilitarization of Kabul, captured last month by the Islamic fundamentalist Taleban movement, could also help but it was premature to discuss an international peace-keeping force.</p>
<p>All three proposals have been floated this week at the United Nations. Discussions there on a possible Security Council resolution are continuing behind the scenes but nothing has been tabled so far.</p>
<p>Although Taleban has seized up to three quarters of Afghanistan, forces of the ousted government under Ahmad Shah Masood have counter-attacked north of the capital in recent days, recapturing some towns.</p>
<p>Burns told a news briefing the United States would be willing to support a U.N. ban on arms sales to Afghanistan.</p>
<p>&quot;Countries are supplying these factions with arms, and they should stop. The countries surrounding Afghanistan ought to end their active involvement in inflaming this fighting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While some countries have backed an arms embargo at the U.N., others say it would be impossible to enforce.</p>
<p>Burns said another proposal advanced at a U.N. debate Wednesday to demilitarize Kabul was &quot;an important idea which we think could be useful and positive in the future&quot;.</p>
<p>But he said calls for an international peace-keeping force were &quot;probably premature at the present time&quot;.</p>
<p>Burns said Washington wanted &quot;a balanced, unbiased resolution which would call for an end to the fighting, which would call for reconciliation among the factions, and which condemns human rights abuses, including the gross human rights abuses against women and girls by the Taleban.&quot;</p>
<p>Despite initial hopes in Washington that Taleban might impose peace across Afghanistan, it has not done so, and its Islamic restrictions on women have given the movement an increasingly bad press in the United States.</p>
<p>Burns' comments Thursday suggested a revival of sympathy for the ousted government of Burhanuddin Rabbani.</p>
<p>&quot;We ought to let these Afghan factions try to sit down as was suggested yesterday by the former government, sit down and try to work out their problems and end the fighting which has victimised the entire population of the country,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
