<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123818" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. urges N.Iraq truce, Kurds want guarantees.</title>
<headline>U.S. urges N.Iraq truce, Kurds want guarantees.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Thursday pressed one of two Kurdish factions battling in northern Iraq for an immediate ceasefire, but the Kurds said they wanted assurances any accord would be respected by their rivals.</p>
<p>U.S. officials repeated warnings to Iraq and Iran to stay out of the conflict, saying any attempt by Baghdad to intervene militarily would be a &quot;grave mistake&quot;.</p>
<p>The talks between State Department officials and the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) opened a new U.S. initiative to end fighting between the KDP and the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) in Western-protected northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Assistant Secretary of State for Near Eastern Affairs, Robert Pelletreau, will set out for the Middle East at the weekend for separate talks with the leaders of both groups.</p>
<p>Pelletreau and other officials met KDP officials for four and a half hours on Thursday.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said they made the &quot;clear point ... that the KDP and the PUK need to move very quickly toward an immediate cease-fire&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;They need to commit themselves to a restoration of the political dialogue that had been under way until August 30 of this year (and) to pay attention to the humanitarian concerns of the Kurdish people in northern Iraq, which are being adversely affected by the continued fighting,&quot; Burns added.</p>
<p>But KDP spokesman Hoshyar Zebari said: &quot;Our question was what assurances we have that tomorrow we will have a ceasefire and it will not be violated.&quot;</p>
<p>He said U.S. officials had promised that &quot;they will try to work more actively to ensure any ceasefire or settlement should stick&quot;.</p>
<p>A U.S. statement on the talks said U.S. officials urged the KDP to ensure the safety of humanitarian relief workers in areas they control and stressed that both factions bore responsibility for reconciliation.</p>
<p>Fighting which erupted between the two groups in August has seriously weakened the U.S. position in northern Iraq, forcing the evacuation of U.S. aid, military and intelligence operations and threatening to draw in Iraq and Iran.</p>
<p>The KDP invited in regular Iraqi forces to help it capture the key city of Arbil at the end of August. The KDP then took control of most of the region, but a recent PUK counter-offensive has recaptured much of the territory.</p>
<p>Burns expressed concern at reports -- apparently stemming from a PUK statement issued in Paris -- that Iraqi troops might again be on the move, and said any such move would be &quot;a grave mistake&quot; by Iraqi President Saddam Hussein.</p>
<p>But U.S. defence officials said they saw no sign of this. &quot;There is no movement. We do not see it,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>KDP leader Massoud Barzani warned on Thursday in northern Iraq, however, that he might again ask Baghdad for help against the PUK.</p>
<p>Burns said no time or place had been set for Pelletreau's meetings next week with Barzani and PUK leader Jalal Talabani. But KDP and Turkish officials said they expected both meetings to take place in Turkey.</p>
<p>Although the meetings are separate, Sami Abdurrahman, head of the KDP delegation in Washington, said he did not exclude direct peace talks with the PUK under certain conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;We have never refused talks,&quot; Abdurrahman told reporters. But, he added: &quot;If somebody pledges to make talks and to make a ceasefire, then when he breaks the ceasefire he should be condemned, he should pay for it.&quot;</p>
<p>Abdurrahman charged that the PUK had started the latest round of fighting by breaking a ceasefire on Aug. 17.</p>
<p>He defended the KDP decision to invite help from Baghdad, saying it was to &quot;counterbalance the Iranian aggression&quot; in support of the PUK. Both Iran and the PUK have denied that Tehran is aiding the group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
