<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123994" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole takes gamble by targeting California.</title>
<headline>Dole takes gamble by targeting California.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Croft</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bob Dole is taking a gamble in deciding to make an all-out effort to win vote-rich California in next month's election, political analysts say.</p>
<p>The Republican presidential candidate's campaign has decided to devote diminishing resources of time and money to trying to erase President Bill Clinton's lead in California and carry the state on Nov. 5, state party sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;California is the battleground,&quot; one source said. &quot;It's very close and it's winnable.&quot;</p>
<p>Lagging by double digits in many national polls, Dole must try to forge a strategy to win enough states to give him the 270 electoral college votes needed to capture the White House.</p>
<p>Polls show Clinton ahead in important Midwestern and Northeastern states and, until recently, he was considered to have a virtual lock on California, the most populous state and biggest prize with 54 electoral college votes. Clinton, who won California in the 1992 election, has visited 27 times since then, underlining its importance for the Democrat.</p>
<p>But several recent polls have shown Clinton's lead in California shrinking, although still large. A poll last week by the independent Field Institute showed Clinton leading by 10 points in California, down from 22 points in September.</p>
<p>The New York Times reported this week that Dole campaign officials had tentatively decided last weekend to pour resources into California while pulling back in other important states like New Jersey and Ohio.</p>
<p>Dale Neugebauer, the Dole campaign's California press secretary, declined comment on the reported strategy switch but said Dole could carry the state. &quot;We plan to run a very competitive campaign in California. We have been buying television (advertising) in substantial levels. We plan to continue to do that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Bruce Cain, professor of political science at the University of California at Berkeley, said the Dole campaign was &quot;grasping at straws&quot; with its California plan and said it was &quot;a sign of desperation&quot; that one opinion poll could have had such an impact on its strategy.</p>
<p>Cain said the $4 million mentioned in some reports as the amount the Dole campaign believed an aggressive campaign in California would cost was &quot;a drop in the California bucket.&quot; Noting that more than $40 million has been spent in recent U.S. Senate races there, he said it was an extremely expensive state to campaign in and to do it in a half-hearted way was &quot;potentially a big waste of money.&quot;</p>
<p>Political analysts see television advertising as crucial to a successful campaign in California and the state has at least six major media markets.</p>
<p>Cain said Dole could not win in California, barring some unforeseen setback for Clinton in the next three weeks, because &quot;economic recovery in the state has put a glow on the incumbent&quot; that other issues Dole might raise would not overcome. The state's economy has recovered sharply from deep recession in 1992.</p>
<p>Clinton himself made that point during Wednesday night's debate with Dole in San Diego. &quot;If you believe that the California economy was better in 1992 than it is today, you should vote for Bob Dole,&quot; he told voters.</p>
<p>Sherry Bebitch Jeffe, a political analyst at California's Claremont Graduate School, said a California strategy was a risk but had several potential benefits for Dole, apart from the outside chance he could win.</p>
<p>It would force Clinton to spend time in California and could energise the Republican base in the state, she said. A good Republican turnout in California is regarded as crucial to the party's hopes of retaining control of the U.S. House of Representatives as well as the California Assembly.</p>
<p>The downside of the strategy is that California would consume Dole's time and money that could have been spent in other states. &quot;Does he trade off time in California for time in Florida or Texas, or time in Ohio?&quot; Jeffe asked.</p>
<p>She believed it would be difficult for Dole to close the gap on Clinton barring a major error by the president or an unexpected event. Clinton's lead could narrow to eight percentage points in the state, she said, but &quot;I don't see the arithmetic beyond that.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
