<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="123945" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FORECAST - Growing U.S. trade gap in '97 may cap dlr.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - Growing U.S. trade gap in '97 may cap dlr.</headline>
<byline>Roanne Daniels</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. trade deficit will steadily deteriorate in 1997, putting political and corporate pressure on the dollar exchange rate from moving too high against other leading currencies, economists said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In 1997, analysts assume the U.S. economy will outperform that of Europe and Japan, encouraging U.S. imports over exports and expanding the U.S. trade deficit, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;The forecasted deteriorating trade numbers do not bode well for the dollar,&quot; said Gail Fosler, chief economist at The Conference Board.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's one of the reasons why we think the dollar's upside is bounded. Looking at the dollar versus the mark, we think the dollar is at or very near its high and it is overvalued versus the yen,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The dollar traded around 112.20 yen and 1.5440 marks in early U.S. trade on Thursday. The dollar hit a 33-month high against the yen on Tuesday, and a 4-1/2-month peak against the mark earlier Thursday.  </p>
<p>A Reuter poll of 14 economists showed, on average, the current account balance of payments deficit is expected to widen to $160.9 billion in 1997 from $159.7 billion this year.</p>
<p>&quot;What will drive the decline is the U.S. economy drawing in imports; maybe some deterioration in export growth, but not a huge amount,&quot; said David Blitzer, chief economist at Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
<p>These forecasts come on the heels of a record monthly drop in the July trade deficit to $11.68 billion. The August figure, scheduled to be released early Friday, October 18, is expected to show a marked improvement to an $8.5 billion shortfall.  </p>
<p>The U.S. bilateral trade deficit with Japan deteriorated sharply to $4.3 billion in July from $3.2 billion in June. This was the largest deficit in nine months and mainly the result of a stronger dollar, Merrill Lynch research said.</p>
<p>A stronger dollar relative to other currencies discourages U.S. exports as U.S. goods become relatively more expensive for foreign buyers paying in their domestic currency.</p>
<p>Economists said the U.S. Treasury this year adopted a strong dollar policy, a typical occurrence during a presidential election year, adding that they expect support for the greenback to falter after the election.  </p>
<p>&quot;The administration actually is talking the dollar up despite objections from powerful industrialists like the Big Three auto makers, which have complained about where the dollar is already,&quot; said Christopher Low, senior economist at HSBC Markets Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect that line to be dropped pretty quickly after the election,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On September 19, Chrysler Corp chief executive Robert Eaton said he believed the dollar was overvalued against the yen and should be trading at a rate of about 100 yen to the dollar.</p>
<p>Eaton said the exchange rate, which at that time was about 109 yen to the dollar, was giving a price advantage to Japanese auto makers.</p>
<p>Economists said the outcome of the election is inconsequential to the dollar as either a Republican or Democratic administration will use the dollar as a tool to crack down on a ballooning trade deficit.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1677</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
