<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124023" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Chirac urges unity as coalition critics rap budget.</title>
<headline>Chirac urges unity as coalition critics rap budget.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac called for unity in his centre-right coalition on Thursday after the junior UDF partner criticised tax provisions in the 1997 budget bill.</p>
<p>Chirac used a lunch with parliamentarians of his Gaullist Rally For the Republic, senior partner in the coalition, to call for both parties to close ranks in the run-up to 1998 general elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Chirac's last message is &quot;Let's be United'. Everything which contributes to dividing the coalition is bad for it,&quot; Michel Pericard, president of the Gaullist group at the National Assembly, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's clear that when we appear divided, when we shoot ourselves in the foot, we can never win,&quot; echoed deputy Renaud Muselier.</p>
<p>In the latest sign of division inside the coalition, the Union for French Democracy (UDF) urged the government to start cutting Value Added Tax and drop plans to increase excise duties on petrol.</p>
<p>Guests at Chirac's lunch included his defeated presidential rival, ex-prime minister Edouard Balladur, who has repeatedly criticised the government's economic policies. The Gaullist heavyweight would only say afterwards that the lunch had been &quot;very pleasant&quot;.</p>
<p>Later on Thursday, Prime Minister Alain Juppe met UDF leaders including Francois Leotard who had said on Monday he would push for cuts in VAT and a rethink of the petrol duty increases.</p>
<p>&quot;It's up to the parliamentary debate to resolve the issues, but this meeting was a very friendly one,&quot; Juppe of the RPR told reporters after seeing Leotard, former justice minister Pierre Mehaignerie and parliamentarian Gilles de Robien.</p>
<p>Mehaignerie said &quot;we saw there was much that we agreed on but there were still one or two differences&quot;.</p>
<p>Petrol duties are due to be raised by about six centimes (one U.S. cent) a litre under the budget. The increases are to partially offset government plans to reduce income tax by 25 billion francs (U.S.$5 billion) next year as part of a proposed five-year reduction totalling 75 billion francs ($15 billion).</p>
<p>Tens of thousands of demonstrators marched through Paris and cities across France as a 24-hour public employees' strike against record unemployment and government cutbacks hit rail, air, school and postal services.</p>
<p>Many schools closed, domestic and short-haul flights were drastically reduced and only one train in three was running in the first major labour unrest since a crippling public sector strike which lasted nearly four weeks in late 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
