<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124017" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. arms chief to look for missing Iraqi missiles.</title>
<headline>U.N. arms chief to look for missing Iraqi missiles.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chief U.N. weapons inspector Rolf Ekeus said on Thursday it would be a &quot;major achievement&quot; if Iraq accounted for a number of missiles capable of carrying biological or chemical warfare agents.</p>
<p>&quot;So it is not a theoretical or accounting problem. It is a real matter of life and death for the states in the region, and therefore we cannot rest until we have accounted for them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ekeus, who in the past has said between six and 16 Iraqi missiles remained unaccounted for, was to leave New York late on Thursday and arrive in Baghdad on Saturday.</p>
<p>He spoke to reporters after briefing Security Council members on his latest written report, issued last Friday, which said Iraq might still be hiding small but significant quantities of forbidden weapons including missiles and chemical and biological warfare agents.</p>
<p>&quot;It is necessary to account for these missiles capable of delivering biological warfare agents or advanced high-quality chemical warfare agents,&quot; Ekeus said. &quot;There is a very serious problem of missiles and the counting of missiles. That would be a major achievement if that could be settled.&quot;</p>
<p>Ridding Iraq of nuclear, chemical and biological weapons is a key requirement for lifting stringent trade sanctions imposed after Baghdad's troops invaded Kuwait in August 1990.</p>
<p>Iraq gave Ekeus' deputy Charles Duelfer, who was in Baghdad this month, nine letters attempting to clarify its disclosure of banned weapons after the U.N. official told the press Iraq's original declarations were flawed and incomplete.</p>
<p>Ekeus said 48 Iraqi missiles were handed over and destroyed under U.N. supervision after the Gulf War, under a U.N. resolution requiring the scrapping of Baghdad's weapons of mass destruction.</p>
<p>But Iraq kept 85 &quot;operational, long-range top-quality missiles,&quot; which in 1992 it finally admitted having concealed. It then said they had been destroyed and took U.N. inspectors to the site where they were said to have been scrapped.</p>
<p>The inspectors had since tried to identify the remnants &quot;with the help of data from the supplier of these missiles -- the then-Soviet Union,&quot; Ekeus said. &quot;And we have still not found that remnants from all missiles are there. There are a number of missiles not accounted for.&quot;</p>
<p>This meant that either Iraq had had a separate secret missile-destruction operation &quot;or Iraq has not destroyed them at all and Iraq still keeps that amount of missiles,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>During the Gulf War, Saudi Arabia and Israel were each hit by about 40 Iraqi missiles armed with conventional explosive warheads. Iraq also launched missiles against Iran during their 1980-88 war.</p>
<p>American U.N. envoy Madeleine Albright said Ekeus had given council members a detailed explanation of the &quot;cynical hide-and-seek game that (Iraqi President) Saddam Hussein is playing.&quot;</p>
<p>British U.N. envoy Sir John Weston said Ekeus had had to &quot;struggle against what he described as an organised mechanism of concealment.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
