<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124152" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan Taleban hold anti-foreign protest.</title>
<headline>Afghan Taleban hold anti-foreign protest.</headline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Afghanistan's Taleban administration in Kabul staged its first demonstration in the capital on Thursday to protest against what it called foreign interference by India, Russia and Iran.</p>
<p>Hundreds of demonstrators, most of them civil servants, were joined by several thousand onlookers who followed the procession on its more than one mile (1-1/2 km ) march to the Iranian embassy and United Nations political office in Kabul.</p>
<p>The protest, the first in the capital since the purist Islamic movement took over the capital nearly three weeks ago, ended with demonstrators calling on the United Nations to recognise the Taleban government.</p>
<p>&quot;Death to interventionists! Down with Iran and Russia!&quot; chanted a Taleban preacher through a megaphone, standing on a car roof.</p>
<p>The fledgling Taleban administration has not been recognised by any country or the U.N., which last week deferred a decision on the credentials of Afghanistan's delegation, leaving in place representatives of the ousted government of Burhanuddin Rabbani.</p>
<p>The demonstration followed a similar protest in the southern city of Kandahar, the headquarters of the Taleban, last Saturday, which made the same demands. A Pakistan-based Afghan news agency said 35,000 people took part in that demonstration.</p>
<p>All three countries recognise Rabbani's government, and the Taleban -- born in Afghan refugee camps in Pakistan two years ago -- have accused the three of giving covert or open support to Rabbani or northern military leader Abdul Rashid Dostum.</p>
<p>Taleban fighters were on Thursday battling to defend or recover positions north of Kabul against the forces of former govrnment military chief Ahmad Shah Masood.</p>
<p>Russia and most Central Asian republics have warned of unspecified measures to prevent the Afghan war from spilling over into their territories.</p>
<p>Armed Taleban fighters guarded Thursday's procession and were often the only ones shouting slogans during the march.</p>
<p>Very few of the other marchers echoed the slogans.</p>
<p>Among them was a group of 30 women and children, one of whom said that the Taleban movement should lift its restrictions on work and education for women.</p>
<p>&quot;We ask the Taleban to provide education and job opportunities for women of Afghanistan,&quot; said the burkha-clad woman, who taught for 40 years in Kabul until the Taleban takeover last month.</p>
<p>Some said they had been summoned for a morning meeting and then had been told to join the march.</p>
<p>&quot;It is like a spontaneous demonstration. We didn't know anything about it,&quot; one participant said.</p>
<p>They delivered a seven-point declaration calling, among other things, for countries to acknowledge Afghanistan's problems were different from those of other nations and for the international community to respect Afghanistan's autonomy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
