<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124191" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Delhi shares end higher, buoyed by state news.</title>
<headline>Delhi shares end higher, buoyed by state news.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Delhi shares wiped off early losses to close higher as the prevailing political uncertainty over Uttar Pradesh state eased following news that president's rule would be reimposed in the state, brokers said.</p>
<p>The bourse's benchmark index closed 3.92 points higher at 709.93. Index was 704.24 at mid session.  </p>
<p>Traders said buying by domestic and foreign financial institutions also helped push share prices higher.</p>
<p>&quot;The outcome of the cabinet meeting on the resumption of President's rule in Uttar Pradesh mainly triggered the upward rise in share prices,&quot; said Jayant Shah of brokers Mudra Consultants.</p>
<p>The Indian cabinet decided to extend New Delhi's direct rule in Uttar Pradesh state where local polls last week returned a hung assembly.</p>
<p>But the decision has to be ratified by President Shankar Dayal Sharma before midnight when direct rule imposed last year expires.</p>
<p>Reliance Industries staged a late session rally to close 5.75 rupees higher at 195.25 on institutional buying, brokers said.</p>
<p>Brooke Bond Lipton India rose 30 rupees, almost 10 percent, to 341 rupees on mutual fund buying, they said.</p>
<p>TISCO edged up 2.05 rupees to 173.15 while State Bank of India gained 1.0 rupee to close at 210.10.</p>
<p>Bajaj Auto lost 16 rupees to 926 on profit taking.</p>
<p>ITC was down 4.0 rupees to 306.0.</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91-11 301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
