<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124261" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices climb again as Lebed sacked, low stocks.</title>
<headline>Oil prices climb again as Lebed sacked, low stocks.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices strode higher again on Thursday, wiping out losses which had been prompting some speculation that a startling rally might have run its course.</p>
<p>London December futures for international benchmark Brent crude at 1515 GMT traded up 35 cents at $24.30 a barrel.</p>
<p>Dealers said the sacking on Thursday of Russian security chief Alexander Lebed, underlining political instability at the heart of one of the world's biggest oil producers, again unsettled oil markets.</p>
<p>Weekly U.S. Department of Energy (DOE) data confirming the tight picture on heating oil markets as winter approached also helped bolster prices.</p>
<p>U.S. heating oil stocks were down 27 percent against the same time last year with key east coast inventories off a huge 43 percent, the DOE said.</p>
<p>&quot;Every time this market seems ready for a substantial correction, it bounces back again,&quot; said a London-based trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact the market was happy to shift higher again just underlines how susceptible it is to the merest hint of supply disruption,&quot; said another. November Brent futures earlier this week broke $25 for the first time in nearly six years as traders fretted over the possibility of a shortage of heating oil supplies in the West this winter.</p>
<p>But prices went into reverse on Wednesday, dipping below $24 amid talk that the U.S. government might intervene to protect heating oil consumers this winter, possibly by encouraging a clampdown on exports.</p>
<p>High European prices have allowed traders to make money by selling more than a million tonnes of heating oil from U.S. markets to European buyers over the past two months.</p>
<p>The exports have exacerbated U.S. inventory shortfalls.</p>
<p>U.S. oil company executives will meet Energy Secretary Hazel O'Leary and a Justice Department representative on Friday to discuss what can be done to ensure low heating oil stocks don't hit consumers too hard this winter.</p>
<p>&quot;What is spooking some people is this meeting on Friday,&quot; said Gerry Samuels, an analyst at U.S. Arb Oil.</p>
<p>Though the Energy Department has said it will not intervene in the market, there has been persistent speculation among traders that companies may volunteer action.</p>
<p>Exxon Corp is rumoured to have told clients that it will stop or at least curtail exports of distillates. The company declined to comment.</p>
<p>Dealers were divided on Thursday on whether oil markets had merely paused for breath before resuming their rise, or whether prices might be set for a heavier tumble.</p>
<p>Some saw signs of market fatigue after the bull run which carried crude up 40 percent in just four months.</p>
<p>&quot;It's too high. I don't think the fundamentals can support prices at these levels,&quot; said a London-based trader.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Oct 17	 Oct 16</p>
<p>						   (1515 GMT)    (close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $24.35	 $24.54</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Dec)	$24.30	 $23.94</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Nov)     $25.43	 $25.17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
