<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124474" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AT&amp;T consumer traffic growth quickened in Q3.</title>
<headline>AT&amp;T consumer traffic growth quickened in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>AT&amp;T Corp, reporting a 12 percent drop in share profits, said on Thursday volume growth in its consumer telephony business picked up in the third quarter over the second.</p>
<p>&quot;While competitive pressure continues in the consumer business, volume growth shows improvement over the previous quarter, particularly in international,&quot; the company said in its third quarter earnings report.  </p>
<p>The company also said wireless services revenue, which include cellular, messaging and air-to-ground, grew 17.7 percent from a year before to $892 million in the quarter.</p>
<p>Consolidated cellular service subscribers grew to 4.78 million, a 33.3 percent increase from a year ago.</p>
<p>Wireline services revenue increased slightly more than two percent to $11.552 billion from last year's third quarter. The growth in long distance revenues came primarily from U.S. business services.</p>
<p>Long distance calling volumes grew slightly more than five percent over the same period in 1995.  </p>
<p>Other communications revenues from such services as consulting and online, were $388 million, an increase of nearly 39 percent compared with the restated year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T said the robust growth was driven by gains in revenues from consulting, outsourcing and on-line services, including strong subscriber growth at AT&amp;T WorldNet Services. Six months after introduction, AT&amp;T WorldNet is the second largest Internet service provider with 425,000 subscribers.</p>
<p>Overall, quarterly communications services revenue rose $497 million, or four percent, year over year, AT&amp;T said.  </p>
<p>Revenue at AT&amp;T's financial services business dropped more than 32 percent to $396 million, primarily because of a securitization program at AT&amp;T Universal Card Services.  Some $6.5 billion of Universal Card Services receivables have been securitized.  Universal Card expenses for its credit-card rewards program rose from last year's third quarter.</p>
<p>Financial services had an operating loss for the quarter of $35 million, as compared with an operating profit of $47 million in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>Customer accounts totaled 18.1 million on September 30.</p>
<p>The demerging company also said total operating expenses from continuing operations increased $530 million, or five percent, for the quarter.</p>
<p>Significant increases in selling, general and administrative expenses were partially offset by a drop in access and other interconnection expenses.  Much of the rise came from higher marketing and sales spending in the consumer and wireless businesses, the company said.</p>
<p>Income from discontinued operations such as Lucent Technologies Inc increased to $73 million compared with a significant loss in the year-ago quarter, primarily due to the third quarter 1995 NCR charge.</p>
<p>-- Michael Connor 212-859-1713</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
