<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124562" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN SHARES SEEN RISING CAUTIOUSLY, EYEING U.S.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN SHARES SEEN RISING CAUTIOUSLY, EYEING U.S.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian shares, which rose modestly in active trading on Thursday, are expected to keep heading nervously north with attention firmly focused on any signs of emerging inflation across the Atlantic, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;One or two indications of rising inflation will be enough to stop the market rising, one or two more and it will start to sell off,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Traders said the Belgian market was not directly affected by the shock announcement in Moscow late on Thursday of the sacking of Russian Security Chief Alexander Lebed, although the resulting rise in the dollar lifted dollar-sensitive stocks.  </p>
<p>Pharmaceutical firm UCB was the market's star performer for the second successive day, adding an impressive 3,550 francs to set a new record closing high of 67,950 francs.</p>
<p>The stock, which has now more than doubled in the past year, climbed 1,300 francs on Wednesday. Traders said the sudden sky-rocket rise followed a &quot;very positive&quot; meeting on Tuesday of domestic and foreign share analysts.</p>
<p>They added that there appeared little to threaten the rally, and openly wondered at the possibility of a tripling of the stock's value.  </p>
<p>Oil major PetroFina , subject of buy reccomendations, also outperformed the market for the second successive day, rising 120 francs to 9,760.</p>
<p>Traders said the combination of the firmer dollar, higher oil prices and rising refining margins made the stock attractive. &quot;It is a company with a positive earnings trend,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>On the downside, fast food retailer Quick fell 60 francs to 2,090 despite reassurances on Tuesday from French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis that the government was not in favour of a new fast food tax proposed by the parliament.</p>
<p>Steel maker Cockerill Sambre and shipper CMB, both of whose sectors are facing tough times and which have also both been mentioned as possible candidates for replacement in the Bel-20 share index by electronics firm Barco, lost ground.</p>
<p>Cockerill lost five francs to 124, and CMB lost 95 francs to 2,300. Barco, by contrast, rose 50 to 5,190 francs.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index ended 6.92 points or 0.39 percent higher at 1,798.06 in a 1,799.06/1,791.55 range. Eleven stocks rose, nine lost ground. Volume was 2.8 billion Belgian francs.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
