<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124863" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: TAP Air Portugal future bleak without alliances.</title>
<headline>TAP Air Portugal future bleak without alliances.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Small or medium-sized European airlines like TAP Air Portugal will go under if they fail to find partners to strengthen their positions, the carrier's senior vice-president on Thursday.</p>
<p>Antonio Alfaiate said the state-owned airline was caught between two camps: the continent's larger airlines and alliances, with their economies of scale and extensive routes, and the low-cost, no-frills airlines now joining the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The conclusion for us is very clear: a small or medium-sized air carrier like Air Portugal cannot survive in the near future (without partnerships),&quot; he told an aviation conference.</p>
<p>Replying to questions, he would not specify which of the growing band of alliances his company wished to team up with.</p>
<p>&quot;I think alliances with the big companies would not be a good choice because of course if we join British Airways or Lufthansa our capacity for negotiation of a good alliance is a very small one,&quot; he told an aviation conference.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are in an alliance where the size of companies is more (balanced) then we can have a strong voice,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom 32 2 287 6800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
