<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124819" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton, Dole debate familiar economic themes.</title>
<headline>Clinton, Dole debate familiar economic themes.</headline>
<dateline>SAN DIEGO 1996-10-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton defended his administration's four-year record on managing the U.S. economy against Republican challenger Bob Dole who insisted a major tax cut is needed to push the economy to grow faster.</p>
<p>In their second presidential campaign debates, neither candidate broke new ground on economic and trade issues.</p>
<p>Dole told the nationwide television audience Wednesday night, &quot;If we don't get the economy to grow, if we don't cut taxes and give people child credits and cut the capital gains rate and get this economy growing, we're going to limp into the next century.&quot;  </p>
<p>Clinton argued that Dole's tax cut would increase the federal budget deficit and force interest rates higher as the government was forced to borrow more money. He noted the budget deficit has declined for four years and also took credit for a gain in U.S. manufacturing jobs since he took office in 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want to see us blow a big hole in the deficit with a tax program we can't pay for so your interest rates will go up. And you'll have to pay back in higher interest rates what you allegedly will get in a tax cut,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Clinton pointed to more than 200 trade agreements with Japan and China and other countries  as &quot;one of the real success stories&quot; of his administration.</p>
<p>Dole responded that the government needed to help keep manufacturing jobs in the United States. &quot;We have got to be more aggressive,&quot; in enforcement of trade policy, Dole said.</p>
<p>Clinton has proposed a tax cut targeted at providing more money for education, the purchase of a first home, health care and child care. Dole has proposed a 15 percent across-the-board tax cut and a reduction in the capital gains tax rate.</p>
<p>Asked how the tax cut would be paid for, Dole said: &quot;We're going to have a constitutional amendment to balance the budget.&quot; He added that his economic plan would spend less than Clinton's while leaving people with more of their own money.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN DIEGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
