<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="124808" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Flood risk to Cuba from Tropical Storm Lili - WSC.</title>
<headline>Flood risk to Cuba from Tropical Storm Lili - WSC.</headline>
<dateline>LEXINGTON, Mass. 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tropical Storm Lili is expected to produce rainfall amounts of locally 6-12 inches over western and central Cuba where flooding could be major, independent forecaster Weather Services Corp said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Lili is beginning to drift northward in the Caribbean and threatens Cuba and eventually southern Florida, WSC said.</p>
<p>Heavy rains are also possible over portions of eastern Central America and the Yucatan, and by Friday, Lili will become an increased threat to the Florida Keys, when it may approach the region as a hurricane, it added.</p>
<p>Shipping will also be threatened throughout the region.</p>
<p>Hurricane warnings are up for Cuba's Isle of Youth and the western mainland provinces of Pinar Del Rio, Havana, Matanzas, Villa Clara, and Cienfuegos in Cuba.</p>
<p>Tropical storm warnings are in effect for the east coast of the Yucatan Peninsula from Cabo Catoche southward to Bahia De Chetumal, and for the Cayman Islands.</p>
<p>Lili has top winds near 65 mph and is 325 miles south-southwest of Havana, drifting north. This motion will continue on Thursday, bringing the centre near western Cuba on Thursday night. Lili may become a hurricane later today.</p>
<p>WSC said heavy rains associated with the storm could damage the sugar crop, especially in Florida and western Cuba, and also the Florida citrus crop.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LEXINGTON, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
