<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125040" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 17.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared by The Broadcast Monitoring Company for Reuters</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- DFS SHARES SLIP ON DISPOSAL</p>
<p>The two children of the founder of of DFS, Britain's biggest furniture retailer, are to sell the majority of their 22 per cent shares in the family company. Sir Graham Kirkham, who built the company from scratch, said he was not disappointed that his son Michael Kirkham and daughter Julie Cross have decided to raise around 100 million stg by the sale. News of the sale sent shares in DFS down 22 to 514.5p, despite announcing record pre-tax profits of 31.1 millions stg, an 18.6 per cent annual rise.</p>
<p>-- FUEL COSTS FORCE BA TO RAISE FARES</p>
<p>Fast rising fuel costs have force British Airways to raise its fares on full published European routes by 2.5 per cent. It is also considering rises on long-haul routes. The decision, which was quickly followed by other airlines, was blamed on the 30 per cent jump in the cost of jet fuel since the middle of July.  SAS is to raise its fares on UK-Scandinavia routes by 2.5 per cent, American Airlines is also planning a 2.5 per cent increase on transatlantic flights out of Heathrow.</p>
<p>-- PIZZA EXPRESS PAYS 25 MILLION STG FOR RESTAURANTS</p>
<p>Pizza Express is to buy back 32 of its franchised restaurants for 25 million stg. The company intends to move out of franchising and concentrate on running its own restaurants. The move is to be funded with 25.5 million stg from a placing and open offer of three million new shares at 475p in Britain and a placing of 2.6 million in the US. Shares in Pizza Express rose 6.5p to 532.5p on the news.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- MORGAN GRENFELL DISMISSES FIVE SENIOR EXECUTIVES</p>
<p>Morgan Grenfell yesterday dismissed five senior executives in a move to distance itself from its recent problems. The dismissals follow the conclusion of an internal investigation into irregularities in three Morgan Grenfell European unit trusts, carried out with the assistance of the accountant Ernst &amp; Young. Morgan Grenfell Asset Management will continue to work closely with Imro and other regulators to resolve outstanding issues.</p>
<p>-- FALL IN JOBLESS LEVEL FUELS FEARS ON RATES</p>
<p>The City was speculating that higher interest rates may be needed to head off inflationary pressures after a large fall in unemployment and a small rise in the growth of earnings was announced. Britain's headline unemployment total fell by 35,600 in September, more than the City had expected and some believe that the Bank of England's calls for higher rates may harden into an official recommendation at the next monetary meeting.</p>
<p>-- OUSTED BET CHIEF WINS 3 MILLION STG IN HIGH COURT</p>
<p>John Clark, who was ousted as chief executive of BET, after its hostile takeover by Rentokil at the start of the year, has won more than 3 million stg in compensation in the high court. The ruling is expected to influence future cases involving executive pay. Mr Clark had a three-year rolling contract and the award was made for loss of his 490,000 stg salary, plus damages for loss of pension rights, bonus payments plus other perks. Mr Clark had been willing to settle out of court for 1 million stg.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- HOTLINE CUTS DOLE QUEUES</p>
<p>The Government's Benefits Agency Fraud Hotline has received 80,000 calls since it's launch in August and is claimed to be a factor behind the fall of 35,600 in the number of people out of work and claiming benefit in September.</p>
<p>-- CBI'S LEADER FINDS REASONS TO SUPPORT MINIMUM-WAGE LAWS</p>
<p>The director-general of the CBI, Adair Turner, speaking to a conference on European business yesterday said that a German style minimum wage and tough employment laws could boost productivity and help companies in Britain compete in the world markets.</p>
<p>-- OLDEST MERCHANT BANK IN US SCRUTINY</p>
<p>The sale of the world's oldest merchant bank, MeesPierson, to Belgian financial services conglomerate Fortis is in question after the discovery of accounting irregularities in a venture capital business linked to MeesPierson's office in New York. A MeesPierson spokesperson confirmed an investigation was under way, but would not name the fund. He said that the scandal would not effect the Fortis takeover.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- SENIOR WICKS MANAGEMENT WAS AWARE OF BOGUS PROFITS 6 MONTHS BEFORE DISCLOSURE</p>
<p>Senior management at Wickes were aware of accounting irregularities at the DIY business six months before the problems were made public. The admission is made in a letter from new chairman, Michael von Brentano, sent out to Wickes shareholders. The letter details how the accounting difficulties arose and who was responsible. The document says that immediate responsibility for the problems lay with former chairman, Henry Sweetbaum.</p>
<p>-- BAe PARTNER WINS BID FOR THOMSON</p>
<p>British Aerospace's French missiles partner, Lagadere, was chosen as the preferred bidder in the privatisation of Thomson, the country's state-owned defence and electronics giant. The decision is seen as a set-back for GEC, who have links with rival bidder Alcatel Alsthom but is a huge boost to BAe's drive to lead the rationalisation of the European defence industry. BAe's shares rose 19p to 1132.5.</p>
<p>-- PEARSON SEEKS SALE OF 440 MILLION STG BSKYB STAKE</p>
<p>Pearson is seeking to sell its remaining shares in BSkyB, Rupert Murdoch's satellite company. The shares are held through the rump of the old British Satellite Broadcasting and represent 14 per cent of BSkyB, with Pearson's indirect stake being around 4 per cent and worth 440 million stg at the current share price.</p>
<p>BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
