<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125111" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Adtrans expects to meet 96/97 budget.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Adtrans expects to meet 96/97 budget.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Australian car and truck distributor Adtrans Group Ltd said on Thursday it expected its budgets for 1996/97 to be achieved, although the first quarter had been tough and performance was currently below-budget.</p>
<p>&quot;The first quarter of the new financial year has been tough, much the same as it was in the final quarter of the past financial year,&quot; Adtrans chairman Graeme Bignell told shareholders at the annual meeting.  </p>
<p>&quot;The October activity is much better and whilst our performance currently is below budget, we believe that like October, there will be good improvements throughout the year and we expect that our budgets for the current year will be achieved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Adrans reported a net profit of A$4.03 million in 1995/96, down on A$4.3 million in 1994/95, with sales rising four percent to A$360.4 million.</p>
<p>Bignell said the Australian new car market remained very competitive, with more than half of the 1996 total new vehicle market taken by imports.  </p>
<p>&quot;With so many entrants in the vehicle market, the future only holds good prospects for lean and mean operations because margins will remain tight,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Adtrans' balance of franchises is good and, despite the competitiveness of this marketplace, we look to the future with confidence,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bignell said the market for trucks had lifted a little in the last couple of months, although unfortunately the penetration by Ford, Adtrans' major truck franchise, was not as good as it should have been.  </p>
<p>He said the company did not disagree with predictions that the market would remain stable for the next 18 months, but the company believed it would generate reasonable profit opportunities.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
