<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125169" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Next Thai govt could last 18 months -- deputy PM.</title>
<headline>Next Thai govt could last 18 months -- deputy PM.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government which wins power in Thailand's November 17 general election is likely to last about 18 months, visiting Thai Deputy Prime Minister Kasem S. Kasemsri said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The next government probably has about a year and a half, a little more perhaps, but not more than that,&quot; Kasem told Reuters Financial Television in an interview.</p>
<p>Kasem said legislation for political reform had been passed and a constituent assembly would be held during the next government's time in power.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the constitution has been approved, either by the house or by the people, then we expect to have another election,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Foreign investors, who have shunned the Thai stock market, helping to push the bourse to three-year lows, would be lured back if Thailand has a stable government, Kasem said, adding that a government lasting 18 months would be considered a stable one.</p>
<p>Thailand has had five governments in as many years.</p>
<p>Kasem came to Japan to attend a seminar on Japan-U.S. security ties.</p>
<p>An independent, Kasem said he did not expect any one party to win a majority in the election, but added that the opposition Democrat Party, and the New Aspiration Party -- which is part of the ruling coalition, were expected to win the most seats.</p>
<p>Tackling Thailand's ballooning current account deficit would be the top economic goal of the new government, Kasem said.</p>
<p>He said Thailand's current account deficit as a percentage of gross domestic product (GDP) was slightly high and the best remedy would be to cut public spending.</p>
<p>The Thai central bank has projected a current account deficit of 7.8 percent of GDP this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
