<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125254" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Key JGB futures bounce back to close a bit higher.</title>
<headline>Key JGB futures bounce back to close a bit higher.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Key December Japanese government bond futures closed a little higher on Thursday, after their rebound to 122.55 indicated the firm support they can expect from investors' buying and speculation surrounding the buying.</p>
<p>But after having climbed a little higher, the December contract stalled and nested in a comfortable zone to wait for the general election on Sunday, dealers said.</p>
<p>Few market participants would be eager to initiate a venture in either direction before they see the results of the election, they said. The December contract closed at 122.74, up 0.12 from Wednesday. Volume was 34,778 contracts.  </p>
<p>Various polls are pointing to a victory by the Liberal Democrats in the election, but many market players are still wary of the chances of the opposition Shinshinto winning.</p>
<p>Shinshinto is calling for a huge tax cut of about 18 trillion yen, which would boost the economy and government debt issues as well.</p>
<p>The market could lose ground if the Shinshinto forms a coalition government with other parties.</p>
<p>More unknown, is if and how the next government decides to pass a supplementary budget to stimulate the economy after the election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
