<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125420" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Oct 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Oct 17.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Broad movement in Arab peace camp. Prime Minister Kabariti carries King Hussein's message to Egyptian President Mubarak. U.S. envoy briefs king on latest developments in peace talks.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Marwan Awad says decision taken in principle to cancel customs duties on private imports of sugar and rice.</p>
<p>- Agriculture Minister Mustafa Shneikat says preliminary estimates put this year's olive oil production at 14,000 to 15,000 tonnes, against local requirements of 19,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>- Director General of Ports Authorities Mohamed Delabih to lead Jordanian delegation to Iraq on October 29 to discuss transport of goods from Jordan's Aqaba Port to Baghdad in light of anticipated oil-for-food deal.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- King Hussein emphasises in interview with MBC television the need for commitment to implementation of peace agreements.</p>
<p>- King's cultural adviser Prince Ghazi bin Mohammad calls for linkage between education and society's needs.</p>
<p>- Kabariti says in Cairo that Israel's accords with Arabs are sacred and cannot be ignored.</p>
<p>- Jordanians and Palestinians consider the king's historic visit to Jericho as crowning his efforts for justice and freedom in the context of a comprehensive peace.</p>
<p>- Two actors apologise to parliamentary speaker Srour over TV comedy which upset parliament.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Awad says no plans to replace income tax with sales tax.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- Kabariti says peace process in grave danger if no Hebron redeployment.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu tells Jordan Times Israel wants better relations with Jordan. Says Likud government not bound by promises made to Syria by previous Labour government.</p>
<p>AL ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Awad says decision to cancel sugar duties will lead to cheaper prices and ease the burden on consumers.</p>
<p>- Kabariti denies plans for four-way summit meeting. Jordan, Egypt and the Palestinians have a single position on peace.</p>
<p>- Palestinian sources say Israel is still denying entry to medical aid donated by Jordanian private and government institutions to victims of last month's bloody clashes.</p>
<p>- Today is last day for offers to be presented to Ministry of Supply for 150,000 tonnes of U.S. winter wheat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
