<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125597" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada's trade surplus hits record high in August.</title>
<headline>Canada's trade surplus hits record high in August.</headline>
<byline>Malina Poshtova Zang</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's trade surplus jumped to a record high in August amid surging exports to the United States, a government agency reported Friday, prompting economists to predict another current account surplus in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Canada's trade surplus rose to a record C$4.02 billion ($2.97 billion) in August from C$2.89 billion ($2.14 billion) in July, Statistics Canada said.</p>
<p>John Johnston, deputy chief economist at RBC Dominion Securities Inc., said the strong trade numbers put Canada's economy in a position to record a second straight current account surplus in the third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that we had a much stronger than consensus expectation on the surplus points toward another current account surplus,&quot; Johnston said.</p>
<p>In the second quarter of 1996, Canada posted a current account surplus of C$1.15 billion ($851 million), the first surplus since the fourth quarter of 1984.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of economists had forecast a trade surplus of C$3.37 billion ($2.49 billion) in August. The survey also forecast imports of C$19.6 billion ($14.5 billion) and exports of C$22.9 billion ($16.95 billion) in August.</p>
<p>Statistics Canada said exports rose 2.7 percent in August to a record C$23.15 billion ($17.13 billion). Exports to the United States, Canada's largest trading partner, rose to a record C$19.17 billion ($14.19 billion).</p>
<p>The strong trade numbers immediately boosted Canada's financial markets, with the Canadian dollar, bonds and Treasury bills all rising on the news.</p>
<p>But the agency also said imports fell in August, due mostly to slower shipments of machinery, industrial goods and auto parts.</p>
<p>Economists were concerned about the weaker imports number, which they said indicated domestic demand in Canada was still lagging and meant the Bank of Canada could continue to cut interest rates to stimulate growth.</p>
<p>&quot;That really tells us that the bank was right to have eased as much as it did since August given that domestic demand during that period continued to be sluggish,&quot; said Andrew Spence, senior economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Steve Saldanha, economic analyst at Canada Trust, said a recent spate of weak economic data could mean the next rate cut is just around the corner.</p>
<p>&quot;That's what the Bank of Canada is trying to do. All their easings, 18 in the past 17 months, have been for the sole purpose to stimulate the domestic economy, not to help exports,&quot; Saldanha said.</p>
<p>He said the bank would probably wait for the release of August retail trade data Monday and the consumer price index for September on Tuesday before making its next move.</p>
<p>The central bank last cut its key bank rate Wednesday, bringing interest rates in Canada to their lowest level in almost 40 years.</p>
<p>Canada's trade surplus has risen steadily as a proportion of gross domestic product, reaching 4.5 percent in the second quarter of 1996 compared with 0.5 percent in 1991.</p>
<p>The upward trend in exports since the second quarter of 1995 largely reflects economic strength in the United States. About C$1 billion ($740 million) worth of goods crosses the border between the two countries every day.</p>
<p>The United States Friday reported a 6.6 percent drop in its trade deficit to $10.83 billion in August from $11.6 billion in July, well above forecasts by private economists for a gap of $8.5 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
