<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125524" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bundesbank warns transfers to E. German must drop.</title>
<headline>Bundesbank warns transfers to E. German must drop.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's central bank warned on Thursday that transfer payments to east German states, topping 600 billion marks since unification in 1990, must be pared to rein in deficits and also reduce tax burdens.</p>
<p>A reduction of government transfers will benefit the economy and ultimately help support poorer east German states as well, the Bundesbank argued in its October report released on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;In the medium term and as the east German economy recovers, a reduction of public transfers to the new states will be unavoidable,&quot; the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is necessary to reduce the stiflingly high tax burden and to try and limit the increase in indebtedness,&quot; the central bank added.</p>
<p>Between 1991 and 1995, the Bonn government has funnelled about 615 billion marks into the new states, mostly to cover social costs, upgrade antiquated industry and expand rotting infrastructure.</p>
<p>The Bonn government may be particularly interested in reducing subsidies to the east as it scrambles to get its finances into shape in order to be among the first nations to join Europe's planned currency union at the end of the decade.</p>
<p>In total these transfers averaged about 4.25 percent of Germany's annual gross domestic product, reaching a peak of 140 billion marks last year, the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>But the volume of transfer costs is likely to begin easing soon, the Bundesbank said, forecasting this year's total would already be some five billion marks lower than last year's number largely because east German tax revenue has climbed.</p>
<p>&quot;Next year another small decline is also expected,&quot; the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>Lower transfers for unemployment assistance will also be a key factor to help reduce the transfers, the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>In fact the Bundesbank said 1997 transfers may be 10 billion marks below 1995's record subsidy level if plans for a new employment initiative are successful, eliminating the need for Bonn to finance a Labour Office deficit.</p>
<p>While the Bundesbank stressed the importance of transfers to the eastern states, it was concerned by the use of funds which still flowed primarily to consumer goods not investments.</p>
<p>&quot;Funds for investments, which are particularly important for the economic development in the new states, they made up only one quarter of the gross transfers sent there between 1991 and 1995,&quot; the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank also warned that the use and efficiency of the transfers must reviewed in order to prevent a &quot;subvention mentality&quot; from forming.</p>
<p>Between 1991 and 1995, the federal government has raised the lion's share of all subsidies, with gross transfers totalling 535 billion marks, the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>Nearly two thirds of that total covered social costs.</p>
<p>--Svea Herbst-Bayliss, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
