<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125556" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan sugar imports seen rising on lower output.</title>
<headline>Pakistan sugar imports seen rising on lower output.</headline>
<byline>Ibrahim Khan</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan may have to import up to 500,000 tonnes of refined crystal white sugar in calendar 1997, up from 375,000 tonnes in 1996, as domestic sugar output sags, mill owners and dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said many sugarcane farmers were opting to produce unrefined brown sugar, known locally as gur, on the spot, rather than send their cane to mills for crushing and refining.</p>
<p>Gur is especially popular in Pakistan's North West Frontier Province (NWFP) and is also in growing demand in neighbouring Afghanistan and Central Asian republics, they said.</p>
<p>Its retail price in the NWFP capital Peshawar is 22 rupees ($0.59) per kg while refined sugar sells for only 18, implying big profit margins for gur producers. Imported sugar sells at state-run shops for 15.50 rupees per kg.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a general fear among sugar mill owners of higher production of gur at farms instead of refined crystal white sugar at mills,&quot; Ali Qazilbash, secretary of the Pakistan Sugar Mills Association (PSMA), told Reuters.</p>
<p>He had no estimate for next year's expected shortfall, but wholesale sugar dealer Abdul Ghaffar said it could be more than 500,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Pakistan's sugar output plunged to 2.47 million tonnes in the 1995/96 (July-June) crop year from 3.0 million in 1994/95. Sugar mills are due to start production next month, with output for 1996/97 forecast at about the same as the previous year.</p>
<p>Pakistan has had to import 375,000 tonnes of sugar this year, including 225,000 tonnes bought by the state-run Trading Corp of Pakistan (TCP) and 150,000 by private importers.</p>
<p>Private importers have now revised their 1997 import forecasts to 500,000 tonnes from about 250,000 tonnes due to the trend towards diverting sugarcane into gur production.</p>
<p>Farmers can produce gur cheaply and easily, and it attracts no excise tax, whereas sugar mills have to pay the government 2.10 rupees per kg on sugar production.</p>
<p>Producing gur means farmers do not have to transport sugarcane to mills, where delivery delays often last up to a week, during which time the sugarcane loses weight.</p>
<p>Gur is made from sugarcane juice produced by old-fashioned cattle-powered crushing machines, though some farmers have now installed electricity-powered crushers. The juice is boiled and thickened into a solid mass or lumps of gur.</p>
<p>Qazilbash said demand for gur was rising in neighbouring Afghanistan and Central Asia where people eat it with bread in winter as a cheap substitute for meat and vegetable dishes.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan is likely to produce 1.2 million tonnes of gur in 1996/97, up from one million tonnes in 1995/96, 800,000 tonnes in 1993/94 and 600,000 tonnes in 1992/93,&quot; Qazilbash said.</p>
<p>He said the trend towards gur production began in NWFP and then spread to the fertile farmlands of Punjab province.</p>
<p>PMSA figures show that stocks of refined sugar produced in 1995/96 had fallen to 100,000 tonnes by end-September.</p>
<p>A TCP official said that with the crushing season imminent, the government had not requested further imports this year.</p>
<p>($ 1 = 37.06 rupees) -- Karachi newsroom 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
