<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125569" id="root" date="1996-10-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan president OKs tax plan to boost investment.</title>
<headline>Taiwan president OKs tax plan to boost investment.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's President Lee Teng-hui has approved the Finance Ministry's &quot;two-into-one&quot; tax merger plan to boost the island's investment and economy, which has been slowing in recent quarters, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;President Lee said the tax proposal is feasible,&quot; a Government Information Office official said by telephone.</p>
<p>Premier Lien Chan and several ministers met with President Lee on Wednesday, the official said.</p>
<p>Officials also quoted President Lee as saying he hoped the proposal will be effective from January 1, 1998.</p>
<p>A Finance Ministry official said: &quot;Officials who attended the meeting said President Lee directed that the proposal should be effective from January 1, 1998, and demanded the Finance Ministry to have good communications with parliament.&quot;</p>
<p>The proposal needs a final approval by parliament.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Paul Chiu said on October 9 that the ministry would merge the island's two income taxes into one business income tax and set the merged rate at 25 percent.</p>
<p>The move would reduce tax revenues by about T$26.8 billion (US$975 million) a year, Chiu said.</p>
<p>But the ministry would recoup the losses by assessing a 10 percent levy on profits that enterprises reserve rather than distribute to shareholders immediately, he said.</p>
<p>The new tax system would avoid double taxation and would help corporate structures, Chiu said.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact this is a tax reduction,&quot; Chiu said. &quot;It will encourage investment (in Taiwan) and increase our international competitiveness.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan has been trying to woo the Asia-Pacific operations of major multinationals by boosting local economic competitiveness, but has been hobbled by the slow pace of promised market liberalisation, including tax reform.</p>
<p>Foreign nationals' taxes were not affected because their maximum rate would remain the same at 40 percent, Chiu said.</p>
<p>The &quot;two-into-one&quot; tax merger is an accounting change that eliminates double taxation of companies' profits and the dividends they pay to shareholders.</p>
<p>Maximum assessments on domestic individuals' income will be capped at 40 percent, compared with a maximum of 55 percent before the merger.</p>
<p>Currently, foreign investors' income is taxed first by a 25 percent business income tax, and then a 20 percent dividend tax on the 75 percent untaxed portion, making the rate at 40 percent.</p>
<p>Economists said the tax reform would encourge domestic investment, but not on foreign investment.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see any improvement on how to encourge foreign investment in the proposal,&quot; said Sun Ke-nan, a panel memeber from the Chunghua Institution for Economic Research.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to develop Taiwan into an Asia-Pacific operation centre, we may consider lowering the dividend tax on foreign investors to 15 percent from the current 20 percent,&quot; Sun said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
