<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125602" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada bonds end stronger, outperform on dlr, data.</title>
<headline>Canada bonds end stronger, outperform on dlr, data.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian bonds closed mostly stronger on Friday, with long-term spreads to U.S. bonds reaching 11-year lows, buoyed by a higher-than-expected Canadian trade surplus and firmer dollar, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a very good trade surplus and the currency strengthened. The strength in the currency over the last couple of days has had more of an impact on the longer end,&quot; said Mark Chandler, an economist with Goldman Sachs Canada.</p>
<p>Canada's 30-year benchmark bond rose C$0.65 to C$109.90 to yield 7.161 percent compared to the U.S. 30-year benchmark which rose 5/32 to yield 6.79 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the benchmark bonds narrowed to an 11-year low of 37 basis points from 41 basis points at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>Canada's merchandise trade surplus rose in August to a record C$4.02 billion from C$2.89 billion in July, revised from C$3.07 billion, Statistics Canada said on Friday.</p>
<p>The dollar rallied past C$1.3500 (US$0.7407) following the report from C$1.3512 (US$0.7401) at the opening.</p>
<p>Also providing support for Canadian bonds was a stronger U.S. Treasuries market, which gained after U.S. trade data prompted many economists to lower economic forecasts.  </p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. had a bad trade report that caused some people to question what the third quarter might look like, and we had a good trade report,&quot; said Chandler.</p>
<p>The Canadian yield curve flattened further today, with long bonds rallying while short-term bonds weakened.</p>
<p>Chandler said the curve flattening is linked to an announcement by the Bank of Canada on Wednesday that they are considering buying more bonds and less T-bills.</p>
<p>In other prices, the Government of Canada 7.0 percent of 2006 rose C$0.46 to C$103.62 to yield 6.504 percent. The U.S. 10-year benchmark rose 2/32 to yield 6.50 percent.  </p>
<p>The spread between the bonds narrowed to close flat for the first time in 11 years, an occurence that had been forecast by many market analysts. The spread was seven basis points on Thursday.</p>
<p>The three-month cash bill traded at 3.35 percent against the U.S. three-month bill at 5.10 percent.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Hodgson (416) 941-8105, e-mail: jeffrey.hodgson@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
