<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125674" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: RALLYING-RALLY LEAVES HONG KONG FOR FINAL TIME.</title>
<headline>RALLYING-RALLY LEAVES HONG KONG FOR FINAL TIME.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>For the final time on Saturday, the world's leading rally drivers will roar out of Hong Kong on the first stage of the week-long Hong Kong-Beijing rally.</p>
<p>From next year the last round of the Asia-Pacific championship will adhere to the new pattern of a three-day event centred near Beijing.</p>
<p>The present 3,800-km event is an anachronism in a world where major rallies have cut distances and now loop around a central point which that makes them easier to package for television.</p>
<p>Millions of spectators will throng the roads of southern China, the biggest audience for any sporting event on the globe, giving massive exposure to the manufacturers and their sponsors who are hungry for a slice of the growing Chinese market.</p>
<p>The championship is finely balanced as Subaru's Kenneth Eriksson and Mitsubishi's Ari Vatanen battle for the Asia-Pacific manufacturers' crown.</p>
<p>They head a field of 50 drivers who will traverse some of the rallying world's most varied terrain.</p>
<p>The rally is scheduled to reach Beijing on October 25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
