<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125664" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-LEHMAN READY FOR BIG RECEPTION.</title>
<headline>GOLF-LEHMAN READY FOR BIG RECEPTION.</headline>
<byline>Brian Creighton</byline>
<dateline>WENTWORTH, England 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Open champion Tom Lehman can expect a big reception when he starts out at the World Matchplay championship on Friday, proof of how his life has changed since he won his first major title three months ago.</p>
<p>Regarded as a good journeyman pro before his victory at Royal Lytham in July, Lehman has been adjusting to his status as a hero ever since.</p>
<p>&quot;The attention has been a little embarrassing at times,&quot; he said on Thursday. &quot;I have never been in that situation before with kids coming up to me in a restaurant or at the airport for autographs and people asking `Who is he?'.</p>
<p>&quot;It is uncomfortable, but people have been so gracious and warm to me. It has made me proud to be the winner. It's a small price to pay for winning the Open.&quot;</p>
<p>The second seed behind titleholder Ernie Els faces fellow American Mark O'Meara on Friday.</p>
<p>He will hope to find his way around the 6,957-yard West Course at Wentworth after getting lost in the dusk on a familiarisation walk on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>He arrived on Tuesday afternoon after a Skins Game at home and confined himself to a stroll over the course, which he last played in 1993 before the British Open.</p>
<p>&quot;As I walked off the 10th it was virtually dark and I thought I was taking a short cut when a little old lady asked me if I was lost and I said no.</p>
<p>&quot;I kept going and discovered I was in her driveway.&quot;</p>
<p>Lehman hopes his game will not have suffered from a lack of practice.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the Open there has been so much going on that my practice time has taken a real beating. I have not worked on my game as I would like. With the contractual things, spare time has been a little short. But that will slow down.&quot;</p>
<p>Lehman and O'Meara stand third and fourth on the U.S. money list for the year, some $44,000 separating them.</p>
<p>&quot;I have played with Mark and if he gets his putter going he will be hard to beat, particularly after his form in the Alfred Dunhill Cup.&quot;</p>
<p>O'Meara, Steve Stricker and Phil Mickelson won the Dunhill title for the United States at St Andrews on Sunday, O'Meara shooting a 63 in the opening round on the Old Course.</p>
<p>Stricker, meanwhile, faces the monumental task of taking on the winner from the last two years, top-seeded South African Ernie Els.</p>
<p>He earned the assignment after a 3 and 2 triumph on Thursday over Els 's victim in last year's final, Steve Elkington.</p>
<p>Stricker and Els both take 6-0 records into the match, albeit compiled in different ways. Stricker won all five matches in the Dunhill Cup and his Thursday victory left him undefeated in six contests on his British visit.</p>
<p>Els won three matches in each of his two title runs here and has never lost. &quot;The odds are not in my favour, which is okay. Everybody expects him to win,&quot; said the 29-year-old American.</p>
<p>World number two Colin Montgomerie, seeded fifth behind the holder and three major champions, faces one of them, PGA champion Mark Brooks.</p>
<p>Montgomerie disposed of European rival and fellow Briton Ian Woosnam 3 and 2 on Thursday.</p>
<p>In the other match, U.S. Open champion Steve Jones faces Fijian Vijay Singh, the conqueror by one hole of Phil Mickelson in the first round.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WENTWORTH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
