<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125706" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-PSG SEEK MORALE-BOOSTING WIN AGAINST CHAMPIONS AUXERRE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PSG SEEK MORALE-BOOSTING WIN AGAINST CHAMPIONS AUXERRE.</headline>
<byline>Francois Thomazeau</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unbeaten French first division leaders Paris St Germain are in a state of shock as they host champions Auxerre for the top match of the league season so far at the Parc des Princes on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Parisians, impressive in the league all season, hoped the clash would be nothing more than a symbolic handover ceremony  -- that they would win and pull 10 points clear of Auxerre to open up a commanding lead in the title race.</p>
<p>But everything changed on Thursday evening in Turkey when PSG crashed 4-2 in a European Cup Winners Cup tie against Galatasaray for their first defeat of the season.</p>
<p>In contrast, and despite the absences of a number of first choice players, Auxerre beat Grasshopper Zurich 1-0 in the Champions league on Wednesday.</p>
<p>So after gradually making up for lost time in the early stages of the domestic league, they have shot back to second place in the standings.</p>
<p>If they beat PSG they will close the gap to just four points. A defeat will leave them seriously in arrears, but at least there is far more pressure on PSG now than there would have been if they had won in Turkey.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a disaster,&quot; summed up Parisian coach Ricardo after the Istanbul defeat.</p>
<p>&quot;We conceded more goals in one tie than in 12 league matches,&quot; echoed club president Michel Denisot.</p>
<p>&quot;We had real problems but personnally, I opt for the bad day explanation&quot;.</p>
<p>To add to their woes, PSG have injury problems. Brazilian playmaker Rai injured a collarbone against Galatasaray and could miss the match.</p>
<p>The Parisians will still be without goalkeeper Bernard Lama, defender Bruno N'Gotty and suspended libero Alain Roche. Second choice keeper Vincent Fernandez will face intense pressure after his nightmare in Istanbul.</p>
<p>The morale is much better at Auxerre but coach Guy Roux also faces some problems.</p>
<p>The Burgundy side, without injured first choice defenders Franck Silvestre and Ned Zelic, will also be without suspended Nigerian defender Taribo West and defensive midfielder.</p>
<p>Roux will be forced to reshuffle his defence, probably moving versatile Alain Goma to the centre.</p>
<p>Auxerre be looking to young striker Thomas Deniaud, called from the back benches to score all of his team's goals in the champions league this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I have only played once at the Parc des Princes, in the third division a couple of years back,&quot; said Deniaud, who has yet to score in the first division.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
