<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125862" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Southeast spot power supported by tight supply.</title>
<headline>US Southeast spot power supported by tight supply.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot bulk electricity prices in the southeastern U.S. ended steady Friday against Thursday's levels, continuing to be supported by tight availability, market sources said.</p>
<p>The expected returns of several large nuclear power stations in the Southeastern Electric Reliability Council (SERC) district will likely ease the generating capacity tightness, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm expecting the market will go down with these units' return. The prices are too high,&quot; said a Houston trader.</p>
<p>The three nuclear units, with total capacity over 3,000 megawatts (MW), were expected to resume service by next week: Carolina Power &amp; Light Co's 683 MW Robinson nuclear power unit 2 in Hartsville, S.C., and Tennessee Valley Authority's (TVA) 1,148 MW Sequoyah 2 in Soddy-Daisy, Tenn., and 1,170 MW Watts Bar 1 in Spring City, Tenn.</p>
<p>Temperatures in SERC were predicted to run eight to 12 Fahrenheit degrees below normal over the weekend before returning near normal by mid-week, according to Weather Services Corp.</p>
<p>While Hurricane Lily was not expected to hit Florida, the system was anticipated to push clouds, strong winds and heavy precipitation to parts of the pennisula over the weekend.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, firm, peak electricity for Monday was assessed at $22.00-$23.00 a megawatt hour (MWh), down from Thursday's $23.00-$24.00 for Friday delivery.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak electricity for Monday at the Ga./Fla. border was valued at $15.00-$16.00, up from a quote of $13.50-$14.00 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Up in the northern portion of the TVA system, firm, peak electricity was quoted at $17.00-$18.00, flat from Thursday.</p>
<p>Off-peak, firm power in northern TVA for Monday delivery was widely assessed at $12.00, but a few participants noted offers reached as high as $16.00.</p>
<p>TVA reportedly offered peak, non-firm power for Monday delivery at $20.50, unchanged from Thursday's value for Friday delivery.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
