<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125838" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sinclair Broadcast sees Q3 cash flow down.</title>
<headline>Sinclair Broadcast sees Q3 cash flow down.</headline>
<dateline>BALTIMORE 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sinclair Broadcast Group Inc said late Friday after the market closed that it estimates pro forma broadcast cash flow for its third quarter to be four to five percent below the previous third quarter and revenues to be flat.</p>
<p>The company said it expects &quot;modest&quot; pro forma growth in revenues and broadcast cash flow for the fourth quarter 1996 over the fourth quarter 1995.</p>
<p>The company said that on an actual basis, its reported broadcast cash flow for the third quarter will nearly double due to various acquisitions completed during 1996.</p>
<p>Figures for last year were not immediately available.</p>
<p>Sinclair said loss of its NBC affiliation in Raleigh, North Carolina and the loss of its Fox affiliation in Birmingham, Alabama resulted in a decline in advertising revenues, as the company anticipated.</p>
<p>The company said these factors coupled with a lack of growth in non-Olympics television advertising will result in flat pro forma third quarter 1996 revenues compared to third quarter 1995.</p>
<p>The company said it had higher costs in the quarter due to an increase in program payments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALTIMORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
