<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="125979" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BankBoston has no comment on takeover report.</title>
<headline>BankBoston has no comment on takeover report.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Boston Corp declined Friday to comment on a published report that quoted a St. Louis-based options trader as saying the bank may soon be acquired by an international financial institution.</p>
<p>The Boston Business Journal, a weekly newspaper, quoted John Holst, owner of Holst Investments, as saying recent options and equity activity and staff changes point to a takeover.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't comment on rumors or speculation of acquisitions,&quot; Bank of Boston spokeswoman Karen Schwartzman said.  </p>
<p>Several analysts told Reuters they believe BankBoston will concentrate on its recent takeover of BayBanks Inc., and is not likely to be a takeover candidate in the near future.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a number of banks who would benefit strategically from acquiring Bank of Boston,&quot; said Michael Stead, manager of the SIFE Fund of Walnut Creek, Calf. &quot;But I know for a fact that they would like to manage their bank as a business...not just patching it up and turning it around and selling it.&quot; He said BankBoston management would consider an offer if it emerged, but he did not see the bank as a takeover candidate.  </p>
<p>Nancy Bush, an analyst with Brown Brothers Harriman, said BankBoston may be an attractive target in the intermediate term, but not imminently.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks to me like it would be very attractive for a foreign bank in a few years if management wants to sell,&quot; she told Reuters. &quot;They're just not ready to sell right now.&quot;</p>
<p>She said in a few years, BankBoston could be hit by some growth constraints in its New England and Latin American markets and would be a better candidate then.  </p>
<p>The Boston Business Journal quoted an unnamed Merrill Lynch &amp; Co money manager who said Dutch banks ABN AMRO Holding NV and ING Groep NV were the most likely partners.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO's Chairman Jan Kalff told Reuters in August that the bank would keep an eye on acquisition possibilities abroad, and was particularly interested in acquiring an asset maanagement company in the United States. And Managing Board Member Rijnhard van Tets said in September the bank was prepared to pay between $200 million and $400 million for a fund manager, preferably in the Chicago area.</p>
<p>-- Michael Ellis, Boston bureau (617) 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
