<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126195" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Leap in BFI reflects improving Panamax rates.</title>
<headline>Leap in BFI reflects improving Panamax rates.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Another spectacular leap in the BFI on Friday reflected sharply improving rates for Panamaxes in most areas except South America. The BFI was up 27 points to 1,145 to make a total gain of 145 points this month.</p>
<p>Brokers believe there is a substantial backlog of business to be fixed from the US Gulf, especially longer haul orders to the Far East.</p>
<p>A number of period fixtures of Panamaxes have given owners encouragement that the revival in their fortunes is not only broadly based geographically but possibly of some duration as well.</p>
<p>Owners are in no hurry to quote rate indications to charterers against their vessels in forward positions believing that the market has further to go in their favour. Handy-sizes have not yet gained in the same way with the exception of parts of the North Atlantic and Caper rates remain largely stagnant despite reports of better demand from charterers.</p>
<p>GRAIN</p>
<p>Brokers were taken aback this morning by reports from Tokyo that Andre fixed Evangelistria for 50,000/10 hss US Gulf/China for Oct 24/Nov 2 at $24.50, up $3.25 from Thursday's reported fixture of Chariot in this trade by Dreyfus. Andre are open again for US Gulf/China for Nov 1/15 and Dreyfus quote 50,000 upto 100,000 tonnes for Oct 21 upto Nov 15.</p>
<p>The implications for the US Gulf/Japan trade are obvious but no fixtures have been reported on this route on Friday. Brokers believe that Panamax heavy grain stem from US Gulf to the Continent must now be worth at least $12.00 compared to last fixed at $10.00. Bontrader 59,662 dwt is believed fixed on private terms by Cho Yang from US Gulf to South Korea. D'amato have taken a 20-year old 65,000 dwt vessel on subjects delivery prompt Atlantic for four to six months at $7,000 daily.</p>
<p>Seagrace II 64,344 dwt has been fixed for Transatlantic business on subjects. Also on subjects is the 1985-built Flavia 65,282 dwt understood to have obtained as much as $10,000 daily as-is delivery and redelivery US East Coast.</p>
<p>This follows and exceeds overnight reports that the 1993-built Bunga Saga Satu 73,000 dwt was booked delivery Antwerp end Oct for 3-5 months by Seatrans at $9,900 daily. The term-relet Lamyra 64,879 dwt fixed delivery continent early Nov trip China with Transfield at a firm $11,200 daily, ballasting from Southern Spain.</p>
<p>Heraklia 65,159 dwt ballasting from the Pacific has been taken by Halla delivery US Gulf mid Nov trip Far East at a strong $11,500 daily plus $215,000 bonus. Atlantic Savior 64,000 dwt has been fixed for grain from Nopac to Bin Qasim on private terms and Dreyfus are said to have fixed 54,000 hss Nopac/Japan for early Nov at an unchanged $11.85 basis no combo.</p>
<p>MINERALS ETC</p>
<p>Amazon 141,000 dwt was said to have been fixed by Korea Line (and possibly relet to Halla) delivery Brazil mid Nov for a trip to South korea with ironore at rates variously reported between $12,000 and $13,000 daily plus $250,000 bonus.</p>
<p>British steel were inked with Exemplar for 100,000 ironore Nouadhibou/Port Talbot for Nov 7/12 at about $3.25/3.50. In the coal trades a Russian Caper vessel was believed fixed by Preag Richards Bay/Ensted and Marine Courage 127,958 dwt may have been booked from Baltimore to Hunterston, but full details were not available. Noble fixed a Panamax on subjects with fertilizers from the Black Sea to China.</p>
<p>HANDIES</p>
<p>Few fixtures came to light in the West but there were reports of Handymaxes fixed in the Pacific. K Line are believed to have fixed a newbuilding 45,000 dwt delivery ex yard Japan for 3-5 months at about $8,000/8,250 daily and a 42,000 dwt vessel is rumoured covered delivery Nopac trip far East at $7,000/7,250 daily plus $120,000 bonus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
