<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126146" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Former London discount houses tie the knot.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Former London discount houses tie the knot.</headline>
<byline>Christopher Adams</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former City of London discount houses Gerrard &amp; National and King &amp; Shaxson Holdings, competing in an unfamiliar and difficult trading environment, said on Friday they would join forces.</p>
<p>The move will create the biggest private client stockbroker in Britain with 10 billion pounds ($15.9 billion) of funds under management, Gerrard said. Jobs will be lost but it declined to say how many.</p>
<p>The merger, which comprises an offer of 17 Gerrard ordinary shares for 25 King &amp; Shaxson shares and values King &amp; Shaxson at 53.7 million pounds, will lead to annual cost savings of around five percent.</p>
<p>But a sharp decline in Gerrard's half-year profits to 6.3 million pounds from 12.1 million and a new dividend policy disappointed the stock market.</p>
<p>Shares in the group slumped to a 1996 low of 270 pence after it said margins were slim and profitability disappointing.</p>
<p>&quot;Bringing Gerrard and King &amp; Shaxson together as Gerrard Group accelerates the strategies of each company,&quot; said the executive chairman of Gerrard, Brian Williamson, who is to become non-executive chairman when the merger is completed.</p>
<p>Since an initial investment in 1982, Gerrard &amp; National has built up a leading London futures and financial options broker in GNI Holdings. King &amp; Shaxson has grown a private client stockbroking and fund management business through the purchase and integration of Greig Middleton and Allied Provincial.</p>
<p>A key benefit arising from the merger will be cost savings, which are projected to be not less than five million pounds annually. Over the course of 1997, the new group will move all settlement office administration for the enlarged stockbroking business to Greig Middleton's Glasgow office.</p>
<p>The transfer of the back office will result in reduced staff numbers, Gerrard chief executive Michael Davies told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a saving in staff numbers,&quot; said Davies, who declined to say by how much the workforce would be cut. The combined group currently employs around 1,300.</p>
<p>He denied that the merger was a defensive reaction to a tough market. Gerrard also reported a sharp fall in operating profits and bemoaned the difficult state of trading conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;Gerrard has always stated it would develop its income and profits from agency commission business and it has done that successfully over the years in derivatives,&quot; said Davies.</p>
<p>&quot;It has a smaller presence in stockbroking (with Gerrard Vivian Gray) and it's been looking for the right opportunity to expand the earnings in that sector by finding the right fit.&quot;</p>
<p>Consolidation of Gerrard and King &amp; Shaxson's money market business will release at least 25 million pounds for investment in the group and future acquisitions, the companies said.</p>
<p>Davies said the likely areas for such development were the fund management and stockbroking businesses, not derivatives, where the company has always grown without acquisitions.</p>
<p>The sharp markdown in Gerrard's share price, while King &amp; Shaxson gained 20 pence to 182-1/2 after touching a new 1996 high of 193, was due to disappointment with the interim results.</p>
<p>&quot;The introduction of the gilt repo market, reduced turnover in foreign exchange and increasing margin pressure in derivative markets combined to create a particularly challenging trading environment,&quot; it said in its results statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The results were very poor, way below expectations,&quot; said a banking analyst who declined to be named. &quot;People are still using the brokers but the fees have gone down tremendously.&quot;</p>
<p>He added the enlarged group's new dividend policy was an unwelcome change for those investors who regard the shares as a solid bet for a rich yield. Gerrard will cut its total dividend to 16 pence from 23 so it can hold on to funds for investment.</p>
<p>King &amp; Shaxson in June posted full year pre-tax profits of 6.5 million pounds, up from 3.9 million the year before. This was boosted by exceptional profits of one million pounds from the sale of the Greig Middleton Channel Islands business. ($1=.6298 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
