<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126262" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe shares end on new high.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe shares end on new high.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's key share index hit new highs again on Friday, propelled by buying pressure from investors trading on a favourable medium-term economic forecast.</p>
<p>Brokers predict the Zimbabwe Stock Exchange (ZSE) would stay on a bullish course on this score.</p>
<p>&quot;Although there are some worries over inflation, and a weakening (Zimbabwe) dollar, the general view is that, in the medium-term, the economy should come right and quite a number of companies should perform well,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>On current forecasts of a near-normal rainy season, Zimbabwe's agriculture-powered economy is expected to grow by seven percent in 1997, up from an an estimated five percent this year.</p>
<p>Investors are also cheering news that the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank would support an economic reform programme due to be launched by President Robert Mugabe's government later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The good is outweighing the bad... and the bulls have resumed their run,&quot; one broker said in reference to annual inflation which rose to 20.6 percent in September after falling to a three-year low of 17.6 percent the previous month, and also the Zimbabwe dollar which is falling fast on major currencies under import pressure.</p>
<p>On Friday, the ZSE's main 57-counter industrial index closed the day 90.19 points higher at 7,356.87, carried to this altitude by big gains in some heavy-weight stocks.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe Newspapers (Zimpapers), clothing group Edgars and First Merchant Bank (FMB) traded 125, 500 and 625 cents higher at 1,800, 3500 and 4,200 respectively.</p>
<p>The industrial index gained a whooping 552.35 points on the week.</p>
<p>The secondary seven-share mining index rose 8.6 points on Friday to close at 1,254.53 after gold producers Ashanti, Falcon and Rio Tinto all traded 100 cents up at 14,100, 1,700 and 3,300.</p>
<p>The index jumped 46.58 points higher on the week.</p>
<p>-- Cris Chinaka, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
