<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126220" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Cricket-Kirsten blitz shapes S.African win.</title>
<headline>Cricket-Kirsten blitz shapes S.African win.</headline>
<byline>Sameer Sandhu</byline>
<dateline>HYDERABAD, India 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>An aggressive innings of 84 in 81 balls from opener Gary Kirsten fashioned a 47-run victory for South Africa in the opening match of the Titan Cup triangular limited-over series on Thursday.</p>
<p>Man-of-the-match Kirsten hit nine fours and one six as South Africa totalled 261 for seven in their 50 overs at Hyderabad's Lal Bahadur Stadium.</p>
<p>India were then bundled out for 214 in 46.3 overs with paceman Allan Donald claiming three wickets for 43 and Fanie de Villiers and Derek Crookes claiming two wickets apiece.</p>
<p>India never recovered from the swift dismissal of skipper and star batsman Sachin Tendulkar, caught by Cullinan at mid-wicket for 11 trying to force De Villiers off his toes.</p>
<p>Debutant opener Sujith Somasundar soon followed for eight when he failed to beat Kirsten's throw from mid-on, having responded late to Rahul Dravid's call.</p>
<p>Dravid, who scored 62 runs off 87 deliveries, waged a lone battle but found the task dfficult after the departure of Mohammed Azharuddin.</p>
<p>Dravid and Azharuddin steadied the innings with a 67-run third-wicket partnership off 96 balls, briefly threatening to take the game away from South Africa until Azharuddin, on 32, hit off-spinner Crookes straight to deep mid-wicket.</p>
<p>Left-hander Saurav Ganguly, who lifted off-break bowler Pat Symcox for a six over long-off, made 31 before skying a Donald delivery to Symcox at long-on.</p>
<p>South African skipper Hansie Crinje attributed the victory to the opening stand between Kirsten and Andrew Hudson.</p>
<p>&quot;The rousing start meant we would always be in the game,&quot; said Cronje. &quot;We were looking towards a total of 280 at one stage but (Anil) Kumble pushed us back with some fine bowling.&quot;</p>
<p>Cronje himself contributed an unbeaten 63, ensuring his side a victory within three days of arriving in India.</p>
<p>&quot;It was great to have won the game even before getting over the jet-lag,&quot; coach Bob Woolmer said. &quot;Winning the toss was a crucial factor as we did not fancy chasing a target against Indian spinners under floodlights.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HYDERABAD, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
