<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126259" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GAMBIA: Gambia coup leader sworn in as civilian president.</title>
<headline>Gambia coup leader sworn in as civilian president.</headline>
<dateline>BANJUL 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Military coup leader Yahya Jammeh was sworn in as Gambia's new civilian president on Friday, in front of a crowd of 20,000 people including dignitaries from neighbours and allies and Western diplomats.</p>
<p>Jammeh, who toppled independence president Sir Dawda Jawara in July 1994 accusing him of corruption, urged the mainly Moslem West African nation's &quot;old and new&quot; development partners to continue to help it develop.</p>
<p>He also expressed support for a U.S. plan for a rapid deployment peacekeeping force in Africa.</p>
<p>Jammeh said his coup had been a response to political and economic frustration and corruption. &quot;It was not a surprise or a matter of regret to the people,&quot; he said. &quot;It was preceeded by silent underground movements as well as tremors.&quot;</p>
<p>Gambia, a finger of territory fronting the Atlantic Ocean and surrounded by Senegal, relies on tourism and groundnuts.</p>
<p>Relations with its traditional Western partners cooled after the coup. It has since strengthened ties with Taiwan, Libya and Cuba, all have whom have provided aid in one form or another.</p>
<p>Friday's ceremony, in Banjul's independence stadium, was attended by Guinea Bissau President Joao Bernando Vieira and senior representatives from Niger, Nigeria, Mauritania, Libya, Senegal and Taiwan.</p>
<p>Gambia, a nation of just over one million people, became independent from Britain in 1965.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GAMB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANJUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
