<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126364" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish shares extend loss, seen inching down.</title>
<headline>Polish shares extend loss, seen inching down.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish shares fell in slightly higher turnover on Friday and analysts saw the market inching down early next week, extending the current profit-taking correction of the 11.1-percent rise since early September.</p>
<p>The WIG index fell 103.4 points, or 0.7 percent, to 14,718.4, and turnover rose 6.3 percent to 91.8 million zlotys ($32.8 million) on both markets as 46 issues fell, 18 rose and 16 were flat.</p>
<p>Analysts expected the market, which already fell 2.4 percent since the October 9 high of 15,078.7 points of the WIG index, to find support on 14,400 or 14,000.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe we will still have falls but the profit-taking correction is unlikely to be a very deep one,&quot; said Wojciech Kossuth, an analyst at Bank Slaski brokerage.</p>
<p>Analysts said early next week some stocks' performance might still be influenced by their earnings reports for September, due after the market's close on Friday.</p>
<p>Mass privatisation NFI units fell 5.1 percent in 22.4-million-zloty turnover ($8 million) in the regular session and fell 4.6 percent in 15-million-zloty ($5.4 million) continuous trade, extending their 9.9-percent fall since October 10, but analysts saw them rebounding soon.</p>
<p>Traders said furniture maker Swarzedz, Friday's biggest main market's loser, fell 7.7 percent in thin 0.1-million-zloty ($35,710) trade after showing a September loss of 28.5 million zlotys ($10.2 million).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
