<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126496" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: OAS chief confident on Nicaraguan elections.</title>
<headline>OAS chief confident on Nicaraguan elections.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Organisation of American States (OAS) chief Cesar Gaviria said on Friday he was confident Nicaragua's upcoming presidential elections would be free and fair.</p>
<p>Gaviria, arriving in Nicaragua to observe the Oct. 20 vote, said he was &quot;satisfied with the peaceful way in which the process has taken place.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We're hopeful and confident that next Sunday we will see free, transparent and competitive elections,&quot; said Gaviria, a former president of Colombia.</p>
<p>Sunday's first round vote will mark the first time a civilian, freely-elected president transfers power to another such president under undisputed circumstances in Nicaragua's violent history.</p>
<p>The election pits right-wing Arnoldo Aleman of the Liberal Alliance against former President Daniel Ortega of the left-wing Sandinista Front.</p>
<p>Aleman holds a slim lead heading into the balloting. If neither candidate gets 45 percent of the vote, a run-off vote will be held between the two top candidates in late November or early June.</p>
<p>Nicaragua's army chief, Gen. Joaquin Cuadra, told Reuters that the army would be loyal and &quot;offer institutional support to the victor.&quot;</p>
<p>The Nicaraguan army, reborn in 1979 as the Sandinista People's Army, underwent radical cuts following President Violeta Chamorro's election upset of Ortega in 1990, ceasing to be the armed wing of the Sandinista party.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time, the bullets and bombs will be absent, and I'm sure that Nicaraguans, in spite of their fears, will vote in peace,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAMS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
