<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126458" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Oct 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Oct 18.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Friday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Croatia gets its first 200 million German marks loan from commercial creditors and arranged by Dresdner Bank.</p>
<p>- Who will get 500,000 sq m property of the former communist party and other political bodies from the previous regime which under a new law belong to the state?</p>
<p>- Most car insurers in Croatia extend invalid policies, state control board said after a brief probe. Maplractices are mostly based on unfounded discounts.</p>
<p>- Hotelier faculty in Pula hosts &quot;Hotel House&quot;, a two day international congress of over 200 experts.</p>
<p>- Inland revenue threatens to denounce companies which might unfoundedly raise prices once VAT is imposed in January.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Trade unions propose a 1,100 kuna non taxable salary base in negotiations with the government.</p>
<p>- Parliamentary speaker Vlatko Pavletic agrees with the opposition, boycotting parliament sessions protesting over lack of media coverage.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- After admission to the Council of Europe, lawyers to become the busiest in Croatia as many laws need adjustment to comply with European conventions.</p>
<p>- Parliament discusses a draft law on trades and small enterprises which now employ some 84,000 people, 50 percent more than in 1991.</p>
<p>- Minister Niko Bulic says tourism would yield 10 million kuna by the end of 1996, but the tourist trade may end the year with a zero profit. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
