<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126433" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACEDONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - Oct 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - Oct 18.</headline>
<dateline>SKOPJE 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Skopje press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NOVA MAKEDONIJA</p>
<p>- Several thousand candidates are starting the race for November 17 local elections which will be contested by 28 political parties and as many independent candidates.</p>
<p>- NATO Secretary Generl Javier Solana to visit Macedonia in December. Macedonia expects to be the last country on his tour of Patnership for Peace member countries.</p>
<p>- Albanian students of Skopje's Education faculty boycott Macedonian language classes. They demand all classess to be in Albanian.</p>
<p>- Foreign medical experts are investigating reasons of the poisoning of Albanian children in Tetovo. They will remain in Tetovo longer to contact the patients.</p>
<p>- Famous doctor Jovially Ugrinovski who operated on Macedonian President Kiro Gligorov and saved his life is the candidate of the ruling SDAM for Skopje mayor.</p>
<p>VECER</p>
<p>- Macedonian Deputy Prime minister Jane Miljovski has sustained light injuries in a car accident close to the Bulgarian border. -- Mircela Casule, Skopje newsroom +389 91 201196</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SKOPJE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACEDONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
