<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126655" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan import delays show rice still political issue.</title>
<headline>Japan import delays show rice still political issue.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Politically sensitive imports of rice, already behind a schedule set by a global trade pact, have been put on hold in the build up to Japan's general election on Sunday, traders and officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Under a 1993 General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade agreement, Japan agreed to gradually open its long-closed rice market and committed itself to importing 511,000 tonnes of rice during the year to the end of next March.</p>
<p>But so far in the fiscal year, the Food Agency, the grain trading arm of the Agriculture Ministry and the sole importer of rice, has bought only 39,500 tonnes, mainly from China and Australia, with the last tender in late July.</p>
<p>&quot;Rice import tenders have been delayed this year because of ample stocks and political circumstances. And a specific tender schedule later this year in not finalised yet,&quot; said Vice Agriculture Minister Hirofumi Ueno.</p>
<p>&quot;But we'll definitely meet our international commitment and import the agreed quota,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But the ministry said it was likely to further defer the imports because of a bumper domestic harvest and sluggish sales of foreign rice.</p>
<p>Rice stocks at the close of the 1995/96 rice crop year which ends this month were expected to climb to three million tonnes from 1.61 million a year ago, industry officials said.</p>
<p>A level of 1.5 million tonnes is considered desirable.</p>
<p>A good Japanese harvest in the last two years has filled grain warehouses.</p>
<p>Local rice traders said Sunday's general election was a key reason behind the delayed rice tenders.</p>
<p>Rice farmers are big supporters of the conservative Liberal Democratic Party (LDP), Japan's largest party.</p>
<p>&quot;It's apparent the Food Agency wanted to postpone import tenders until the general election,&quot; a major trade house official said. &quot;Rice is still a politically sensitive commodity.&quot;</p>
<p>The delays are likely to hurt Australia. Because of its different growing season in the Southern hemisphere, Australia normally exports rice to Japan from early March through August.</p>
<p>The delayed tenders will put Australia at a disadvantage against Northern hemisphere producers such as the United States and China.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand the Japanese government's dilemma, but were very disappointed,&quot; said an agriculture officer at the Australian Embassy in Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;The present tender system is an indirect discrimination against Australian rice. We believe import tenders should be spread (throughout the year),&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
