<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126631" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine firms seen buying more U.S. wheat.</title>
<headline>Philippine firms seen buying more U.S. wheat.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine flour mills are expected to go back for more U.S. wheat in the coming week if prices fall further from current levels, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Traders expected local flour millers to buy 200,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat for their November and December requirements.</p>
<p>Philippine flour mills asked for price quotes for 109,000 tonnes of U.S. this week.</p>
<p>&quot;U.S. wheat prices are expected to fall further next week due to reports of bumper harvests in other exporting countries,&quot; said one Manila trader.</p>
<p>In fact, wheat exporters from Canada, Australia and Argentina are courting Philippine buyers, the trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Canadian suppliers said they plan to offer us some stocks in December. We have asked Australian suppliers to give us sample stocks for test milling and, we're also looking at Argentina's offer,&quot; said an executive in a local flour company.</p>
<p>On Friday, a group of Philippine flour mills bought 32,000 tonnes of dark northern spring wheat with a 14 percent protein content at $4.13 per bushel FOB, and 3,000 tonnes of western white wheat at $4.11 per bushel FOB, said one trader.</p>
<p>Another order for 19,000 tonnes of soft white wheat was clinched by a Japanese commodity house from Philippine flour mills Wednesday at $162 per tonne FOB.</p>
<p>Both orders were for November deliveries.</p>
<p>Traders said local flour prices were steady. The retail price of hard flour in Metro Manila was pegged at 300 pesos ($11.53) per 25 kg while soft flour was quoted at 260 pesos, traders said.</p>
<p>Local corn prices were mixed.</p>
<p>The state-owned National Food Authority (NFA) said wholesale price of white corn grain was unchanged at 8.70 pesos (33.46 cents) per kg while the wholesale price of yellow corn grain edged up to 8.85 pesos per kg from 8.80 pesos.</p>
<p>The NFA may likely tender for 150,000 tonnes of yellow corn in the coming week to meet increased demand from poultry and hog raisers during the Christmas season.</p>
<p>President Fidel Ramos approved tax and duty-free imports of yellow corn to bring down the cost of local meat products, the Presidential Palace said in a statement on Friday.</p>
<p>Conversion $1 =26</p>
<p>--Manila newsroom (632) 841-89-36</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
