<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126719" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole steps up attack as Clinton takes break.</title>
<headline>Dole steps up attack as Clinton takes break.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, Political Correspondent</p>
<p>Republican Bob Dole kept up his offensive against President Bill Clinton's ethics on Friday as U.S. campaign race turned relentlessly negative.</p>
<p>Clinton took a brief break from campaigning but his campaign staff hit back at Dole with a statement highlighting the Republican nominee's purported role in a questionable effort to defend then-President Richard Nixon in 1970.</p>
<p>With two-and-a-half weeks left before Election day on November 5, Dole edged closer to Clinton in the latest Reuters tracking poll, in which he trailed by nine percentage points.</p>
<p>The poll showed previously lukewarm Republicans were finally rallying to the Dole ticket following Wednesday's second presidential debate, in which Dole sharply attacked the ethical standards of the Clinton administration.</p>
<p>Three other polls put the challenger 10 to 14 points back, with Reform Party candidate Ross Perot in single digits.</p>
<p>At a rally in Albuquerque, Dole pounded Clinton on the character issue, referring to news stories about questionable contributions to the Democratic Party from businessmen linked to Indonesian, South Korean and other foreign interests.</p>
<p>&quot;Every day we have a new scandal involving the foreign corruption of America. Our elections are not for sale to some foreign influence or some foreign interest,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>&quot;Come clean Mr. President!&quot; Dole said on the first stop of a hectic day that would take him from New Mexico to Colorado, Kansas and Kentucky.</p>
<p>Firing back, Clinton spokesman Joe Lockhart said that 26-year-old documents released by the National Archives on Thursday portrayed Dole, then Republican Party chairman, urging Republicans into &quot;politically-inspired investigations of past misdoings by Democratic administrations&quot; to deflect attention from Nixon, then a target of Vietnam War protests.</p>
<p>The campaign provided copies of a memorandum to Nixon dated Feb 10, 1970 from then-White House adviser Pat Buchanan outlining what Buchanan said was Dole's proposal.</p>
<p>Lockhart said Dole's attacks on Clinton were &quot;sadly consistent with his 35-year record&quot; in Washington politics.</p>
<p>Dole appears to have decided he has nothing to lose by sharply escalating his attacks on Clinton's ethics.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to get tough,&quot; Dole said at a rally in California, on Thursday. &quot;You haven't seen anything yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole campaign manager Scott Reed on Friday issued a detailed statement addressed to Clinton and fleshing out Dole's accusations.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of your party's biggest contributors appear to have been Indonesian billionaires, South Korean companies, parishioners at Buddhist temples and foreign gardeners with green cards,&quot; Reed said.</p>
<p>&quot;The questions that keep coming up are the same: where did the money come from? How was it funnelled to your campaign coffers? What did it buy?</p>
<p>Republicans have attacked Clinton over reports that an Indonesian couple with ties to the financial conglomerate Lippo Group made a $425,000 donation to the Democratics.</p>
<p>House of Representatives Speaker Newt Gingrich on Thursday called for an investigation into whether the Indonesian government won U.S. foreign policy favours in return for the money. Clinton officials have denied all such suggestions.</p>
<p>Lockhart responded to Reed's statement by citing three investigations of alleged campaign finance violations by the Dole campaign that he said were currently underway.</p>
<p>In one, a Massachusetts businessman who was a Dole campaign national finance vice chairman had admitted illegal contributions, agreed to pay a $6 million fine and faced a hearing next week to determine his prison term, Lockhart said.</p>
<p>Clinton is due to leave on Sunday on his next campaign swing. It will take him to the hotly contested states of New Jersey, Ohio, Michigan and Florida.</p>
<p>In a sign of confidence, he also plans to raid Dole's Republican heartland with a trip to Alabama next week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
