<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126830" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. says Savimbi statements are positive.</title>
<headline>U.S. says Savimbi statements are positive.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Friday urged Angola's opposition UNITA leader Jonas Savimbi to make good on recent positive statements and fulfil his obligations in a peace agreement with the government.</p>
<p>&quot;We have since seen ... some very positive statements by Mr. Savimbi -- that he would, in fact, meet his commitments to the United Nations, to the United States and others, that he would act in such a way to promote a continued reconciliation with the Angolan government,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We now need to see those nice fine statements turned into concrete action on the ground,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Savimbi, slammed by the Security Council for delaying a peace plan to end two decades of civil war, has told the United Nations he will complete remaining steps in the pact within a month.</p>
<p>The Security Council has threatened to implement sanctions against UNITA (the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola) after Nov. 20 if it fails to meet its obligations under the pact signed with the government two years ago.</p>
<p>The U.N. special envoy to Angola, Alioune Blondin Beye, held three hours of talks with Savimbi at his base in Bailundo on Tuesday -- the first since the Security Council last Friday extended its peacekeeping mandate in Angola by two months.</p>
<p>Beye told a news conference on his return to the government-controlled capital Luanda that Savimbi had reaffirmed his commitment to peace and would complete remaining steps by Nov. 15.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher stopped in Angola on Monday on a five-nation Africa tour to also press for compliance, saying it was &quot;imperative&quot; that Angola's rival factions honour peace accords and warning that the world would not tolerate renewed war.</p>
<p>Savimbi refused to meet him in Luanda so Christopher sent a senior aide, Assistant Secretary of State George Moose, to meet the UNITA leader at his bush stronghold. Burns said severe weather prevented Moose's plane from landing and he returned to Washington.</p>
<p>In his place, U.S. Ambassador to Angola Donald Steinberg visited Savimbi later in the week and conveyed Christopher's message on the importance of Savimbi &quot;do(ing) the right things to promote national reconciliation in Angola,&quot; Burns said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
