<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="126937" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Xerox posts disappointing results, stock plummets.</title>
<headline>Xerox posts disappointing results, stock plummets.</headline>
<dateline>STAMFORD, Conn. 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Xerox Corp. said Friday a decline in copier revenues led to disappointing third quarter results, triggering a sharp decline in its stock.</p>
<p>Xerox said it earned $250 million, or 71 cents a share in the period ending Sept. 30, which was up from $236 million, or 68 cents a year earlier, but fell short of Wall Street's expectations.</p>
<p>Xerox's stock dropped $9.25 to $47.75 in morning trading the New York Stock Exchange. Wall Street analysts had expected Xerox to earn 82 cents a share, according to estimates compiled by First Call.</p>
<p>Third quarter revenue increased to $4.16 billion from $4.01 billion.</p>
<p>Xerox Chairman Paul Allaire said results were hurt by a decline in its traditional strength, stand-alone copiers, while revenues from networked printing systems, or enterprise printing, increased.</p>
<p>&quot;I am disappointed in the results this quarter,&quot; Allaire said. &quot;Although enterprise printing revenue growth accelerated in all major geographic areas, overall revenue growth was adversely affected by a modest decline in black-and-white copier revenues.</p>
<p>Black-and-white copier revenues declined by 4 percent and as of the end of the quarter, represented 56 percent of the company's total revenues, Xerox said. Enterprise printing revenues grew by 23 percent and represent 30 percent of total revenues.</p>
<p>Black-and-white copier revenues declined as a result of several factors, including price pressure and difficult economic environments in Europe and a number of emerging markets, Xerox said.</p>
<p>For the first nine months, Xerox earned $780 million, or $2.14 a share, on sales of $12.3 billion. A year earlier, Xerox earned $697 million, or $1.91 a share, on sales of $11.8 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STAMFORD, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
