<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12698" id="root" date="1996-08-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian Socialists start landmark reform congress.</title>
<headline>Albanian Socialists start landmark reform congress.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-08-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's opposition Socialist Party began a two-day congress on Saturday to discuss major jettisoning its links with almost half a century of Stalinist dictatorship in the Balkan country.</p>
<p>&quot;The congress will approve new concepts that will turn the party into a Social-Democratic and electoral party, not a class and ideological one,&quot; the Socialist Zeri i Popullit daily said in an editorial.</p>
<p>Jailed Socialist leader Fatos Nano made the first call for change in July, a month after the party's chief opponents, the conservative Democrats of President Sali Berisha, almost swept the board in a disputed general election.</p>
<p>The Socialists, reformed heirs to the communists, pulled out of the poll saying it was a sham.</p>
<p>Acting Socialist leader Servet Pellumbi has said he too will urge the party to scrap the ideas of Karl Marx at the congress.</p>
<p>The pro-reform stance of some of the party leadership initially caused a storm and triggered the resignation last month of the party's Secretary-General Gramoz Ruci.</p>
<p>More recently political commentators have reported a growing consensus, however, and a rift at the meeting looks increasingly unlikely.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
