<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127043" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Allianz sees Nov ruling in Vereinte case. [CORRECTED 15:05 GMT]</title>
<headline>Allianz sees Nov ruling in Vereinte case. [CORRECTED 15:05 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Allianz AG Holding, Europe's leading insurer, said on Friday it expected German and European cartel authorities to reach a decision in November on its plans to take over the Vereinte Holding AG insurance group.</p>
<p>An Allianz spokesman said it hoped to begin selling Vereinte health insurance products through its own sales network as soon as the expected approval for the takeover came through.</p>
<p>The European Commission in Brussels said on Monday Allianz and Vereinte had officially registered their intention to fuse.</p>
<p>Allianz announced its surprising plans to take over Vereinte fully in July after trying unsuccessfully to find a buyer for the group, which it had partly acquired as part of a package from reinsurer Swiss Re in 1994.</p>
<p>Allianz decided to sell its DKV health insurance unit to Muenchener Rueckversicherungs AG in return for a majority in Vereinte's health insurance unit, the loan insurance firm Hermes and other smaller holdings.</p>
<p>Cartel authorities in Germany had objected to Allianz's original acquisition of Vereinte on the grounds that it would give Allianz too large a role in health insurance.</p>
<p>Since DKV and Vereinte occupy first and second position in the German health insurance market, ownership of both would have placed Allianz in a monopoly position.</p>
<p>Allianz's spokesman said no direct lay-offs would be made during the takeover, in line with an agreement to protect staff which is effective through to the year 2000.</p>
<p>(Corrects to make clear that staff will not be dismissed, but it is not yet clear whether jobs will be lost).</p>
<p>A Vereinte spokesman said the agreement applied to all 7,500 staff.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
