<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127133" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida theft ring exported cars to Russia.</title>
<headline>Florida theft ring exported cars to Russia.</headline>
<byline>Jim Loney</byline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. authorities said on Friday they had dismantled a Florida car theft ring run by Finnish nationals who exported hundreds of stolen vehicles, boats and weapons to Estonia and Russia.</p>
<p>Authorities said the ring reflected the dramatic growth of international car theft and the emergence of burgeoning markets for U.S. goods in the former Soviet bloc.</p>
<p>The thieves used a malodorous method of hiding their stolen goods -- secreting the vehicles in shipping containers lined with rotting animal hides to deter curious Customs inspectors, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;These people get pretty creative,&quot; said John Sullivan, agent-in-charge of the U.S. Customs office in West Palm Beach, Florida. &quot;They try to do it in a way that if inspectors decided to open the container, it's so disgusting that they won't bother to inspect it.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the alleged leaders of the ring was a Finn who served time in a Finnish prison for the murder of his parents and brother and was wanted for questioning in connection with a Helsinki car bombing, officials said.</p>
<p>Suspects in the case told authorities the operation, based in the small Florida town of Lake Worth, just south of Palm Beach, sent up to 500 vehicles a year out of the United States, making it the largest theft ring of its kind in recent memory, Sullivan said.</p>
<p>Aided by Interpol and the Finnish National Bureau of Investigation, U.S. law enforcement agencies arrested 15 suspects and seized at least 30 vehicles worth more than $700,000, officials said.</p>
<p>Export to Russia was a new twist in a long-running problem in southern Florida. In the past, most stolen vehicles were shipped to Latin America.</p>
<p>&quot;Because they (former Soviet Union) are entering a whole new era of development, Western-produced goods have a great deal of value,&quot; said Sullivan. &quot;There was definitely a clear profit motive. Many times they were more than doubling the price when they sent goods overseas.&quot;</p>
<p>Authorities identified the ring's leaders as Pauli Juntunen, 37, of Suomussalmi, Finland; Veli Virtanen, 30, of Helsinki; and Riejo Mork, 40, of Janakkala, Finland.</p>
<p>Juntunen, the alleged mastermind, was arrested in March on state charges but was released from the Palm Beach County jail on bond and fled the United States a week later.</p>
<p>Mork and Virtanen remained in custody in Florida pending sentencing. Agents completed a roundup of other suspects about three weeks ago but did not announce the arrests until now to protect the investigation in other countries, where more arrests were expected, authorities said.</p>
<p>Finnish authorities sought to question Virtanen, who served seven years in a Finnish prison for the 1987 slayings of his parents and younger brother, and is wanted for questioning in a 1995 car bombing of Helsinki police headquarters and courthouse, officials said.</p>
<p>The ringleaders recruited local criminals to steal cars in Florida's major metropolitan areas -- Miami, Fort Lauderdale, West Palm Beach and Jacksonville -- and shipped the cars through Finland and Estonia to Russia, officials said.</p>
<p>One of the stolen cars, a 1991 Cadillac, turned up in the possession of an innocent high-ranking Finnish government official who had no knowledge it was stolen, U.S. agents said.</p>
<p>The ring also dealt in jet skis, boats, car parts, construction equipment, tools, weapons and narcotics.</p>
<p>The Chicago-based National Insurance Crime Bureau said the export of stolen vehicles for sale in former Soviet bloc countries was a relatively new phenomenon, though authorities had recently uncovered a major theft operation shipping cars to Poland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
