<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127458" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW - Gerrard to cut back office staff.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Gerrard to cut back office staff.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The newly enlarged broking and specialist banking Gerrard Group, which will comprise Gerrard &amp; National and King &amp; Shaxson, is to cut back office staff numbers as part of a plan to achieve annual savings of at least five million stg a year, chief executive Mark Davies said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a saving in staff numbers... there will be reductions,&quot; Davies told Reuters in an interview on Friday, but declined to say by how much the workforce would be reduced.</p>
<p>Former City of London discount houses Gerrard &amp; National and King &amp; Shaxson earlier announced plans to merge, creating a combined group with 10 billion stg of funds under management.  </p>
<p>Gerrard is making a recommended bid for King &amp; Shaxson, valuing it at 53.7 million stg. Its offer comprises 17 Gerrard ordinary shares for 25 King &amp; Shaxson shares.</p>
<p>Since an initial investment in 1982, Gerrard has built up leading futures and financial options broker GNI Holdings, while King &amp; Shaxson has grown a private client stockbroking and fund management business through the purchase and integration of Greig Middleton and Allied Provincial.</p>
<p>Over the course of next year, the new group will move all settlement office administration for the enlarged stockbroking business to Greig Middleton's Glasgow office in Scotland.  </p>
<p>Davies said the combined group currently employed around 1,300 people. The annual savings resulting from the merger will be about five percent of the combined group's current cost base.</p>
<p>Davies denied the merger was a defensive reaction to tough conditions, which have affected Gerrard in particular. The group reported a sharp fall in interim pre-tax profits to 6.3 million stg from 12.1 million and blamed &quot;reduced turnover in foreign exchange and increasing margin pressure in derivative markets&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Gerrard has always stated it would develop its income and profits from agency commission business and it has done that successfully over the years in derivatives,&quot; said Davies.  </p>
<p>&quot;It has a smaller presence in stockbroking (with Gerrard Vivian Gray) and it's been looking for the right opportunity to expand the earnings in that sector by finding the right fit.&quot;</p>
<p>Consolidation of Gerrard and King &amp; Shaxson's money market business will release at least 25 million stg for investment in the group and future acquisitions.</p>
<p>Davies said the likely areas for such development were the fund management and stockbroking businesses, not derivatives, where the company has always grown without acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see ourselves going off and doing something completely different to what we're doing at the moment. It is building funds under management and agency commissions and we will pursue that strategy.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
