<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127495" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Israel, PLO adjourn talks, snipe at each other.</title>
<headline>Israel, PLO adjourn talks, snipe at each other.</headline>
<byline>Wafa Amr</byline>
<dateline>TABA, Egypt 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel and the PLO sniped at each other on Friday as they adjourned talks on a long-delayed Israeli redeployment in the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>Palestinians blamed Israel for a setback in negotiations. Going into talks overnight at Israel's Eilat Red Sea resort, Palestinians had thought a deal on Hebron, where 400 Jewish settlers live amid 100,000 Palestinians, was in sight.</p>
<p>Israel, in response to the Palestinian charge, accused the PLO of spreading &quot;disinformation&quot;.</p>
<p>Palestinians and Arab states regard the Hebron redeployment as a litmus test of Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's intentions regarding the peace process.</p>
<p>Negotiators left Eilat before dawn on Friday saying no deal had yet been struck. The sides later met for two hours in the Egyptian vacation spot of Taba just across the border.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed to continue meetings on Monday alternating between Eilat and Taba. On the weekend, subcommittees will be meeting,&quot; Palestinian negotiator Hassan Asfour told reporters after the talks in Taba on Friday.</p>
<p>It was not clear which town would host Monday's talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not reached a framework of agreement over Hebron because of the internal disputes in the Israeli delegation yesterday,&quot; Asfour said.</p>
<p>Israeli negotiating team spokesman Moshe Fogel had earlier denied Palestinian reports of disputes between political and military representatives on the Israeli delegation.</p>
<p>&quot;It's unfortunate that the Palestinians are involved in disinformation of that type,&quot; Fogel told Reuters.</p>
<p>U.S. envoy Dennis Ross, mediating the talks, told reporters differences had been narrowed but each side had &quot;concerns&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to do our best to try to reach agreement as soon as possible on Hebron. That is the first priority but we are going to be discussing other issues as well,&quot; Ross said.</p>
<p>Israeli negotiating team head Dan Shomron said a solution was &quot;very close&quot; but he did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials said overnight Israel was no longer insisting on a buffer zone to divide Israeli and PLO forces in Hebron or on the right of &quot;hot pursuit&quot;, allowing Israel to chase wanted Palestinians in areas coming under PLO control.</p>
<p>They said it was also agreed that talks on all other outstanding issues in a 1995 interim deal would start immediately after a Hebron agreement.</p>
<p>But Israeli media, quoting sources on the Israeli team, on Friday said that far from Israel dropping the demands, the sides were working on a compromise in which a joint PLO-Israeli force would carry out hot pursuit and patrol buffer areas.</p>
<p>Israel's Haaretz daily, quoting a senior Israeli source, said Netanyahu approved the proposal. Asfour denied the reports. Fogel refused to comment.</p>
<p>Israel's previous government in September 1995 signed a deal with the Palestine Liberation Organisation (PLO) to expand Palestinian self-rule in the West Bank.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Israel was to redeploy from seven West Bank towns including Hebron. It was also to begin pulling back from rural West Bank areas by September 1996.</p>
<p>Six towns were handed over to the PLO last year but the partial pullback from Hebron, due to have occurred in March, was delayed after Islamic suicide attacks in February and March killed 59 in Israel.</p>
<p>Netanyahu, elected in May, put the deal on hold, saying changes were needed to enhance security for Jewish settlers.</p>
<p>Palestinians say there is flexibility in the deal but they refuse to make substantive changes to it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TABA, Egypt"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
