<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127623" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Deputy holds two hostages in bank standoff;one dead.</title>
<headline>Deputy holds two hostages in bank standoff;one dead.</headline>
<dateline>HOUMA, La 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Louisiana deputy sheriff killed one woman and was holding two hostages early Friday -- including his ex-wife -- in a 12-hour standoff at a bank, state police said.</p>
<p>The deputy, Chad Louviere, 24, earlier Thursday freed one hostage in exchange for lunch, a second in mid-afternoon for a radio and a third Thursday night as a good-faith gesture, police said.</p>
<p>But Louviere had not released the body of 27-year-old Pamela Duplantis, who was shot to death shortly after he entered the Argent Bank late in the morning where his estranged wife works, a state police spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>He would not say what, if any, demands Louviere had made but said negotiations were continuing to free the remaining hostages. The bank has been surrounded by state, parish and city law enforcement officers.</p>
<p>Louviere was on duty, armed and in uniform when the incident began. Another police source said the deputy is suspected of raping another woman early Thursday morning.</p>
<p>Capt. Mike Elstner of the Terrebonne Parish sheriff's department said negotiators still hope to convince Louviere to surrender.</p>
<p>&quot;Right now it's just on a standstill, we're waiting it out,&quot; he said Thursday evening.</p>
<p>Houma is about 45 miles southwest of New Orleans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUMA, La"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
