<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127621" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Oct 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Oct 18.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories on Friday:</p>
<p>- Two senior executives at Archer Daniels Midland Co have resigned as a federal investigation into price fixing at the company deepens.</p>
<p>- U.S. indicators on industrial production, housing starts and employement sparked a bond market rally and helped pull stock prices higher.</p>
<p>- AT&amp;T Corp reported a third-quarter profit from continuing operations of $1.36 billion or $0.84 per share.</p>
<p>- Nearly nine out of 10 senior company executives believe the U.S. economy is going well, according to a poll conducted by The New York Times and CBS News.</p>
<p>- Silicon Graphics Inc reported a first-quarter loss due to special charges and product transition issues.</p>
<p>- Only 10 percent of the corporate executives at the 500 biggest companies in the United States are women, according to the results of a census.</p>
<p>- British media conglomerate Pearson PLC named Marjorie Scardino as its chief executive. Scardino was chief executive of the Economist Group, which publishes the magazine of the same name.</p>
<p>- California has reduced from 60 to 45 days the suspension ordered against Chrysler Corp regarding the shipment of care and trucks to the state.</p>
<p>- Wall Street reacted with displeasure towards the merger of Tenet Healthcare and OrNda Healthcrop.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
