<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127795" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks close at highest since May 1994.</title>
<headline>French stocks close at highest since May 1994.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares closed at a fresh high on Friday, taking the blue-chip CAC-40 index to its highest close since May 1994, after a series of U.S. data this week, ending with the trade data on Friday, was well received.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index was up 19.90 points or 0.92 percent at 2,185.23 while the CAC-40 October futures contract was up 23 at 2,190.</p>
<p>On May 18, 1994, the CAC-40 closed at 2,183.99 and it has closed below that level every trading day until today.</p>
<p>The CAC-40 index also hit an intra-day high for the year at 2,187.07. The index gained 1.7 percent compared to last Friday, with falls on Monday and Wednesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said they expected profit taking next week with a support level for the October future contract seen at 2,160.</p>
<p>Volume was 5.8 billion francs of which 4.1 billion in blue-chip shares.</p>
<p>Investors appeared to be reasssured that Thursday's national strike by public sector employees &quot;was no big deal,&quot; said a head of equity sales at a French broker.</p>
<p>Danone fell 1.73 percent to 738 francs on disappointment over nine-month sales. Danone said on Thursday after close its nine-month sales were up two percent on a like-for-like basis. Broker Cheuvreux de Virieu lowered its recommendation on Danone to sell from buy.</p>
<p>SGS-Thomson gained 3.32 percent on third quarter results. Morgan Stanley upgraded the share to strong buy from outperform.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
