<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127949" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRA-Australia labor disputes fall in July.</title>
<headline>RTRA-Australia labor disputes fall in July.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of Australian labour disputes fell in July to 43 from 52 in June, the Australian Bureau of Statistics said on Friday.</p>
<p>But the total number of working days lost due to industrial disputes increased three percent to 137,300 from 133,400.  </p>
<p>The construction industry was the worst-hit sector, losing 56,100 working days, or 41 percent of all days lost in July, the bureau said.</p>
<p>&quot;Significant increases and high levels of disputation were also evident in coal mining (33,100) and Other industries (predominantly government administration and defence) which reported 25,000 working days lost,&quot; the bureau said.</p>
<p>The latest figure is a substantial increase over the same month last year, when just 36,500 working days were lost from 69 disputes.  </p>
<p>The number of working days lost in the fiscal year to June 30 increased dramatically over the previous year to 899,600, compared with 580,300 in 1994/95, the bureau said.</p>
<p>But the number of disputes fell to 563 from 651, the bureau said. More than half the working days lost in 1995/96 occurred in just two industries -- construction, which lost 286,900 days, and education, health and community services, which lost 234,200 days.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
