<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127922" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks end off highs after profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks end off highs after profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian shares ended a touch firmer on Friday with profit-taking dragging the market off its early highs as investors decided to square positions after the market reached record highs during the week.</p>
<p>The benchmark All Ordinaries index closed just 1.2 points higher at 2,355.0, well off its intra-day high of 2,369.3.</p>
<p>The December share price index ended up 11 points at 2,384 and at a 29 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said stocks targeted by profit takers were those blue chip issues that rose the most during the week, namely major resource issues, BHP, WMC and CRA.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has had a good run up this week and investors were quite happy to take some profits at the end of it,&quot; a dealer at Sydney-based brokerage said.</p>
<p>The dealer said investors were also showing caution due to the high level of the Wall Street market. He said recent media commentary had suggested the Dow could be near levels which may prompt a significant retracement.</p>
<p>&quot;However, local market sentiment is still good because the feeling is that the Australian market is relatively undervalued compared to other world markets,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is well-positioned to take advantage of any more gains by Wall Street without being too badly affected by a pull-back in that market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Amongst the stronger issues on the day was Woodside Petroleum which rallied from the open after the company said on Thursday that partners in the North-West Shelf liquefied natural gas project had agreed to a A$6.0 billion (US$4.7 billion) expansion.</p>
<p>Woodside stock closed eight cents higher at A$8.93.</p>
<p>The shares of engineering group ANI also closed firmer on high turnover ahead of the company's annual meeting on Monday which is expected to resolve a dispute between directors.</p>
<p>ANI shares ended six cents higher at A$1.24.</p>
<p>(A$1 = US$0.79)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
