<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127974" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan to include bond repo trade in money market.</title>
<headline>Taiwan to include bond repo trade in money market.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's central bank said on Friday it plans to include the island's repurchase agreement trade on government bonds in the money market by the end of this year.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank just held a meeting with the Ministry of Finance, and both sides decided to include repurchase agreement trade on government bonds in the money market, so as to help the healthy development of the government bond market,&quot; a central bank official told journalists.</p>
<p>Following the increases of the government's budget deficits -- with the government bond issuance outstanding totalling T$894.6 billion at the end of September -- the government bond's secondary market has enjoyed a booming development, the central bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>But most of the secondary bond market trade was conducted in repurchase agreements, the statement said.</p>
<p>In September 1996 alone, 87.8 percent of the total monthly trade in the government bond market at T$2.437 trillion was conducted in repurchase agreements, with only the remaining 12.2 percent in outright purchase and sale, it said.</p>
<p>The repurchase agreement trade has basically the same function as a money market tool, but according to the current securities transaction rule, it is considered a capital market tool, it said.</p>
<p>The local bond mutual funds had a total net asset value of T$183.7 billion at the end of September 1996, up 170 percent from end-January 1996, it said.</p>
<p>Of the September figure, 44.1 percent was invested in time deposits, 37.8 percent in bonds' repurchase agreements, 16.3 percent in outright purchase and sale on bonds, and 1.8 percent in others, it said.</p>
<p>Currently, the central bank has yet to allow the establishment of money market mutual funds, but in considering the repurchase agreement trade as a money market tool, Taiwan in fact already has money market mutual funds, it said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
