<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="127975" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares end up on speculative buying.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares end up on speculative buying.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta shares ended up despite weak market sentiment on Friday following bargain-hunting in some blue-chip stocks coupled with local-led speculative buying of some secondaries, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Composite Index rose 1.08 points, or 0.19 percent, to close at 570.20 points after hitting an intra-day high of 572.35 points in early trade. Gainers led losers by 62 to 45, with 60 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market was likely to be mixed in slow trade in the coming week as many investors were seen focusing on the primary market and trading on a short-term basis.  </p>
<p>There would be little change in the composite index, they said. &quot;But third-quarter results or other corporate news next week could put a positive tone on the market and support the index,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>&quot;Any news on Astra International could also move the market either toward positive or negative area,&quot; said one foreign broker.</p>
<p>Brokers said some heavyweight stocks including Telkom, Indosat and Sampoerna rose on bargain-hunting but volumes were relatively small.  </p>
<p>Telecommunications firm Telkom traded unchanged at 3,600 rupiah, off a high of 3,675 rupiah in early trade, on a volume of 2.9 million shares. Brokers said investors took profits after an early rise in line with gains in New York overnight.</p>
<p>Cigarette maker Sampoerna rose 150 rupiah to 18,900 on a volume of 370,000 shares on bargain-hunting due to perceptions that current prices were at bargain levels.</p>
<p>Vehicle maker Astra International fell 50 rupiah to 4,000 rupiah with 1.8 million shares changing hands on reports that tobacco tycoon Putera Sampoerna, who effectively controls 12.66 percent of the firm, will not sell his stake.  </p>
<p>Brokers said earlier the reports could lead to the Nusamba group, which is linked to President Suharto and has evinced interest in Astra, picking up shares in the market.</p>
<p>Property firm Bhuwanatala IP topped the active list with 29.9 million shares traded, rising 200 rupiah to 1,700 rupiah. Brokers said it was due to market talk that the firm might obtain a syndicated loan or link up with a Singapore firm.</p>
<p>Secondary shipping firm Rig Tender was also actively traded following speculation that the firm had won some contracts and might propose a private placement. Company officials declined comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
