<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128024" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: FEATURE - Korean firms see Britain as door to Europe.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Korean firms see Britain as door to Europe.</headline>
<byline>Katherine Bruce</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korean companies, fearful of being shut out by looming European trade barriers, have chosen Britain as their doorway to trade with the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the easiest way to get beyond trade barriers and into the whole of Europe,&quot; said Daniel Harwood, regional director for HG Asia Securities. &quot;You just load up the ferries and ship the goods over.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 30 Korean firms have manufacturing bases in Britain.</p>
<p>The value of South Korean investment in Britain soared from 1992 to 1995, according to British government figures. Last year, deals worth a total of $215.97 million were approved, up from $35.54 million in 1992.</p>
<p>This month, Hyundai Electronics, a unit of the Hyundai Group, announced that it would build a $1.5 billion semiconductor plant in Dumferline, Scotland.</p>
<p>Britain also won the largest single direct investment overseas by a South Korean company. In July, the LG Group said LG Electronics and LG Semicon would spend $2.6 billion on semiconductor and consumer electronics facilities in Newport, Wales.</p>
<p>When completed in 2002, the LG plants will directly employ 6,100 people and create hundreds more related jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;Our investment in Britain fits in with our company's global strategy of localising manufacturing bases,&quot; said Elvis Kim, general manager of LG Semicon. &quot;We aim to deliver locally manufactured products to local customers. And from Britain, we will be able to provide service to our European customers.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1996 alone, South Korean firms have committed to $4.09 billion in direct investment in Britain.</p>
<p>According to analysts and company executives, Britain offers relaxed labour laws, skilled workers and a developed infrastructure.</p>
<p>&quot;Korean managers can also communicate to their workers in English. Where are you going to find many Korean managers who can speak French, German or Spanish?&quot; said a local analyst.</p>
<p>While none of the firms would give details on the incentives offered by the government, company executives who asked not be named said that they were a significant part of the allure.</p>
<p>British newspapers have speculated that LG was offered grants of up to 200 million sterling ($316.6 million) to attract the plants.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, assistance has been given to LG to set up in Wales,&quot; Parliamentary Undersecretary of State for Wales Gwilym Jones told Reuters. &quot;But as with most investors, I don't believe they look upon the grant as the most important thing... If they're traveling thousands of miles to be there, they want to make a decision for a generation, not just next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Some South Koreans are worried that the outflow of funds for overseas projects is draining the domestic economy.</p>
<p>&quot;To put it into perspective, up to several years ago, Korea had only a half of China's outward investment and a quarter of Taiwan's. So when we hear of the large investments that the nation is making overseas, what it is doing is catching up with the rest of the world,&quot; said British Ambassador Thomas Harris.</p>
<p>Back in Britain, some newspapers have questioned the influx of Asian firms seeking to escape spiralling wage costs at home.</p>
<p>&quot;Britain, the newest sweatshop,&quot; cried a Sunday Telegraph headline in July.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't call working in a semiconductor plant the same thing as working in a sweatshop,&quot; said HG Asia's Harwood. &quot;But the industrial cycle has come full circle in the U.K. It has gone through restructuring, there has been massive unemployment and labour unions have been broken. Here in Asia, costs are escalating and productivity is relatively inefficient.&quot;</p>
<p>Since 1987, 16,000 new jobs have been created in Britain by South Korean companies. Unemployment is currently at 7.5 percent.</p>
<p>($1=.6317 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
