<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128011" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tobishima draws up new restructuring plan.</title>
<headline>Tobishima draws up new restructuring plan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese construction firm Tobishima Corp said on Friday that it has drawn up a new restructuring plan to try to solve its financial difficulties.  </p>
<p>The company said the new plan would not affect its earnings forecast for the 1996/97 business year.</p>
<p>Under the plan, it would ask its creditors to reduce their claims against Tobishima for the debts owed by its group companies from about 740 billion yen to 100 billion yen.  </p>
<p>Tobishima would pay back the guaranteed loans over the next 20 years upon request of the creditors, the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>In 1992, Tobishima transferred its real estate development business and debts to its group companies in conjunction with a five-year rescue plan hammered out by the construction company and its creditors.</p>
<p>Tobishima and its group companies currently owe a total of 1.09 trillion yen. Of the total, the parent company's debts total 190 billion yen, while the group companies owe the rest.</p>
<p>Of the 900 billion yen owed by the group companies, 740 billion yen has been guaranteed by Tobishima. The rest is not guaranteed, and the group companies will continue to be held responsible for repayment under the new plan, the statement said.</p>
<p>The company explained the new plan to its creditors and asked for their cooperation at its headquarters on Friday, the statement said.</p>
<p>Tobishima expects to post 420 billion yen in sales and 8.5 billion yen in parent current profit for the current business year ending on March 31, 1997.  </p>
<p>Company president Shoichiro Ishihara said the firm's new restructuring plan may falter if too many creditors oppose it.</p>
<p>There are total of 50 creditors, the president said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
