<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128122" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper ends down on spot over-surplus.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper ends down on spot over-surplus.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended mostly down in active trading on Friday with investors building large short positions at high levels due to an over-surplus of domestic spot copper, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active January 1997 contract ended at 18,750 yuan ($2,259) per tonne, losing 150 yuan. It opened at 19,100 yuan, hitting an intra-day high of 19,140 and a low of 18,620.</p>
<p>November fell 260 to 18,400 yuan, December 200 to 18,600, February 160 to 18,770, March 120 to 18,880, April 100 to 19,020, May rose 50 to 19,250.</p>
<p>Combined volume fell to 129,530 tonnes from 147,350.  </p>
<p>Copper opened higher on overnight gains on the LME but profit-taking and fresh selling pushed prices down for most of the session.</p>
<p>Traders said long-term sellers built short positions due to the domestic spot copper surplus, resulting in sharp falls.</p>
<p>&quot;Large amounts of 'hot money' came in to build short positions at high levels, while long position holders took advantage of gains on the LME to offset their positions,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Traders said most Shanghai contracts breached the key support of 19,000 yuan level even though the LME has been fairly static around $1,900-$1,970, due to the over-supply of domestic spot copper.</p>
<p>The Futures Daily said on Friday that China imported 65,958 tonne of copper in September, bringing total imports for the first nine months of the year to 467,026 tonnes, up 27.4 percent from the same 1995 period.</p>
<p>Exports of copper dropped to 7,625 tonnes in September and 76,814 tonnes in the first three quarters of 1996, down 11.7 percent from the year-ago period, the newspaper said.  </p>
<p>China's output of copper rose to 664,800 tonnes in the first nine months of 1996, up 5.44 percent from the same 1995 period, the China Securities newspaper said on October 9.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumption levels have not caught up with rising domestic copper production and imports, resulting in hedgers and institutions building short positions at high levels,&quot; a second trader said.</p>
<p>Analysts said copper was expected to maintain a downward trend in the next few days pending the emergence of new factors.</p>
<p>Aluminium ended down. The only traded November contract closed at 13,500 yuan, losing 20 yuan on volume of 370 tonnes.</p>
<p>($1=8.2980 yuan)</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
