<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128290" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austria set to call for CA bids.</title>
<headline>Austria set to call for CA bids.</headline>
<byline>Janet McBride</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austria moved a tentative step nearer privatising flagship bank Creditanstalt-Bankverein on Friday when Finance Minister Viktor Klima said he was ready to call for bids and hit at the board for obstructing progress.</p>
<p>Klima told Reuters that the government would issue an updated memorandum to interested parties on Monday -- one week later than originally planned. The release would be followed by a four-week bidding period.</p>
<p>He assured potential investors that they would receive full cooperation from the finance ministry and a sometimes recalcitrant Creditanstalt management.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be an agreement between the finance ministry and Creditanstalt to ensure interested parties have the right to see all relevant information,&quot; Klima said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never had such a difficult cooperation with a board. I was angry because they said they needed two weeks for the memorandum but already three have passed,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The stop-start privatisation of Austria's most traditional bank, now in its seventh year, has faltered in the past on political lobbying for an &quot;Austrian solution&quot; and sometimes open resistance from Creditanstalt's management.</p>
<p>Last year Germany's Allianz dropped its interest in Creditanstalt amid finance ministry accusations that the bank had failed to release essential information.</p>
<p>Klima said the government still aimed to sell its entire 70 percent of ordinary voting shares but he hinted that he may be ready to compromise on the volume.</p>
<p>&quot;The memorandum is phrased in such a way that it will not place too many restrictions on potential investors. We don't want to give the impression we will only sell if we get a bid for everything,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The most recent offer, from an Austrian-German-Italian consortium led by insurer EA-Generali, failed last month because of the group's reluctance to take on more than half the government's 19.9 million shares.</p>
<p>Klima said the report, by US investment house JP Morgan, was not a fresh valuation but merely an update of last year's assessment. That valued the government's Creditanstalt stake at around 18 billion schillings ($1.66 billion). At current market prices it is worth about 14 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We have updated the memorandum with Creditanstalt's latest results but it is not a new valuation. There is nothing that we need to publish,&quot; the finance minister said.</p>
<p>The government has been eager to minimise media attention on the sale, keenly aware that the marathon privatisation has done nothing to enhance Austria's reputation with foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;You won't hear anything about (the study) unless you want to make an offer for Creditanstalt and sign a confidentiality agreement first,&quot; a finance ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>Klima declined to say how many &quot;interested parties&quot; would receive a copy of the report.</p>
<p>There have been only two public declarations of interest -- by the EA-Generali group, which also includes Germany's Commerzbank and Banca Commerciale Italiana, and by Die Erste Oesterreichische SparCasse Bank (First Austrian).</p>
<p>The EA-Generali consortium, openly favoured by the Creditanstalt board and some conservative politicians, has said that it may be ready to improve its previous bid of 6.7 billion schillings for half the state's stake.</p>
<p>First Austrian has kept its cards close to its chest since it split from the EA-Generali group in September and announced plans to form a rival consortium.</p>
<p>($1=10.82 Schilling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
