<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128272" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel accepts low-level French Orient House visit.</title>
<headline>Israel accepts low-level French Orient House visit.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel will accept a visit by a junior French minister to the disputed PLO headquarters in Arab East Jerusalem, government sources said on Thursday, denying a diplomatic crisis over the matter.</p>
<p>Asked if there was a crisis over the visit during a tour next week by French President Jacques Chirac, Israeli Foreign Ministry spokesman Danny Shek said: &quot;This particular issue -- no. We have been informed.&quot;</p>
<p>Chirac's spokeswoman had said Foreign Minister Herve de Charette would not accompany Chirac to Israel next week as planned and that in his place the junior health minister would visit Orient House, the unofficial PLO headquarters in the city.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Catherine Colonna said Chirac had informed Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu in September of his wish to send de Charette to Orient House in line with European Union policy on maintaining the status quo in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Netanyahu had objected, and prolonged negotiations between the two sides had not changed the Israeli stance, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The president has decided with great regret that Mr de Charette will not accompany him to Israel, although he will be on all the other stages of the trip,&quot; Colonna said. &quot;The president has decided that junior health minister Herve Gaymard will be charged with going to Orient House.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel, which claims sovereignty over the whole of Greater Jerusalem, argues that President Yasser Arafat's Palestinian Authority is in breach of peace agreements by conducting business from Orient House.</p>
<p>EU policy is that foreign ministers should visit the office, headed by Palestinian minister Faisal al-Husseini, on each official visit to uphold the status quo in the city pending final status negotiations between Israel and the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Israeli government sources said that they although they would have preferred no one go to Orient House, the visit would be acceptable so long as the contact was non-political. Health was one issue for discussion Israel would not oppose.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not oppose obviously dealings with the Palestinians in East Jerusalem about health, welfare or education or any other issue concerning the welfare or promotion of community affairs -- anything that is non-political,&quot; Shek said.</p>
<p>&quot;The non-senior minister that is coming is the junior minister of health,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
