<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128339" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Germany's foreign minister slams &quot;Europlug&quot; failure.</title>
<headline>Germany's foreign minister slams &quot;Europlug&quot; failure.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel criticised Europe's failure to agree a common power plug and socket, saying it must not be a model for monetary union or enlargement of the European Union.</p>
<p>&quot;No member state of the European Union can afford a power failure,&quot; Kinkel said in a statement on Thursday.</p>
<p>He was reacting to the news that the quest for a common &quot;Europlug&quot; had suffered a major setback, with national members of the electrical standards body (Cenelec) that must devise the new system rejecting a draft plan.</p>
<p>The Brussels-based standards body Cenelec said in a statement on Wednesday that a proposal to create a &quot;Europlug&quot; to replace the many different types of connectors across Europe had failed to receive the necessary majority.</p>
<p>Kinkel said that after the &quot;victory of national plugs&quot; over the interests of consumers, European citizens rightly asked: &quot;How are we Europeans going to realise a common foreign policy, the common European currency and the EU enlargement if Brussels can't even manage the harmonisation of six European electricity plug norms?&quot;</p>
<p>The proposal would have introduced a standard plug with two or three round pins to allow appliances to be used across Europe without adapters. Cenelec groups the national standards bodies from the 15 EU countries and Norway, Switzerland and Iceland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
