<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128379" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Chinese Mercantile Bank '96 profits seen to triple.</title>
<headline>Chinese Mercantile Bank '96 profits seen to triple.</headline>
<byline>Benjamin Kang Lim</byline>
<dateline>SHENZHEN, China 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's major state-owned banks are wincing under a three-year-old, anti-inflation credit squeeze but the fledgling joint venture Chinese Mercantile Bank is grinning from ear to ear.</p>
<p>Mercantile's profits are expected to more than triple in 1996, with bank president Huang Mingxiang forecasting after-tax profits to surge to $7.5 million in 1996 compared with $2.43 million in 1995 and $1.27 million in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;There is less government intervention,&quot; Huang told Reuters in an interview late on Thursday at the bank's headquarters on the 23rd floor of a skyscraper in the southern boomtown of Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Major state banks operate like women with bound feet -- the central bank imposes an annual credit quota and requires them to give lending priority to state firms, many in the red.</p>
<p>&quot;The tighter the funds, the better it is for us,&quot; Huang said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have more customers to choose from...and can select the good ones.&quot; Limitations on lending by Mercantile are subject to availability of funds, or no more than 75 percent of deposits.</p>
<p>Mercantile plans to increase its capital to 1.0 billion yuan ($120 million) in 1997 from the current $34.49 million and to 10.0 billion yuan ($1.2 billion) by the end of 1998, Huang said.</p>
<p>Pending approval by its board and by Chinese securities authorities, the bank plans to list in Shenzhen and to issue negotiable instruments abroad each year, Huang said.</p>
<p>Competition is tough in the banking world in the Special Economic Zone of Shenzhen, a showcase of what Beijing calls its economic miracle with Chinese characteristics.</p>
<p>The four state giants -- the Bank of China, Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC), the Agricultural Bank and the Contruction Bank -- all have a presence in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Nine regional Chinese banks, 13 Chinese commercial banks and 25 foreign financial institutions also have branches in town.</p>
<p>As one of China's six Sino-foreign joint venture banks, Mercantile has carved out a niche for itself that is difficult for Chinese or foreign financial institutions to match.</p>
<p>Mercantile can engage in renminbi business -- which wholly foreign-owned banks are barred from doing -- as an agent of ICBC, one of Mercantile's three shareholders, Huang said.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong Chinese Bank Ltd has a 40 percent stake in Mercantile, while ICBC and China Travel Service (Holdings) Hong Kong Ltd each hold 30 percent.</p>
<p>Unlike China's regional banks, Mercantile is not restricted to operating only in cities where it has a branch, although it has applied to open a branch in Shanghai and another in southern Guangzhou.</p>
<p>Mercantile has some flexibility on the interest it charges borrowers and pays depositors, with a range of about 10 percent above or below levels set by the central bank, Huang said.</p>
<p>It has another edge over domestic financial institutions -- it can raise funds and lend money abroad, he said. Its deposits rose to $164.37 million as of the end of June compared with $118.33 million at the end of 1995 and $21.78 million at the end of 1994.</p>
<p>Mercantile had extended $90 million in loans as of the end of 1995, Huang said but gave no comparative figure. Shenzhen absorbed half the loans, Hong Kong 40 percent and other Chinese cities 10 percent.</p>
<p>Mercantile's market share among foreign banks in Shenzhen was one-seventh of deposits and one-40th of loans, Huang said.</p>
<p>Ninety-five percent of Mercantile's customers are foreign-funded ventures. Of total customers, 40 percent are manufacturers, 30 percent are exporters and 30 percent real estate mortgages.</p>
<p>Its assets stood at $226.77 million at the end of 1995 and liabilities were $188.74 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHENZHEN, China"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
