<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128365" id="root" date="1996-10-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's ITC approves end-March Channel 5 launch.</title>
<headline>UK's ITC approves end-March Channel 5 launch.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Independent Television Commission (ITC) said on Friday it would allow Britain's new terrestrial channel to delay its launch until March 30 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The members of the ITC agreed to a variation of the Channel 5 licence at their meeting yesterday, changing the start of broadcasting from 1 January 1997 to not later than 30 March 1997,&quot; the commercial television watchdog said in a statement.</p>
<p>Channel 5 chief executive David Elstein told Reuters this week that he expected to launch at the end of March.</p>
<p>The delay was caused by extra video retuning work required, after the channel was allocated an additional frequency.  </p>
<p>Channel 5 confirmed it would begin broadcasting on March 30 -- Easter Sunday.</p>
<p>The company has employed thousands of retuners who must visit more than 10 million British homes to adjust video recorders to prevent interference from the new channel's signal.</p>
<p>The allocation of the additional frequency extends Channel 5's coverage to 80 percent of the UK by adding an extra 1.8 million homes to its reach. But it creates potential interference problems for around three million households.</p>
<p>Channel 5 said last month that it would delay its launch for 4-6 weeks. It has now conceded that retuning will take longer.  </p>
<p>&quot;The task of visiting all the homes in our coverage area and retuning if necessary is well underway, with over one million homes completed, 3,000 retuners in action and over 2,000 more trained and ready to be deployed,&quot; Elstein said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The business is looking stronger than ever with wider coverage than we originally planned. The results of our first full-day test transmission last weekend are also very encouraging, indicating that levels of interference may be lower than anticipated, which would reduce the amount of retuning required,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Channel 5 is a consortium comprising British media group Pearson and United News &amp; Media, Luxembourg broadcaster CLT and U.S. investment firm Warburg Pincus.</p>
<p>It will become Britain's third commercial television channel, joining the mainstream ITV network and Channel 4, which has a special remit to cater for minority interests. The two BBC channels are funded by an annual licence fee paid by all television set owners.</p>
<p>-- Keith Weir, London Newsroom 44 171 542 8793</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
