<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128398" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-MIXED EMOTIONS FOR PIENAAR AS TRANSVAAL REACH FINAL.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-MIXED EMOTIONS FOR PIENAAR AS TRANSVAAL REACH FINAL.</headline>
<byline>Andy Capostagno</byline>
<dateline>PRETORIA 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ousted Springbok captain Francois Pienaar indicated on Saturday he would prefer not to join the forthcoming tour to Argentina, France and Wales even if injuries offered him a route back into the squad.</p>
<p>There has been public outrage in South Africa since Pienaar, carried shoulder high from the field at Loftus Versfeld after helping Transvaal reach next week's Currie Cup final against Natal, was omitted from the 36-man Springbok squad announced by manager Andre Markgraaff last Saturday.</p>
<p>But Pienaar revealed he intends to take a break from the game and does not want to be called up as a result of injuries.</p>
<p>&quot;I've applied officially for leave to SARFU (the South African Rugby Football Union) for the whole of November and chief executive Rian Oberholzer has granted my wish,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm in a dilemma because from a personal perspective I think too much has happened for me to be able to tour. But professionally I am contracted to SARFU and I must do what they say.&quot;</p>
<p>Pienaar's extraordinary week continued when his house was broken into on Friday night.</p>
<p>&quot;My wife was there when it happened which was very worrying for me. Then on the way to the ground today our team bus broke down. But now we're in te Currie Cup final hopefully things will start to improve.&quot;</p>
<p>Monday is the deadline for players to prove their fitness for the tour of Argentina, France and Wales. Os du Randt and Christiaan Scholtz have already withdrawn and winger Pieter Hendriks is now also out after tearing a hamstring in a tackle.</p>
<p>Embattled springbok coach Andre Markgraaff was due to announce the replacement for injured Free State prop Os du Randt, but did not attend the game and will make his selection at the Springbok training camp in Pretoria on Monday. Western Province wing Justin Swart is likely to replace Hendriks.</p>
<p>Back on the field, Transvaal stunned Northerns with three tries in the first 48 minutes. Fullback Gavin Lawless opened the try scoring with a brilliant score in the right corner and Pienaar was prominent in the move which saw Springbok centre Japie Mulder force himslf over the line.</p>
<p>When another World Cup Springbok Rudolf Straeuli finished a movement which spanned the length of the field, Transvaal led 25-6 and despite a Northerns revival in the final quarter it was too little too late.</p>
<p>Natal, who have set the standard in South African rugby during 1996, earlier posted their 14th successive win in the competition by beating Free state 35-20.</p>
<p>Although former French international Thierry Lacroix and Springbok fullback Andre Joubert missed six kicks between them, Gary Teichmann's side ran in five tries through James Small, Federico Mendez, Wickus van Heerden, Joubert and Kevin Putt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRETORIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
