<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128422" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: CRICKET-AKRAM HITS CENTURY FOR PAKISTAN AGAINST ZIMBABWE.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-AKRAM HITS CENTURY FOR PAKISTAN AGAINST ZIMBABWE.</headline>
<dateline>SHEIKHUPURA, Pakistan 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan captain</p>
<p>Wasim Akram completed his second test century in seven years and</p>
<p>shared a record-breaking stand with Saqlain Mushtaq on the third</p>
<p>day of the first cricket test against Zimbabwe on Saturday.</p>
<p>Akram was 122 not out and Pakistan were 368 for seven at</p>
<p>tea, just seven runs behind Zimbabwe's first innings total of</p>
<p>375.</p>
<p>Akram and Saqlain Mushtaq (32) shared an unbroken</p>
<p>eighth-wicket stand of 131, beating the previous Pakistan record</p>
<p>for the wicket of 130 compiled by Hanif Mohammad and Asif Iqbal</p>
<p>against England at Lord's in 1967.</p>
<p>Pakistan added 75 runs to their lunch score of 293 for seven</p>
<p>after starting the day at 189 for six.</p>
<p>Akram achieved his century in grand style by hoisting</p>
<p>off-spinner Andrew Whittal into the main grandstand for his</p>
<p>fourth six.</p>
<p>He took 198 minutes and 162 balls to reach his hundred, his</p>
<p>first since he made 123 against Australia in Adelaide in the</p>
<p>1989-90 series.</p>
<p>The left-hander slammed 13 fours and and hit three of his</p>
<p>four sixes off leg-spinner Paul Strang, the best Zimbabwe bowler</p>
<p>with five wickets.</p>
<p>The only wicket to fall in the first two seassions was that</p>
<p>of Moin Khan, dismissed by Strang for 18.</p>
<p>Captain Alistair Campbell took the second new ball</p>
<p>immediately after lunch but it made no impact on the</p>
<p>well-established Pakistani pair.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHEIKHUPURA, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
