<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128563" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: FEATURE - Smugglers keep Polish jewellers in amber.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Smugglers keep Polish jewellers in amber.</headline>
<byline>Ryszard Wesolowski</byline>
<dateline>GDANSK, Poland 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Booming worldwide demand for amber sustains a $200-million-a-year industry in Poland, earning the honey-coloured fossil resin the local nickname of Polish gold.</p>
<p>But more than 90 percent of the substance that keeps many thousands of skilled craftsmen and women in work has no legal business to be in Poland at all.</p>
<p>Officials say it is smuggled from the crime-ridden neighbouring Russian Kaliningrad enclave on the Baltic coast, which has most of the world's amber deposits, and much is stolen from the Primorskoye mining combine there.</p>
<p>&quot;By our estimates, about 160 tonnes of amber is smuggled into Poland every year, mostly overland but also on ocean-going launches,&quot; Grzegorz Gorynski, customs service spokesman in the Polish Baltic city of Gdansk, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Andrei Gorbunov, senior inspector of Kaliningrad customs, confirmed there were repeated thefts from the enclave's amber producer, saying the loot was smuggled to Poland and Lithuania.</p>
<p>He said Russian authorities were doing their best to battle the illegal trade and had seized 800 kg of raw amber this year, but conceded: &quot;The smugglers are quite inventive and I don't think it is possible to halt all their attempts.&quot;</p>
<p>Once in Poland, it is transformed by an estimated 20,000 people employed in around 4,000 workshops, mostly in Gdansk, into jewels that sell especially well in North America, western Europe and Japan, said city police spokesman Wojciech Deptula.</p>
<p>&quot;The majority of these workshops operate in the grey zone,&quot; Deptula added -- meaning that employers are not too concerned about registering their businesses and paying tax.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a major industry, annual production of which is worth about $200 million,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Amber has been exported from Poland's coast, where lucky beachcombers still find pieces, since Roman times when an &quot;amber road&quot; brought traces of Mediterranean culture north.</p>
<p>Mining it in Poland is now largely banned for environmental reasons, although in recent years rogue amber hunters have devastated woodlands at night using high-pressure water hoses to flush chunks from the soil.</p>
<p>Russian imports have now rendered such efforts unnecessary to the industry concentrated in Gdansk, which has a long tradition of amber production and now hosts the world's largest annual trade fair of products made from it.</p>
<p>Amber has boomed in popularity due partly to Steven Spielberg's blockbuster movie &quot;Jurassic Park&quot; -- in which blood-sucking insects trapped in pieces many millions of years old yielded the genetic material to recreate dinosaurs.</p>
<p>The reawakened fascination has been reflected this year by a popular exhibition at New York's Natural History Museum called &quot;Amber: Window to the Past.&quot;</p>
<p>Polish jewellers are proud to have wrested the lead in amber jewellery production from western makers while leaving Russia's own industry standing. They also tend to be unabashed about their product's legally murky origin.</p>
<p>&quot;For now we are knocking the Russians silly with our technology, creativity and readiness to adjust to orders from new markets,&quot; said Krzysztof Jacobson, whose golden-glowing workshop on Gdansk's Mariacka street is a craft showcase.</p>
<p>&quot;The West is also not a serious competitor for us because is is not so keen to secure raw materials by illegal means,&quot; Jacobson confided to Reuters -- adding that Polish labour costs were lower and craftsmanship often better.</p>
<p>Amber is innately fascinating, not just because it can preserve remarkable specimens of life from an impossibly remote past, caught in hardened globules of forest sap.</p>
<p>Clear or milky, often enlivened by intriguing internal flaws, it resembles a semi-precious stone but is warm to the touch and eye and light, can burn yielding aromatic smoke and is surrounded by legend and folklore around the world.</p>
<p>Romans valued a modest piece of amber more than a slave, Japanese see it as a symbol of happiness and health.</p>
<p>The rich 18th century decorations looted from the so-called amber room of the Tsarist summer palace near St Petersburg by World War Two German invaders are one of the world's greatest missing treasures.</p>
<p>According to Gdansk jewellers, smuggled raw amber sells for an average of 300 zlotys ($106) a kg (2.2 lb), depending on quality.</p>
<p>Amber bead necklaces, weighing from 100 to 500 grammes, cost between 80 and 700 zlotys while bracelets of between 200 and 500 grammes fetch 150 to 500 zlotys.</p>
<p>Brooches, mostly set in silver, can fetch up to 700 zlotys.</p>
<p>Despite such attractions, Gdansk jeweller Jacobson recognised a need to keep the current appetite for the substance sharp by inventiveness and skilful marketing.</p>
<p>This is being attempted by Polish artists who, in addition to the traditional 19th century or Art Nouveau-style leafy silver settings have been producing amber jewellery and decorations in a startling range of inventive modern designs.</p>
<p>&quot;The climate for amber will not last for ever if it is not skilfully nourished,&quot; Jacobson said. ($1=2.8290 Zloty)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GDANSK, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
