<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128514" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Lord Haw Haw's daughter defends her father.</title>
<headline>Lord Haw Haw's daughter defends her father.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The daughter of William Joyce, known as Lord Haw Haw, has spoken for the first time in defence of the man who taunted Britain with Nazi propaganda broadcasts during World War Two, a Sunday newspaper said.</p>
<p>Fifty years after Joyce was hanged for treason, Heather Iandolo, 64, told the Sunday Telegraph: &quot;I can never think of my father as a traitor. I do not think he deserved to die.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;My father never killed anyone. He only made speeches. He was wicked, I suppose, but he was not as evil as some.&quot;</p>
<p>Joyce made broadcasts on behalf of Josef Goebbels, the Nazi propaganda chief, which were intended to demoralise the British people. But he became a butt of jokes and was nicknamed Lord Haw Haw because of his plummy English tones.</p>
<p>He was executed after the war for treason and buried in unconsecrated ground at Wandsworth prison in London. In 1976, Iandolo was allowed to have the body reburied in Ireland, where he grew up.</p>
<p>Iandolo, a French teacher who lives in southern England, said she remembered her father as &quot;lively and fun although he had a terrible temper.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
