<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128520" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Leave Sinn Fein out, says Protestant leader.</title>
<headline>Leave Sinn Fein out, says Protestant leader.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northern Ireland's chief Protestant party said on Saturday that rival politicians in multi-party talks must press ahead with efforts for communal peace and forget about the IRA's political arm Sinn Fein.</p>
<p>In a speech to supporters, Ulster Unionist Party (UUP) leader David Trimble said Irish Republican Army violence had put republicans beyond the pale. He appealed to moderate Roman Catholic Irish nationalists to throw their weight behind negotiations on a settlement based on continued British rule.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be worth going on. For we want to build a Northern Ireland comfortable with its unique heritage. We offer a genuine partnership to all the people of Northern Ireland,&quot; told the UUP annual conference.</p>
<p>He cautioned that time was running short because a British general election due early next year would halt the province's faltering political momentum.</p>
<p>&quot;There is only a limited time available. The prospect of an election will soon close down the political process. So, we have only a few months. But we are, and have been prepared to do serious business, if others will respond.&quot;</p>
<p>Trimble denied his party had relaxed pressure for an IRA truce or scrapping of weapons earlier this week to facilitate progress with the nationalist Social Democratic and Labour Party (SDLP) in the current Anglo-Irish sponsored talks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not softening on a ceasefire or (arms) decommissioning. Rather we are insisting on an acknowledgement that the time has come to settle (these matters) and put Sinn Fein/IRA behind us,&quot; Trimble said.</p>
<p>&quot;We challenge the SDLP and the (British) government to go on now without Sinn Fein, and with no backward glances.&quot;</p>
<p>A staunch advocate of British rule, Trimble said his brand of politics held the key to the future.</p>
<p>&quot;It is only Unionism that can genuinely be multinational and multicultural. It believes that the sum of the whole is greater than that of the parts. This is a better vision than anything sectarian Irish nationalism can offer. That is why we say that the union (with Britain) is our future together...&quot;</p>
<p>Unionist parties, which speak for the province's intensely pro-British Protestant majority, want London and Dublin to harden their stance against the Irish Republican Army, and Sinn Fein, in the face of fresh IRA hostilities aimed at ending rule from London.</p>
<p>London and Dublin have insisted that Sinn Fein will not be given a seat in talks until the IRA calls a new truce. Sinn Fein argues that it is a separate entity from the IRA and accuses the governments of political bias.</p>
<p>IRA bombers attacked British army headquarters in Lisburn, south of Belfast on October 7 in their first action in the province for more than two years. A truce declared in September 1994 ended in February with bombs in London.</p>
<p>Unionist parties say the IRA bomb, which put immense pressure on a two year truce by outlawed Protestant guerrillas, was more evidence that the guerrillas have no commitment to democratic principles.</p>
<p>Four months of wrangling in peace talks ended this week when the UUP and the SDLP reached agreement on an agenda, paving the way for talks on accommodating Nationalist and Unionist aims in economic and political structures in Northern Ireland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
