<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128585" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BAHAMAS: Hurricane Lili lashes Bahamas.</title>
<headline>Hurricane Lili lashes Bahamas.</headline>
<byline>Nicholas Doughty</byline>
<dateline>SAN SALVADOR, Bahamas 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hurricane Lili on Saturday hit the Bahamas head on, ripping off roofs, snapping palm trees and downing telegraph poles, but no casualties were reported.</p>
<p>Lily pounded the port of Cockburn on San Salvador island and tore through a holiday resort, frightening foreign tourists, many of whom did not know what to expect.  Driving rain lashed San Salvador all night but eased in the morning, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The hurricane, which slammed across Cuba on Friday, hit San Salvador in the early morning hours of Saturday and later in the day was heading towards Bermuda.</p>
<p>San Salvador's airport control tower was toppled and in Cockburn, home to most of the island's 700 residents, roofs and balconies were torn off.</p>
<p>Palm trees were snapped and coconuts scatterd everywhere. Driftwood and debris were strewn across beaches and the normally clear blue waters boiled in a dark morass.</p>
<p>At the Club Med resort, angry tourists complained they received little advice about how to cope with a hurricane.</p>
<p>Laura Ferris, 36, from Detroit, said: &quot;I went and slept in the bathroom. They didn't give very good information about what to do.&quot;</p>
<p>Clem Cleri, 46, from Chino Hills, California, added: &quot;A lot of people were scared and I don't think they gave out enough information.&quot;</p>
<p>About 260 vacationists, mostly Germans, Americans and French, were booked into the resort. Club Med spokeswoman Margo Leader said no one was hurt as far as she knew.</p>
<p>The complex suffered considerable damage however. Even though the holiday huts are hurricane proof many roofs were sheered off.</p>
<p>The pier was sagging and watersports equipment scattered around. One windsurfing board was left perched in a tree. Flood waters covered much of the grounds.</p>
<p>Sherri Chiricosta, from Los Angeles, said: &quot;I was a little frightened because I didn't know what to expect from a hurricane.&quot;</p>
<p>Her husband Woody added: &quot;I got up real early and started picking up coconuts from the beach. I could see the roof of the bungalow next to us blowing off.&quot;</p>
<p>Schools had closed early on Friday in the Bahamas, an archipelego of hundreds of islands stretching more than 600 miles (950 km) in the Atlantic.</p>
<p>Flights were canceled and customers crowded into food stores and gasoline stations to gather supplies for the storm.</p>
<p>San Salvador, a 25-mile long (40 km) island, claims to be the first place in the New World where explorer Christopher Columbus stepped foot in 1492.</p>
<p>The National Hurricane Center in Miami said at 11 a.m. EDT (1400 GMT), the storm was located 125 miles (200 km) east northeast of San Salvador at latitude 25 north and longitude 72.8 west.</p>
<p>It was packing maximum sustained winds of 115 mph (185 kph) and moving at 25 mph (40 kph). Little change was expected in its strength or direction, forecasters said.</p>
<p>Hurricane warnings remained in effect for the central Bahamas but were discontinued for the northwest. A tropical storm warning was still in effect for the southeast Bahamas and the Turks and Caicos.</p>
<p>Flooding from the storm was blamed for 10 deaths in Nicaragua, Honduras and Costa Rica earlier in the week but there were no reports of deaths in Cuba, officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN SALVADOR, Bahamas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BAHAMAS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
