<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128675" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait's new parliament starts four-year term.</title>
<headline>Kuwait's new parliament starts four-year term.</headline>
<byline>Inal Ersan</byline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kuwait's newly elected parliament meets on Sunday in the first test of political wills between the state and opposition deputies seeking more powers for the only elected Gulf Arab assembly.</p>
<p>Emir Sheikh Jaber al-Ahmad al-Sabah will open the first session of parliament, elected on October 7, before the assembly chooses its speaker.</p>
<p>There are two main candidates running for the job of parliament speaker -- a respected, veteran opposition leader and a wealthy former finance minister.</p>
<p>The government has not yet indicated who will get its vote to lead parliament, setting the tone of the second assembly since the 1991 Gulf War which will take oil-rich Kuwait into the next century.</p>
<p>An elected MP said: &quot;The first battle will be between pro- government deputies and opposition deputies on the chairmanship. The result could have deep effects on parliament's performance.&quot;</p>
<p>Many analysts say the government is expected to have a smoother four years with the new parliament compared to the last opposition-dominated house which probed its every move.</p>
<p>They say if the government supported Jassem al-Kharafi, a member of one of Kuwait's wealthiest families with global holdings, former speaker Ahmad al-Saadoun would lead a fierce opposition camp from the floor.</p>
<p>&quot;They have to think...Can the government afford to send Saadoun to the floor from where he will lead the opposition, or is it better to keep him in the speaker's chair?,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The pro-democracy campaigner was speaker of the last house which restored parliamentry life after a six-year break. The 1985 parliament, also headed by Saadoun, was dissolved citing security concerns at the height of the nearby Iran-Iraq war.</p>
<p>The new house is made up of 50 elected MPs, four of whom are also ministers, and 10 ministers. According to the law, the government must include at least one elected MP.</p>
<p>There are no political parties in Kuwait but analysts say about 19 of the elected MPs are pro-government who are further strengthened with the 10 minister members.</p>
<p>The last house opened wide probes into alleged official corruption and the state's handling of the crisis with Iraq ahead of its 1990 invasion and occupation of Kuwait.</p>
<p>A U.S.-led coalition ejected Iraq's troops in 1991.</p>
<p>Shi'ite and Sunni Moslem fundamentalists and pro-Islamists have about 14 parliament seats, six seats are held by liberals and the rest is shared by independents and tribal candidates.</p>
<p>Although fundamentalists often stand together to demand closer implementaion of sharia Islamic law they belong to different groups which disagree on several issues and even have rebels from within.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
