<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128655" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China Jan-Sept fixed-asset investment up 19.3 pct.</title>
<headline>China Jan-Sept fixed-asset investment up 19.3 pct.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's fixed-asset investment reached a total of 826.9 billion yuan ($99.6 billion) in the first nine months of the year, up 19.3 percent from the same period of 1995, the China Securities newspaper said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The rate of growth was down slightly from the 20.2 percent recorded in the January-August period.</p>
<p>The real rate of growth -- excluding the impact of inflation -- was about 13 percent, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>The report, quoting the State Statistical Bureau, said the total of completed investment projects did not include investment from the private sector and from rural enterprises.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the completion of priority government projects had shown improvement during the period. It gave no details but such projects normally include the key energy, transport and telecommunications sectors.</p>
<p>The newspaper said there were some areas of concern such as the sharp rise in real estate investment, which reached a total of 162.3 billion yuan, up 31.9 percent.</p>
<p>Continued controls on the volume of fixed-asset investment were necessary in the final months of the year, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
