<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128668" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan stocks fall slightly, revisit four-week low.</title>
<headline>Jordan stocks fall slightly, revisit four-week low.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on Jordan's stock exchange fell back fractionally on Saturday, revisiting a four-week low they hit last week after a steady slide caused by political uncertainties in the Middle East.</p>
<p>The Amman Financial Market 60-share index fell 0.03 points to 146.72 points in moderate trade worth 631,000 dinars ($891,000), dragged down mainly by industrial stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The wait-and-see mood continues. The message is: 'Sit and Watch',&quot; said Samir Jaradat of Jordan Investment Finance Bank.</p>
<p>Eighteen stocks fell, six rose and seven traded but closed unchanged.</p>
<p>The market has been depressed by an impasse in Palestinian- Israeli talks and growing fears that neighbouring Iraq, Jordan's biggest trading partner, will be unable to sell oil under a limited UN deal before the end of the year.</p>
<p>The index for industrial shares fell 0.2 percent, led by a five percent slump in Woollen Industries which closed at 1.28 dinars after trade worth 71,500 dinars.</p>
<p>&quot;Still some of the (industrial) companies which usd to depend on the Iraqi market have not readjusted,&quot; Jaradat said. &quot;Palestinian markets and the Gulf states have also not opened up as much as expected.&quot;</p>
<p>He said unless one of Jordan's traditional export markets were unlocked soon, investors could remain sidelined from the exchange for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>Quick passage through government of a package of laws covering customs duties, company laws and the regulation of the stock exchange itself could also revive the bourse, he added.</p>
<p>Arab Bank, which surged in September on expectations it would benefit from the new companies law, rose a modest 0.500 dinars to 242.500 after trade worth 24,000 dinars. Housing Bank  THBK.A was the busiest traded share, with turnover of 131,000, but it fell back 0.01 dinars to 4.750.</p>
<p>&quot;There's oversupply of Housing Bank shares, but it's still a good buy,&quot; Jaradat said.</p>
<p>The private Pearl Investable Index of the 45 best performing shares on the exchange fell 0.16 percent to 80.54 points from 80.67 points on Wednesday, 15.67 percent down from the same time last year.</p>
<p>-- Amman newsroom, 962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
