<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12876" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-MICKELSON WINS FOURTH TITLE OF YEAR IN AKRON.</title>
<headline>GOLF-MICKELSON WINS FOURTH TITLE OF YEAR IN AKRON.</headline>
<dateline>AKRON, Ohio 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Phil Mickelson birdied two of the last three holes to win World Series of Golf by three strokes over Billy Mayfair on Sunday.</p>
<p>It was the fourth tournament title this year for Mickelson, who shot an even-par 70, after being tied for the lead with Billy Mayfair with three holes to play.</p>
<p>Along with Mayfiar at 277 for the tournament were Steve Stricker, who had a 68, and Duffy Waldorf, with a 66.</p>
<p>&quot;It was very hard to sleep last night because there was so much I could accomplish with this win,&quot; said Mickelson, who had a three-stroke lead entering the third round. &quot;This was a win I wanted very, very much.&quot;</p>
<p>Mickelson's victory gave him a 10 year exemption to the PGA Tour.</p>
<p>The $378,000 first place check brings Mickelson back to the top of the money list with $1,574,799 won this year.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a major championship golf course, and for me to perform well on this style of course is a big step up for me in my career and my performance in future majors,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mickelson three-stroke lead was cut to two when Mayfair birdied the course's only easy hole, the par five second hole, while Mickelson three-putted for par from 25 feet.</p>
<p>On the back nine Mickelson began driving erratically, and poor tee shots resulted in bogeys on the, eighth, 12th and 13th holes, bringing Mickelson back to four under par, tied with Mayfair, who had parred 14 straight holes after the birdie on no.2.</p>
<p>Mickelson then set up a tap in birdie on the 16th, sending a wedge shot to 18 inches. He had another birdie on the 17th, where he his a 6-iron to six feet.</p>
<p>Mayfair bogeyed the 17th, missing a five foot par putt, and dropped from solo second place to a three way tie for second. It was the second successive year in which Mayfair has finished runner up in this tournament. He lost to Greg Norman in sudden death last year.</p>
<p>The defending champion was in contention, two behind Mickelson for much of the day, until he bogeyed the 13th and 14th holes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AKRON, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
