<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128795" id="root" date="1996-10-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: RBI expects 1 pct point cut in Indian prime rates.</title>
<headline>RBI expects 1 pct point cut in Indian prime rates.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Reserve Bank of India (RBI) governor Chakravarty Rangarajan said on Saturday he expected banks to reduce their prime lending rates by at least one percentage point.</p>
<p>He was speaking at a press conference after the central bank announced a series of measures aimed at injecting liquidity into the banking system, including reducing banks cash reserve ratio requirements and a lowering a cap on deposit interest rate.  </p>
<p>Asked by journalists how much prime rates may be reduced in the wake of the central bank's latest measures, Rangarajan replied, &quot;At least by one percent (percentage point) immediately.&quot;</p>
<p>Indian banks prime rates, the rate avalable to banks' best customers, currently range between 15.5 percent and 19.0 percent.</p>
<p>The central bank also asked banks to announce a maximum spread of interest rates above their prime rates.</p>
<p>The RBI in its statement on monetary policy for 1996/97 (April-March) cut banks cash reserve ratio to 10 percent from 12 percent and lowered the cap on interest for deposit accounts of up to one year to 10 percent from 11 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
