<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128850" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN WALKING TALL.</title>
<headline>MOTORCYCLING-DOOHAN WALKING TALL.</headline>
<byline>Robert Galvin</byline>
<dateline>EASTERN CREEK, Australia 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four years after almost losing his leg following an horrific race accident, Michael Doohan is walking tall as the undisputed champion of 500cc motorcycle racing.</p>
<p>Three consecutive world championship titles have not dimmed the Australian's appetite for hurtling around race tracks at speeds fast enough to dominate his rivals.</p>
<p>Not even a spectacular fall on the last lap of the season-ending Australian grand prix on Sunday can diminish his achievement in winning eight of the 15 races this season.</p>
<p>Typically, he was leading team mate Alex Criville when their two bikes collided at Eastern Creek, an accident Doohan blamed on the Spaniard, who had been chasing him for 30 laps.</p>
<p>Equally typically, Doohan immediately leapt to his feet and remounted his Honda in a forlorn bid to win in front of his home fans. He finished eighth.</p>
<p>Such a setback pales in significance against the effects of a high-speed crash at Assen in 1992 when Doohan's right leg was crushed, prompting doctors to fear it might have to be amputated after the limb became infected.</p>
<p>But both incidents reveal how this intense, introverted 31-year-old appears driven by a relentless will to win every grand prix he enters, even when there's little or nothing at stake.</p>
<p>After capturing the world championship last month, the Queenslander gave a perfect illustration of his attitude to racing at the Brazilian grand prix two weeks ago.</p>
<p>With the championship already won, many would have excused Doohan for simply going through the motions in Rio, protecting his already battered limbs from the risk of further injury in this punishing, dangerous sport.</p>
<p>During the race, Doohan made a rare mistake, skidding on to the grass to lose ground on the leaders. But instead of cruising home to collect the points available for a minor place, he fought back tenaciously to overtake Criville on the last lap for a thrilling win.</p>
<p>It's a level of motivation that Doohan himself admits is hard to maintain.</p>
<p>&quot;It's definitely been difficult to keep the motivation going to win this third world title,&quot; Doohan was quoted as saying in Australia's Inside Sport magazine.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to be motivated to win one championship -- a fair amount of riders have lost interest after one. My approach is to concentrate on winning every race, because that's what I enjoy doing.&quot;</p>
<p>But his career almost ended because of the leg injury before Doohan had chance to assert his dominance.</p>
<p>He recovered through a mix of fierce willpower and hardwork, completing his comeback by capturing his first world title two years later.     </p>
<p>&quot;You must have the will to win and the dedication -- to have a goal and work towards it, whatever the cost,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EASTERN CREEK, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
