<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128831" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-LAST MINUTE SIBIERSKI PENALTY GIVES AUXERRE 1-1 DRAW.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-LAST MINUTE SIBIERSKI PENALTY GIVES AUXERRE 1-1 DRAW.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A last minute penalty by Antoine Sibierski earned champions Auxerre a 1-1 draw with leaders Paris St Germain in the highlight match of the French first division on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Parisians, who keep a six-point lead over Monaco, dominated for most of the first half and opened the scoring through former Nantes defender Benoit Cauet in the 35th minute.</p>
<p>But Auxerre, despite losing international playmaker Sabri Lamouchi, reacted in the second half and amply deserved their late equaliser.</p>
<p>Auxerre are now third on 22 points, one behind Monaco, who crushed neighbouring Nice 4-1 on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;On the whole, I think we deserved to equalise. We dominated the last 20 minutes,&quot; said Auxerre's coach Guy Roux.</p>
<p>But he insisted that his side were &quot;not in contention for the title&quot;.</p>
<p>PSG's coach Ricardo blamed the lacklustre second half performance of his players on weariness after a hard week.</p>
<p>In the first half, PSG looked as though they had recovered from their 4-2 defeat at Galatasaray in the European Cupwinners' Cup last week.</p>
<p>Auxerre's goalkeeper Lionel Charbonnier saved a couple of fine Parisian chances but he could not do anything about Cauet's goal, scored after a brilliant one-two between two of PSG's Latin American players, Brazil's Leonardo and Panama's Julio Cesar Dely Valdes.</p>
<p>Cauet missed Auxerre's late goal as he was carried away from the pitch after a collision with an opponent in the 85th minute.</p>
<p>Auxerre, who are now without seven first choice players, lost both striker Bernard Diomede and Lamouchi. Ironically, Lamouchi's replacement by American Steve Marlet seemed to spur them into attack in the second half.</p>
<p>Marlet hit the post on the hour but the French champions had to wait for the last minute to see Parisian defender Jose Cobos stop a powerful shot by Algerian Abdelhafid Tasfaout with his hand.</p>
<p>Cobos was sent off and Sibierski easily converted the penalty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
