<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128954" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British gun group to field election candidate.</title>
<headline>British gun group to field election candidate.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British gun lobby group said on Sunday it planned to field a candidate in the Scottish parliamentary seat that includes Dunblane, where 16 children and their teacher were massacred by a gunman last March.</p>
<p>The announcement by the Shooters' Rights Association came just days after Britain's Conservative government announced plans for a massive crackdown on the ownership of handguns in an attempt to avert another similar tragedy.</p>
<p>Pro-gun groups said the government's proposals, which would outlaw all but the smallest calibre pistols, went too far.</p>
<p>The Shooters' Rights Association said it planned to put up a candidate against Scottish Secretary Michael Forsyth, whose highly-marginal constituency of Stirling includes Dunblane.</p>
<p>His majority is just 703 and a general election must be held by next May.</p>
<p>Scottish nationalist member of parliament Roseanna Cunningham attacked the move as &quot;beyond belief&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This can only add to the distress of people in Dunblane and those directly affected by the tragedy, and I think it is despicable that the gun lobby could be so hurtful as to even consider standing,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Shooters' Rights Association, which claims to have 6,000 members in Britain, said it would challenge Forsyth in protest at the government's proposed handgun curbs.</p>
<p>The association's secretary, Richard Law, said the candidate could be his wife Elizabeth, but this had yet to be decided.</p>
<p>&quot;The government have gone too far. They are scapegoating decent people for police ineptitude, and they should address the real problem instead,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Law said the problem lay not in guns but in their licensing, and added that the Dunblane masscare occurred because of failures in this respect by Scottish police.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
