<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128932" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: TRIUMPHANT AHO SEES CHANGES IN FINNISH POLICY.</title>
<headline>TRIUMPHANT AHO SEES CHANGES IN FINNISH POLICY.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The triumph for the opposition Centre Party in Finland's municipal and European Parliament elections will affect general policy and transform the political map, Centre Party leader Esko Aho said on Sunday.</p>
<p>But government leaders said the elections were not about government policy, and the five-party coalition will continue to push for Finnish entry in the third phase of Economic and Monetary Union, despite a strong showing by EMU-sceptics in the European Parliament election.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quite clear that this has great significance for general policy,&quot; Aho said while votes were still being counted.</p>
<p>&quot;You are going to see a major change in the political map of Finland as a result of these elections,&quot; Aho said, calling the shift in his party's favour &quot;staggering&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe and hope that the government will take seriously the fact that a large portion of the people do not approve of EMU,&quot; Aho added.</p>
<p>According to unofficial results when 96 percent of votes had been counted, support for the Centre Party in the municipal election was at 22.5 percent -- up from 19.8 percent in the 1995 general election and 19.2 percent in the 1992 local government polls when Aho led a centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>Centre Party candidates took 24.7 percent of European Parliament election votes, and the party seemed to be losing one of its five Euro-legislature seats.</p>
<p>The elections were held one week after the Finnish markka was linked to Europe's Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM) -- seen as an important step towards Finnish participation in EMU.</p>
<p>In the Europoll, two of Finland's most outspoken opponents of European integration topped the list of 16 winning candidates in the first direct poll for the Strasbourg-based parliament.</p>
<p>Current Euro-MP Paavo Vayrynen -- a former foreign minister and the Centre Party's top Eurosceptic -- and Esko Seppanen -- a rogue anti-EMU member of the governing Left Wing Alliance -- came first and second.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen's Social Democratic Party -- by far Finland's biggest political grouping in the 1995 general election with 28.3 percent -- fell to 24.7 percent in the municipal election and scored just 21.5 percent in the European Parliament polls, but retained its four Strasbourg seats.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will stick with its policy. This was not an election about government policy,&quot; Lipponen said.</p>
<p>The outcome of the Euro-election showed &quot;a certain amount of ... Euro-scepticism,&quot; he said, adding, however, that: &quot;The EMU train has left and the only alternative for the government is to act as if EMU will take off in 1999.&quot;</p>
<p>Leftist Seppanen turned the ERM-link into a major campaign issue and analysts, noting that about 60 percent of Finns have in opinion polls said they oppose a single currency, said this apparently paid off.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm an anti-federalist and I've made it clear that I don't want Finland to join EMU. I think the anti-federalist mood of the people was clearly expressed,&quot; Seppanen told Reuters.</p>
<p>The conservative National Coalition Party chaired by Finance Minister Sauli Niinisto advanced to 21.5 percent in the municipal election, from 17.9 percent in 1995 and from 19.1 percent in the 1992 local polls.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that the ERM-link, which we had to do, has had an effect,&quot; Niinisto said, referring to the overall outcome.</p>
<p>But the conservatives themselves did well, he said, noting the party was heading towards keeping their four European Parliament seats.</p>
<p>Claes Andersson, chairman of the Left Wing Alliance, said his party would stay in the rainbow left-right-green government despite Seppanen's demand that the party should &quot;draw certain conclusions&quot; from the electorate's anti-EU verdict.</p>
<p>&quot;We've made most of the difficult decisions. I don't see any reason to jump off now,&quot; Andersson said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Lipponen's coalition would remain in office.</p>
<p>Seppo Hentila, a political historian at the University of Helsinki said the votes for the SDP and the Centre Party had switched places compared to the last opinion surveys.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will stay in power, but it (the election outcome) probably will stop them making this kind of sudden big decision -- like the ERM link,&quot; Hentila said.</p>
<p>Voter turnout was 61 percent -- the lowest in municipal elections since the early 1950s, television said.</p>
<p>Esko Antola, a professor of European Affairs at the University of Turku said the election &quot;lacked passionate attitudes, people found no reason to become enthusiastic.&quot;</p>
<p>According to preliminary results, the Centre Party would win 4,448 local government council seats, up 450, the SDP would shed 395 seats to 2,735, the conservatives win 169 new seats to 2,178 and the Left Wing Alliance lose 188 seats to 1,131.</p>
<p>--Peter Starck, Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 9 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
