<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="128979" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RUGBY UNION - Spencer eyes Mehrtens' All Black jersey.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION - Spencer eyes Mehrtens' All Black jersey.</headline>
<text>
<p>AUCKLAND, Oct 20 - The irony in Carlos Spencer's five-try burst as Auckland sank Otago 59-18 in yesterday's NPC first division rugby semifinal at Eden Park is that the youngster is only rated fourth-best in the country, NZPA reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>For a long time the 20-year-old has been regarded as a player of immense potential, but yesterday he shrugged off that tag to move into a position where he is now a genuine contender for Andrew Mehrtens' All Blacks' No 10 jersey.  </p>
<p>The Auckland first five-eighth, who is rated behind Mehrtens, Simon Culhane and Jon Preston for the test berth, scored arguably the two best individual long range tries of the NPC this season.</p>
<p>The first, after halfback Ofisa Tonu'u bagged Auckland's opening try, was from inside his own 22 midway through the game when Otago were breathing heavily down Auckland's neck trailing 7-6.  </p>
<p>Given a penalty in front of the posts, Otago strangely decided to run the ball instead of taking the gift three points, they knocked it on and Auckland, allowed advantage by referee Colin Hawke, juggled it out to Spencer.</p>
<p>The first five-eighth ran, chipped over the defence and then in a masterful display of ball control kicked it all the way, some 60 metres to dive and score which took Auckland out to 12-6 and some relief.  </p>
<p>Then, three minutes to the break, once again he burst out of his 22 on the left flank, sprinted into Otago territory, held the ball out like some tantalising offering as fullback Jeff Wilson loomed up in front in defence, dummied the pass, stepped off his left foot and was gone.</p>
<p>Adrian Cashmore's conversion took Auckland out to 19-6 at the break.</p>
<p>Spencer had gone into the game with Great Britain's magical little rugby league halfback Bobbie Goulding, who has watched him play against North Harbour, rating him as one of the best young players he has seen in either code.  </p>
<p>And what did Wilson say as he burst past him?</p>
<p>&quot;I think the last words I heard were something about cover defence...&quot; Spencer said.</p>
<p>Modestly he said his three-try burst in the second half was a case of being at the right place at the right time.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm definitely very happy, fair to say I'm absolutely buggered and, no, I haven't scored five before,&quot; Spencer said.</p>
<p>Then there was his outstretched finger pointing into the crowd as he finished off his tries.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a couple of my nephews out here so I was just giving them the No 1 salute,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>While Otago tried gamely to compete in the second half, they just didn't have the firepower to match Auckland who ran in nine tries to two.</p>
<p>However, the only sour point of the game was a driving shoulder tackle from former Auckland loose forward Isatola Maka that left All Blacks prop Olo Brown out cold for nearly a minute late in the second half.</p>
<p>Brown was helped from the field looking dazed but appeared to have recovered at the end of the game.</p>
<p>However, he will undergo medical tests during the week to see if he is fit to play the final at Eden Park next Sunday.  </p>
<p>Scorers:</p>
<p>Auckland 59 (Carlos Spencer 5, Brian Lima 2, Ofisa Tonu'u, Lee Stensness tries; Adrian Cashmore 7 con) Otago 18 (Jason Wright, Stephen Bachop tries; Tony Brown 1 con, Brendan Laney 2 pen). Halftime: 19-6.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
