<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129053" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Right-wing candidate on anti-Sandinista mission.</title>
<headline>Right-wing candidate on anti-Sandinista mission.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arnoldo Aleman, tipped by most opinion polls as the likely winner of Nicaragua's presidential election on Sunday, is a burly right-wing populist on a mission to defeat his old enemy -- the left-wing Sandinistas.</p>
<p>His anger still burns over confiscation of his property and his arrest by the revolutionary Sandinista government, which ruled Nicaragua from 1979 to 1990. Daniel Ortega, his main rival at the polls, was president at the time.</p>
<p>&quot;There is neither mask nor makeup that can hide (the Sandinistas') failures. They are the same as ever,&quot; said Aleman, who heads the Liberal Alliance party.</p>
<p>A 50-year-old lawyer and coffee grower who enjoys backing from right-wing exiles in Miami, Aleman has already put his tough rhetoric into practice. When elected mayor of Managua in 1990, he kicked thousands of Sandinistas off the city payroll, painted over several elaborate revolutionary murals on public buildings and even cut off the gas to the lamp burning at the tomb of Carlos Fonseca, founder of the Sandinista party.</p>
<p>He even had giant Sandinista party initials FSLN on a hillside overlooking Managua changed to FIN, &quot;the end&quot; in Spanish.</p>
<p>This fierce anti-Sandinista stance, as well as talk of backing for Aleman from members of the former Somoza dictatorship, has led to fears of post-election conflicts.</p>
<p>&quot;The real risk with Aleman is that he wins with a large majority and puts in place a far-right, anti-Sandinista agenda. This would be dangerous. He has shown authoritarian tendencies in the past,&quot; political analyst Carlos Chamorro told Reuters.</p>
<p>The number of potential flashpoints between Nicaragua's two most powerful political forces is high.</p>
<p>For one, Aleman has said he will make wealthy Sandinistas who expropriated properties before leaving power in 1990 pay for what they took. The house Ortega lives in was confiscated from banker Jaime Morales Carrazo, now Aleman's campaign chief. Aleman says Ortega must pay for the house or get out.</p>
<p>His fierce anti-Sandinista sentiments, conservative politics and contacts among right-wing Nicaraguans in exile have led critics to compare him to Anastasio Somoza, the dictator toppled by the Sandinista revolution in 1979 after decades of oppression.</p>
<p>&quot;(Aleman's) is the discourse of a dictator. The message of Aleman has been the message of Somoza,&quot; Ortega said.</p>
<p>The Sandinista-owned newspaper Barricada claimed if Aleman wins he will make Somoza's son, Anastasio Somoza Portocarrero, army chief. Aleman denies it. He has also denied he ever belonged to pro-Somoza youth groups.</p>
<p>On the economic front, Aleman expounds a free-market position, promising to create jobs and lay a firm legal base for business. He said he plans to help small and medium-sized producers and his top priority is &quot;to reactivate the productive sector, including the generation of employment, and the best solution for this is found in agriculture.&quot;</p>
<p>His wife, Maria Dolores Cardenal, died of brain cancer in 1989, leaving him with four children. He has not remarried.</p>
<p>Born in Managua in 1946, Aleman graduated with a law degree from Nicaragua's Autonomous University in 1967. He went on to work as a lawyer for many of Nicaragua's top banks and businesses and later led Nicaragua's coffee producers' union. He was Managua's mayor for five years starting in 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
