<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129182" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Thai bourse official sees post-poll rise.</title>
<headline>Thai bourse official sees post-poll rise.</headline>
<byline>Mantik Kusjanto</byline>
<dateline>NUSA DUA, Indonesia 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The plunge in Thailand's stock index to a 39-month low last week was a cyclical phenomenon and the market is likely to recover after next month's election, the Thai stock exchange's president said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say in view of the upcoming election we are going to see a functional government which will address economic issues which require serious attention,&quot; Singh Tangkhasawasdi, president of the Stock Exchange of Thailand, told Reuters in an interview at the weekend.</p>
<p>He was in Indonesia's tropical resort of Bali for a conference on capital flows in the region.</p>
<p>Singh said it was likely an opposition party would win the November 17 elections, an apparent reference to former Prime Minister Chuan Leekpai's Democrat Party which many political analysts say should form the core of any new government.</p>
<p>If that happened, he said, &quot;I would say automatically public confidence in the stock market would return because previously the party has shown its expertise in managing the economy&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't have to do anything, public confidence will be back,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Thai stock market has had a bumpy ride for the past few months, with Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa's woes over the economy coupled with expectations of poor third-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>The Thai bourse sank to a 39-month low at 905.34 points on Tuesday, but recovered on bargain-hunting to 948.09 points on Friday.</p>
<p>Singh ruled out possible regulative measures to shore up the ailing market.</p>
<p>&quot;As a general rule, we are trying to keep away from all kinds of intervention. We prefer market mechanisms,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there will be any kind of incentives to revive the market. The market has no structural problem but only a cyclical one.&quot;</p>
<p>But Singh admitted that the performance of a number of listed companies had been below investors' expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;Many companies are in the middle of an expansion process. They have to incur relatively high financing costs and to bear interest expenses. Coincidentally, our export performance is not doing so well either,&quot; Singh said.</p>
<p>Those two factors and political uncertainty had panicked offshhore investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors have reviewed our credit risks and cut down their exposure to the Thai market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Foreign investors account for some 40 percent of the daily turnover in the Thai stock market.</p>
<p>UBS Global Research said in a report on the Thai economy early this month that both structural and cyclical constraints to economic growth looked set to preclude any rapid recovery.</p>
<p>Investor confidence would hinge on a government that would ignore political expediency for longer-term economic needs.</p>
<p>Singh said foreigners' perspectives on Thai politics differed from local views.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally think that our political system is quite strong and strong enough to take care of some of the economic issues. I think our bureaucratic system is quite capable of maintaining a minimum stability in our economy,&quot; Singh said.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We need some sort of guideline. Without a strong leadership on the political front we may come across a further slowdown in economic growth.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NUSA DUA, Indonesia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
