<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="12916" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan vice-premier set to leave for South Africa.</title>
<headline>Taiwan vice-premier set to leave for South Africa.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwanese vice-premier Hsu Li-teh is scheduled to leave for South Africa late on Sunday to cement business and diplomatic links as fears grow the island's biggest ally might switch ties to Beijing.</p>
<p>Hsu, leading a large business delegation, was expected to meet South African President Nelson Mandela, government officials and trade and industry leaders during the 10-day mission, state media said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The delegation consisted of officials and business leaders from major Taiwan state and private companies, such as Chinese Petroleum, China Steel, Taiwan Power, Chunghwa Telecom and Pacific Wire and Cable.</p>
<p>Hsu was expected to visit Pretoria, Cape Town and Johannesburg before returning to Taipei on September 4, state media said.</p>
<p>&quot;The South African government pays a great attention to Hsu Li-teh's visit,&quot; state-funded radio quoted a foreign ministry official as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The delegation will sign several economic cooperation and purchasing projects,&quot; the radio said without elaborating.</p>
<p>The mass circulation United Daily News said both sides would discuss the island's imports of gold, coal, agricultural products and cars from South Africa and a possible petrochemical joint-venture deal.</p>
<p>The Liberty Times said Taiwan plans to buy 600,000 tonnes of corn from South Africa and increase import quota for apples and oranges to 2,400 tonnes and 1,500 tonnes respectively.</p>
<p>Hsu has said the main purpose of the visit was to review investment projects and seek new business opportunities.</p>
<p>At least 278 Taiwanese businesses have invested US$1.5 billion in South Africa, and Taiwan is also considering an industrial zone for 20-40 of its major manufacturers.</p>
<p>Taiwan's two-way trade with South Africa totalled $1.87 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>South Africa is the biggest of Taipei's 30 diplomatic allies as of Monday after the West African state of Niger switched recognition to Beijing. Impoverished Niger split from Beijing to recognise Taipei in 1992.</p>
<p>South Africa has openly expressed willingness to establish diplomatic ties with China.</p>
<p>Its foreign minister Alfred Nzo made a high-profile &quot;fact-finding&quot; tour to Beijing in March, raising fears that Taiwan might lose its biggest diplomatic ally soon.</p>
<p>Nzo visited Taiwan in June.</p>
<p>Beijing says that countries seeking formal ties with China must first sever relations with what it regards as the &quot;rebel&quot; Republic of China government, which took refuge on Taiwan after losing a civil war to the communists in 1949.</p>
<p>Taiwan foreign minister John Chang recently described relations with South Africa as &quot;solid&quot; and &quot;stable&quot;.</p>
<p>Despite a lack of diplomatic ties, South African trade ties with China have soared in recent years, fuelling pressure for formal recognition.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
