<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129150" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan PM's party short of majority--exit polls.</title>
<headline>Japan PM's party short of majority--exit polls.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) was heading for failure on Sunday in its bid to win an outright majority in Japan's general election, two television exit polls predicted minutes after polling ended.  </p>
<p>Japan's authoritative NHK public television said the LDP was heading for a tally of around 240 seats, with a minimum of 251 required for a clear majority. However, it said there was still a chance that the LDP might scrape home with a majority. NHK polled 410,000 voters in its exit poll.</p>
<p>In another exit poll of 300,000 voters, Nippon Television (NTV) said Hashimoto's party would fall well short of an outright majority, with only around 237 seats.</p>
<p>In the outgoing parliament, the conservative LDP held 211 of the 511 Lower House seats and governed in a coalition with the Social Democrats and the Sakigake Party, an LDP splinter group. The main opposition grouping Shinshinto (New Frontier Party) held 160 seats in the outgoing parliament.</p>
<p>Sunday's vote for a 500-seat Lower House in a revised electoral system was the first general election since 1993, when the conservative, pro-business LDP lost its 38-year unbroken grip on power, ushering in a period of coalition rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
