<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129159" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China to curb loss of state property to foreigners.</title>
<headline>China to curb loss of state property to foreigners.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>China called on Sunday for vigilance to control the alarming flow of state-owned property to foreigners.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investment is not a free lunch,&quot; the official China Daily Business Weekly quoted Tang Zongkun of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Blind pursuit of foreign investment without consideration of cost would merely relieve the current fund shortage instead of solving enterprises' fundamental difficulties,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Rules should be drawn up immediately to govern deals with foreign investors that concerned property rights, Tang said.</p>
<p>Current regulations had failed to respond to new trends in investment, prompting alarming losses of state-owned property during transactions with overseas investors, he said.</p>
<p>Some regions competed with each other to woo overseas investors, benefiting only the foreigners, he said.</p>
<p>By the end of 1995, foreigners had invested a total of $135.4 billion in 120,000 enterprises in China that employed 120,000 people, the newspaper said. Many of the companies taken over by foreigners were loss-making state firms.</p>
<p>China has grown increasingly concerned in recent years at the loss of state property, the legal ownership and control of which is often only hazily defined.</p>
<p>China's National Administrative Bureau of State-owned Properties was speeding up efforts to develop rules to standardise the treatment of state property in foreign investment deals, the newspaper said but gave no details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
