<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129299" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn closes lower on technicals, wheat/soy.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn closes lower on technicals, wheat/soy.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Technical sell signals plus a sharp drop in wheat and soybeans knocked CBOT corn futures to a lower close, traders said.</p>
<p>The sag occurred despite a bullish USDA weekly export sales report and prospects for a slowdown in the U.S. corn harvest due to rainy weather, they said.</p>
<p>USDA Friday said U.S. corn net sales during the week ended October 10 tallied 858,000 tonnes, eight percent up from the previous week and 16 percent above the four-week average.</p>
<p>But chartists pointed to bearish flags for corn from the four- and 20-day moving averages.</p>
<p>Going into Friday's session the first resistance level for December was at $2.84-1/2 per bushel and second resistance was at $2.87-1/2. The session high for December was at $2.85-1/4.</p>
<p>First support for December was at $2.81-1/2,  second support was at $2.78-1/2 and December closed at $2.80-1/4, indicating a potential bottom of the market may have been set.</p>
<p>The nine day relative strength index for December closed  at 21.293 points. Traders generally view an RSI of 20 or less as indicative of a very oversold market.</p>
<p>Corn closed 1-1/2 to 3-1/4 cents per bushel lower, with December down three at $2.80-1/4.</p>
<p>The four and 20-day moving averages as of Thursday's close were giving off bearish signals before Friday's open and the fund selling was broad-based in early dealings but had slowed by the close, traders said.</p>
<p>E.D. and F. Man International sold six million bushels of December, Dean Witter Reynolds, R.J. O'Brien and Farmers Commodities Corp each sold two million bushels of December, floor sources said.</p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated at 53,000, up from 51,317 Thursday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>Corn options traders took note of Prudential Securities purchase of 550 December $3.20 calls at 1/4 cent and purchase of 500 December $3.10 calls at 1/2 to 5/8 cent, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 26,000, up from 24,438 Thursday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
