<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129240" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanese official blasts Hariri's economic policies.</title>
<headline>Lebanese official blasts Hariri's economic policies.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A key Lebanese government minister fiercely attacked outgoing Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri saying in remarks published on Sunday that the billionaire tycoon's postwar rebuilding policies have impoverished the people.</p>
<p>Minister for Displaced People Walid Jumblatt told the London-based daily Asharq al-Awsat in an interview in Beirut that Hariri has to reconsider his four-year-old multi-billion dollar plan to rebuild Lebanon from the 1975-90 civil war.</p>
<p>&quot;This course has to be reconsidered together with its consequences which led directly or indirectly to impoverishment of 40 percent of the Lebanese people,&quot; Jumblatt, a pro-Syrian Druze former civil war chieftain, said.</p>
<p>The rare diatribe from Jumblatt, who has been for years a Hariri ally, came a few days before President Elias Hrawi begins consultations with the newly elected parliament to nominate a new prime minister. Hariri is expected to be re-nominated.</p>
<p>&quot;If Hariri and his team do not realise that priorities have to be reconsidered and certain sectors have to supported...and that privatisation (of public utilities) should not be entered into by providing the funds or covering the mounting debts, then we would have entered the dark tunnel...,&quot; Jumblatt said.</p>
<p>Critics have said Hariri's economic policies were sinking Lebanon into debt by borrowing on international capital markets to finance rebuilding and of not having a social policy catering for the poor.</p>
<p>Social Affairs Minister Estefan ad-Douwaihi said on Thursday 30 percent of the Lebanese were living below the poverty line.</p>
<p>But Hariri has said the new cabinet must make social policy a top priority. Hariri's cabinet resigned last week in the wake of recent parliamentary elections to make way for the formation of a new government but stayed on in caretaker capacity.</p>
<p>Jumblatt also criticised Hariri's talks with U.S. President Bill Clinton in the White House on Friday saying they were &quot;useless&quot;. He said Hariri's begging Washington for political support was futile since U.S. policy was controlled by Israel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
