<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129203" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraqi Kurds exchange shells ahead of U.S. talks.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Kurds exchange shells ahead of U.S. talks.</headline>
<byline>Osman Senkul</byline>
<dateline>CHARKORNA, Iraq 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rival Kurdish forces exchanged artillery fire on Sunday in a battle for northern Iraq's strategic Dukan Dam ahead of U.S. peace talks to end the fighting.</p>
<p>Witnesses said militiamen of the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) fired 155-mm shells towards Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK) forces defending the dam. The PUK returned lighter artillery fire, they said.</p>
<p>Massoud Barzani's KDP, which received Iraqi military backing during earlier fighting in August, reached within 10 km (six miles) of the dam on Saturday in a push to retake their rival's stronghold Sulaimaniya, the mountainous region's biggest city.</p>
<p>The dam lies on a main road to the city.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll try to reach Dukan Dam today,&quot; leading KDP commander Roj Nuri Shuwayis told Reuters. About 1,000 of his fighters were gathered near the artillery position but Shuwayis said another 5,000 other were fighting in nearby mountains.</p>
<p>&quot;The big clashes are in the mountains,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The United States has called on both sides to end the fighting, which has weakened U.S. influence in north Iraq and threatened to draw in Iran and Iraq.</p>
<p>Robert Pelletreau, U.S. assistant secretary of state for near eastern affairs, was due in Ankara later on Sunday to meet with Barzani in southeast Turkey. The envoy is to meet PUK leader Jalal Talabani in Turkey next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Tomorrow morning he is going to the southeast to meet Barzani,&quot; a Turkish foreign ministry official in Ankara told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Kurds broke from Baghdad at the end of the 1991 Gulf War and set up a power-sharing parliament that has since collapsed under the weight of the Kurdish feud.</p>
<p>President Saddam Hussein had been kept out of the Kurdish region by U.S.-led air patrols over northern Iraq until Barzani joined with Baghdad's forces to take the city of Arbil -- seat of the former parliament -- six weeks ago.</p>
<p>Washington last month evacuated more than 2,000 Kurds who had worked for U.S. military, aid and intelligence programmes in northern Iraq and feared Saddam's return to the region.</p>
<p>Around 700 other Iraqi Kurds linked to U.S.-affiliated organisations took refuge in Turkey overnight, Turkish border officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Turkish customs officers and two U.S. officials questioned them on their arrival, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Talabani's group said in a statement that Iraqi forces were taking part in the KDP's latest drive but there was no clear sign on the ground of Iraqi government intervention.</p>
<p>Barzani has denied receiving further aid from Baghdad and has in turn accused Talabani of fighting alongside Iranian forces in northern Iraq, something Talabani and Tehran deny.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARKORNA, Iraq"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
