<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129360" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Doubts emerge over Sicilian Mafia &quot;turncoat&quot;.</title>
<headline>Doubts emerge over Sicilian Mafia &quot;turncoat&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sicilian anti-Mafia magistrates suspect that captured boss Giovanni Brusca is a &quot;fake turncoat&quot; who has been deliberately trying to mislead investigators, Italian newspapers reported on Sunday.</p>
<p>The bearded Brusca, a 32-year-old mobster with one of the most violent reputations in Sicily despite his chubby appearance, was arrested in May this year and has been &quot;cooperating&quot; with police since August.</p>
<p>Magistrates, fearing a possible plot by the Mafia to undermine investigations with false information, have said they are wary of his evidence until they can corroborate it.</p>
<p>The newspapers reported that magistrates were losing patience with Brusca and tended to believe that he was playing games -- a suspicion raised by several politicians.</p>
<p>&quot;The few bits of information leaking through the thick wall of secrecy surrounding this new mystery leave no doubts about the negative assessment of the magistrates from Palermo, Caltanissetta and Florence,&quot; said the left wing L'Unita.</p>
<p>The paper said the magistrates had set Brusca a test, presenting him with various minor cases that had not been reported by the media but about which a handful of turncoats had provided identical reports and details.</p>
<p>It said Brusca had given different versions, replacing the names of Mafiosi close to him with those of others.</p>
<p>La Stampa said Brusca was also believed to have been betrayed by his arrested brother Enzo, who wanted to turn state's evidence and had contradicted Giovanni.</p>
<p>&quot;Brusca has been rejected. He is still not a turncoat,&quot; reported the Milan daily Corriere della Sera.</p>
<p>It quoted prosecuting magistrate Paolo Giordano from the central Sicilian town of Caltanissetta as saying that &quot;a cycle has closed, a parenthesis of questions and checks, with an unsatisfactory verdict. But nothing definitive.&quot;</p>
<p>Judicial sources said Brusca had revealed nothing new or sensational during his talks with investigators.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe if he had said something against me I would have considered him more believable,&quot; joked former prime minister Giulio Andreotti, who is on trial for alleged Mafia links during his lifetime in Christian Democrat politics.</p>
<p>Brusca had also denied accumulating any great wealth as a boss, which few magistrates were inclined to believe.</p>
<p>However his lawyer Luigi Li Gotti said the investigators had not yet completely given up on Brusca.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there has been a decision yet,&quot; he said. &quot;Let's just say there is a moment of scepticism.&quot;</p>
<p>Brusca, branded &quot;a beast&quot; by another turncoat whose 12-year-old son he was alleged to have strangled and disposed of in acid, has been charged with several Mafia attacks.</p>
<p>Investigators believe he pushed the button detonating a bomb under anti-Mafia judge Giovanni Falcone's motorcade near Palermo in 1992, killing Falcone, his wife and three bodyguards.</p>
<p>Brusca is also accused of helping plan 1993 bombings against cultural monuments in Rome, Florence and Milan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
