<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129352" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ENI share offer seen attracting good demand.</title>
<headline>ENI share offer seen attracting good demand.</headline>
<byline>David Jones</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The second tranche of shares to be offered in Italy's energy giant ENI looks set to be priced attractively enough to encourage a strong response, oil industry analysts said on Sunday.</p>
<p>With the maximum price of the issue and the discount to retail buyers set on Saturday, demand from the Italian public sale to run this week and from institutions is likely to be strong enough to see over-allotment options triggered, they added.</p>
<p>The Italian Treasury announced on Saturday the second tranche of shares in the oil and chemical group would have a maximum price fixed at 7,425 lire ($4.84) a share while private investors will pay 3.5 percent less for their shares than the big institutional investors.</p>
<p>The Treasury is set to announce the actual price of the share offer on October 26 and trading is set to start in the new shares on Monday October 28.</p>
<p>&quot;All the signs are that the issue will be priced at a sufficient discount to the current market price to get all the shares away and trigger the green shoe option,&quot; said one oil industry analyst at a major investment bank in London.</p>
<p>The analyst added that market expectations are still for a share offer price of around 7,200-7,300 lire, putting a total value of 5.8 trillion lire ($3.8 billion) on the share offer, making it Europe's largest so far this year.</p>
<p>The second tranche placement of around 700 million shares would bring the Italian Treasury's stake in ENI down to around 76 percent from 85 percent.</p>
<p>It is the first time that Italy has offered a discount to private investors, and those who hold their shares for a year will get one bonus share for every 10 bought. The discount for ENI employees will be four percent.</p>
<p>ENI is the world's seventh largest oil group after Royal Dutch Shell, BP and U.S. giants Exxon, Mobil, Amoco and Chevron in market capitalisation terms, and its first offer of shares last November was quickly snapped by eager investors.</p>
<p>This first offer saw some 15 percent of ENI shares offered at 5,250 lire a share on the Milan, London and New York stock markets raising 6.3 trillion lire for the Treasury, and making ENI by far Italy's largest listed company.</p>
<p>ENI has a market weighting in Milan MIB30 index of top Italian stocks of over 20 percent, or twice that of Italy's next biggest company, insurer Generali, and has had a marked influence on trading on the Milan market this year.</p>
<p>While the Italian share market has been rather sluggish over the last 11 months compared to other world stock markets, ENI shares have risen sharply to close on Friday up 0.77 percent at 7,498 lire a share after hitting a year high on July 2 of 7,925.</p>
<p>&quot;The Treasury was quite conservative on pricing the first tranche, so I expect it again to come down on the side of caution to give the investor an attractive price,&quot; said one industry analyst based in Milan.</p>
<p>In the offering, 300 million shares are being offered to Italian retail investors, 235 million to institutional investors and 165 million to investors in the United States.</p>
<p>Global coordinators for the sale, Italian investment bank IMI and CS First Boston, have been granted an over-allotment or &quot;green-shoe&quot; option of a further 105 million shares which will be offered to institutions in case of heavy demand.</p>
<p>The Treasury has said the offer, which accounts for 8.75 percent of ENI's share capital, or 10 percent if the green shoe is included, could be increased if demand was strong enough.</p>
<p>The Italian public sale of the shares will run from October 21 to October 25 and the final share price will be fixed on October 26 and trading is expected to start on October 28. ($1=1535 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
