<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129343" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Sea of white as Belgians call for justice clean-up.</title>
<headline>Sea of white as Belgians call for justice clean-up.</headline>
<byline>Nieck Ammerlaan</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Belgians turned the centre of Brussels into a sea of white on Sunday in protest against the failures of their political and legal system in a horrifying case of child sex abuse and murder.</p>
<p>The parents of four dead girls and two still missing led the march, dressed all in white and carrying white flowers.</p>
<p>Behind them, silent and serious, trooped sympathisers from all over Belgium, plus supporters from abroad, wearing white or carrying white balloons and flowers. Police estimated the crowd at 275,000.</p>
<p>Plain white banners fluttered in a chill wind from balconies along the route, the three km (two miles) boulevard leading from Brussels' North Station to its South Station.</p>
<p>Posters on some shops along the way proclaimed: &quot;Stop the Cover-up by the Gendarmerie and Courts.&quot;</p>
<p>Belgian news media have repeatedly charged, but have not found proof, that there was a high-level police, judicial and political protection of a paedophile ring alleged to have been led by convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux.</p>
<p>The group are blamed for the deaths of at least four victims. Two other sexually abused girls were rescued from Dutroux's cellar in August.</p>
<p>One of the organisers, Paul Marchal, father of An Marchal who died at the hands of the child molesters, told the crowd to &quot;Keep your fists in your pockets&quot; and contain their anger.</p>
<p>&quot;The criminals are much better organised than the authorities,&quot; Marie-Noelle Bouzet, mother of missing girl Elisabeth Brichet, told RTL television.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
