<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129423" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Tax authorities raid Murdoch subsidiary in Israel.</title>
<headline>Tax authorities raid Murdoch subsidiary in Israel.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli tax authorities said on Sunday they had raided the offices of a company controlled by media magnate Rupert Murdoch and removed documents, but denied media reports of any arrests.</p>
<p>News Datacom Research Ltd, a Jerusalem-based company controlled by Murdoch's UK-based News Corp, forcefully denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>&quot;It is correct that we are directing an investigation against News Datacom Research,&quot; said Sarit Giladi-Dor, a spokeswoman for the Income Tax Authority.</p>
<p>She said investigators had also raided the offices of News Datacom's attorneys and auditors but would not confirm their names.</p>
<p>Giladi-Dor said further details could not be released until the investigation was formally declared public.</p>
<p>She denied Israel Radio reports that the authority had petitioned the Jerusalem District Court to detain Murdoch if he were to enter Israel or that there had been any arrests.</p>
<p>Israel Radio said authorities were investigating suspicions that News Datacom had failed to pay as much as 500 million shekels ($163 million) in taxes and royalties owed the Israeli government.</p>
<p>The radio said authorities believed the company had failed to pay full income tax or royalties due the government in exchange for research and development assistance. Giladi-Dor declined comment on the report.</p>
<p>News Datacom said it was &quot;appalled&quot; by the media reports.</p>
<p>&quot;Allegations of tax evasion are entirely without merit,&quot; the company said in an unsigned statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The company also wishes to clarify that it has not received any research grants which carry any restrictions on technology transfer - contrary to some media reports.&quot;</p>
<p>News Datacom develops and sells encryption systems mainly for pay television broadcasters, like Murdoch's SKY Television.</p>
<p>The News Datacom statement attributed leaks to the media about the investigation to &quot;a continuing extortion campaign against the company by former employees who have been sued in the UK by NDC (the Israeli company's parent) for defrauding it of millions of dollars,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.27 shekels)</p>
<p>- Jerusalem newsroom, 972-2-537-0502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
