<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129493" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-GILLINGHAM EXTEND HELPING HAND TO TROUBLED BRIGHTON.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GILLINGHAM EXTEND HELPING HAND TO TROUBLED BRIGHTON.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Troubled Brighton, whose future looks bleaker almost by the day, look set to share Gillingham's ground for the next two seasons, Gillingham chairman Paul Scally said on Monday.</p>
<p>The troubled English third division club, who spent four seasons in the top division in the 1980s and reached the F.A. Cup Final in 1983 but who are now facing extinction, have sold their Goldstone Ground home and must move out at the end of the season.</p>
<p>Gillingham chairman Paul Scally confirmed on Saturday that Brighton had made an approach, and said on Monday: &quot;It wasn't so long ago that Gillingham came close to going to the wall, so we know better than most what Brighton and their supporters are going through. If we can help, we will. Nobody wants to see the club go under.&quot;</p>
<p>Any ground-share agreement would need league backing and that was not a certainty on Monday.</p>
<p>A spokesman said: &quot;We allowed Chester to lodge with Macclesfield a few years ago because they were building a new stadium having sold their ground.</p>
<p>&quot;So far as we can ascertain Brighton do not have another ground to go to once they leave the Goldstone, which is another matter entirely.&quot;</p>
<p>Brighton fans have mounted a series of protests over the future of their club who are currently 92nd and bottom of the four English league divisions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
