<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129431" id="root" date="1996-10-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC states reach broad accord on info-tech policy.</title>
<headline>APEC states reach broad accord on info-tech policy.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States has won firm support from Asia-Pacific nations in its efforts to liberalise the global trade in information technology, a senior APEC official said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Philippine foreign affairs undersecretary Federico (rpt Federico) Macaranas told a news conference that members of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum had agreed to draw up a common stance on lowering tariffs on computers, telecommunications equipment and other &quot;info-tech&quot; products.</p>
<p>This common stance would be presented at the World Trade Organisation ministerial meeting in Singapore in December, said Macaranas, chairman of an APEC senior officials' meeting which ended in Manila on Sunday.</p>
<p>Details about the range of products to be covered and the timetable for tariff reductions still had to be worked out, he said.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;It is the desire of the senior officials that there be a collective stance on this. It will become a collective effort to move the (U.S. information technology) proposal.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. envoy to APEC John Wolff expressed satisfaction with the fruits of the senior officials' meeting, the final formal session before an APEC ministerial meeting in Manila on November 22-23 and the leaders' summit on November 25.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had excellent discussions (on the info-tech proposal). The process has moved forward considerably,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>U.S. assistant trade representative for APEC Bob Cassidy stressed the information technology proposal had extensive knock-on effects through a whole range of industries which employed this type of equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;Automobiles, for example, are the biggest consumers of semiconductors in the world,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cassidy added that the United States imported around $100 billion worth of information technology equipment a year, 80 percent of it from Asia-Pacific nations.</p>
<p>&quot;We are net importers,&quot; he said, adding that the United States imported twice as much info-tech equipment as it exported.</p>
<p>APEC officials have said agreement on the U.S. plan would underline the grouping's commitment to dropping all tariff and non-tariff trade barriers in the region by 2010 for developed members and 2020 for those who are less advanced.</p>
<p>Macaranas said individual action plans (IAPs) for bringing this goal to reality had made substantial progress and several of APEC's 18 member economies had gone beyond their earlier commitments under the Uruguay Round of world trade talks.</p>
<p>&quot;This to us is a landmark achievement of the IAPs, the fact that, voluntarily, economies are going beyond their Uruguay Round commitments,&quot; Macaranas said.</p>
<p>APEC members now have until October 30 to finalise any revisions to their action plans, which will be harmonised into a collective action plan for ministers' approval in November.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
