<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129498" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-ENGLISH/SCOTTISH LEAGUE FIXTURES FOR OCTOBER 25-28.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ENGLISH/SCOTTISH LEAGUE FIXTURES FOR OCTOBER 25-28.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>English and Scottish league soccer</p>
<p>fixtures for period October 25-28:</p>
<p>Friday, October 25:</p>
<p>English division one - Barnsley v Bolton.</p>
<p>English division three - Cambridge v Doncaster.</p>
<p>Saturday, October 26:</p>
<p>English premier league - Arsenal v Leeds, Chelsea v</p>
<p>Tottenham, Coventry v Sheffield Wednesday, Leicester v</p>
<p>Newcastle, Middlesbrough v Wimbledon, Southampton v Manchester</p>
<p>United, Sunderland v Aston Villa, West Ham v Blackburn.</p>
<p>Division one - Birmingham v Norwich, Charlton v Oxford,</p>
<p>Crystal Palace v Grimsby, Huddersfield v Port Vale, Ipswich v</p>
<p>Tranmere, Oldham v Southend, Reading v Swindon, Sheffield United</p>
<p>v Queens Park Rangers, Stoke v Portsmouth, West Bromwich v</p>
<p>Bradford.</p>
<p>Division two - Blackpool v Watford, Brentford v Millwall,</p>
<p>Bristol City v Notts County, Burnley v Plymouth, Bury v Bristol</p>
<p>Rovers, Chesterfield v York, Gillingham v Preston, Luton v</p>
<p>Bournemouth, Rotherham v Peterborough, Shrewsbury v Crewe,</p>
<p>Walsall v Stockport, Wycombe v Wrexham.</p>
<p>Division three - Barnet v Carlisle, Brighton v Fulham,</p>
<p>Cardiff v Leyton Orient, Chester v Hereford, Exeter v</p>
<p>Hartlepool, Lincoln v Colchester, Northampton v Darlington,</p>
<p>Scarborough v Mansfield, Scunthorpe v Rochdale, Torquay v</p>
<p>Swansea.</p>
<p>Scottish premier division - Aberdeen v Raith, Dundee United</p>
<p>v Hearts, Dunfermline v Kilmarnock, Hibernian v Celtic, Rangers</p>
<p>v Motherwell.</p>
<p>Division one - East Fife v Airdrieonians, Greenock Morton v</p>
<p>Dundee, Partick v Falkirk, St Johnstone v St Mirren, Stirling v</p>
<p>Clydebank.</p>
<p>Division two - Ayr v Brechin, Clyde v Hamilton, Dumbarton v</p>
<p>Queen of the South, Livingston v Stranraer, Stenhousemuir v</p>
<p>Berwick.</p>
<p>Division three - Arbroath v Alloa, Inverness v Forfar,</p>
<p>Montrose v Cowdenbeath, Queen's Park v Ross County.</p>
<p>Sunday, October 27:</p>
<p>English premier league - Liverpool v Derby.</p>
<p>Division one - Manchester City v Wolverhampton.</p>
<p>Scottish division three - Albion v East Stirling.</p>
<p>Monday, October 28:</p>
<p>English premier league - Nottingham Forest v Everton.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
