<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="129989" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Budgie problems to hit Sleepy Kids profits.</title>
<headline>Budgie problems to hit Sleepy Kids profits.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Animated cartoon group Sleepy Kids on Monday said lower U.S. revenues would hit its pretax profits this year after its &quot;Budgie the Little Helicopter&quot; series ran into marketing problems.</p>
<p>It was &quot;too early to quantify the degree to which profits have been affected,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Budgie, a cartoon character created by the Duchess of York, former wife of Queen Elizabeth II's second son, Andrew, has not performed as expected in the United States because of delays in getting a merchandising programme under way, it added.</p>
<p>The former Sarah Ferguson, known by the British tabloid press as &quot;Fergie,&quot; received a two million British pounds ($3.2 million) divorce settlement from Andrew but is reported to be heavily in debt.</p>
<p>Sleepy Kids said &quot;important momentum was lost&quot; on Budgie merchandising after the agent responsible in the United States, Launey Hachmann Harris Inc., filed for bankruptcy protection in April and has not yet been replaced.</p>
<p>When a replacement is found, it said, Budgie would be launched throughout the U.S. market through a stronger agent.</p>
<p>Sleepy Kids shares slid on the news on Monday to close down 6-1/2 pence (10 cents) at 20 pence (32 cents), near a year low of 17 pence (27 cents).</p>
<p>Fox Children's Network (FCN), which was broadcasting the Budgie series in the United States, stopped showing the Fox Cubhouse programme in which the helicopter cartoon series featured, Sleepy Kids said.</p>
<p>Rights licensed to FCN will revert back to Sleepy Kids if FCN does not buy a fourth series by March 1997, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very frustrating to have such a success on coast-to-coast U.S. television, only for it to be wasted by missed opportunities,&quot; said Sleepy Kids chairman Martin Powell.</p>
<p>But he added that it was a temporary setback and the company pointed to ratings figures from FCN, which were regarded as very successful.</p>
<p>Sleepy Kids said it was discussing a U.S. home video deal on Budgie and had signed a publishing deal with Simon &amp; Schuster for further books. In Britain, it is talking about a fourth series  of Budgie for 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to emphasise that Sleepy Kids is not solely dependent upon (Budgie) or any other individual property,&quot; Powell added.</p>
<p>Sleepy Kids turned in pretax profits of around 325,000 British British pounds ($516 million) for the first half of the year, up 6.9 percent, on sales up 29 percent to just over 950,000 pounds ($1.5 billion) when it reported on July 18.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741112">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
