<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130182" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>bosnia: Nine held for hijackings on Bosnia road.</title>
<headline>Nine held for hijackings on Bosnia road.</headline>
<dateline>TUZLA, Bosnia 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnian Serb police arrested nine men on suspicion of hijacking cars and robbing motorists at night along a post-war transit corridor, the United Nations said on Monday.</p>
<p>NATO peace troops reopened a major road linking Bosnia's government-controlled north with eastern Croatia and central Europe last winter, four years after it was cut by separatist Serbs seizing the northeast fringe of the country.</p>
<p>Bosnian Moslems and Croats as well as foreigners travel the route safely by daylight where it crosses a narrow strip of Serb-held territory. But security deteriorates after nightfall despite the presence of U.S. soldiers.</p>
<p>The nine men were arrested last Thursday and Friday in connection with holdups of motorists on what the Americans call &quot;Route Arizona&quot;, said Andrea Angeli of the U.N. police monitoring force in Bosnia.</p>
<p>He told Reuters in Tuzla, the main government city in northeast Bosnia, that there had been 39 hijackings of vehicles along the Serb-controlled segment of the transit route since it reopened last December.</p>
<p>The road is often clogged with commercial traffic in addition to private motorists, many of them Moslems and Croats who now live in Western Europe but who return home frequently to visit relatives and trade in local markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUZLA, Bosnia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
