<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130153" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: NUM, Northam to meet on wage deadlock.</title>
<headline>NUM, Northam to meet on wage deadlock.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Union of Mineworkers (NUM) and Northam Platinum Mines Ltd management will meet on Monday to seek a settlement to avert a strike, a union official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Management has requested a meeting in the next hour or so. And we don't know what they want and we are hoping they have something to offer,&quot; NUM regional coordinator Mahlakeng Mahlakeng told Reuters by telephone from Rustenburg.</p>
<p>Some 96.8 percent of the NUM's 3,300 members at Northam voted in favour of strike action last Wednesday.</p>
<p>The union and management at the mine, owned by Gold Fields of South Africa Ltd, reached deadlock over wage increases on September 26.</p>
<p>The union had initially demanded a 15 percent pay hike but was prepared to accept management's offer of 10 percent.</p>
<p>NUM said the point of contention was wage parity as Northam's minimum wage of around 556 rand was well below that of other mines.</p>
<p>Mahlakeng said the union and mine management met on Saturday but no progress was made.</p>
<p>&quot;We met on Saturday but obviously as a result of the last minute request by management, we felt that it might be useful to give them a hearing (on Monday),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Northam produced 75,365 ounces of precious metals in concentrates in the three months to September.</p>
<p>The mine recorded a net loss before capital spending of 7.39 million rand in the September quarter after turning in a profit of 8.17 million in the previous quarter.</p>
<p>Analysts said the mine would be hard pressed to deal with a strike by almost two-thirds of its workforce who belong to the NUM.</p>
<p>--Marius Bosch, Johannesburg newsroom +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
