<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130139" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Institutions snap up S.African Forbes tender offer.</title>
<headline>Institutions snap up S.African Forbes tender offer.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Institutions have eagerly snapped up a tender offer aimed at raising 60 million rand for South African financial services concern Forbes Group, the company said on Monday.</p>
<p>The offer, priced at 535 cents a share after initial estimates of 475-550 cents a share, is part of a book building process that will see the firm list on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange (JSE).</p>
<p>&quot;While it is not possible because of the book build process to calculate how many times the offer was oversubscribed, I can tell you that it was many times more than eight times subscribed,&quot; managing director Paul Heinamann said in a statement.</p>
<p>The special book build process, whereby 25 institutions were invited to subscribe for the shares, was used because the firm will be the only one of its kind to list on the JSE.</p>
<p>Forbes, currently 70 percent owned by Servgro International Ltd, consists of employee benefits consultancy Alexander Forbes and Price Forbes, Africa's largest short-term insurance broker and risk management company.</p>
<p>The group has forecast gross revenues of 611 million rand and attributable earnings of 70 million rand for the year to March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>The offer price gives the firm a prospective p/e (price/earnings) multiple of 15.3 times.</p>
<p>The firm wants to list in order to establish itself as an independent business with its own profile and objectives, to raise additional capital for expansion of the business in the short-term both locally and internationally, and to facilitate its future long-term expansion.</p>
<p>Forbes shares are expected to start trading in the JSE's insurance sector on Monday, November 4.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
