<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130311" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - oct 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - oct 21.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Monday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Croatian Helsinky Watch may face a rift after its member Drago Plisel accused head Zvonimir Cicak of straining relations with the Catholic church.</p>
<p>- New law on rents introduces maximum prices to protect certain categories of tenants.</p>
<p>- German company RWE to invest 50 million German marks to complete construction of Plomin 2, one of the biggest thermal power plants in Croatia.</p>
<p>- Bakers in Sisak, Sibenik and Pula pleased with quality of imported French flour after initial suspicions. Snjezana Dumbovic of Sisak bakery invited for a one-year course in France to learn the art of making baguettes.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Ministry of agriculture demands 15 percent more money to for subsidies to farmers and fishermen similar to European practices.</p>
<p>- Original owners of companies and hotels that were nationalised after World War Two will get their share back in 1997, state privatisation agency says. The whole process may take a long time as some have gone to court to raise the estimated value of their property.</p>
<p>- Croatia and Bavaria agree to build the Phyrn highway, connecting Nuerenberg with Split port via Maribor and Zagreb.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Croatia's current law on concessions, providing for agreements of up to 99 years after the Hong Kong model, seems inadequate because of much quicker capital turnover, says Boris Kale of the state road corporation. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
