<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130499" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Repco CEO charged under Securities Act.</title>
<headline>Repco CEO charged under Securities Act.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Repco Holdings Bhd's chief executive officer was charged with giving a misleading statement that could have affected trading in his company's stock, the national Bernama news agency reported.</p>
<p>Choo Chin Thye pleaded not guilty on Monday in the Sessions Court to the charge of giving a false or misleading statement on a material fact under the Securities Industry Act, Bernama reported late on Monday.</p>
<p>Shares of Repco, a timber and gaming concern, had risen sharply since last year on speculation about gaming licenses. Its shares jumped as much as 2,000 percent in one year.  </p>
<p>Choo, who is also a company director, is accused of committing the securities offence on January 27, 1996.</p>
<p>His signature appears on a letter with that date sent from Repco to the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange outlining a profit forecast for the years ending June 30, 1996 and June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>But a week after issuing that forecast, the company withdrew the letter and issued a lower profit projection, saying it had prematurely assumed approvals for a new gaming licence which were still pending.</p>
<p>Choo was charged under section 86 of the Securities Industry Act, which carries a maximum 10 years' jail or fine not exceeding 1 million ringgit on conviction, Bernama reported.</p>
<p>On Monday, Judge Zura Yahya allowed bail of 50,000 ringgit in two sureties pending trial on Feb 15 next year and impounded Choo's travel documents, Bernama said.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
