<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130592" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>QATAR: Qatar to name new premier this week - officials.</title>
<headline>Qatar to name new premier this week - officials.</headline>
<byline>Kedar Sharma</byline>
<dateline>DOHA 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Qatar's emir is expected to appoint a new prime minister as well as his heir apparent this week ahead of a cabinet reshuffle in the oil and gas-rich Gulf Arab state, officials and diplomats said on Monday.</p>
<p>Several senior officials said the announcements would probably be made by the Emir Sheikh Hamad bin Khalifa al-Thani as soon as Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the emir is set to appoint his younger brother Abdullah bin Khalifa al-Thani as prime minister, a post the emir currently holds. He will also name one of his four sons as heir apparent.</p>
<p>Western-educated Sheikh Abdullah, who played a key role in the bloodless palace coup that toppled his father, Sheikh Khalifa bin Hamad al-Thani in June 1995, is currently the interior minister and deputy prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;The announcement will be made tomorrow (Tuesday),&quot; said one senior official. &quot;Other cabinet changes will be annoucned next week.&quot;</p>
<p>The diplomats and officials said the cabinet reshuffle, which had been expected last month, gained momentum after the ruling family said on Sunday it had ended a row over billions of dollars missing from the treasury since the former emir was toppled by his son last year.</p>
<p>They said the changes were prompted by the need to give adequate representation to different sections of the ruling al-Thani family, which is the single largest Qatari family.</p>
<p>Currently, 11 of the 19 ministers in the cabinet are from the al-Thani family.</p>
<p>Among the other expected changes is at the Oil Ministry. Oil Minister Abdullah bin Hamad al-Attiyah may move to the Public Health Ministry and the emir is expected to create a supreme council of energy to be headed by himself.</p>
<p>The current Foreign Minister, Sheikh Hamad bin Jassim bin Jabr al-Thani, may be named deputy prime minister. The Minister of State for Defence, Sheikh Hamad bin Abdullah al-Thani may be moved to the Interior Ministry with the same rank.</p>
<p>Some new faces are also expected in the reshuffled cabinet.</p>
<p>The diplomats and officials said the settlement between the emir and the father he deposed helped consolidate his power and paved way for the expected new appointments.</p>
<p>They said the deposed emir was expected to return to Qatar soon as part of the settlement over the disputed accounts. Unofficial estimates say the sum controlled by the deposed emir ranged from $3 billion to $7 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;He (the former emir) will return as a highly respected citizen and a revered member of al-Thani family, but with no ruling powers,&quot; one official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="QATAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOHA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="QATAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
