<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130673" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Viacom, MCA in settlement talks.</title>
<headline>Viacom, MCA in settlement talks.</headline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del.</dateline>
<text>
<p>The legal battle between media giants Viacom Inc. and Seagram Co. Ltd. moved from the courtroom to the conference room Monday as both sides sought to reach a settlement covering the companies' joint cable venture.</p>
<p>Viacom, which owns Paramount Pictures, MTV and Nickelodeon, and Seagram, which owns entertainment and theme park concern MCA Inc., have been fighting for control of their cable channel USA Network, with each side accusing the other of violating the terms of the partnership agreement.</p>
<p>On Monday, testimony was suspended until Thursday to give both sides an opportunity to reach a settlement.</p>
<p>According to a report in Daily Variety, Viacom and MCA are discussing a plan in which Viacom would receive MCA's half of the USA Network in return for Viacom's half of the Sci-Fi cable channel and a substantial cash settlement.</p>
<p>Representatives from both sides declined to comment on the report.</p>
<p>Seagram filed suit against Viacom in April, charging the company with violating the terms of the partnership agreement by launching Nick at Nite TV Land. Seagram said the partnership prevents either company from operating or launching entertainment cable networks outside of the USA Network.</p>
<p>Viacom has countered there is no breach of the partnership, that the partnership is working well and that MCA is trying to get control of USA Network &quot;at an unfairly low price&quot;.</p>
<p>After the testimony of MCA attorney Jeffrey Nagin ended Monday the trial before Vice Chancellor Myron Steele was adjourned until Thursday.</p>
<p>If a settlement is reached by Thursday the trial will end.</p>
<p>During the trial MCA witnesses have recounted the drafting of the original joint venture agreement in 1981 among MCA, Paramount and Time Inc. In 1987, Time sold its share to the remaining partners.</p>
<p>If the trial does continue potential witnesses include Seagram Chief Executive Edgar Bronfman and Viacom Chairman Sumner Redstone.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
