<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130807" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mortgage lending disparities remain--Cleveland Fed.</title>
<headline>Mortgage lending disparities remain--Cleveland Fed.</headline>
<byline>Isabelle Clary</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four years after a highly controversial study by the Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, disparities in mortgage lending remains an unresolved issue for the U.S. banking system, a Federal Reserve Bank of Cleveland economist said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Whether or not widespread lending discrimination exists is a hard issue, and we can't find any easy answer,&quot; Cleveland Fed economist Stanley Longhofer told Reuters. &quot;That there are major disparities in the allocation of mortgage credit across races is not disputed.&quot;  </p>
<p>Longhofer, who authored a research paper on mortgage lending recently published by the Cleveland Fed, stressed &quot;the true magnitude of the debate lies in how it can help us better deal with those disparities.&quot;</p>
<p>Longhofer also said &quot;understanding why disparities exist, and in particular whether racial discrimination is at their source, is a crucial first step in developing policies that can effectively address this fundamental social problem.&quot;</p>
<p>The controversial Boston Fed study on &quot;Mortgage Lending in Boston&quot; was authored by Alicia Munnell and other Boston Fed economists in October 1992.  </p>
<p>Munnell's paper triggered bitter criticism among the U.S. banking community that rejected suggestions of lending discrimination based on racial prejudice and cited flaws in the data collection used for the study.</p>
<p>The criticism prompted the Fed to issue in July 1995 another study, &quot;The Cultural Affinity Hypothesis and Mortgage Lending Decisions.&quot;</p>
<p>That paper, authored by William Hunter, Director of Research at the Chicago Fed, and Mary Beth Walker, of Georgia State University, was based on the Boston Fed data, but showed no discrimination against top-tier minority borrowers.  </p>
<p>&quot;I am very fond of Mr. Hunter's work as a test of the theory on cultural affinity,&quot; Longhofer said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the data are pretty clear. African-Americans and Hispanics receive less mortgage credit than whites and Asians do. Why does this occur, is this solely due to benign or illegal discrimination, that's an issue that is still hotly debated,&quot; Longhofer added.  </p>
<p>The Cleveland Fed economist said identifying whether &quot;illegal discrimination is or is not at the source of the problem does not solve the problem. The disparities may be enough of a concern that we should correct those we have not changed.&quot;</p>
<p>Longhofer stressed &quot;knowing how race is associated with default rates may point to the source of any discrimination that exists, but it cannot help us determine whether it occurs in the first place.&quot;</p>
<p>The Cleveland Fed economist noted one problem in mortgage lending is that small loans -- mainly for properties in neighborhoods where little appraisal takes place -- are not very profitable for lending institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;The Boston Fed data does have problems and do not provide all the answers. Nevertheless, it's a very provocative study,&quot; Longhofer added, noting Munnell's paper was reprinted in the March issue of the American Economic Review.</p>
<p>The Chicago Fed said it would release in 1997 a nationwide survey of mortgage lending practices, based on data compiled by the 12 Fed district banks.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1666</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
