<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="130820" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: At least nine homes destroyed by Calif. wildfire.</title>
<headline>At least nine homes destroyed by Calif. wildfire.</headline>
<dateline>TUSTIN, Calif. 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least nine expensive homes were destroyed by a fast moving wildfire in an exclusive Orange County community on Monday and more houses were threatened, officials said.</p>
<p>Fire Capt. Scott Brown said the southern California blaze was being fanned by winds of up to 40 miles per hour (64 kph). High winds were also hampering the efforts of water-dropping helicopters, turning the water into a fine spray that had little effect on the flames.</p>
<p>The cause of the fire was not immediately known. Officials said it appeared to have started in a tree near a home. That home then burned and embers from the fire carried by the wind spread to other homes as far as 300 yards (metres) away. Homes in the area have wood shake roofs that burn easily, Brown said.</p>
<p>Evacuation of the area, including two nearby schools, was ordered by the fire department as flames soared 500 feet (152 meters) into the air, but no injuries were reported. An evacuation center was set up in Tustin City Hall.</p>
<p>Fire department spokesman Dave Romano said the blaze was in Leomon Heights, an exclusive area of Tustin about 35 miles (56 kms) southeast of downtown Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Firefighters said they were close to containing fully a wildfire that had threatened homes and businesses along a scenic stretch of California's coast in the Ventana wilderness area of the Los Padres National Forest, an area famous for its natural beauty. It has consumed 668 acres (270 hectares).</p>
<p>Firefighters said cooler temperatures and a drop in the winds had given them the upper hand on the blaze, which broke out on Friday afternoon in a canyon near the town of Big Sur, about 150 miles (240 kms) south of San Francisco. The Big Sur fire was now 85 percent contained and firefighters said full containment was expected by Monday night.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather should enable us to contain the fire,&quot; said fire information officer Kathy Good. She said the blaze was no longer threatening about 25 homes and a half-dozen businesses in the area and a section of Highway One that was closed on Saturday has been reopened.</p>
<p>One travel trailer was destroyed in the blaze but no homes have been lost. Two firefighters suffered minor injuries.</p>
<p>About 750 firefighters were battling the Big Sur blaze on Monday, backed by four air tankers and eight helicopters. Officials estimated the cost to date of the multi-agency fire fighting effort at nearly $900,000 but said the total could reach $1.5 million.</p>
<p>The cause of the Big Sur fire was under investigation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUSTIN, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
