<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13100" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SENEGAL: Expelled Africans return home on &quot;flight of shame&quot;.</title>
<headline>Expelled Africans return home on &quot;flight of shame&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Diadie Ba</byline>
<dateline>DAKAR 1996-08-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A first group of Africans expelled by France after a police raid on a Paris church landed in Senegal and Mali overnight. Airport staff dubbed a French plane carrying them a &quot;flight of shame&quot; and refused to handle it.</p>
<p>More than 50 illegal immigrants from Senegal, Mali, Zaire and Gabon were put onto an Airbus 310 at a French military base for the journey home to the world's poorest continent after a long-running standoff at the Saint-Bernard church.</p>
<p>On arrival, those who left the plane in Dakar remarked bitterly that they had fled poverty at home and had been forced to leave behind a new life and loved ones in France but official African reaction to the crisis has been muted.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been in France for 16 years, I left my French wife there, my father, my mother and even my grandfather. I don't understand what's happening to me,&quot; one of 13 Senegalese deportees told reporters, declining to give his name.</p>
<p>&quot;The French authorities must understand that we are not criminals but economic refugees. We left our country because life is difficult. That's the reality,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In France, Prime Minister Alain Juppe sought to soften the crackdown on illegal immigrants with promises of more humanity.</p>
<p>Only four Africans out of 210 arrested in the church on Friday morning were deported on the charter plane with more than 50 other illegal immigrants bound for Mali, Senegal and Zaire on Saturday evening from a military airbase west of Paris.</p>
<p>Witnesses said a French military supply plane accompanied the Airbus to Mali, where 23 people, including the four from the church, disembarked. The plane was due to leave for Zaire.</p>
<p>Dozens of other immigrants, including 10 on the 50th day of a hunger strike when riot police smashed doors and windows to break into the church with batons and teargas, were in detention in France on Sunday. All children and most women were freed.</p>
<p>The Interior Ministry said 40 of those seized in the church would be granted residence permits &quot;due to family or health situations&quot;. The Africans had demanded residence rights for all.</p>
<p>Defence lawyers said they would continue arguments in court on Sunday aimed at averting threatened new deportations.</p>
<p>West African governments, vocal about the expulsion by Angola this month of illegal migrants from their region, have been muted in their reaction to events at the Paris church.</p>
<p>But ground workers in Dakar refused the handle the French plane. &quot;No worker from Air Afrique should take part in this base task by helping these flights of shame on the ground,&quot; the Francophone African multinational carrier's union said.</p>
<p>It urged ground staff in fellow African countries to boycott all such deportation flights from former colonial power France.</p>
<p>From Dakar, the plane, which also carried 18 Zaireans and two Gabonese, later landed in Mali, where once again there were no airport staff on hand to service the plane.</p>
<p>Political parties in Mali, where torrential rain fell on Sunday, planned a protest rally.</p>
<p>In France, the church raid triggered protests against the centre-right government and clashes between stone-throwing protesters and riot police in Paris on Friday. Outside Evreux military airbase more than 100 people scuffled with police. One civilian, hurt in a police charge, was taken away by ambulance.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SENEG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAKAR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SENEGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
