<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13116" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Chechen peace search goes on after talks aborted.</title>
<headline>Chechen peace search goes on after talks aborted.</headline>
<byline>Brian Killen</byline>
<dateline>NOVYE ATAGI, Russia 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sensitive peace negotiations between Russian and rebel leaders to end the war in Chechnya hit a snag when Kremlin envoy Alexander Lebed returned to Moscow empty-handed from the region.</p>
<p>Lebed, who called off a meeting on Sunday with separatist chief-of-staff Aslan Maskhadov, said he would consult President Boris Yeltsin and other leaders to try to nail down the legal technicalities of Moscow's proposals for Chechnya's political future.</p>
<p>A rebel spokesman said Moscow had accepted the separatists' demand for a referendum, though possibly not for some years. The rebels say a free vote would back their goal of independence.</p>
<p>But Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, while saying voters should, eventually, decide the future, stressed in a television interview that Moscow also believed Chechnya should forever remain an integral part of Russia.</p>
<p>A rebel spokesman said Lebed and Maskhadov agreed at talks on Saturday on a face-saving political formula for both sides. He gave no details and Lebed apparently thought better of concluding a deal on Sunday.</p>
<p>Apart from optimistic rebel comments and the hard-nosed confidence of Lebed, a political novice with a former general's knack of making things sound simple, it was hard to spot the compromise that would save the latest truce from the bloody fate of previous ceasefires in the 20-month war.</p>
<p>But Maskhadov was due to meet Russian army commander General Vyacheslav Tikhomirov at noon (0800 GMT) on Monday in the village of Novye Atagi, south of the regional capital Grozny, to seal a final accord on keeping the peace.</p>
<p>The meeting was postponed on Sunday after Tikhomirov angrily accused the rebels of breaking the ceasefire deal by disarming a unit of Russian troops in Grozny.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not going to play cat and mouse,&quot; Interfax news agency. quoted him as saying. He was later reported to have talked to Maskhadov and agreed to Monday's talks.</p>
<p>A Chechen spokesman blamed renegade guerrillas for the incident and said the seized weapons would be handed back.</p>
<p>Despite this and other tense moments, the ceasefire arranged last week by Lebed and Maskhadov has broadly held.</p>
<p>Russian troops began withdrawing from the rebel-dominated Caucasus foothills in the south and joint Russian-Chechen patrols to police the truce in Grozny got under way, albeit with a fair degree of scepticism among their members.</p>
<p>More troubling for hundreds of thousands of Chechens forced from their homes by the war, including fierce battles in Grozny after the rebels seized much of the city on August 6, was the lack of clear-cut progress on a political solution.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin, apparently trying to counter speculation that Lebed was going out on a limb in seeking compromises with the Chechens, stressed that Lebed was acting in full cooperation with Yeltsin and government and military agencies.</p>
<p>Asked to confirm that Moscow might offer a referendum on Chechnya's political status, Chernomyrdin told Russian Television: &quot;The people must decide. As they decide, so it will be.&quot;</p>
<p>But he did not explicitly say a referendum was on offer. He also said people would have to wait till the region recovered from the war before the political question could be settled.</p>
<p>He also insisted: &quot;Chechnya should be part of the Russian Federation. That's simple. But when, how and with what status? It is essential not to decide that now.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NOVYE ATAGI, Russia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
