<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="131331" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM to launch car delivery program - WSJ.</title>
<headline>GM to launch car delivery program - WSJ.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp is revamping the way it sends vehicles to its dealers in an effort to deliver the exact car that a potential buyer wants within a day, the Wall Street Journal reported Monday.</p>
<p>The newspaper cited &quot;people close to the situation&quot; as saying the new program will eventually affect all of the company's brands by keeping large inventories of cars and light trucks at 75 regional distribution centers across the United States.</p>
<p>It said authorized dealers who did not have in stock a particular vehicle sought by a customer would be able to get it from a regional center in less than 24 hours.</p>
<p>The strategy board of the company's North American Operations had already approved the plan, it added.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the plan is an expansion of the Cadillac division's Custom Xpress Delivery service.</p>
<p>Cadillac intended to launch its plan nationally early next year, while General Motors had begun testing the same concept with Chevrolet and GMC sport utility vehicles in certain areas, it said.</p>
<p>The company planned to launch the plan nationally for all its brands in several years, it said.</p>
<p>General Motors declined to comment except to confirm the Cadillac, Chevrolet and GMC operatinos, it added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
