<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="131477" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt to privatise storage firm soon.</title>
<headline>Egypt to privatise storage firm soon.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt's offical Holding Company for Rice and Flour Mills said on Monday it would offer to the public shares in subsidary General Silos and Storage next week.</p>
<p>The holding company did not specify the exact date of the offering or how many shares would be sold but Public Enterprise Minister Atef Obeid was quoted on Thursday as saying the state would sell 40 percent of the firm by the end of the month.</p>
<p>The offering would be the first by the government since a lull hit the privatisation programme, the spearhead of the state's economic reforms.</p>
<p>The programme started in 1993 but did not start to gather pace until early this year, when a new cabinet took office under Prime Minister Kamal Ganzouri.</p>
<p>Officials said last week that the government was planning to sell some or most of the shares in 91 state companies by the end of June 1998 in an accelerated drive towards privatisation.</p>
<p>Shares in 27 of the companies will go on sale to the public through the stock exchange and for the other 64 companies the state will seek an anchor investor, they said.</p>
<p>It was not clear how General Silos and Storage would be sold but the holding company said the firm was one of its largest subsidiary with storage facilities all over Egypt.</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +202 578 3290/91</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
