<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="131574" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU farm leader open to partial British cattle cull.</title>
<headline>EU farm leader open to partial British cattle cull.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The top European Union farm minister opened the door on Monday to a partial lifting of the ban on British beef exports if Britain agreed to speed up the slaughter of cattle in some regions to fight mad cow disease.</p>
<p>In a piece of good news for Britain, which had angered its EU partners by refusing to implement a previously agreed plan to cull 147,000 cattle most at risk, Irish Farm Minister Ivan Yates said a regional approach might be acceptable.</p>
<p>&quot;We would favour, but this is a matter for Britain to propose, a regional approach whereby the accelerated cull could go ahead, perhaps in Northern Ireland, and thereby allowing a regional lifting of the ban to be considered,&quot; Yates told a news conference in Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the Florence agreement there is a clear procedure set out. Britain must produce a working document to show the implementation of their eradication plan,&quot; Yates added.</p>
<p>The Irish official, in Paris for an international food fair, is president of the EU farm council of ministers as Ireland now holds the rotating EU presidency.</p>
<p>British Ministry of Agriculture officials had first raised the question last week of a possible regional easing of the plan to slaughter 147,000 cattle.</p>
<p>The officials had discussed with European Commission aides whether herds certified to be freed of mad cow disease might be spared in some regions.</p>
<p>EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler had insisted as recently as Friday, however, that Britain must carry out the full cull.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland, where there is a computerised tracking system, and the Scottish islands would be the first to benefit from a regional approach.</p>
<p>After initially agreeing to the cull of 147,000 cattle, Britain had withdrawn its support, arguing that new evidence showed the cull would not speed up the elimination of mad cow disease, known scientifically as Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy.</p>
<p>British officials said new research by Oxford academics showed that killing younger cattle would not speed up the elimination of mad cow disease, because the malady would die out naturally early in the next century, with or without the cull.</p>
<p>The reversal had infuriated Britain's EU partners, who are already weary of London's go-it-alone attitude on EU policies ranging from a single currentcy to common security.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
