<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="131596" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch closing share market report.</title>
<headline>Dutch closing share market report.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares closed slightly weaker on Monday after an early spurt on the back of Wall Street's record close evaporated as investors quickly showed themselves nervous in the new record territory, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;There was just no follow-through buying. Which ever way you look at it -- this market is getting very expensive,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The AEX of blue chip stocks rose strongly early on, hitting a new all-time high of 597.80, before slipping back to trade around a 595 points for most of the afternoon. A weaker start on Wall Street on Monday further undermined sentiment and a late slip meant the index closed down 1.90 points at 592.43.  </p>
<p>Dealers said profit-taking increased as the market neared 600 points but some still expected the level to be reached within the next few trading sessions.</p>
<p>But they were divided ovedr whether it could hang onto such a level. Some said further gains would be a healthy sign.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd rather stay out of the market as it is now and then come back in if we got to 610,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>But technical signals were still positive and chart analysts were setting initial targets at between 625 and 630 points, with initial resistance expected around 598 points.</p>
<p>&quot;Buying activity remains strong,&quot; brokers ING commented.  </p>
<p>The index won support through the day from heavyweight Royal Dutch where the oil price surge and firmer dollar have boosted the stock recently. But some dealers were sceptical that such strong gains were justified ahead of the group's third quarter earnings figures due at the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;Those figures are going to have to be very, very good,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Royal Dutch put on 2.80 guilders to close at 291.10, a new year high and building on the 3.10 guilder rise on Friday.</p>
<p>But the other index heavyweight Philips slipped on continued investor jitters after the profit warning issued last week.  </p>
<p>Analysts are braced for a huge restructuring charge at the electronics giant, when it reports its third quarter results on Thursday. Some analysts believe the charge may be as high as one billion guilders. The shares closed down 1.50 guilders at 59.30.</p>
<p>Another index underperformer was retailer Koninklijke Bijenkorf Beheer (KBB), which announced earlier in the day it had bought 500,000 of its own shares from a placement by Vendex International. Vendex sold its 36 percent stake in KBB, raising a 130 million guilder book profit. KBB closed down 1.80 guilders at 118.70 and Vendex ended down 0.70 at 71.40 guilders.</p>
<p>-- David Evans, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
