<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="131660" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Monday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Monday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Monday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Peter Guilford said negotiations with the South-Korean authorities on the telecoms sector would take place from Wednesday to Friday to prepare a new framework agreement to be signed next week in Luxembourg.</p>
<p>Spokesman Nicolaas Wegter briefed on Commissioner Hans van den Broek's meeting with Polish Prime Minister Wlodzimiertz Cimoszewicz in Warsaw last Friday. Wegter said the Central and Eastern European Countries' accession to the EU would now only depend on themselves. Wegter also said the Commission was extremely happy with Poland's progress in applying pre-accession strategy but that further progress could still be made in certain specific areas.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, spokesman Josep Coll i Carbo said a decision could be made on the troika's mission to the Middle-East on Monday during the General Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Sophie Petzell said the fight against paedophilia and missing children would take place in the framework of Europol if that was made possible by the Member States.</p>
<p>Spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas said there would be a technical briefing in Brussels on Wednesday after the adoption by the Commission of the communication on the implementation of the Community's environment legislation.</p>
<p>Van der Pas also said Commissioner Neil Kinnock would hold a news conference at 1215/1015 GMT on Thursday on the liberalisation of air traffic.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/96/940: The cleaning industry: first agreements on the new employment in the sector.</p>
<p>- IP/96/942: Commission makes last ditch effort to solve telecom dispute with Korea.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/258: Seech of Commission President Jacques Santer on the European enterprises network against social exclusion.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/259: Speech by Commissioner Joao de Deus Pinheiro to the Ivory Coast national assembly.</p>
<p>- Agenda of the Commission meeting on Wednesday October 22 in Strasbourg.</p>
<p>- Eurostat news release No 70/96: EU invests 8.214 million ecu in Central and Eastern Europe between 1992 and 1994.</p>
<p>- European Economy, supplement B, Business and consumer results No 8/9 - 1996.</p>
<p>- ME96/21.10: Midday Express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
