<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13162" id="root" date="1996-08-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia's COAL in A$300 mln float - paper.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia's COAL in A$300 mln float - paper.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mining company Coal Operations of Australia Ltd (COAL) has said it would float on the Australian Stock Exchange for up to A$300 million in November, The Australian Financial Review reported on Monday.</p>
<p>COAL Managing Director Tony Haraldson told the newspaper he expected the float of COAL, which is 96.3 percent owned by the AMP Society, would be closer to A$300 million than A$200 million. &quot;The float will be a combination of the AMP selling down, recapitalising the company in its current state, giving us a solid start, and establishing our capital requirements for the the immediatee future,&quot; Haraldson said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we stick to our timetable, hopefully we'll go to market in November,&quot; Haraldson said.</p>
<p>He said AMP, Australia's largest life office, had indicated it would sell down to a level which would be seen as a long term investment without being perceived as an overhang.</p>
<p>&quot;No decision has been made as to the final number AMP will hold, but it has to be seen as the right number and there's no way they'll be selling their total stake,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>COAL owns a majority stake in four mines in the Hunter Valley in New South Wales which will produce five million tonnes this year.  </p>
<p>It also owns an 80 percent stake in three mines in the Wallarah district and an 85.5 percent stake in the Bayswater mine.</p>
<p>COAL also holds a 42 percent stake in the joint venture that won the right to develop a 900 million tonne coal resource at Wyong in New South Wales.</p>
<p>The forthcoming float would not seek to raise any funds to develop the Wyong resource, Haraldson told the Financial Review.</p>
<p>The capital raised this year would be used to expand Bayswater to a five million tonne a year mine and put in a longwall at the Moonee underground mine by 1998, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we look to do something else, it would be financed at the time, whether through a rights issue or debt,&quot; Haraldson said.</p>
<p>Haraldson was chief executive of Coal &amp; Allied Industries Ltd until June 1993 when RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd took control of Coal &amp; Allied.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
