<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="131654" id="root" date="1996-10-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: INSIGHT-Chartists mostly optimistic on Bel-20.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-Chartists mostly optimistic on Bel-20.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian analysts said they were mostly optimistic about the trend of the Bel-20 share index .BFX after a week of gains.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 ended at 1,806.20 on Friday, up from 1,773.35 on October 11, and down from October 3's record 1,829.85 close.</p>
<p> Contributor     Trend    Previous   Resistance     Support</p>
<p>						 First Second   First Second</p>
<p> Cera Bank	 up	  up	   1829  n/a     1800  1750</p>
<p> Bank Degroof    up	  neutral    1812  1830    1785  1765</p>
<p> Ecofis	    neutral   neutral    1830  1850    1800  1776</p>
<p> Generale Bank   up	  neutral    1810  1830    1800  1781</p>
<p>Contributors' own analysis:</p>
<p>CERA - The Bel-20 index rose 1.9 percent last week, ending above our previous resistance (now our first support) of 1,800. Cyclical stocks were among the advancing shares and this will continue in the near future. The Bel-20 benchmark is expected to continue breaking record highs in coming days amid a strong dollar and the continuing prospect of low interest rates as the economy continues to grow without fuelling inflation. -- Guy Sips.</p>
<p>BANK DEGROOF - Due to the bullish environment the market should at least be well-supported and we still see no reason for a downturn in the present situation. Moreover, new issues covering will add strength to the underlying wave of buying. So &quot;ceteris paribus,&quot; keep your long positions till Friday and, even if more and more dangerous at these levels, try to step in on dips (if any). -- Joel Crevecoeur.</p>
<p>ECOFIS - The doji star of last Friday stands for a loss of upward momentum. This may mean 'pause to reversal.' Short-term stochastics are also supportive of this view. If not, 1,800 needs to be consolidated quickly by white candles whose bodies lie fully above 1,800, a first support. Second support lies at 1,776, the low of the bullish window made between 14 and 15 October. But the movement since October 1995 is still a perfect uptrend. -- Frank Boll.</p>
<p>GENERALE BANK - The bearish picture that was prevailing last week turned systematically more positive over the week. The important resistance at 1,760 was confirmed, and on Thursday the first resistance level at 1,781 gave way. The 1,800 level was overtaken as well, which is a further indication for the strength of the market. The upmove over the week was more gentle, which makes it more sustainable. Trading tools like stochastics are pointing to a continued positive orientation of the market. -- Geert Vanderbeke.</p>
<p>(If you want to be included in this survey, please phone Reuters Brussels Newsroom on +32 2 287 6810 or fax your contribution to +32 2 230 77 10 before 1100 a.m. (0900 GMT) on Monday morning.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
