<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13446" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe capital markets ignore strike chaos.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe capital markets ignore strike chaos.</headline>
<byline>Emelia Sithole</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe markets on Monday ignored turmoil in the civil service after the government fired thousands of striking workers but brokers and analysts warned delays in resolving the crisis might spook foreign investors.</p>
<p>The Zimbabwe Stock Exchange (ZSE) -- which soared to record levels last Friday on the back of prospects of falling inflation and interest rates -- opened the week higher in a tense Harare teeming with police deployed to keep an eye on the fired workers.</p>
<p>The ZSE's key 57-share industrial index rose 22.76 points to close at 5,697.93 -- another historic high.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally our stock market is a little bit insensitive to internal problems. We have not noted any change in trade so far but we are keeping an eye on developments,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;However, if the situation continues like this foreign investors will become hesistant about investing in our market and shun it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The government of President Robert Mugabe sacked at the weekend thousands of civil servants who went on an unprecedented weeklong strike for higher pay which plunged key social services into a crisis.</p>
<p>The strike poses a rare challenge to Mugabe and his ruling ZANU-PF party, who have ruled Zimbabwe virtually unchallenged since 1980.</p>
<p>The government showed no signs of compromising on its position as it deployed scores of riot-control police wielding batons and semi-automatic rifles to guard state buildings and bar the dismissed workers from entering.</p>
<p>Richard Chitumba, an investment analyst with economic and share market analysts Dataworld, said if the current impasse continues, it may dent Zimbabwe's investment image abroad and reverse recent gains on the local bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;The stock market is now buoyant because there was exciting news of inflation and interest rates coming down. This current trend of unrest in the civil service might dampen that optimism,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>He and a bank economist, who refused to be named, said the strike may also hit economic growth this year if it continued for long and derailed government plans to meet key targets.</p>
<p>&quot;Already, revenue generation and collection in the public sector is virtually at a standstill with no staff collecting duties at the borders...The governmnent is losing money every day this goes on unresolved,&quot; the economist said.</p>
<p>&quot;So less revenue will mean it won't be able to cut down on its expenditure so the budget deficit will not come down to projected figures, neither will inflation,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The government -- under pressure from Western donors to restore macroeconomic stability -- aims to bring down its deficit to 8.5 percent of gross domestic product in the 1996/97 financial year ending June 30 from 10.1 percent in 1995/96.</p>
<p>It sees annual inflation falling to 17 percent by the end of December from 22 percent in July.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
