<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13531" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares open lower, quiet day ahead.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares open lower, quiet day ahead.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore share market opened lower on profit taking on Monday after the market rumours behind sharp advances in small cap stocks subsided, dealers said.</p>
<p>Institutional interest would be limited with the London exchange closed for a holiday, they said. At 0220 GMT, the 30-share Straits Times Industrials Index had fallen 11.89 points to 2,169.63 in line with Wall Street's fall on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Profit taking is inevitable as some retail investors were badly burnt in anticipation of takeovers coming through,&quot; said a dealer with a foreign bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Metro and Fu Yu had proven the market wrong,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Retailer Metro Holdings soared on Friday. Then it denied market talk of First Capital Corp mounting a take over bid and the share price dropped 7.44 percent, or Singapore $0.45, to S$5.60 on Monday with 1.47 million shares traded.</p>
<p>A lack of institutional interest saw foreign tranches of blue chips falling. Singapore Press foreign led the blue chip losers, dropping 30 cents to S$25.20.</p>
<p>The Stock Exchange of Singapore Property Index slipped 2.08 points to 684.41. City Development dropped 10 cents to S$11.40 on a volume of 236,000 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
