<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13608" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian ex-minister ups stakes in tyre plant row.</title>
<headline>Austrian ex-minister ups stakes in tyre plant row.</headline>
<byline>Janet McBride</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian tyre plant Semperit Reifen AG's fight for survival took a new twist on Monday when a former government minister said he wanted to buy the works from German owners Continental.</p>
<p>Hannes Androsch, finance minister from 1970 to 1981, said he had written to Continental shareholders on behalf of a group of Austrian investors offering to open negotiations to purchase the factory, which employs 2,400 people.</p>
<p>Last month Continental unveiled plans to halve car tyre production at the plant in Traiskirchen, eastern Austria and transfer the work to the Czech Republic, where labour costs are significantly lower.</p>
<p>The move is likely to cost 400 jobs and has cast doubt on the long-term survival of the 100-year old factory.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a healthy reduction, it is starvation. If Semperit has become a burden to Continental we can look at ways of taking on the load,&quot; Androsch told Austrian radio.</p>
<p>As chief executive of Creditanstalt-Bankverein between 1981 and 1988, Androsch oversaw the sale of then Creditanstalt unit Semperit to Continental in 1985.</p>
<p>But on Monday he criticised Continental's decision to slash production at the plant. &quot;It will increase costs by 15 percent and is the first step to closure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Androsch, an often controversial figure, is not new to the business of acquiring ailing firms.</p>
<p>He is currently vying to buy into former state salt monopoly Salinen and last year Austrian media linked him with troubled sporting manufacturer Head Tyrolia Mares and insolvent Danube shipping company DDSG.</p>
<p>His glittering political career has been tarnished by a tax evasion scandal. A Vienna court in May upheld an earlier verdict that he was guilty of failing to pay almost half a million dollars in taxes. Androsch is lodging a further appeal.</p>
<p>If successful in his bid for Semperit, Androsch said he would trim production costs, expand truck tyre manufacture and seek cooperation with international partners. He said he aimed to hold on to the Semperit trade name.</p>
<p>A Continental spokesman said the firm did not rule out selling the Austrian plant but he insisted the Semperit brand name was not up for grabs.</p>
<p>&quot;We are open for talks,&quot; Austrian news agency APA quoted spokesman Dieter von Herz as saying.</p>
<p>Semperit's woes have struck a chord among Austrians who resent the economic influence of neighbouring Germany. Unions have called for a boycott of Continental products if the firm pulls out of Austria.</p>
<p>Semperit Reifen made a net profit of 18.4 million schillings ($1.8 million) last year after a loss of 50.3 million schillings in 1994. The plant, which is the main employer in Traiskirchen, produced 4.8 million car tyres and 464,000 truck tyres last year. ($ = 10.39 Austrian Schillings)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
