<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136643" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine minister sues Cavallo for slander.</title>
<headline>Argentine minister sues Cavallo for slander.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine Interior Minister Carlos Corach on Wednesday sued former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo, who accused him of trying to manipulate judges and hamper corruption investigations.</p>
<p>&quot;There were multiple declarations by Cavallo which were considered crimes against (Corach's) honor,&quot; the minister's attorney Ricardo Klass told a television interviewer after presenting the suit against Cavallo for alleged slander.</p>
<p>The former minister is travelling out of the country at this time and was unavailable for comment.</p>
<p>Cavallo last week accused Corach and Justice Minister Elias Jassan of manipulating judges and of seeking to hinder investigations of alleged corruption by goverment officials.</p>
<p>In Congress, legislators met to consider whether Cavallo, who was fired by President Carlos Menem in July after seven years in the cabinet, should be called to testify.</p>
<p>&quot;We consider it vital that Cavallo comes to parliament,&quot; said legislator Federico Storani of the opposition Radical Party. If Cavallo can substantiate his charges, &quot;the natural thing to do would be to impeach&quot; the two ministers and the judges involved, he said.</p>
<p>Cavallo, who has admitted he has no concrete evidence, on Monday pointed his finger at another top government official, Menem's chief of staff Alberto Kohan.</p>
<p>According to testimony in court printed on Wednesday by an Argentine daily, Cavallo said Kohan had indicated he was aware that government officials had paid bribes to secure a contract between state-run Banco Nacion and the U.S. computer giant IBM's local branch.</p>
<p>Cavallo said Kohan made those remarks at a meeting the two held with Menem. Both Menem and Kohan deny such meeting ever took place.</p>
<p>-- David Haskel, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
