<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136750" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: RBNZ says conditions somewhat firmer than needed.</title>
<headline>RBNZ says conditions somewhat firmer than needed.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Reserve Bank of New Zealand said on Thursday that monetary conditions had become slightly firmer than needed to keep inflation in its 0-2 percent target range.  </p>
<p>David Archer, Chief Manager of the Reserve Bank's Financial Markets Department, said in a statement: &quot;The sharp exchange rate appreciation that we have seen in recent days has been accompanied by a relatively small drop in interest rates, leading to a marked tightening in overall monetary conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>He said while the bank had expressed concern about too rapid an easing in monetary conditions following the surprisingly low inflation result for the September quarter, it could see no particular policy requirement for monetary conditions to have firmed as much as has occurred in recent days.  </p>
<p>&quot;The issue for monetary policy is that, as the exchange rate rises, somewhat lower interest rates are needed to keep the impact of overall monetary conditions on inflation broadly the same. But those lower interest rates also take some of the disinflationary pressure off the housing market. Rapidly rising prices in the housing sector have been one of the main factors behind our recent surge in inflation,&quot; Archer said.  </p>
<p>&quot;However, preventing interest rates falling a little also means that upward pressure on the exchange rate would remain. The end result would be too much overall monetary policy tightness, with an even greater proportion of the pressure coming onto the export sector.&quot;</p>
<p>Archer said that in order to keep overall monetary conditions consistent with price stability, it seemed the bank would have to accept rather less interest rate pressure and rather more exchange rate pressure than might be ideal.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
