<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136707" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico bellwether Cetes rate up on inflation fears.</title>
<headline>Mexico bellwether Cetes rate up on inflation fears.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's bellwether one-month primary Cetes rate rose at the auction on Tuesday on expectations of higher inflation, analysts said.</p>
<p>But a decline in longer-term rates showed that the trend for inflation was down, they said.</p>
<p>The one-month paper rate rose 180 basis points to 27.70 percent at the auction. The 91-day Cetes were assigned at 28.79 percent, four basis points higher than last week.</p>
<p>The rate on the 182-day paper fell 24 basis points to 28.81 percent. One-year paper was at 28.41 percent, compared with 28.65 percent last week.</p>
<p>Inverlat analyst Francisco Gutierrez said the rise in the 28-day paper reflected &quot;the pressure that inflation is putting on rates, while the decline in the longer terms reflects a clear downward trend (in inflation)&quot;.</p>
<p>He said Cetes rates had risen recently due to an over-reaction in the secondary money market to exchange rate volatility and to short-term political and economic uncertainty.</p>
<p>Analysts said the results of the auction were as expected and that treasury bill rates could stabilise at around present levels.  </p>
<p>&quot;The auction went as expected, with mixed results. We are expecting that with this increase, rates will stabilise at these levels,&quot; said one market analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;However, everything depends on the reaction of the exchange rate. But I don't think that any increases in rates ... will be very large,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>The Cetes yield curve has been flattening in recent auctions.</p>
<p>Banco de Mexico recently tightened its liquidity objective in the money markets while the peso has been weakening.</p>
<p>However, inflationary pressures are expected to ease over time and that has allowed long-term rates to fall.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
