<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136716" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua tense as election results challenged.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua tense as election results challenged.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brooding tension reigned on Managua's streets on Tuesday, as Sandinista ex-revolutionaries muttered oaths about a disputed presidential election and ordinary citizens feared street violence.</p>
<p>&quot;At the grass roots level, party activists are angry, angry, angry,&quot; said Antonia Tiffer, a Sandinista militant.</p>
<p>Tempers were nearly at breaking point among Sandinistas in some rural northern regions, she added, especially former war zones where revolutionaries fought U.S. backed-Contra rebels in the 1980s.</p>
<p>The army spoke of a &quot;tense but calm&quot; situation across the country, saying that people were unhappy but had so far contained their anger.</p>
<p>But in the northern province of Matagalpa, opposition politicians alleged that observers had found 3,000 Sandinista ballots concealed in a house. They also said Sandinista supporters had seized and beaten up a man who had allegedly stolen 1,000 more Sandinista votes and hidden them in his car.</p>
<p>The report could not be confirmed.</p>
<p>Partial official results on Tuesday showed Sandinista candidate Daniel Ortega had failed to regain the presidency that he occupied from 1979-1990, losing by a margin of nearly 10 points to portly right-wing lawyer Arnoldo Aleman.</p>
<p>But Ortega claimed &quot;serious irregularities&quot; and &quot;fraudulent intentions&quot; had marred Sunday's vote and refused to accept defeat.</p>
<p>At the headquarters of the left-wing Sandinista Front, in run-down old taxis and in talk on the capital's rutted and dilapidated streets, nervous citizens wondered if the Sandinista's powerful grassroots would rise up against the official results.</p>
<p>Some Sandinistas said they were ready to lash out at what many viewed as election fraud but party bosses held them back.</p>
<p>Ortega's campaign manager Alvaro Fiallos was on a damage control mission on Tuesday, calling party officials, radio stations and television channels in a bid to pass on the message: &quot;Remain calm, and don't do anything rash&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm half angry, half sad,&quot; said Sandinista activist David Flores outside a sombre party headquarters. &quot;It was a shameless fraud. We wanted to rise up against it, but the party leadership asked us to remain calm.&quot;</p>
<p>Top Sandinista officials on Tuesday said their leader had a legal right to challenge the vote count, and denied that he was stirring up trouble after an embarrassing loss.</p>
<p>In a country torn apart in the 1980s by pro- and anti- Sandinista armies, memories of how quickly the country could degenerate into left-right warfare were fresh.</p>
<p>Rivalry between Aleman and Ortega was intense. During the campaign both men slammed each other as quasi-dictators bent on driving Nicaragua back to its oppressive past.</p>
<p>Aleman said he hoped &quot;Comandante Ortega has matured&quot; and called on the Sandinistas to accept the voters' verdict.</p>
<p>The pain of defeat was bolstered by the jubilant, and at times mocking, celebrations of Aleman's supporters, who let off fireworks throughout the night and partied wildly.</p>
<p>Sitting in front of a giant revolutionary portrait in the Sandinista Worker's Centre headquarters, activist Alex Reyes Cuaresma promised a show of strength if fraud was proven.</p>
<p>&quot;If the elections were not clean, there's going to be a massive peaceful reaction by the Sandinista Front to show that we still have power, we still have bases, and we are capable of defending ourselves,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
