<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136811" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China's sugar price dips as new crop arrives.</title>
<headline>China's sugar price dips as new crop arrives.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sugar in China's southern cane production areas is starting to run low, but supplies arriving from the newly harvested beet crop in the north are helping ease prices, traders and industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The wholesale price, including value-added tax (VAT), had dipped to about 4,600 (US $554) yuan per tonne, down from 4,750 ($572) yuan per tonne two weeks ago, the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;I estimate about 10 percent of the new crop beet has hit the southern markets,&quot; said a Hong Kong-based sugar trader.</p>
<p>While the amount of beet being transferred to the south from the north was not substantial, it was enough to have an impact on the Guangxi market, he said.</p>
<p>Industry sources estimate China's 1996/97 sugar crop at between 6.5 million-7.5 million tonnes, up from 3.3 million the previous year.</p>
<p>China's beet crop will reach the market during November, and traders were waiting for sugar prices to stabilise, traders said.</p>
<p>Demand in China for sugar was beginning to strengthen, with supplies in large cities tight, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I reckon some sugar will arrive in China this week,&quot; one said, but no specific deals had emerged, he said.</p>
<p>A Hong Kong trading firm on Monday reportedly received an order to sell white sugar to China, but no details were available, an industry source said.</p>
<p>Rumours of China buying up to ten cargoes of Thai raw sugar recently for March/May delivery remained unconfirmed, Hong Kong traders said.</p>
<p>Sugar traders in Thailand and Japan have said that China bought over five cargoes of Thai raw sugar for March-May shipment on a free-on-board basis earlier this month when Thai sugar premiums dipped to around 0.75 cents a lb over New York futures.</p>
<p>Japanese traders said that short-covering of raw sugar by Thai producers recently contributed to firmer Thai premiums.</p>
<p>Japan premiums for Thai raw sugar for March/May delivery were quoted at around 0.80/0.90 cent a lb (bid/offer) over the most active March futures on New York's Coffee, Sugar and Cocoa Exchange (CSCE) FOB basis.</p>
<p>Premiums were 0.65/0.75 cent a lb (bid/offer) on October 7.</p>
<p>January/March delivery was quoted at 0.95/1.05 cent over New York futures while May/July was quoted at 0.80/0.95 cent over New York.</p>
<p>But Japan's physical market remained quiet, with little actual business done due partly to wide price indications between sellers and buyers.</p>
<p>Traders said Japan's sugar refiners had already covered their needs through the end of this year, and they were focusing on purchasing Thai sugar for January/March or April shipments.</p>
<p>They added that sugar shipments to Japan from Australia and South Africa had been proceeding normally.</p>
<p>Hong Kong traders continued to target 1997 for China's sugar buying activity.</p>
<p>If China imported significant amounts of sugar it would do so after April 1997, when the crushing season was safely over, thereby protecting the sugar refining industry, Hong Kong traders said.</p>
<p>With China's total production estimated at 6.5 million and total consumption at eight million, China would need to import 1.5 million tonnes in 1997, said a China-based trader.</p>
<p>China's sugar exports reached 557,617 tonnes in January-September 1996, up 288.9 percent compared with the same year-ago period, customs figures showed on Tuesday. ($1=8.3yuan)</p>
<p>-- Mishi Saran, Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6358. Eichiro Tokumoto, Tokyo newsroom (81-3) 3432-7391</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
