<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="136918" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Candidates duel in Florida; polls bad news for Dole.</title>
<headline>Candidates duel in Florida; polls bad news for Dole.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner, U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>Republican presidential challenger Bob Dole took a triple punch from polls in the key states of California, Michigan and Ohio on Wednesday as he renewed an attack on President Bill Clinton's ethics.</p>
<p>In a campaign message broadcast on CNN, Dole returned to his theme of last week, alleging the Clinton administration was riddled with individuals who had committed criminal action and impropriaties.</p>
<p>&quot;How can a president lead Americans when he is the source of our cynicism? ... We have a duty to talk about this administration's public ethics because it is a matter of public trust,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people have asked the question, do public ethics really matter? Today, I am asking a different question: Could anything possibly matter more?&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>Undermining Dole's message somewhat, a former vice chairman of the Republican nominee's campaign finance committee agreed on Wednesday to pay $1 million in fines for violating federal campaign laws.</p>
<p>Former Dole fundraiser Simon Fireman, 71, pleaded guilty and was also sentenced to one year of probation with six months to be served under home detention.</p>
<p>Three polls provided sombre news for Dole from key states. Reuters surveys said Clinton was leading Dole among likely voters by 14.5 percentage points in Michigan and by 11.6 points in Ohio -- the latter being especially ominous for Dole since no Republican has become president without winning that state.</p>
<p>But the most devastating news for him was a Los Angeles Times poll showing Clinton leading in California by 20 points with only 13 days left until the Nov. 5 election.</p>
<p>Dole decided last week to concentrate much of his remaining resources on California -- the richest single political prize of all 50 states -- after another poll said he had cut Clinton's lead in the state to 10 points.</p>
<p>The Republican nominee sent several of his top campaign operatives to the state in a last-ditch effort to turn the election around and began spending heavily on television advertisements in California, which has some of the most expensive media markets in the country.</p>
<p>To pay for the blitz, Dole pulled his ads off the air in other key states, including New Jersey and Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>California, the most populous state, has 54 electoral votes -- one-fifth of the 270 Electoral College majority needed to win the presidency under the indirect U.S. system.</p>
<p>Ohio and Michigan account for a further 39 votes.</p>
<p>Both candidates were campaigning on Wednesday in Florida, a usually Republican bastion where Clinton narrowly leads this year thanks to his support among women and elderly retirees.</p>
<p>Clinton, staying presidential, started the day with a round of golf before addressing a rally in Daytona Beach where he highlighted a government report showing that child support payments have risen 50 percent over the last four years.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to keep going until we raise child support more and more and more. We're going to move hundreds of thousands of people off welfare by making sure that the parents do what they ought to do -- take responsibility for their children and their future,&quot; he told a cheering crowd.</p>
<p>Dole, trying to keep his spirits up, has been telling supporters to ignore the polls. He started his day at a sparsely-attended rally in Macon, Georgia, then flew to Panama City in the normally Republican Florida Panhandle.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a state we must win, this is a state we should win. I'm a conservative, he's a liberal, don't let him fool you,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>But some Republicans are deserting Dole to concentrate on retaining control of both houses of Congress, which the party won two years ago for the first time in 40 years.</p>
<p>Republicans are pouring money into a handful of close Senate races and dozens of tight House races, trying to turn back a gathering Democratic tide.</p>
<p>Democrats need a net gain of three seats to split the Senate, where Republicans hold a 53-47 majority, and give the tie-breaking vote in deadlocks to Vice President Al Gore, as Senate president, assuming Clinton is re-elected.</p>
<p>The Democrats need 18 additional seats to take control of the 435-member House of Representatives.</p>
<p>The state polls offered some good news for Republicans, showing that support for Democratic congressional candidates lagged far behind support for Clinton in all three states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
