<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13719" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: CRICKET-MUSHTAQ MASTERMINDS DRAMATIC ENGLAND COLLAPSE.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-MUSHTAQ MASTERMINDS DRAMATIC ENGLAND COLLAPSE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mushtaq Ahmed masterminded a dramatic England collapse at The Oval on Monday as Pakistan refused to settle for the easy option of a draw on the final day of the third test.</p>
<p>The bustling leg-spinner had collected five England wickets for 69 at tea as the home side stumbled to 227 for seven, a mere 32 ahead with one session to play.</p>
<p>England, already 1-0 down and heading for defeat in the three-test series, lost five wickets for 54 runs in mid- afternoon as they scrambled to overhaul Pakistan's first innings lead of 195.</p>
<p>The bubbling Mushtaq, bowling unchanged from the Vauxhall End, made the initial inroads, turning the ball a long way and appealing with all his customary zest, before Waqar Younis and Wasim Akram returned to grab a further wicket apiece before tea.</p>
<p>Despite losing Alec Stewart and Michael Atherton to bat-pad catches before lunch for 54 and 43 respectively, England must have felt they were out of serious bother at 166 for two with Nasser Hussain in excellent form.</p>
<p>They reckoned without Mushtaq's tenacity. Thorpe edged a good ball to Wasim at slip, Hussain was adjudged lbw playing no shot having made 51 off 96 balls and Nick Knight offered a return catch with England still in arrears.</p>
<p>At 187 for five, with a worn ball available for the Pakistan pace attack, it offered a real challenge for Chris Lewis, seeking to restore his reputation after being axed from his country's one-day squad for poor timekeeping.</p>
<p>He battled it out with John Crawley for half an hour, only to fall lbw to the returning Waqar Younis for four with England just 10 ahead.</p>
<p>When Wasim persuaded John Crawley to glove a catch to silly point, the lead was still only 25 with a 2-0 winning margin still a Pakistan target.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
