<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137288" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Trial urged for French Polynesia leader - sources.</title>
<headline>Trial urged for French Polynesia leader - sources.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paris prosecutors want Gaston Flosse, a conservative ally of President Jacques Chirac and president of French Polynesia's territorial government, to be tried on corruption charges, justice sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A criminal court will rule on the recommendation on November 25, the sources said.</p>
<p>Flosse, re-elected president of French Polynesia's territorial assembly last May, refers to Chirac as &quot;my brother&quot;.</p>
<p>A member of Chirac's Gaullist Rally for the Republic (RPR) party, he strongly supported France's last series of nuclear tests in the South Pacific, which ended in January and sparked outrage in French Polynesia and around the world.</p>
<p>Flosse, along with fellow RPR politician Jean Juventin, is suspected of personally profiting from pay-offs by illegal gambling operations, given in exchange for protection from prosecution, the sources said.</p>
<p>The investigation has been conducted by a Paris appeals court presided by Martine Anzani, they said.</p>
<p>Flosse, 65, said last year that he had been cleared in a dozen corruption probes, adding that two remained open. He did not offer specifics.</p>
<p>Justice officials say that several dozen French Polynesian politicians are now under investigation in corruption cases. Such probes are routinely handled in Paris.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FPOLY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
