<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137275" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: OSCE says Bosnia local polls not before next April.</title>
<headline>OSCE says Bosnia local polls not before next April.</headline>
<byline>Elizabeth Fullerton</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of the international mission organising Bosnia's post-war elections said on Wednesday local polls originally set for November were unlikely before next April at the earliest.</p>
<p>Robert Frowick, chief of the Bosnia mission for the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), told reporters elections looked feasible between April and June 1997, provided the ruling parties in the region agreed to renew the OSCE's mandate.</p>
<p>The OSCE on Tuesday announced the November polls would be postponed because of continuing political problems.</p>
<p>&quot;My own urging is that these elections take place in the April-to-June timeframe,&quot; Frowick told a news conference after addressing the Vienna-based OSCE permanent council.</p>
<p>&quot;Once we have that mandate, that's the essential basis for proceeding with the elections,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Bosnian Serb authorities, citing security concerns in villages where Moslems have resettled, had threatened to boycott the poll if the OSCE went ahead with it in November. Croat and Moslem ruling parties had also objected to the timing of the poll.</p>
<p>Frowick said the Serbs on Wednesday had declared they were not yet prepared to sign a new mandate for the polls, although the other two parties had indicated they were willing to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;Republika Srpska (the Serb republic) has not ever said it rejects the concept of OSCE supervision of any of the elections. Therefore, we think that by extension perhaps it will be acceptable (to them),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An OSCE summit in Lisbon set for December 2 and other forthcoming high-level meetings should help to rally international agencies together behind the mandate, Frowick said.</p>
<p>It remained unclear whether NATO's peacekeeping force, IFOR, scheduled for downsizing, would help with the elections as originally planned.</p>
<p>&quot;But it would seem to me some kind of ongoing and strong military presence by the international community would be essential for the period ahead,&quot; he noted.</p>
<p>He would not say whether he would continue as head of the OSCE mission in Bosnia.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have to engage in some difficult diplomacy to create a base that's solid and reliable for the elections to take place as soon as possible,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
