<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137259" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - Issing quashes lingering rate cut hopes.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Issing quashes lingering rate cut hopes.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank board member Otmar Issing, making an unusually categorical statement on monetary policy, said on Wednesday there was no reason to expect further cuts in key German interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Key rates are at a historic low and here nothing more is to be expected or necessary,&quot; Issing, the central bank's chief economist, said in an interview on German television.</p>
<p>Germany's economy is performing better than expected at the start of the year and there is reason to believe that the upswing will continue into next year, he told the ZDF channel.</p>
<p>The comments, a day ahead of the Bundesbank's next council meeting, prompted a decline in bond and share prices and strengthened the mark, although most market participants had not expected a rate cut on Thursday.</p>
<p>Economists said the remarks came as no surprise given recent evidence of a stable recovery and seemed aimed at preventing bond prices from becoming inflated even more by unjustified expectations of more interest rate cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;Issing's comments are positive in that they should counter false bond market expectations,&quot; said Thomas Mayer, senior economist at Goldman Sachs in Frankfurt. &quot;It should let some air out of the bond price bubble.&quot;</p>
<p>The yield on the benchmark 10-year April German government bond rose to 5.99 percent from 5.96 after Issing's comments hit traders' screens. The December future on 10-year German bonds fell about a quarter of a point to 99.50.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a more explicit view and the market obviously saw it that way,&quot; said Armin Kayser, an economist at Swiss Bank Corp in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Analysts have said that with the German economy gaining pace and prospects for another Bundesbank rate cut slim to non-existent, there is no fundamental reason for bond yields to be as low as they are at present.</p>
<p>&quot;Issing was taking into account the fact that the economy was buoyant in the third quarter,&quot; said Uwe Angenendt, an economist at BHF-Bank in Frankfurt. &quot;There is no need for further interest rate cuts.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists predicted key interest rates would remain unchanged until well into 1997 because there was virtually no danger of an early upturn in inflation, now around 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>Besides, an easing in the mark against the dollar in recent weeks had made life easier for German exporters, thereby stimulating the economy in the same way in which a rate cut would.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank has achieved what it wanted,&quot; said Holger Fahrinkrug, an economist at UBS in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The central bank last trimmed its main money market rate, the repo, by 30 basis points to a historical low of three percent at the end of August.</p>
<p>Its discount and Lombard rates, seen as setting the floor and ceiling for German money market rates, have been at 2.50 percent and 4.50 percent, respectively, since April.</p>
<p>Recent comments by Bundesbank officials have also dampened prospects for further interest rate cuts but have been less categorical than Issing's.</p>
<p>Bundesbank council member Reimut Jochimsen said earlier this month he did not see a need for another cut in German interest rates but added &quot;you never can tell. Never say never.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
