<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137280" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Juppe stays &quot;serene&quot; as popularity plunges.</title>
<headline>Juppe stays &quot;serene&quot; as popularity plunges.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe, whose popularity has sunk to near-record lows against a backdrop of austerity policies and unemployment, pledged on Wednesday to stick to his task &quot;with serenity and determination&quot;.</p>
<p>One opinion poll published on Thursday showed Juppe's standing slipping to 31 percent from 33, while another said that Juppe was viewed favourably by just 24 percent versus 31 percent in September.</p>
<p>&quot;These polls show that that public opinion does not trust the government. For my part, I trust the French, their realism, their common sense and I am convinced that the more we explain our measures..., and as people see the first results, we will understand each other better,&quot; Juppe told France 3 television.</p>
<p>He blamed difficult times and the unpopularity of the measures he had to take for his poor rating. &quot;I will continue my task with serenity and determination,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A CSA poll for the weekly La Vie showed the premier had dragged President Jacques Chirac down for the first time since the head of state took office in May 1995.</p>
<p>But Juppe, whose job often includes sheltering fellow-conservative Chirac from criticism, stressed that he was following a course chartered by the president.</p>
<p>&quot;The prime minister, given these directions, defines policies. I did that, I submitted them to parliament. The ruling coalition approved it...That's democracy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The second poll, a BVA group survey for the magazine Paris Match, found that less than a fifth of adults are happy about the way the country is being run.</p>
<p>The result was the lowest level of voter satisfaction since the centre-right coalition scored a resounding victory in the 1993 general election and replaced a Socialist government.</p>
<p>Just 18 percent of those polled were satisfied with the government.</p>
<p>The CSA poll questioned 1,011 voters on October 11 and 12 while the BVA survey was based on interviews with 924 individuals conducted between Thursday and Saturday last week.</p>
<p>According to the CSA poll, 38 percent of voters trusted Chirac to tackle the country's problems against 44 percent last month, while the BVA poll found that 35 percent had a favourable opinion of Chirac compared with 40 percent a month earlier.</p>
<p>The scores were Chirac's worst since late 1995, when his popularity plunged amid crippling public sector strikes over plans to reform welfare benefits.</p>
<p>Civil service unions staged a one-day strike last Thursday against feared job cuts, a record unemployment rate of 12.6 percent and austerity policies aimed at enabling France to qualify to take part in a planned single European Union currency from 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
