<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137357" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany wants to liberalise power, gas utilities.</title>
<headline>Germany wants to liberalise power, gas utilities.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's cabinet on Wednesday gave Economics Minister Guenter Rexrodt the go-ahead to liberalise Germany's electricity and gas markets, now carved up by a club of exclusive regional monopolists.</p>
<p>Rexrodt wants to pass legislation by the middle of next year to open up gas and power grids to third-party access. But he faces a hostile coalition of opposition Social Democrats (SPD), Greens and environmentalists who want to block the move.</p>
<p>Defending the liberalisation of a utility-friendly law dating back to 1935, Rexrodt told journalists it would lead to medium-term cuts in electricity and gas prices for users.</p>
<p>&quot;Under free competition utilities would be forced to cut prices to remain attractive to the consumer,&quot; Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>He added that regional utilities still had plenty of room to cut prices -- with electricity costing up to 15 percent more in Germany than in neighbouring countries.</p>
<p>The measures, if implemented, would open regional German utilities like RWE Energie, Veba/PreussenElektra and Viag/Bayernwerk to competitive pressures for the first time.</p>
<p>It would give households and most industrial consumers the chance to choose between suppliers. Energy providers and customers would also gain the right to force grid operators to allow access, Rexrodt said.</p>
<p>Under the reforms, state oversight over the sector would be reduced and access to the existing gas and power grid would be made easier. Regional economics ministries currently decide on allowing most tariff increases.</p>
<p>Opposition parties and environmentalists opposed the plan, saying it would discriminate against environmentally-friendly energy alternatives in favour of dirty fuels.</p>
<p>Small local utilities, fearing for their survival, had also mounted a lobbying campaign to block the proposal which caused a delay in cabinet approval for Rexrodt's proposal.</p>
<p>But Ernst Hinsken of the Bavarian Christian Social Union (CSU) -- sister party of Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) -- said it may be possible to amend the legislation in parliament to protect communal utilities.</p>
<p>The SPD, which has already wielded its majority in the upper house of parliament to wreck the government's 1997 tax plans, said it would also block Rexrodt's liberalisation bid.</p>
<p>SPD energy spokesman Volker Jung said the measures were an attack on consumer rights to local energy supplies which are rooted in Germany's basic law. Communal authorities would also lose up to 5 billion marks ($3.3 billion) in revenues.</p>
<p>The Green party echoed the SPD's attack, while the Nature Protection Federation (NABU) said the measures would trigger a price war, boosting energy consumption and leading to wastage.</p>
<p>But industry welcomed the initiative, with the German Industry Federation (BDI) saying that -- if enacted -- it would help cut energy costs and help make industry more competitive.</p>
<p>The Federation of German Chambers of Commerce and Industry (DIHT) said the cabinet decision was an &quot;overdue breakthrough&quot; towards introducing competition into the gas and power sector.</p>
<p>But the Association of Gas and Water Utilities (BGW) said an overnight lifting of regional demarcation would mean that the basis for gas supply would collapse, adding that interim rules to handle the transition would be needed.</p>
<p>($1=1.5247 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
