<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137407" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan women demonstrate against Taleban.</title>
<headline>Afghan women demonstrate against Taleban.</headline>
<byline>Marie Frail</byline>
<dateline>MAZAR-I-SHARIF, Afghanistan 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 400 Afghan women students staged a procession in the northern city of Mazar-i-Sharif on Wednesday to show their distaste for curbs on women imposed by the Islamist Taleban militia in Kabul.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the women marched from Mazar-i-Sharif University, now the only university in Afghanistan that women are free to attend, to the city's Ali Hazrat shrine.</p>
<p>Organisers said they wanted to show support for women in Kabul and appeal to the international community for help in protecting women's rights in Afghanistan.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disappointed that the women in Kabul have to stay at home,&quot; said one of the organisers, Rahullah Hashim, who works for the U.N. urban renewal agency Habitat. &quot;We want to remind them that we care and that we want peace,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Taleban ordered women employees, except health workers, to stay at home and effectively prevented girls from going to school after they seized Kabul on September 27.</p>
<p>Similar restrictions were already in force in other parts of Afghanistan controlled by the radical Sunni Moslem militia.</p>
<p>&quot;Islam allows women to have a life,&quot; said Fasyan (one name), an engineer who lectures at Mazar-i-Sharif University. &quot;Women should go to school, not be illiterate. We won't accept this.&quot;</p>
<p>She said restrictions on women's right to work were particularly hard on the thousands of Afghan war widows who had no other means to support themselves and their children.</p>
<p>Mazar-i-Sharif is controlled by General Abdul Rashid Dostum, leader of an alliance of anti-Taleban factions. Few strictures are imposed in the name of Islam in the six provinces he holds.</p>
<p>The Taleban, led by militant religious scholars trained in Moslem colleges in Pakistan, have vowed to enforce a purist Islamic order throughout Afghanistan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MAZAR-I-SHARIF, Afghanistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
