<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137647" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spiegel hurt by consumer credit decline.</title>
<headline>Spiegel hurt by consumer credit decline.</headline>
<dateline>DOWNERS GROVE, Ill. 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spiegel Inc, reporting a third quarter loss, said Wednesday it continues to feel the effects of declines in consumer credit, and its Spiegel Catalog and Newport News businesses were also hurt by lower productivity from catalog mailings.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to feel the effects of the stressed consumer credit market, especially the rising number of personal bankruptcies,&quot; John Shea, president, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The catalog retailer's Eddie Bauer division will be the driver of Speigel's growth in the near future, Shea said.</p>
<p>A new management team is working to reposition the Spiegel catalog operation by boosting the catalog's fashion brands, polishing the look of the book, and improving customer-acquisition efforts and service.</p>
<p>&quot;Parts of the plan are now being implemented, and we're confident that over time it will help turn things around for this business,&quot; Shea said in a statement.</p>
<p>Total catalog sales fell 10 percent in the quarter due to weak response rates at Spiegel and Newport News. Eddie Bauer's same-store sales fell six percent. The Eddie Bauer division has dropped some footwear assortments, which are a lower-margin business, to create selling space for activewear.</p>
<p>Gross profit margin on net sales rose to 31 percent in the quarter from 30.4 percent a year ago, due partly to fewer promotions at Eddie Bauer. Average inventories fell 11 percent during the quarter. Selling, general and administrative expenses were 36.3 percent of total revenues, down from 39.1 percent a year earlier.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DOWNERS GROVE, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
