<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="137946" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GNC plans 400 UK stores in next five years.</title>
<headline>GNC plans 400 UK stores in next five years.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States General Nutrition Companies Inc plans to open 400 stores in Britain's major urban centres in the next five years, Margaret Peet, managing director of GNC's UK retail arm, said.</p>
<p>Peet, whose chain of health stores and manufacturing plant in Manchester was acquired by GNC last November, said GNC would invest 41.5 million stg in the expansion programme by end-1998. The first new store opens in Bristol, west England, on Thursday.</p>
<p>GNC aims to open 80 new stores in city centres by the end of 1997 and the expansion plan should create up to 2,000 jobs. GNC UK currently employs 380 staff, of which 160 work in its stores.  </p>
<p>The UK market for vitamins, minerals and supplements is growing by 20 percent a year, Peet said, and demand for herbal products is also rising.</p>
<p>The trend for preventive medicine and a more health-conscious lifestyle shows no sign of abating, she added.</p>
<p>&quot;We tend to mirror the U.S. trends, where I think it's something like two thirds of people who work out on a regular basis,&quot; she said in an interview.</p>
<p>The stores will stock 4,000 lines including nutrition, scientific and sports nutrition products.  </p>
<p>Forty percent of GNC products are own-label brands.</p>
<p>&quot;The stores have a warm wooden feeling, with handmade cabinets and touch screen technology which allows you to search by condition for a product,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>GNC in the United States achieves operating margins of 63 percent and 58 percent in Britain, said Peet.</p>
<p>GNC's expansion will put further competitive pressure on Boots and health chain Holland &amp; Barrett, owned by takeover target Lloyds Chemists.</p>
<p>The UK health food market is expected to be worth 746 million stg by 2000.</p>
<p>-- Tim Farrand, London Newsroom +44 171 542 6437</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
