<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138081" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Southwest Asian heroin smugglers convicted in U.S..</title>
<headline>Southwest Asian heroin smugglers convicted in U.S..</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-10-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Iranian nationals and a Turkish national were convicted on Tuesday of conspiring to smuggle more than a ton of heroin into the United States.</p>
<p>The maximum sentence for the three men, alleged to be high-ranking members of a Southwest Asian heroin ring, is imprisonment for life without possibility of parole, authorities in San Francisco said.</p>
<p>Michael Yamaguchi, U.S. attorney for the Northern District of California, said a federal jury in Texas returned guilty verdicts Tuesday against Hakki Aksoy, a Turkish national, and Aziz Ghanbari and Sayadi Takhtehkar, both Iranian nationals, on charges of conspiring to import 500 to 1,000 kilos (1,100 to 2,200 pounds) of heroin.</p>
<p>Assistant U.S. Attorney Jeffrey Cole said the convictions were a major breakthrough for U.S. authorities and that the investigation of the heroin-smuggling ring would continue.</p>
<p>&quot;These were top players, without a doubt,&quot; said Cole, lead prosecutor on the case. &quot;By being able to convict men in the upper echelons of the organisation should deter other people from trying to put their heroin into this country.&quot;</p>
<p>The jury returned verdicts of guilty against all three defendants for conspiracy to import heroin, conspiracy to possess with the intent to distribute heroin, and distribution of heroin. In addition Takhtehkar was convicted of tampering with a witness.</p>
<p>Authorities said the men were high-ranking members of a major Southwest Asian heroin smuggling ring that bought large quantities of base morphine from groups in Pakistan. The morphine was processed in Romania and Turkey.</p>
<p>The smuggling ring then shipped the processed drugs to countries around the world, U.S. authorities said.</p>
<p>The men were indicted in San Francisco but the case was tried in Lubbock, Texas, where some of their heroin was stored. The men were being held in a Texas facility.</p>
<p>The convictions followed a lengthy investigation that involved negotiations between government undercover agents and the defendants in Europe and San Francisco.</p>
<p>They were arrested in San Francisco and New York after they transferred 25 kilos of heroin, worth $2 million wholesale, as a sample to undercover agents. Cole said the men were negotiating with the agents to ship a container of heroin containing between 500 and 1,000 kilos.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
