<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138176" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FORECAST-Analysts see Italy rate cut by end-Nov.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Analysts see Italy rate cut by end-Nov.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Preliminary Italian inflation figures for October, which came in better than expected, have not changed analysts' expectations of a fall in official interest rates of 75-100 basis points by the end of November.</p>
<p>This was the conclusion of a survey of 13 analysts conducted by Reuters.</p>
<p>Preliminary CPI figures on Monday and Tuesday from 10 Italian cities indicated that Italian October inflation would fall to 3.0 percent from 3.4 percent in September. Before the figures were published, analysts were looking for an October CPI figure of 3.2 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Bank of Italy will likely wait for preliminary November inflation data, due around November 21, for the next cut in Italy's official discount rate. The last discount rate of 75 basis point to 8.25 percent was in July.</p>
<p>Preliminary November data will be published a little after Italy's parliamentary lower house is expected to approve the 1997 financial buget on November 17.</p>
<p>Only one analyst saw the October preliminary data as accelerating the timing of a cut in interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The objective of inflation has been reached, and it is not necessary to wait for the approval of the budget in the lower house. A future interest rate cut will depend on the timing of fiscal policy,&quot; said Francesco Giordano, senior economist at San Paolo Bank. He sees inflation at 2.8 percent by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The governor of the Bank of Italy Antonio Fazio has said that the approval of the 1997 financial budget will accelerate the fall in interest rates. He sees average inflation in 1996 at below four percent.</p>
<p>All the analysts questioned said that an interest rate cut in late 1996 will not be the last, and they see a further cut in the first six months of 1997.</p>
<p>The size of this second cut will depend on the size of the first, with analysts looking for an average of a further 50 basis points, or a range of between 25 and 125 basis points.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the second interest rate cut will depend on the value of the lira and the timing of the lira's re-entry into Europe's Exchange Rate Mechanism.</p>
<p>SURVEY QUESTIONS</p>
<p>1. Will there be a further interest rate cut?</p>
<p>	 Yes						   (12 out of 12)</p>
<p>	 No								(0/12)</p>
<p>2. When will the interest rate cut be?</p>
<p>	 Before the end of October				 (1/12)</p>
<p>	 After final October CPI data			    (0/12)</p>
<p>	 After preliminary Nov CPI data			  (9/12)</p>
<p>	 After final Nov CPI data				  (2/12)</p>
<p>3. What will be the size of the rate cut?</p>
<p>	 75 basis points					     (5/12)</p>
<p>	 75-100 basis points					 (1/12)</p>
<p>	 100 basis points					    (6/12)</p>
<p>4. Will there be a further interest rate cut?</p>
<p>	 Yes							     (12/12)</p>
<p>	 No								 (0/0)</p>
<p>5. When will this further cut be?</p>
<p>	 By the end of 1996					  (2/12)</p>
<p>	 By end of first quarter of 1997			 (8/12)</p>
<p>	 By June 1997						  (2/12)</p>
<p>NOTE - The following took part in the survey Banca di Roma, Bank of America, Banco di Sardegna, Caboto, Comit, Credit, Deutsche Bank, Dri-McGraw Hill, IBJ international, NatWest, Paribas, San Paolo Bank and one participant who declined to be named.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
