<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138121" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgium acts as go-between in east Zaire crisis.</title>
<headline>Belgium acts as go-between in east Zaire crisis.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium is acting as a go-between in the crisis in the central African Great Lakes region involving Zaire and its neighbours Rwanda and Burundi, the Foreign Ministry said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Belgium has assumed the role of facilitator,&quot; the ministry spokesman told the weekly briefing.</p>
<p>Belgium was not putting forward any proposals to help end the crisis, but offering the parties involved the use of its facilities. In addition, it was &quot;trying to convince both sides that it made sense to talk to each other,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rivalry between Hutus and Tutsis in the region is feeding a multi-sided war, triggering a humanitarian crisis in east Zaire.</p>
<p>Zaire is a former Belgian colony, Rwanda and Burundi are former Belgian protectorates.</p>
<p>Zaire is accusing Rwanda and Burundi's Tutsi-dominated armies of having launched an attack inside South Kivu province and says Rwandan soldiers launched raids inside North Kivu. Both provinces are in the east of Zaire.</p>
<p>The foreign ministry spokesman said Belgium did not want to act as a mediator. &quot;That is better handled by Africans in the framework of the OAU&quot; (Organisation of African Unity).</p>
<p>He said Belgium had called on OAU chief Salim Ahmed Salim to act in the conflict.</p>
<p>As part of the Belgian efforts, the ambassador in Kigali, Yves Hazendonk, met Rwandan vice-President and Minister of Defence Paul Kagame in Rome on Tuesday to urge Kigali to exert restraint.</p>
<p>He said the prime ministers of Zaire and Rwanda had agreed to meet, but gave no details.</p>
<p>The fighting in Kivu has fueled fears that rivalry between ethnic Hutus and Tutsis, which was behind the 1994 genocide of minority Tutsis by Hutu hardliners in Rwanda and Burundi's bitter civil war, could lead to strife in the whole region.</p>
<p>Up to a quarter of a million Hutu refugees took flight after fighting between the Zairean army and Tutsi Banyamulenge rebels flared on Friday near the town of Uvira and the Burundi border.</p>
<p>The Banyamulenge, who migrated from Rwanda in the late 18th century, accuse local Zaireans of forcing them to leave.</p>
<p>Aid workers, who predict a humanitarian catastrophe, say Zairean civilians have started to join the refugees and warn that food is running short.</p>
<p>&quot;The humanitarian situation is very dangerous,&quot; the Belgian foreign ministry spokesman said. Belgium has told its citizens not to travel to the area and those who are there, an estimated 350, to leave.</p>
<p>The embassy in Kinshasa would advise them on the best routes to take, he said, there were private and commercial airfields in the area. The road to Bujumbura, the capital of Burundi, was inaccessible, he noted, because it had been mined.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
