<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138349" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Limelight Group sees 16.5 mln stg trading profit.</title>
<headline>Limelight Group sees 16.5 mln stg trading profit.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>British retailer Limelight Group Plc, set to trade on the London Stock Exchange next month, said on Wednesday it expected its operating profit from continuing operations to be not less than 16.5 million stg for the year.</p>
<p>The forecast excluded exceptional items, the company said in its statement.</p>
<p>Limelight, which makes fully-fitted home improvement products, also predicted its pro forma profit before exceptionals and tax would be not less than 15.8 million stg for the year ended December 31.  </p>
<p>Limelight plans to place the bulk of the shares, about 85 percent, with institutional investors and offer some shares to staff and 15 percent to intermediaries.</p>
<p>The placing will start on November 14 when the offer price and basis of allocation will also be announced. Dealing in the new shares is due to start on November 15.</p>
<p>Limelight management own 56 percent of the company, including the 50 percent holding of former chairman and chief executive Stephen Boler.</p>
<p>Schroder Ventures owns 27 percent and ADT just over 16 percent.  </p>
<p>ADT plans to sell its entire shareholding while Schroder Ventures is expected to reduce its stake to about 10 percent.</p>
<p>Boler is expected to sell about half of his holding.</p>
<p>Current chief executive Stephen Cotter said in an interview that the company is benefitting from a pick-up in the UK economy and stronger consumer spending on home improvement.</p>
<p>&quot;We can see the economy picking up and people spending more on their homes. Our view is that it will continue on into 1997 and 1998,&quot; said Cotter. He said trading in the second half of 1996 continues to be strong with Mobens and Kitchens Direct performing above forecasts.  </p>
<p>Limelight, which operates nationally from 555 showrooms, said it had identified 33 sites for showroom openings before June 30, 1997, with potential for a further 200 locations in high streets and retail parks over the long term.</p>
<p>Sharps, Limelight's fitted bedrooms business which has a relatively high market share in Britain, is currently negotiating two concession agreements in mainland Europe.</p>
<p>-- Tim Farrand, London Newsroom +44 171 542 6437</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I46700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
