<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138419" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Costello says CPI good outcome for economy.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Costello says CPI good outcome for economy.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said on Wednesday September quarter inflation data released earlier was a very good outcome for the economy.</p>
<p>Costello told reporters the data, showing the consumer price index (CPI) rose 0.3 percent in the September quarter for an annual inflation rate of 2.1 percent, showed there was no need for a push for increased wages.  </p>
<p>&quot;This is a good result for the consumer price index for the September quarter ... that's a very good outcome for the Australian economy. What it shows is that we are in a low inflationary growth environment,&quot; Costello said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's important I think that employees understand that we are now in a low inflation economy. They don't have to seek wage increases to chase prices because prices are not substantially moving,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's the important point about today's outcome, so we've got to make sure that our wages results are quite consistent with this low price movement and if we can do that, that will be a major improvement,&quot; Costello said.</p>
<p>The Treasury's measure of underlying inflation rose 0.5 percent also in the September quarter to stand at 2.4 percent for the year, back in the Reserve Bank's two to three percent target range.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
