<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138462" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Leap in interim profit seen for Proton.</title>
<headline>Leap in interim profit seen for Proton.</headline>
<byline>Azhar Sukri</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian car maker Perusahaan Otomobil Nasioanal Bhd's (Proton) profits for the half-year ended September 30 1996 look set to astonish market watchers, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>HLG securities said Proton's management had confirmed to them that it anticipates the first-half pre-tax profit to September 30 1996 would be around 450 million ringgit.</p>
<p>The group's pre-tax profit for the financial year to March 31, 1996 amounted to 454.6 million ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;We contacted (Proton's) management which confirmed pre-tax profit would be in the region of 450 million ringgit,&quot; HLG said in a report distributed to clients.</p>
<p>&quot;We are surprised with the rumoured strong results. Obviously, the impact of the yen and cost control had played a bigger part than what we or the industry had expected.&quot;</p>
<p>Proton executives were unavailable for comment. The results are expected to be released towards the end of next month.</p>
<p>Analysts said they had expected higher profits due to a weaker Japanese yen against the ringgit and the cutting of component costs by Proton's local parts suppliers. But they now say they underestimated the impact on Proton's bottom line.</p>
<p>&quot;The improvement in earnings was mainly due to a drop in yen/ringgit from 2.75 ringgit to 2.55 ringgit,&quot; Kuala Lumpur-based Jupiter Securities said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The yen/ringgit rate is significant for Proton since roughly 30 percent of the vehicles' components are imported from Japan.</p>
<p>Jupiter's report also attributed the sharply better profits to a &quot;five percent drop in production costs due to aggresive cost-cutting measures&quot;. Analysts had earlier predicted component costs to be roughly two percent lower.</p>
<p>The anticipation of the better-than-expected earnings helped boost Proton's shares to 15.70 ringgit at Wednesday's close from 13.90 on October 17.</p>
<p>But the outlook for Proton beyond the immediate future remains clouded by several factors, analysts said.</p>
<p>Sales of Proton cars are growing but at a slower rate.</p>
<p>Choo Swee Kee, auto analyst at equities research house Vickers Ballas in Kuala Lumpur, predicts sales for the first half to September 30 1996 will have grown by 11 percent. But that is down from the 14 percent growth recorded for the whole of the previous financial year to March 31, 1996.</p>
<p>Analysts attribute this to Malaysia being in the fourth year of a five-year replacement cycle -- consumers in Malaysia tend to replace their cars once in every five years. The next cycle is expected in 1998, making 1997 a slow year for car sales.</p>
<p>The Japanese yen is currently at a three-and-a-half year low against the ringgit. &quot;So any upturn in the yen could wipe out any profits,&quot; said the HLG Securities auto analyst.</p>
<p>Foreign imports are also likely to cause some competition for Proton in certain model ranges, the analysts said. Honda recently launched the 1300 cc 'City' model. Although priced above the equivalent Proton Tiara, it will likely be attractive to brand-conscious consumers, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1996 budget saw import tariffs on cars come down from 300 percent to 200 percent, with the plan being to reduce them to 50 percent by the 2000-2003 time frame,&quot; said HLG's auto analyst. &quot;We (Malaysia) should start to reduce tariffs now in order to reduce the burden on Proton later,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But reduced tariffs on imported cars means more competition for Proton at home.</p>
<p>Proton's answer is to increase capacity to achieve greater economies of scale, thereby increasing margins. Capacity is expected to increase from the current 180,000 units per annum to around 450,000 units per annum by 1999.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
