<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138455" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Oct 23.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Chinese newspapers - Oct 23.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Chinese political and business stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Beijing. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not guarantee their accuracy. Telephone: (8610) 6532-1921. Fax: (8610) 6532-4978.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PEOPLE'S DAILY</p>
<p>In speech to mark the 60th anniversary of the Long March, President Jiang Zemin praises the gruelling trek as an unparalleled undertaking in Chinese history that will be remembered as a permanent monument to the communist revolution.</p>
<p>China and Germany should view their bilateral relations from a long-term and strategic perspective, President Jiang Zemin tells visiting German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel.</p>
<p>China shuts down nearly 50,000 severely polluting enterprises since August.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA DAILY</p>
<p>Premier Li Peng and visiting Colombian President Ernesto Samper agree that all countries, big or small, have the right to choose their road to development in line with their own national conditions.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Taiwan Affairs Office under the State Council, or cabinet, calls Taiwan's new opposition party, the Taiwan Independence Party, a reactionary political organisation set up with the explicit purpose of splitting the motherland.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>CHINA SECURITIES</p>
<p>Chinese rubber supply exceeds demand as January to September output reaches 1.32 million tonnes, up 21.5 percent compared with the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>The number of containers imported and exported from Shanghai between January and September soars to 1.17 million cases, up 22.5 percent compared with last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
