<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13853" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. airlines saw more calls ahead of excise tax.</title>
<headline>U.S. airlines saw more calls ahead of excise tax.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rushing to beat the 10 percent passenger excise tax, which returns at midnight, consumers flooded airlines reservation lines on Monday, carriers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our call volume was running ahead of normal for this time of year and the percentage of people making bookings on those calls is also higher than normal,&quot; said Tim Smith, a spokesman for AMR Corp's American Airlines.</p>
<p>The question remains whether or not airlines will tack the 10 percent excise tax onto existing fares, or absorb all or part of the tax themselves.  </p>
<p>Carriers declined to comment on Monday on their plans, citing federal restrictions on &quot;fare signaling&quot; -- or commenting on future fare.</p>
<p>Some major carriers, such as Continental Airlines Inc , ran advertisements on Monday urging customers to purchase tickets before the excise tax returns at midnight.</p>
<p>&quot;The major airlines are gearing up to add the 10 percent excise tax back to the current airfares,&quot; said Tom Parsons, author of Insider Travel Secrets and editor of Best Fares Discount Travel Magazine.  </p>
<p>Major U.S. airlines recently raised fares by about 10 percent, citing higher costs due to tougher security measures and the pending excise tax.</p>
<p>Wall Street analysts question whether or not the airlines will be able to force consumers to pay both the higher fares and the excise tax.</p>
<p>&quot;Twenty percent is a lot to put on consumers in a short time,&quot; Jeffrey Long, an analyst with J.P. Morgan Securities.</p>
<p>Airlines will add the tax starting at midnight, but may launch sales if bookings drop off radically, analysts said.</p>
<p>When the excise tax lapse on December 31, airlines initially passed the 10 percent savings on to consumers.</p>
<p>Then, carriers slowly began raising fares about six percent to eight percent, benefitting from funds that would normally go to the federal government.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
