<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138524" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Nikkei futures clamber above 21,000 at close.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Nikkei futures clamber above 21,000 at close.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bout of late short-covering pushed SIMEX Nikkei futures back above the psychological 21,000-points but failed to propel the market to a firm close on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;People tried to push it above 21,100 looking for (buy) stops that may have been set up during all the selling in the morning but it came back off at the close,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>After hitting a high of 21,130, the benchmark Nikkei 225 December contract ended at 21,085 against its previous settlement at 21,195. Volume was a healthy 23,145 lots.  </p>
<p>&quot;We got near some key support levels at 20,840/50 and if we had gone below there, it could have gotten pretty ugly,&quot; said the trader, adding that the December Nikkei's next crucial support level was at 20,660.</p>
<p>He said the market could rally back towards the 21,500 region by the end of the week if it managed to hold above support levels, but added that such gains would be short-term.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese economy isn't doing anything to warrant a move up right now,&quot; he said, noting that the Japanese bond market was drawing more investor's interest.  </p>
<p>Dealers said sentiment on the underlying cash market had been weakened by uncertainty about the direction of Japanese government policy after Sunday's general election.</p>
<p>-- Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
