<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138520" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan dollar ends sharply down at 3-month low.</title>
<headline>Taiwan dollar ends sharply down at 3-month low.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Taiwan dollar closed sharply lower against the U.S. dollar on Wednesday, pushed to its lowest level in three months by heavy U.S. dollar demand, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Taiwan dollar dipped to an intrasession low of T$27.620 to the U.S. dollar before rebounding slightly to end at T$27.586 against Tuesday's T$27.550 close.  </p>
<p>Turnover through brokers was a hectic US$569.5 million, the heaviest since US$606.5 million recorded on March 15 at the height of Taiwan's acute military tensions with China.</p>
<p>Those tensions, sparked by Beijing's intimidating war games and missile tests in waters near Taiwan, sent U.S. dollar demand soaring and triggered massive defensive intervention by the central bank. The crisis eased measurably after Taiwan's historic March 23 election with the Taiwan dollar holding to the central bank's decade-old defence level of T$27.5.</p>
<p>Dealers attributed the latest depreciation to strong U.S. dollar demand, apparently from state or military organisations.  </p>
<p>&quot;Most dealers said the very heavy U.S. dollar demand came from other state firms or military agencies,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>The dollar's slide on Tuesday and Wednesday also reflected slowing flows of foreign funds into the local stock market.</p>
<p>Foreign funds, whose inflows had helped the Taiwan dollar to resist the U.S. dollar's overseas strength, have been net sellers in the stock market for several sessions.</p>
<p>Dealers said they noted likely intervention by the central bank in the last half hour to smooth the local unit's fall.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's very likely that the central bank orchestrated some U.S. dollar sales to smooth the Taiwan dollar's sharp fall,&quot; said another dealer.</p>
<p>Dealers said they also saw non-delivery forward selling on U.S. dollars by foreign funds in early and late trading.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rate could test T$27.65 on Thursday.</p>
<p>The central bank won praise in May by trying to engineer a Taiwan dollar devaluation, saying it was abandoning its old T$27.5 defence level to stimulate the sagging export economy.  </p>
<p>That sent the dollar sliding to within a few cents of T$28 in June, but recent months have seen it bounce back to precisely the old defence level.</p>
<p>-- James Peng (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
