<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138536" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Toyota says can keep 40 pct domestic share in 1996.</title>
<headline>Toyota says can keep 40 pct domestic share in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's top car maker Toyota Motor Corp said on Wednesday that it would be able to keep its 40 percent share of the domestic car market in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Our share (in the domestic vehicle market) should be able to reach 40 percent this year,&quot; Toyota director Kazushi Iwatsuki told Reuters.</p>
<p>Toyota's market share in 1995 was 40.0 percent.</p>
<p>The company's share in the January-September period of this year was 38.4 percent, down 0.8 percentage point from the same period a year ago, Iwatsuki said separately in a news conference on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said, however, that Toyota's share would exceeed 39 percent in the January-October period.</p>
<p>Toyota's slower domestic sales were due to sluggish demand for its current saloon models and a delay in the introduction of several new multi-purpose vehicles, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Iwatsuki, however, told the news conference: &quot;Demand for the new models which we launched this year is good and our supply cannot keep up with it.&quot;  </p>
<p>Toyota announced on Wednesday that it would start selling remodelled LiteAce and TownAce wagons later this year. This would bring the number of new models Toyota has announced so far this year to 10, Iwatsuki said.</p>
<p>This year's new models also include three remodelled luxury sedans which Toyota announced in September in the hope of lifting its share of the domestic market.</p>
<p>Nissan Motor Co Ltd, which is Japan's second largest car maker, captured a 23.4 percent share of Japan's market in the January-September period, a Nissan spokeswoman said without elaborating. -- Tokyo Equities Desk +81-3-5473-3714</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
