<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138681" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine stockbrokers cry foul on new IPO system.</title>
<headline>Philippine stockbrokers cry foul on new IPO system.</headline>
<byline>Lilian Karunungan</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine stockbrokers are crying foul over a new scheme of distribution for initial public share offerings, saying that it is a step backward on capital reforms.</p>
<p>Securities and Exchange Commission chairman Perfecto Yasay issued a memorandum on Monday requiring brokers to get their IPO allocations from underwriters, and not from the Philippine Stock Exchange (PSE) as they have previously done.</p>
<p>In case of a &quot;hot&quot; issue, brokers cannot buy shares for their own account. But in instances of a &quot;cold&quot; issue, brokers must purchase the shares for their own account.</p>
<p>Yasay said this new scheme is meant to ensure the wider distribution of IPOs. Some brokers have been accused of keeping IPO allocations under the old system for themselves instead of selling them to investors.</p>
<p>&quot;Definitely, we're not really for it. The broker is at the mercy of investment houses,&quot; said Harry Liu, president of Summit Securities and a former governor of the Philippine Stock Exchange.  </p>
<p>Market participants said those brokers that will suffer from this new ruling would be brokers with no underwriting or investment house affiliations.</p>
<p>The new scheme also loses the advantage of tapping the 177 operating members of the exchange as outlets, brokers said.</p>
<p>Under the old system, underwriters are mandated to set aside 50 to 15 percent of an IPO for the PSE depending on the size of the issue. The PSE, in turn, would distribute the issue to its members.</p>
<p>&quot;What's bad about this is that the capital of brokers would be at risk in case of a cold issue,&quot; said Noel Reyes, research head of Anscor-Hagedorn Securities, adding that brokers would now have to make a firm commitment to sell those shares.</p>
<p>Under the old scheme, brokers can just return those shares in case of a low-demand IPO.</p>
<p>Analysts say this would impact badly on small brokers who constitute the larger share of the membership of the exchange. The big brokers are a minority, numbering about 20 but they account for nearly 80 percent of trading volumes.  </p>
<p>Bourse members have been called to a special meeting this afternoon at 3 p.m. (0700 GMT) to vote on further reforms to the way the PSE polices itself.</p>
<p>Small brokers have resisted these changes but the SEC has threatened to impose them by law if the bourse fails to accept them.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
