<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138768" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Property woes hit French GAN profits.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Property woes hit French GAN profits.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>French state insurer GAN revealed a first-half loss of nearly a billion francs ($193 million) on Wednesday because of exposure to a moribund property market and raised prospects of a capital injection before it is privatised.</p>
<p>GAN chairman Jean-Jacques Bonneaud told a news conference the insurer also expected a net loss for the full year but that the figure would not necessarily reach double the loss turned in in the first half.</p>
<p>The insurer reported a net consolidated loss of 965 million francs for the six months to end- June, more than double the loss of 387 million francs at the same stage last year, and said its full-year result could suffer from more one-off charges.</p>
<p>Behind the dive was an increased loss of 799 million francs from its UIC property banking arm, which turned in a loss of 596 million last time, as well as increased losses of 988 million on property asset divestments.</p>
<p>The group's insurance business made a profit of 464 million francs after slashing the losses in non-life insurance in France and a big improvement in underlying profits from its French life assurance business.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the recovery of insurance results and good results shown by CIC, exceptional items could have a negative impact on the results of GAN in 1996,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The group is studying ways to reinforce shareholder funds looking ahead to its privatisation,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Its French life assurance business generated a profit of 425 million francs versus 627 but the figure last time round had been inflated by one-off gains of 432 million francs.</p>
<p>The CIC regional bank grouping, currently in the throes of a privatisation tender itself, contributed 472 million francs to the result, against 387 million francs in June 1995.</p>
<p>Many French banks and insurers invested heavily in property and property lending during a boom in the 1980s but have been hit extremely hard after the bottom fell out of the market in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>The government has opened a tender for a trade sale of 67 percent of the Credit Industriel et Commercial (CIC) regional bank grouping, seen as pre-requisite to the sell-off of GAN itself.</p>
<p>Societe Generale and BNP banks are the most frequently cited as possible buyers but there is considerable press speculation about the price they are willing to pay and the impact which a relatively low price would have on GAN's own preparations for privatisation.</p>
<p>GAN made a net attributable loss of 1.8 billion francs in 1995. ($1=5.182 French Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
