<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13870" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Q2 venture financing jumps 32 pct to $2.8 Bln.</title>
<headline>U.S. Q2 venture financing jumps 32 pct to $2.8 Bln.</headline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE, Calif. 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. venture capital investments in the second quarter totaled $2.8 billion, a 32 percent increase over second quarter 1995 levels, according to a Price Waterhouse survey published on Monday.</p>
<p>The quarterly Price Waterhouse National Venture Capital Survey found high technology companies accounted for two thirds of companies receiving funding in the quarter and for nearly 60 percent of all dollars invested.</p>
<p>Venture capital funding of red hot Internet companies soared by nearly eight times its second quarter 1995 level, with the number rising to 61 from just eight a year earlier.  </p>
<p>Price Waterhouse said the $2.8 billion in venture-backed investments in the second quarter of was the highest level of activity it had recorded since it began conducting the quarterly surveys two and a half years ago.</p>
<p>For the first six months of 1996, venture capital investment topped $5 billion, a rise of 38 percent above the same period in 1995. The blistering pace in the first half makes a record for the year highly likely compared with the unprecedented $7.5 billion invested last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The third quarter I would say is still up for grabs,&quot; said Kirk Walden of Price Waterhouse.  </p>
<p>A sharp downturn in the volatile technology sector on the stock market could dampen VC's enthusiasm in the second half, although many in the undustry expect a healthy number of deals in the financing pipeline to gain further funding.</p>
<p>Walden noted that startup and early stage companies accounted for some 40 percent of all companies that received venture capital and around 30 percent of all investments made by the industry in the second quarter.</p>
<p>This was considered strong, compared with average rates around the first quarter's 26 percent level, he said, and could be seen as a bullish indicator since investors were willing to take a longer period to recoup investments.</p>
<p>Silicon Valley far outdistanced all other U.S. regions in the second quarter, with 160 companies receiving funds, or 28 percent of all companies nationwide, totalling $769 million.</p>
<p>This was up sharply from the first quarter, when $497 million of investments were made in 117 companies.</p>
<p>Technology firms -- biotechnology, communications, electronics, environmental, medical instruments, computers semiconductor and software industries -- collectively accounted for more than two-thirds of all companies funded.</p>
<p>-- sam.perry@reuters.com, Palo Alto Bureau +1 415 846 5400</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150203">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
