<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138824" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German wheat prices ease under supply pressure.</title>
<headline>German wheat prices ease under supply pressure.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>German wheat sellers reduced prices as European new crop supplies were confirmed at high levels and as cheap British and Danish feed wheat offers weighed on local prices, brokers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Overnight falls in Chicago on a high Australian supply estimate added to the downward pressure with competition building among world exporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Turnover is still very thin apart from the occasional export trade enquiry for Eastern European shipment,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>&quot;European millers are not buying our bread wheat.&quot;</p>
<p>Hamburg trader Toepfer last Friday put the EU soft wheat crop at 90 million tonnes versus 80.5 million last year.</p>
<p>Brokers said that German prices should move nearer the lower European average sooner or later given such ample supply.</p>
<p>Even if outright levels were not cut sharply, sellers were unlikely to achieve monthly incremental storage fees, which they try to add from the end of the harvest onwards.</p>
<p>But prices would depend on the EU export policy, which last week offered a 6.90 Ecus a tonne rebate for 332,500 tonnes of wheat, which stemmed a price decline in France.</p>
<p>Brokers said the EU needed to award high subsidies to compete with cheaper suppliers such as Argentina and to avoid wheat flows into intervention, but this might provoke transatlcantic trade rows.</p>
<p>Free Hamburg premium wheat last traded at 287.50 marks a tonne.</p>
<p>British feed wheat was at 270 marks cif north Germany and French bread wheat at 280 marks for 1997.</p>
<p>The Hamburg grain exchange this week maintained its new crop bread wheat price (12.5 percent, 220 hagberg) at 285 marks and its spot feed wheat price free Hamburg at 275.</p>
<p>In the fob export market, 12 percent material was quoted three to five marks cheaper at 287-294 marks, 13 percent wheat was also lower at 292-302 marks and top qualities with 14 percent cost 310-315.</p>
<p>Fob barley was quoted in a 255-270 marks range, underpinned by tightness as a result of a lower harvest.</p>
<p>Domestic barley free delivered Hamburg traded little changed at 257.50 marks a tonne.</p>
<p>Fob bread rye remained at 262.50 marks and feed rye was quoted steady at 255-262 in the hope of overseas interest.</p>
<p>The November intervention price for all grains will be 230.50 marks when the buying season begins.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
