<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="138945" id="root" date="1996-10-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares open up, cheap stocks get boost.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares open up, cheap stocks get boost.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore stocks were firmer at mid-morning on Wednesday with low-priced counters getting a boost from the glitter of newly-listed shares.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a follow-through firmness from the last few days performances,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;Investors are taking a second look at these new counters and small capitalised stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>Topping the actives were mostly recently listed shares like SMB United, Advanced Systems Automation, Labroy Marine, Delifrance, Dovechem, Presscrete and NatSteel Broadway.</p>
<p>SMB United and Advanced Systems Automation topped the actives with nine million and eight million shares respectively.</p>
<p>Cheap and small-capitalised stocks, including electronic counters like Aztech Systems, Eltech Electronics and Sunright, rode on the back of better sentiment of newly listed companies.</p>
<p>At 0230 GMT, the Straits Times Industrials Index was up 15.61 points at 2,054.45. Turnover was light at 59 million shares, with gainers leading losers at 164 to 27.</p>
<p>Malaysian Resources led the gainers, rising Singapore $0.40 (US$0.28) to S$5.85. Other gainers were foreign counters of OCBC, DBS and UOB, all up by S$0.20-0.30.</p>
<p>Malaysian MISC Foreign and Sime Darby shed S$0.08 and S$0.05 respectively to S$4.26 and S$4.54.</p>
<p>US$1.00=S$1.41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
