<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139016" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SOCCER-WORRIED CAF TO VISIT NATIONS' CUP HOSTS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-WORRIED CAF TO VISIT NATIONS' CUP HOSTS.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Confederation of African Football (CAF) will send another delegation to Burkina Faso early next year amid growing concern over the country's ability to host the 1998 African Nations' Cup finals.</p>
<p>CAF press officer Viken Dzijmedjian said on Thursday that a three-man team would travel to Ouagadougou in either January or February to check on the west African country's preparations.</p>
<p>The inspection team -- CAF executive committee members Slim Aloulou and Farah Addo and technical committee member Mamadou Wade -- visited Burkina Faso earlier this year and made a report to the September meeting of CAF's executive committee in Cairo.</p>
<p>CAF released no details of the report, fuelling speculation that the Burkinabe were lagging behind the timetable to upgrade stadia and hotels for the 16-country event.</p>
<p>The last Nations' Cup finals, in January this year, were taken away from original hosts Kenya after several inspection visits by CAF and awarded to South Africa.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe host the tournament in 2000 and officials said recently their country would be ready to step in two years earlier if requested.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UPVOLA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
