<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139169" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ARXA acquires working interests.</title>
<headline>ARXA acquires working interests.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>ARXA International Energy Inc said Thursday it has acquired a two percent working interest in one major producing property and one exploitation area for an undisclosed amount of cash.</p>
<p>The company said it has an option to acquire an additional eight percent working interest in both properties.</p>
<p>It said &quot;the initial two percent working interest in the two properties will increase ARXA's cash flow. Acquisition of the additional eight percent working interest, which is planned in the next two months, will materially increase ARXA's cash flow.&quot;  </p>
<p>The interests were acquired in the West Sandy Creek Producing Area and the West Lavaca River Exploitation Area, which covers 17,000 acres. Both are located in Lavaca County, Texas.</p>
<p>West Sandy Creek's proved developed reserves are some 357,000 barrels of oil and 250 million cubic feet of natural gas, the company said.</p>
<p>The area also has proved undeveloped reserves. Thus far, 15 prospect locations have been defined and the company will drill a minimum of one prospect per month, it said.  </p>
<p>The West Sandy Creek acquisition includes a two percent working interest in the West Sandy Creek Pipeline System and its established revenue flow.</p>
<p>Based on the 15 prospects already identified, ARXA said, production on the West Sandy Creek property should increase by 50 percent to 100 percent within the next 12 months.</p>
<p>Next year, it added, several deeper prospects will be drilled and that each of these has the potential of doubling existing reserves and production.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
