<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139791" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zairean rebels say they captured eastern towns.</title>
<headline>Zairean rebels say they captured eastern towns.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean Banyamulenge ethnic Tutsi rebels said on Thursday they had captured three eastern Zairean towns and were besieging the South Kivu provincial capital of Bukavu.</p>
<p>Muller Ruhimbika, Rwanda spokesman for the Banyamulenge's People Democratic Alliance, told Reuters the rebels were joined by the Kaasai, Shaba and Katangese groups and had captured and controlled the Zairean towns of Kamanyola, Nyangezi and Bwegera.</p>
<p>The Kaasai, Shaba and Katangese have been centres of armed opposition to President Mobutu Sese Sekmo since the 1960s. They almost seized the mineral-rich Shaba region in the 1980s but were repelled by Moroccan, Belgian and French intervention.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, is receiving chemotherapy as an outpatient at a hospital in Lausanne, Switzerland, after being operated on for prostate cancer on August 22, according to Swiss media.</p>
<p>Ruhimbika said the Banyamulenge had been joined by fighters from the Popular Revolutionary Party made up of people from Shaba and Katanga regions, the National Democratic Resistance Group made up of the Kaasai tribe and the Revolutionary Liberation Movement whose fighters are drawn from Bukavu area.</p>
<p>&quot;All these parties are grouped together under the name of the Alliance of Democratic Liberation Forces of Congo-Zaire. We will effectively continue our fight against the Zairean army,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Kamanyola is ours, Nyangezi is ours and Bwegera is ours. We are now pushing the Zaireans fast into Bukavu. We will carry on hitting them and anybody who sides with them until the Zairean army withdraws from the Kivu region,&quot; Ruhimbika added.</p>
<p>He said the ethnic Tutsi rebel force was besieging Bukavu after its advances from the Banyamulenge heartland to the south and denied accusations it was receiving support from Rwanda.</p>
<p>An exiled Hutu lobby group said on Thursday Rwanda had deployed up to 1,800 soldiers to fight alongside the Banyamulenge but the Rwandan government denied the charges.</p>
<p>Aid workers said Zairean authorities closed a main border crossing with Rwanda on Thursday after accusing Rwandan troops of fighting alongside ethnic Tutsi rebels in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;We were told by the Zairean security the border with Rwanda at Gisenyi has been closed as of this morning,&quot; said an aid worker who was at a security meeting in the eastern Zairean town of Goma.</p>
<p>The Banyamulenge are an ethnic Tutsi group who came to Zaire from Rwanda at the end of the 18th century. They say they are discriminated against on the basis of language and ethnicity.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
