<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139793" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire refugee town under curfew after rebel thrust.</title>
<headline>Zaire refugee town under curfew after rebel thrust.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>BUKAVU, Zaire 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The town of Bukavu in east Zaire, tense in the face of a Tutsi rebel advance, spent a second night under curfew after Zairean troops pulled back from positions to the south in confusion.</p>
<p>&quot;We are waiting for something. We do not know what it is or why it is happening,&quot; a visibly frightened school teacher said in the South Kivu capital, where up to 300,000 uprooted Hutu refugees from Rwanda and Burundi have headed seeking refuge.</p>
<p>Earlier, anxious Zairean soldiers set up roadblocks in case of attack. Shops were closed for a second straight day.</p>
<p>In Brussels, Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo accused troops from Rwanda's Tutsi-dominated army of entering Zaire to back their kinsmen among the Banyamulenge rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;Rwanda must withdraw from Zaire. Zaire will defend its rights with all means at its disposition,&quot; Kengo said.</p>
<p>Zaire has appealed to the U.N. Security Council over what it terms &quot;external aggression&quot; in its eastern region.</p>
<p>Rwanda and Burundi have denied any link with the fighting.</p>
<p>Zaire, sprawling and chaotic, has been a powder keg since Hutu-Tutsi hatred spilled across its borders in 1994.</p>
<p>Over a million Hutus arrived from Rwanda fearing reprisals after Hutu hardliners massacred minority Tutsis there that year. Other Hutus have fled from civil war with Tutsis in Burundi.</p>
<p>Fighting between Zairean troops and the Banyamulenge flared on Friday around Uvira near the border with Burundi. More than 200,000 Hutu refugees in camps in the area took flight.</p>
<p>Aid workers reported dozens of people killed.</p>
<p>The Banyamulenge, who migrated from Rwanda late in the 18th century, accuse Zaireans of trying to force them to leave.</p>
<p>A Banyamulenge spokesman in Rwanda said they had joined forces with Zairean groups of Kaasai, Shaba and Katangese and captured three eastern towns -- Kamanyola, Nyangezi and Bwegera.</p>
<p>The Kaasai, Shaba and Katangese have led armed opposition to President Mobutu Sese Seko off and on since the 1960s.</p>
<p>The spokesman said all the 300,000 Banyamulenge wanted was the return of property stolen by troops and militiamen and the granting of Zairean citizenship, denied to them in 1981.</p>
<p>Aid groups earlier expressed fears of lack of food for the flood of refugees descending on Bukavu and its outskirts.</p>
<p>Refugees arriving in their thousands were being directed towards a camp at Nyamarengwe, about 20 km (12 miles) to the southwest.</p>
<p>Some appeared to be carrying provisions. Many had harrowing tales of their five days on the move.</p>
<p>&quot;There were women giving birth on the road. There were old men and women collapsing with exhaustion,&quot; Georges Nzohikera, a Hutu from Burundi, said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUKAVU, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
