<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="13974" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT-CSCE Dec coffee jumps to four-month highs.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT-CSCE Dec coffee jumps to four-month highs.</headline>
<byline>Clive McKeef</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE September coffee jumped to its highest level since July last year Monday, while the more active December coffee saw its highest levels in four months, on a breach of key resistance levels, news of possible damage to Colombia's coffee crop and expectations for a further fall in weekly CSCE warehouse stocks, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;September coffee led the way, with another fall in CSCE weekly warehouse stocks expected in the data due later Monday, and the break of the key $1.3000 resistance level leading to further buying,&quot; Smith Barney analyst Walter Spilka said.  </p>
<p>September coffee ended up 4.20 cents a lb at 136.50 cents, after seeing a session high at 138.50 cents.</p>
<p>The September/December spread widened to 10.50 cents, helping to lift December coffee to a four month high at 128.50 cents, before settling at 125.20 cents.</p>
<p>September coffee, which expires on September 18, and now has open interest of 2,089 contracts, broke through the key chart resistance level around $1.3000 on Thursday and Friday last week and the move was confirmed Monday, forcing another burst of shortcovering in the contract, traders said.  </p>
<p>December coffee, which has open interest of 17,836 lots, broke through chart resistance around 120.00 cents last week and tested further resistance around 125.00 cents Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>The popular four, nine and 18-day triple moving average trend-following indicator has been in an uptrend since early August for December coffee, analysts noted.</p>
<p>But the standard nine-day relative strength index (RSI) reached overbought levels around 90 pct Monday, suggesting a correction may not be far away.</p>
<p>&quot;The coffee market has surged in recent weeks, even exceeding our bullish expectations,&quot; Smith Barney analyst Judy Ganes said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The rally is based on growing fears of tightness for the September delivery period.&quot;</p>
<p>CSCE warehouse coffee stocks have been declining for nearly two years, analysts noted.</p>
<p>Certified warehouse stocks fell to 34,736 bags in the week ended August 16, down from 1.25 million bags on December 30, 1994.</p>
<p>CSCE stocks represent only stocks certifiable for delivery against the futures contract, but as of July 31, total U.S. coffee stocks were 1.909 million bags, down 252,000 bags from the previous month, a one month decline of 12 percent, according to the Green Coffee Association.  </p>
<p>New supplies of 1996-97 season coffee from Colombia and Central America will not begin arriving for several more weeks, analysts noted.</p>
<p>In news earlier Monday torrential rains and gale force winds hit parts of Colombia but there was no word yet on any damage which may have been sustained by the Colombian coffee crop.</p>
<p>&quot;Beyond the September delivery period though we question whether this market can continue to advance,&quot; Ganes said.</p>
<p>&quot;While there might not be much Central American coffee available for delivery in December, there is apt to be more coffee available then than there is now as the new crops come in.&quot;  </p>
<p>--New York Commodities Desk, +1-212-859-1641.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
