<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139843" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria debt servicing distorts H1 budget outcome.</title>
<headline>Nigeria debt servicing distorts H1 budget outcome.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria recorded a budget deficit of 6.577 billion naira in the first half of 1996, the central bank said, in contrast to an eight billion naira surplus declared for the same period last month by finance minister Anthony Ani.</p>
<p>The bank said in its half-year review of the economy released on Wednesday that the difference between the deficit and the surplus reported by Ani was due to conflicting figures for debt servicing.</p>
<p>&quot;While the federal ministry of finance recorded 22 billion naira and six billion naira for external and domestic debt service payments, actual payments in the central bank indicated 26.804 billion naira and 12.133 billion, respectively,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>But the central bank said the budget deficit represented only 0.4 percent of the gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>A key plank of General Sani Abacha's economic policy is to control budget deficits which ballooned to 70 billion naira during the administration of former military ruler General Ibrahim Babangida now retired.</p>
<p>The central bank said if debt service obligations were excluded, the government recorded 32.360 billion naira as &quot;primary surplus.&quot;</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>--Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
