<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139841" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Rwandan Hutu group says Rwandan troops in Zaire.</title>
<headline>Rwandan Hutu group says Rwandan troops in Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>An exiled Rwandan Hutu lobby group said on Thursday 1,800 Rwandan troops were fighting alongside Banyamulenge rebels against Zaire's army in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Rwanda swiftly denied the accusations, saying stunning military advances by the Banyamulenge this week were an indication of gross incompetence by the Zairean military.</p>
<p>Aid workers said ethnic Tutsi Banyamulenge fighters reached the town of Nyangezi, 27 km (17 miles) south of Bukavu, the capital of Zaire's South Kivu province on Wednesday night. It was not clear if the town had fallen.</p>
<p>Unconfirmed reports from Zairean soldiers said Banyamulenge had also seized Kamanyola and Bwegera towns, south of Bukavu.</p>
<p>Innocent Butare, executive director for the exiled Rally for the Return of Refugees and Democracy in Rwanda (RDR), told Reuters his group had accurate intelligence which pointed to Rwandan military involvement in fighting in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;We know there are up to 1,800 Rwandan troops helping the Banyamulenge fight Zairean government troops in Uvira, Nyangezi and they are now moving towards Bukavu,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Eastern Zaire has been a powderkeg since the 1994 civil war in Rwanda and genocide sent more than a million Hutus afraid of reprisals for the slaughter into the region and fuelled local rivalries.</p>
<p>Diplomats and aid officials fear Tutsi-dominated armies in Burundi and Rwanda could be drawn into the fighting, sparking a wider conflict in Central Africa's volatile Great Lakes region.</p>
<p>Aid workers said on Thursday Banyamulenge -- an ethnic Tutsi group which came to Zaire from Rwanda at the end of the 18th century -- rebels had pushed close to Bukavu on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Butare's accusations were backed by exiled former Rwandan interior minister Seth Sendashonga who said: &quot;I have no doubt whatsover in my mind that Rwanda is militarily involved in eastern Zaire.&quot;</p>
<p>Sendashonga, a senior member of the Rwandan government until he fled to Kenya last year, said the operation involved more than 1,000 Rwandan soldiers.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a well-planned operation and so far it looks like Rwanda's military objective (of strengthening the Banyamulenge and driving Rwandan refugees back home) is going to work,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Aid workers said nearly 300,000 refugees were on the move in eastern Zaire following the fighting and they faced epidemics and food shortages unless food aid arrives in a few days.</p>
<p>Butare said the Rwandan strategy was to cut off the airports at Bukavu and the North Kivu provincial city of Goma before driving over a million Rwandan Hutu refugees back home.</p>
<p>&quot;This is going to become the biggest humanitarian crisis for Rwandan refugees and we appeal to the international community to intervene to stop it,&quot; said Butare.</p>
<p>Diplomats said they had reports of Rwandan involvement in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>But Claude Dusaidi, a senior aide to Rwandan military strongman and Vice-President Major-General Paul Kagame, told Reuters by telephone from Kigali that the charges were baseless.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no truth to that at all. The Banyamulenge do not need our help to fight the Zairean army. Zaire is a country at war with itself,&quot; Dusaidi said.</p>
<p>He said military successes by the Banyamulenge were due to the fact that Zaire's army was ill-disciplined and incompetent.</p>
<p>&quot;The Zairean army is no army at all. Troops are demoralised, they have not been paid for many years and so they cannot fight. Anybody can buy a gun in Zaire,&quot; Dusaidi added.</p>
<p>&quot;Zaire should not be allowed to confuse the world about what is happening there. The Banyamulenge problem is an internal one which Zaire should address.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
