<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139999" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish 1997 budget deficit may spur debt market.</title>
<headline>Polish 1997 budget deficit may spur debt market.</headline>
<byline>Wojciech Moskwa</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish government's surprise move not to cut the 1997 budget deficit should have a limited impact on the country's macro-economic situation next year but could make its debt market more attractive, analysts said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the government unexpectedly proposed to keep the 1997 deficit at 2.8 percent of gross domestic product instead of cutting it to 2.6 percent as earlier planned.</p>
<p>Poland's economy is expected to grow between five and six percent this year and next year.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government has to find more money (in real terms), it has to offer an instrument which will be more attractive... it is possible that yields will not fall as quickly next year as they might have,&quot; said Andrzej Ladko, chief dealer at Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>Ladko said next year's budget proposal to scrap tax-benefits for Poles who purchase bonds would curb a low-cost method of financing the deficit by retail investors.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was not possible to esitmate additional inflationary pressure coming from the planned increase in the budget gap until the government made clear how it planned to raise the extra revenue, but said an impulse would be felt.</p>
<p>&quot;The increased deficit will have some inflationary impulse but there are many unknowns, such as budgetary effects of the planned decreases in income tax levels,&quot; said Slawomir Kurkowski, senior bond dealer at BRE SA.</p>
<p>The government's proposal, which the finance minister assured would be financed in a non-inflationary way, met with stiff disapproval from the National Bank of Poland.</p>
<p>The central bank said the increased deficit would boost inflation and push next year's 13 percent target out of reach.</p>
<p>Analysts said Polish debt instruments would likely remain attractive despite the loosening of the fiscal policy for the 1997 election year.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase of the budget deficit to 2.8 percent of GDP in an election year will not be a big problem and we continue to be bullish on long duration Polish risk, such as Bradys,&quot; said Arnab Das, emerging market strategist at JP Morgan.</p>
<p>Das said PDI Bradys as well as longer-term fixed zloty debt such the 16-percent two-year bonds remained attractive.</p>
<p>Analysts said the central bank's recent statements that next year's monetary policy would be restrictive to curb price growth was a sign than nominal interest rates would grow.</p>
<p>They said higher nominal rates may stimulate greater foreign investor exposure to Polish debt despite the zloty's one-percent per month devaluation rate against the basket of hard currencies.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
