<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="139949" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria suspends corporate stocks floor trading.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria suspends corporate stocks floor trading.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Securities and Stock Exchange Commission (SSEC) said on Thursday it has suspended corporate stocks' trading on exchange floors after companies failed to meet legal requirements, exchange officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission informed us that none of the public companies that have issued shares so far have not registered them with the commission under the new regulations and they are not eligible for floor trading,&quot; a Bulgarian Stock Echange (BSE) official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Altogether 19 companies with 28 issues were quoted on the SSEC exchange floors, of which four companies with 10 issues actually traded.</p>
<p>Under the stock trading law public share companies had to submit by September 19 a detailed report on the size and distribution of their capital and their shareholders to the SSEC for approval to become eligible for floor trading.</p>
<p>None of these companies has presented a report to the commission, the BSE official said.</p>
<p>SSEC officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>The RABSI's (Reuter All Bulgaria Stock Index) calculation has been suspended at Wednesday's 41.28 points until floor trading resumes, experts said.</p>
<p>Over-the-counter trading was not affected by the commission's decision.</p>
<p>The Sofia-based Sofia Stock Exchange, the country's second largest, announced on Monday it suspended daily sessions and probably would not resume trading before a planned merger with the BSE is carried out.</p>
<p>-- Dessislava Popova, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
