<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140077" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Nicaragua to review vote count in disputed election.</title>
<headline>Nicaragua to review vote count in disputed election.</headline>
<byline>David Koop</byline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nicaragua's election authorities said on Wednesday they would stop giving out presidential election results for one week while they double-checked the disputed vote count.</p>
<p>With a preliminary count of 87.48 percent of the vote, right-winger Arnold Aleman was 11 points ahead of former Sandinista revolutionary Daniel Ortega, with 49.34 percent to 38.09 percent.</p>
<p>Aleman, candidate for the populist, business-backed Liberal Alliance, has already claimed victory and most see no way his triumph can be undone.</p>
<p>But Ortega, who ruled the country during revolution and civil war from 1979-1990, has disputed the result, saying the elections were spoiled by a string of &quot;serious irregularities&quot; that may not be serious enough to overturn Aleman's victory, but should be investigated.</p>
<p>Ortega's challenge had raised fears of social unrest in the Central American nation, where voter turnout was an enthusiatic 80 percent in Sunday's elections.</p>
<p>Rosa Marina Zelaya, head of the Supreme Election Council, told a news conference the final tally would be based on electoral documents collected province-by-province by authorities. She would no longer use summaries of them sent in by radio, fax or telegram.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm going to give the last report based on telegrams, fax or radio transmission,&quot; Zelaya said.</p>
<p>The full preliminary results were not expected to be published until about a week from Thursday, she said. An official winner would be announced another week after that.</p>
<p>&quot;Work has begun but it's going very slowly,&quot; she said, urging Nicaraguans to remain calm while the agonizingly delayed count is completed.</p>
<p>Seeking to defuse tensions, radio stations broadcast throughout the day a message from President Violeta Chamorro urging people to keep a level head.</p>
<p>&quot;I ask (Nicaraguans) to maintain their calm and civility as they await the final results, which should be given by the Supreme Electoral Council as soon as possible,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Police issued a statement banning street protests while the count was taking place.</p>
<p>Nicaragua's Catholic bishops, and the jubilantly pro-Aleman business sector, criticised dissident parties for challenging the results that were declared fair, if flawed, by international observers.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be not only disrespectful to the Nicaraguan conscience, it would be a cruelty and an injustice to it, to fail to recognise this result or cast doubt upon it,&quot; the Bishop's Conference said in a communique that was a thinly veiled attack on its old Marxist enemy, Ortega.</p>
<p>The United States pitched in on Aleman's behalf, clearly relieved that its former foe had not regained the presidency.</p>
<p>&quot;With 80 percent of the votes gathered, you don't have to be a doctor in mathematics to see that the trend is irreversible,&quot; U.S. Ambassador to Nicaragua John Maisto told reporters after meeting with Aleman. &quot;For the United States, it's perfectly clear that the next president of Nicaragua is Arnoldo Aleman.&quot;</p>
<p>The Sandinistas have said they will accept the results once election officials have reviewed them based on the voting documents drawn up at each polling station, signed and validated by representatives of each political party.</p>
<p>Ortega's party lieutenants have also sought to ensure Ortega's protests did not stir violence.</p>
<p>Aleman, the portly former mayor of Managua dubbed the &quot;Fat Man,&quot; caused rapture among his followers by keeping the Sandinistas, who ruled from 1979 to 1990, out of power.</p>
<p>Besides the presidency, Aleman's Liberal Alliance looked set to win the lion's share of seats in the National Assembly -- though perhaps not a majority -- and a clutch of town halls across the country, including the capital Managua.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
