<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140014" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION - profiles of contenders.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION - profiles of contenders.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgarians vote on Sunday in the Balkan country's second presidential election since the end of communist rule.</p>
<p>Opinion polls show lawyer Petar Stoyanov, the candidate of the united opposition, ahead of his nearest rival, the Socialist Ivan Marazov, but short of a first round majority.</p>
<p>Following are brief profiles of main personalities:</p>
<p>President Zhelyu Zhelev, 61, lost a U.S.-style primary election in June and is not standing for re-election. A former dissident philosopher, he was elected president by parliament in 1990 and has led Bulgaria's transition from one-party rule.</p>
<p>He brought to his job both a folksy informality and a moral weight born of his pre-1989 struggle against Todor Zhivkov's communist regime.</p>
<p>His cohabitation with the Socialist government formed after parliamentary elections in December 1994 has been frequently stormy. Earlier this year he called for greater powers for the presidency.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Petar Stoyanov, 44, vice-chairman of the Union of Democratic Forces, defeated Zhelev in the primary, winning 66 percent of votes cast.</p>
<p>A pro-market liberal, he favours closer ties with NATO and the European Union and criticises the Socialists for avoiding a clear position on the issue.</p>
<p>He made pre-election visits to Germany and Poland where he met Chancellor Helmut Kohl and President Aleksander Kwasniewski.</p>
<p>A professional politician but untainted by the past, he offers a younger, slicker image and his speaking style is more pragmatic and businesslike than the philosophical speeches of Zhelev.</p>
<p>He has made a particular effort to appeal to young voters and has the support of Bulgaria's international soccer stars Hristo Stoichkov and Emil Kostadinov.</p>
<p>Stoyanov was born on May 25, 1952 in Plovdiv and studied law at Sofia University. He practised law in Plovdiv and became deputy justice minister in the first UDF government from 1991 to 1992, and was elected to parliament in December 1994.</p>
<p>A former volleyball player, he is married with two children. His wife is a diplomat at the Bulgarian embassy in London.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Ivan Marazov, 54, the culture minister and Socialist candidate, models himself on other East European intellectuals who became heads of state after the fall of Communism in 1989.</p>
<p>A little-known scholar of Thracian mythology, he was drawn into politics on a joint ticket with Foreign Minister Georgy Pirinski, whose candidacy was rejected because he was born in the United States.</p>
<p>He prefers open-necked shirts and sweaters to the formal wear of party functionaries, but diligently attends party rallies commemorating dates in communist history and speaks nostalgically of the low prices in pre-1989 Bulgaria and lost Russian markets for Bulgaria's lacklustre industrial goods.</p>
<p>His &quot;Together for Bulgaria&quot; campaign has the difficult task of appealing equally to the Socialists' two main constituencies -- private entrepreneurs and to older voters nostalgic for the security of the former one-party regime.</p>
<p>Born on March 15, 1942 in the village of Pirne near the Black Sea port of Bourgas, he trained as an art historian and edited a major Bulgarian art magazine during the communist regime, which collapsed in 1989.</p>
<p>Married with one child, Marazov entered politics as deputy culture minister in the first post-communist caretaker government in 1991. He headed the Art History Institute of the Bulgarian Academy of Sciences between 1988 and 1992.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>George Ganchev, 57, colourful head of the Bulgarian Businessmen's Bloc, presents himself as the centrist alternative to the UDF and the Socialists and appeals to voters for his populist, no-nonsense style and nationalist rhetoric.</p>
<p>A former fencing teacher and film screenplay writer, he polled 17 percent in the 1992 presidential election. His party usually votes with the Socialists in parliament.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Comedians Hristo Boichev, 46, and Ivan Koulekov, 45, running a satirical campaign for the presidency and vice-presidency, have won praise from voters who say they are the only ones talking sense. Televised campaign spots have included a minute's silence to mourn Bulgaria's crisis.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
