<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140007" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Moscow mazut trade sees export curbs, unsure when.</title>
<headline>Moscow mazut trade sees export curbs, unsure when.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian heavy fuel oil exports will probably be restricted through tariffs this winter, and total volumes over the soon-to-end peak export season will be flat or below 1995 levels, trade sources said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Traders are expecting a tariff, not an outright ban or quotas, but nobody knows when and how much.</p>
<p>&quot;What the government thinks and plans is always an unknown -- they don't really plan these things in advance,&quot; one trader at a Western company said.</p>
<p>Mazut export curbs are usually issued by decree from Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin after consultation with the Foreign Economic Relations, Finance and other ministries.</p>
<p>In the past, such decrees have come with little advance warning, leaving traders guessing until the last minute.</p>
<p>Vyacheslav Savin of the Economy Ministry's industrial balance department said Russia would have mazut for home and export markets, but said he had no details on possible tariffs.</p>
<p>One source said he had heard both Russia and Belarus would slap on a tariff in European currency units (Ecus) in November.</p>
<p>Fuel and Energy Minister Pyotr Rodionov told Reuters in September that an export tariff would be levied, but declined to provide details. Deputy Minister Alexander Yevtushenko said in August that the duty could be 14 Ecus per tonne.</p>
<p>One European trader said total mazut exports from St Petersburg over May-October, the peak export season, would be 1.5-2.0 million tonnes, below 1995's level.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been many small problems this year -- water levels (on the Volga River), crude oil prices,&quot; he said. &quot;But we're still seeing some healthy volumes coming out.&quot;</p>
<p>A second source said overall volumes from St Petersburg would be 25 percent lower this year. He said Russian exports would tail off in the first week of November when rivers linking refineries to the export outlet of Petersburg usually freeze.</p>
<p>Traders can count on a cold winter and high domestic demand.</p>
<p>&quot;This winter is going to be as cold as last year's and as cold as any we've seen in the past 10 years,&quot; said Viktor Trenin of the State Weather Forecasting Service (Gidromettsentr). &quot;It will increase the burden on energy suppliers, no doubt.&quot;</p>
<p>He noted the past decade had been uncharacteristically warm.</p>
<p>One trader said Russia was in a good position to meet its winter needs. But the State Statistics Committee put Russia's total mazut reserves as of October at 6.4 million tonnes, below October 1995's level of 7.3 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Russia has produced less mazut so far this year, but has also sold less on the domestic market, leaving more for export.</p>
<p>January-September mazut output dropped four percent year-on-year to 47.4 million tonnes. But mazut sales over this period on the domestic market dropped 11 percent year-on-year to 27.8 million tonnes -- leaving more to sell abroad.</p>
<p>September domestic mazut sales were half of year-ago levels.</p>
<p>Traders said St Petersburg's Oil Terminal would continue exporting heavy fuel oil received by rail when the peak export season closes, but in lower volumes.</p>
<p>Arkhangelsk, which exported mazut this year in greater volumes than in previous years, suspended exports last week over heating problems with oil product pipelines.</p>
<p>Russia suspended most mazut exports from December 1994 to April 1995 to bolster winter stocks. This year, the country faces a shortfall in tax revenues and could be tempted to levy export duties even though it scrapped them by July under a $10 billion three-year International Monetary Fund loan deal.</p>
<p>-- Lynnley Browning, Moscow Newsroom +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
