<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140016" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin aides says Russian arms sales booming.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin aides says Russian arms sales booming.</headline>
<byline>Gareth Jones</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's arms trade is booming to such an extent that other exporters, alarmed by Moscow's success at finding new buyers, are seeking a deal to carve up lucrative markets, an aide to President Boris Yeltsin said.</p>
<p>In an interview with the newspaper Nezavisimaya on Thursday, Boris Kuzik, who advises Yeltsin on military-technical cooperation, said Russia hoped to clinch several big arms deals by the end of 1996 worth around $2 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Representatives of our competitors, seriously frightened by the aggressive and successful policy of the Russian Federation in the area of arms exports, have recently suggested striking an agreement to divide up markets for arms and military technology in a number of regions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kuzik said the proposal showed that Russia was a force to be reckoned with in the multi-billion international arms industry.</p>
<p>&quot;In the arms business people only respect the strong. Today Russia is certainly one of the leading players,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Miilitary analysts were cautious about Kuzik's claim that foreign exporters hoped to divide markets with Moscow. They said Russia itself had proposed such a deal several years ago in a bid to claw back markets lost after the Soviet Union's demise.</p>
<p>But they agreed that arms sales were an increasingly important earner of desperately needed foreign currency for the former superpower.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are picking up. There is obviously a niche to be filled and Russia has a competitive edge in many areas,&quot; said analyst Dmitri Trenin of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace think-tank.</p>
<p>Russian arms exports in 1996 are expected to total around $3.5 billion, up from $3.05 billion last year and $1.7 billion in 1994, Kuzik said. Total sales this year are put at around $7 billion, industry sources said.</p>
<p>The figures are still small set against the achievements of the Soviet Union, which in an average year racked up sales of $14 billion and hit a peak of more than $20 billion in 1987.</p>
<p>&quot;The improving picture has to be set in the context of a tenfold drop (since the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991) in the amount of physical weaponry being sold,&quot; Trenin said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not talking about miracles here,&quot; he added, saying increased exports would not be enough to solve acute cash shortages in the military sector which have resulted in officers and soldiers going unpaid for months.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has expressed concern about the state of the armed forces. Sacked security chief Alexander Lebed has said there is a danger of a mutiny in the army.</p>
<p>Soviet arms sales were directed mainly at allies in eastern Europe and the Third World but Russia must now look further afield for customers. It currently sells arms to 51 countries, with India, China, Syria and Malaysia among its biggest clients.</p>
<p>This week Russia signed a defence cooperation agreement with India but failed to clinch a $1.8 billion warplane deal.</p>
<p>The state company Rosvooruzheniye is responsible for the bulk of Russia's arms sales but other firms have the right to sell arms. The producers of Russia's MiG-29 fighters were on the verge of sealing an order with a European country, Kuzik said.</p>
<p>Vitaly Nosov, chief of the foreign economic department at MiG, told Reuters the order for 12 planes would probably be signed in the near future. Officials declined to name the purchaser but defence sources in Moscow said it was Yugoslavia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
