<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140108" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Astrologer released from prison in Venezuela.</title>
<headline>Astrologer released from prison in Venezuela.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>An astrologer detained for predicting the demise of Venezuelan President Rafael Caldera was released on Thursday and said his forecast had not been politically motivated.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that among the taboo subjects is the health or mortality of the president,&quot; Jose Bernardo Gomez told Reuters in a brief telephone interview after his release.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jose Guillermo Andueza said on Wednesday the secret police were investigating the &quot;political implications&quot; of the astrologer's prediction.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a purely astrological prediction: he (Caldera) has Pluto ascending, Uranus on top of the sun, Mars reversing over his birth moon and an eclipse over the planet Quiron,&quot; Gomez said after spending two days in prison.</p>
<p>Gomez said he was kept in a small room with no bed, but insisted he was treated cordially.</p>
<p>The astrologer had told a conference on Oct. 12 that &quot;Caldera will not pass 1997.&quot; Caldera, whose second presidential term ends in 1999, will be 81 in January.</p>
<p>Gomez is president of Venezuela's astrologers association and according to followers is one of the best in his field. Among his celebrated predictions was Caldera's surprise electoral triumph in 1993.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
