<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140298" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs reach new highs in late trade.</title>
<headline>SIMEX Euroyen, JGBs reach new highs in late trade.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>SIMEX Euroyen futures were propelled higher late on Thursday as Japanese government bond (JGB) futures continued to plough upwards in bullish trade.</p>
<p>&quot;The fixed interest market has a rocket behind it at the moment. There's just no holding it back,&quot; said a trader with a European futures house.</p>
<p>He said sentiment was being boosted by indications of slowing economic growth and expectations a Liberal Democratic Party-led coalition would hike Japan's consumption tax and introduce a supplementary budget after last Sunday's election.  </p>
<p>Dealers said December JGBs rose to a new contract high of 124.52, partly on news the Finance Ministry's Trust Fund Bureau would maintain its portfolio strategy, which is heavily weighted on JGBs. The December contract settled at 124.52 against its opening 123.83.</p>
<p>The lead June Euroyen contract was quoted at a new contract high of 99.29 in late trade against its IMM close at 99.23. March was at 99.39 against 99.36.</p>
<p>&quot;The big trades today were in the March-June spread,&quot; said a dealer, adding that the market was pricing in a steady interest rate policy until next June.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's very dangerous. Three tankans will have come in by then and that's a lot of risk,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Eurodollar futures finished a notch higher after being frozen in a two-tick band on a lack of fresh leads ahead of Friday's U.S. durable goods data.</p>
<p>March ended at 94.30 against its IMM close at 94.29.</p>
<p>--Sonali Desai (65-8703090)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
