<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140291" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: N.Korea says U.S. &quot;spy&quot; doesn't know how to pray.</title>
<headline>N.Korea says U.S. &quot;spy&quot; doesn't know how to pray.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korea said on Thursday an American it is holding on espionage charges cannot be a missionary as he claims because he does not know the Ten Commandments or how to pray.</p>
<p>Pyongyang said the situation would only get &quot;gloomier&quot; if the United States, which has demanded Carl Hunziker's release, did not apologise for the incident and bring South Korea &quot;to task&quot; for employing Hunziker as a spy.</p>
<p>The United States and Hunziker's family there have denied that Hunziker, 26, is a spy, saying he was a missionary who inadvertently strayed into North Korea while on a visit to China. His family said he had been working in South Korea before his trip to China.</p>
<p>The official Korean Central News Agency (KCNA), in a report monitored in Tokyo, rejected any suggestion Hunziker strayed in accidentally or that he should be freed without punishment.</p>
<p>&quot;Not only mass media but officials call for a 'humanitarian release' of Hunziker, claiming that he went to China as a member of a tourist group, that he came to (North) Korea as a missionary residing in China and that he was drunk when swimming across the Amnok River (into North Korea),&quot; KCNA said.</p>
<p>The Amnok is also known as the Yalu river.</p>
<p>KCNA said Hunziker had no identification papers and &quot;took an insincere attitude&quot; towards the North Korean investigators.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a stark fact that Hunziker was arrested for illegal infiltration into the DPRK,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>KCNA said Hunziker was paid by South Korean security to undertake his mission.</p>
<p>&quot;Hunziker confessed that he infiltrated into the DPRK in order to spy on the situation of the DPRK such as the conditions of the army, the life of civilians, economic conditions and social environment. He himself wrote the confession and signed it,&quot; KCNA said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although Hunziker said he went to China as a missionary, he does not know the Ten Commandments, the hymn and the method of praying,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>&quot;If the United States adopts a negative attitude as now toward the spy case, far from calling the South Korean puppets to task and apologising to the DPRK, the possibility of a solution to the case will be gloomier,&quot; KCNA said.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyone who offends against the law of the DPRK will be punished under this law,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
