<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140241" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONGOLIA: Kinkel in Mongolia, pledges moral support.</title>
<headline>Kinkel in Mongolia, pledges moral support.</headline>
<dateline>ULAN BATOR 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peter Ehrlich</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel arrived in Mongolia on Thursday for a whirlwind visit and pledged moral support for the country's economic reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany is following the reforms in Mongolia with sympathy,&quot; Kinkel told Mongolia's parliament.</p>
<p>Mongolia has embraced market-oriented reforms and debunked Stalinist economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;We will support your country as good partners and friends,&quot; said Kinkel, who is visiting Mongolia for 24 hours.</p>
<p>He did not announce any new financial support for Mongolia but Germany is already one of Mongolia's biggest aid donors, giving $130 million between 1991 and 1996.</p>
<p>Kinkel is the first foreign minister of the united Germany to visit Mongolia, which had strong ties with the former communist East Germany.</p>
<p>He arrived in Mongolia after a fence-mending trip to China.</p>
<p>Kinkel's China tour had been delayed by Sino-German differences over Beijing's policies in the restive Tibet region.</p>
<p>The foreign minister had planned to visit in July but Beijing withdrew its invitation after the German lower house of parliament passed a resolution accusing China of trying to eradicate Tibet's cultural identity.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Kinkel said China and Germany had put their differences behind them and were now on a course for improved economic ties. During the visit he met with Chinese President Jiang Zemin and Premier Li Peng.</p>
<p>Kinkel also said Germany wants to set up a third China consulate in Chengdu, capital of the most populous province of Sichuan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONGLA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ULAN BATOR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONGOLIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
