<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140227" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-INTERVIEW-Miners need marketing - Normandy.</title>
<headline>RTRS-INTERVIEW-Miners need marketing - Normandy.</headline>
<byline>James Regan</byline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia-based gold miner Normandy Mining Ltd, which is looking at listing its shares on a North American stock exchange, said on Thursday that Australian miners have done a poor job of marketing their industry overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;People are shocked when you say (Australia) is the same size as the (United) States,&quot; Normandy's executive chairman, Robert Champion de Crespigny told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't sold that story well enough ourselves. We haven't had companies large enough to even see them,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>De Crespigny said the key to attracting big overseas institutions to invest in Australian mining companies was providing needed liquidity.</p>
<p>&quot;They need to have enough liquidity to get in and out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With annual output of around 1.6 million ounces of gold and a resource base of some 26.3 million ounces, Normandy is ranked among the world's top ten gold producers.</p>
<p>De Crespigny also said the Australian industry was hurting itself by taking domestic issues and projecting them internationally.  </p>
<p>&quot;The diesel fuel rebate, like native title, was a domestic issue ... Alaska is a native title issue, but you don't get the same stigma attached to it, so we hurt ourselves that way,&quot; de Crespigny said.</p>
<p>Native title has been pushed to the forefront of the Australian mining industry this week with attempts by Aboriginal groups to lay claim over land on which MIM Holdings Ltd and Savage Resources Ltd  are developing the Ernest Henry copper and gold mine in Queensland.  </p>
<p>Also earlier this year, the federal government retained a diesel fuel tax rebate worth hundreds of millions of dollars to miners but only after a hard-fought lobbying campaign.</p>
<p>De Crespigny blamed a lacklustre Normandy share price on a weak gold price while noting the stock has slightly outperformed other gold stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;It (Normandy share price) hasn't performed well ... but neither has anyone else,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Normandy shares closed one cent lower at A$1.77 on Thursday.</p>
<p>De Crespigny said gold was &quot;out of favour&quot; currently among investors, which was weighing on Normandy's share price.  </p>
<p>&quot;Gold's weak and gold's out of favor and that's the real thing that's stopping it (the share price),&quot; de Crespigny said.</p>
<p>He said operations continued to be under review at Normandy's 62 percent-owned Bounty gold mine in Western Australia, the highest cost mine in the Normandy stable, in view of the company's push internationally.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a number of projects that are touch and go whether they fit the parameters of us selling ourselves internationally and that obviously is one we've got to think about,&quot; de Crespigny said.  </p>
<p>The remaining 38 percent in the Bounty mine is held by Forrestania Gold NL.</p>
<p>Speaking earlier to the Australia-Israel Chamber of Commerce in Perth, de Crespigny said no single mine dominated the Normandy portfolio, noting seven of the company's mines produced in excess of 100,000 ounces a year.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
