<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140268" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Outgoing Thai PM cites reasons for his downfall.</title>
<headline>Outgoing Thai PM cites reasons for his downfall.</headline>
<byline>Rajan Moses</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Outgoing Thai prime minister Banharn Silpa-archa on Thursday blamed himself, the previous administration and the civil service for the collapse of his six-party coalition government last month.</p>
<p>The dimunitive Banharn, who was prime minister for only 14 months, said it was his inability to hold together his grand coalition which caused it to crumble and forced him to call fresh elections for November 17.</p>
<p>Banharn told Reuters in an interview that his battered Chart Thai party would keep its options open after the elections and did not rule out being in the opposition.</p>
<p>He said he would not take any cabinet post even if offered one in any new coalition.</p>
<p>He said weakening economic fundamentals resulting from actions by the previous Chuan Leekpai government in 1993-95 had caused a Thai economic slowdown during his brief rule and cost him his job as prime minister.</p>
<p>Banharn, accused by the opposition of having mismanaged the once-booming Thai economy and condoning corruption, was forced late last month by his own coalition allies to resign but turned the tables on them by calling fresh elections.</p>
<p>&quot;After the (last July) elections I wanted to try to see how we can combine all the various politicians into one coalition (government) like that in Malaysia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But there has been a diverse range of views within the parties and so we tried to coordinate their positions into one view, but that has been difficult,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Banharn said the civil service and its bureaucratic traditions had made it difficult for his coalition to execute decisions quickly, and this caused widespread dissatisfaction.</p>
<p>Banharn's stormy rule saw the resignation of two finance ministers, the head of the central bank and a top securities industry regulator. The opposition launched an unsuccessful no-confidence motion against him.</p>
<p>The once-robust Thai economy was hit hard during Banharn's tenure by sluggish exports and foreign investment. Economists project the economy, which had an average growth of nearly 9.0 percent annually, would slow to below 7.0 percent this year.</p>
<p>Banharn said a current account deficit that ballooned during his rule, rising inflation and short-term borrowings, as well as other economic woes, resulted from Chuan administration economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the opposition did point to the economic slowdown in Thailand, they did not discuss the underlying reasons behind it,&quot; he said. &quot;They only said we suffered trade imbalances... but did not say how or why they arose.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;To look at the reasons behind the fall in rate of exports growth, for example, one must look not only at the immediate year that went by but also at 1993/94/95,&quot; he added. &quot;On the first day I took office the rate of exports growth was already slowing down.&quot;</p>
<p>Banharn said Chart Thai, which at one time controlled 91 seats in parliament, had suffered mass defections of stalwarts to other parties after the call for elections. It would shrink to a middle-sized party now.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking now for quality rather than quantity. Although we have taken one step backward now, it is so that we can take two steps forward in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
