<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140276" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan opposition leader defends anti-nuke move.</title>
<headline>Taiwan opposition leader defends anti-nuke move.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's opposition leader said on Thursday he had to use &quot;undemocratic&quot; strong-arm tactics in a losing fight against a nuclear power plant because the island's fledgling democracy still gives the state too much power.</p>
<p>Democratic Progressive Party chairman Hsu Hsin-liang said public opposition to the controversial fourth nuclear power station project forced him to scramble for means to counter what he called the government's anti-democratic nuclear policy.</p>
<p>&quot;We knew very well that there was no way to stop that -- no democratic way to stop that,&quot; Hsu told Reuters Television in an interview at party headquarters.</p>
<p>&quot;We had to go through an undemocratic way.&quot;</p>
<p>Amid vocal and at times violent anti-nuclear protests, parliament voted on Friday to restore the US$4.1 billion power station budget that it had cancelled in May.</p>
<p>The vote sparked fiery riots in one of the worst outbreaks of political chaos to mar Taiwan's fledgling democracy.</p>
<p>Resorting to militant means, opposition lawmakers tried four days before the vote to kill the project by physically barring Premier Lien Chan from entering parliament to speak.</p>
<p>Hsu, whose party challenged martial law and authoritarian rule to champion Taiwan's democratisation in the 1980s, defended opposition lawmakers' militant tactics as justified in a system where the ruling party could prevail with a third of the vote.</p>
<p>Lien assailed the opposition strong-arming and his exclusion from parliament as a &quot;dark day for democracy&quot;.</p>
<p>Parliament had humiliated the Nationalist government in May by cancelling funding, but state utility Taiwan Power has pushed ahead with the partially built project as the cabinet formally appealed, necessitating Friday's showdown vote.</p>
<p>Hanging in the balance was U.S. giant General Electric Company's US$1.8 billion contract to supply the light-water plant's twin reactors and generators.</p>
<p>But unlike the May vote, passed by a simple majority, rules of the Legislative Yuan, or parliament, require a two-thirds vote to overturn such an appeal. The ruling Nationalist Party prevailed with its knife-edge 51 percent majority.</p>
<p>Hsu called this unfair.</p>
<p>&quot;The Legislative Yuan passed a resolution to reject the new nuclear power plant and the government tried to veto that again with one-third (of the) votes. That's undemocratic,&quot; Hsu said.</p>
<p>&quot;The position to oppose the nuclear power plant is not only supported by the (Democratic Progressive Party) but also supported by the majority of the people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The opposition leader denied the row over the nuclear power plant would hurt Taiwan's democratic development, saying such brinksmanship was unlikely to be needed often.</p>
<p>Hsu vowed to fight on against the power plant.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no need for a new nuclear power plant,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
