<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140302" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil products fall on weak crude futures.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil products fall on weak crude futures.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil products prices fell on Thursday on lower crude prices, traders said.</p>
<p>Gas oil fell in reaction to a big drop to opening gas oil trades on the London's International Petroleum Exchange. Prompt gas oil fell $5.75 per tonne to $220.00.</p>
<p>Traders said a 150,000-barrel cargo loading Nov 14-18 traded at $29.70 per barrel between a Singapore trader and a Japanese trading company, down 20 cents from Wednesday's offer.</p>
<p>November gas oil swaps traded lower within a narrow 20 cent range of between $29.65 to 29.85, down from Wednesday's close of $29.90/29.95.  </p>
<p>Traders said the gas oil market was on edge as it assessed the fall in the west. &quot;If the market in the west rebounds then prices here are not likely to fall further,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Buyers from China were sidelined in expectations of further weakness in gas oil.</p>
<p>Traders are also wary of the coming India tender to purchase for December delivery following the shut down of two floating jetties at the west coast Kandla port. India may reduce imports as its demurrage bill is high, one trader said.</p>
<p>Jet fuel remains weak with one major offering at parity to Singapore spot quotes on talk of ample supplies.  </p>
<p>Naphtha fell in line with weaker crude. A November swap was traded at $22.10 while at the day's end, levels were notionally lower at $21.90/22.05 down from $22.50/$22.70 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Gasoline was actively traded. A western trader seeking a 97-octane unleaded dropped its bid to $26.00 a barrel fob Singapore lifting November 18-22, down from Wednesday's $26.25 but a deal was later reported at $26.40.</p>
<p>Traders said a Japanese trader bought two cargoes of 92-octane at $24.30 and $24.10 fob Singapore for November 19-23 and 20-24 respectively.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-8703093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
