<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140390" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu in unity call as Israel remembers Rabin.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu in unity call as Israel remembers Rabin.</headline>
<byline>Danny Gur-arieh</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu made a call for unity on Thursday as the country marked with political rifts the anniversary of the assassination of Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin by a religious Jew.</p>
<p>&quot;The murder of Yitzhak Rabin must remind us of a basic truth: peace begins at home,&quot; Netanyahu, accused by Rabin's widow of having fostered an atmosphere of hate that led to his death, told a memorial session of parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;The choice before us today is to seal the rift and unite or widen the division and disintegrate,&quot; the right-wing leader said.</p>
<p>Israelis marked the anniversary as divided politically as they were on the eve of the murder.</p>
<p>In Tel Aviv, thousands of people streamed to the public square where Rabin was shot dead a year ago by a religious Jew opposed to his peace policies with the Palestinians. They lit memorial candles and wept.</p>
<p>Schoolchildren marked the killing in a moment of silence.</p>
<p>The murder took place on November 4, 1995, but Israelis marked the anniversary according to the Jewish calendar.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to ask your forgiveness, Grandfather. A year has passed and nothing has changed. It appears nothing has changed,&quot; Rabin's grandson Yonatan Ben-Artzi said in a speech at the official gravesite ceremony in Jerusalem.</p>
<p>Family and Israeli leaders across the political spectrum gathered at the gravesite for a state memorial. Friends and family wept.</p>
<p>At the cemetery on Jerusalem's Mount Herzl, Leah Rabin spoke on a phone moments before the ceremony began. Israel Television said it was a call from U.S. President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>But sparring between left and right continued unabated over the peace process Rabin embodied and the fate of Israeli-occupied land.</p>
<p>A procession of religious and right-wing cabinet members -- who took office in June on a platform opposed to Rabin's policies -- laid wreathes on the grave but only family members spoke at the ceremony.</p>
<p>It was in sharp contrast to Rabin's funeral last year which attracted scores of world figures, including Arab leaders drawn to the man who paid with his life for his peace policies.</p>
<p>&quot;The murder did not succeed in creating a common experience for all of the public. On the contrary, each side became more fortified in its position,&quot; wrote the newspaper Haaretz in an editorial.</p>
<p>Israel Television said on Wednesday Netanyahu and dozens of legislators had received death threats in recent weeks, including opposition leader Shimon Peres, who shared the Nobel prize with Rabin for their 1993 peace deal with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>Netanyahu defeated Peres in elections last May by fewer than 30,000 votes.</p>
<p>Rabin's landmark peace deals with Palestinian leader Yasser Arafat made the Israeli leader and former war hero a traitor in the eyes of some right-wing Jews who view the West Bank as land promised to the Jews by God.</p>
<p>&quot;There were calls of 'traitor', 'murderer' -- calls aimed at...murdering his character and in the end, spilling his blood,&quot; Peres told the parliamentary session. &quot;But Yitzhak moved forward without surrendering to the pressure, fears, zealots and threats.&quot;</p>
<p>The idea that a Jew would murder the prime minister of the Jewish state shocked Israelis but a year later left and right could not even agree on how to commemorate the assassination.</p>
<p>Israel's High Court ruled on Thursday against a petition to make the anniversary a national memorial day after right-wing legislators overruled the initiative in parliament that was put forward by a member of Rabin's Labour party.</p>
<p>Some Israelis felt the initiative was an attempt by the left to gain political mileage from the assassination.</p>
<p>Leah Rabin, said the left was always the victim and the right the aggressor.</p>
<p>&quot;No one ever fired from left to right. If shots were fired, they were fired from right to left and this is no coincidence,&quot; she said earlier in the day.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a certain style, which is on the one hand violent and on the other hand takes...violence up to a point, up to murder,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
