<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140577" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hercules approves two expansion projects.</title>
<headline>Hercules approves two expansion projects.</headline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del. 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hercules Inc said Thursday it approved two expansion projects: hydrocarbon resins, used in adhesives, graphic arts, rubber and plastics, in Middelburg, the Netherlands; and carrageenan, an ingredient in food and personal care products, in Cebu, the Philippines.</p>
<p>The company said the resins project will bring total hydrocarbon capacity in the Netherlands to about 60,000 metric tons. The company said the flexible technology allows for the production of all hydrocarbon resins, while the focus will be aliphatic C5 resins and hydrogenated hydrocarbon resins.</p>
<p>The company said the new plant is expected to start up in mid 1998 and will raise Hercules' total capacity for hydrocarbon resins to more than 175,000 metric tons worldwide. The carrageenan project will produce 2,400 metric tons at capacity using new cost-savings technology, Hercules said.</p>
<p>When completed in mid 1998, it will both replace existing production in Denmark and add 600 metric tons of annual capacity, Hercules said.  </p>
<p>The &quot;major expansion&quot; Middelburg will use flexible technology that will allow to manufacture an array of hydrocarbon resins, Hercules said. The focus will be aliphatic C5 resins and hydrogenated hydrocarbon resins.</p>
<p>This expansion will add 17,000 metric tons of annual capacity to the Middelburg plant's existing 42,000 metric tons, the company said.</p>
<p>R. Michael Alberts, Resins vice president and general manager, said the expansion fulfills the last key step in the turnaround strategy we laid out in 1991 to grow our hydrocarbons business and become a sustainable worldwide supplier.</p>
<p>&quot;Going forward, our strategy focuses on continued growth through geographic expansion, cost improvement, and technology innovation,&quot; Alberts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We also are planning capital investments in niche markets, such as resin dispersions, where we can provide added value to our customers.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
