<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140684" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - caution due to inventories.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - caution due to inventories.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bonds fell from 1/4 to 3/8 of a point on Thursday afternoon, hurt by softer U.S. Treasuries and concern about an avalanche of new issues sold this week though traders said the long-end was in demand.</p>
<p>&quot;People are cautious because they want to keep inventories rolling over,&quot; a trader said. &quot;The next deal may be priced so cheaply that your issue may be obsolete so you've got to keep it moving,&quot; he explained.</p>
<p>A pivotal $713 million bond sale on Wednesday by New Jersey Transportation Trust Fund Authority, which was priced at a true interest cost of 5.4826 percent, went reasonably well, helping to set the tone for the rest of the week.  </p>
<p>&quot;There was demand waiting for the new issues, if there was anything the hot money was going to go to, it was the new issues, which apparantly were priced to sell,&quot; he added, though he cautioned most of the deals were done as swaps.</p>
<p>The New Jersey offering drew instititional buying and traders suggested that dealers now are holding less than $100 million of these bonds in inventory.</p>
<p>Thursday's sales included almost $218 million of Chicago O'Hare International Airport Illinois revenue bonds, which were won by Bear Stearns &amp; Co, were priced at 6.125 percent in 2018.  </p>
<p>Despite the municipal market's recent losses, the nearly $4.8 billion worth of bonds slated for sale this week could have hit prices harder. &quot;I would have expected it to have dropped further,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>But concerns remained that the municipal bonds likely will underperform the U.S. Treasury market over the next few weeks as it tries to absorb additional sales.</p>
<p>The 30-day visible supply calender, which often rises in the autumn due to tax-driven trades, appears a bit high for this season, a trader said.  </p>
<p>And dealers said demand for this week's new issues appeared to be concentrated in the long-end, with the intermediate sector, say from 2003 to 2009, drawing much less interest.</p>
<p>&quot;There was some good follow-through but I think inventory is a little heaver than it has been,&quot; another trader said, though the source added that this was not a major concern.</p>
<p>Still, the market's ability to digest the supply in an orderly fashion could be jarred if a few of the new issues slated for this week and next week fare badly.</p>
<p>&quot;If a couple of deals get hung up, everyone's going to run for the door at once,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Actively quoted municipal issues included Dade County Florida Water and Sewer System Revenues of October 2025, which were bid at 5.80 percent NET, unchanged. The bonds have a 5-1/2 percent coupon.</p>
<p>And Denver Colordo City and County Airport Revenues of November 2025, were bid at 5.85 percent NET, also unchanged. The bonds pay a 5-1/2 percent coupon.</p>
<p>    --Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
