<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140688" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tisch firm lifts Gunther stake to 14.6 pct.</title>
<headline>Tisch firm lifts Gunther stake to 14.6 pct.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four Partners, a New York partnership controlled by sons of Loews Corp co-chairman Laurence Tisch, said Thursday it raised its stake in Gunther International Ltd to the equivalent of 649,189 common shares or 14.6 percent of the total outstanding.</p>
<p>In a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, the partnership said that on September 26 it bought in a privately negotiated deal 64,286 additional shares of Gunther at $3.50 a share.  </p>
<p>The partnership said it holds the stake in Gunther for investment purposes. The stake includes 494,189 common shares amd 155,000 additional shares issuable upon exercise of warrants at $6.00 a share.</p>
<p>The Tisch brothers who control the partnership are, Andrew Tisch, chairman of the management committee, Loews Corp; Daniel Tisch, general partner, Mentor Partners L.P.; James Tisch, president, Loews; and Thomas Tisch, managing partner, FLF Associates.  </p>
<p>Gunther is a Norwich, Conn., maker of high speed mailing machines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
