<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140793" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Quaker Oats food operating income drops.</title>
<headline>Quaker Oats food operating income drops.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quaker Oats Co said Thursday its total foods operating income in the third quarter was $89.0 million, down from $90.4 million a year ago.</p>
<p>Total food sales were $840.2 million, three percent above $817.3 million a year ago.</p>
<p>U.S. and Canadian foods operating income of $92.6 million, excluding a $6.4 million restructuring charge, was seven percent above last year's $86.7 million, despite a price decrease for ready-to-eat cereals, Quaker said.</p>
<p>Sales of $687.3 million were two percent above last year's $676.6 million, despite the 15 percent cereal price cut.  </p>
<p>Overall unit volume rose one percent from a year ago, as double-digit gains in hot cereals and ready-to-eat cereals, along with single-digit gains in granola bars, Canada and corn goods, offset declines in rice cakes and food service.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to have positive momentum in hot cereals with six consecutive quarters of volume increases,&quot; William Smithburg, chairman, said in a statement. &quot;Our ready-to-eat cereals business also performed very well, with a 14 percent volume gain, in an intensely competitive environment...&quot;</p>
<p>He said the value-priced bagged cereals business continues to grow at double-digit rates.</p>
<p>Operating margins expanded across many U.S. foods businesses, while Quaker held advertising and merchandising basically even in the quarter.</p>
<p>International foods operating income in the quarter was $2.8 milion, down from $3.7 million last year.</p>
<p>Sales of $152.9 million were nine percent above last year's $140.9 million, with increases in Latin America, Europe and the Pacific. Total volume for international foods was three percent below last year, due largely to a decline of sales of food in Brazil.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787  </p>
<p>A Quaker spokesman said the company's pasta business, one of its larger operations in Brazil, had a difficult quarter for competitive reasons.</p>
<p>No separate results for Brazil or the pasta business were available.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
