<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140836" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgium tries to improve image of the law.</title>
<headline>Belgium tries to improve image of the law.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium's justice minister attempted on Thursday to restore confidence in the law by promising better communication between the judiciary and the public and extra spending on its infrastructure.</p>
<p>Anger over what Belgians see as an inefficient and corrupt legal system has engulfed the nation since a child sex and murder scandal erupted in August, reaching barely containable levels last week when masses of protesters took to the streets.</p>
<p>&quot;It's important to show now that things are moving so that people have a bit more confidence in the system,&quot; Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerck told a news conference.</p>
<p>He stressed that the initiatives had already been agreed in February, before the child sex scandal broke, as part of a wider plan to modernise the legal and judicial system.</p>
<p>Since August detectives have found the bodies of four girls, who disappeared at least a year earlier, and rescued two others alive but sexually abused.</p>
<p>Families have complained of being ill-informed about the search for their missing children and not even being allowed to identify their bodies.</p>
<p>The father of Elizabeth Brichet, a girl missing since 1989, said he was taking Belgium to the European Court of Human Rights in Strasbourg asking for a law change to allow victims' families access to their case files.</p>
<p>The Belgian government has said it is looking into the matter, but Belga news agency said Francis Brichet was seeking damages at the court of one million Belgian francs ($32,000).</p>
<p>De Clerck said an extra 12 billion Belgian francs ($383 million) would be spent over the next few years on court buildings in major cities on top of the annual 1.0 to 1.5 billion francs already spent on judicial buildings and prisons.</p>
<p>Magistrates would be nominated in each district to liaise with the media and answer questions on judgements and procedures, a move which he said was aimed at making the whole system more open to the public.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim is for the contact between the judiciary and the public to be more acceptable. It is important for the image of the law today,&quot; De Clerck said.</p>
<p>Judicial bungling and incompetence in the investigation into the child sex scandal caused a storm of public outrage and fuelled theories that the chief suspect Marc Dutroux might have had high-level protection.</p>
<p>Confidence in the system ebbed to a new low last week when the popular magistrate leading the investigation, Jean-Marc Connerotte, was accused of bias and thrown off the case for accepting a free meal from the families of child victims.</p>
<p>More than 250,000 people marched through Brussels last Sunday to protest against Connerotte's removal and to demonstrate their wider discontent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
