<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140861" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU parliament debates allegations against BP.</title>
<headline>EU parliament debates allegations against BP.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Members of the European Parliament on Thursday called for the publication of a controversial Colombian government report on the activities of British Petroleum in the Casanare region of Colombia.</p>
<p>&quot;The European Parliament calls on the Colombian President to fully publish his own Human Rights Commission report on the activities of British Petroleum in Casanare,&quot; the European Union's directly-elected assembly said in a resolution.</p>
<p>The resolution, which is non-binding, urged all European oil companies working in Colombia &quot;to observe the highest standards of respect for human rights and environmental protection&quot;, and to begin talks with the local community in Casanare on a sustainable economic development plan.</p>
<p>BP has denied allegations linking the company with allegations of human rights abuse in Colombia.</p>
<p>In a statement issued after the vote in the European Parliament, it said it shared the Parliament's concern with human rights.</p>
<p>It denied &quot;any abuse of human rights in Colombia or anywhere else&quot; and said it would welcome any investigation of &quot;each and every one of these cases&quot;.</p>
<p>British Socialist Euro-MP Richard Howitt told the EU assembly he had been given a copy of the report by Colombian government officials and that it included serious allegations against BP.</p>
<p>Howitt, the only British member of the parliament's cross-party fact-finding mission to Colombia in September, said BP had denied the allegations.</p>
<p>But he said BP officials in Colombia had told him of environmental problems.</p>
<p>&quot;Weekly oil spills, water contamination, chemical overflows, illegal sites and the invasion of protected forest (were) all admitted by local BP officials,&quot; Howitt told the assembly.</p>
<p>In their resolution, the EU deputies unreservedly condemned all incidents of human rights abuses in Colombia and called on the government to stop violations by the army.</p>
<p>Richard Oliver, deputy chief executive of BP Exploration, said: &quot;We are dismayed and outraged by the number of unsubstantiated and absurd accusations made by Mr Howitt against BP and obviously believe them to be wholly incorrect, untrue and preposterous. There is no truth in any of them.&quot;</p>
<p>The assembly said it was shocked by the recent murders of the chairman of Colombia's Human Rights Committee and peasant farmers engaged in a land dispute with the Bellacruz estate.</p>
<p>It said the Bogota government should honour its promise to provide land for the farmers evicted from Bellacruz.</p>
<p>It must also allow the United Nations High Commissioner to go ahead with plans to open a human rights office in Bogota.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
