<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140825" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Husky Oil files for $500 mln in notes/debentures.</title>
<headline>Husky Oil files for $500 mln in notes/debentures.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Husky Oil Ltd said Thursday it filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission to sell up $500 million in senior notes and senior debentures.</p>
<p>The Canadian company, headquartered in Calary, Alberta, said one set of senior notes is due 2003, another 2006 and the senior debentures are due 2016.  </p>
<p>Husky said the securities are being offered as part of an overall recapitalization of the company.</p>
<p>The offering will be made through BT Securities Corp, CIBC Wood Gundy Securities Corp, Goldman Sachs &amp; Co, HSBC Securities Inc, Merrill Lynch &amp; Co and J.P. Morgan &amp; Co.</p>
<p>The company said it does not intend to apply for listing of the securities on any national securities exchanges or for quotation of the securities through an automated quotation system.  </p>
<p>The proceeds from the recapitalization are estimated to be $982.6 million, including gross proceeds of the offering estimated to be $682.6 million, the filing said.</p>
<p>Proceeds will be used for repayment of existing term credit facilities, repayment of loans and general corporate purposes, the filing said.</p>
<p>Husky is an integrated oil and gas company and its equities securities are privately held. Li Ka-Shing and trusts for members of his family indirectly hold 46 percent of the voting securities of the company, the filing said.</p>
<p>Hutchison Whampoa Ltd indirectly holds 49 percent of the voting securities and Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce indirectly holds five percent, the filing said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
