<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="140945" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PGS books record revenues in Q3.</title>
<headline>PGS books record revenues in Q3.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian seismic and offshore services company Petroleum Geo-Services ASA (PGS) on Thursday booked record revenues in the third quarter of 903.5 million crowns, a rise of 63 percent from the year-ago period.</p>
<p>The figure included 130 million crowns related to the sale of the group's two-dimensional (2-D) multi-client seismic data. Excluding the sale, revenues showed an increase of 39 percent year on year.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase in total revenues for the third quarter versus the third quarter of 1995 was primarily the result of improved vessel productivity and pricing gains, significant increases in 3-D multi-client marine seismic sales and the final sales related to the company's 2-D multi-client marine seismic data,&quot; PGS said in a statement.</p>
<p>Operating profits for the quarter jumped 45 percent to 247.8 million crowns versus 171 million crowns, while income before taxes rose to 197.5 million crowns compared with 159.3 million crowns a year ago.</p>
<p>Earnings per share were posted at 5.09 crowns against 4.06 crowns, a rise of 25 percent.</p>
<p>For the first nine months, revenues soared 52 percent to 2.15 billion crowns against 1.42 billion crowns and operating profits rose to 462 million crowns versus 298 million crowns.</p>
<p>The results fell above expectations and PGS stock surged on the Oslo bourse to an intra-day high at 236 crowns. It later fell back to close at 224 crowns, a gain of 11.50 crowns.</p>
<p>--Oslo newsroom, +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
