<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14106" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius 1996 free zone exports set to top $1 bln.</title>
<headline>Mauritius 1996 free zone exports set to top $1 bln.</headline>
<byline>Mike Chung</byline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Export earnings from the free Export Processing Zone in Mauritius are expected to reach 20.5 billion rupees ($1 billion) in 1996, a top Mauritius EPZ Association (MEPZA) official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Big customers from France and England who left Mauritius five to six years ago and went to other sources are gradually coming back to us,&quot; MEPZA chairman Francois Woo told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;They say producers in Mauritius are more reliable in terms of delivery and quality,&quot; Woo added.</p>
<p>In 1995, the Mauritian EPZ sector exported 18.3 billion rupees worth of manufactured goods, mainly clothing items such as shirts, pullovers and casual wear.</p>
<p>&quot;The tough winter in Europe also helped to boost demand for our (clothing) products this year as stocks in our export markets quickly got depleted. Mauritian book orders are full until summer 1997,&quot; said Woo, who is also managing director of leading textile producing units in Mauritius.</p>
<p>Export of textile products through the EPZ was the main engine behind the economic turnaround which Mauritius staged during the second half of the 1980s.</p>
<p>But with rapid wage increases in late 1980s, Mauritian textile products lost their competitive edge at the turn of the decade and the traditional European customers went to other countries with much lower production costs.</p>
<p>The &quot;Made in Mauritius&quot; label was recently seen attracting renewed interest from these customers as local production units improved their product quality and customers service.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not mere luck that these customers are coming back to us. Mauritian manufacturing firms have been through a sort of filtering. The non performing ones died but this is like a natural (selection) process. On the other hand, we have also witnessed the survival of the fittest,&quot; Woo said.</p>
<p>Firms operating in the Mauritian EPZ totalled 481 units at end 1995, down from an all time high of 591 in 1988, figures from the Central Statistical Office show.</p>
<p>&quot;Some years back EPZ firms were thought to be heading towards a sure death because of world trade liberalisation. But if the ones remaining continue to improve themselves, we have every good reason to be more optimistic now,&quot; Woo said.</p>
<p>He cited two reasons why EPZ firms in Mauritius are still upbeat: investments in high technology manufacturing and improved quality of products and services.</p>
<p>Woo said EPZ investments in new equipment remained erratic with an expected 700 million rupees in 1996, up from 400 million rupees in 1995, but down from 1.2 billion rupees in 1992.</p>
<p>He said a nation-wide consciousness campaign on improving product quality over the past few years also helped to improve the international image of the Mauritian manufacturing base.</p>
<p>&quot;As compared to five years back, there is no longer any need to convince people that the customer is king,&quot; Woo said.</p>
<p>Woo said Mauritius as a manufacturing base suffered from two major drawbacks: absence of raw materials that have to be imported and the island's geographical isolation, far from its main markets, resulting in high delivery costs.</p>
<p>($1=20.25 Mauritian rupees).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
