<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="141083" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Stocks fall in London, Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Stocks fall in London, Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is how major stock markets outside the United States ended Thursday.</p>
<p>LONDON - Continued worries about recent Wall Street falls saw British shares retreat below the psychologically important 4,000 mark for the first time in two weeks in another unsettled session. Since setting a new high of 4,073.2 on Monday, the market has struggled. Thursday the market ended at 3,999.4, a fall of 29.0 points with losers leading gainers nearly two to one.</p>
<p>FRANKFURT- Stocks ended bourse dealings lower, weighed upon slightly by news that the Bundesbank had left its key rates unchanged, although hopes for a rate cut had largely been dashed in advance. The 30-share DAX index ended the floor session down 21.10 points at 2,678.43. In post bourse trade the Dax stood at 2,681.94, up 3.05.</p>
<p>PARIS - French shares shrugged off Wall Street's weakness to settle slightly higher after fluctuating between negative and positive throughout the day. The blue-chip CAC-40 index finished up 0.13 percent or 2.76 points at 2,151.62.</p>
<p>ZURICH - Swiss shares closed slightly higher in listless trade, yielding midday gains after early losses on Wall Street put pressure on the market. The blue-chip SPI added 4.70 points to close at 2,409.42.</p>
<p>TOKYO - Stocks ended on a feeble tone for the fourth consecutive day, with market activity subdued by a lack of factors to steer it in a certain direction. Dealers added that most of the fluctuations during the session came from futures-linked trade. The 225-issue Nikkei average closed down 78.66 points, or 0.37 percent, at 21,003.49.</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Stocks closed down slightly after seesawing in a 100-point range throughout the day, chiefly due to futures-related trading. The Hang Seng Index closed off 18.81 points at 12,473.56, falling sharply from the day's high of 12,535.19 in the early afternoon.</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The stock market ended at a record closing high, its third record close in less than two weeks, after weak wages data heightened speculation that interest rates would be cut soon. The All Ordinaries index closed 30.9 points or 1.3 percent higher at 2,377.6.</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - South African shares spent the day skulking beneath the shadow of a dismal rand and gilts market, finishing weaker but off their day's worst. Buoyed by bullion for much of the day, golds nosed above opening levels at one stage, but as the metal softened shares lost confidence and dropped. The market was cautious and seen remaining so ahead of Friday's money supply and trade data. The overall index was off 20.0 points to 7,016.4, industrials lose 7.0 points to 8,274.4, and golds were off 14.1 points to 1,713.7.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
