<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14116" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa unleaded fuel sees slow but steady growth.</title>
<headline>S.Africa unleaded fuel sees slow but steady growth.</headline>
<byline>Lynda Loxton</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four months after the full availability of unleaded gasoline, South African oil companies are generally pleased with the growth in market penetration.</p>
<p>South African Petroleum Industry Association (Sapia) director Colin McClelland told Reuters that unleaded's market share was now just under 10 percent.</p>
<p>Although unleaded petrol was first introduced in February, it has only been available throughout the country since May and was expected to grow to between 15 and 25 percent of the market within a year.</p>
<p>McClelland dismissed speculation that the industry was disappointed with the growth in unleaded petrol sales and might press for the current four cents a litre discount on unleaded fuel to be increased.</p>
<p>&quot;Unleaded sales are not a great concern at the moment and there is little chance of a higher discount at the present time,&quot; McClelland said.</p>
<p>&quot;But if we are still at 10 percent by the end of the year, we may have to press for an increased discount.&quot;</p>
<p>Sapia initially asked the government for a five percent discount, or about 10 cents, but the government only agreed to a four cents differential between leaded and unleaded petrol.</p>
<p>McClelland said international experience had shown that this was the only way in which to encourage motorists to switch over to unleaded fuel.  </p>
<p>Further growth would depend on the rate at which new cars that can use unleaded gasoline came onto the market and the rate at which old cars were converted. New car sales have been growing at between four and 4.5 percent this year.</p>
<p>Sapia members -- Royal Dutch/Shell Group, Total SA, British Petroleum Co Plc (BP), Caltex (jointly owned by Chevron Corp and Texaco Inc ) and Engen Ltd -- invested more than 270 million rand over the last three years modifying their refineries and operations for unleaded gasoline.</p>
<p>Coal-based petrochemical company Sasol Ltd committed about 300 million rand between 1993 and 1997 to produce and market unleaded.</p>
<p>McClelland said earlier this year that it was essential that unleaded gasoline had a 20 to 25 percent market share &quot;quite quickly&quot;, after which the price differential could be reviewed as a much larger share would require further investment.</p>
<p>Most oil companies contacted, however, believed that it would take about a year to reach that level.</p>
<p>&quot;But we are quite happy with sales at the moment,&quot; one oil company official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Sapia and the Department of Mineral and Energy Affairs have agreed to meet every three months after the full availability of unleaded fuel to evaluate progress in sales. The first meeting is due to take place this Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom +27 21 25 2238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
