<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="141355" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. may have to pay utilities to store nuke waste.</title>
<headline>U.S. may have to pay utilities to store nuke waste.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>A long-simmering battle between the U.S. government and nuclear power plant owners is set to erupt next year ahead of a 1998 deadline for the government to take over their highly radioactive waste.</p>
<p>With no acceptable central storage facility in sight, the government might have to pay nuclear power plants to keep their spent fuel until the Energy Department builds a dump to bury the waste, utilities and anti-nuclear groups said.  </p>
<p>Paying utilities is one of a few options the Energy Department has in light of its decision this week to bow to an appeals court ruling that under a 1982 law the government must take control of spent fuel from commercial power plants by February 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not a whole lot the DOE (Energy Department) can do, because they don't have a place to put the waste,&quot; said Bill Magavern of consumer group Public Citizen, opponents of nuclear energy.</p>
<p>The Energy Department has said only that it was reviewing its options.</p>
<p>Reimbursing utilities for storage costs at their plants would probably entail crediting them for payments into the federal nuclear waste fund from 1998 onward.</p>
<p>About $12 billion has already been paid into the fund by consumers who get their electricity from nuclear plants. They continue to pay into the fund 0.1 cent per kilowatt hour of nuclear power generated, which was meant to cover the costs of building a nuclear waste site by 1998.</p>
<p>The Energy Department does not expect to have a dump ready before 2010, assuming its tests on Yucca Mountain in Nevada prove the site is safe for burying radioactive waste for thousands of years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I1610109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
