<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="141474" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Italian lira sags after surprise rate cut.</title>
<headline>Italian lira sags after surprise rate cut.</headline>
<byline>Julia Meehan</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Italian lira sagged on Thursday after the Italian government's surprise cut in its key discount rate on Wednesday to 7.5 from 8.25 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts had thought the central bank would wait to cut its borrowing rates until after Italy's deficit-cutting 1997 budget had passed the initial test in parliament in mid-November.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing of the cut was sooner than expected,&quot; said Sharde Persaud, economist at San Paolo Bank.</p>
<p>Persaud said the sudden cut had dented sentiment, but much of the Italian currency's weakness was due to the advance of the mighty German mark on fading expectations of further German rate cuts.</p>
<p>The lira dipped against the mark overnight to a low of 1007.10 lire against 1002.90/3.20 in late Europe on Wednesday but recovered to 1005.80/6.05 at 0855 GMT.</p>
<p>Long-term, however, the move is seen as constructive and follows preliminary data pointing to October inflation of 3.0 percent year-on-year after 3.4 percent in September and improving sentiment regarding the 1997 budget plans.</p>
<p>&quot;This will all help the Italian economy,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Improved sentiment about the 1997 budget followed an apparent deal on Wednesday night by the governing coalition on controversial plans to reform the income tax system.</p>
<p>Initial opposition to the plans had raised uncertainty about the passage of Prime Minister Romano Prodi's 1997 budget, which aims to slash the public sector deficit by 62.5 trillion lire ($42 billion).</p>
<p>Despite the short-term dent in the lira, analysts said the rate cut should help revive the economy in the longer term and ease the bloated public sector debt.</p>
<p>Italian gross domestic product (GDP), for instance, grew by 0.7 percent year-on-year in second quarter 1996 but fell 0.4 percent from the first quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth is still very sluggish, there is very low consumer confidence,&quot; Persaud said.</p>
<p>Prodi was quick to endorse the rate cut on Wednesday. &quot;It's a recognition of the validity of the work carried out by the government and a useful encouragement for the path that we still have to pursue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prodi is keen to bring the economy back into step and reduce public spending to prepare the country for its re-entry into the European exchange rate mechanism and, he hopes, for membership of the European single currency by 1999.</p>
<p>Aside from the lira, the mark was generally firmer against other European currencies on Thursday, gathering pace against the dollar and yen with the help of remarks by senior Bundesbank officials which apparently ruled out German interest rate cuts.</p>
<p>Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing on Wednesday said key German interest rates were at historic lows and nothing more should be expected or is necessary.</p>
<p>Bundesbank vice president Johann Wilhelm Gaddum also on Wednesday said current interest rate levels were correct and the central bank wanted to keep rates steady for as long as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank has led us up blind alleys before but I really don't think there's much chance of a rate move after those comments,&quot; said Peter Wood, trader at Bank of Boston.</p>
<p>--London newsroom, +4471 542 79 28</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
