<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14153" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albanian leader says left riven by dissent.</title>
<headline>Albanian leader says left riven by dissent.</headline>
<byline>Benet Koleka</byline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albania's conservative President Sali Berisha on Monday dismissed steps by his Socialist rivals to modernise their party, saying reformers had been hijacked by former communists and secret police agents.</p>
<p>Berisha said a key Socialist congress this weekend had shown that the party was riven by faction-fighting and incapable of embracing social democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The (former communist) Party of Labour with a new name could not be reformed. So-called reform was simply a clan struggle,&quot; said Berisha, whose Democratic Party won nearly all parliamentary seats in a disputed general election in May.</p>
<p>&quot;In yesterday's congress, reforming elements were replaced by former ministers of (last communist president) Ramiz Alia, collaborators and persecutors of the Sigurimi secret police,&quot; Berisha added.</p>
<p>The Socialists, heirs to the former communist party headed by Stalinist Enver Hoxha that ruled for four decades, on Sunday scrapped Marxist doctrine and officially condemned the Hoxha dictatorship in the ground-breaking congress.</p>
<p>More than 600 delegates backed proposals to help stimulate the private sector, support legitimate private business and back private ownership of land in the biggest lurch away from the left since the fall of communism in 1990.</p>
<p>Jailed Socialist leader Fatos Nano was re-elected party chief but drew criticism from some delegates for proposing that some ex-communist officials should sit on a new ruling body.</p>
<p>&quot;We condemned Ramiz Alia but then voted to the most important decision-making body some people who cooperated with him,&quot; said one young Socialist, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The new body, the 101-seat General Directive Committee, has yet to elect a secretary-general, who will effectively serve as acting Socialist leader while Nano remains in jail.</p>
<p>Socialist in-fighting will hand Berisha more political ammunition following the bitter general election and ahead of nationwide local polls on October 20.</p>
<p>Opposition parties boycotted the general election after complaining of voter intimidation and fraud. Foreign observers said the election did not meet international standards.</p>
<p>The United States and the European Union, which expressed concern over the conduct of the election, have urged Tirana to hold a fresh general election at the earliest opportunity.</p>
<p>Foreign governments have signalled that they will be watching local elections closely to ensure Albania is sticking to its commitment to democracy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
