<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="141852" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka to double power capacity, rely on coal.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka to double power capacity, rely on coal.</headline>
<byline>Rohan Gunasekera</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka plans to invest up to $2 billion to more than double its electricity-generating capacity over the next 10 years and will rely heavily on coal to meet future energy needs, an official with the national utility authority said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) will build only one new hydroelectric plant under its plan to add almost 1,300 megawatts of power to the national grid by 2006, said the official, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Plants powered by coal, diesel fuel and natural gas will provide the rest of the new capacity with coal accounting for the lion's share, or about 900 megawatts, he added.</p>
<p>Most of the new plants will be on build-operate-own or build-operate-transfer terms, the CEB official said.</p>
<p>The CEB plans first to add 390 megawatts of capacity through new diesel and combined-cycle (a combination of gas and steam turbines) plants by 1999, the official said.</p>
<p>Two, 150-megawatt coal plants are slated to be built by 2002. From then on all new power plants, providing the remaining 600 megawatts of capacity, will be coal-fired.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be all coal (after 2002) unless we go for nuclear power which is unlikely as the country is too small,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The coal-powered plants will be built on the west coast because of opposition from environmentalists to building them in the eastern port city of Trincomalee, the CEB official said.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka currently has a generating capacity of about 1,250 megawatts. Hydroelectric plants represent 84 percent of total capacity and thermial-fired stations the remainder.</p>
<p>The CEB will go ahead with plans to build a 70-megawatt hydroelectric plant in the central hills but has shelved a 150-megawatt hydroelectric plant in the same area for environmental reasons, he said.</p>
<p>Italy's Fiat Avio, a unit of Fiat SpA, is building a 115-megawatt gas turbine plant at the CEB's Kelanitissa power station to come on stream by mid-1997 while Germany's MAN B&amp;W Diesel AG, part of the MAN AG group is building a 40-megawatt diesel plant to be commissioned around the same time, he added.</p>
<p>KHD Great Britain Ltd, a unit of Germany's Klockner-Humboldt-Deutz AG is building a $62 million 51-megawatt diesel-powered plant, also expected to be commissioned by mid-1997.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka faced a severe power crisis earlier this year, with daily power cuts of up to eight hours. It was blamed on delays in building new plants.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
