<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="141989" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: U.K. doctor guilty on one NZ manslaughter charge.</title>
<headline>U.K. doctor guilty on one NZ manslaughter charge.</headline>
<byline>Victoria Batchelor</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>British heart and lung surgeon Keith Ramstead was found guilty on one of three counts of manslaughter by a New Zealand court on Thursday.</p>
<p>The foreman of the jury at the High Court in Wellington said it found Ramstead guilty of the manslaughter of an elderly woman, Nancie Muncie, on whom he performed a lung removal operation when working in New Zealand in 1992.</p>
<p>However, Ramstead's lawyer David Collins told reporters no conviction had been entered and a further hearing had been tentatively set for November 1 to address certain issues, which he did not specify.</p>
<p>It was not clear if or when Ramstead would be sentenced.</p>
<p>Ramstead was cleared of two further counts of manslaughter and one charge of making a false statement about a death. The jury failed to bring down a decision on a second charge of making a false statement.</p>
<p>Ramstead looked pale but showed no emotion as the verdicts were delivered.</p>
<p>During the 4-1/2 week trial, the prosecution alleged Ramstead failed to use the reasonable standard of knowledge, skill and care of a competent thoracic surgeon and so caused the deaths of two men, aged 50 and 74, and Muncie.</p>
<p>All died on the operating table at a Christchurch hospital.</p>
<p>Using diagrams to illustrate Ramstead's alleged mistakes, prosecutor Brent Stanaway said in his closing address on Monday that Ramstead's defence was built on his own evidence about what happened and this evidence had been shown to be both unreliable and dishonest.</p>
<p>However, in his closing address on Tuesday, defence laywer Collins said the prosecution's case was &quot;fundamentally flawed&quot; because its theories ignored facts.</p>
<p>&quot;During the course of this trial we have seen a number of experts... change their minds on very fundamental points,&quot; Collins said.</p>
<p>The 44-year-old Liverpool surgeon returned voluntarily to New Zealand to stand trial after an extradition action was started in April 1994.</p>
<p>It took the jury of six men and six women 24 hours of deliberation spread over three days to reach a decision.</p>
<p>The trial involved detailed medical testimony of numerous medical professionals for both the prosecution and defence, with often conflicting views on crucial details of the operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Rarely has a case of such complexity been put before New Zealand juries,&quot; defence counsel Collins told the court.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
