<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="141976" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>australia: Australians not racists, says PM Howard.</title>
<headline>Australians not racists, says PM Howard.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard on Thursday defended Australia as a tolerant society, but once again refused to condemn a maverick politician whose remarks have driven a xenophobic national debate on immigration.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not believe Australia is made up of a mob of bigots,&quot; Howard said in a lengthy Sydney radio interview dominated by the issue of race.</p>
<p>&quot;Australians are to be congratulated, not denigrated, for the extraordinary tolerance and decency (they) have demonstrated over the years to successive waves of migration from different parts of the world,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>Howard said Australia had the second highest population growth in the developed world in the 1980s, fuelled almost entirely by immigration.</p>
<p>But the conservative prime minister refused to speak out decisively to end a debate on immigration and race, which has heightened racial tensions and seen one town mayor call children of mixed race marriages &quot;mongrels&quot;.</p>
<p>The race debate was sparked last month when politician Pauline Hanson made a parliamentary speech claiming the country was being swamped by Asians and that indigenous  Aborigines were gaining unfair preferential treatment.</p>
<p>Howard, who in 1988 questioned the level of Asian immigration to Australia, said an immigration debate was long overdue, but called for a sensitive and tolerant discussion.</p>
<p>&quot;The immigration policy is meant to serve the interest of Australia and not to serve the interest of a particular ideology,&quot; he told Sydney commercial radio station 2UE.</p>
<p>Asked to condem independent politician Pauline Hanson, Howard said: &quot;I am not going to have this debate hijacked by responding to the speech by an independent in parliament&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We all have a responsibility to keep the damn thing in perspective...and also you don't want to turn people into martyrs...,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the process of taking the cork out of the bottle, we've got to be certain that the ratbags and the bigots...get treated as they deserve...with contempt.&quot;</p>
<p>Australia introduced non-discriminatory immigration in the early 1970s after years of a &quot;white Australia&quot; policy and Howard said the government did not intend to turn back.</p>
<p>But he said he defended people's right to free speech.</p>
<p>&quot;I will of course defend the right of any Australian to argue in a reasonable and sensitive fashion for any proposition. (But) there will always be some unreasonable and insensitive people. You will never get a perfect society.&quot;</p>
<p>Ethnic leaders on Thursday criticised Howard for failing to show leadership by not condeming Hanson and her comments.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there needs to be an unequivocal, bi-partisan appeal for condemnation against racism and for multiculturalism and immigration and indigenous people in Australia,&quot; said Angela Chan, chair of the News South Ethnic Communities Council.</p>
<p>&quot;What we've seen recently with Pauline Hanson and her like is not only a threat to our racial harmony but a blow to our political process,&quot; Chan said.</p>
<p>Recent newspaper polls have shown that more than seven out of 10 Australian voters believe immigration levels are too high, despite a government plan to cut them by 11 percent over the current financial year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
