<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142016" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Seven says interested in Optus buy.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Seven says interested in Optus buy.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven Network Ltd said on Thursday that if it were successful in its legal action against other shareholders in Optus Vision it would probably exercise its option in that outcome to buy out the other shareholders in the pay television operator.</p>
<p>Seven owns two percent of Optus Vision.</p>
<p>Asked by reporters if Seven would buy out the remaining 98 percent if given that right by the court, chairman Kerry Stokes said: &quot;At this stage, if that were to be one of the outcomes, we would probably buy it.&quot;  </p>
<p>Seven has sued Optus Vision's major shareholders -- Optus Communications with 46.5 percent, Continental Cablevision (46.5 percent) and Publishing and Broadcasting (five percent) -- claiming a breach of Optus Vision's shareholders agreement.</p>
<p>Seven argues that the major shareholders breached the agreement in August when they agreed to reward PBL for securing a joint-venture deal with former pay-TV rival Australis Media Ltd.</p>
<p>The reward was a change of terms in PBL's option agreement, which entitles PBL to increase its stake to 20 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;If we assume the court action is successful -- it depends on the judgments handed down -- the documents provide that we are able to buy the whole of the network at the lower of market or value,&quot; Stokes said.</p>
<p>He said he could not foresee an out-of-court settlement at this stage.</p>
<p>&quot;I understand that they did not wish to negotiate in a manner that I have suggested so I guess that we just go ahead at this stage,&quot; Stokes said, adding he expected a ruling next year.  </p>
<p>But, whatever the final value put on Optus Vision, Seven would be able to raise the funds needed to buy out the remaining 98 percent of the company, if that was the outcome, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't know until next year the outcome, but we do have 12 months to pay for it, interest free, so we could raise the money,&quot; Stokes added. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Business relations between Seven and Optus Vision have been strengthened, he said, adding: &quot;We have just objected to the way the shareholders have conducted themselves.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3-9286-1421</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
