<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142067" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares end mixed on profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares end mixed on profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore stock market shaved off earlier gains to end mixed on a late bout of profit-taking, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They added sentiment was weak despite a re-rating of the key electronic sector by some brokerage houses.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been no solid proof or data to show signs a recovery is near, apart from hopes the business cycle is due for a seasonal lift,&quot; a dealer with a local institution said.</p>
<p>The key Straits Times Industrials Index closed 13.16 points up at 2,059.61. Turnover was light at around 127 million shares, with losers leading gainers by 228 to 129.</p>
<p>Dealers said caution ahead of Malaysia's budget on Friday exacerbated the market's thin activity.</p>
<p>Electronic counters SMB United, Sunright Ltd and Advanced Systems Automation dominated the actives with over five million shares each. Uraco Holdings topped the list with 7.3 million shares, including one million blocked at S$0.831 (US$0.59).</p>
<p>The SES electronics index ended 0.27 points off at 81.51.</p>
<p>CityDev Ltd and Cerebos led gainers, rising S$0.40 and S$0.30 respectively to S$11.40 and S$10.10.</p>
<p>Malaysian Samanda Holdings led the losers, easing S$0.40 to S$8.60.</p>
<p>US$1.00=S$1.41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
