<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14203" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Three shares hit highs on mixed Budapest bourse.</title>
<headline>Three shares hit highs on mixed Budapest bourse.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices closed mixed on the Budapest Stock Exchange on Monday in modest turnover, which traders attributed to a lower number of investors due to market holiday in Britain.</p>
<p>The BUX index ended a shade higher at 3,359.48 points, up 2.39. BUX index futures ended mixed. Spot share turnover totalled 547.1 million forints.</p>
<p>While three of the rising shares strengthened sharply to hit new life highs, oil and gas company MOL was still in the focus after the government's announcement last Thursday to delay energy price hike to January 1, 1997 from October 1.</p>
<p>MOL which fell sharply last Friday declined far less rapidly to end at 1,565 forints, down 30.</p>
<p>&quot;The energy decision has evidently had a negative impact on MOL,&quot; said Adam Santha of Daiwa-MKB Rt. &quot;But I don't think it would weaken too much more,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition the company has announced bids to buy back employee share, so I don't think it would be a bad investment.&quot;</p>
<p>Three shares, home improvement product maker Graboplast, pharmaceutical Egis and tile manufacturer Zalakeramia hit new highs.</p>
<p>Graboplast closed at a new high of 3,850 forints, up 245; Zalakeramia ended at 6,500 forints, up 100. Egis jumped to a new high of 9,625 forints, but eased to close at 9,600, up 200.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
