<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142011" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Reef Casino looks at reorganisation.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Reef Casino looks at reorganisation.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reef Casino Trust, operator of the loss-making Cairns casino in northern Queensland, said it hired a leading merchant bank to advise on a new capital structure for the trust as well as equity-raising opportunities.</p>
<p>&quot;Reef Corporate Services (RCS) has engaged Grant Samuel and Associates to investigate and advise on the capital structure for the trust and options for raising equity,&quot; chairman John Coates told shareholders at Thursday's annual meeting.</p>
<p>Coates said this may involve variations or assignments of one or more leases and other changes to the trust's legal structure.  </p>
<p>Reef Casino was also urging the Queensland state government to cut the tax rate on junket and premium gaming to five percent from a current eight percent.</p>
<p>Trade in Reef Casino was halted earlier this month after the company announced it had made a loss of A$5.9 million for the three months to September 30 but it has been reinstated. Reef subsequently said it would be receiving a cash injection of A$6 million in two instalments from the lessee, Casinos Austria International Ltd.  </p>
<p>&quot;I am of the opinion the Reef Hotel casino can neither sustain, nor function in an operational sense to its full potential so long as there exist different operators and lessees,&quot; Coates said in his chairman's address.</p>
<p>There were different operators for the casino, the hotel and ancillary facilities as well as a trust manager &quot;each with their own overheads and at times, different philosophies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The casino licence is held by Perpetual Trustee and managed by Reef Corporate Services, owned by Touraust Corporation, itself owned jointly by Development Capital of Australia Ltd and Austzeal Pty Ltd.  </p>
<p>The casino is leased to the casino operator Casinos Austria International and the hotel, food and beverage areas to the hotel operator Australis Hotels.</p>
<p>&quot;We are committed to working with Grant Samuel to find a solution that will restore value to your unitholdings,&quot; Coates said at the meeting in Cairns.</p>
<p>Coates said RCS and Touraust had agreed to waive management fees for the balance of the current financial year, other than those required to engage any external advisers.</p>
<p>RCS and Touraust also agreed to determine a new basis for calculation of fees from July 1, 1997, Coates said.  </p>
<p>Coates said the Reef casino had lost relative competitiveness following the Queensland government's decision to halve the gaming tax rate to 10 percent for the main Brisbane casinos but only to eight percent from 10 percent for the Townsville and Reef casinos.</p>
<p>Meanwhile additional incentive programmes were under review for the international market, Coates said.</p>
<p>In addition to a Singapore office, there was an agent in Hong Kong representing the casino to the regional junket and premium market, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150203">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
