<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142121" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan Telecom to start Internet access service.</title>
<headline>Japan Telecom to start Internet access service.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan Telecom Co Ltd said on Thursday that it would launch a new computer network service, including Internet access, next year to compete with a rival service by industry giant NTT.</p>
<p>Japan Telecom's Open Data Network (ODN) will be launched next April and will provide individual users with Internet dial-up. Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp (NTT) plans a similar service in December.</p>
<p>For volume users, Japan Telecom will lay low-cost dedicated cables, which can be used for such things as computer data transmission and the construction of local call networks.</p>
<p>The service will be similar to NTT's, but the network will be priced more competitively, a Japan Telecom spokesman said.</p>
<p>Details of prices were not disclosed.</p>
<p>NTT has said it plans to charge individual users 2,300 yen ($20) a month to access the Internet for up to 15 hours a month, which is less than the cost of most other Internet access service providers in Japan.</p>
<p>Japan's Internet users often complain about the relatively high cost of surfing the Worldwide Web.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
