<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142243" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan Trust Fund Bureau to maintain JGB weighting.</title>
<headline>Japan Trust Fund Bureau to maintain JGB weighting.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Trust Fund Bureau of the Ministry of Finance (MOF) will maintain its current portfolio strategy which puts the heaviest weighting on Japanese government bonds (JGBs) for the next fiscal year, starting on April 1, a bureau official said.</p>
<p>The bureau is one of Japan's giant public funds, with massive holdings of JGBs.</p>
<p>Its portfolio held 63.63 trillion yen in long-term JGBs at the end of September, up 1.24 trillion yen from the previous book closings on March 31. It also had 5.10 trillion yen in short-term JGBs, up 829.6 billion yen from March.  </p>
<p>An official at the bureau told Reuters in an interview; &quot;A gap between (the bureau's) revenue and expenditure is likely persist in the coming fiscal year, and it will be mostly filled by investment in JGBs.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if the Bureau is willing to extend its plan to buy JGBs from the secondary market beyond December, the official said: &quot;We cannot make any comment at the moment.&quot;  But he said it was not easy to make a drastic reshuffling of the portfolio, as eligible vehicles that the bureau can invest in are by law limited to JGBs, bank debentures and yen-based foreign bonds of sovereign, quasi-sovereign or global bodies.  </p>
<p>In June, the bureau said it would resume outright bond purchases for the first time since 1993. It then said it would buy 100 billion yen worth of JGBs from the secondary market twice a month for about six month.</p>
<p>The bureau's original purchase plan will fall due in November, and the JGB market is keen to see whether it is willing to extend it, because persistent JGB buying would influence the supply-demand balance in the JGB market.</p>
<p>The official said the bureau's bond purchases are purely aimed at diversifying the portfolio and have no policy implications.  </p>
<p>Commenting on calls in the market for the bureau to participate in the JGB repo market, the official said: &quot;It would probably be difficult for us to tap the market under the current legal framework. If we are to participate, it would require approval by the Cabinet Legislative Bureau.&quot;</p>
<p>Market traders want the bureau to go into the bond repo market as a major JGB lender, after a chaotic short-squeeze in the JGB market in September that drove up the lending rate for a cash JGB bond to 32 percent.</p>
<p>At the moment, despite rising market turnover, participation in secured repo deals is still limited.  </p>
<p>The bureau also has up to 300 billion yen in cash available per year for yen-denominated foreign bonds issued via public placement.</p>
<p>There were market rumours that it had bought part of Italy's 100 billion yen 3.7 percent 20-year Euroyen bond launched on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The official said the bureau was in no rush to spend the 300 billion yen allocations, as eligible issues suitable for its portfolio are limited.</p>
<p>The bureau relies for most of its revenue on the government Postal Savings System and the public pension funds.  </p>
<p>Capital inflows from those funds into the bureau have been on an uptrend, with deposits from postal savings rising to 218.12 trillion yen in September, an increase of 6.495 trillion yen since March 31.</p>
<p>The bureau funnels massive funds to public works spending and other loans through government agencies under the Fiscal Investment and Loan Programme (FILP), often referred to as the second national budget.</p>
<p>Its cash disbursement for FILP has been falling due mainly to weak loan and investment demand, giving scope for it to buy more JGBs.--Yoshiko Mori, Tokyo Treasury Desk 81-3-3432-8676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
