<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142329" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Saudi arrests 11 people for June blast - paper.</title>
<headline>Saudi arrests 11 people for June blast - paper.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi authorities have arrested 11 people in connection with a June blast that killed 19 Americans at a military housing complex in eastern Saudi Arabia, a Beirut daily newspaper close to Saudi circles said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Saudi authorities have dismantled a sabotage network and arrested the saboteurs who planned or carried out the blast at the American forces housing complex in Dammam,&quot; al-Bayrak daily said in a brief frontpage report.</p>
<p>&quot;They are being interrogated minutely and in utmost secrecy,&quot; al-Bayrak added.</p>
<p>The paper said there was a link between the 11 suspects and &quot;elements&quot; behind a November 13, 1995 explosion that killed seven people, including five Americans, at the U.S.-run Saudi National Guard headquarters in Riyadh.</p>
<p>Three groups, the Tigers of the Gulf, the Islamic Movement for Change, and the Combatant Partisans of God Organisation, have claimed responsibility for the Riyadh blast. Four Saudis who confessed to carrying it out have been executed.</p>
<p>Saudi Interior Minister Prince Nayef bin Abdul-Aziz was closely following up the interrogation  of the 11 suspects, said al-Bayrak, whose owner/publisher Milhem Karam, head of the Lebanese Editors Syndicate, is close to Saudi officials.</p>
<p>&quot;He awaits the investigation to end to announce the names of the instigators, their plans, the executors, parties that financed them from abroad and the country that hosted their meetings,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The fuel truck bomb, which ripped through a housing complex for the King Abdul-Aziz airbase where some 3,000 Americans were based, also wounded about 400 people of different nationalities.</p>
<p>Al-Bayrak said the 11 suspects had &quot;infiltrated a licenced entity in Saudi Arabia and capitalised on the trust that this entity has, moved from within it, therefore they were not suspected at the start.&quot;</p>
<p>But it said the authority and influence of this entity have fallen after it became subject to very strict supervision.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
