<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142461" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia waits for rate cut after good wage data.</title>
<headline>Australia waits for rate cut after good wage data.</headline>
<byline>John Mair</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's share market reached a record closing high on Thursday after the second piece of economic good news in two days cleared the way to an early cut in interest rates.</p>
<p>Official statistics showed that wage rises -- seen as the main obstacle to a rate cut -- rose only 3.5 percent in the year to August, at the low end of market forecasts.</p>
<p>After news on Wednesday that consumer inflation was down to a two-year low of 2.1 percent, economists predicted a rate cut to boost economic growth and reduce unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard to overstate how good these numbers are,&quot; Bankers Trust Australia senior economist Peter Munckton said.</p>
<p>&quot;If the inflation numbers were a necessary condition for an easing, today's wages numbers were a sufficent condition,&quot; added Bruce Freeland, chief economist at Commonwealth Bank.</p>
<p>Australian markets have been getting increasingly excited about the possibility of a cut in the official interest rate, which was reduced to 7.0 percent in July.</p>
<p>Bond yields fell last month when Australian Treasurer Peter Costello remarked obscurely in the United States that Santa Claus (Father Christmas) could come &quot;this year and next&quot; -- taken as a hint that he expected a rapid rate cut.</p>
<p>But the Reserve Bank of Australia, which controls monetary policy, forced economists to revise their forecasts by warning that wage agreements were running too far ahead of inflation and productivity.</p>
<p>Costello welcomed Thursday's data, telling reporters that &quot;low inflation and moderate wage growth always brings its own rewards&quot; by easing pressure for high interest rates.</p>
<p>Industry groups were among those looking for a near-term rate cut, arguing that with low inflation achieved, a sluggish labour market and economy needed a helping hand. The RBA board next meets on November 5.</p>
<p>&quot;Following on from the CPI (inflation data), there can be no doubt that interest rates should come down and they should come down now,&quot; Mark Paterson, chief executive of Australia's Chamber of Commerce and Industry, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Bond and stocks rallied on the wages data, as markets built in a 1996 rate cut.</p>
<p>The yield on 10-year bonds closed at 7.39 percent, their lowest close in over 2-1/2 years, while the main stock market index, the All Ordinaries index, rose more than one percent to register a record close of 2377.6.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar -- which would be less attractive to overseas investors if rates were lowered -- fell around 20 U.S. cents to just above US$0.7910.</p>
<p>Asked on Thursday whether Father Christmas could be on his way again, Costello replied: &quot;Santa doesn't seem to come to adults as regularly as he does to children -- and you should not interpret the activities of Santa in a monetary sense.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
