<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142497" id="root" date="1996-10-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INTERVIEW-Changes in store for New Zealand Herald.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Changes in store for New Zealand Herald.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Brockett</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Changes are in store for the New Zealand Herald newspaper when media magnate Tony O'Reilly's flagship company Independent Newspapers Plc (INP) takes control, INP financial director James Parkinson said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Parkinson said the new owners of New Zealand's largest circulation newspaper would look to restructure their investment and may consider raising the Herald's cover price.</p>
<p>&quot;I think one would look at some restructuring, yes, but restructuring in the sense of improving the product,&quot; Parkinson told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Definitely I think the product can be improved. There are various ways that one could look at improving it, particularly I think in the business section, and as a result generate increased revenue.&quot;</p>
<p>Parkinson said once that had been achieved, INP may consider raising the Herald's cover price from the currenct charge of NZ 70 cents a copy.</p>
<p>&quot;Possibly one's got to look then at cover prices. If you have a much better product, then you get a better price for that better product,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Through a subsidiary, INP is bidding NZ$11 (US$7.70) or 1.375 exchangeable INP shares for each share in Wilson and Horton, the Herald's publisher.</p>
<p>INP and family trusts linked to principal Tony O'Reilly held 45.15 percent of Wilson and Horton prior to the bid, and with 18.14 percent of the outstanding shares acquired since the takeover was launched, INP has already obtained control.</p>
<p>Parkinson said it was important that newspapers move with the changing demographics of their country and there was room to jazz up New Zealand newspapers.</p>
<p>&quot;Initially I would have felt that in that sense the New Zealand Herald probably didn't move forward with the changing demography within New Zealand. I think at the end of the day, it's the life blood of going forward.&quot;</p>
<p>While there had recently been some reformating of the Herald, which had improved it, there was room for further development. &quot;One instinctively feels that there's a range of opportunity, but at this point in time it's hard to be categorically certain that you can do X,Y and Z,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we would feel that there is scope for revenue enhancement and therefore hopefully increased profitability.&quot;</p>
<p>He said INP would make use of its other information resources to improve the Herald, such as the Independent newspaper in the United Kingdom, in which INP has a 46 percent stake.</p>
<p>&quot;The Independent in the UK...is a very, very high quality newspaper with very high ability to accumulate international news, and we would see that as being definitely of benefit to Wilson and Horton,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But Parkinson rejected the suggestion that INP would seek to influence the Herald's editorial content. &quot;We don't interfere in editorial. We're very much newspaper proprietors and as such run the business from the commercial end of it.&quot;</p>
<p>He said INP was in New Zealand for the long haul.</p>
<p>&quot;We would tend to take a very long term view. We're very attracted to New Zealand, we're very attracted to where we see it going over the next 10, 20 years and so on. In that sense it's a very long term objective.&quot;</p>
<p>US$1 = NZ$1.42</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
