<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14287" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil CRT telecom stake attracts foreign interest.</title>
<headline>Brazil CRT telecom stake attracts foreign interest.</headline>
<byline>James Craig</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven foreign-led groups have prequalified to bid in November on a 35 percent stake in Brazil's state-owned Companhia Riograndense de Telecomunicacoes (CRT), officials said Monday.</p>
<p>The auction, the first opening of Brazil's telecoms sector to private capital, is considered by analysts to be a preview of the planned sell-off of the sprawling government-owned Telebras system.  </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Rio Grande do Sul state's energy, mines and communications office told Reuters that the groups that prequalified to bid on CRT shares consisted of companies from Asia, Brazil, Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>They include France Cables et Radio de France, GTE International Telecommunications with GTE Corp of the United States and Korea Telecom of South Korea, she said.  </p>
<p>Two others consist of Japan's Nippon Telegraph &amp; Telephone Co. with Itochu Corp and Cia Suzano de Papel e Celulose of Brazil, and Stet SpA of Italy on its own, she added.</p>
<p>Prequalified groups also include Telefonica Internacional de Espana of Spain with Brazil's RBS Participacoes S.A. and Chile's Cia Telecomunicaciones de Chile, and Sweden's Telia Overseas AB and Brazil's Partech.  </p>
<p>&quot;The company is hoping to get a strategic partner who will bring technology and capital that the state can't afford on its own,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Under the sale, Rio Grande state will sell off a 29.15 percent stake in CRT, while Telebras will shed a 5.85 percent holding.</p>
<p>A schedule for the sale said the groups have until September 16 to formalize their consortia and undergo a second pre-qualification process by September 23.</p>
<p>Due diligence is set for October, bids will be opened in November and the winner announced in early December, though no specific dates have been set, state officials said.</p>
<p>The shares are expected to be transferred on December 20.</p>
<p>-- Sao Paulo newsroom, 5511 232 4411</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
