<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142831" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - Calvo says Mexican peso not overvalued.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Calvo says Mexican peso not overvalued.</headline>
<byline>George Lerner</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economist Guillermo Calvo said on Friday he believed the Mexican peso is not overvalued, but urged policymakers to restructure the country's short-term domestic debt.</p>
<p>&quot;I see no indication of overvaluation,&quot; the University of Maryland economist, who predicted Mexico's 1994 financial crisis, said in an interview with Reuters. &quot;I don't see anything preventing the peso, if it is really undervalued or overvalued, from moving to the right equilibrium.&quot;  </p>
<p>Calvo said the Mexican authorities should not abandon monetary discipline to allow peso depreciation because such a tactic could spook the financial markets. The markets still recall in horror the surprise devaluation of December 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;My fear is that if you start tampering around with the peso, you may lose control of the peso,&quot; Calvo said.</p>
<p>In the wake of recent comments by U.S. economist Rudiger Dornbusch, the peso has lost ground in recent weeks, ending close to one full year of relative stability.</p>
<p>Dornbusch said the peso's real appreciation was leading to an overvaluation that repeated Mexico's mistakes of 1994.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the markets for any reason read any active policy a la Dornbusch as an indication that the central bank is abandoning monetary discipline, then there could be a stampede away from pesos and a devaluation,&quot; Calvo said. &quot;You could generate a crisis.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday, the Mexican currency dropped 5.3 centavos to 7.9150/7.9250 pesos per dollar amid jitters over the upcoming &quot;pacto,&quot; an agreement on economic measures hammered out by the government, business and labor leaders.</p>
<p>In the aftermath to the peso's move, overnight Cetes rates opened 125 basis points higher but later fell back.  </p>
<p>The rise in Cetes rates illustrated the main problem facing Mexican policymakers -- the potential for instability if investors lose confidence, Calvo said.</p>
<p>&quot;The instability has not disappeared because Mexico still has a large mass of short term debt,&quot; Calvo said &quot;I don't think it is major. They have the wherewithal and the instruments to control it, but not 100 percent.&quot;  </p>
<p>Should investors lose confidence for any reason, the $7.0 to $8.0 billion Cetes market could rapidly challenge Mexican policymakers. To head off any hint of uncertainty, authorities should replace short-term Cetes debt with longer-term obligations from the international market, Calvo said.</p>
<p>&quot;What they should do is restructure the domestic debt into longer-term instruments,&quot; the Argentine economist said. &quot;Ideally they should fund the instruments outside the country.&quot;  </p>
<p>Currently, the country does not face a crisis of confidence, and has dramatically improved its debt profile by redeeming about $28 billion of short-term dollar-indexed Tesobonos last year.</p>
<p>The strategy to stem peso instability by pushing Cetes rates higher has proved highly effective, but may be difficult to sustain over the long haul, Calvo said.</p>
<p>The use of higher interest rates to control the peso over a long period would both weigh on the economy and give troubling indications that the exchange rate is not at equilibrium, Calvo said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In the short-run, they are doing what they ought to do,&quot; Calvo said. &quot;In order to be able to lower interest rates, they have to restructure. Once they restructure the debt, then they will be able to afford to intervene without causing instability.&quot;</p>
<p>-- 212 859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
