<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="142807" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PacifiCorp files for new form of regulation.</title>
<headline>PacifiCorp files for new form of regulation.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>PacifiCorp said Friday it reached agreement with citizens' and environmental groups on a proposal to separate sales volumes from rates for the distribution side of the electric service business.</p>
<p>The agreement, reached between the company, the Citizens' Utility Board, the Natural Resources Defense Council, the Oregon Department of Energy and the Northwest Conservation Act Coalition, was filed this week for review by the Oregon Public Utility Commission.</p>
<p>Environmental groups and others have raised concerns that a deregulated electricity market would emphasize power sales at the expense of energy conservation.</p>
<p>Under the proposal put forward by PacifiCorp, the company could not earn a higher profit on the distribution component of its business by increasing sales, Phil Carver of the state's energy department said in a statement.</p>
<p>The agreement also sets a price cap for generation and transmission and a revenue cap for distribution.</p>
<p>Overall price increases would be limited to less than the rate of inflation, and to no more than two percent per year, with a six percent cap over a four-year period.</p>
<p>--Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
