<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143098" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: U.N. plans food airlift to Zaire refugee zone.</title>
<headline>U.N. plans food airlift to Zaire refugee zone.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>BUKAVU 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations will airlift emergency food supplies this weekend to thousands of refugees in eastern Zaire who have fled fighting between Tutsi rebels and Zairean soldiers.</p>
<p>The World Food Programme said a chartered C-130 transport plane would ferry supplies from Entebbe in Uganda to Bukavu and Goma in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>The two towns are within range of the town of Uvira, near the border with Burundi, which Banyamulenge Tutsi rebels claim they have captured in recent battles.</p>
<p>European Humanitarian Aid Commissioner Emma Bonino appealed for an end to the fighting and warned of further genocide in Central Africa's Great Lakes region.</p>
<p>Her ominous note came as Zaire accused Tutsi-dominated armies in Rwanda and Burundi of helping their Banyamulenge kinsmen to destabilise its volatile eastern region, which is host to over a million rival Hutus from Rwanda and Burundi.</p>
<p>The Banyamulenge, who migrated from Rwanda 200 years ago, blame their revolt on Zaire's refusing them citizenship and expelling them.</p>
<p>A rebel leader, saying he was speaking by satellite phone from Uvira, told the British Broadcasting Corporation they had taken the town and were cleaning up pockets of resistance.</p>
<p>A top Burundian army officer, Security Coordinator Lieutenant-Colonel Jean Bosco Daradangwe, told Reuters battles between the army and rebels around Uvira raged all day.</p>
<p>South Kivu governor Kyembwa wa Lumuna told Reuters that the town of Kamanyola between Bukavu and Uvira was in rebel hands and that rebels had &quot;taken certain positions&quot; on the road south.</p>
<p>He said Rwandan troops were fighting alongside the rebels and that some had been taken prisoner and sent to Zaire's capital Kinshasa. He denied there was fighting around Uvira on Friday. Rwanda denies its forces are involved.</p>
<p>In Kinshasa, Zaire's main human rights group AZADHO said demoralised Zairean troops had effectively demobilised.</p>
<p>&quot;The troops are expressing more and more their discontent with the total lack of logistical support, santitary structures, moral support or chain of command,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Zairean soldiers faced tactically and materially superior foreign troops, it added.</p>
<p>Many of the refugees running short of food are Rwandan Hutus who fled to Zaire in 1994 fearing reprisals for the Hutu genocide of up to an estimated one million Tutsis and Hutu moderates there, and Burundian Hutus who fled civil war at home.</p>
<p>The fighting has cut supply routes from the north and south to refugee camps in Bukavu and Goma.</p>
<p>Aid officials say Bukavu camps have six days of supplies left. Food rations to individuals were halved to extend supplies to as many people as possible.</p>
<p>U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees Sadako Ogata urged Rwandans among up to 300,000 Hutu refugees who have fled the fighting this week to consider returning home.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUKAVU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
