<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143119" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria says oil firms to build platforms locally.</title>
<headline>Nigeria says oil firms to build platforms locally.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's joint venture oil production partners will now have to fabricate their off-shore platforms and other facilities within the country, oil minister Dan Etete said.</p>
<p>&quot;Oil producing companies must now patronise specialised service companies with major local content in their engineering activities,&quot; Etete told an oil industry workshop in the mid-western town of Warri on Thursday.</p>
<p>Two months ago, the minister announced measures such giving Nigerians preference for jobs in the oil industry which he said were aimed at getting nationals more involved in the production of crude oil, the nation's economic lifeblood.</p>
<p>Most on-going oil projects in the country usually have their equipment manufactured abroad and shipped to Nigeria.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Chevron Corp's Nigeria unit, which is executing a gas gathering project on behalf of its joint venture with state oil company NNPC, took delivery in Japan of floating storage facilities for the project built in that country.</p>
<p>Etete said fabricating equipment for Nigeria abroad would not encourage industrial take-off of the African country.</p>
<p>&quot;The department of petroleum resources and NNPC have been instructed to ensure that only projects with major local inputs are approved for the joint ventures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>NNPC controls 60 percent in most of the joint ventures which are with Royal Dutch Shell Group, Chevron, Mobil Corp, Agip SpA, Elf Aquitaine and Texaco Inc.</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
