<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143171" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Rates marginally down at Kenya T-bill auction.</title>
<headline>Rates marginally down at Kenya T-bill auction.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interest rates on government treasury bills were down marginally at the Central Bank of Kenya's weekly auction on Thursday, the bank said on Friday.</p>
<p>The bank said it offered 9.0 billion shillings of treasury bills which was under-subscribed by 99.65 million shillings. But it accepted only 321.95 million shillings of bills.</p>
<p>There were 14 bids for 28-day bills of which two were successful, three were unsuccessful and nine were non-competitive. There were 298 bids for 91-day bills with 15 successful, 209 unsuccessful and 74 non-competitive.</p>
<p>The bank said that it offered an average interest rate of 23.424 percent percent for its main category of 91-day treasury bills compared to 24.090 in the previous week.</p>
<p>It offered 15.005 percent on 28-day bills compared to 15.049 percent previously. The bank offered 20.070 percent rates on the rarely sold 182-day category of treasury bills.</p>
<p>Of the amounts tendered, 30.30 million was for 28-day bills and 8.869 billion for 91-day bills, the bank added.</p>
<p>It was the first time in more than a year that the bank had accepted around one-third of what it had tendered and a senior official said that reflected its fight on interest rates.  </p>
<p>&quot;What we accepted reflects our fight against rising interest rates,&quot; said Reuben Marambii, chief banking manager at the Central Bank of Kenya. &quot;The (central) bank is determined to keep interest rates down.&quot;</p>
<p>Marambii said bids that came in had asked for interest rates of as high as 30 percent, which was &quot;ridiculous&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone is bidding high. We can't keep following that trend because that would keep swelling the speculative spirit.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What we wanted was to keep interest rates roughly where they were last week and we got very few bids there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bank does not normally indicate whether it was foreign or domestic investors that bid for the treasury bills.</p>
<p>The bank invited tenders for another 7.0 billion shillings of treasury bills to be submitted by Thursday next week.</p>
<p>($1=56 shillings).</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
