<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143292" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: New Surgutneftegaz shares will not reach market.</title>
<headline>New Surgutneftegaz shares will not reach market.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new issue of shares in OAO Surgutneftegaz will not reach the secondary market, a senior official at majority shareholder Surgut Holding (NK Surgutneftegaz) said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;These shares are necessary for (Surgut Holding) to strengthen controls over its subsidiary. They are not intended to be converted into shares of subsidiaries or for ADR issues,&quot; Andrei Serebryakov, acting head of Surgut Holding's securities department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Surgut Holding said on Thursday it had acquired an entire new issue of Surgutneftegaz shares, which raised its paid-in capital by 534 billion roubles to 5.998 trillion roubles, or 5.998 billion shares.</p>
<p>The move takes Surgut Holding's stake in Surgutneftegaz to about 43.5 percent from 38 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We intended to strengthen our control because some of the shares belonging to employees of Surgutneftegaz have already been sold,&quot; Serebryakov said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, some decisions require a much bigger stake than 38 percent or 51 percent of the voting shares. We need three quarters of the votes.&quot;</p>
<p>The new issue was not related to plans to issue level-one American Depositary Receipts later this year or early next year, he said. The company would discuss these plans with Bank of New York next month, he said.</p>
<p>Surgutneftegaz shares fell sharply on news of the issue on fears of increased supply, and concerns by existing shareholders that their stakes would be diluted.</p>
<p>Surgutneftegaz preferred fell on Thursday to $0.232 from $0.290 on Wednesday, and ordinaries fell to $0.425 from $0.462. At 1030 GMT Surgutneftegaz preferred were at $0.221 and ordinaries at $0.416.</p>
<p>--Aleksandras Budrys, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
