<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143381" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PANAMA: Haiti says Cedras still a destabilizing factor.</title>
<headline>Haiti says Cedras still a destabilizing factor.</headline>
<dateline>PANAMA CITY 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Haitian military ruler Gen. Raul Cedras and his chief of staff Phillipe Biamby continue to destabilise Haiti from exile in Panama, a leading Haitian politician said on Friday.</p>
<p>The two men &quot;are taking advantage of their (exile) status in Panama to continue destabilising Haiti,&quot; Jean Gabriel Fortune, president of the Haitian parliament's Foreign Affairs Commission, told a news conference during an official visit.</p>
<p>Cedras and Biamby left for Panama in a U.S. military plane when Haiti's military regime collapsed after the arrival of U.S. troops in 1994 to restore ousted President Jean-Bertrand Aristide.</p>
<p>Fortune said the two &quot;should be returned to Haiti for trial.&quot;</p>
<p>The Haitian government recently issued arrest warrants for Biamby and Cedras' wife Yannick, who live in exile in a wealthy neighbourhood of Panama City. They are wanted on charges of corruption.</p>
<p>Fortune said Haiti would probably seek to extradite the former leaders and their families, but he noted that Panama and Haiti do not share an extradition treaty.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PANAMA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
