<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143368" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina denies Falklands sovereignty discussed.</title>
<headline>Argentina denies Falklands sovereignty discussed.</headline>
<byline>Daniel Helft</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine Foreign Minister Guido Di Tella on Friday dismissed reports quoting President Carlos Menem as saying Argentina and Britain were secretly negotiating the sovereignty of the Falkland Islands.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish that were the case. Unfortunately it is not. Secret negotiations? Not at all, that is definitely not the case,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;The press reports are just not true.&quot;</p>
<p>Argentina's biggest newspaper Clarin on Friday quoted Menem as saying: &quot;When I say my intuition tells me there is a possibility of regaining sovereignty over the islands, possibly you will think I am crazy. But there is dialogue and conversation.&quot;</p>
<p>Argentina still claims sovereignty over the remote South Atlantic islands, which it calls the Malvinas, despite its defeat in the 1982 war that cost 1,000 lives. Diplomatic links with Britain were restored in 1989, putting the issue of sovereignty aside under a diplomatic &quot;umbrella&quot; while forging ahead in trade relations and even British royal family visits.</p>
<p>According to Clarin, Menem added that &quot;there is an umbrella, but that does not prevent us from talking about it in circumstances we obviously cannot make public.&quot;</p>
<p>Di Tella said reports in Britain of an alleged relaxation of a ban on arms sales to Argentina, in place since the Falklands War, were politically motivated to hurt Prime Minister John Major's Conservative government.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the answer to why these allegations are made,&quot; Di Tella said. &quot;If those allegations were true, I imagine this might be harmful to the present (British) government.&quot;</p>
<p>The British media has reported recently that London secretly agreed to help re-equip Argentine Navy warships in contravention of the arms embargo.</p>
<p>But Di Tella lashed out at Britain for maintaining the embargo so long after the conflict ended and seven years after diplomatic relations between the two countries were restored. &quot;It is preposterous that after 14 years we have this embargo and relaxation is not in sight,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>He noted, however, that progress was being made on the issue of cooperation in oil and gas exploration around the Falklands. &quot;It is a good aspect of the relationship,&quot; he said. &quot;In the next few weeks we will have some news regarding oil licenses and that will be a very, very important step.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FALK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
