<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143412" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru govt has legislative powers extended 15 days.</title>
<headline>Peru govt has legislative powers extended 15 days.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Peruvian Congress granted late Thursday a 15-day extension to the government's special legislative powers to allow decrees on the modernization of the public sector and company taxes, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We were coming to the end of the (special legislative) period already granted by Congress,&quot; said Justice Minister Carlos Hermoza Moya on local radio. &quot;We are still finishing the details on a few things that remain to be done, especially in relation to the modernization of the state, the question of company taxes and a series of important aspects that could not be finished today or tomorrow.&quot;  </p>
<p>The government's powers -- already extended once by Congress -- were set to expire October 26 after 120 days, during which the executive has produced a wide range of political, economic and financial legislation.</p>
<p>During the latest month-long extension, the government issued decrees on regulations covering the local stock market and investment funds.</p>
<p>Hermoza rejected claims that the government was taking over the role of Congress, where it has a comfortable majority.</p>
<p>But he said the government had been able to decree laws &quot;without very long debates in Congress that take up a lot of time before producing a legal measure.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Saul Hudson, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
