<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143534" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore shares close firmer, upside seen capped.</title>
<headline>Singapore shares close firmer, upside seen capped.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore stock market ended up on technicals on Friday with small-capitalised stocks dominating the actives, dealers said. They added the upside was capped by lacklustre economic fundamentals.</p>
<p>After opening at 2,061.51, the key Straits Times Industrials Index ended at 2,077.20, up 17.59 points.</p>
<p>The bulk of the gains in the index was generated by Cerebos Pacific, Fraser &amp; Neave and Keppel which rose S$0.50, S$0.30 and S$0.10 respectively, albeit in light volumes.</p>
<p>Turnover was light at around 108 million shares, with gainers leading losers at 173 to 143.  </p>
<p>Dealers said there was some nibbling of selected blue-chips by institutions. The UOB blue-chip index rose 6.92 points to end at 895.86. Retailers stayed keen on small-capitalised stocks like Venture, Labroy Marine and Uraco Holdings, all of which topped the actives. Venture saw 7.8 million shares traded, including 7.4 million crossed in the morning at S$2.55.</p>
<p>Foreign counters of SIA Ltd and Singapore Press rose S$0.70 each to S$14.00 and S$24.90. Bukit Sembawang Estate fell S$0.50 to S$33.00. Dealers said Malaysia's budget announcements made little impact. The UOB OTC index which tracks Malaysian shares here ended 2.40 points off at 1,201.97.--Angela Tan (65 8703083)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
