<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143758" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Okla. City bomb defendants to be tried separately.</title>
<headline>Okla. City bomb defendants to be tried separately.</headline>
<byline>Judith Crosson</byline>
<dateline>DENVER 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A judge handed the two defendants in the Oklahoma City bombing trial a major victory on Friday by ordering separate trials for them, saying it was the only way to provide a fair hearing.</p>
<p>U.S. District Court Judge Richard Matsch also ordered that Timothy McVeigh be tried before co-defendant Terry Nichols.</p>
<p>&quot;A joint trial of these defendants presents such an unacceptable risk of prejudice to both of them as to require separate trials,&quot; Matsch said in a 20-page decision.</p>
<p>McVeigh and Nichols, former U.S. Army buddies, are accused of the April 19, 1995 bombing of the Alfred P. Murrah federal building in Oklahoma City which killed 168 people and injured about 500.</p>
<p>Both defendants urged the judge to grant separate trials because, they said, their defences would be based in part on pointing the finger of blame at each other.</p>
<p>Their attorneys argued earlier this month in a pre-trial hearing that, in a sense, each defence lawyer would become a second prosecutor in the courtroom and that this would be unfair to the defendants.</p>
<p>McVeigh's attorney Stephen Jones said the decision &quot;clears the underbrush&quot; and will allow him to focus on the facts to be presented at the actual trial.</p>
<p>The trial was moved to Denver because it was deemed virtually impossible to grant the two men a fair hearing anywhere in the state of Oklahoma.</p>
<p>The Nichols statements were made in Herington, Kansas, during a nine-hour session with authorities. They remain under seal and can only be used against Nichols and not McVeigh, Matsch previously ruled. However, Nichols mentioned McVeigh's name more than 60 times, McVeigh's lawyers have said.</p>
<p>Also, Nichols is not expected to take the stand, which would prevent McVeigh's attorneys from cross-examining him.</p>
<p>The judge said such an outcome would prevent McVeigh from exercising his right under the Sixth Amendment to the U.S. Constitution to confront witnesses against him.</p>
<p>A University of Colorado law professor and former federal prosecutor, Mimi Wesson, said Matsch's decision &quot;was almost inevitable&quot; because of a 1968 Supreme Court decision that reinforced a defendant's right to confront an accuser.</p>
<p>Prosecutors opposed the defence motion for separate trials, saying that trying the two men together would provide a jury with a full picture of the crime.</p>
<p>After Friday's ruling, one of the government attorneys, Larry Mackey, said, &quot;It's time to get the facts before a jury and we are prepared to move forward.&quot;</p>
<p>Prosecutors also had argued a single trial would cause less pain to survivors and relatives of the blast victims.</p>
<p>No dates had been set for the trials pending settlement of the issue of separate trials.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DENVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
