<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143732" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jackie O's childhood farm up for sale.</title>
<headline>Jackie O's childhood farm up for sale.</headline>
<dateline>NEWPORT, R.I. 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>For all those who missed the auction, another property associated with Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis is on the block. Price tag -- $7.95 million.</p>
<p>The oceanfront Newport, Rhode Island farm where Onassis spent her summers as a teen-ager, site of the wedding reception when she married John F. Kennedy, has recently received several firm offers, a realtor said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been up (for sale) for about a year and two or three months. We've got one offer right now that is receiving consideration and we expect a few other offers coming in,&quot; said Neal Balboni, listing agent for Natick, Massachusetts-based Burr Associates.</p>
<p>The 48-acre (19.4 hectare) Hammersmith Farm, formerly owned by Onassis' step-father Hugh Auchincloss, is &quot;a classic, turn-of-the-century, shingle-style home,&quot; Balboni said.</p>
<p>The farm, with a 28-room summer house, stables, and a children's playhouse now run as a shop, is owned by a group of Massachusetts business people. It is open to the public as a tourist site and hosts about 100,000 visitors annually.</p>
<p>Most of the contents of the house are included in the price but few belonged to Onassis, who died in 1994. A Sotheby's auction of her belongings in April, called the celebrity sale of the century, raised $34.5 million as her admirers paid thousands for everything from pillows, books and furniture to fake and valuable jewelery.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWPORT, R.I."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
