<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143739" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Battle for swing district in Missouri.</title>
<headline>Battle for swing district in Missouri.</headline>
<byline>Shera Dalin</byline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican Representative Jim Talent is seeking a third term in a contest that has become a test of his all-out backing for Speaker Newt Gingrich and another target for Democrats hoping to turn over enough seats to win back control of the House.</p>
<p>The race is in the St. Louis area's Second Congressional District, where voters have tossed out incumbents three times in the last 10 years. Although remapping in 1990 gave the district a Republican tinge, many of its voters are still considered unpredictable.</p>
<p>The Democratic candidate is Joan Kelley Horn, who upset a Republican incumbent in 1990 by 54 votes in the closest federal election that year. She lost out to Talent two years later by about 9,000 votes and did not run in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one of the true swing districts in the United States Congress in recent memory,&quot; said Steven Puro, a political science professor at St. Louis University.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a good amount of conservative Democrats in the swing portion of this district, what we might call Reagan Democrats. The question is will they vote on economic issues or family issues.&quot;</p>
<p>Talent, 39, is a labour-management lawyer who has campaigned on a straight-up Republican platform: cutting the capital gains tax, strict welfare requirements, reforming Washington, a balanced budget amendment and term limits.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing we could do is cut the capital gains tax,&quot; he said. &quot;That creates jobs and economic growth. In past Congresses it wasn't even on the agenda.&quot;</p>
<p>A firm supporter of Republican policies that swept his party into control of the House and Senate two years ago, he proposed one of the most restrictive welfare bills introduced in the House.</p>
<p>Horn, a 59-year-old moderate who has allied herself with President Clinton, agrees the capital gains tax should be cut but opposes an across-the-board slash. Her campaign has emphasised money for college loans, backing for the Americorps programme, a balanced budged, environmental protection and funding for Headstart programmes and drug-free school projects.</p>
<p>The district covers wealthy St. Louis suburbs such as Ladue and working class neighbourhoods such as Florissant. It is one of the areas across the country that will test the Republicans' abiity to maintain their 235-198 House majority.</p>
<p>Puro said economic concerns were the &quot;make or break issue&quot; of the campaign. &quot;Perhaps the key group in this election will be the voters 35 to 50 years old, married, with some children and dual incomes. It is probably the most undecided bloc.&quot;</p>
<p>Talent has raised nearly $865,000 in the last 20 months and spent $445,000. He still has more than $600,000 on hand, about three times more than Horn, who has raised more than $250,000 since April and spent about $76,000, acccording to the Federal Election Commission.</p>
<p>The St. Louis Post-Dispatch, endorsing Horn this month, said Talent &quot;stands too far to the right on most of the important issues ... he supported extreme Republican proposals for cutting back on environmental protection; he opposed gun control and the crime bill that put more police on the streets.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
