<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143886" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Epidemics flourish as defences weaken - agencies.</title>
<headline>Epidemics flourish as defences weaken - agencies.</headline>
<byline>John Follain</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Health agencies warned on Friday that epidemics including cholera, sleeping sickness and meningitis were breaking out more and more frequently while their means of fighting back were inadequate.</p>
<p>Experts at a Paris medical conference organised by Medecins Sans Frontieres (Doctors Without Borders) said pharmaceutical companies were at least partly to blame but added there was often no political will to tackle such outbreaks.</p>
<p>&quot;Epidemics like cholera, sleeping sickness and meningitis are increasingly frequent and the means to control them are extremely limited,&quot; MSF president Philippe Biberson told Reuters at the conference, called to mark the group's 25th anniversary.</p>
<p>&quot;Meningitis affected 400,000 people in Africa last year, at least 10,000 people died. But this did not prompt enough interest worldwide,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Representatives from the World Health Organisation (WHO), UNICEF, research laboratories and other agencies said that in many cases medication or vaccines were not available in large enough supplies or were too costly to be used on a large scale.</p>
<p>In July 1994, cholera among Rwandan refugees who had fled to camps at Goma, Zaire, affected more than 60,000 people and killed more than 10,000 in a few weeks, Dr Christophe Paquet of the Paris-based Epicentre research group said.</p>
<p>&quot;Pre-emptive treatment has to be the cornerstone of dealing with cholera. But the new WC-BS killed vaccine is still not available today for large-scale mass campaigns,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Many of the newer vaccines being developed by scientists use genetic or molecular biology technology that is far more expensive than older vaccines that cost a few cents a dose.</p>
<p>Vaccine development also occurs mainly in the private sector in industrialised countries and these vaccines may not work as well against the slightly different strains of diseases in poorer countries, where the market is not as profitable for drug companies.</p>
<p>Biberson said that for meningitis, health workers had yet to set up adequate detection systems, and efficient vaccines were not yet sufficiently available.</p>
<p>Medicine available for treating sleeping sickness, which has resurfaced after a lull of more than a decade, date from 40 to 50 years ago. One of them contains arsenic and is thus toxic and difficult to administer.</p>
<p>&quot;To fight sleeping sickness, we urge pharmaceutical laboratories to resume research. That implies a strong political push, through the World Health Organisation, and funding,&quot; Biberson said.</p>
<p>Delegates said pharmaceutical companies should prove more willing to withhold patent rights for fixed periods to allow other organisations to market medicine or vaccines which could help contain epidemics.</p>
<p>A report by WHO and UNICEF last month urged manufacturers to charge less for poorer nations in a &quot;tiered pricing&quot; policy. It called on governments and donors to commit to spend more on vaccines, with aid better targeted to the neediest countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
