<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143864" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Alcatel says would not have sold TMM.</title>
<headline>Alcatel says would not have sold TMM.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Engineering group Alcatel Alsthom, the loser in the bidding war for state electronics group Thomson SA, said on Friday that its proposal did not entail the sale of control of TV manufacturer Thomson Multimedia (TMM).  </p>
<p>&quot;Following public declarations referring to the similarity of the offers by the Lagardere group and Alcatel Alsthom for Thomson, Alcatel Alsthom notes that its proposal envisaged the purchase of 100 percent of TMM and then the search for an Asian partner, given TMM's need to solidly implant itself in Asia...Alcatel Alsthom indicated it would be an equal partner in this new entity,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This new entity would have constituted the base of a global industrial entity in which French interests would have been solidly represented,&quot; Alcatel said.  </p>
<p>Lagardere, whose proposal for Thomson was selected last week over Alcatel's offer, plans to sell Thomson's consumer electronics division TMM to South Korea's Daewoo Electronics for the symbolic sum of one franc.</p>
<p>Although government officials say the price reflects TMM's serious financial difficulties, the terms of the privatisation have triggered a public outcry. Opposition politicians and unions are demanding an inquiry.</p>
<p>Four trade unions at a Thomson factory in Angers called on workers to lay down their tools for an hour on Friday to protest against the sale of TMM to Daewoo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
