<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143830" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-AgrEvo sees 1996 profit jumping over 30 pct.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-AgrEvo sees 1996 profit jumping over 30 pct.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>German crop protection group AgrEvo GmbH on Friday said its 1996 operating profit will surge by over 30 percent to around 200 million marks ($130 million), as higher volume sales have helped boost overall results.</p>
<p>&quot;Our 1996 operating profit will total around 200 million marks while sales will show a rise of over 11 percent to around 3.75 billion marks,&quot; AgrEvo chief executive Gerhard Prante told a news conference, after nine-month sales climbed 12.3 percent.</p>
<p>For 1997 AgrEvo, jointly owned by Frankfurt-based chemicals and drugs giant Hoechst AG and Berlin-based drugs group Schering AG, is equally optimistic, forecasting operating profit growth will be at least 10 percent.</p>
<p>Looking ahead AgrEvo, the world's second largest crop protection group, expects operating profit to total 15 percent of sales by 1999, an ambitious jump from the current operating margin of six percent, board member Peter Henkel said.</p>
<p>Operating profit, which AgrEvo said had already improved markedly in the first nine months, grew despite extraordinary costs, including charges for restructuring and an acquistion made in August 1996, Prante said.</p>
<p>&quot;In total we will face one-off costs of 50 million marks and provisions totalling 80 million marks this year,&quot; Henkel said, adding however the group would also realise 155 million marks in savings this year.</p>
<p>Last year AgrEvo posted an operating profit of 147 million marks and sales of 3.4 billion marks, as the negative effect of weaker currencies, particularly the soft U.S. dollar, cost the group 200 million marks in results.</p>
<p>With currency turmoil largely behind it, AgrEvo said higher volume sales made up the lion's share of this year's jump in sales growth. Foreign exchange factors contributed three percent while price hikes added one percent to sales growth.</p>
<p>Europe remained AgrEvo's largest single market posting forecast sales of 1.52 billion marks this year, marking a four percent jump from year-ago levels.</p>
<p>Latin America, posting a 27 percent jump in growth to a forecast 430 million marks, remained the strongest growing region. In North America sales will likely total 640 million marks, representing a 14 percent increase, AgrEvo said.</p>
<p>Among its product groups, herbicide sales jumped 11 percent to a forecast 1.5 billion marks, trailed by a 10 percent jump in insecticide sales to a forecast 921 million marks and a nine percent jump in fungicides to a forecast 588 million marks.</p>
<p>Environmental health sales grew by five percent to a forecast 406 million marks, AgrEvo said.</p>
<p>AgrEvo will soon acquire the remaining five percent stake in Dutch/Belgian plant biotechnology group Plant Genetic Systems, in which it already took a 95 percent stake for 1.1 billion marks in August.</p>
<p>In total AgrEvo will have invested 400 million marks in research and development and some 150 million marks, excluding this year's acquistion, in fixed assets this year.</p>
<p>Prante said AgrEvo plans to achieve its strategic goal of expanding its market share in North America and Asia by launching new herbicides for rice in Asia and its herbicide Liberty in Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>($1=1.5250 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
