<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143909" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss panel says &quot;mad cow&quot; cull beef fine to eat.</title>
<headline>Swiss panel says &quot;mad cow&quot; cull beef fine to eat.</headline>
<dateline>BERNE 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Swiss parliamentary panel suggested on Friday that beef from the country's planned &quot;mad cow&quot; cull be put on sale to the public because it posed no health hazard.</p>
<p>Rolf Buettiker, chairman of the upper house of parliament's economics committee, said his panel supported the government's plan to slaughter 230,000 animals in a bid to wipe out Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy in Switzerland once and for all.</p>
<p>Scientists say humans could develop a form of the brain-wasting disease by eating contaminated food products. But Buettiker said meat was safe to eat as long as the brains and other critical organs were removed.</p>
<p>&quot;Because scientific research shows beef can be consumed without danger, the meat does not have to be destroyed or processed into animal meal,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The slaughter is set to be finished in 1999 in a programme to cost around 320 million Swiss francs. With 226 cases of BSE so far reported, Switzerland is second only to Britain in the number of infected cattle.</p>
<p>The cabinet proposed the slaughter of cattle born before December 1, 1990, the year Switzerland banned feeding cows with beef bone and remains which could help spread the disease.</p>
<p>It also recommended the slaughter of direct offspring of BSE infected cows to help boost consumer confidence.</p>
<p>Some countries have banned imports of beef from Switzerland and the Swiss themselves are eating less beef.</p>
<p>The upper house panel backed the government's proposal to pay farmers 1,000 francs per animal under the scheme.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot let farmers go empty handed over the winter,&quot; Buettiker said.</p>
<p>Some 10,000 farmers marched in Berne on Wednesday to protest against plans to finance the scheme in part by cutting milk price subsidies. Police used teargas and water cannon to disperse the crowd when the protest started getting violent.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the Federal Health Bureau in Berne said Swiss measures to protect consumers from the disease were sufficient even in light of recent scientific evidence linking BSE to its human equivalent.</p>
<p>Brains and other suspect organs from cattle have been removed from the human food chain since 1990. Neither beef nor milk is deemed dangerous to health.</p>
<p>No cases of the new variety of Creutzfeld-Jakob Disease linked to BSE have been reported in Switzerland so far.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
