<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143944" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Warcrimes trial told Bosnia forced witness to lie.</title>
<headline>Warcrimes trial told Bosnia forced witness to lie.</headline>
<dateline>THE HAGUE 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A United Nations warcrimes investigator testified on Friday the Bosnian government forced a key prosecution witness to lie when giving evidence against a Bosnian Serb accused of committing atrocities against Moslems.</p>
<p>Robert Reid, a warcrimes investigator for the U.N. criminal tribunal for former Yugoslavia, told the Hague court that Dragan Opacic, previously known only as witness &quot;L&quot;, had been told to lie in testifying against the accused Dusan Tadic, or be killed.</p>
<p>Reid said Opacic, himself convicted by a Bosnian court of &quot;serious crimes&quot;, had been trained by military police in Sarajevo, was shown videos of Tadic and the Trnopolje prison camp in Bosnia and was told to lie in court.</p>
<p>He added Opacic was told he would be executed if he refused. &quot;By which, I understood (he would be) murdered,&quot; Reid said.</p>
<p>The investigator did not speculate as to why the Bosnian authorities might want to send a &quot;false witness&quot; to the trial.</p>
<p>Opacic, a key prosecution witness, told the court in mid-August that he had been a guard with Tadic at the Serb-run camp at Trnopolje, one of three camps in northwest Bosnia where Tadic is accused of killing and torturing non-Serbs as part of an &quot;ethnic cleansing&quot; campaign in the region in 1992.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Grant Niemann told the three tribunal judges that he had reviewed Opacic's testimony and was dropping one of the 31 charges against Tadic.</p>
<p>&quot;Over the past couple of weeks we have been investigating this witness and his testimony and, as a consequence, the prosecution now feels it can no longer support that witness as a witness of truth,&quot; Niemann said.</p>
<p>Defence lawyer Michail Wladimiroff told reporters earlier that Opacic had made up his story from &quot;A to Z&quot;. &quot;Right from the start it was clear that &quot;L&quot;'s testimony didn't ring true,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>After Reid's brief testimony, Tadic himself took the stand.</p>
<p>Smartly dressed in a blue suit and tie and speaking through an interpreter, the accused took the oath and answered general questions on his family background from British defence attorney Stephen Kaye.</p>
<p>Tadic, 41, denies charges that he toured three Serb-run camps -- Trnopolje, Omarska and Keraterm -- on an orgy of killing, raping and torturing non-Serbs in the summer of 1992.</p>
<p>The Trnopolje charge is only one of 31 counts against the former cafe owner and karate coach.</p>
<p>Tadic still faces a maximum life jail term if found guilty of committing atrocities at the other camps.</p>
<p>The trial, which began in May, is expected to end next month, with a verdict in the spring.</p>
<p>The majority of the 75 suspects charged by the tribunal, including former Bosnian Serb leader Radovan Karadzic and his army commander General Ratko Mladic, remain at liberty. One has died and seven are in tribunal custody.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="THE HAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
