<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143994" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India says &quot;worst is over&quot; with dengue fever.</title>
<headline>India says &quot;worst is over&quot; with dengue fever.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>An outbreak of dengue fever which has killed at least 260 people in the Indian capital has peaked and the death rate has declined sharply, the government said on Friday.</p>
<p>But it said a committee of government experts had warned authorities in the southern state of Andhra Pradesh to be on the lookout for possible outbreaks of dengue as well as malaria and cholera following torrential rains.</p>
<p>The Health Ministry said in a statement that in Delhi &quot;during the last 24 hours, it was revealed that there were no deaths in the central government hospitals...and the number of admissions had also declined considerably&quot;.</p>
<p>Dengue, a mosquito-borne disease also called breakbone fever, broke out in Delhi during monsoon rains in late August. More than 5,000 people have been admitted to hospitals, and at least 260 have died.</p>
<p>The ministry said more than 13,000 workers had inspected some 2.8 million households in the sprawling capital.</p>
<p>Many Delhi households use water and air coolers, breeding grounds for mosquities during the hot summer months, and authorities have ordered homeowners to get rid of stagnant water.</p>
<p>The Press Trust of India (PTI) quoted Health Minister Saleem Iqbal Shervani as saying that the &quot;worst is over and the situation (is) under control&quot;.</p>
<p>The government said there were no reported cases of dengue yet in Andhra Pradesh, where more than 300 people were believed to have died in flash floods earlier this week.</p>
<p>But it said state health authorities had been asked to take steps to prevent possible outbreaks of dengue, malaria, gastroenteritis and cholera.</p>
<p>Additional quantities of insecticides and medicines were being sent to the state, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
