<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143940" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures rallied after Bundesbank council members hinted on Friday that there was still a possibility German rates could be cut, two days after stating there was no reason for further reductions.</p>
<p>The December bond future surged more than half a point from the day's low to settle at 126.50, close to the week's high of 126.68 reached early on Wednesday.</p>
<p>December PIBOR hit a high of 96.46, within a whisker of its contract high of 96.47 reached on Monday, amid expectations the Bank of France will cut its key intervention rate next week and a stronger franc.  </p>
<p>Traders said there had been domestic buying of cash bonds when the contract was at the day's lows but activity petered out as the futures contract rallied later in the session.</p>
<p>Francois-Xavier Chauchat, economist at Banque Nationale de Paris said what the Bundesbank really wanted to see was lower long-term interest rates.</p>
<p>The fact long-dated bonds had sold off after Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing said on Wednesday there was no reason to cut short-term rates had probably prompted the change of tone by Bundesbank members today, he said.  </p>
<p>Asked today whether he could rule out a cut in rates Issing said &quot;of course not. There is never an end.&quot; However he repeated that &quot;under existing circumstances&quot; there could be no rate cut in Germany.</p>
<p>Chauchat said the outlook for next week was positive as the U.S. economic release would probably be favourable for bond markets. He said the 10-year yield on French and German government bonds could well fall to 5.75-80 percent.</p>
<p>Ciaran O'Hagan, bond analyst at JP Morgan in Paris, said the boost to the market from the Issing comments and U.S. economic figures was accentuated by a short squeeze.  </p>
<p>Eric Chaney, economist at Morgan Stanley in Paris, said French trade balance figures released on Friday, showing a new record monthly surplus of 13.9 billion francs, would help support the franc and lent further weight to the case for a rate cut next week.</p>
<p>&quot;All in all, the trader numbers support our call for a 10 basis point cut in the intervention rate next Thursday. In the event it could even be a 15 basis point cut if the currency appreciates further,&quot; Chaney said.</p>
<p>O'Hagan said hopes for a French rate cut next week were pretty much discounted in the market but he urged caution.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure how reasonable it is,&quot; O'Hagan said. He said he thought the French central bank would want to wait until short-term money market rates between France and Germany had moved closer together.</p>
<p>Although the gap between the French intervention rate and the German repo rate is 25 basis points, the spread between French and German call money remained at 31 basis points and the gap between December PIBOR and Euromark contracts was 37.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Bank of France will want to be led by the market,&quot; said O'Hagan. &quot;It's less likely the BoF will be in a hurry to lower rates.&quot;  </p>
<p>The franc rallied for the second consecutive day against the German mark, reaching its highest level since April 30 at 3.3735. At 1510 GMT it was at back at 3.3759, close to its level of 3.3767 on Friday last week.</p>
<p>Call money was unchanged at 3-1/4 3/8 percent.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
