<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="143941" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Tietmeyer sees no foreseeable need for rate cuts.</title>
<headline>Tietmeyer sees no foreseeable need for rate cuts.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer said in an interview to be broadcast on German radio that he sees no need for further interest rate cuts in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer added that he saw 1996 economic growth of one percent or more and said that from the interest rate point of view, nothing stood in the way of economic growth.</p>
<p>He said he saw &quot;a strong chance&quot; of Germany's economic recovery continuing into 1997.</p>
<p>However, he said he was against the sale of gold reserves to help narrow current deficit levels.  </p>
<p>Tietmeyer said in the interview to be broadcast on Sunday morning that growth of one percent or more was not a large upturn but an &quot;important beginning&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;And I am assuming that there is a strong chance that (such growth) will continue into next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer said interest rates, currently at historic lows, were no barrier to investment in the German economy and as such there was no foreseeable need for a rate cut.</p>
<p>His comments come after two key Bundesbank figures had earlier on Friday appeared to revive hopes for lower German rates.</p>
<p>Speaking at separate events, Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing and council member Ernst Welteke also stressed there was no need to cut rates now, but held out hope the central bank could consider a further easing.</p>
<p>Issing's comments in a German television interview last Wednesday had dashed financial market hopes for lower rates.</p>
<p>Welteke told reporters in Frankfurt that in the medium term, &quot;a repo cut is still possible depending on developments.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
