<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144173" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Federal-Mogul sees Q4 charge up to $40 mln.</title>
<headline>Federal-Mogul sees Q4 charge up to $40 mln.</headline>
<dateline>SOUTHFIELD, Mich. 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal-Mogul Corp said it may record a largely non-cash charge in the fourth quarter of up to $40 million after-tax on a continuing top-to-bottom review of its balance sheet.</p>
<p>The company said this year it may not top 1995 financial results, as previously expected.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disappointed with our earnings and do not believe the company will be able to exceed 1995 results as previously expected,&quot; said chief executive Robert Miller.</p>
<p>Shares in the auto, truck, farm and construction vehicle parts manufacturer were off 5/8 to 23-1/4.  </p>
<p>He added, &quot;We anticipate that the positive impact of our reengineering initiatives and operational improvements should start appearing on the earnings line by early next year.&quot;</p>
<p>Federal-Mogul on Friday reported a third-quarter net loss of $17 million, or $0.56 per share, versus net earnings of $11 million, or $0.25 per share, in 1995.</p>
<p>The loss included a special, after-tax charge of $24 million, or $0.70 per share. Excluding the special charge, operating earnings were $22 million, net earnings were $7 million and earnings per share were $0.14, the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The third quarter special charge is the result of a top-to-bottom review of the company's balance sheet and business units begun at the request of the board of directors this summer. This review has intensified since September 18 when ... change in management occurred,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>On September 18, chairman and chief executive Dennis Gormley resigned. Roderick Hills, a Federal-Mogul director since 1977, was named chairman of the board of directors and Miller, a director since 1993, became acting chief executive.</p>
<p>The company hired a firm to assist in the search for a new chief executive officer.  </p>
<p>On September 30, the company agreed to sell its U.S. ball bearing manufacturing operations. The sale is expected to be completed during the fourth quarter and proceeds to be used to reduce debt, the company said.</p>
<p>The company said it is satisfied the third-quarter charge will not hurt the company's earnings capacity. &quot;Approximately $5 million, or 15 percent of the total, will have a cash impact through 1997,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;The balance sheet and business unit review will continue through year-end,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>The third-quarter charge, totalling $38 million on a pre-tax basis, includes several items: a $6-million loss on the sale of the U.S. ball bearing business; professional fees and severance costs of $6 million related to management changes; changes in accounting estimates of $6 million in environmental liabilities and of $10 million in customer programs; a charge of $3 million on a change in methodology for the recognition of capitalized interest to better reflect asset value; inventory adjustments of $3 million; recognition of additional employee benefits of $2 million; and miscellaneous items totaling $2 million.</p>
<p>As a result, a charge in the fourth quarter is anticipated for additional severance and professional fees, supplier issues, the impact of potential operational changes in the international aftermarket and of losses related to the sale of business units, Federal-Mogul said.</p>
<p>&quot;When completed, this review could result in a fourth quarter after-tax charge of as much as $40 million, which would predominantly be of a non-cash nature,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The board also expects the new chief executive will wish to review possible restructuring alternatives, which could result in an additional charge in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOUTHFIELD, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
