<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144397" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Will the trade gap return to haunt sterling?.</title>
<headline>Will the trade gap return to haunt sterling?.</headline>
<byline>Phil Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Another good set of British trade data helped underpin the already rampant pound and while a burgeoning external deficit has pulled the rug from under sterling in the past, problems on this front are a way off.</p>
<p>Britain's trade position will certainly deteriorate at some point and hit the pound, but with European economies picking up export markets are set to expand and offset any rise in import penetration as U.K. domestic demand increases.</p>
<p>&quot;We will see the same old end-game unfold for both the trade deficit and the pound,&quot; said Kevin Gardiner, international economist at Morgan Stanley. &quot;But with the worst will in the world I can't see that happening in a hurry.&quot;</p>
<p>Economic data comes in and out of fashion and at the moment output and inflation are the stars. But every dog has its day and trade will again come round to be the most watched figure.</p>
<p>August data showed a trade gap of 584 million sterling, well down on July's 1.22 billion shortfall with total exports up 1.0 percent while total imports fell 3-1/2 percent.</p>
<p>In 1995 the trade deficit was 11.63 billion sterling and in the first two quarters this year it amounted to 7.26 billion.</p>
<p>This might seem large but it is peanuts compared with the 21.48 billion gap in 1988 and 24.68 billion in 1989.</p>
<p>A re-run of the situation during the early part of the 1980s is the most likely scenario, when the pound held up much better than people had expected until it was tripped up by the current account gaps opened up by the (Chancellor Nigel) Lawson boom late in the decade.</p>
<p>The pound's peak after the 1980s run-up was reached in January 1989, when the monthly deficit tipped above 2.0 billion. By the end of the year sterling was nearly 13 percent lower in trade weighted terms.</p>
<p>Analysts said it is hard to see the trade deficit significantly exceeding one percent of Gross Domestic Product next year and it is only when it reaches two or three percent that it becomes of market interest.</p>
<p>However, a firmer pound will start to hit manufacturers when their goods become less competitive abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;If the pound firms further it will be very bad for the manufacturing sector and for exports, but it doesn't have a knock-on impact on consumer spending,&quot; said David Bloom, currency strategist at HSBC markets.</p>
<p>With windfall gains from Building Society flotations, tax cuts and low base rates, consumer spending will keep imports up but the firm pound will at the same time hit exports.</p>
<p>&quot;That could start turning the trade numbers a little nasty next year,&quot; Bloom added.</p>
<p>To make this situation worse it looks like Chancellor Kenneth Clarke will tend to aim for a more relaxed fiscal stance and a steady or firmer monetary stance, something which will tend to hurt manufacturers in terms of borrowing costs but boost domestic demand via lower taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;What is really needed is to cut base rates and raise taxes because that hits the consumer the hardest and gives manufacturers a breathing space...but it looks like they are going to do the opposite,&quot; Bloom added.</p>
<p>&quot;That could cause a problem for the trade situation.&quot; ($1=.6264 Sterling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
