<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144465" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus stocks subdued at end of week.</title>
<headline>Cyprus stocks subdued at end of week.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Cyprus Stock Exchange remained subdued this week despite signs of a recovery on Thursday and Friday.</p>
<p>The 41-share CSE index, set at 100 points, closed at 83.78, marginally lower from the 83.85 close last week.</p>
<p>The market opened lower on Monday, losing ground until Thursday when the downtrend was partiall reversed.</p>
<p>CISCO, the Cyprus Investment and Securities Corporation, said in its weekly report that government plans to deregulate interest rates should have a positive impact on the market in the weeks to come,</p>
<p>Cypriot Finance Minister Christodoulos Christodoulou told Reuters this week that legislation scrapping the present nine percent ceiling on interest rates would be tabled for approval to the House of Representatives before the end of the year.</p>
<p>CISCO said deregulation would possibly pull down rates, currently set by commercial banks at 8.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;This will in turn lead to a significant boost in the stock market, since the latter will obviously provide more worthwhile investment opportunities,&quot; CISCO said.</p>
<p>The banking sub-index, which concentrates the bulk of transactions on the exchange, closed at 92.14, up 1.02 points or 1.11 percent, from 91.12 it closed at last Friday.</p>
<p>Fully-paid shares of the Bank of Cyprus closed at 345.5, gaining from losses made during the week but still half a cent lower from 346 last week.</p>
<p>Fully-paid shares in the Cyprus Popular Bank stood at 330.5, gaining seven cents from its closing figure last week of 323.5. Fully paid shares of Hellenic Bank made gains of 10.5 cents and closed at 269.</p>
<p>The sub index for tourism enterprises closed at 74.31, slightly lower than 74.79 last week. The largest company in the sector, the Cyprus Tourism Development Company closed at 890, down 20 cents from last Friday's close of 910.</p>
<p>The index of the insurance sector closed at 61.27 from 61.69 last week.</p>
<p>Universal Life Insurance, which on Friday announced its half yearly pre-tax profit was up by 26 percent, closed at 380 from 383.5 last week. Paneuropean Insurance fully paid closed at 138.5, up 1.5 cents from last week.</p>
<p>Fully paid shares in subsidiary Interamerican Insurance closed at 104, down two cents from last week.</p>
<p>The stock market will be closed on Monday, a Greek national holiday.</p>
<p>--Michele Kambas, Nicosia newsroom 357 2 365089</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
