<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144581" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fitch's upgrade of Detroit wins praise from mayor.</title>
<headline>Fitch's upgrade of Detroit wins praise from mayor.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fitch Investors Service raised Detroit's general obligation debt rating to BBB on Thursday, citing its improved financial condition, a decision hailed by the city's mayor, Dennis Archer.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very pleased to learn of our third straight debt rating upgrade,&quot; Archer said in a statement. &quot;Detroit is on solid fiscal footing, and our best days are ahead of us.&quot;</p>
<p>Fitch raised Detroit's general obligation debt rating from BBB-minus to BBB. This is the third upgrade of Detroit debt in the last week by a major rating agency.</p>
<p>In its statement, Fitch said Detroit's financial condition had improved demonstrably, with sluggish revenue growth and net operating deficits giving way to economic expansion and financial improvement.</p>
<p>However, the rating agency warned that Detroit continued to face risks. The challenges include its significant debt burden, its ability to manage through an economic downturn, and its revenue vulnerability.  </p>
<p>The Fitch upgrade followed an October 22 announcement by Standard &amp; Poor's Corp that its credit outlook on Detroit had changed from stable to positive. Moody's Investors Service Inc raised Detroit's general obligation debt rating from Ba1 to Baa on October 17.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
