<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144558" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IMC Global 2-3 year outlook 'positive'.</title>
<headline>IMC Global 2-3 year outlook 'positive'.</headline>
<dateline>NORTHBROOK, Ill. 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>IMC Global Inc, a fertilizer producer, said Friday its two-to-three year outlook remains &quot;highly positive.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Record-low world grain stocks, strong farm incomes due to high grain prices, and a continued increase in planted acres in North America are expected to further strengthen demand for crop nutrients,&quot; Wendell Bueche, chairman, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Accelerating global food needs can only be achieved through greater crop yields, which requires increased use of crop nutrients.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the company's strong cash flow and access to capital, we intend to pursue future growth opportunities on a global scale,&quot; Bueche said.  &quot;Our recently-announced participation in the feasibility stage of a phosphate mining and processing venture in China's Yunnan Province is consistent with this objective.&quot;</p>
<p>IMC Global reported earnings for the first quarter ended September 30 of $0.31 a share before an $0.08 charge.  </p>
<p>A year ago, it earned $0.35 a share.</p>
<p>First quarter earnings included $56.4 million in selling, general and administrative expenses, up from $46.0 million a year ago.  The company said these costs were largely due to acquisitions and increased operating expenses associated with higher sales volume at IMC AgriBusiness.</p>
<p>&quot;Potash revenues rose 11 percent primarily due to higher domestic and and export volumes,&quot; Bueche said.</p>
<p>Despite improved potash sales, gross margins fell 15 percent, largely due to increased production costs associated with an extended summer shutdown at four Canadian mines to reduce inventories.</p>
<p>&quot;Conversely, phosphate sales declined 10 percent due to reduced international diammonium phosphate (DAP) volumes and lower phosphate rock revenues,&quot; Bueche said.</p>
<p>DAP exports to China, India and Japan were less than last year, but increased shipments of granular monoammonium phosphate and granular triple superphosphate softened the impact, he added.</p>
<p>Bueche said a later than normal fall harvest has delayed fall applications of nutrients, which contributed to first quarter results that were &quot;essentially flat.&quot;</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHBROOK, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
