<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144589" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bar, restaurant owners fear losses from smoke ban.</title>
<headline>Bar, restaurant owners fear losses from smoke ban.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. bar and restaurant owners fear a proposed ban on smoking in the workplace will cause them major economic losses, according to a survey released on Thursday.</p>
<p>The survey found that 83 percent of bar owners anticipate a loss a revenue and 81 percent estimate losses at over 15 percent. Nearly half the restaurant owners and managers polled felt they would lose money by an outright ban on smoking.</p>
<p>The National Licensed Beverage Association, a liquor industry trade group that sponsored the survey, said it opposes a proposed indoor air quality regulation by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) that would ban smoking in the workplace.</p>
<p>OSHA said the workplace would include dining areas, bars, hotel rooms or anywhere else where work is performed, so waiters and waitresses would be barred from entering.</p>
<p>The survey found that 91 percent of owners and managers of bars and 72 percent of restaurateurs preferred to make their own smoking policies without government supervision.</p>
<p>The survey, conducted by the Roper Starch Worldwide polling firm, was based on telephone interviews with 1,300 people and has a margin of error of plus or minus four percentage points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
