<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144532" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arkansas gambling amendment backers want judge removed.</title>
<headline>Arkansas gambling amendment backers want judge removed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Backers of a gambling amendment booted off Arkansas' Nov 5 ballot have filed for a rehearing, and want a special justice disqualified from the case.</p>
<p>The Arkansas Supreme Court Monday announced a four to three vote to remove Amendment 7 because of ballot title problems, according to release issued by The Committee to Promote Arkansas, which supports Amendment 7. The constitutional amendment called for a state-wide lottery, charity bingo and limited casino gaming.</p>
<p>Amendment supporters want Special Justice Sandra Smith Hochstetter disqualified from the case &quot;because of a perceived conflict of interest,&quot; the release said. Hochstetter, who cast the deciding vote, was appointed by Gov. Mike Huckabee after another justice, Robert Brown, recused himself due to a conflict of interest, it said.</p>
<p>According to the release, Hochstetter is assistant general counsel for a business called Arkla Gas. Arkla is represented by Friday Eldredge &amp; Clark, a law firm that also represents Amendment 4, a gaming amendment in competition with Amendment 7. A Friday Eldredge attorney who argued the Amendment 4 case before the court, also represents Arkla, the release said.</p>
<p>&quot;The appearance of impropriety is what we're talking about here,&quot; David Couch, an Amendment 7 attorney, said. &quot;If one of my clients was sitting in judgment of the case involving Oaklawn, I don't think they'd be very happy about that.&quot;</p>
<p>Oaklawn Park is one of the proposed casino sites.</p>
<p>Couch cited copies of a circuit court case filed in May 1996 in which Arkla is represented by Friday Eldredge. Justice Hochstetter could not be reached immediately for comment.</p>
<p>The release added that in 1994, backers of Amendment 7 put forth a similar measure that was stricken two weeks before the election.</p>
<p>&quot;In redrafting the amendment this time around, we followed the court's instructions from 1994,&quot; Couch said. &quot;We followed their rules, but it seems the rules have been changed on us.&quot;</p>
<p>Amendment 7 was one of three gambling amendments removed from Arkansas ballot, making Amendment 4 the only gambling amendment left on the ballot.</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
