<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144613" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Bayernverein sees 1996 profit hike.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Bayernverein sees 1996 profit hike.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bayerische Vereinsbank AG on Friday said its earnings would grow by more than 10 percent in 1996 and held out the prospect of a dividend rise after operating profit rose 17.5 percent in the first nine months.</p>
<p>Group operating profit after risk provisions at Germany's fourth largest bank, recently at the heart of takeover speculation, rose to 1.0 billion marks ($655 million) in the nine months to September 30 from 872.6 million marks in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>The bank's results matched analysts' expectations for a slowdown in earnings growth from the 24 percent rise at the half-year stage, partly because of the comparison with a particularly strong second half of 1995.</p>
<p>Chief executive Albrecht Schmidt seized on the solid earnings performance to counter market talk that his bank may become a target for acquisition after giant rival Deutsche Bank announced in July it had amassed a 5.21 percent stake.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to remain an independent, Munich-based bank,&quot; Schmidt told a news conference.</p>
<p>Asked to comment on rumours that Deutsche has been increasing its stake since July, Schmidt said he did not know.</p>
<p>&quot;The shares of Bayerische Vereinsbank are esteemed by many investors,&quot; Schmidt said. &quot;I can only congratulate them.&quot;</p>
<p>Deutsche has said it took the stake to deter potential bidders but had no immediate plans to increase it.</p>
<p>Bayernverein's share price has risen sharply since Deutsche's disclosure and Schmidt noted that it outperformed the shares of its four German rivals with 33 percent growth in the five years to end-1995.</p>
<p>On Friday, Bayernverein's shares closed floor trade unchanged at 56.27 marks after the results.</p>
<p>Schmidt said, &quot;I am confident we will reach double-digit growth in operating profit in 1996. Our shareholders will profit appropriately from this, we will do something for them.&quot;</p>
<p>Bayernverein already raised its dividend payout for 1995, to 1.50 marks per five-mark share from 1.45 marks.</p>
<p>Schmidt said he would be happy with profit growth of between 10 and 15 percent for the full year.</p>
<p>Deutsche, which kicked off the German bank nine-month reporting season on Thursday, also posted slower profits growth.</p>
<p>Bayernverein, a leading mortgage lender, said earnings growth was driven by a 7.7 percent rise in net interest income to 3.44 billion marks amid buoyant new mortgage loan approvals.</p>
<p>Net commission income rose 16.4 percent to 885.9 million marks as a result of rising share and bond markets, it said.</p>
<p>But that growth masked a disappointing performance in own-account trading income during the third quarter due to a sharp drop in trading income at Hamburg-based unit Vereins- und Westbank AG, Schmidt said.</p>
<p>&quot;Vereins und West-Bank was not on the right side in its assessment of interest rates in the third quarter,&quot; Schmidt said. Group own-account trading profit totalled 189.8 million marks in the first nine months, below the 191.8 million marks earned in the first half and up just four percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>Bayernverein said it earned 137.5 million marks from currency trading, 39.3 million marks from bond trading and 13 million marks from equity transactions in the period.</p>
<p>Risk provisions rose 17 percent to 580.6 million as the need for loan cover remained unchanged despite Germany's slight upturn, Schmidt said.</p>
<p>Group lending rose to 298.4 billion marks, up 6.2 percent from end-1995, while the balance sheet total rose to 384.8 billion marks from 356.5 billion.</p>
<p>($1=1.5250 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
