<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144664" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Court leaves to national courts issue of music royalties.</title>
<headline>Court leaves to national courts issue of music royalties.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Court of Justice upheld on Thursday a decision by the European Commision not to pursue complaints against SACEM, a French copyright management society.</p>
<p>Robert Tremblay, Harry Kestenberg and others appealed a Court of First Instance (CFI) decision which upheld the European Commission's decision not to take on the issue of whether SACEM infringed competiton rules, on the basis of subsidiarity and finding no Community interest.</p>
<p>The court dismissed some of the pleas as they were challenges to findings of fact by the CFI and the court reviews only appeals raising issues of law.</p>
<p>The CFI accepted the Commission's statement of reasons that there was adequate relief under national law and there was insufficient Community interest to pursue the complaints.</p>
<p>As to the substance of the claims that SACEM abused its dominant position in France to charge excessive royalty rates, the court said the Commission's decision would not prevent national courts from finding fault, and relief for the appellants.</p>
<p>In the first decision, the claimants argued a Commission report showed a basis for finding the abuse of a dominant position. &quot;It may be inferred that the appellants consider...the communication of the report alone is sufficient to enable the national courts to assess the situation,&quot; the court said.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>EXCERPTS FROM THE JUDGMENT</p>
<p>(Court translation into English. Original language of the case: French)</p>
<p>&quot;Appeal - Competition - Rejection of a complaint - Absence of Community interest&quot;</p>
<p>In Case C-91/95 P</p>
<p>24 October 1996</p>
<p>Roger Tremblay</p>
<p>Harry Kestenberg</p>
<p>Syndicat des Exploitants de Lieux de Loisirs (SELL), appellants</p>
<p>appeal against the judgment of the Court of First Instance of the European Communities of 24 January 1995 in Case T-5/93 Tremblay and Others v Commission (1995) ECR II-185, seeking to have that judgment partially set aside</p>
<p>the other party to the proceedings being</p>
<p>Commission of the European Communities</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE COURT hereby</p>
<p>1. Dismisses the appeal;</p>
<p>2. Orders the appellants to pay the costs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
