<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144616" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Jews outraged as Italy Court rejects compensation.</title>
<headline>Jews outraged as Italy Court rejects compensation.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A regional court has ruled that persecution on the grounds of race alone is not sufficient cause to compensate Jews who suffered under Italian Fascism, sparking outrage on Friday among members of Italy's Jewish community.</p>
<p>The judges, whose decision is certain to be challenged, ruled that Jews had to demonstrate that they had been persecuted as active anti-Fascists in order to be considered for a state pension of about 600,000 lire ($390) a month.</p>
<p>Made public on Thursday, the ruling was delivered by a section of the Court of Accounts responsible for the Friuli-Venezia Giulia region of northeast Italy.</p>
<p>It conflicted with earlier rulings on the same issue by other regional sections of the court, which examines how public funds are spent.</p>
<p>Jews on Friday said they were dumbstruck by the decision, taken in response to appeals to the court from Jewish victims of Fascist dictator Benito Mussolini's race laws whose applications for pensions had been turned down by the government.</p>
<p>&quot;We express our profound regret over this episode and hope this unacceptable decision can be reversed,&quot; Tullia Zevi, president of Italy's Jewish communities said.</p>
<p>Franco Pavoncello, a professor of political science in Rome, told Reuters he had not studied the details of the decision but what he had heard about it &quot;makes very little sense.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;For the Germans, the mere fact that we were Jews was enough to send us to the camps. For the Italian state on the other hand, it seems that is not enough to grant us a pension as persecuted people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is so absurd that it is almost farcical.</p>
<p>&quot;How can you ask Jews to be obliged to show they were anti-fascist when they were simply eliminated from all the professions...they did not exist any more.&quot;</p>
<p>Mussolini, allied with Adolf Hitler, introduced race laws aimed against Jews in 1938.</p>
<p>Jews were expelled from schools, sacked from public jobs, interned, exiled and had property and marriage rights curtailed.</p>
<p>From 1943, nearly 8,000 of the 50,000 Jews in Italy were deported to Auschwitz and other death camps. Only 610 survived.</p>
<p>&quot;It is clear to everyone that a Jew, precisely because of the discrimination, could only be anti-Fascist,&quot; said Riccardo Pacifici, leader of the youth group of Rome's Jewish community.</p>
<p>He said his father had lost both his parents during World War Two, been expelled from primary school and forced into hiding at a Roman Catholic convent in Florence for five years.</p>
<p>&quot;Maybe the judges would like to tell me how a five-year-old boy was meant to have played an active part in the anti-fascist struggle,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Italy passed laws in 1967 and 1980 enabling Jews to apply for compensation for persecution under Fascism but the wording of the legislation has led to uncertainty over eligibility.</p>
<p>The Court of Accounts rejected previous broad interpretation of the provisions.</p>
<p>&quot;That would lead to a generalised recognition of the right to compensation for all citizens of the Jewish race,&quot; the written ruling said.</p>
<p>It said the clear intent of the law was to compensate Jews who had faced persecution beyond the &quot;albeit grave, unjust... torments and restrictions common to all the other Jews.&quot;</p>
<p>The court listed precise conditions under which compensation should apply.</p>
<p>These included detention for political reasons, internal exile or forced labour on political grounds, imprisonment of at least one year for anti-fascist activities and detention in jail or a concentration camp for anti-fascist activity outside Italy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
