<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14478" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China's Hainan Airlines applies to issue B shares.</title>
<headline>China's Hainan Airlines applies to issue B shares.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hainan Airlines intends to make an offer of 75 million class B shares and list the stock on the Shanghai bourse, a company spokeswoman said on Monday.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman told the China Securities Bulletin the airline had submitted an application on the offer of B shares to the China Securities Regulatory Commission with the support of the Hainan provincial government. B shares are reserved for foreign investors.</p>
<p>If the offer is approved, Hainan Airlines would be China's first public civil aviation company, she said.</p>
<p>Hainan Airlines already is the first Chinese airline to become a foreign joint venture. American Aviation Investment, a fund partially controlled by U.S. financier George Soros, took a 25 percent stake for US$25 million in November last year.</p>
<p>The spokeswoman said Hainan Airlines, which became a joint-stock entity in 1993, has total share capital of 400 million shares. These include 100 million shares held by American Aviation, 240 million held by China-based institutions and 60 million class A shares for local investors. The latter were offered at one yuan per share in early 1993.</p>
<p>If the B share offer goes through, Hainan Airlines would use the proceeds to expand its operation, she said.  </p>
<p>Hainan Airlines, based in Haikou, capital of China's island province of Hainan, operates 13 rented planes, including nine Boeing 737 jets, within mainland China.</p>
<p>It had net earnings of 81 million yuan in 1995, 87 million yuan in 1994 and 67 million yuan a year earlier, the spokeswoman said. She did not issue a profit forecast for this year or provide an explanation for the profit drop in 1995.</p>
<p>Shenzhen J&amp;A Securities has been named as the preliminary domestic lead underwriter for the offer, while an international coordinator had yet to be selected, she added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
