<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144766" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: More Danish firms setting up own risk operations.</title>
<headline>More Danish firms setting up own risk operations.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading Danish firms, hoping to improve their risk management, are increasingly looking to set up their own in-house insurance operations, the Confederation of Danish Industries said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that we are going to see a growing interest among Danish firms in insuring themselves,&quot; Erik Larsen of the confederation's risk management section told the daily newspaper Berlingske Tidende.</p>
<p>&quot;We know several big firms are seriously looking into the possibility. I predict a doubling in firms running their own risk operations within the next five to 10 years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said that 10 major Danish firms had so far set up insurance operations. However, administering one's own risks would be viable only for large companies, he noted.</p>
<p>Larsen said the trend reflected increasing demand for more flexible, individual insurance services, tailor-made for individual needs.</p>
<p>Widespread mergers in recent years unsettled the Danish insurance industry and brought charges of falling service standards during the period of adjustment.</p>
<p>-- Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom +45-33969652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
