<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144722" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German industry welcomes Spain's Eurofighter move.</title>
<headline>German industry welcomes Spain's Eurofighter move.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's main aerospace industry group, headed by Daimler-Benz Aerospace AG (Dasa) chief executive Manfred Bischoff, on Friday welcomed Spain's decision this week to order 87 Eurofighter combat aircraft.</p>
<p>Spain has joined Britain in declaring it would fund serial production of the 21st-century fighter by a four-country consortium starting next year, but a strapped German government is still in talks on funding.</p>
<p>&quot;The pressure among European partner countries is mounting on the federal government...to take the overdue decision to release enough funds in the 1997 budget,&quot; Bischoff said in a statement by the German Aerospace Industries Association.</p>
<p>Britain has already said it would buy 232 out of a total production run of 620 Eurofighters, and Spain has decided now to commit 25 billion pesetas ($195 million) to the project in 1997.</p>
<p>The spending is being funded by a credit from the Spanish industry ministry to the defence ministry repayable from 2002 onwards, the statement said.</p>
<p>The total Spanish financial commitment to the Eurofighter project will be 980 billion pesetas, guaranteeing the future of 22,000 skilled jobs in Spain.</p>
<p>Germany intends to buy 180 Eurofighters -- 140 fighter combat jets and 40 fighter-bombers -- but talks are continuing on price. Dasa has warned that a delay in placing a firm order could lead to an explosion in project costs.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Volker Ruehe said on Thursday in India that talks on Germany's procurement of the Eurofighter were still going on.</p>
<p>&quot;Especially the question of money we can use for the Eurofighter in the next four years...I will negotiate until I have satisfactory results. I can only spend the money I have. We need a plane and we want it to be a European plane,&quot; he told reporters in New Delhi.</p>
<p>German newspaper reports have said that Ruehe has only offered 100 million marks ($65.6 million) for Eurofighter next year, while the plane's builders want a minimum payment of 392 million marks.</p>
<p>Die Welt newspaper said on Friday that the government was under increasing pressure to agree on a proposal ahead of a key sitting of parliament's budget committee on November 14.</p>
<p>Dasa, which will make the fuselages of the Eurofighters, has a 30 percent stake in the project. British Aerospace owns 37.5 percent, Italy's Alenia Spa 19.5 percent and Spain's Casa 13 percent.</p>
<p>-- Douglas Busvine, Bonn newsroom, 49-228-26097150 ($ = 128.3 Spanish Pesetas) ($ = 1.524 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
