<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144727" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss group to advise China on energy sector.</title>
<headline>Swiss group to advise China on energy sector.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss consulting group Pacific Consult AG said on Friday that it had won a mandate from the Asian Development Bank (ADB) to advise the Chinese government on how to change its legal and regulatory framework to attract foreign investment needed to modernise the country's energy sector.</p>
<p>The current supply of electricity in China is estimated to be 20 percent below its needs and the availability of electricity is seen as a key factor in the further economic development of China, Pacific Consult said in a statement.</p>
<p>Expected demand for additional capacity over the next years is estimated at 17,000 megawatts annually and the aim is to attract $20 billion in foreign capital to China by the end of this century, the consultants said.</p>
<p>China is aware that foreign capital is necessary to meet its needs, but the current legal and regulatory framework is not seen as attractive or transparent enough to entice foreign investments to improve energy production, transmission and distribution systems, Pacific Consult said.</p>
<p>Pacific Consult will head a consortium comprised of representatives from Switzerland's Elektrowatt Engineering, Swiss bank Credit Suisse, U.S. legal firm Skadden Arps, Slate, Meagher &amp; Flom and Beijing's China International Engineering Consulting Corp.</p>
<p>The main financing model that is under consideration is the Build-Operate-Transfer (BOT), under which foreign investors operate a power plant or other equipment for a few years after construction and then transfer ownership to the Chinese state, mostly for free.</p>
<p>Pacific Consult's mandate expires mid-1997.</p>
<p>-- Peter Nielsen, Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
