<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144812" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian phone, postal strike said near end.</title>
<headline>Indian phone, postal strike said near end.</headline>
<byline>Nelson Graves</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Indian trade union leader and a senior government official said on Friday they expected a quick end to a three-day strike by more than one million government workers that has disrupted mail and phone services.</p>
<p>&quot;It might be called off because the offer of the government in connection with our demands is more or less available,&quot; O.P. Gupta, secretary general of the National Federation of Telecom Employees, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident things will work out very soon, maybe today,&quot; Pradeep Bhatnagar, private secretary to Communications Minister Beni Prasad Varma, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Gupta said the six trade unions leading the strike -- three representing telecommunicatinns workers and three in the postal sector -- were awaiting written assurance from the government that it would address their concerns.</p>
<p>Telecommunications, postal and income tax staff employed by the government are demanding the elimination of a ceiling on annual bonuses, arguing that a cap on bonuses for railway workers had already been lifted.</p>
<p>Gupta said union leaders would decide later on Friday whether to call off the strike and wait for a cabinet meeting, tentatively set for Tuesday, to agree their demands.</p>
<p>The strike has crippled government mail services with some 15 million letters piling up in the general post office in the financial capital Bombay, the Press Trust of India said.</p>
<p>The strike was a windfall for private courier services, which said they were flooded with requests.</p>
<p>Telecommunications services, which are largely automated, have fared better. But operator-related services and repair and maintenance were badly disrupted.</p>
<p>Several dozen postal workers burned an effigy of Communications Minister Varma on Friday in front of New Delhi's main post office.</p>
<p>Gupta said senior officials in the Communications Ministry had agreed at a meeting on Friday morning that a 3,500 rupee ($100) ceiling on annual bonus payments would be raised.</p>
<p>He said the ministry had also agreed that striking workers would be paid for any days missed during the work stoppage, which began on Wednesday and quickly spread across the country.</p>
<p>&quot;They (government officials) are confident that the issue will be settled at the next cabinet meeting,&quot; Gupta said.</p>
<p>V.L. Narayan, telecommunications expert at the Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FICCI), said there were no reliable estimates of the value of business that may have been lost due to the strike.</p>
<p>He said companies in India were accustomed to breakdowns in power and phone services, and many had begun resorting to private courier companies to deliver mail.</p>
<p>Indian newspapers routinely devote large amounts of space to telephone subscribers' complaints.</p>
<p>A front-page cartoon in The Times of India on Friday showed a woman picking up a telephone receiver and telling her husband: &quot;It's called off and they have returned to work, I think. The phone has gone dead again.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
