<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144806" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Bank Negara Indonesia's IPO seen oversubscribed.</title>
<headline>Bank Negara Indonesia's IPO seen oversubscribed.</headline>
<byline>Helen Lumban Gaol</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's largest state-owned bank, Bank Negara Indonesia 1946 (BNI), should get an overwhelming response when a quarter of its equity is floated on the local bourse next month, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>BNI set an offer price on Thursday of 850 rupiah for its shares. It plans to offer about 1.1 billion shares to the public from November 4 to 7 and it will list the shares on November 25.</p>
<p>Analysts said the stock should be heavily oversubscribed as the offer price is attractive.</p>
<p>&quot;The IPO (Initial Public Offering) price of 850 rupiah ($0.37) will put the share at 8.2 times 1997 earnings based on the forecast collected by the underwriter. At this price we regard the IPO as attractive,&quot; said Stephan Schmidle, an analyst with Kleinwort Benson Securities (Asia) Ltd.</p>
<p>Another analyst from a Hong Kong-based firm said the total market capitalisation of BNI was about $1.6 billion, which would give it considerable weighting on the Jakarta index.</p>
<p>&quot;BNI will be among the heaviest stocks and the most liquid bank shares listed in Jakarta. Foreign fund managers must include BNI in their portfolios if they buy Indonesia stocks. So I think it will be eyed by many institutional buyers,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Brokers said the announcement by BNI of an offer price for its shares had stalled trade on Friday since the morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall trading is affected by the offer price of BNI. The market sees the price as meeting everybody's expectations and the issue could be oversubscribed,&quot; said a broker from a major local firm.</p>
<p>Brokers said many traders were cashing in earlier gains to subscribe to BNI as the stock is the single largest IPO during 1996.</p>
<p>Analysts pointed to the country-wide network of BNI and its single-digit price earnings ratio as prime factors for its attractiveness.</p>
<p>&quot;With the single digit PE, BNI is a really attractive bank share,&quot; said one analyst from a Singapore-based firm. She added her estimated net forecast for 1996 was conservative, in line with the company forecast of 326.2 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>&quot;...Our earnings per share target for 1996 is 107 rupiah and average EPS growth of 14 percent per annum for the next three years,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Schmidle said Kleinwort Benson estimated earnings for 1997 at 448.7 billion rupiah and 525.1 billion rupiah in 1998 with EPS growth of 11.9 percent for 1997 and 17.0 percent for 1998.</p>
<p>He said BNI would be one of the main beneficiaries of increasing monetary intermediation, or the extent to which people use financial institutions, in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;...There are only 23 million bank accounts for a population of 200 million people,&quot; Schmidle said.</p>
<p>He added that one tangible sign of rising intermediation is the increasing use of the bank system for salary payments, which are currently cash-based.</p>
<p>&quot;With its nationwide network and solid &quot;brand image&quot; in the domestic population, BNI will be a prime beneficiary of this shift,&quot; he added. ($1 = 2,325 rupiah)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
