<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="144916" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia wheat sector to protect private AWB.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia wheat sector to protect private AWB.</headline>
<byline>Michael Byrnes</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's A$3-A$4 billion wheat export industry has agreed that the Australian Wheat Board's (AWB) monopoly export powers will remain intact and that the body will be protected from infiltration or take-over by outside groups despite partial privatisation next year.</p>
<p>A new structure for the AWB, expected to be passed by legislation next year, is being set ahead of the Australian government's withdrawal of guarantees on AWB borrowings and the AWB competition policy review, both set for 1999.  </p>
<p>A plan privately advanced by the AWB that the A$350 million grower-owned Wheat Industry Fund (WIF) be opened up to non-grower investors through the issue of &quot;B&quot; class shares, to accompany the issue of &quot;A&quot; shares to growers, had been rejected in meetings concluded this week, Xavier Martin, New South Wales Farmers' Association Grains Committee Chairman, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;(There was) major resistance to outside shares,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Martin said the potential of groups such as major Japanese trading houses to influence AWB wheat export policy was one reason why outside shareholdings were rejected. The Japanese had definitely become more interested in wheat, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Growers are very aware of the travails coal, as another major export commodity, has had to bear ... there's no way that they can allow (this in wheat),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The growers have a strong view that allowing external capital is the thin edge of the wedge to what they see as a thoroughly modern marketing tool of coordinated export selling.&quot;</p>
<p>Partial privatisation of the AWB from next year will involve at least one subsidiary acting under company law, operating in AWB pool management, cash trading and value-adding activities.  </p>
<p>The WIF, which will provide backing for AWB borrowings, is to be moved into a trust fund until the 1999 competition policy review is settled, according to decisions taken this week by a working party of Grains Council of Australia, the AWB and the Department of Primary Industries and Energy.</p>
<p>Under the decisions, the AWB's export monopoly will be held by a statutory authority, which will delegate its powers to a pool operating company, Martin said. This company will finance pool advances from the capital trust.  </p>
<p>While operation of the single desk by the statutory authority and its operating company will not occur until 1999, major change will begin to occur at the AWB from next year, especially involving financial matters, Martin told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the trust will be set up reasonably promptly so that the finance markets (can have) a level of confidence in how the trustees are managing that capital base,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>With the fund expected to reach A$500 million to A$600 million, the capital base was targeted to produce the same creditworthiness as presently commanded by the AWB, he said.  </p>
<p>This was important because potential premiums on fundraising would have a significant impact on future wheat-growing and even on land-values for farmers who did not grow wheat, he said.</p>
<p>Under arrangements agreed on by the working party, the decision to put the WIF into trust came after abandonment of a push for the fund to be revolved back to growers. A revolving fund was seen as a cumbersome, illiquid process, Martin said.</p>
<p>Restructuring the AWB would cause marketing changes within Australia which would require end-users to buy wheat further ahead -- pool wheat would not automatically be immediately available, Martin said.  </p>
<p>But there would be no change to export marketing, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
