<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145002" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore gas oil swaps up with IPE, Indian demand.</title>
<headline>Singapore gas oil swaps up with IPE, Indian demand.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gas oil swaps firmed on Friday following a technical rebound in the west and expectations by some players that Indian Oil Corp (IOC) would buy up to 600,000-tonnes for December, traders said.</p>
<p>November gas oil swaps were quoted at $30.20/$30.35 in the mid-afternoon. Levels had already firmed by midday with trades at $30.10, up from Thursday's close of $29.90/$29.95, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market fell yesterday evening as the IPE (International Petroleum Exchange) at that time was down about $5.75 per tonne,&quot; one broker said.  </p>
<p>November gas oil futures on London's IPE recovered sharply later and closed down $2.00 at $223.75 per tonne.</p>
<p>Similarly, November heating oil on NYMEX traded to a session low of 68.90 cents before recovering to close at 70.49. In after hours ACCESS trading, heating oil continued to pare its lossess to trade  at 70.95 cents at 1520 GMT.</p>
<p>On IOC's purchase of diesel for delivery in December which is likely to be awarded late Friday, traders said that market expectations are at around 400,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;It won't be a bumper award. It should be within market expectations,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>But others said they won't be surprised if IOC does the unexpected and buys alot. Some traders said that IOC may buy up to 600,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>IOC cancelled its November tender due to port congestions.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
