<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145017" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia 1997 jobless rate seen falling to 2.5 pct.</title>
<headline>Malaysia 1997 jobless rate seen falling to 2.5 pct.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's unemployment rate is projected to fall slightly to 2.5 percent in 1997 against an estimated 2.6 percent in 1996 and 2.8 percent in 1995, the Finance Ministry said on Friday in its annual Economic Report.</p>
<p>With virtually full employment, there was pressure on wages, the ministry said. The average wage rose 8.6 percent during the first seven months of 1996, compared with a 10.5 percent increase in the similar 1995 period.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase in real average wages, estimated at 7.1 percent, (was) not commensurate with the 3.9 percent increase in productivity,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>Employment is forecast to rise by 3.2 percent in 1997 to 8.4 million from an estimated 3.4 percent gain this year to 8.2 million, the report said.</p>
<p>In 1995, the country's employment showed a 4.1 percent gain to 7.9 million. Malaysia's population is forecast to rise to 21.2 million in 1996 and 21.7 million in 1997 from 20.7 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Manufacturing would continue to account for the bulk of total employment, rising to 27 percent in 1996 from 25.9 percent in 1995, it said.  </p>
<p>The rise in total employment for 1996 stemmed from increased investment in construction activities, such as the Kuala Lumpur City Centre, Kuala Lumpur International Airport as well as in commercial and residential property development.</p>
<p>The airport project alone accounted for more than half the new jobs created, the ministry said.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 201-4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
