<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145254" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo Nikkei ends down for fifth session.</title>
<headline>Tokyo Nikkei ends down for fifth session.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Tokyo Nikkei average fell for the fifth successive day on Friday as investor sentiment was bogged down by uncertainties over a new coalition government as well as the state of the economy, brokers said.  </p>
<p>The benchmark Nikkei ended down for the fifth consecutive session, losing over 870 points in the process. The last time it hit a five-session losing streak was in July. Between July 4 and July 10, it shed about 600 points.</p>
<p>Brokers said rounds of arbitrage-linked selling ,which gave the market its gloomy tone, were inspired by falls in U.S. markets overnight.</p>
<p>On Thursday on Wall Street, the Dow slid below the 6,000 level, closing 44 points lower at about 5,992. In Chicago, December Nikkei 225 futures lost 155.0 points to close at 20,910, below the 21,090 Osaka close.  </p>
<p>&quot;There was some domestic investor buying, but most of it was overwhelmed by foreign investor selling, futures-linked selling and dealers squaring longs created last week ahead of the elections,&quot; said Yasuo Ueki, general manager at Nikko Securities.</p>
<p>Before last Sunday's election, investors and dealers bought shares, confident the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) would win an overall majority in the Lower House of parliament.</p>
<p>But the dominant partner in Japan's outgoing coalition government fell 12 seats short of a majority.  </p>
<p>The thought of a wobbly coalition framework and economic policies which would be activated only after the emergence of a new government froze investors, brokers said, forcing them to the sidelines for most of the week.</p>
<p>But despite the subdued, sell-dominant market atmosphere, brokers said a free-fall was unlikely.</p>
<p>&quot;Margin trade expiries also helped push the index down today, but there were also institutional investors preventing falls, which means there is support,&quot; a &quot;Big Four&quot; broker said.</p>
<p>The broader TOPIX index fell 13.33 points, or 0.85 percent, to 1,557.76.  </p>
<p>The Nikkei 300 lost 2.57 points or 0.87 percent to stand at 291.99. The second section index slid 7.14 points or 0.35 percent to 2,032.64, with a turnover of 11.59 million shares, little changed from the 11.04 million on Thurday.</p>
<p>With few factors to steer the market, brokers said investors were scrutinising interim earning results and forecasts, looking for issues to buy or sell.</p>
<p>&quot;The mood is so weak the market is reacting more sharply to firms expecting to falter, rather than to those which are seen improving,&quot; Yamaichi's Kobayashi said.  </p>
<p>Sharp Corp dropped 60 yen to 1,720 yen, depressed by an earnings forecast which was not was good as expected, brokers said. It ranked 15th on the large trade volume list.</p>
<p>Japan Tobacco briefly rose to 84,000 yen on news that the company and its U.S. partner will apply for approval in the United States to market a jointly developed drug for treating HIV, the virus that causes AIDS, brokers said.</p>
<p>It closed unchanged from the Thursday close of 80,000 yen.</p>
<p>Issues included in the Nikkei 225 average with few shares available for trade fell. Tokyo Dome Corp shed 70 yen to close at 2,200 yen.  </p>
<p>&quot;Issues with slim volumes available for trade are bearing the brunt of small-lot, arbitrage-linked selling because of their low liquidity,&quot; a trader at a second-tier brokerage said.</p>
<p>Mori Denki Manufacturing Co slipped on news of a new share issuance. It closed 44 down yen at 551 yen.</p>
<p>Retreating issues totalled 798 and advancing 283, while 160 were unchanged.</p>
<p>The main gaining sector was credit/lease. The leading decliners were mining, fisheries, sea transport, warehouse, transport equipment and insurance.</p>
<p>--Masako Iijima, Tokyo Equities Desk (81-3-3432-9052)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97412">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
