<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145343" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: PRESS DIGEST - Taiwan newspapers - Oct 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Taiwan newspapers - Oct 25.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Taiwan press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Newspaper headlines:</p>
<p>CHINA TIMES - Taipei prosecutors find one senior police official involved in a video game scandal, granting the official bail after questioning.</p>
<p>UNITED DAILY NEWS - President Lee Teng-hui urges Taiwanese people to conduct spiritual reform on the date marking the 51st anniversary of Taiwan's emergence from Japanese control.</p>
<p>Cabinet approves proposal to spend more than T$600 billion (US$22 billion) in the next nine years to reconstruct residences for military servicemen and their families.</p>
<p>COMMERCIAL TIMES - China Airlines' planned release of 16 percent of its shares overseas will be aimed at foreign airline companies.</p>
<p>Foreign-flagged but China-owned vessels will be allowed to sail to designated Taiwan harbours.</p>
<p>ECONOMIC DAILY NEWS - Finance Ministry suggests all government offices to reduce spending by three percent.</p>
<p>Third-quarter balance of payments is initially estimated to record a surplus of US$1.6 billion.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
