<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145530" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - Microvision paints video screen on human eye.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Microvision paints video screen on human eye.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>LAKE BUENA VISTA, Florida 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A soldier looks up from his foxhole, scans the terrain with his naked eye and immediately sees hidden land mines, artillery and even troops behind walls.</p>
<p>A doctor looks down at her patient and sees not only the body but a detailed outline of the organs and vessels beneath the skin and knows exactly where to begin the procedure.</p>
<p>This Superman-like vision, which does away with video monitors by beaming information directly from a transmitting device on to the eye, could soon become a reality with work funded by Microvision Inc of Seattle. The transmitting device could be small enough to be hand held.</p>
<p>Microvision has been developing a technology called Virtual Retinal Display, which creates a virtual video screen for viewers by rapidly scanning an image directly on to the retina with a pinpoint beam of light.</p>
<p>Developed by the University of Washington's Human Interface Technology Laboratory, the laser beam paints rows of pixels on to the eye. The viewer sees the information, or picture, as if a full colour screen were hanging in the air just in front of them.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the utter simplicity of it and that is the beauty of it,&quot; said Richard Rutkowski, president of Microvision, which demonstrated the technology with a prototype at a recent conference in Lake Buena Vista, sponsored by the Gartner group.</p>
<p>Microvision is backed by a number of &quot;high net worth individuals&quot; in the Seattle area, according to Microvision Vice President Todd McIntyre. The company went public on August 27 and raised a further $16 million.</p>
<p>Although commercial products are not expected until the third quarter of 1998, the company believes it is well capitalised. &quot;The funding we now have is going to carry us for sometime,&quot; said McIntyre.</p>
<p>Rutkowski said the concept of &quot;augmented vision&quot; could prove popular in the military, medical and industrial fields where information -- diagrams of various sorts -- could be superimposed over the regular vision to provide intricate details.</p>
<p>The U.S. Army has been keen to find ways to deliver its storehouse of information gathered from satellites and the like to the soldier in the field. Conventional devices such as laptop computers have not proved practical but the idea of using Visual Retinal Display has been gaining interest among the military pesonnel, company officials say.</p>
<p>In the consumer field, one application would be to use the technology in conjunction with the cellular phone. Instead of just talking and listening to voice mail messages, the phone could be equipped with a small opening to beam up information to allow an image of electronic mail or even access to the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;It's obviously a stunning development in display technology, something that seems like science fiction but is actually here today,&quot;  said Gartner analyst Jackie Fenn in a panel discussion with Microvision.</p>
<p>Fenn, however, wondered if people would not fear doing damage to their eyesight with such revolutionary technology.</p>
<p>Rutkowski said the scientific answer was that the amount of photon energy coming out of the system, depending on the application, was anywhere from 10,000 to 100,000 times less light than that considered safe by the American National Standards Institute.&quot;</p>
<p>But he acknowledged &quot;perception&quot; was sometimes one of the toughest hurdles in the introduction of new technology.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a challenge as you educate your prospective customer base to assure people that this is in fact an entirely safe technology to use,&quot; Rutkowski said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAKE BUENA VISTA, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
