<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145510" id="root" date="1996-10-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks open lower, Rhone shares rally.</title>
<headline>French stocks open lower, Rhone shares rally.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks opened weaker on Friday, pressured by Wall Street's fall below 6,000 points and lower bond prices.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index was down 6.98 points or 0.32 percent at 2,144.79 at 0900 GMT while the CAC-40 October futures contract was 11.50 points lower at 2,145.50.</p>
<p>The bourse, which has trailed the rise in the U.S. and other European stockmarkets and remains well below its 1994 all-time high, is less volatile on the downside than other markets.</p>
<p>Among the CAC stocks, Rhone-Poulenc shares were up 1.82 percent at 145.10 francs after the group announced a rise in third-quarter net income to 756 million francs from 669 million.</p>
<p>It said that by September 30, it had sold six billion francs in non-strategic assets and expects to sell assets worth between seven and nine billion francs by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Lagardere shares, which have risen sharply since the government said it preferred Lagardere's bid for Thomson SA over a rival offer from Alcatel Alsthom, were down 1.65 percent at 167.20 francs.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Arthuis said on Thursday that Thomson's debt would be 28 billion francs at the end of the year, up from 23.8 billion at the end of 1995.</p>
<p>Also, the privatisation has come under political fire, notably for the one-franc sale price.</p>
<p>&quot;(The newspaper) La Tribune notes that while defending the agreement, the Minister of Finance has left himself an out, noting the privatisation commission -- which is to give its verdict in mid-December -- can block the deal if it has problems with the deal,&quot; a brokerage house said in its daily comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
