<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145659" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: 200,000 more refugees flee in eastern Zaire.</title>
<headline>200,000 more refugees flee in eastern Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Peter Smerdon</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Attacks by Tutsi rebels forced up to 200,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees to flee a camp in eastern Zaire on Saturday, bringing the total uprooted in the region to nearly half a million, officials said.</p>
<p>Aid officials said heavily armed attackers wounded some 30 refugees overnight in and around Kibumba camp north of Goma city. It is the second largest Rwandan refugee camp in Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;Some 200,000 refugees from Kibumba camp near Goma are heading down the road towards the city,&quot; said a U.N. official, who declined to be identified.</p>
<p>Aid workers in Goma said loud explosions, apparently mortar bombs, were heard in and around Kibumba on Friday and Saturday.</p>
<p>A mass exodus in the Goma area of North Kivu province was feared by aid officials for the past week since an offensive by Tutsi Banyamulenge rebels against Zairean troops uprooted nearly 300,000 Burundian and Rwandan refugees in South Kivu province.</p>
<p>The Goma area is home to some 700,000 of the 1.1 million Rwandan Hutu refugees who fled to eastern Zaire in 1994 in fear of reprisals for the Hutu-orchestrated genocide of hundreds of thousands of minority Tutsis.</p>
<p>Elodie Martel, head of the Goma office of the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies, said 3,000 of the refugees from Kibumba camp arrived in Goma city in the afternoon.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of them are still on the road. Others have fled either into the national park or towards the Rwanda border. Those arriving in Goma are being diverted to Mugunga camp.&quot;</p>
<p>Mugunga already has some 150,000 refugees.</p>
<p>She said the Zairean commander in Goma had lost contact with his troops who were supposed to guard Kibumba camp.</p>
<p>Paul Stromberg, a spokesman for the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), said U.N. and Zairean officials wanted to stop the refugees entering Goma city and redirect them to other camps or across the border into Rwanda if they wanted to return.</p>
<p>Stromberg said UNHCR planned to pull out non-essential staff by air from Goma on Saturday because insecurity meant no foreign aid workers could reach camps in the area.</p>
<p>Aid workers in Goma said the town of Rutshuru, 10 km from the Katale refugee camp and 50 km (30 miles) north of Goma, had fallen to Tutsi rebels after heavy fighting with troops.</p>
<p>The town is on a key route from Zaire to western Uganda.</p>
<p>The Hutu refugees in eastern Zaire have resisted calls from the Rwandan government and persuasion from UNHCR to return, saying they fear persecution by the Tutsi-dominated Rwandan army.</p>
<p>A Rwandan Hutu lobby group, the Rally for the Return of Refugees and Democracy in Rwanda, said the refugees were fleeing Tutsi rebels and Rwandan troops in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;The refugees have so far dodged the trap and are braving the hostile environment in the hills and forests of South Kivu, where they are likely to die a slow but sure death,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>It said in North Kivu Rwandan troops were poised to attack the refugee camps to escort their inmates to Rwanda at gunpoint.</p>
<p>Rwanda has denied Zairean accusations that its Tutsi troops are fighting alongside the Tutsi rebels in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>The rebels say they are fighting to resist expulsion from Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
