<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145651" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Sale of Mahatma Gandhi letters thrown into doubt.</title>
<headline>Sale of Mahatma Gandhi letters thrown into doubt.</headline>
<byline>Helen Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A puzzled London auction house said on Friday it hoped to go ahead with the sale of writings by Indian nationalist leader Mahatma Gandhi, even though the seller has said he wants a postponement.</p>
<p>Gandhi's former secretary, Venkataraman Kalyanam, who has kept the papers for nearly 50 years, told Reuters in Madras on Thursday that he had sent a fax asking auctioneers to put off the sale. Phillips auction house said it had not heard from him.</p>
<p>&quot;The information we received from Reuters is in conflict with our understanding regarding the instructions for the sale,&quot; said Elizabeth Merry, head of Phillips' manuscripts department.</p>
<p>&quot;However, Phillips is very concerned that the wishes of all the relevant parties are respected and we are doing everything possible to clarify the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>Kalyanam, 75, said the Indian government had told him that selling the papers, dating from the last six months of Gandhi's life before he was assassinated in 1948, would put valuable national heirlooms into the hands of speculators.</p>
<p>The Indian High Commission in London said it had been concerned at news of the sale and had passed newspaper reports about it to the Culture Commission in New Delhi.</p>
<p>But a spokesman declined to comment on suggestions that it had pressured Kalyanam to abandon the sale. &quot;We asked the Culture Commission to look into it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The collection of handwritten papers includes letters to Britain's wartime prime minister, Winston Churchill, and Louis Mountbatten, the last British viceroy of India.</p>
<p>Many of the 450 pages in Gandhi's crabbed handwriting are in a cheap notebook and others were written on the backs of used envelopes by the environmentally-conscious leader, who led 350 million Indians in a non-violent campaign against British rule.</p>
<p>Phillips believes the sale could raise up to one million pounds ($1.60 million). Kalyanam says he does not want the money for himself but would donate it to a Hindu charity.</p>
<p>The papers, now in London, reveal Gandhi's anxieties in the months before India gained independence in 1947 and his distress at the sectarian conflicts that erupted on partition.</p>
<p>Fighting between Hindus and Moslems had turned Delhi into &quot;a city of the dead,&quot; he wrote before he fasted to try to bring peace to the Indian capital.</p>
<p>&quot;I had to be in Delhi to do or die...No Man, if he is pure, has anything more precious to give than his life,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His fast succeeded. After five days, religious leaders from the warring communities pledged to end their violence to save the life of &quot;The Great Soul&quot;.</p>
<p>Phillips said the papers had additional rarity value because they were written in English, the language Gandhi used most. Aides often translated his speeches into Hindi and then they were translated back into English.</p>
<p>&quot;At times the effect was akin to Chinese whispers&quot;, Phillips said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
