<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145676" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Oct 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Nigeria - Oct 26.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are significant stories in the Nigerian press on Saturday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>WEEKEND TIMES</p>
<p>- A racket in faking business certificates is booming in the capital Abuja where a syndicate operates in front of the headquarters of the corporate affairs commission which is charged with registering businesses, investigations show.</p>
<p>- Kaduna Textiles Ltd in the north makes spectacular turnaround with profits at 133 million naira by end March 1996 from owing 103 million naira in 1990 when it was acquired by conglomerate Churchgate Industries, Churchgate director says.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN ON SATURDAY</p>
<p>- Political associates of first Nigerian president Nnamdi Azikiwe, who died in May, vow to revive his legacies including the now liquidated African Continental Bank and West African Pilot newspaper which folded 15 years ago.</p>
<p>THISDAY</p>
<p>- Federal government sets up three committees to share assets and liabilities among the old and newly created six states in the country.</p>
<p>- President Paul Biya of Cameroon tells United Nations General Assembly in New York that his country is committed to peaceful settlement of its border dispute with Nigeria.</p>
<p>($1=80 naira)</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
