<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145644" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan secures capital to foil Islamist protest.</title>
<headline>Pakistan secures capital to foil Islamist protest.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani authorities diverted trains and blocked roads into the capital, Islamabad, on Saturday to foil a planned protest by Islamic militants, officials and witnesses said.</p>
<p>The action coincided with a general strike called by opposition parties and business groups angered by tough new economic measures designed to persuade the International Monetary Fund to resume a stalled $600 million standby loan.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Saturday's stoppage proved partly effective. Some markets and businesses were closed, but there was only limited disruption to transport and many shops and factories stayed open in cities across the country.</p>
<p>The extraordinary security measures in Islamabad were designed to prevent the opposition Jamaat-i-Islami (JI) party from carrying out plans to bring a million people to join an anti-corruption sit-in outside parliament.</p>
<p>Officials of state-run Pakistan Railways in the Punjab provincial capital of Lahore said 24 mail and passenger trains that normally pass through Rawalpindi, near Islamabad, had been diverted, suspended or cancelled. Reimbursing passengers would cost an estimated 15 million rupees ($373,000), they said.</p>
<p>Security forces used cranes to block the main highway from Lahore to Islamabad with empty containers, witnesses said. The obstacles, on the outskirts of the capital, cut the normal route to the international airport serving Islamabad and Rawalpindi.</p>
<p>Earlier, paramilitary forces were drafted into the capital, replacing police who normally guard foreign missions.</p>
<p>In another sign of tension, Islamabad's International School, mainly for American and other foreign children, announced that it would stay closed on Sunday as a precaution.</p>
<p>JI leaders said the security forces had rounded up more than 5,500 of its supporters to try to disrupt the planned sit-in.</p>
<p>Islamabad-based JI spokesman Ovais Qasim, said the party's leader, Qazi Hussain Ahmad, was in hiding. &quot;He is on the move to avoid arrest,&quot; Qasim said. &quot;He is being chased by police.&quot;</p>
<p>An Interior Ministry spokesman said the JI figure for detainees was exaggerated, but could not say how many people had been seized. He denied that the JI leader was being sought.</p>
<p>&quot;All this fuss is a smokescreen designed to hide what they know will be a failed event,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Three JI members of parliament resigned their seats in the National Assembly (lower house) on Saturday, following the example of Ahmad, who quit his seat last month in an attempt to put pressure on Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto to resign.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Naseerullah Babar on Thursday offered to release all JI detainees if the party agreed to shift the venue of its sit-in to a park in the nearby city of Rawalpindi.</p>
<p>JI rejected the offer as well as a suggestion by President Farooq Leghari that the sit-in be held in Islamabad, but not at parliament, which is close to the presidential palace, prime minister's house, government offices and diplomatic enclave.</p>
<p>Three people were killed and 60 wounded when gunfire broke out during a JI demonstration in Rawalpindi in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
