<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145724" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Former Philippine rebel area said luring investors.</title>
<headline>Former Philippine rebel area said luring investors.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former war zone in the southern Philippines is currently attracting huge interest from investors, especially from Malaysia and Indonesia, a senior government official said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Presidential assistant for Mindanao Paul Dominguez said in a memorandum to President Fidel Ramos that a number of Indonesian conglomerates have already started operating in the former stronghold of Moslem rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the signing of the historic peace agreement between the government and the MNLF, there has been a definite surge in investor interest in Mindanao,&quot; Dominguez said.</p>
<p>The Moro National Liberation Front (MNLF) ended its 24-year struggle for self-rule two months ago as it signed a peace agreement with the government.</p>
<p>MNLF chief Nur Misuari was recently elected as the governor of an autonomous area in Mindanao.</p>
<p>New Indonesian businesses include a ferry service operated by the Bakrie Brothers, a savings and development bank of the Dharmala Group, hotels by Bouraq Airlines and financial services from Lippo Bank.  </p>
<p>Dominguez also said about 300 Malaysian businessmen recently accompanied Sabah's chief minister Yong Teck Lee on an investment mission to Mindanao.</p>
<p>Several memoranda of agreements have been signed including pacts on cattle breeding, trading of processed food and marine products, and construction projects.</p>
<p>Local businessmen have also expanded their operations in Mindanao with the establishment of new sugar mills, a grains terminal, and a softdrink manufacturing plant, Dominguez said.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom 63 2 8418938 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
