<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145703" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Vatican envoy criticizes U.S. embargo against Cuba.</title>
<headline>Vatican envoy criticizes U.S. embargo against Cuba.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Visiting Vatican Foreign Minister Jean Louis Tauran criticised the longstanding U.S. embargo against Cuba on Saturday, saying the Holy See did not support &quot;imperial policies.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Isolation by blockades is not a method for international relations,&quot; Tauran told reporters before starting talks with Cuban Foreign Minister Roberto Robaina.</p>
<p>&quot;We (the Vatican) have always been faithful to the principles of international law, of non-interference in the internal affairs of states and of solidarity between peoples,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't like imperial policies,&quot; he added in remarks that were bound to be well-received by his hosts.</p>
<p>Tauran began a five-day visit to Cuba on Friday that could pave the way for a meeting between President Fidel Castro and the pope, and for a later papal visit to the communist-ruled island.</p>
<p>His comments on the U.S. embargo followed criticism last week by senior Vatican Cardinal Roger Etchegeray of a recent U.S. move to tighten the 34-year trade ban.</p>
<p>Tauran also said the Vatican would do everything possible to help Cuba on its way forward. He added that the Vatican and Cuba together could work together, not just to develop the Cuban Roman Catholic Church but to help the Cuban people.</p>
<p>On his arrival in Havana Tauran made clear that although church-state relations in Cuba had improved recently, more could be done. He said he came to encourage the church to play an active role in Cuba, indicating it should have a say in public life.</p>
<p>Tauran, the first Vatican foreign minister to be invited to Cuba by the government, brought a donation from the pope to to help victims of Hurricane Lili. The storm swept through central and western Cuba a week ago, destroying more than 5,000 homes and damaging crops and communications.</p>
<p>Tauran, who later on Saturday was holding talks with parliamentary president Ricardo Alarcon, was also likely to meet Castro during his stay although there has been no official confirmation of this.</p>
<p>His visit could help prepare for a meeting between Castro and the pope if the Cuban leader goes to Rome for a World Food Summit that the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation is holding there from Nov. 13 to 17.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources in Rome have said that if Castro sees the pope he will probably invite him to Cuba, perhaps next year. The island is the only Latin American country the pope has not visited.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
