<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145739" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul blue chips fall, but rebound seen next week.</title>
<headline>Seoul blue chips fall, but rebound seen next week.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue chips closed lower on Saturday but sentiment is expected to improve next week on expectations of interest rate cuts, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed 1.97 points lower at a provisional 791.81.</p>
<p>&quot;Profit-taking on blue chips continued. But a rebound is expected next week after this consolidation,&quot; said Yoo Jae-kyong, a broker at Daishin Securities.</p>
<p>Brokers said a bribery scandal involving former defence minister Lee Yang-ho, helped dampen sentiment.  </p>
<p>Lee was arrested on Saturday on charges of taking a 150 million won bribe in connection with an arms deal. He sacked by President Kim Young-sam last week.</p>
<p>Volume totalled 17.9 million shares for Saturday's half-day trading, compared with 26.7 million shares on Friday. Decliners outpaced gainers 514 to 339 with 142 unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said the central Bank of Korea's plan to lower the bank's reserve requirement ratios to an average of 5.5 percent from November 8 would lead to a cut in overall interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations of lower interest rates will buoy sentiment next week with the index testing 850,&quot; Yoo said.  </p>
<p>Samsung Electronics Co Ltd, fell 1,000 won to 62,000, while Pohang Iron and Steel Co dropped 700 won to 43,000. DACOM lost 2,000 won to 127,000 and LG Electronics fell 100 won to 13,700.</p>
<p>--Kim Myong-hwan (822) 727 5645</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
