<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145718" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Weak prices harming rubber trade, Malaysia say.</title>
<headline>Weak prices harming rubber trade, Malaysia say.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The global rubber trade is being hit by weak prices and Malaysia's Primary Industries Minister Lim Keng Yaik has warned consumers that driving prices lower could backfire and disrupt supply.</p>
<p>&quot;It pays in the long run to give natural rubber the fair remunerative prices which the industry seeks, otherwise, consumers will be faced with a real shortage when they need rubber, Lim told the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board's annual dinner late on Friday.</p>
<p>He said consumers were doing their best to push rubber prices to their lowest levels in Thailand, Indonesia and Malaysia -- the world's largest rubber producers -- and Singapore, the main trading centre for the commodity.</p>
<p>Lim said rapid industrialisation and rising costs in Malaysia, Indonesia and Thailand were already shrinking rubber plantations, which sometimes have to make way for more lucrative crops or property development.</p>
<p>&quot;If they don't get the prices they want, these countries may not find it worthwhile producing rubber any more,&quot; he warned.</p>
<p>Regional rubber markets have been depressed over the past two months due to thin demand from consumers, awaiting better prices after meeting their short-covering needs.</p>
<p>Lim said Malaysia's benchmark Ribbed Smoked Sheet One (RSS1) and Standard Malaysian Rubber 20 fetched average prices of 362.70 cents ($1.46) per kilogramme and 337 cents per kg in the first nine months of 1996, compared to 393.61 and 382.60 for the whole of 1995.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry said in its annual economic report on Friday that RSS1 was expected to average 370 cents a kg for the whole of 1996 and 300 cents in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we can look at this as a breather for the market, it will still be better if the prices are stable,&quot; Lim said. &quot;We certainly don't want the RSS1 to fall to around 200 cents (a kg). It should ideally be around 350 cents,&quot; Lim said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
