<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145708" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Aboriginal culture may be oldest living religion.</title>
<headline>Aboriginal culture may be oldest living religion.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's aboriginal culture may be the world's oldest living religion according to a study of &quot;Rainbow Serpent&quot; rock art in northern Australia, say Australian and British anthropologists.</p>
<p>The &quot;Rainbow Serpent&quot; is one of the sacred symbols of creation for Aborigines and a study of 107 rock paintings has found the spiritual tradition dates back 6,000 years, according to a report in The Sydney Morning Herald newspaper on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a major creation being regarded as extremely important for four to six millenia,&quot; said Australian Museum anthropologist Paul Tacon.</p>
<p>&quot;In that sense the major component of this spiritual belief system is much older than the major components of religions and spiritual belief systems found elsewhere in the world,&quot; Tacon said in the newspaper.</p>
<p>Hinduism emerged about 3,500 years ago in India and Judaism in the Middle East nearly 4,000 years ago, he said.</p>
<p>The team says that while rock art in Europe dates as far back as 20,000 years, it died out about 9,000 years ago, unlike the aboriginal &quot;Rainbow Serpent&quot; which has been continuously painted from 6,000 years to today.</p>
<p>Aborigines believe that in the &quot;Dreamtime&quot;, the begining of time, when the earth was barren and featureless, the &quot;Rainbow Serpent&quot; ploughed through the earth creating rivers and bays.</p>
<p>Tacon and fellow anthropologists from Australia and Britian's Cambridge University have published their study in the latest edition of the journal, Archaeoloy in Oceania, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>The team based its study on 137 characteristics of 107 &quot;Rainbow Serpent&quot; rock paintings in Arnhem Land in the Northern Territory and interviews with aboriginal leaders.</p>
<p>Aborigines are believed to have arrived in Australia 40,000 years ago from Southeast Asia. There are now about 300,000 Aborigines in Australia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
