<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145728" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia demands top job in rubber body INRO.</title>
<headline>Malaysia demands top job in rubber body INRO.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Primary Industries Minister Lim Keng Yaik has issued a veiled threat after demanding that Malaysia be granted the executive director's post in the International Natural Rubber Organisation (INRO).</p>
<p>&quot;Don't take us for granted. Please go back and tell your respective governments to give us a chance, so I'm not forced into a corner, to do things I'm not fond of doing,&quot; Lim told the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board dinner in Kuala Lumpur late on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are among the world's top three rubber producers with Thailand and Indonesia. They've already headed INRO and we want our chance,&quot; Lim said at the dinner, also attended by Thai and Indonesian rubber industry excutives.</p>
<p>The Kuala Lumpur-based INRO is made of up 23 major natural rubber consuming countries and six major producers. It is the nucleus of the International Natural Rubber Agreement (INRA), now the only global commodity pact with economic provisions and a buffer stock that allows the industry to buy and sell rubber to stabilise prices.  </p>
<p>INRA has already completed two agreements and is now into its third cycle -- INRA 3. Malaysia wants the top job in INRO under the current pact, saying Thailand and Indonesia have had their representatives in the post under earlier agreements.</p>
<p>Indonesia argues that Malaysia already hosts the INRO headquarters in Kuala Lumpur and as such, the executive director's post should return to Jakarta.</p>
<p>Malaysian rubber industry executives told Reuters that Lim's warning should not be taken lightly as Malaysia might back out of the INRA 3 despite having signed the agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;That's what he (Lim) might propose ... and that could complicate the pact,&quot; said a Kuala Lumpur rubber trading house senior manager, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Lim did not elaborate in his speech on Friday how he intended to get his way with the INRO job. He said the dinner was his last opportunity to address an international rubber gathering before the INRA 3 came into force in January.</p>
<p>&quot;Hopefully, when I come back from my holidays at the year-end, I'll get some good news on our bid,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The dinner is an annual event for rubber producers, consumers and traders to close ranks and set new targets or aspirations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
