<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145764" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: IMF expresses reservations on Turkish 1997 budget.</title>
<headline>IMF expresses reservations on Turkish 1997 budget.</headline>
<byline>Servet Yildirim</byline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>An IMF team assessing the Turkish economy expressed its concern over Turkey's ambitious 1997 budgetary targets and urged the government to implement an urgent anti-inflationary programme.</p>
<p>&quot;In the present situation of high inflation and a widening external current account deficit, the IMF mission urged the adoption by Turkey of a comprehensive anti-inflationary programme,&quot; the team said in a communique obtained by Reuters on Saturday.</p>
<p>Turkey introduced a zero-deficit 1997 budget draft to parliament last week, envisaging raising $8.5 billion revenue through sale of state assets and a minority stake in the telecommunications giant Turk Telekom.</p>
<p>The communique said the IMF mission welcomed the intention of the government to accelerate privatisation and strengthen tax administration.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, it expressed reservations on the feasibility of realising the tax revenue projections of the budget and the expected proceeds from privatisation and asset sales within the envisaged time frame,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The team will leave Turkey after a two-week examination of the economy hit by big public deficits and inflation running at around 80 percent.</p>
<p>The communique said the dialogue between the IMF and Turkey would be maintained through further discussions in early 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The mission also expressed its concern at the large and growing deficit of the social security system, which requires urgent measures to improve its operational balance. Firm control over expenditures would also be needed to achieve the targets.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists and businessmen say the budget targets are unrealistic, and urge the Islamist-led coalition government of Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan to implement an IMF-monitored medium-term stability programme and reach an accord with the Fund for a new stand-by arrangement.</p>
<p>The team held talks with Erbakan and Deputy Prime Minister Tansu Ciller -- who is also foreign minister -- on Friday.</p>
<p>Officials say the coalition's centre-right wing, Ciller's True Path Party (DYP), had put pressure on Erbakan -- who had opposed all deals with the IMF, World Bank and European Union in the past five years -- to reach an accord with the Fund.</p>
<p>Erbakan made no comment after the meeting with the IMF mission, but State Minister Ufuk Soylemez, a cabinet member from the DYP wing, said the dialogue with the Fund would continue.</p>
<p>Economic officials say the IMF is likely to urge Turkey to revise its 1997 targets before a stand-by deal is agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;The IMF does not endorse any unrealistic programme. It shakes their credibility,&quot; an official said.</p>
<p>Bankers say Turkey, which has sub-investment credit ratings, should win the IMF's support to borrow in international financial markets easily at reasonable costs.</p>
<p>In its reports in May and August, the IMF urged Turkey to implement a medium-term stabilisation programme including three major elements -- a fiscal tightening, structural reforms and measures designed to break &quot;inflationary inertia and entrenched inflationary expectations.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
