<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="145780" id="root" date="1996-10-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Three UN oil inspectors arrive in Baghdad.</title>
<headline>Three UN oil inspectors arrive in Baghdad.</headline>
<byline>Hassan Hafidh</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-10-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three United Nations oil inspectors arrived in Baghdad to look at oil facilities as part of the delayed deal to allow Iraq to sell limited amounts of oil, a U.N. source in Baghdad said on Saturday.</p>
<p>The inspectors will go to Iraqi oil installations in the south and to the northern town of Zakho, near the Turkish border, to trace the Iraqi-Turkish pipeline that will be used to move the bulk of the oil when the deal goes into effect.</p>
<p>Iraq and the United Nations on May 20 signed an agreement allowing Iraq oil sales worth $2 billion every six months to buy food and medicine for its people, suffering from stringent U.N. trade sanctions for the 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Arrangements to launch the plan stalled when Iraqi President Saddam Hussein sent troops into the country's north at the end of August to help a Kurdish faction fighting a rival.</p>
<p>Since then Iraq has made demands on the arrangements that the United Nations finds unacceptable, while the United States must still approve the oil pricing formula, already endorsed by the other Security Council members.</p>
<p>Some United Nations envoys in New York have said they do not expect the deal to be put into effect for months.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim (of the inspcectors' visit) is to check (Iraq's) oil facilities in the south and the north and oil measurement equipment,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Iraq's advance into the north -- effectively out of its control since the 1991 Gulf War -- led the U.S. to retaliate by firing cruise missiles at military installations in the south.</p>
<p>The Kurdish fighitng in the north, meanwhile, halted this week under a U.S.-sponsored ceasefire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
