<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146042" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Last US nukes gone from UK base, group claims.</title>
<headline>Last US nukes gone from UK base, group claims.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>British anti-nuclear lobbyists said on Sunday that the United States had removed its last nuclear weapons from Britain by shifting 90 bombs from Lakenheath air force base in eastern England.</p>
<p>The Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament said the B-61s, tactical gravity bombs loaded onto fighter aircraft such as the F-111, had been at the base since the mid-1980s.</p>
<p>It said its observers, who regularly watch U.S. bases had seen large missile carrying trucks leaving Lakenheath, which used to be a major U.S. Air Force installation.</p>
<p>The base now appeared to have a skeleton crew on duty, with television cameras along the perimeter fence inoperative.</p>
<p>&quot;While it is possible the bombs may have been moved elsewhere, there have been no reports from local CND groups near other USAF bases of any large-scale movements or heightened security that would suggest the bombs had been moved there instead,&quot; said CND spokesman Eddie Goncalves.</p>
<p>&quot;Private chats with a couple of people inside the MoD (Ministry of Defence) seem to confirm that,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If the American nuclear presence in Britain really has come to an end, then this has absolutely enormous implications. The end of Britain's role as America's unsinkable aircraft carrier closes a major chapter in post-World War Two history.&quot;</p>
<p>At the height of the Cold War, U.S. air bases were liberally sprinkled across Britain, especially east Anglia. But the bases have been gradually closing, especially since the collapse of the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>At its peak in 1961, the U.S. military presence in Britain included 80,000 troops and civilian support staff. Long-range bombers such as B-52s, fighters such as F-4s and F-111s and spy planes like the U-2 and SR-71 were all based in Britain.</p>
<p>Lakenheath was also used as a weapons storage depot.</p>
<p>Both U.S. and British defence officials declined to comment on the CND report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
