<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146061" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Britons drink more wine but shun local vintage.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Britons drink more wine but shun local vintage.</headline>
<byline>Dale Faulken</byline>
<dateline>CHUDLEIGH, England 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britons are drinking more wine than ever but they won't touch the local vintage.</p>
<p>&quot;English producers make good, quality wine but we have still to convince the British public,&quot; admitted Tony Wakeling, owner of the Chudleigh Vineyard in southwest England.</p>
<p>The traditional English pub, once a bastion of beer drinkers, has seen wine sales soar by nearly 20 percent between 1991 and 1995. But patrons invariably opt for French, Italian, Spanish, German or so-called New World wines.</p>
<p>&quot;English wine accounts for less then 0.3 percent of total British consumption,&quot; said Wakeling, who annually produces around 6,000 bottles of white wine on his three-and-a-half acre (1.5-hectare) vineyard which overlooks the scenic Dartmoor National Park.</p>
<p>He says the problem stems from a combination of poor marketing as well as the public's ignorance of the variety and quality of English wines.</p>
<p>&quot;Retail outlets put English wines on the bottom shelf, out of view,&quot; Wakeling said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not in the public's eye, it tends to be a bit pricey and consumers are reluctant to pay one or two more pounds for what they believe is a comparable wine.&quot;</p>
<p>But Wakeling says the British public &quot;in a high proportion of cases&quot; is not comparing like with like. The majority of supermarket purchases are of blended wines made up from several estates whereas the English wine is from a single estate.</p>
<p>&quot;If you go to buy estate-bottled and grown French wine you will pay a lot of money for it -- probably more than for the comparable English wine,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ian Berwick, head of the United Kingdom Vineyards Association (UKVA), which represents Britain's 420 registered vineyards, believes the problem is more deeply rooted.</p>
<p>&quot;The perception in the British public's mind is that if it's foreign it must be better,&quot; said Berwick. Like the nation's car, clothing, and motorbike industries, wine drinkers suffer from a national inferiority complex.</p>
<p>&quot;If you go to France and take French cars off the road you're left with wide open spaces. In this country, if you take English cars off the road, you are still left with a traffic jam.&quot;</p>
<p>Berwick said English wine has improved dramatically over the past 15 years as wine makers become more skilled and as the vines themselves grow older.</p>
<p>&quot;The quality of the wine improves as the vines age. The mere fact that the vines are getting older will show through in the wines,&quot; he said, adding that English wines have started to win accolades in international wine competitions.</p>
<p>Berwick's comments come on the heels of news that Germany is launching its first major new wines since Liebfraumilch was introduced 100 years ago.</p>
<p>The dry wines are designed for the middle price range which popular New World wines have recently made their own.</p>
<p>Britain has been chosen as the first country to receive the wines because it is Germany's biggest export market.</p>
<p>&quot;This is German wine trying to rid itself of its cheap and sweet image,&quot; said Tan Harrington of the British-based German Wine Information Service.</p>
<p>Most of the 14,000 hectolitres of wine made in Britain is white but increasingly good red wine can be found, Berwick said.</p>
<p>The 1995 British output is dwarfed by the 50 million hectolitres produced last year by France, the 64 million from Italy, 45 million from Germany and 40 million from Spain.</p>
<p>The higher volume allows the big producers, like the Germans, to undercut English producers on price.</p>
<p>The new German wines will be in shops by Christmas selling from four pounds ($6.25) to five pounds ($7.80), the price segment which now accounts for 12 percent of the market compared with just four percent three years ago.</p>
<p>English wines tend to be priced well over the five pound level. &quot;We just don't have the financial muscle to compete,&quot; said Wakeling. &quot;But once people try our wines, they will come back for more.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHUDLEIGH, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
