<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146106" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatia reburies WW2 foes together.</title>
<headline>Croatia reburies WW2 foes together.</headline>
<dateline>OMIS, Croatia 1996-10-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The remains of about 100 soldiers from Croatia's World War Two fascist army were reburied in a low-key ceremony on Sunday alongside anti-Nazi Partisan fighters, despite Jewish outrage.</p>
<p>Some 6,000 people followed the coffins wrapped in Croatian national flag to the Vrisovci cemetery, outside the Adriatic seaside town of Omis.</p>
<p>The coffins contained the remains of elite Ustasha and regular army soldiers, as well as two partisans, killed in battle 50 years ago. Traffic on the Adriatic main road was suspended while the column made its way to the cemetery.</p>
<p>A memorial ceremony at the picturesque graveyard on a hill overlooking the coast was attended by local and several higher state officials, Roman Catholic priests and members of Croatia's contemporary armed forces.</p>
<p>Despite the controversy there was nothing extraordinary about the ceremony itself, which was marked by funeral music and the sound of weeping from a few elderly women.</p>
<p>The remains had previously been recovered from unmarked mass graves around the town, where bodies of the killed were dumped haphazardly in 1945.</p>
<p>Croatia's 1941-45 Nazi puppet Ustasha regime massacred many thousands of Jews and Serbs. In 1991, Croatia won independence from communist Yugoslavia under a nationalist government that has been accused of whitewashing the fascist past.</p>
<p>The reburial was requested by descendants of Ustasha soldiers who were long distressed that their loved ones had not been properly buried by Yugoslav communist authorities at the end of World War Two.</p>
<p>Officials said the ceremony was a private family affair, but Slobodna Dalmacija daily said the reburial was financed from Omis town funds. It was meant to symbolise post-war reconciliation of all Croats, the daily said.</p>
<p>An association of anti-fascist war veterans, bitterly opposing the reburial, said in a statement they thought it was &quot;foolish to reconcile fascism and anti-fascism... It represents attempts to embellish history&quot;.</p>
<p>The Simon Wiesenthal Centre, a prominent Jewish group that monitors respect for the victims of Nazism and investigates alleged Nazi war criminals who may still be living, strongly protested to the Croatian government over the Omis reburial.</p>
<p>It urged the Croatian parliament to withdraw its involvement in the ceremony and cancel the reburial.</p>
<p>President Franjo Tudjman stirred an uproar last April when he said he wanted to rebury the bones of Croatian fascists at a Yugoslav-built memorial to Jews and Serbs slain at the Ustasha's Jasenovac concentration camp.</p>
<p>But Jewish protests forced him to shelve the proposal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OMIS, Croatia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
