<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146280" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: French Coface signs credit risk cover with Jordan.</title>
<headline>French Coface signs credit risk cover with Jordan.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>French export insurance company Coface signed on Sunday with Jordan's Loan Guarantee Corporation an accord to extend credit risk cover to local exporters in world markets, officials said.</p>
<p>Jordan's Central Bank Governor Ziyad Fariz told reporters at the signing ceremony that the French insurance group's provision to extend credit risk guarantees would boost Jordanian exporters competitiveness in global markets.</p>
<p>&quot;In the case of Jordan which is liberalising its economy, the accord will enhance export led growth,&quot; Fariz said.</p>
<p>Chairman of Coface, Francois David, said the accord would help in particular a thrust towards European markets by Jordanian exporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We think there is a high potential for growth...We know right now that there are a lot of Jordan firms who want to export to Europe but feel they do not know the European market well and feel there is a risk for them,&quot; said David.</p>
<p>Jordan Loan Guarantee Corporation (JLGC) was set up in 1994 to help banks to provide venture capital for entrepreneurs in productive sectors which banks traditionally shy away from in favour of large customers.</p>
<p>The Central Bank has a key 42 percent stake in its present 10 million dinar ($14 million) capital -- with the rest from private banks, the chambers of commerce and industry and two insurance companies.</p>
<p>JLGC is also expanding in the field of widening export credit guarantees to manufacturers as part of a government led-strategy to promote export oriented industry, a key element of wider IMF-directed reforms to liberalise the Jordanian economy.</p>
<p>David said the accord was also part of the French firms global expansion &quot;which helps Jordan and it helps us in our international strategy.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the accord with Jordan was the second in the region, citing an earlier accord with Oman signed last year. Most of Coface's similar accords are in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>JLGC sees the accord as helping to widen commercial risk gurantees provided to Jordanian exports and tapping Coface's world wide data base for potential clients for Jordanian goods.</p>
<p>-- Amman Newsroom +9626-623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
