<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146212" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Patten understands deputy's decision.</title>
<headline>HK's Patten understands deputy's decision.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Governor Chris Patten said on Sunday he understood why his deputy Anson Chan was staying out of the race to lead the territory after the British leave next year.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure that people will understand and sympathise with her arguments and will agree very much with what she has said,&quot; Patten told reporters at Kai Tak airport after returning from an official trip to Britain.</p>
<p>Hong Kong will revert to China at midnight on June 30, next year. The territory's first post-colonial leader will be chosen by a 400-member selection board in December.</p>
<p>Chan, the colony's chief secretary and the popular choice to succeed Patten, annouced on Saturday that she would not be joining the race for the top post.</p>
<p>&quot;After careful consideration of all the relevant factors governing the selection process and having consulted my senior colleagues within the civil service, I have decided not to put my name forward as a candidate for the chief executive post,&quot; said Chan, who is head of Hong Kong's civil service.</p>
<p>Chan has consistently topped polls as the most preferred choice to lead the territory after the handover, although she had declined to state her intentions until now.</p>
<p>Popularity will count for little since the selection board will by chosen by a China-appointed Preparatory Committee, however. The committee is responsible for overseeing Hong Kong's transfer of sovereignty.</p>
<p>The front-runners in the chief executive contest are shipping tycoon Tung Chee-hwa, Hong Kong's outgoing Chief Justice Sir Ti Liang Yang, billionarie businessman Peter Woo, the son-in-law of late shipping magnate Sir Yue-kong Pao, and former Appeal Court judge Simon Li.</p>
<p>Tung and Li had officially registered their candidacy on Saturday, while Yang and Woo and any other eligible parties have until Monday to file their candidacy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
