<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146255" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Settler shoots at Arab homes in Hebron - witnesses.</title>
<headline>Settler shoots at Arab homes in Hebron - witnesses.</headline>
<dateline>HEBRON, West Bank 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Jewish settler fired shots at Arab houses in the West Bank town of Hebron on Sunday but caused no casualties, Palestinian witnesses said.</p>
<p>Israel Radio said two settlers shot in the air after Palestinians stoned their car from rooftops near the Tomb of the Patriarchs.</p>
<p>Witnesses said soldiers detained one settler and took his gun away.</p>
<p>Some 400 settlers live in Hebron, home to 100,000 Palestinians and a flashpoint of Arab-Israeli violence. Israel and the PLO are currently negotiating the implementation of a long-delayed Israeli troop redeployment from the town.</p>
<p>In 1994, Baruch Goldstein, a Jewish settler from nearby Kiryat Arba, massacred 29 Arab worshippers in a Hebron mosque.</p>
<p>Palestinians have complained frequently of mistreatment by Hebron settlers, who include some of the most militant Israelis living in the West Bank.</p>
<p>Settlers have said a partial Israeli army pullout from the town would put their lives in jeopardy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEBRON, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
