<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14634" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends up sharply, Sept near 1-year high.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends up sharply, Sept near 1-year high.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended up sharply Monday, as broad-based short covering lifted the spot September contract to its highest settlement in nearly a year, traders said.</p>
<p>The most-active December contract rose to its highest close in nearly four months.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a squeeze, and shorts are being forced to cover,&quot; said Refco analyst Ann Prendergast.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts noted that there were still no delivery notices issued against the spot September contract, which entered notice period last Thursday and expires September 18.</p>
<p>On Friday, September's open interest fell 48 lots, to 2,089 lots, the equivalent of over 500,000 bags of coffee. The Exchange reported last Monday its warehouses held only 34,516 bags of coffee.</p>
<p>The CSCE will release updated U.S. certified stock figures after today's close, and some traders said they anticipated a further decline in CSCE warehouse inventories.  </p>
<p>&quot;September coffee led the way, with another fall in CSCE weekly warehouse stocks expected in the data due later Monday, and the break of the key $1.30 resistance level (last week) leading to further buying,&quot; Smith Barney analyst Walter Spilka said.</p>
<p>Front-month September ended 4.20 cents higher, at 136.45, its highest level since September 6. Benchmark December coffee closed up 2.65 cents a lb, to 125.20 cents, after ranging between 128.50 and 119.75. The remaining months ended 1.65 to 4.25 higher.</p>
<p>Local liquidation of long positions pressured values from the outset, traders said. But after the selling dried up, funds covering short positions, combined with trade and commission house buying, pushed December coffee through 124.50 resistance. September also breached today's upside target of 134.00-135.00.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the nearby September/December switch swelled to 11.25 cents today, compared with 9.70 cents on Friday, while the December/March switch widened to 7.50 cents versus 6.50 cents at Friday's close.</p>
<p>Traders said the market also got a boost from news earlier Monday of torrential rains and gale force winds in parts of central Colombia. But there was no assessment yet on any damage Colombia's coffee crop, which begins harvest next month, may have sustained.</p>
<p>Volume was brisk, at an estimated 11,671 lots.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
