<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146331" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gold stolen by Nazis said scattered worldwide.</title>
<headline>Gold stolen by Nazis said scattered worldwide.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal, not Switzerland, may have been the recipient of the largest unaccounted-for chunk of gold stolen by the Nazis in the Second World War, Newsweek reported.</p>
<p>The magazine, in its Oct. 28 editions, said its investigation showed that while the Swiss have borne the blame for laundering gold stolen by the Nazis, many parties around the world were involved in moving and hiding assets stolen mainly from Jews, and keeping them from their rightful owners afterwards.</p>
<p>Newsweek said a spokesman for Portugal's central bank &quot;confirmed last week&quot; that &quot;we acquired a lot of gold coming from Germany because, as you know, we sold a lot of goods and services to Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I suppose one or two bars are left with swastikas on them, but they're museum pieces,&quot; the magazine quoted the spokesman as saying from Lisbon.</p>
<p>Newsweek also said the previous estimates of how much stolen gold remained hidden in Swiss banks were exaggerated. It said its review of a Swiss National Bank report of dealings with the German Reichsbank, and a briefing paper from 1946, show that some $400 million in gold was sold to the Swiss National Bank by Germany during the war.</p>
<p>A handwritten ledger of Reichsbank dealings from 1940 to 1945 largely confirm the $400 million figure, Newsweek said.</p>
<p>But the Swiss then sold nearly half to the Bank for International Settlements and another $168 million to Portugal, Spain, Turkey and Germany during the war. Millions more was sold by the Swiss National Bank to Swiss businesses and banks in an attempt to support the Swiss franc, the magazine said.</p>
<p>Another $58 million was paid by the Swiss as part of a post-war settlement negotiated largely by U.S. officials in 1946 of stolen-assets claims.</p>
<p>&quot;Tragically what's left of all unclaimed assets stolen by the Nazis is loose change -- a few dormant bank accounts here, an extra piece of 'residual gold' there, worth perhaps $65 million,&quot; the magazine concluded.</p>
<p>Jewish leaders and a U.S. senator, citing newly-uncovered documents, last week made fresh accusations against Switzerland, saying it conspiring with Communist Poland to confiscate the unclaimed assets of Holocaust victims and may have entered into similar deals with other East European countries.</p>
<p>Jewish groups allege that most of the heirless assets were from Jews who died in the Holocaust and who had used Swiss banks as a safehaven from the Nazis, and demanded restitution.</p>
<p>The Swiss government has ordered Swiss banks to waive their tough secrecy laws and help with the investigation. In May, the banks too, after some delay, agreed to work with international Jewish organisations on the matter of stolen assets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
