<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146316" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton starts seven-state campaign trip in Virginia.</title>
<headline>Clinton starts seven-state campaign trip in Virginia.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>SPRINGFIELD, Va. 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton brought his campaign into enemy territory on Sunday, taking to the stump in Virginia, a state that has not supported a Democrat for the White House since 1964.</p>
<p>The visit, the start of a three-day, seven-state campaign swing, illustrated the Clinton campaign's growing confidence as it races down the final stretch to the Nov. 5 election.</p>
<p>Leading in all national polls -- the latest Reuters tracking poll gave Clinton a 13.4 percentage point lead over Republican Bob Dole while CNN/USA Today Gallup put it at 20 points -- Clinton appeared to be playing a complex campaign endgame.</p>
<p>On one hand he sought to buttress his commanding position in traditionally crucial Midwestern states like Illinois and Ohio, which he will visit on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>On the other, he wanted to use the campaign's waning days to further objectives beyond his own re-election -- like positioning Vice President Al Gore for a 2000 run at the White House and helping Democratic candidates for Congress.</p>
<p>During a quick afternoon visit to Springfield, Virginia, a Washington, D.C., suburb, Clinton campaigned with Mark Warner, a businessman seeking to oust three-term Republican John Warner from the Senate, and Democratic U.S. Senator Charles Robb.</p>
<p>Recent polls gave Clinton a six- to nine-point lead over Dole in Virginia, one of the most reliably Republican states over the past three decades.</p>
<p>&quot;Senator Robb called me about a week ago and he said: 'You know, my father-in-law was the last Democrat to carry the state of Virginia, but I think if you'll come accross the river and see us, you'll be the next',&quot; Clinton told about 2,000 at an outdoor rally at the high school park.</p>
<p>Robb's wife, Lynda, was the daughter of Lyndon Johnson, who in 1964 was the last Democratic candidate to win Virginia in a presidential election.</p>
<p>As he has done throughout the campaign, Clinton sought to paint himself as the candidate of the future and, without mentioning him by name, to portray Dole as a man of the past.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people in Virginia have been voting against members of my party for president for over three decades now and I know how hard it is to break a habit,&quot; Clinton said, prompting laughter. &quot;One of the things we all teach our kids is that some habits have to be broken.</p>
<p>&quot;I want you to go out from this place and spend the next nine days and tell your fellow Virginians they did a great thing for America when they and their native sons led us into the 19th century 200 years ago,&quot; he added. &quot;Virginia can help lead American into the 21st Century nine days from now.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton was scheduled to fly later in the day to Nashville, Tennessee, making his fourth visit to the state since August in an apparent effort to ensure that Gore did not suffer the embarrassment of losing his home state, or doing poorly there.</p>
<p>There seemed little danger of that, as a recent Tennessee opinion poll gave Clinton a 15 percentage point lead over Dole, but the Clinton-Gore campaign was taking no chances.</p>
<p>On Monday Clinton was scheduled to make speeches in St. Louis, Minneapolis and Chicago and on Tuesday in Columbus, Ohio, and Philadelphia.</p>
<p>After a one-night stopover at the White House, Clinton was to begin a seven-day campaign blitz across the country ending in Little Rock, Arkansas, for election night -- near the site where he declared his candidacy in October 1991.</p>
<p>Before leaving Washington, Clinton announced a $30 million increase in funding for research into the genetics of breast cancer, the creation of an Internet web site on the disease and the establishment of an &quot;Office of Cancer Survivorship&quot; to study issues of concern to survivors of all cancers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SPRINGFIELD, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
