<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146416" id="root" date="1996-10-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Anti-Taleban Afghan forces hit from air, on ground.</title>
<headline>Anti-Taleban Afghan forces hit from air, on ground.</headline>
<byline>Michael Battye</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anti-Taleban forces struck at the purist Islamic militia from the air and on the ground on Sunday as Afghanistan's latest war continued to expand.</p>
<p>Warplanes apparently belonging to a northern alliance swept over Kabul twice on a moonlit night and again early on Sunday, dropping bombs on the airport and setting off furious barrages of anti-aircaft fire.</p>
<p>Another tried again to hit the airport on the northeast edge of the capital on Sunday morning as Uzbek forces of northern chief Abdul Rashid Dostum launched an assault on Taleban lines north of the city.</p>
<p>Reuters correspondent Chris Bird said the Uzbeks used rockets, artillery and planes in the assault, apparently alongside forces of ousted government military chief Ahmad Shah Masood.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very busy right now,&quot; said General Abdul Rauf Begi, Dostum's commander on the front lines 25-30 (15-19 miles) north of Kabul.</p>
<p>Masood commander Sayid Akbar said two of Dostum's warplanes bombed Taleban positions on hills below the De Sabz pass some 30 km (19 miles) north of the capital.</p>
<p>Masood's largely ethnic Tajik fighters have tried in vain to break through the Taleban lines in the pass, which would give the northern alliance a relatively clear run to the edges of Kabul.</p>
<p>On Saturday night a warplane screamed low over the city just before the 9 p.m. (1630 GMT) curfew and aimed bombs at the airport.</p>
<p>A second appeared about three hours later and a huge explosion rocked central Kabul in what Afghan residents said were the first night-time bombing raids on the capital in 17 years of war in the country.</p>
<p>Witnesses said the bomb hit a park, shredding trees and shattering glass in some 40 nearby shops, but apparently wounding no one.</p>
<p>Early on Sunday morning, another plane struck at the airport, which is used for both civilian and military traffic, but Taleban guards said they missed their target.</p>
<p>Dostum and Masood formally allied two weeks ago after two years of bitter estrangement and Dostum sent tanks, artillery and men to Masood's front line on the plain north of Kabul.</p>
<p>The Taleban started using two combat aircraft -- a MiG-25 and a Sukhoi -- last week to help hold their lines and in one raid a Taleban bomb killed at least 14 civilians in the front-line village of Kalakan.</p>
<p>The air raids were the latest evidence that the war between the Taleban, who now control three-quarters of Afghanistan, and the northern alliance is expanding and that hopes of an early ceasefire are dead.</p>
<p>The front lines north of Kabul have been static for a week, despite several attempts by Masood to force a breakthrough and the Taleban have been noticeably more confident after holding him.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the Taleban signalled an end to any lingering hopes of a ceasefire by attacking Dostum directly in the remote northwestern province of Badghis.</p>
<p>The Taleban said they had taken the province and pushed into neighbouring Faryab and said on Sunday their forces were pushing towards the provincial capital of Maimnna, where Dostum has a major base.</p>
<p>If they took the city, then they could threaten Dostum's capital of Mazar-i-Sharif.</p>
<p>There have been no reliable independent reports of the fighting in the northwest, but a Masood spokesman implicitly denied the loss of Badghis on Saturday, saying fighting was going on, mostly involving infantry and armoured vehicles.</p>
<p>Reuters correspondent Marie Frail reported from Mazar-i-Sharif that U.N. special envoy for Afghanistan Norbert Holl was headed on Sunday for talks with Dostum.</p>
<p>Holl's plane stopped at Mazar-i-Sharif but then flew on towards Shibergan airbase to the west, where he was due to meet the Uzbek chief, U.N. sources said.</p>
<p>Holl has been shuttling between Mazar-i-Sharif, Kabul and the Taleban headquarters in the southern city of Kandahar in a so-far fruitless effort to arrange a ceasefire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
