<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146573" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-GENEROUS JUVENTUS SET TO TURN MEAN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-GENEROUS JUVENTUS SET TO TURN MEAN.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marco Delvecchio's last-gasp equaliser against Juventus in the Italian league at the weekend delighted Roma fans but their joy at the discomfort of the European champions may be shortlived.</p>
<p>The mood in the Juventus camp after the 1-1 draw at the Olympic Stadium in Rome on Saturday night suggested that Delvecchio's injury-time shot could speed a change in mentality, with league leaders Juventus sharpening up their act.</p>
<p>Coach Marcello Lippi, whose team were held 0-0 by third division Nocerina in an Italian Cup third round tie last Wednesday, lambasted and complimented his men in almost equal measure after the match.</p>
<p>His men controlled the pace of the game, scored a beautiful 59th-minute goal and then gave away their advantage when second-half substitute Delvecchio scored.</p>
<p>Juventus have now been held in their last three away matches, all against lesser opponents, and Lippi accused his men of complacency and taking a win for granted.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm sure they won't make that mistake again,&quot; he said, delivering a few choice but unrepeatable words.</p>
<p>But he added that he had liked what he had seen until Delvecchio's strike undid all the good work.</p>
<p>&quot;We played a good game, I saw a better team in every sense -- technical, tactical and athletic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Austria's Rapid Vienna, who play Juventus in a European Champions' League clash in Turin on Wednesday after drawing 1-1 at home thanks to another late equaliser, can expect frustration to be vented on them.</p>
<p>Juventus lead Group C with seven points and can afford to rest several key players, such as French international Zinedine Zidane who had a workmanlike game on Saturday.</p>
<p>But they have strength in depth and intend to finish top of the group. All the signs are that &quot;La Vecchia Signora&quot; is tightening up her boot laces and squaring her jaw.</p>
<p>Rapid may find the tackles a little harder, the time-wasting at the end a little more evident than hitherto.</p>
<p>Italian international midfielder Angelo Di Livio, the outstanding player against Roma on Saturday, suggested his team mates needed to take a crash course in cynicism.</p>
<p>&quot;In the last three away matches we have had three draws that should have been wins,&quot; he said bitterly.</p>
<p>&quot;Why? I think it's due to the youth of this team. We have changed a lot this year and we lack the cynicism that helps one not to throw away chances like the one in Rome.</p>
<p>&quot;They are things that one learns with time and I think the lesson of the Olympic Stadium will do the trick.&quot;</p>
<p>Juventus stayed top of the league after Milan lost to Fiorentina but the draw at Roma allowed Inter -- whom they beat 2-0 at home last weekend -- to pull level on 14 points.</p>
<p>&quot;We missed a great opportunity,&quot; said Juventus striker Michele Padovano, who scored his team's goal.</p>
<p>In fact, the Roma game was also Juventus's third missed opportunity in the league in seven matches this season and all have been in away matches which they dominated.</p>
<p>At lowly Reggiana, Juventus led 1-0 but allowed the home team back into the match for a 1-1 draw. At Vicenza, now third, the score was 1-1 until Juve were caught out by a defensive error and lost their unbeaten league record.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
