<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146522" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SOCCER-SOUTH AFRICA NAME EIGHT EUROPEAN-BASED PLAYERS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SOUTH AFRICA NAME EIGHT EUROPEAN-BASED PLAYERS.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa have named eight European-based players in an experienced squad for their World Cup qualifier against Zaire next month.</p>
<p>Mark Fish of Italy's Lazio, Austrian-based striker Brendan Augustine and defender Lucas Radebe of English premier league Leeds United are back in the 23-man party after missing a Four Nations Cup tournament in South Africa last month.</p>
<p>Kaizer Chiefs striker Pollen Ndlanya, the leading goalscorer in South Africa's new premier league, is the only new call-up for the match in Johannesburg on November 9.</p>
<p>Squad:</p>
<p>Goalkeepers - Mark Anderson (Umtata Bucks), Andre Arendse (Cape Town Spurs)</p>
<p>Defenders - Mark Fish (Lazio, Italy), Sizwe Motaung (St Gallen Switzerland), David Nyathi (St Gallen, Switzerland), Lucas Radebe (Leeds United, England), Neil Tovey, Jacob Tshisevhe (Kaizer Chiefs).</p>
<p>Midfielders - Linda Buthelezi (Mamelodi Sundowns), Doctor Khumalo (Columbus Crew, U.S.), Thomas Madigage (Supersport United), Isaac Kungwane (Kaizer Chiefs), John Moshoeu (Kocaelispor, Turkey), Helman Mkhalele (Orlando Pirates), John Moeti (Orlando Pirates), Dumisa Ngobe (Orlando Pirates), Eric Tinkler (Cagliari, Italy).</p>
<p>Strikers - Brendan Augustine (LASK, Austria), Shaun Bartlett (Colorado Rapids, U.S.), Pollen Ndlanya (Kaizer Chiefs), Phil Masinga (Salanitana, Italy), Jerry Sikhosana (Orlando Pirates), Mark Williams (PE Warriors).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
