<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146534" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-ROMARIO'S RETURN GOES SOUR.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ROMARIO'S RETURN GOES SOUR.</headline>
<byline>Brian Homewood</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian World Cup striker Romario's return to Flamengo went sour on Sunday when he hobbled off injured before halftime while his team conceeded two late goals and lost at home to Internacional.</p>
<p>A 35,000 crowd was present for Romario's comeback at the Maracana stadium in a Brazilian championship match, lured by the expectation of seeing him play alongside Bebeto, his striking partner in Brazil's 1994 World Cup team.</p>
<p>Romario was sold to Valencia in July but was re-signed on loan by Flamengo on Friday after just 78 days with the Spanish club. During his stay with Valencia, Romario was twice dropped by coach Luis Aragones, the second time for oversleeping and missing training.</p>
<p>Flamengo took an early lead through midfielder Nelio but things began to go wrong just before halftime when Romario pulled up clutching his thigh as he went for a challenge and had to be substituted.</p>
<p>It was not immediately known how long the pulled muscle would keep him out of action.</p>
<p>Flamengo's day turned to complete disaster when Internacional substitute Fabiano scored twice in the last six minutes to give his team what could be a crucial 2-1 win.</p>
<p>The three points left Internacional eighth in the tournament and Flamengo 14th. The teams who finish in the top eight qualify for the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>Vasco da Gama's Alcir Portela became the 14th coach to lose his job since the tournament started in August when he was sacked following his team's 3-2 defeat at home to Coritiba on Saturday.</p>
<p>Portela was replaced by Antonio Lopes, himself a victim of the managerial merry-go-round when he lost his job with Parana earlier in the tournament. Lopes returned for his fourth spell at Vasco.</p>
<p>Sao Paulo coach Carlos Alberto Parreira, who led Brazil to their World Cup victory in 1994, was in danger of becoming the next victim after his team lost 2-0 to Vitoria.</p>
<p>Sao Paulo, early leaders, have failed to win any of their last 10 games and have slipped to 17th.</p>
<p>Palmeiras regained the lead when they drew 1-1 away to Gremio to overtake Cruzeiro, beaten 1-0 away to Goias.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
