<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146600" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY BOND UPGRADE SHOULD DISPEL DOUBTS - ANALYSTS.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY BOND UPGRADE SHOULD DISPEL DOUBTS - ANALYSTS.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The upgrading of Hungary's long-term foreign currency-denominated debt on Monday by Standard &amp; Poor's to an investment grade was expected and should help dispel some investors' fears, analysts said.</p>
<p>Standard &amp; Poor's announced in New York that it had raised its rating for the National Bank of Hungary's long-term foreign currency-denominated debt to triple-B minus, the lowest investment grade, from the previous double-B plus.</p>
<p>The NBH had no immediate comment on the upgrade, which for the first time raises NBH debt issues to investment grade from one of the two most influential credit rating agencies, but analysts said the move should be a boon to Hungary.</p>
<p>&quot;The upgrade was expected at some point about now because of Hungary's improved financial stability,&quot; said Roger Monson, chief equity strategist for Daiwa Ltd in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Typically, a change of rating like this is already discounted in market interest rates and bond yields,&quot; Monson added.</p>
<p>&quot;But what it does do is reinforce some people who may have had deeper doubts about the progress being made and it should create a platform from where bond yields and interest rates can make some further progress.&quot;</p>
<p>In a statement, Standard &amp; Poor's said, &quot;The upgrade of Hungary's foreign currency debt reflects the success of disciplined financial policies in sharply reducing Hungary's external debt burden in recent years.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Downsizing of the public sector, together with privatisation and modernisation of the economy, are supporting an increasingly dynamic export base and an improving banking sector,&quot; S&amp;P's added.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that upgrading was expected because of the improved macroeconomic conditions and signs of the the austerity measures are working,&quot; said Rudy Voros, analyst for ICE Securities in London.</p>
<p>&quot;This is still the lowest investment grade, but the country will obviously benefit from it both on the macroeconomic and the microeconomic siide, because companies will be able to borrow at more advantageous rates,&quot; Voros added.</p>
<p>However, an economist for a New York-based investment house, who asked to remain anonymous, said, &quot;The fact (of the upgrade) is not surprising but the timing is somewhat surprising.</p>
<p>&quot;It was surprising because a few weeks ago S&amp;P publicly ...said that for the time being they did not regard Hungary as mature enough to be put into the investment grade category, because the mid- and long-term maintainability of fiscal austerity was heavily dependent on the not yet accepted pension and health financing reform,&quot; the analyst added.</p>
<p>But Monson said that Hungary's economy was showing better opportunities for investors on other fronts as well.</p>
<p>&quot;As well as the improvement in rating, we did see some cut in certain rates by the NBH, so those two things go very well together,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hungary launched an austerity programme last March, which led to a slump in real wages but helped the country to reduce its current account deficit to $2.5 billion in 1995 from $3.9 billion in 1994.</p>
<p>Hungary hopes that the current account deficit will drop below $2 billion this year.</p>
<p>Hungary also expects to bring down inflation to 22 to 24 percent this year from 28.2 percent in 1995, and plans to reduce it further to 18 percent next year.</p>
<p>The country cut its net foreign debt from 72.9 percent of the gross domestic product (GDP) in 1993 to 66.8 percent in 1995 and expects this ratio to fall to 60.1 percent by the end of this year.</p>
<p>The budget deficit is expected to drop to four percent of the GDP this year from 6.6 percent in 1995, but it will increase to 4.9 percent in 1997 as the government forecasts, due to changes in accounting the foreign debt, which the government called a technical change.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
