<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146695" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Genesis Health says billings dispute settled.</title>
<headline>Genesis Health says billings dispute settled.</headline>
<dateline>KENNETT SQUARE, Pa. 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Genesis Health Ventures Inc said on Monday a settlement over Medicare billing was reached between the United States and a company Genesis recently acquired.</p>
<p>The settlement arises out of alleged billing improprieties by Life Support Ambulance, a unit of Geriatric and Medical Cos Inc. Genesis acquired Geriatric and Medical on October 11, 1996.  </p>
<p>Genesis Health said the settlement, which makes no admission of liability, involves claims that were submitted prior to Genesis' acquisition of Geriatric and Medical Companies.</p>
<p>As part of the settlement, Life Support Ambulance agreed that the United States would retain $4.6 million of funds which had previously been withheld from the ambulance company, Genesis said.</p>
<p>Funds held by the government in excess of the settlement amount will be paid to Life Support Ambulance and no further withholdings will occur, the company said.</p>
<p>Genesis said it will implement a corporate compliance program for Life Support Ambulance that will assure the accuracy of Medicare claims and the company will be audited over a several year period.</p>
<p>Genesis Health said it helped resolve the matter with the U.S. Attorney's Office, the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, Health Care Financing Administration (HCFA), Xact Medicare Services, the Pennsylvania Department of Public Welfare and Pennsylvania Blue Shield.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KENNETT SQUARE, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
