<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="146786" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Merrill Lynch analyst upbeat about Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>Merrill Lynch analyst upbeat about Hong Kong.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign investors should continue using Hong Kong as a proxy for investing in China -- now and after 1997, said Merrill Lynch political analyst Richard Margolis.</p>
<p>The separation of foreign investors from domestic investors in A-share and B-share markets in China poses a difficult problem that is best avoided by investing in the liquid Hong Kong Hang Seng stock index, Margolis, who is based in Hong Kong, told a press luncheon here.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hang Seng index demonstrates a good correlation to China's economic policy,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;You can buy an orthodox portfolio of Hang Seng index constituent stocks and gain sensible exposure to China.&quot;</p>
<p>The strong performance of the Hang Seng index over the past five months reflected the successful soft landing of  China's overheating economy.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's transition to Chinese sovereignty in 1997 will not signficantly alter its long-standing symbiotic relationship with China, or its political risk profile.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain basically positive on the Hang Seng index through the transition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Margolis considered Taiwan, rather than Singapore or Shanghai to be the main competition for Hong Kong in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;As an exporter of capital, a source of entrepreneurial skills and an effective manager and developer of China's cost advantages, Taiwan likely has the ability to match Hong Kong across the board,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1660</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
