<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14698" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French court bars three hunger strikers' expulsion.</title>
<headline>French court bars three hunger strikers' expulsion.</headline>
<byline>Francois Raitberger</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Paris court on Monday barred the expulsion of three African immigrants who staged a 52-day hunger strike for the right to stay in France as immigrant leaders said they hoped their cause would become a national movement.</p>
<p>Riot police ringed the administrative court as it considered appeals against expulsion orders for some 80 of the 210 immigrants forcibly ejected on Friday from a Paris church that they had occupied in protest at tough French immigration laws.</p>
<p>Lawyer Anne Bremaud said the court ruled that the three men -- among a total of 10 Africans who had staged the hunger strike -- could not be deported in view of their health.</p>
<p>Police said that only one of the 10 would qualify for residence, but the government has said it would not expel anyone who was seriously ill.</p>
<p>The 10 hunger strikers, most of them from Mali, called off their fast on Sunday after police released them.</p>
<p>&quot;They have started taking mashed food as they are unable to eat any solid food. They are very tired,&quot; said their spokesman, Doro Traore.</p>
<p>Supporters of the Africans' cause have scheduled a major demonstration in Paris on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The Africans themselves are now calling for a second protest on September 18 in front of the headquarters of the Council of Europe in the eastern French city of Strasbourg.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the French people's support,&quot; said Ababakar Diop, who had acted as a spokesman for the protesting Africans when they were occupying the Saint-Bernard church in the capital's multi-ethnic Goutte d'Or district.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of French public opinion is today favourable to our cause. We say that this is a victory,&quot; added Madjiguene Cisse, a spokeswoman for the Africans.</p>
<p>An IPSOS opinion poll for the daily Le Monde showed voters evenly divided in their views of the government's policy of strictly enforcing immigration laws while reviewing each protester's case on an individual basis on humanitarian grounds.</p>
<p>But 46 percent said they sympathised with the protesting immigrants while 36 percent were hostile, according to the poll.</p>
<p>Most of the protesters were resting after moving their headquarters to a disused ammunition factory in the eastern Vincennes suburb. Some were enjoying the sunshine in the Vincennes park after weeks holed up in the Saint-Bernard church.</p>
<p>Lawyers managed to get most protesters released at the weekend in a legal battle to keep them in the country, prompting some media to accuse the government of confusion. &quot;The Great Muddle,&quot; the left-wing daily Liberation said in a headline of the confusion about the legality of expulsion orders.</p>
<p>Traore said all but 15 of the protesters were free and in the care of human rights groups.</p>
<p>Four were deported to Senegal, Mali and Zaire on a French military plane at the weekend. Three others were jailed for two to three months, and a few were still in custody.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre had said 30 to 40 percent of the protesters would be allowed to stay in France. His adviser on immigration, Jean-Claude Barreau, later told Liberation that as many as two-thirds might end up with residency papers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
