<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147035" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE fuel oil up, Turkey to buy high, low sulphur.</title>
<headline>NWE fuel oil up, Turkey to buy high, low sulphur.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>NWE high sulphur cracked fuel oil markets were firmer on Monday alongside futures, but traders said business was quiet.</p>
<p>High sulphur barges were firmer and traded at $118 fob ARA. Physical and swaps in ARA were around $3 a tonne up from Friday, despite lacklustre barge demand.</p>
<p>High sulphur cargoes were slightly firmer. A Turkish tender to buy 25-50,000 tonnes of high sulphur, and 55-60,000 tonnes of low sulphur fuel, added support.</p>
<p>Traders were surprised at the tender as Turkey does not usually buy high sulphur cracked fuel oil.</p>
<p>The tender fax from Tupras invited bids for the high sulphur tender related to published low sulphur quotes. Traders thought this may have been a typographical error. Tupras officials were not available for comment.</p>
<p>A U.K. utility bought a small top-up Russian piece on Friday, to add to an existing cargo, at a 50 cent premium to the mean of means of published quotes. At least four Russian cargoes with low water levels were seen available for early November. These were assessed at around $2-$3 over the mean of means of published quotes. --Nicholas Shaxson, London newsroom +44 1715428167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
