<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147098" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bank of Canada cuts key interest rate to 3.50 percent.</title>
<headline>Bank of Canada cuts key interest rate to 3.50 percent.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Canada on Monday cut its key bank rate to 3.50 percent from 3.75 percent, the lowest short-term interest rate Canada has seen in 36 years.</p>
<p>The move quickly prompted five of Canada's six major chartered banks to lower their prime lending rates to 5.0 percent from 5.25 percent, their lowest level since July 1956.</p>
<p>The bank rate, which has changed in nature over past decades, is now at its lowest level since August 1963.</p>
<p>It was the 10th rate cut this year by the Bank of Canada, and the 19th since the central bank began easing in May 1995. The Bank of Canada has now cut rates by 475 basis points since May 1995 in a bid to jump-start Canada's sluggish economy.</p>
<p>Through direct intervention in the money market, the central bank dropped its target range for the overnight lending rate to 3.0-3.50 percent from 3.25-3.75 percent.</p>
<p>The Bank of Canada uses the bank rate for loans it gives to financial institutions as lender of last resort. It is the top of the central bank's target range for the overnight rate.</p>
<p>Canadian Treasury bills firmed after the rate cut, while the currency and bonds traded steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
