<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14706" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Chile introduces measure to force peace in Burundi.</title>
<headline>Chile introduces measure to force peace in Burundi.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile introduced a Security Council resolution on Monday aimed at persuading Burundi factions to negotiate by threatening sanctions, and promising development aid if peace is achieved.</p>
<p>Council members said there might be amendments to the Chilean plan, the first concrete steps offered in the Security Council, but that no one had objected to it outright. At the same time there has been no open support from the United States, whose special envoy to Burundi, Howard Wolpe, briefed council members individually on Monday on his efforts.</p>
<p>The United States has been less critical than other council members of Major Pierre Buyoya, installed in a July 25 coup by the Tutsi-run army.</p>
<p>The army overthrew the elected Hutu president, Sylvestre Ntibantunganya, who sought refuge in the U.S. ambassador's residence in Bujumbura and is still there. Parliament is suspended and political parties are banned.</p>
<p>In a carrot and stick approach, the Chilean resolution, backed by Botswana, demands an immediate end to fighting and says all parties and factions should initiate negotiations with a view towards reaching a comprehensive agreement within 60 days after the resolution is adopted.</p>
<p>The resolution would also impose an arms embargo as soon as it is adopted. Should the talks succeed, it says the United Nations would hold a conference to raise funds for reconstruction of the country, where more than 150,000 people have died in fighting over the past three years.</p>
<p>But if the parties fail to make progress within 60 days, the draft resolution threatens &quot;targeted measures&quot; in the &quot;political, military and diplomatic fields&quot; aimed at the government and political leaders who encourage violence.</p>
<p>The Security Council on Wednesday plans a public debate on the issue which will allow African leaders to speak. But no action will be taken then.</p>
<p>The new rulers say they seized power to prevent genocide in Burundi between between minority Tutsis and ethnic Hutus, who make up around 85 percent of the population.</p>
<p>East and Central African states agreed at a July 31 summit to impose sanctions on the landlocked country of about 5.6 million people and its immediate neighbours have done so.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
