<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147137" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zairean dead lie in east Zaire village, witnesses.</title>
<headline>Zairean dead lie in east Zaire village, witnesses.</headline>
<dateline>BUMBA, Zaire 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The bodies of more than 14 men, women and children lay in an eastern Zairean village on Monday with the hands and feet of other dead sticking out of the ground, witnesses said.</p>
<p>Reuters Television cameraman Leon Malherbe said he saw at least 14 bodies including two with their arms tied behind their backs and the remains of other dead burned in huts in Bumba village, which neighbours on the now-empty Kibumba refugee camp.  </p>
<p>&quot;The houses were still smouldering. It looked like a massacre the way people -- including women and children -- were killed,&quot; Malherbe said after a visit to Bumba, which was attacked on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the dead were dumped in pit latrines,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zairean civilians who crossed into Rwanda on Sunday said earlier on Monday many dead and wounded were left in Bumba.</p>
<p>The refugees said the village and Kibumba camp were attacked by unidentified gunmen. Some Rwandan refugees in the Goma region of Zaire have told U.N. aid workers the attackers were Rwandan soldiers and others say they were ethnic Tutsis from Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUMBA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
