<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147239" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia's Dadas mulls merger with Primofin.</title>
<headline>Slovenia's Dadas mulls merger with Primofin.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Troubled Slovenian financial consultancy Dadas said on Monday it was considering a merger with fellow consultancy Primofin, in the latest sign that the country's financial sector is on the brink of a deep overhaul.</p>
<p>Dadas said the proposal would be discussed at its shareholder's meeting on November 29. Both Dadas and Primofin declined to comment on the planned tie-up.</p>
<p>Last week, banks Gorenjska and UBK announced they were in talks about a merger, aimed at increasing their joint market share and cutting costs. On Friday, listed Dolenjska banka also said it was in talks with other banks about a possible tie-up.</p>
<p>Slovenia, which has a population of two million, currently has 27 registered banks.</p>
<p>Should the merger between the two financial consultancies take place, each listed Primofin share would be exchanged for four Dadas shares, while 2,000 unlisted Primofin shares would be exchanged for 20 Dadas shares each, Dadas said in a press release.</p>
<p>The merger would boost Dadas' equity, currently 125.3 million tolars ($907,971), by 62.4 million tolars.</p>
<p>&quot;Dadas is probably trying to increase its capital and cut its operational costs with this move,&quot; said Davor Dubokovic, a trader at brokerage Eastbrokers.</p>
<p>Traders said Dadas already owns between 40 and 50 percent of Primofin shares.</p>
<p>&quot;Dadas and Primofin are two shares that are interesting only for investors who care just about short-term gains. The two shares are very volatile,&quot; said Goran Brankovic, a trader at Nova Ljubljanska banka.</p>
<p>Dadas faced serious problems at the end of March after the stock market's watchdog pushed to prohibit Dadas' mutual fund Proficia Dadas from trading on alleged trading irregularities.</p>
<p>Since March, Dadas' share price has plunged 93 percent. On Monday, Dadas dropped 33 percent while Primofin surged 75 percent on the news of a possible tie-up. -- Novica Mihajlovic, Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83951">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
