<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14728" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Aon group to take over German group - sources.</title>
<headline>Aon group to take over German group - sources.</headline>
<dateline>COLOGNE 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Aon Group, the world's second largest insurance broker, is set to acquire German industrial insurance broker Wesselhoeft, Ahlers und Schues KG, insurance sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>These sources told Reuters that a preliminary agreement has been signed between Aon and the Hamburg-based German group. Wesselhoeft, Ahlers and Schues will be sold by the two managing partners Peter Wesselhoeft und Bjoern Ahlers.</p>
<p>Wesselhoeft, Ahlers und Schues KG declined to comment.</p>
<p>The Aon Group recorded revenue of 3.466 billion marks last year, making it one of the leading global players.</p>
<p>In recent months the group has spent large sums expanding its international presence. Its latest acquisition was that of the largest insurance broker in Colombia, Saiz y Cia Ltda Corredores de Seguros.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Wesselhoeft is one of the 10 largest brokers in Germany with a staff of 220 and offices in eight cities.</p>
<p>Revenue from brokerage commission and other services is estimated at between 80 and 90 million marks.</p>
<p>According to the sources, Aon plans to merge Wesselhoeft with its existing German subsidiary Havag/Hudig-Langeveldt Internationaler Versicherungsmakler GmbH, possibly under the name Aon Deutschland or Aon Versicherungsmakler (insurance broker).</p>
<p>Havag is considerably larger than Wesselhoeft with a staff of 300.</p>
<p>Joined into one company, Aon's German operation would be one of the country's top five insurance brokers.</p>
<p>Both concentrate on industrial insurance. In addition, Havag/Hudig-Langeveldt has a reputation as a specialist in the field of fine art insurance, carried out via its subsidiary Artscope Internationaler Kunstversicherungsmakler GmbH. Wesselhoeft owns, with its subsidiary Wacus Kredit-Versicherungsmakler GmbH, Germany's leading specialised broker for credit insurance.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOGNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
