<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147375" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian stocks end mixed amid profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Colombian stocks end mixed amid profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks ended mixed in a wave of profit-taking in Banco de Colombia, brokers said.</p>
<p>Bogota's IBB index edged 0.11 percent up to 879.32 on the back of 2.36 billion peso in trading, while Medellin's IBOMED general price index drifted 0.22 percent down to 13,606.74 on a thin 635 million pesos.</p>
<p>&quot;Local investors came out to sell and take profits in Banco de Colombia. Given the current state of the markets nobody can afford to hold on to a share for much more than three days and once the opportunity comes they move to sell,&quot; one Bogota broker said.  </p>
<p>More than 1.36 billion pesos in Banco de Colombia changed hands on the Bogota exchange, as it slid 3.26 percent to 445 pesos. The fluctuations in the country's second largest bank in terms of assets began last week after Spain's Banco Central Hispanoamericano (BCH) announced it was to buy as much as 36 percent of Banco de Colombia in a deal that would cost between $200 million and $260 million in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Despite the drop in Banco de Colombia, the Bogota exchange managed to brake its fall thanks to the demand by foreign funds for Banco de Bogota shares, which rose 0.5 percent to 6,142 and for brewing giant Bavaria, unchanged at 4,100.  </p>
<p>Another highlight on the Bogota exchange was a 185 million peso trade in insurance company Compania Suramericana de Seguros, which remained unchanged at 18,500 pesos.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect there will be more speculation in Banco de Colombia shares, that will probably mean a new rise after a 20 peso drop, followed by another round of profit-taking until the time that details of the BCH deal are known, which will then lead to the price firming up,&quot; another Bogota broker said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
