<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147575" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Mauritius stock market plans switch to daily trade.</title>
<headline>Mauritius stock market plans switch to daily trade.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mauritius stock exchange plans to switch to daily trading early next year, opening on two extra days a week, chief executive Richard Morin said on Monday.</p>
<p>At present the share market on the Indian Ocean island, noted for its determination to build an open economy, opens only on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays.</p>
<p>Morin told the annual meeting of the African Stock Exchange Association that within a few weeks of the introduction of a central depository and settlement system the market would switch to daily trading.</p>
<p>The new settlement system would speed up transactions and virtually eliminate paperwork. Shareholders could ask for certificates if they wished but there would be no need to swop paper in a normal deal.</p>
<p>The news may help boost a market recently in the doldrums and suffering from uncertainty about the appointment of a new finance minister, market analysts said.</p>
<p>Morin said software and hardware for the new system were already in place. &quot;The only thing we are waiting for is regulatory approval. It appears today the way has been cleared for regulatory approval some time in December or at the latest in January, 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>At present investors must wait until the Friday of the week after they trade to receive their shares. The new system would allow trades to be registered on any trading day and completed five working days' later, giving the exchange &quot;T+5&quot; settlement.</p>
<p>The central bank would be used as a clearing bank for all trades. &quot;We will guarantee finality of payment on T+5. There will be no wondering if the cheque will bounce, because there is no cheque,&quot; Morin said.</p>
<p>Not all 45 companies listed on the exchange would be included in the new system immediately, but the plan would be to extend the system to all stocks by July 1997. -- Cairo newsroom 20-2-578-3290</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
