<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147568" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: Gaddafi obliged by sanctions to visit Tunis by land.</title>
<headline>Gaddafi obliged by sanctions to visit Tunis by land.</headline>
<byline>Abdelaziz Barrouhi</byline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi on Monday travelled to Tunisia by land, apparently deciding against carrying out his threat to again defy an air embargo imposed on his country by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Tunisian officials said Gaddafi, who had been invited by President Zine al-Abidine Ben Ali, crossed the border post of Ras Jedir at dawn where he was greeted by Interior Minister Mohamed Jegham.</p>
<p>He reached Tunis in the afternoon where he joined President Ben Ali for a welcome by thousands of people in main Tunis street Avenue Habib Bourguiba.</p>
<p>It is Gaddafi's first trip outside Libya since June when he flew to and from Cairo in violation of an air embargo imposed on Libya in 1992 for its failure to extradite two men indicted in Britain and the United States for the explosion of a Pan Am flight over Lockerbie, Scotland, in 1988.</p>
<p>Egypt at the time said Gaddafi took it by surprise. The Security Council protested against the violation. Gaddafi in July sent a message to the Council saying he would travel again by air to any country he wished despite U.N. sanctions.</p>
<p>&quot;It is interesting to note that he didn't. We believe that Tunisia, which has always respected the U.N. resolutions, had been sufficiently convincing,&quot; a Western diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Tunisian state-run press on Monday stressed that Tunisia has been active in supporting Libya to find a solution to its crisis over the Lockerbie case and for an end to the U.N. sanctions.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the visit would last about a week. Ben Ali and Gaddafi last met in January for a few hours at the border between the two countries.</p>
<p>Both countries are members of the Arab Maghreb Union, a regional economic and political grouping set up in 1989 with Algeria, Mauritania and Morocco.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
