<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14763" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>Pakistan: PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - August 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Pakistan - August 26.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Monday's Pakistani newspapers.</p>
<p>DAWN</p>
<p>- Floods destroyed rice fields near Sialkot town in Punjab province and washed away many houses. The army was called out in the Multan and Muzaffargarh districts in view of high flood due to pass in the next 24 hours.</p>
<p>- The government may allow an increase of up to 12 percent in medicine prices from September 1.</p>
<p>- All the opposition deputies and senators from the North West Frontier Province presented their resignations from both houses of parliament to opposition leader Nawaz Sharif.</p>
<p>- At least 20 people were killed and 17 injured when a passenger bus tumbled from a mountain road into a river in Pakistan-ruled Azad (free) Kashmir.</p>
<p>- The second review of the 1996/97 (July-June) budget by the International Monetary Fund (IMF) is expected to take place in October following which the second and third tranches of $80 million each out of the $600 million standby loan agreement are expected to be released, government sources said.</p>
<p>- The Central Board of Revenue has waived customs and regulatory duty on import of most edible oil seeds, including soyabean, colza, rape, sunflower, canola and salicornia.</p>
<p>BUSINESS RECORDER</p>
<p>- The government assured cotton traders that it would impose no restriction on the free export of raw cotton.</p>
<p>- Traders said 1,000 tonnes of refined sugar worth 21 million rupees stocked in Lahore were damaged by rain.</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- The state-run First Women Bank has suffered a loss of 700 million rupees ($20 million) in forward trading of U.S. dollars.</p>
<p>- The state-run Habib Bank Limited has announced a $300 million credit line to finance exports.</p>
<p>-- Islamabad newsroom 9251-274757</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
