<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147687" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end lower in dull trade, await data.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end lower in dull trade, await data.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries ended lower in extremely thin trade on Monday as investors mostly played defense ahead of a slew of key economic indicators to be released this week, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Any movement we have in the market is setting up for the string of indicators that we'll get starting tomorrow,&quot; said Christopher Low, senior economist at HSBC Markets Inc. &quot;People want to make sure they are on the right foot.&quot;</p>
<p>The 6-3/4-percent 30-year benchmark Treasury bond ended down 9/32 at 98-28/32 to yield 6.84 percent.  </p>
<p>Treasuries opened higher, buoyed by gains in the dollar, but lost steam as players squared portfolios ahead of the upcoming data, which include the Employment Cost Index (ECI) for the third quarter on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We had some people adjusting accounts here, but it's nothing really dramatic,&quot; said a trader at a primary dealership. &quot;We actually had a very quiet day.&quot;</p>
<p>Prices remained mostly trapped in a narrow range on Monday, but some analysts said upcoming data have the potential to propel the market out of the doldrums.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're still in a range. I think it's going to be difficult to get through that range, but we could get out of it this week with the right set of statistics,&quot; said Marilyn Schaja, an economist at Donaldson, Lufkin and Jenrette.</p>
<p>Analysts said the yield on the 30-year benchmark bond is seen fluctuating in a fairly broad range between 6.75 percent and 7.00 percent. A more narrow range, however, was placed between 6.78 percent 6.86 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts also said the last batch of economic indicators suggested the U.S. economy slowed in the third quarter and has so far failed to show any concrete signs of recovery.  </p>
<p>&quot;The economy is slowing ... and it looks like that going into the fourth of the year, there is not a lot of momentum,&quot; Schaja said.</p>
<p>She downplayed a sharp 4.6-percent jump in the September durable goods report Friday, saying the rise was mostly due to an increase in aircraft and computer sales.</p>
<p>&quot;It's aircraft, and besides aircrafts it's computers. It's very, very concentrated,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Market players were also gearing up for the announcement of the Treasury's quarterly refunding auctions on Wednesday, which will include, among others, a 30-year bond sale.  </p>
<p>&quot;We should get relatively favorable data this week. So I think the market will be able to absorb the supply,&quot; Schaja said.</p>
<p>On Monday, the market bought some $28 billion in three- and six-month bills at the Treasury's weekly auction. The government placed the securities at 5.04 percent and 5.15 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Analysts said flows were very thin on Monday, with day-traders and speculators dominating the trading session. Retail investors were mostly out of the market.  </p>
<p>The three-month Treasury bill rate closed up four basis points at 5.03 percent. The six-month bill rate rose two points to 5.13 percent. The year bill rate was up two points at 5.26 percent.</p>
<p>The two-year note closed down 1/32 at 99-29/32, yielding 5.93 percent. The five-year note traded off 3/32 at 99-27/32 to yield 6.29 percent. The ten-year note closed down 5/32 at 99-18/32, yielding 6.56 percent.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
