<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147791" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Oil Products Outlook - gasoline takes reins.</title>
<headline>U.S. Oil Products Outlook - gasoline takes reins.</headline>
<byline>Oliver Ludwig</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. refined products are likely to remain hopping this week as tight stocks keep gasoline and heating oil on a bullish track.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts note that with industry data showing inventories staying low on both main product sectors, attempts to boost production of one will almost surely come at the expense of the other.  </p>
<p>&quot;If you dig yourself a hole on gasoline and dig yourself a hole on heating, chances are you won't be able to dig your way out of both,&quot; said John Saucer, an oil markets analyst with Smith Barney in Houston.</p>
<p>Saucer and others note the market's obsession with increasing heating oil stocks at the expense of gasoline following recent meetings between the U.S. energy secretary Hazel O'Leary and industry executives, politicians and futures exchange people.</p>
<p>Cash gasoline prices, riding futures on NYMEX as well as differentials, rose last week by 2.50 cents in New York Harbor (NYH) and by nearly 6.00 cents a gallon in Houston.  </p>
<p>&quot;A week ago Gulf gasoline was about eight cents lower than heating oil, but they're now drawing even to each other,&quot; one Gulf Coast trader said, predicting refiners will begin increasing gasoline output as a result of more attractive prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Bet on refiners charging up their hydrocrackers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A number of outages at refineries, most planned, pushed prompt regular conventional gasoline in Houston to about 70 cents a gallon Friday, while prompt regular reformulated gasoline in NYH rose to 70.75 cents a gallon.  </p>
<p>Sources note the outage at Petroleos de Venezuela's huge 108,000 barrel per day catalytic cracker at its 510,000 bpd Amuay refinery was the centerpiece of gasoline's flaming comeback last week in the Gulf of Mexico market that saw it take the lead in the oil complex.</p>
<p>&quot;One refinery problem checked the heating oil selling,&quot; said Bob MacMinn, a consultant at MPAS Inc in Toronto, referring to the way the Amuay problem slowed heating oil selling last week.  </p>
<p>A market rife with talk about sundry refinery problems or outages further stoked the market higher, with most of the talk focused on units that make gasoline, like fluid catalytic crackers or hydrotreaters.</p>
<p>&quot;That's just the way it's going to be from now on. It's not a crude supply problem it's a hardware problem,&quot; MacMinn said.</p>
<p>New York Harbor conventional unleaded was seen likely to encounter downward pressure this week however, from significant import volumes and increasingly backwardated November to December futures prices that will discourage stock building.  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of barrels are floating in the harbor or arriving in the next 10 days,&quot; one East Coast trader said, citing wide-ranging estimates of between 150,000 and 400,000 barrels looking for a home.</p>
<p>Also, cash heating oil and diesel prices in Houston were weaker last week after the Colonial Pipeline Co's decision to allocate space on its huge Houston-to-New York distillate line to accomodate all the barrels being produced on the Gulf Coast's Refinery Row.  </p>
<p>Some Houston traders said they expect prices to come down further, especially if east cost weather remained mild. But others see the bullish trend of the past few months as hard to break.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say longer term trends are coming home to roost,&quot; said Smith Barney's Saucer.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Midwest traders said spot unleaded gasoline and diesel fuel prices would continue to find support from a legal dispute that threatened to idle Clark Refining and Marketing Co's 80,515 barrel per day Chicago-area refinery after a fire.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's certainly been keeping differentials as strong as they are, and if it is shut basis would go even higher,&quot; one Kansas City, Mo., trader said.</p>
<p>On the West Coast, gasoline margins stayed weak -- about 21 percent below last quarter -- and market observers said refiners could ease oversupply pressure by cutting production or sending cargoes overseas this week.  </p>
<p>&quot;They will sacrifice only conventional (gasoline) to offshore markets,&quot; said one broker. Conventional grade gasolines manufactured in California meet Federal air quality standards but not those of the state, which has the most stringent emmission laws in the U.S.</p>
<p>CARB-grade gasoline, for statewide use, is normally more expensive, but could cost the same if refiners export conventional or &quot;clear&quot; grades.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't be surprised to see conventional go over CARB,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1620</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
