<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147744" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Revco seen making quick fix to Big B.</title>
<headline>Revco seen making quick fix to Big B.</headline>
<byline>Robin Sidel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Revco D.S. Inc is expected to leverage its size and experience to overcome the host of problems that pushed regional drugstore chain Big B Inc into a deal with the Ohio-based drugstore giant.</p>
<p>Industry experts said Revco is well-placed to capture profits in the southeast by taking advantage of Big B's underused distribution center and closing overlapping stores in Georgia.</p>
<p>&quot;Revco will be able to integrate Big B really quickly,&quot; said Eric Bosshard of Midwest Research-Maxus Group.  </p>
<p>The two companies on Monday said that Big B had accepted a sweetened acquisition offer from Revco in a cash transaction valued at $380 million, or $17.25 per share.</p>
<p>It is the latest in a string of recent acquisitions in the drugstore industry. Just two weeks ago, Rite Aid Corp agreed to buy West Coast-based Thrifty PayLess Inc for $1.4 billion.</p>
<p>Big B initially fought a takeover by Revco, rejecting its unsolicited bid of $15 per share last month and inviting interested parties to submit formal offers.  </p>
<p>Like many other regional drugstores, Big B was burdened by problems that have accompanied the burgeoning clout of managed health care and huge discount retailers.</p>
<p>Big B's profit margins began to tumble last year due to difficulty in calculating the impact of lower prescription prices paid by managed care providers. Although it invested heaviliy in a new computer system to better track profit margins, people familiar with the company have said its newly-expanded distribution center is operating at only 60 percent of capacity.  </p>
<p>One of its first steps will be to assess store overlap, especially in Georgia where Revco operates 180 stores and Big B has 160 stores.</p>
<p>&quot;Once they get the distribution and the stores together, it will be a real profit center for Revco,&quot; said John Strauss of investment advisory firm Strauss Financial Group.</p>
<p>Revco has said that the acquisition will boost its earnings in the first year of the combination.</p>
<p>After some haggling about terms, Revco signed a confidentiality agreement, took a peek at Big B's books and apparently liked what it saw.  </p>
<p>The Big B board met over the weekend and accepted the new and higher offer from Revco. Details of other offers were not immediately known, although Eckerd Corp was viewed as a potential bidder.</p>
<p>Eckerd declined to comment.</p>
<p>Revco's expanded southeast presence is expected to lead to heightened competition with Eckerd, CVS, a unit of Melville Corp, and Thrift Drugs, a unit of J.C. Penney Co .</p>
<p>The deal with Big B was seen as a significant acquisition for Revco which earlier this year was involved in a failed transaction with Rite Aid. The two companies had signed a pact for Rite Aid to buy Revco for $1.8 billion, but the deal collapsed after regulators expressed concern that the union would raise consumer prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
