<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14776" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistani stocks dip at close on short selling.</title>
<headline>Pakistani stocks dip at close on short selling.</headline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistani stocks dipped at the close on Monday on short-selling ahead of an opposition rally in Karachi on Wednesday, the next trading session, dealers said. The bourse will be closed for a local holiday on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Karachi 100-share price index dipped 11.22 points, or 0.78 percent, to 1,430.90 amid 164 gainers and 79 losers. Volume fell to 17 million shares from Sunday's 18 million.</p>
<p>Fresh short-selling depressed the market, dealer Asif Jan said, adding: &quot;With the rollover in positions sentiment seems to be depressed.&quot;  </p>
<p>One broker said Wednesday's planned rally called by opposition parties as part of a campaign to bring down Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's government had dampened sentiment.</p>
<p>Wellcome Pakistan shed 3.90 rupees to 120, Siemens Engineering dipped 5.00 to 160, Lever Brothers lost 1.00 to 681, Adamjee Insurance fell 4.00 to 95, PTCL shrank 0.40 to 35.60 and HUBCO 0.70 to 30.20. Dewan Salman rose 1.45 to 26.25.</p>
<p>						     Monday     Previous</p>
<p>KSE all-share index			     988.37	 992.67</p>
<p>Market capitalisation in billion rupees   482.69	484.79</p>
<p>Trading value in billion rupees		 0.50	  0.59</p>
<p>-- Ibrahim Khan 9221-5685192</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
