<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147882" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: EU names Mideast envoy, calls for Hebron pull back.</title>
<headline>EU names Mideast envoy, calls for Hebron pull back.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union moved on Monday to bolster its role in the Middle East peace process, appointing a special envoy to the region and pointedly joining with Egypt in calling for Israel to withdraw from Hebron.</p>
<p>Foreign ministers from the 15-nation bloc named Spain's ambassador to Israel, Miguel Angel Moratinos, to represent them in the peace process, establish relations with Israeli and Palestinian negotiators and report on possible EU actions.</p>
<p>French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette told reporters it was crucial for Europe that it took a serious role in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is a return to violence, to terrorism, that will have a direct effect on Europe,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a joint statement after the ministers met Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa, the two sides said they were seriously concerned about the absence of progress in the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides agreed that peace in the region requires, as a first step, the full implementation of existing agreements between Israel and the Palestinians, in particular the redeployment from Hebron...,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>A three-week U.S. effort to broker an Israeli pullout from the occupied West Bank town of Hebron collapsed on Monday with Palestinians and Israelis each blaming the other for the deadlock.</p>
<p>EU diplomats said the statement was in line with tough words issued by the foreign ministers at their last meeting, on October 1, when they rebuked Israel for failing to meet its obligations under the Oslo peace accord.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the statement had caused great concern in Israel.</p>
<p>Moussa, meanwhile, made it clear that Cairo wanted the EU involved in putting the peace process back on track.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our task and yours to make the Israeli government realise that (their new) policies will lead nowhere but to less security, less stability and therefore less prosperity for us all,&quot; he told the ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;The EU has the means to bring across this message and to help redress a sharply deteriorating process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The EU, egged on by France, has been seeking a stronger role in the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>France is irritated that the United States has made much of the running, leaving the EU to act as bankroller.</p>
<p>De Charette made much of the appointment of an envoy, which he saw as underlining the bloc's commitment to the region.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good news for Europe, it is good news for the Middle East and, I hope, it is good news for peace,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Others were less sanguine. German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel warned against the bloc trying to take over Washington's longstanding role in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Germany believes that Europe should not overestimate its role. It should coordinate closely with the United States,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
