<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147952" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan to fence border with India.</title>
<headline>Pakistan to fence border with India.</headline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan said on Monday it would fence its border with India to check an &quot;increasing illegal immigration&quot;.</p>
<p>The proposal to check illegal immigration was approved by a meeting of Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto's cabinet on Monday, an official statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The cabinet decided that, in addition to fortifying and reinforcing measures already in force for the purpose, fencing of the border area will also be taken in hand under a phased programme, starting with (the southern province of) Sindh,&quot; it said, without giving details.</p>
<p>Sindh borders India's Rajasthan state.</p>
<p>India has already built a barbed wire fence along the border of its troubled Punjab state with Pakistan's Punjab province.</p>
<p>India has been accusing Pakistan of helping a Sikh separatist movement in Punjab state while Islamabad has often accused New Delhi of sponsoring violence in the Sindh capital of Karachi.</p>
<p>Karachi's population of about 12 million is dominated by Urdu-speaking Moslems who migrated from India at Partition in 1947 and their descendants.</p>
<p>Pakistan has objected to India's plans to extend its Punjab state fence to a tense military control line in the disputed Kashmir region, where New Delhi is fighting a Moslem separatist revolt since 1990.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
