<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147920" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX seen hovering around 2,700-level.</title>
<headline>German DAX seen hovering around 2,700-level.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sporadic buy interest and a firm dollar sent Germany's blue chip DAX index firmly back over the 2,700-point level in bourse trade on Monday and most dealers said the market should hold this key level.</p>
<p>The 30-share IBIS DAX index, which tracks electronic dealings, was up 6.50 points at 2,697.29 points at 1410 GMT, having eased slightly from its bourse close of 2,703.83.</p>
<p>&quot;The market made several efforts to fall to get some breathing space but it hasn't worked, 2,700 seems to be where it wants to be,&quot; said one Frankfurt dealer.</p>
<p>The December DAX futures contract was up 9.5 at 2,711.5.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile merger news sparked interest in chemical groups, with BASF AG up 1.40 marks at 48.95 marks after it finalised an agreement for a joint venture with Dutch firm DSM.</p>
<p>Dealers said activity on the broader market was relatively weak and some suggested the market's persistent resilience could be linked with the imminent launch of shares in telecoms monopoly Deutsche Telekom, expected on November 18.</p>
<p>&quot;People want to hold the DAX at higher levels to create a optimum paying field for the Telekom issue,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>However others said a mid-term consolidation was still possible, with strong DAX support still at 2,600.  </p>
<p>Positive corporate news sent blue chips such as Daimler-Benz AG, Volkswagen, BASF AG higher Monday and dealers also noted that gains on heavily weighted insurance stocks Allianz and Munich Re had helped buoy the market.</p>
<p>Daimler was up 1.51 at 89.95 marks, as the market continued to view as positive a report, denied by Daimler, that its chief executive Juergen Schrempp had threatened to resign in order to ensure a management restructure.</p>
<p>VW was up 6.20 at 601.20, off a high of 608 but still buoyed by hopes of a liberalisation of its shareholder laws.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
