<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="147971" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India rupee slips on month-end spurt in dlr demand.</title>
<headline>India rupee slips on month-end spurt in dlr demand.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Indian rupee closed at 35.64/65 per dollar on Monday, down from the opening rate of 35.60/61, with action shifting to the spot from the forward market, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The spot (rate) moved in jerks, all in one direction,&quot; said a dealer at a foreign bank. In the morning session, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) bought dollars at 35.6250, dealers said.</p>
<p>In the afternoon session, a leading state-run bank began bidding for dollars, pushing the rupee to the day's low, the 35.6450/6550 level, dealers said.  </p>
<p>After being stuck on 35.59/61 level for nearly a weak, the rupee moved in a wide range of 35.61/65 of Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like the elusive month-end dollar demand has arrived,' said a dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;SBI has said it will use its GDR dollars to match outflows,&quot; said a bank dealer, referring to funds raised by State Bank of India from the overseas equity market.  </p>
<p>&quot;The demand for dollars has been supressed -- it will assert itself,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The forward dollar market was subdued on Monday. There was some import covering and the premia inched up, with April dollars quoted at 1.24/1.26 rupees towards the close.</p>
<p>The six month premia close around 7.07 percent annualised. It could fall further to around 6.5 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
