<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148088" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Freight train derails near Fresno, Calif.</title>
<headline>Freight train derails near Fresno, Calif.</headline>
<dateline>FRESNO, Calif 1996-10-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A freight train carrying hazardous materials derailed early Sunday south of Fresno, Calif., causing no injuries but forcing local authorities to seal off the area.</p>
<p>Authorities said they believed the cause of the accident was a break in steel bars connecting the rails. The break may have been caused by temperature changes.</p>
<p>&quot;Sabotage has been ruled out,&quot; Burlington Northern Santa Fe Corp spokesman Mike Martin said.</p>
<p>There were some hazardous materials on board, including paint, batteries, pesticides and compressed gas cylinders. &quot;There hasn't been any discovery of a release of hazardous materials at this point,&quot; Martin said.</p>
<p>The Burlington Northern Santa Fe freight train derailed at 4:19 a.m. local time in a remote area about 10 miles south of Fresno. The train was traveling about 60 miles per hour at the time, within the speed limit, the company said.</p>
<p>Fifteen of the 33 freight cars derailed, causing trailers and containers to split open, Martin said. The rail cars and containers were stacked three high in some places.</p>
<p>The derailment forced the closure of the Burlington Northern Santa Fe line, which runs from Bakersfield to the San Francisco Bay Area. The line handles about 20 freight and eight passenger trains a day.</p>
<p>The rail line is Burlington Northern Santa Fe's only Central Valley link from southern to northern California. Trains that normally take the line were rerouted. The company said it hoped to reopen the track by noon on Monday.</p>
<p>Local authorities said no one was injured in the accident but that they were forced to evacuate three nearby homes.</p>
<p>A Burlington Northern Santa Fe hazardous materials team arrived at the scene to work with local authorities. Officials said the clean up effort was progressing slowly because of the way the rail cars were stacked.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRESNO, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
