<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148123" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Chino copper talks adjourned, set to resume in Nov.</title>
<headline>Chino copper talks adjourned, set to resume in Nov.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Labor talks at Phelps Dodge Corp's Chino mine in New Mexico on Oct 24 and 25 ended without agreement, but a further round was tentatively scheduled early next month, the company said.</p>
<p>The company met with labor union representatives in a bid to end the four-month deadlock. Unionized employees have been working without contract since the previous three-year deal expired June 30.</p>
<p>Phelps' spokeswoman Sue Suver said last week's meeting was businesslike.</p>
<p>&quot;The discussions were productive and the unions indicated they may want to come back for further discussions on or about Nov 7,&quot; Suver said.</p>
<p>&quot;They discussed a lot of different issues in the offer that we presented to them,&quot; Suver added.</p>
<p>Manny Armenta, an organizer for the USWA, confirmed that tentative talks were scheduled for November 7 through 9 after the unions made proposals to the company last week.</p>
<p>Phelps presented its final offer to the unions late August and Suver said no amendments were made to that offer during last week's talks.</p>
<p>Armenta said the talks were &quot;encouraging&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is a slowdown in production definitely. The people are not content because they felt other companies have reached an agreement, like ASARCO and Kennecott and they got pretty decent packages,&quot; Armenta said.</p>
<p>&quot;The mood is low and the tensions are very high,&quot; Armenta added.</p>
<p>Suver said Chino was working normally.</p>
<p>Phelps is offering a pay freeze while contracts ratified recently at an ASARCO location, and at Kennecott Utah Copper Corp last week, included a pay hike.</p>
<p>Chino produced 170,000 tonnnes of contained copper in 1995.</p>
<p>--Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
