<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148174" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Entergy to replace Arkansas steam generator.</title>
<headline>Entergy to replace Arkansas steam generator.</headline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Entergy Corp said Monday its directors have decided to proceed with replacement of the steam generators at Arkansas Nuclear One, Unit 2.</p>
<p>As previously reported, cracks in steam generator tubes at 858 megawatt plant were repaired after being discovered during an outage in 1992. Further inspections and repairs were conducted at subsequent refueling and mid-cycle outages, including the most recent refueling outage in October 1995.</p>
<p>Entergy said the board has authorized its nuclear management subsidiary, Entergy Operations Inc, to negotiate a contract for fabrication and replacement of steam generators.  </p>
<p>It generally takes more than four years for steam generators to be built and delivered, Entergy noted.</p>
<p>The company said it estimates the cost of fabrication and replacement of steam generators could be about $150 million. Entergy will have an option to cancel the order up to year 2000.</p>
<p>Entergy said the board's decision to proceed is based to a great extent on the excellent operating performance of the unit. The Combustion Engineering pressurized water reactor achieved a three-year average capacity factor between 1993-95 of 87.7 percent.</p>
<p>On August 19, 1996, the unit broke its previous record of 257 consecutive days on line and has now operated 327 days without interruption.</p>
<p>Combustion Engineering is now an ABB Group subsidiary.</p>
<p>Arkansas Nuclear One is in Russellville, Ark. It is owned by Entergy Arkansas Inc, an Entergy subsidiary.</p>
<p>-- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
