<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148258" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bloodied rand has further to fall, say London analysts.</title>
<headline>Bloodied rand has further to fall, say London analysts.</headline>
<byline>Phil Smith</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rand will continue to take a beating on foreign exchanges in coming months with the economic backdrop failing to improve quickly enough to come to its aid, London-based analysts said. &quot;Right now the situation isn't improving enough to believe that current levels are unsustainable, that's the problem for the market,&quot; said Chris Tinker, chief economist treasury at Standard Chartered. The rand was at a record low of 4.6515 to the dollar amid speculative pressure out of London.</p>
<p>Tinker saw the rand getting down to 5.00 over the next six months. &quot;After that we could trade to 5.25 but if we get there we would probably get back to 5.00 quite quickly. Around 5.00 is that sort of level where anything weaker really isn't sustainable.&quot;</p>
<p>At that kind of level you will see a significant impact in terms of competitiveness, not just via exports to third party markets but also to in terms of protecting domestic manufacturers from overseas imports.</p>
<p>&quot;If we get to 5.00 on the dollar it will put South Africa in a similar situation to sterling post the ERM crisis,&quot; Tinker said.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts said the rand had in many ways been oversold since 4.25 per dollar.</p>
<p>But, they said, if the depreciation on a currency stokes inflation, a vicious circle evolves where the real interest rate position demands a lower currency.</p>
<p>On top of this, the current account situation is not exactly supportive for the rand but its weakness could alter the outlook for that particular indicator.</p>
<p>&quot;The real exchange rate has fallen to levels which would make me feel that an export-led acceleration in growth in 1997 must be more likely than it was,&quot; said Kevin Gardiner, a senior economist at Morgan Stanley.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are right and the world economy grows more rapidly than in any year since 1988, their export sector should have the best of both worlds.&quot;</p>
<p>But the overall view is for a continued rand decline unless something drastic happens on the interest rate front. This looks highly unlikely given comments from Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals that September money supply and credit growth figures implied the maintenance of the status quo on rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has shown continued reluctance to raise interest rates so the rand will remain vulnerable,&quot; said one analyst at a leading U.S. bank. &quot;Unless the government do something with rates the pressure will remain.&quot;</p>
<p>But analysts pointed out that interest rate rises do not necessarily help a currency much if they are perceived as knocking future economic growth for six.</p>
<p>Also, a rate rise would do nothing for asset markets in general, a situation that would tend to undermine rather than boost the rand.</p>
<p>On the other side of the interest rate coin, the cautious Reserve Bank is not going to deliver the interest rate cuts the stuttering economy needs while credit growth is around 17-18 percent, well over a target of 10-12 percent, analysts said.</p>
<p>Investors also feel safe selling the rand given the low level of central bank reserves, which have halved in dollar terms since the end of 1995.</p>
<p>It is true that South Africa has credit lines in place but they would be dangerous to use in the market's eyes. &quot;If they drew down credit lines to defend the currency it would only erode confidence further,&quot; the U.S. bank analyst said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
