<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148361" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: War jitters spur Israeli army to ask for funds. [CORRECTED 14:22 GMT]</title>
<headline>War jitters spur Israeli army to ask for funds. [CORRECTED 14:22 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Colleen Siegel</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's defence chiefs have told Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu the army needed more than $1 billion because of an increased chance of war with Syria, Israeli security sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>They confirmed a report in Israel's Haaretz daily that said: &quot;The heads of the defence establishment presented last week to the prime minister...a strengthening plan needed to prepare the army for war in light of the Syrian threat.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The cost of the plan...is 3.5 billion (corrects from million) shekels ($1.07 billion),&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Haaretz said in a separate article that senior Egyptian military officers had in the last several weeks violated their 1979 peace treaty by touring an area close to the border with Israel where only regional police officials were permitted.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's office and the defence ministry refused to comment on the reports. There was no immediate corroboration of the report on the Egyptian officers from other sources.</p>
<p>Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai, speaking to reporters in parliament, said:</p>
<p>&quot;We have an interest in continuing the dialogue that was stopped with the Syrians. Our intentions are to calm the situation. We are taking the required readiness steps and not more than that&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;With that, the army has needs and demands as a result of the erosion which has taken place over the course of years in various areas and in terms of these erosions we will see how we can fill them.&quot;</p>
<p>A parliament official who briefed reporters after Mordechai's appearance at the parliamentary foreign affairs and defence committee quoted the minister as saying Syria had changed its strategic stance.</p>
<p>&quot;From a strategic standpoint there is some kind of change. Until a certain point the Syrian strategy was that the diplomatic process was the only option,&quot; Mordechai was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;Recently, they are talking as well about the possibility of a military option. We cannot give it a time frame but it requires the maximum response,&quot; Mordechai said.</p>
<p>He told the committee a large Syrian military exercise was planned in the coming days and Israeli forces were &quot;taking the necessary steps for maximum alertness&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if there is an assessment that until the elections in the United States (Syrian President Hafez al-) Assad will not act, we cannot ignore the field whether it be preparations for an exercise or preparations for a different option.&quot;</p>
<p>In September, Syria redeployed some 12,000 troops in Lebanon, moving some to within striking distance of a key Israeli position on the Golan Heights, spurring war jitters in Israel.</p>
<p>Syrian officials have accused Netanyahu, who won Israel's May elections vowing to hold on to the Golan Heights Israel captured in the 1967 Middle East war, of making threatening statements.</p>
<p>Mordechai hinted Israel's right-wing government could consider giving up some of the Golan Heights to Syria in return for peace.</p>
<p>&quot;Not one senior official in the Israeli government has said: 'Not one inch on the Golan',&quot; Mordechai told the committee. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Former Likud prime minister Yitzhak Shamir, ousted from power by the centrist Labour party in 1992 elections, used the term &quot;not one inch&quot; during his tenure to underscore his government's stand that there would be no Golan concessions.</p>
<p>Labour, in power until this June, was prepared to make at least a partial Golan withdrawal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
