<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148340" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan shares fall in quiet market.</title>
<headline>Jordan shares fall in quiet market.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares on Jordan's stock exchange slipped fractionally on Monday in lacklustre trade dominated by block trades in two industrial firms, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said a handful of trades in Jordan Cement Factories and Jordan Industrial Resources, possibly resulting from funds shuffling portfolios, accounted for nearly two thirds of the day's 612,000 dinar ($864,000) turnover.</p>
<p>&quot;The rest of the market is very quiet, like the economic scene in Jordan,&quot; said investment banker Samir Jaradat of Jordan Investment Finance Bank.</p>
<p>Slight falls in both Jordan Cement Factories and Jordan Industrial Resources helped push the Amman Financial Market 60-share index down by 0.02 percent to 148.47 points on Monday.</p>
<p>Jordan Cement Factories slipped back 0.02 dinars to 3.36 dinars after soaring 0.30 dinars on Sunday. The government has said it wants to divest a 20 percent stake in the company's 60 million dinar equity.</p>
<p>Even market stalwart Arab Bank Group, seen as impervious to the political tensions between Israel and Palestinians which have paralysed other stocks on the market, fell 0.25 dinars to 246.75 dinars in modest turnover.</p>
<p>Declining shares outnumber rising stock by 20 to five on Monday, with 15 trading but closing unchanged.</p>
<p>The private Pearl Investable Index of the 45 best performing shares on the exchange fell 0.15 percent to 80.55 points from 80.67 points on Sunday, or 15.66 percent down from the same time last year.</p>
<p>-- Amman newsroom, 962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
