<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148443" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Oct 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times business - Oct 28.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following business stories on Monday:</p>
<p>- Oracle Corp and Netscape Communications Corp are expected to announce on Monday that they will endorse each other's products in a new alliance.</p>
<p>- Apple Computer Inc plans to launch on Monday a new computer for elementary and high schools that will cost half as much as the multimedia systems being used today.</p>
<p>- General Motors Corp and the Canadian Automobile Workers union rush towards a final agreement for a labor contract under the pressures of an approaching deadline.</p>
<p>- The  Kelley Blue Book Co is putting its lists of used car prices onto the Internet.</p>
<p>- Mexico's government reached an agreement with the country's business and labor leaders to keep wages at the same level and maintain an austerity plan.</p>
<p>- The decline in AT&amp;T Corp's stock following the appointment of a new president shows how Wall Street was not impressed with the company's choice.</p>
<p>- Wall Street is not as bullish about Internet companies like CompuServe Corp as had been expected because it wants to see more growth and profits.</p>
<p>- Competition between cable news networks has spread to the Internet as the Cable News Network of Turner Broadcasting System Inc and others create home pages offering stories and other information.</p>
<p>- The World Wide Web is eliminating the ability of government regulators to control gambling, especially on the Internet.</p>
<p>- Religious bookstores are not selling as many Bibles as they used to.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
