<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148585" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Waigel reported saying EU finances need overhaul.</title>
<headline>Waigel reported saying EU finances need overhaul.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union financing needs overhauling, according to comments by German Finance Minister Theo Waigel reported in Spain's El Pais newspaper on Monday.</p>
<p>The newspaper reported Waigel suggested Germany was paying too much into EU coffers and that Spain was taking too much out.</p>
<p>El Pais said the comments were in a letter from Waigel to German Chancellor Helmut Kohl which was distributed to his cabinet.</p>
<p>&quot;Our objective has to be braking the growth in expenditure in the community,&quot; Waigel said in the letter, which El Pais said was marked &quot;personal, confidential and not destined for publication.&quot; The newspaper did not say how it got hold of the letter.</p>
<p>In Bonn, a German government source who asked not to be identified confirmed the letter from Waigel to Kohl was genuine but said it was a routine informational briefing and not secret.</p>
<p>In the letter, Waigel pointed out the high burden of the EU budget on Germany, which paid a net 11.5 billion Ecus in 1995, while Spain received 7.5 billion Ecus. This has a negative impact on acceptance of the EU by the German public, the letter said, according to the German government source.</p>
<p>El Pais said Waigel's letter said Spain was taking &quot;the lion's share&quot; of the budget, referring to graphs showing funding and expenditure levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We need a system to limit the excessive net transfers not only for budgetary reasons but also for reasons of political acceptance in Europe,&quot; El Pais cited the letter as saying.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
