<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148648" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam says tourist market set to double by 2000.</title>
<headline>Vietnam says tourist market set to double by 2000.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam is set to become one of southeast Asia's leading tourist destinations, attracting more than three million visitors a year by the end of the century, the National Administration of Tourism predicted on Monday.</p>
<p>The tourism department's vice-chairman, Bui Xuan Nhat, told Reuters in an interview he expected 1.5 million foreign visitors -- about a quarter of them people on business -- to arrive in Vietnam this year, about 20 percent more than in 1995.</p>
<p>That would mark a slowdown from last year's growth of 35 percent and average annual growth of around 40 percent since Hanoi opened its doors to the outside world in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>Nhat shrugged off the slowdown in arrivals and said he was confident that the country's wealth of culture and natural attractions would keep tourists flowing in.</p>
<p>However, he said heavy investment was needed to improve the quality of services available for tourists and upgrade infrastructure.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to raise the quality of service,&quot; he said. &quot;The question of infrastructure is one of the biggest in developing countries. We can't solve that problem overnight.&quot;</p>
<p>The country is still a challenging destination for Western tourists because of poor roads, unreliable or sometimes non-existent public transport and a shortage of information. The most typical visitor is still the impecunious backpacker.</p>
<p>Nhat also said he was not overly concerned about a glut of hotel rooms which has emerged in Ho Chi Minh City and, to a lesser extent, in Hanoi.</p>
<p>He said the &quot;invisible hand&quot; of market forces would ensure that an equilibrium of supply and demand is eventually established.</p>
<p>The oversupply situation has hit state-run hotels, which generally offer poorer services than new foreign hotels, hard and left many with unsustainably low occupancy and room rates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
