<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148611" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain details privatisation schedule up to June 97.</title>
<headline>Spain details privatisation schedule up to June 97.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Industry Minister Josep Pique detailed on Sunday a more precise privatisation calendar for the first six months of 1997, local media reported.</p>
<p>The remaining 21 percent state stake in Telefonica will be put on sale in January or February, while the remaining 10 percent of Repsol will be offered on the market in February or March, Pique said in Tenerife.</p>
<p>By summer the Spanish government has planned to put Argentaria on the market, Pique added. Spain has a remaining 25 percent stake in the banking group.  </p>
<p>Pique explained that this privatisation program will go ahead providing market conditions allow and other countries' programmes do not interfere.</p>
<p>Eletrical firm Endesa, in which the state holds a 66-percent stake, will be privatised in three tranches, he said.</p>
<p>In the first, Spain is expected to sell a 20- to 25-percent stake. This sale should be concluded by the end of 1997. All three sales will be concluded by 1999.</p>
<p>The reason for the three-tranche approach is the relatively large market capitalisation of the firm -- almost two trillion pesetas. Each tranche will be around 600 and 700 billion pesetas, Pique said.</p>
<p>Pique said he expected the process, though difficult, to succeed.</p>
<p>--Madrid Newsroom +34 1 585 2167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
