<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148627" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Canal Plus in film rights deal with Univ.</title>
<headline>Canal Plus in film rights deal with Univ.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>French pay television broadcaster Canal Plus on Monday signed an exclusive long-term film rights deal with Universal Pictures, securing an important source of movies for the digital television age.</p>
<p>Canal Plus started its Canalsatellite digital satellite television service on April 27 and a rival French consortium, TPS, is due to start services before Christmas and recently signed up the Paramount and MGM Hollywood studios for a total of some $650 million.</p>
<p>In a joint statement, Canal Plus and the MCA Inc unit of Canada's Seagram Company Ltd, said they had concluded a long term agreement, including exclusive film rights and the creation of a special Universal channel on Canalsatellite.</p>
<p>Universal Pictures is part of MCA.</p>
<p>Canal Plus and Germany's Kirch Gruppe both claim to have Europe's biggest catalogue of film tittles.</p>
<p>The Universal channel &quot;will be dedicated to action-adventure/mystery product drawing upon French and European programming as well as Universal's extensive library of titles from this genre, such as &quot;Columbo&quot;, &quot;Magnum P.I.&quot;, &quot;Murder She Wrote&quot; and &quot;The A-team&quot;&quot;, Canal Plus said.</p>
<p>The deal also gives exclusive pay television rights to Canal Plus and Canalsatellite for &quot;Waterworld&quot;, &quot;Babe&quot; and &quot;Apollo 13&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This agreement solidifies the 10-year association that Universal has enjoyed with Canal Plus and we are delighted to have this opportunity to build and broaden this mutually beneficial relationship,&quot; Blair Westlake, President of Universal Pay Television and Television Business Development was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Pierre Lescure, chairman of Canal Plus, said that &quot;This agreement ... also marks a new area of cooperation between Europe's leading pay TV network and a US major studio. It symbolises a common strategic approach -- together we are entering the digital age.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal also included exclusive pay-television rights on Universal's library.</p>
<p>&quot;I am pleased to be in partnership with Universal, whose rich history as one of Hollywood's oldest and most established studios is evident in its vast library and continued international box office successes,&quot; Canalsatellite chairman Bruno Delecour said.</p>
<p>Canal Plus officials declined to divulge financial details.</p>
<p>The rival TPS -- Television Par Satellite -- consortium is headed by commercial broadcaster TF1, itself part of Bouygues and state-owned France Television.</p>
<p>Lyonnaise des Eaux unit M6 and Luxembourg Compagnie Luxembourgeoise de Telediffusion (CLT) are also part of the consortium.</p>
<p>CLT operates the RTL channels in Germany and the Benelux countries and a small eastern part of France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
