<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148745" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Canberra sees growth, jobs under new labour system.</title>
<headline>Canberra sees growth, jobs under new labour system.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's conservative government promised more jobs and faster economic growth on Monday after securing essential minor-party backing for radical labour relations reforms.</p>
<p>Industrial Relations Minister Peter Reith, who concluded a weekend deal to get his reforms through parliament, said the system inherited from the former Labor government was too rigid and discouraged flexible wage contracts to boost productivity.</p>
<p>&quot;We're addressing those problems,&quot; Reith told Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>&quot;We're simplifying the system and all of that should encourage higher growth and of course from higher growth comes a better job outlook for the Australian community.&quot;</p>
<p>Like many Western economies, Australia suffers from intractably rising unemployment, even though it enjoys economic growth that averages more than three percent a year -- higher than most developed countries.</p>
<p>Although the unemployment rate has declined from a peak of 11 percent in 1992, it stopped falling at above eight percent a year ago and has now nudged up to 8.7 percent.</p>
<p>The government's answer has been to drive the economy faster -- Treasurer Peter Costello said this month that more than four percent growth was needed -- but it has arged that a well-oiled labour-relations system would produce greater productivity and non-inflationary growth.</p>
<p>Reith's deal with the Democrats at the weekend means his Workplace Relations Bill can pass through the upper house or Senate, where the government lacks a clear majority.</p>
<p>The Democrats will table 171 agreed amendments to the bill, although Reith said its &quot;basic integrity&quot; had been kept.</p>
<p>Trades unionists said the new laws, which would allow non-unionised workers to bypass them in making deals directly with employers, would only cause more strikes.</p>
<p>Traditionally, Australian wages were set by a central industrial court that heard arguments from unions and employers.</p>
<p>The Labor government, which lost power in March to a conservative coalition, had begun to deregulate the system but unions still kept their powerful role.</p>
<p>&quot;I think industrial disputation will increase, particularly against companies that want to use the legislation for their own ideological purposes,&quot; the president of the Australian Council of Trade Unions, Jennie George, told reporters.</p>
<p>But Reith told Reuters he thought the the new system's cooperative approach would create industrial harmony.</p>
<p>&quot;The changes to the agreement process will encourage a more cooperative, harmonious approach to workplace negotiations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reith's bill is expected to become law within a few weeks and be put into operation as early as February next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
