<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148763" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Woodside seeks to lift oil output.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Woodside seeks to lift oil output.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Woodside Petroleum Ltd said on Monday it was investigating ways to lift crude oil production capacity at the Cossack Pioneer project on Australia's North West Shelf to 135,000 barrels a day from 115,000.</p>
<p>The investigation centers on alleviating a &quot;bottlenecking&quot; problem at the processing stage, which is currently restricting output, a Woodside spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Cossack Pioneer is currently producing about 50,000 barrels a day while repairs are made to the facility's gas export system, the spokesman said.  </p>
<p>The repairs are scheduled to be completed by November 6. &quot;We're on schedule with the repair work,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Woodside intends to run the Cossack Pioneer at about 115,000 barrels a day once the repair work is completed, he said.</p>
<p>Woodside holds a one-sixth interest in the North West Shelf field and is operator on behalf of five other equal partners.</p>
<p>An increase in capacity would encourage early development of the recently discovered Hermes oil field and possibly the Spica prospect, which was spudded last weekend, the spokesman said. Spica is six km northeast of the Hermes discovery well.  </p>
<p>The increase in production for the Cossack-Pioneer would be part of broader development plans for the North West Shelf, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The North West Shelf partners are in negotiations with Japanese power industry customers to roughly double production of liquefied natural gas (LNG) from the North West Shelf to about 14 million tonnes a year by 2003.</p>
<p>The Japanese customers, who currently purchase the North West Shelf's total annual output of 7.33 million tonnes, are studying a proposal for expansion presented to them in Osaka earlier this month, the spokesman said.  </p>
<p>The expansion of LNG production would occur through the development of two LNG trains of 3.4 million tonnes capacity each.</p>
<p>&quot;The first new train would come on in 2002 followed by second soon after, probably early in 2003,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The expansion would likely offer opportunites to sell LNG on the spot market until projected demand for gas in Japan caught up with the added tonnage, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>In the past South Korea has been an active buyer of LNG on spot markets and could be a potential customer again, he said.  </p>
<p>Spain and Turkey, which emerged as buyers of North West Shelf LNG during its initial development starting in 1989, also are seen as potential customers, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>An expansion would also meet projections for higher domestic sales of gas, including sales to a new iron ore processing plant and power station under construction in Port Hedland by The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd, he said.</p>
<p>Production of condensate, propane and butane would also increase under proposed development plans, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>A critical component of the expansion plan is construction of a second trunkline, he said.  </p>
<p>An existing trunkline leading to the Burrup Peninsula in Western Australia will be operating at maximum capacity starting next year to meet existing sales commitments, he said.</p>
<p>He said the partners hope to have a second trunkline commissioned by 1999 in line with BHP's requirements for its iron ore operations.</p>
<p>The other partners in the North West Shelf are BHP, Chevron Corp, Royal Dutch/Shell, The British Petroleum Co Plc and Japan Australia LNG (MiMi) Pty Ltd.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
