<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="148924" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan coalition talks drag on, only partial deal.</title>
<headline>Japan coalition talks drag on, only partial deal.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Potential coalition partners in Japan's hung parliament failed to strike a deal to form a new government on Monday, remaining far apart on security issues and political reform, party officials said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) began negotiations last Saturday with its old allies, the Social Democrats and the Sakigake party, after failing to win a parliamentary majority in general elections on October 20.</p>
<p>The talks were to continue on Tuesday. The government has said it would reconvene parliament on November 7 to elect a new prime minister.</p>
<p>&quot;We did agree to set up a watchdog group within parliament to oversee the conduct of bureaucrats,&quot; said Taku Yamazaki, the LDP policy head, but he added that there was still no convergence of view on some other key issues.</p>
<p>&quot;We are on a parallel track with our partners on security issues and political donations,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Streamlining the bloated and overly powerful bureaucracy was the biggest issue in the general elections, after a series of scandals involving the finance and health ministries.</p>
<p>Hashimoto could be forced to lead an unstable minority government should he fail to cement a renewed alliance.</p>
<p>The LDP holds 239 seats, a dozen short of a majority in parliament's powerful Lower House.</p>
<p>It needs the Social Democrats' 15 Lower House seats and 32 Upper House seats to command majorities in both houses. Sakigake has two Lower House and four Upper House seats.</p>
<p>But fearful of becoming an irrelevant force in an LDP-dominated coalition, the Social Democrats have demanded that the LDP agree to a blanket ban on political donations from corporations, and agree to scale down a set of new military guidelines under the U.S.-Japan Security Treaty.</p>
<p>The two issues are anathema to the LDP, which has long aimed to strengthen military ties with the United States and has survived on donations from big businesses.</p>
<p>The representative from the third party in the talks, Sakigake deputy chief Hiroyuki Sonoda, said the three parties also agreed to review the new electoral system.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed to conduct a thorough review of the electoral system,&quot; Sonoda said after Monday's talks.</p>
<p>&quot;This includes the problem of double candidates. We also agreed to reduce the overall number of (Lower House) seats.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the system introduced in the October 20 general elections, a candidate running in one of 300 single-seat constituencies could also be listed on the party proportional representation list in 11 regional blocs.</p>
<p>In some cases, candidates finishing a dismal fourth in the first-past-the-post constituency won seats anyway as a result of the party gaining enough votes through proportional representation, even though the second or third finisher failed to win a seat.</p>
<p>That twist in the system came under severe criticism from voters and political analysts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
