<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149084" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Visa's second quarter Asia trade volume up 25 pct.</title>
<headline>Visa's second quarter Asia trade volume up 25 pct.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Credit card company Visa International said in a statement on Monday that its second quarter 1996 Asia-Pacific trading volume was up 25 percent year on year to US$27.5 billion.</p>
<p>Full year comparison for the 12 months ended June 30, 1996, saw volumes rise to a record US$104.1 billion, also a increase of 25 per cent, it said.</p>
<p>Visa said it has issued about 94 million cards in the region, which were used in 712.9 million transactions in the 12 months to June 30, 1996.</p>
<p>The biggest growths in volume in the quarter were recorded in India and Pakistan at 80 percent (to US$60 million) and 59 percent (to US$30 million) respectively against the second quarter of 1995, said the statement.</p>
<p>Singapore had the slowest volume growth of 13 percent to US$740 million in the three months to June 30, 1996 compared to the same period in 1995.</p>
<p>Strong growth in volume was also recorded in Taiwan (57 percent), Philippines (55 percent), Malaysia (42 percent) and Australia (35 percent).  </p>
<p>The figures include goods and services purchasing in China, which saw volume up 34 percent to US$5.1 billion in the 12 months to June 30.</p>
<p>Japan remains Visa's biggest Asia-Pacific market with 53.5 million cards and 38 percent of the volume (US$39 billion) for the 12 months ending June. South Korea is second biggest with about 21 percent of volume (US$21.5 billion) from 10.8 million cards.</p>
<p>Visa is a worldwide payment card system grouping 20,000 member financial institutions and 13 million locations accepting the card as payment.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150108">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
