<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149104" id="root" date="1996-10-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan Sugar says buys 3-yr, 180,000T sugar supply.</title>
<headline>Taiwan Sugar says buys 3-yr, 180,000T sugar supply.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>State-owned Taiwan Sugar Corp said on Monday it had completed a contract to buy 60,000 tonnes of sugar a year over three years from January 1997 from Czarnikow, setting the deal at a private tender in New York.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have decided to buy the three-year sugar supply from Czarnikow,&quot; a Taiwan Sugar executive confirmed to Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>The executive said the deal was reached on Thursday in New York at an invitation-only tender but not disclosed publicly and that pricing details would remain confidential.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides have agreed not to disclose the purchase price in a long-term relationship,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Shipments and freight would be set with Czarnikow, a British specialist supplier, as actual demand occurs, the Taiwan Sugar executive said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's state sugar monopoly is on track to import 120,000 tonnes of sugar in 1996, industry sources have said.</p>
<p>Taiwan Sugar bought two 30,000-tonne shipments of sugar on June 26 in New York at US$305.50 and US$302 per tonne on a cost-and-freight basis.</p>
<p>Traders said the company hoped to streamline its sugar procurement by landing one long-term contract rather than relying on smaller as-needed tenders.  </p>
<p>Taiwan Sugar, like most state companies on the rapidly liberalising island, is under mandate to privatise.</p>
<p>But the cabinet, in a June 27 ruling, determined it would not face serious competition before 2002.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
