<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149397" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-KARLSRUHE KILL OFF ROMA'S COMEBACK HOPES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-KARLSRUHE KILL OFF ROMA'S COMEBACK HOPES.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Karlsruhe killed off Roma's hopes of a UEFA Cup comeback on Tuesday despite conceding two first half goals by Argentine striker Abel Balbo in the space of five minutes at the Olympic Stadium.</p>
<p>The Germans lost the second-round second-leg clash 2-1 on the night but won 4-2 on aggregate.</p>
<p>Roma's Argentine coach Carlos Bianchi, whose team were beaten 3-0 by Karlsruhe in the first leg, threw caution to the wind and almost masterminded an upset.</p>
<p>He ditched the cautious 4-4-2 line-up he usually favours and started with three strikers up front.</p>
<p>In the second half, as Karlsruhe retreated into defence, Francesco Totti came on as a fourth attacker for the Italians.</p>
<p>Roma, unrecognisable from the downcast and disorganised team that has lost twice and drawn once in their last three matches, began briskly and were unlucky not to score more goals.</p>
<p>Balbo slotted in their first after 22 minutes after Marco Delvecchio served up a fine cross into the area.</p>
<p>The Argentine scored again in the 26th. Uruguayan Daniel Fonseca's shot was parried, Delvecchio knocked it past Karlsruhe goalkeeper Claus Rettmaier and Balbo swept the ball home.</p>
<p>But Karlsruhe midfielder Marc Keller made the score 2-1 seven minutes from time with a rasping shot from the edge of the area to shatter Roma's hopes.</p>
<p>&quot;At 2-0 I thought we had done everything we had to do in the first half,&quot; Bianchi said. &quot;In the second it was much harder to get at the goal but the team played very well.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
