<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149304" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Unocal to carve out 76 Products unit, mulls sale.</title>
<headline>Unocal to carve out 76 Products unit, mulls sale.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unocal Corp. said Tuesday it plans to separate its 76 Products Co. subsidiary from its core exploration and production businesses and may ultimately sell the unit.</p>
<p>Los Angeles-based Unocal said 76 Products was formed in 1994 and controls refining, marketing, and transportation assets, but does not legally hold them. The ownership of those assets will be transferred to 76 Products Co. on Jan. 1.</p>
<p>Unocal said it expected to carve out the separate unit once 76 Products became consistently profitable and will consider an initial public offering, a joint venture, or an outright sale.</p>
<p>&quot;The timing for implementing one of these options depends upon 76 Products' continued progress in developing sustainable earnings and cash flow,&quot; said Roger Beach, the company's chairman.</p>
<p>The 76 Products Co. will employ 3,100 people and hold about $2.7 billion in assets, Unocal said.</p>
<p>These assets will include three refineries in California, with a combined crude oil input capacity of 251,000 barrels per day. The unit will lease or own a chain of 1,200 service stations in six western states.</p>
<p>Unocal said 76 Products will control interests in bulk plants and terminals, West Coast pipelines and a marine fleet of one crude oil tanker and two refined product tankers.</p>
<p>For the first nine months of 1996, the business unit reported pretax income of $128 million on revenues of $3.6 billion, Unocal said.</p>
<p>Unocal shares rose $1.125 to $36.625 in late trading on the New York Stock Exchange trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
