<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149421" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIAN PREMIER RULES OUT POST-ELECTION RESHUFFLE.</title>
<headline>BULGARIAN PREMIER RULES OUT POST-ELECTION RESHUFFLE.</headline>
<byline>Liliana Semerdjieva</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgarian Prime Minister Zhan Videnov said on Tuesday he had no plans for a cabinet reshuffle even though his ex-communist ruling party suffered big losses in weekend presidential elections.</p>
<p>Official results from Sunday's first round voting showed opposition candidate Petar Stoyanov had 43.92 percent of the vote to Socialist Ivan Marazov's 26.92 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;None of the presidential candidate teams won more than half of the votes, therefore the commission announces that a second round will be held on November 3,&quot; an electoral commission spokesman told state radio.</p>
<p>Videnov, under fire from the opposition and from dissidents within his Bulgarian Socialist Party over his management of an unprecedented economic crisis, told a news conference cabinet changes now could make matters worse.</p>
<p>&quot;If we make such changes in the coming months we risk failing to prevent a real financial catastrophe in the country,&quot; Videnov told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an illusion that with lightning changes in the government and the party leadership, the problems can be solved.&quot;</p>
<p>Delays in implementing market reforms have dragged Bulgaria deep into economic crisis. An International Monetary Fund mission arrives on Wednesday for more talks on a twice-delayed $115 million credit, vital if Bulgaria is to avoid default on its foreign debt.</p>
<p>&quot;We will try to convince the IMF mission that all planned measures aimed at improving financial discipline...in the country have been fulfilled,&quot; Videnov said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the Fund will be interested mainly in the macroeconomic situation in the country, which unfortunately cannot be seen as favourable.&quot;</p>
<p>Gross domestic product is expected to shrink by up to 10.5 percent this year and the annual inflation rate is put at 240 percent. Record high interest rates introduced to stabilise the collapsing banking system have doubled internal debt this year.</p>
<p>Videnov said economic hardship had turned voters away from the Socialists. &quot;Economic reform, started under such conditions, has its hard political price. We are prepared to pay for it and we are paying for it at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Former colleagues of communist leader Todor Zhivkov hastily renamed themselves socialists after he was toppled in 1989 and stunned the rest of Europe by winning parliamentary elections in 1990.</p>
<p>The party draws much of its support from older people nostalgic for the low prices and greater security of the past, but Videnov said many of its supporters abstained on Sunday and the party hoped to woo them back for the second round.</p>
<p>&quot;In the second decisive round it depends on them whether we will return and give a chance for reform to bear its first positive fruit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 63 percent turnout on Sunday was much lower than the 75 percent in 1994 parliamentary election.</p>
<p>Videnov said there was no alternative to the government's policies and he had no plans for a coalition government.</p>
<p>Analysts said the Socialists lost votes to protest candidates like George Ganchev of the Bulgarian Business Bloc, who polled 21.79 percent, and independent candidate Alexander Tomov, a former communist, who took three percent.</p>
<p>Videnov said the socialists would hold talks with Ganchev and Tomov on Wednesday, hoping to secure their support in the second round. Ganchev has ruled out any deal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
