<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149412" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-BUOYANT DORTMUND STILL HAVE PROBLEMS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BUOYANT DORTMUND STILL HAVE PROBLEMS.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Smith</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Borussia Dortmund, virtually assured a place in the European Cup quarter-finals, will be severely below strength at home to Atletico Madrid on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Seven players are out injured and two more -- Juergen Kohler and Joerg Heinrich -- are suspended.</p>
<p>But the Germans go into the match in confident mood, having beaten Atletico in Madrid two weeks ago and trounced Arminia Bielefeld 5-0 in the Bundesliga last Saturday.</p>
<p>Dortmund, who head Group B with maximum nine points, will give Norwegian Steinar Peddersen his Champions' League debut after losing defender Martin Kree with a thigh muscle strain. </p>
<p>This still leaves trainer Ottmar Hitzfeld with defensive problems. Kohler is out after picking up two yellow cards, while Matthias Sammer, one of Germany's Euro 96 winners, and Austrian international Wolfgang Feiersinger are among the injured.</p>
<p>Knut Reinhardt is likely to replace Heinrich in midfield.</p>
<p>Atletico hope to have international playmaker Jose Luis Caminero fit again after a month.</p>
<p>&quot;We will do some tests in the Borussia stadium before making a decision,&quot; coach Radomir Antic said.</p>
<p>Atletico have struggled in Caminero's absence, although the Spanish champions ended a run of three defeats with a 1-0 victory at Sporting Gijon on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;This victory strengthened our morale, although we know we're going to have a hard time in Dortmund,&quot; Atletico striker Kiko Narvaez said.</p>
<p>Antic restated his belief that his team were better than Dortmund despite having lost 1-0 against the Germans two weeks ago and looking fragile in the Spanish league.</p>
<p>&quot;We're happy to be going to Dortmund,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Defender Toni Munoz will have a late fitness test before Wednesday's game because of a muscle strain but is expected to play.</p>
<p>Antic brings back Czech midfielder Radek Bejbl, who was dropped for Atletico's last league game, to replace Argentine midfielder Diego Simeone, who is suspended.</p>
<p>Four headed goals make Simeone Atletico's leading marksman in the Champions' League and the Spanish side may miss him badly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
