<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149559" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CRITEF partners postpone merger votes.</title>
<headline>CRITEF partners postpone merger votes.</headline>
<dateline>ROCKVILLE, Md. 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The general partners of CRITEF partnerships said they postponed meetings to approve proposed mergers between CRITEF partnerships and affiliates of Capital Apartment Properties Inc until November 8.</p>
<p>The meeting was changed from October 29 to give investors more opportunity to vote their interests, they said.</p>
<p>There are two CRITEF partnerships with three series of securities that trade on the American Stock Exchange - Capital Realty Investors Tax Exempt Limited Partnership and Capital Realty Investors Tax Exempt Fund III Limited Partnership.  </p>
<p>CRITEF general partners also cited alleged attempts by Dominium Tax Exempt Fund LLP to impede the proposed merger.</p>
<p>&quot;The barrage of misinformation disseminated by Dominium in its self-serving effort to block the merger appears to have confused some Beneficial Assignee Certificate holders and may have caused them to withold their votes,&quot; CRITEF general partners were quoted as telling Beneficial Assignee Certificate holders in a letter.</p>
<p>&quot;Accordingly, the CRITEF Funds have not yet received the approval of a majority of the outstanding Beneficial Assignee Certificates,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>Dominium was not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROCKVILLE, Md."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
