<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149563" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DSP shares off on merger news.</title>
<headline>DSP shares off on merger news.</headline>
<byline>Sue Zeidler</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares of DSP Communications Inc fell nearly 33 percent on Tuesday in reaction to the company's announced $400 million merger with Proxim Inc reflecting concerns that DSP may have too much.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said DSP was also hurt by fears the stock deal might be dilutive to earnings, something DSP officials denied.</p>
<p>DSP stock tumbled $17.125 to $35.25, while Proxim's shares rose $2-51/64 to $21.50.  </p>
<p>Under the terms of the deal, Proxim shareholders will get 0.70 of a DSP common share for each Proxim share. The deal values Proxim at $36.66 per share, based on Monday's closing price, well above the current price. During a conference call with analysts and investors, DSP officials were questioned about the valuation.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't understand why you felt you need to pay such a premium (for Proxim) and that's what DSP shareholders are quite disturbed,&quot; said one institutional investor. &quot;It's not clear why you should pay a price that is double the price of the stock for a deal that would hopefully be synergistic and not immediately so.</p>
<p>Company officials said they were confident the merger would be non-dilutive to earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;Analysts estimate that it will be five percent dilutive&quot; in 1997, said DSP chief executive Nathan Hod at an industry conference in Monterey. &quot;Knowing what analysts don't know about DSP, I believe this deal will not be dilutive.&quot;</p>
<p>Several analysts said the sell-off was an overreaction.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a great story from a long-term perspective,&quot; said Robert Kaimowitz, analyst with Unterberg Harris.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe it could be marginally dilutive in 1997, but could easily be accretive by 1998 and 1999.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
