<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14950" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lloyd's says most members accept settlement - WSJ.</title>
<headline>Lloyd's says most members accept settlement - WSJ.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lloyd's of London said 75 percent of its worldwide membership had accepted the terms of its 3.2-billion-pound ($4.7 billion) settlement offer by midday Saturday, The Wall Street Journal reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The announcement followed an appeal launched on Saturday to overturn a federal ruling against the insurance giant's rescue plan.</p>
<p>On Friday, U.S. District Judge Robert Payne blocked Lloyd's from imposing its rescue plan on dissident U.S. investors and ordered a trial on charges the insurer withheld critical financial information on the planned restructuring of the insurance market.</p>
<p>However, the judget did not block U.S. investors from accepting the deal if they chose to do so.</p>
<p>Payne issued an injunction extending the deadline for U.S. members to accept or reject the settlement offer to October 30 from August 28. He also found Lloyd's in violation of U.S. securities laws, because the firm used the mail to recruit U.S. investors' support for the restructuring plan.</p>
<p>About 2,700 of Lloyd's 34,000 worldwide members are American, a Lloyd's spokesman told the newspaper. He said some U.S. members had accepted the terms, but would not specify how many of the approximately 25,500 members who have accepted the terms are U.S. members.</p>
<p>Lloyd's investors, or &quot;names,&quot; must pledge their entire net worth to make good on the insurance policies they agree to underwrite.</p>
<p>Lloyd's chairman David Rowland said, &quot;At 75 percent valid acceptances with four days to go before the deadline of 12 noon, Wednesday, August 28, I'm confident that, by the deadline, the offer will have been accepted by the overwhelming majority of members.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
