<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149581" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lehigh Group to merge with First Medical.</title>
<headline>Lehigh Group to merge with First Medical.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lehigh Group Inc said on Tuesday it executed a definitive merger agreement with First Medical Corp, a privately-held integrated medical services company, for undisclosed terms.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the deal, First Medical would merge into a newly formed Lehigh subsidiary, Lehigh said. After the merger, Lehigh shareholders would retain four percent of the capital stock of Lehigh, it said.  </p>
<p>The transaction was approved by the both companies' boards but was subject to shareholder approval, Lehigh said, adding it expected shareholders meetings to be held in late December.</p>
<p>For the six months ended June 30, First Medical had revenues of $26 million, Lehigh said. It operated businesses in physician management, hospital services and international primary care centers.  </p>
<p>Lehigh chairman and chief executive officer Salvatore Zizza also sold First Medical an option to buy up to six million Lehigh shares at $0.50 per share, Lehigh said. That option, if exercised in full, would equal about 37 percent of Lehigh's stock at that time, it said.</p>
<p>Zizza agreed to use his best efforts prior to the record date for the Lehigh stockholders' meeting to obtain irrevocable proxies for Lehigh shares he and other Lehigh officers and directors owned.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
