<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="14964" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Bank of Israel chief says high rates still needed.</title>
<headline>Bank of Israel chief says high rates still needed.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Israel Governor Jacob Frenkel said the central bank would further lower interest rates only if inflation is seen to go down.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters Financial Television, Frenkel said: &quot;We will not lower interest rates on the hope of lower inflation. When we see positive results (in inflation) interest rates will be adjusted further.&quot;</p>
<p>Frenkel said the 0.5 percentage point cut in its key lending rate to commercial banks, announced earlier on Monday, was justified by the fact that there is a reversal of inflation expectations and Israel is already seeing some benefits of the monetary restraint exercised by the central bank.</p>
<p>But, he said, &quot;inflation is still above the set target of the government and calls for a continuation of monetary restraint.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that with the success of the monetary restraint policies he expected that in a few months inflation would be back in line with the government target. He also said that the government's proposed 1997 budget cuts would help share the burden of cooling the economy.</p>
<p>Frenkel said that one of the main sources for the crisis in the capital markets is the uncertainty caused by the rise in government deficit and high inflation. Another cause was the structural problems of the market which needed to be solved.</p>
<p>He said part of the capital markets problems would be solved &quot;once macro-economic policies get in line and the political uncertainty associated with the government policies is put to rest.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
