<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149780" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MMS to streamline royalties appeals process.</title>
<headline>U.S. MMS to streamline royalties appeals process.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Minerals Management Service said Tuesday it proposed a rule setting a 16-month limit for the agency to process administrative appeals from lessees, producers and payers of oil and natural gas royalties on federal and Indian lands.</p>
<p>Under the proposal, appeals that were not decided by MMS within 16-months -- other than those with formal extensions or agreements -- would automatically be deemed denied by MMS and the appellant could continue the appeal before the Interior Department's Board of Land Appeals.  </p>
<p>The Federal Oil and Gas Simplification and Fairness Act, signed into law in August, sets a 33-month timeframe for the department to issue a final decision on administrative appeals on federal oil and gas royalty payments.</p>
<p>The new rule would ensure that appeals were decided at the first level within the first half of the statutory deadline.</p>
<p>The MMS rule also would speed processing of appeals not covered by the new oil and gas act, such as appeals involving leases on Indian lands and leases for minerals other than oil and gas.  </p>
<p>The proposed rule would impose a $100 uniform filing fee on all appeals, but the fee for appeals filed by Indian tribes or allottees will be waived.</p>
<p>MMS would return the filing fee if no appeal decision were made within 16 months.</p>
<p>The rule only would apply to appeals made after the rule took effect. MMS will hold the proposal open for public comment through December 27.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
