<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149710" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OshKosh B'Gosh to close Kentucky plant.</title>
<headline>OshKosh B'Gosh to close Kentucky plant.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBIA, Ky. 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>OshKosh B'Gosh Inc said Tuesday it will close its manufacturing plant in Columbia, Ky., which makes children's woven bib overalls, jumpers and jeans, in mid-March.</p>
<p>&quot;Excess capacity, mainly a result of a shift in consumers' demand to more knit products versus woven products, has led to a decrease in available work for our Columbia operation,&quot; Michael Wachtel, chief operating officer, said in a statement issued here. &quot;Regrettably, we have no alternative but to close this facility.&quot;  </p>
<p>Any future demand for the type of products currently manufactured at Columbia will be primarily sourced offshore, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Over five years ago we began implementing a strategy to develop our offshore sourcing capabilities,&quot; Wachtel said. &quot;We have been forced to develop this capability as a means of survival in an increasingly competitive marketplace.&quot;</p>
<p>The Columbia plant employs about 413 people. Eligible employees will receive severance pay and outplacement assistance.</p>
<p>OshKosh B'Gosh said it is actively pursuing a buyer for the Columbia facility.</p>
<p>Excluding the Columbia facility, OshKosh B'Gosh operates seven manufacturing and two distribution centers, employing over 3,000 people in the United States. Total corporate-wide employment is approximately 5,500 employees.</p>
<p>OshKosh B'Gosh, which makes children's apparel, is based in Oshkosh, Wis.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I45300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBIA, Ky."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
