<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149791" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM, UAW resume labor pact discussions.</title>
<headline>GM, UAW resume labor pact discussions.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Auto Workers bargainers reconvened at General Motors Corp's headquarters on Tuesday following a day off Monday, but discussions between the two sides maintained a low profile, UAW and company spokesmen said.</p>
<p>UAW workers continued to report to their jobs at GM's U.S. factories, despite the expiration of their national labor agreement with the automaker at 11:59 p.m. EST Sunday.</p>
<p>GM spokesman Charles Licari said there were no major &quot;main-table&quot; meetings scheduled, but key negotiators were communicating in small groups and via telephone.  </p>
<p>&quot;Discussions are taking place, but there is no set timetable regarding the negotiations,&quot; Licari said, adding that such communications still may prove fruitful.</p>
<p>However, a person close to the talks said he did not expect the situation to change much before Saturday, when the union's key plant-level GM local leaders are scheduled to meet in Detroit.</p>
<p>UAW President Stephen Yokich recessed the talks on Monday and expressed disappointment with the progress of the negotiations, but he refrained from calling a strike against the world's largest automaker.  </p>
<p>Still, Yokich said some of the union's GM locals may resort to strikes if progress in local negotiations doesn't improve. In addition to the national contract, GM is negotiating with more than 100 UAW locals for pacts that cover plant-specific issues.</p>
<p>In New York on Tuesday, GM Chairman Jack Smith said little about the UAW negotiations, but told reporters he hoped there would be no local strikes.</p>
<p>The threat of additional strikes comes less than a week after Canadian Auto Workers members returned to work following a three-week walkout over job security and outsourcing issues.  </p>
<p>Smith, speaking at a news conference on alternative fuel vehicles, declined to specify the dollar cost of the strike.</p>
<p>&quot;We lost quite a few cars,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>GM said on Tuesday that 22,913 workers in its U.S. assembly, powertrain and stamping operations remain idled because of lingering shortages of Canadian-made parts.</p>
<p>The automaker said it laid off an additional 465 workers at its Lordstown, Ohio, metal stamping plant on Tuesday, one of four such plants affected.</p>
<p>GM's nearby Lordstown, Ohio, assembly plant remains completely idled, as does its Buick City assembly plant in Flint, Mich. Five other assembly plants remain partially idled, bringing GM's laid off assembly workers to 15,284.</p>
<p>GM has 5,702 engine and transmission workers laid off, with six such powertrain plants partially idled.</p>
<p>In the UAW talks, which cover a total of 215,000 U.S. hourly workers, GM has resisted the union's demand that it follow a pattern set by Ford Motor Co and Chrysler Corp and guarantee jobs for 95 percent of current workforce over the next three years. GM wants to exclude from the guarantee several parts plants it wants to sell. The automaker has identified 12 facilities that it considers uncompetitive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
