<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149845" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE December Brent ends down on day, but above sup.</title>
<headline>IPE December Brent ends down on day, but above sup.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE December Brent closed down some 45 cents on the day but held just above support with the market awaiting weekly API statistics due out after markets close, brokers said.</p>
<p>December Brent closed down 45 cents at $23.73 a barrel.</p>
<p>&quot;If we get bullish stats we could have a very sharp rebound tomorrow morning as the major support on the bull trend which has been running since mid summer would have held. On the other hand if we break through (trend line) everyone is going to want to sell,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>A Reuter survey forecast stock builds in crude and heating oil but a draw in gasoline stocks in the United States.</p>
<p>Below $23.70 the next support level on December Brent was seen around $23.00 a barrel followed by $22.70 a barrel.</p>
<p>Downward pressure on Brent could also come from the physical market where a cargo of Brent crude traded earlier at an unexpectedly low level. An early loading cargo of Brent sold for December Brent -43 cents, down 37 cents on the day and around a one dollar drop in differentials in ten days.</p>
<p>Physical traders said the European market was well oversupplied and could fall further for other sweet grades.</p>
<p>On the basis of the Brent and NYMEX heating oil close, November gas oil was called to open down $1-$2 a tonne from Tuesday's settlement at $223 a tonne.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
