<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="149839" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - U.S. data stems stock losses, dlr lower.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - U.S. data stems stock losses, dlr lower.</headline>
<byline>Roger Jeal</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reassuring news for markets from the first items on this week's busy schedule of U.S. data helped European bourses stem their losses on Tuesday, while prompting U.S. bonds and Wall Street to early gains.</p>
<p>A weaker than expected rise in third-quarter employment costs -- 0.6 percent versus forecasts around 0.8 percent -- eased some inflation fears and sparked a rally in U.S. bonds and shares.</p>
<p>Later news that the U.S. consumer confidence index fell to 106.2 in October from a revised 111.8 in September brought more encouragement that U.S. interest rates, which set wider trends, might not have to rise just yet to keep inflation in check.</p>
<p>Wall Street, the world's biggest stock market watched keenly by markets elsewhere, fluctuated within a 39-point range centred on the Dow Jones industrial average's previous close in the first hour of trading.</p>
<p>After investors had digested the news, it ended the period with a gain of around five points but European bourses were still well into the minus column.</p>
<p>The recently buoyant dollar lost some of its shine after Germany's top economic institutes said the country's 1997 public deficit was likely to exceed its target for European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU). But the U.S. unit showed a fairly muted reaction to the latest American data.</p>
<p>Currency dealers said the institutes' report provided a reminder of the struggle European countries could have in meeting tough economic criteria for EMU, while hinting at the possibility of higher German interest rates.</p>
<p>Both these factors would be bullish signals for the mark, Europe's dominant currency at present.</p>
<p>Weighing in with their contribution to a long-running debate,  Bundesbank council members Olaf Sievert and Hans-Juergen Koebnick said there was no reason at present to make a move on rates but left open the chance of a further drop.</p>
<p>Their comments were seen by analysts as a fresh attempt to counter market nerves, set on edge last week when Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing seemed to rule out more rate cuts.</p>
<p>In Asian trading, the dollar had hit a new 42-month high of 114.88 yen against a Japanese currency weakened by a search by Japanese investors for higher-yielding investments abroad and political uncertainty after recent elections.</p>
<p>But the U.S. currency had soon headed lower against the mark and yen after the institutes' comments.</p>
<p>A sharp reverse on Wall Street on Monday and jitters over interest rates had undermined European stock markets from the start, prompting losses that exceeded one percent in some cases.</p>
<p>Just as the Dow, surrendering more than the amount it regained on Friday, ended below the key 6,000 level on Monday, London's FTSE 100 index slipped below its 4,000 landmark.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has a nervous feel...with last night's hurricane bringing back memories of 1987..today is a day to watch support levels,&quot; said Chris Chaitow at Robert Fleming Securities, referring to storms that lashed Britain overnight and the stock market crash nine years ago.</p>
<p>In Frankfurt, shares lost more than one percent due to uncertainty over interest rates, Wall Street's decline and a weaker dollar, which made less pleasant news for exporters.</p>
<p>French shares also fell more than one percent amid worries that Germany might boost interest rates, which would have a knock-on effect in other European countries. But they revived a little after bonds were boosted by the U.S. figures.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1530 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was around 1.5095 marks and 114 yen versus 1.5207 and 114.26 in late European business on Monday. It earlier fell as low as 1.5061 and 113.50.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the South African rand hit a record low of 4.6965 against the dollar before recovering marginally to 4.6890.</p>
<p>STOCKS AT 1530 GMT</p>
<p>London's FTSE 100 index was down 27.5 points at 3,997.8, having lost 36 points at one stage.</p>
<p>Germany's DAX index ended bourse floor trade 30.21 lower at 2,673.62. In Paris the CAC-40 index lost 26.79 to 2,123.60.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold eased to a fix of $381.70 an ounce in the afternoon from a morning fixing of $382.35 and Monday's London close of $383.35. Silver dropped 10 cents to $4.83.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
