<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150024" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Oct 29.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- Reserve Bank governor Chris Stals reiterated assurances that South Africa would follow the right policies as the rand crashed through records against the dollar and the pound.</p>
<p>- Malbak shareholders could be in for a fillip of at least one billion rand over the market value of the shares they receive from the unbundling of the consumer group.</p>
<p>- Off-peak domestic air travel is at its cheapest since 1991 after an airfare war broke out between SAA and British Airways-Comair.</p>
<p>- Parastatal Transnet waived normal tendering procedures in awarding a multi-million rand scrap metal contract to curb theft and promote black economic empowerment.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- The embattled rand hit record lows against the dollar and the pound fuelling speculation that it could soon reach five rand to the dollar.</p>
<p>- Oil company Engen improved substantially on last year's dismal performance by posting a 201 percent rise in net income for the year to August 31 of 349 million rand.</p>
<p>- The U.S. commerce department has identified South Africa as a preferred emerging market with special growth potential, officials in the South African embassy in Washington said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Commercial airline Comair went a step further than SAA and slashed prices to an all-time low for an indefinite period.</p>
<p>- An independent inquiry into irregularities in the Gauteng province matric exams is to be launched by the province's Education MEC, Mary Metcalfe.</p>
<p>- A second front has developed in the fighting in eastern Zaire and an estimated 800,000 people are now displaced in the region.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
