<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150053" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croat refugees to visit graves in Serb enclave.</title>
<headline>Croat refugees to visit graves in Serb enclave.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Up to 2,500 Croatian refugees from Eastern Slavonia plan to return to the Serb-held enclave for the first time in years and pay respect to their dead on the All Saints Day, a U.N. official said.</p>
<p>Philip Arnold, spokesman for the U.N. Transitional Administration for Eastern Slavonia (UNTAES), told Retuers on Tuesday between 2,000 and 2,500 refugees would cross over in buses on Friday under police and U.N. escort.</p>
<p>&quot;They will visit several grave sites in the area. It is religious observation and then they are going to come back (to government-ruled territory),&quot; Arnold told Reuters from the area's largest city of Vukovar.</p>
<p>He said both sides had pledged support to the visit, the details of which would be finalised on Wednesday. The visitors would be escorted by joint Croat-Serb police, UNTAES and U.N. civil police units, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect both sides to cooperate because everybody realises it is only religion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Every year thousands of believers in the former Yugoslav republic customarily visit graves of their loved ones on All Saints Day.</p>
<p>Croatian officials also agreed to allow Serbs from the enclave to visit cemetaries in Croatia, Arnold said.</p>
<p>Minority Serbs captured oil-rich and fertile Eastern Slavonia in mid-1991, at the outset of their rebellion against Croatia's independence from federal Yugoslavia. They expelled thousands of non-Serbs from the region.</p>
<p>Croatian army recaptured all other Serb-held areas in 1995, while Eastern Slavonia, now policed by 5,000 U.N. troops, is to revert to government rule some time next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
