<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150035" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Yugoslavia, Croatia agree cooperation moves.</title>
<headline>Yugoslavia, Croatia agree cooperation moves.</headline>
<byline>Mark Heinrich</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatia and rump Yugoslavia, building on their normalisation treaty, agreed on Tuesday to draw up benefit packages for people uprooted by war and to cooperate on international security issues.</p>
<p>Yugoslav Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic, on his first official visit to Zagreb following the August 23 treaty, and Croatian Foreign Minister Mate Granic focused in their talks on practical steps to harmonise relations.</p>
<p>Granic said two joint commissions would meet next month on a key emotional issue -- accounting for thousands of Croats and Serbs missing from the 1991-95 wars sparked by Croatia's secession from former federal Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>The two ministers also agreed that Croatian Interior Minister Ivan Jarnjak would visit Belgrade on November 11 to discuss accords on fighting drug trafficking, terrorism and other security concerns.</p>
<p>&quot;These are absolutely necessary European standards, border security for example,&quot; Granic told reporters, alluding to requirements set by the European Union for eventual integration of east European countries.</p>
<p>Talks would also begin in early November on harmonising welfare, pension and and health benefits for Croats and Serbs who lost ancestral homes in either country during the war.</p>
<p>Two commissions set up to reopen railway traffic between Croatia and rump Yugoslavia will meet in Belgrade on November 4 to sign agreements, Granic said.</p>
<p>Milutinovic said he expected 10 important practical agreements taking normalisation forward would be signed by the end of 1996. &quot;This expresses considerable political will to carry out principles of the August treaty,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Belgrade and Zagreb opened full diplomatic relations after a surprise summit between Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic and Croatian President Franjo Tudjman this year.</p>
<p>Belgrade recognised Croatia's sovereignty over Eastern Slavonia, the last rebel Serb enclave on its territory. The region, bordering Yugoslavia, is to be handed back to Croatia next year after a transitional period under U.N. authority.</p>
<p>Minority Serbs seized almost a third of Croatia in a 1991 revolt against independence backed by the Yugoslav army but lost everything except for Eastern Slavonia to Croatian army offensives in 1995.</p>
<p>Tudjman is under domestic pressure to resettle 80,000 Croat refugees in Eastern Slavonia and says Zagreb will accept a U.N. mandate extension for a maximum three months to April 15, 1997, with U.N. peacekeeping troops to be out by July.</p>
<p>Croatia has accused the East Slavonian Serbs of stalling for an autonomy deal by demanding a one-year extension to January 1998, a time frame thought to be supported in principle by their old ethnic patrons in Belgrade.</p>
<p>Croatian government sources had said Granic wanted to seek a consensus with Milutinovic on when U.N. authorities should formally hand back Eastern Slavonia to Croatia.</p>
<p>But Granic and Milutinovic, asked about the issue, said only that Eastern Slavonia must be reintegrated peacefully.</p>
<p>&quot;Exact dates were not discussed,&quot; Granic said later. &quot;But for us it's very important that extremists do not determine the way or timetable of reintegration.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
