<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150124" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania's 1996 aluminium output seen at 148,000 T.</title>
<headline>Romania's 1996 aluminium output seen at 148,000 T.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania expects to produce 148,000 tonnes of aluminium in 1996, around 21 percent up on last year, the industry ministry said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>January-September aluminium output totalled 107,800 tonnes, 2.1 percent up on the same period last year, and Romania exported 80,000 tonnes over the nine-month period, ministry data showed.</p>
<p>Initial estimates put 1996 aluminium output at 145,000 tonnes. Last year production totalled 122,500 tonnes.</p>
<p>Romania plans to reorganise its state aluminium industry to streamline production and better direct investment, the industry ministry said recently.</p>
<p>Under the project, the country's five state-run plants -- the Alor SA and Alum SA alumina refineries, Alro Slatina SA smelter, Alprom SA rolling mill and the  Elcaro SA cable maker -- would be brought into a holding to better coordinate production and costs, it said.</p>
<p>Over the past year, Romania's aluminium sector has attracted the interest of Western firms including  Balli Trading Ltd of Britain, Finnish chemicals group Kemira Oy and Glencore International AG of Switzerland.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Balli bought 51 percent of Alum, with plans to upgrade the plant and increase its present capacity of 400,000 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>The group also said it planned to enter tenders to purchase shares in Alro and Alprom.</p>
<p>This year, Norway's Norsk Hydro, a major purchaser of Romanian aluminium before the 1989 collapse of communism, reopened its Bucharest office and said it was interested in the country's aluminium sector.</p>
<p>--Adrian Dascalu, Bucharest Newsroom +40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
