<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150116" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croatian stocks down, further losses expected.</title>
<headline>Croatian stocks down, further losses expected.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-10-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian stocks were mostly down on meagre trading on Tuesday with losses among some of the blue chips as traders predicted the downward trend to continue for a while.</p>
<p>&quot;Share prices will continue going down this week and probably next,&quot; said Igor Kos of Taurus brokerage.</p>
<p>He blamed the plunge on previously overestimated valuations of most shares and said prices might fall even below their realistic level.</p>
<p>&quot;All issues will fall, particularly tourist companies,&quot; he said, adding that only fully listed drug firm Pliva and Zagrebacka Banka would resist the trend.</p>
<p>&quot;Pliva and Zagrebacka may oscillate within a four percent range above or below their current value,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Following a downward trend in London, Zagrebacka edged down 50 kuna to close at 980 on volume of 271 shares, while Pliva was not traded.</p>
<p>For the second day running turnover failed to exceed the million kuna mark, staying at 0.7 million, and volume was up from Friday at 2,806 shares.</p>
<p>Of five issues traded four were down and one up.</p>
<p>The first tranch of public debt refinancing bonds traded at 5.3 percent above par from 3.14 percent below three weeks ago.</p>
<p>The biggest loser was confectioner Kras, which plunged 160 kuna to close at 490 on a meagre volume of 100 shares.</p>
<p>The only gainer was hotelier Suncani Hvar, which inched up 3 kuna to close at 60 on volume of 1,084.</p>
<p>Among the losers were also Istrian hotelier Jadranturist, which lost five kuna to close at 275, trading 71 shares, and food processor Podravka, which lost 9 kuna to close at 250 on a record volume of 1,280. ($1 = 5.4359 kuna)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
