<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150151" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACEDONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - Oct 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Macedonia - Oct 29.</headline>
<dateline>SKOPJE 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Skopje press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified them nor does it vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NOVA MAKEDONIJA</p>
<p>- In an opinion poll of 1,500 citizens conducted by Gallup Brima agency on the November 17 local elections, 15 percent said they would vote for the ruling party SDSM, 9.86 for the ethnic Albanian PDP and 9.57 for the opposition IMRO-DPMNY.</p>
<p>- Russia's permanent representative to the United Nations Sergei Lavrov said in Skopje the U.N. mandate in Macedonia could be extended but with a reduced number of peackeepers. The mandate should be adjusted to the improved conditions in the region.</p>
<p>- The Macedonian stock market shows no significant movement six months after its opening. There are many obstacles to the development of the capital market.</p>
<p>- The government adopted a programme for development of small and medium companies. With the help of EBRD the first fund for so-called risk capital is to be established in Macedonia.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- If Macedonia continues to follow the regional model of association with the EU, it could mean an end to a sovereign Macedonian state, newspaper editorial says. -- Mircela Casule, Skopje newsroom +389 91 201196</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SKOPJE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACEDONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
