<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150215" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico Cetes close higher on tight liquidity, peso.</title>
<headline>Mexico Cetes close higher on tight liquidity, peso.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's overnight Cetes rate closed up 60 basis points at 28.60 percent on Tuesday, as liquidity was drained by banks having to settle balances outstanding with the central bank on Wednesday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Liquidity was short from early on, but when Banco de Mexico assigned its credits at such high rates, trading rates reached session highs and dealing dried up,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Banco de Mexico injected 5.6 billion pesos of liquidity into the market by auctioning four credits, which it assigned at between 32.31 and 32.71 percent.</p>
<p>Other traders noted that overnight rates did recede after reaching a session high of 30.25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of the rise was due to the market over reacting, but it calmed down towards the close.</p>
<p>Also pushing rates up were changed expectations for the primary Cetes auction, whose results were due Tuesday evening.  </p>
<p>&quot;Until this morning, we thought that long-term rates might fall a little, but given today's high trading rates and renewed pressure on the peso, we now expect hikes across the board,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of 10 money market traders showed they expected bellwether 28-day Cetes rates to increase by an average of 141 basis points, to 29.11 percent, at the primary auction. They meanwhile expected other issues to gain by up to 50 basis points.  </p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour peso closed 3.6 centavos off at 7.9350/7.94 per dollar.</p>
<p>Bank paper meanwhile closed 190 basis points up at 31.85 percent.</p>
<p>Total credit maturities for Wednesday were forecast at 3.530 billion pesos.</p>
<p>-- Patricia Lezama, Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9554</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
