<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150252" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Communist chief arrested for Pinochet ''slander''.</title>
<headline>Communist chief arrested for Pinochet ''slander''.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police arrested the president of the Chilean Communist Party on slander charges on Tuesday after she called former military ruler Augusto Pinochet a blackmailer and a psychopath.</p>
<p>Six plainclothes police agents stopped party chief Gladys Marin as she drove in her car and took her to a women's detention centre, said Communist Party Central Committee member Mireya Baltra.</p>
<p>Pinochet's lawyers filed slander and defamation of character charges against Marin last month over statements she made about Pinochet on the 23rd anniversary of the military coup which brought him to power.</p>
<p>Marin, whose husband was one of about 3,000 Chileans who &quot;disappeared&quot; during Pinochet's rule, was due to appear before a judge on those charges later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't know what's going to happen her,&quot; Baltra told Reuters. &quot;She had promised the judge she would appear voluntarily at the hearing.&quot;</p>
<p>Marin last week repeated the charges she made against Pinochet, in which she called him a &quot;blackmailer and a psychopath who came to power through deceit, treason and murder.&quot;</p>
<p>She added last week that the slander charges were themselves &quot;an act of slander, an affront to the people of Chile which struggled for so long to return to democracy.&quot;</p>
<p>Marin made the original charges at a memorial ceremony for the roughly 3,000 Chileans who were kidnapped by security forces and never seen alive again during Pinochet's rule.</p>
<p>Marin lived most of the Pinochet years in exile and has given the Communists a more combative, vocal role in Chilean politics since becoming party chief in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
