<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150386" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: FOCUS - Malaysian YTL seen better without CEPA bid.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Malaysian YTL seen better without CEPA bid.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's YTL Corp Bhd's decision on Tuesday to drop its efforts to buy Hong Kong power firm Consolidated Electric Power Asia Ltd (CEPA) was generally viewed as good news for the company.</p>
<p>Investors heaved a sign of relief, saying the $2.6 billion bid would have been a cash drain on the Malaysian infrastructure developer and power concern, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a huge amount&quot; that would have been a drain on YTL's resources, said Vickers Ballas research manager Irene Tan.</p>
<p>YTL Managing Director Francis Yeoh Sock Ping told a news conference the company decided to withdraw an offer to buy the entire stake of CEPA when its controlling shareholder, Hong Kong tycoon Gordon Wu, would not commit &quot;irrevocably&quot; to the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;The plan was too far-out for YTL,&quot; said a research head at a Malaysian securities firm. &quot;I think they are better off with local projects. Anyway, what can YTL do that Gordon Wu cannot?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We weren't playing up the bid story,&quot; said Adin Jarjis, power analyst at Pesaka Jardine Fleming. &quot;It was a long shot.&quot;</p>
<p>YTL's stock fell as much as 80 cents in Tuesday trading, before recouping to end 10 cents down to 14.40 ringgit.</p>
<p>Francis Yeoh said he had made three offers for CEPA.</p>
<p>One was to buy out the company for HK$19 a share. A second offered a mix of cash and shares in YTL's proposed new power company listing on the Kuala Lumpur stock exchange. The third would have offered investors a mix of cash and shares plus additional cash, contingent on financing from an Indonesian power deal. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Francis Yeoh said the deal would have been financed by raising $740 million from YTL's own resources.</p>
<p>Another $900 million would have come from an agreed loan facility from Barclays Bank Plc. The Malaysian Finance Ministry's investment company Khazanah Nasional had agreed to make an equity investment of $1 billion, he said.</p>
<p>But YTl's hopes were dashed when CEPA's 60-percent shareholder, the Wu-controlled Hopewell Holdings Ltd, said it had agreed to sell most of its stake in CEPA to U.S. utility firm Southern Co's Southern Electric International for HK$18.50 a share.</p>
<p>Francis Yeoh said YTL believed its proposals had been &quot;positively received by Mr. Wu who indicated support for them&quot;.</p>
<p>But YTL &quot;sought an irrevocable undertaking from Mr. Wu as the major shareholder to support (YTL's) proposals,&quot; Francis Yeoh said. &quot;Mr. Wu was unable to provide this undertaking or any similar confirmation.&quot;</p>
<p>Francis Yeoh said YTL would go ahead with plans to group all of its power generation interests under a new company, YTL Power International, and float it on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Analysts said the listing news was expected but YTL needed to assure shareholders that the move would not hurt them.</p>
<p>&quot;The question now is how to package it in such a way that shareholders are protected,&quot; said Adin at Pesaka Jardine.</p>
<p>Asked if the door was firmly closed on the CEPA deal, Francis Yeoh said: &quot;For the time being. What I am saying is I'm going to float YTL Power International. I'm not going to consider anything else until that's done.&quot;</p>
<p>YTL Corp, one of the five independent power producers in the country, has a plant each in Terengganu and Johor states with a total capacity of 1,212 megawatts. Both plants have been generating electricity since October 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
