<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150403" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Deal outlook looks better.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Deal outlook looks better.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lots of deals are on the outlook for Asian debt markets, but Tuesday had very little to offer during Asian hours.</p>
<p>The U.S. market may provide excitement in coming days.</p>
<p>Dealers expect South Korea's Pohang Iron and Steel (Posco) to launch its US$300 million Yankee bond via lead manager Salomon Brothers this week, possibly later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bankers will be watching the deal carefully to see how it fares in the wake of South Korea's invitation to join the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development.</p>
<p>Many other Korean deals also are looming in the future, with many of the top-rated banks lining up for financing.</p>
<p>Hanil Bank is likely to be the first out of the block. It plans to launch a US$200 million three-year floating rate note that is expected to pay a coupon of 21 basis points and an all-in return of around 26 basis points.</p>
<p>It will be launched bond style at 99.97.</p>
<p>Bankers said BZW ASia, Fuji International Finance, Lehman Brothers, LTCB Asia and Sanwa International Finance are leads.</p>
<p>In line with the trend, the Hanil deal is priced quite a bit tighter than its last transaction and slightly skinnier than recent Korean bank deals of the same caliber.</p>
<p>Bankers expect the transaction to attract interest in Europe, where Korean names are becoming more popular. The tight pricing may not dissuade European lenders because many of these enjoy a low cost of funds, one investment manager said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the old positive arbitrageurs that borrow underneath that (pricing) in order to buy these products and lock the spread in, there may not be that much juice left (with spreads tightening),&quot; the manager said.</p>
<p>&quot;But in Europe a lot of these investors have access to very cheap capital because of their higher credit ratings overall, and that's why we are seeing a change in which European investors are becoming increasingly interested in opportunities in Asia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As for other Korean deals, Korea First Bank is taking bids on a US$100 million floating rate note, and news on Hana Bank's US$100 million issue is expected later this week.</p>
<p>There's plenty of action outside of Korea as well.</p>
<p>Indonesia's Bank Danamon is on the road with Merrill Lynch this week showing its US$100 million floating rate note. Sources said Bank Bumi Daya is taking bids.</p>
<p>From Thailand, First Bangkok City Bank is expected to be in the market again this week with an FRN.</p>
<p>The US$300-400 million 144a bond for Thailand's Total Access Communications could be launched into the U.S. market shortly via lead manager Union Bank of Switzerland.</p>
<p>In other news, the HK$5.037 billion loan for a consortium led by Singapore's Wing Tai Group was signed today. Proceeds will be used for a development project for Hong Kong's new airport and related railroad facilities.</p>
<p>The airport-related financings have been popular in Hong Kong and seventeen banks joined coordinating arrangers HSBC Markets and Hang Seng Bank in the deal.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371 fax (852) 2845-0636</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
