<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150423" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Suit filed by Indonesian leader to begin next week.</title>
<headline>Suit filed by Indonesian leader to begin next week.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A lawsuit filed by Indonesia's ousted minority party leader Megawati Sukarnoputri against the East Jakarta mayor for closing her temporary headquarters will begin next week, a member of her legal team said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The lawyer, who spoke on condition of anonymity, told Reuters the court hearing the case held a pre-trial examination of evidence on Tuesday and set November 5 for the start of proceedings.</p>
<p>Megawati's suit claims that East Jakarta Mayor Sudarsono broke the law when he ordered the office set up by Megawati's supporters sealed on September 23 on the grounds it was in a residential area and broke zoning regulations.</p>
<p>Megawati's supporters set up the temporary office on September 9 after being evicted by police from the head office of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) on July 27. She was ousted as PDI head at a government-backed congress in June.</p>
<p>The July 27 seizure of the PDI headquarters sparked the worst riots in Jakarta in more than 20 years. Indonesia's official human rights commission said at least five people died, 149 were injured and 23 remain missing.</p>
<p>Megawati, daughter of late founding president Sukarno, has filed a suit against the government's national election institute for rejecting her list of candidates for next year's parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>She has also appealed to the high court after a district court ruled it did not have the jurisdiction to settle a lawsuit she filed against the government and the military over her ouster from the PDI.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
