<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150467" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Thousands of Israelis rally for Hebron.</title>
<headline>Thousands of Israelis rally for Hebron.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of right-wing Israelis rallied in rainy Jerusalem on Tuesday calling on the government to cancel an agreement with the PLO on a troop withdrawal from parts of Hebron in the West Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope the government will stay strong and have the courage not to turn over parts of the city of our fathers to the hands of terrorists,&quot; said Dov Lior, rabbi of the Kiryat Arba settlement near Hebron, a town holy to Jews and Moslems.</p>
<p>Authorities sealed off Jerusalem's busiest downtown street for the rally and police said 1,200 law enforcers were on hand to preserve order.</p>
<p>Participants, many wearing the skullcaps of religious Jews, waved signs supporting the 400 Jewish settlers who live among 100,000 Palestinians in Hebron and calling on the U.S. to stop pressuring Israel to withdraw.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Clinton, Israel is not a banana republic,&quot; read one sign. &quot;(Warren) Christopher, we won't let you turn Israel into a reservation for endangered Jews&quot; read another, referring to the U.S. secretary of state.</p>
<p>U.S. mediation efforts have failed to bring Israelis and Palestinians to agree on terms for the Jewish state's pullout from parts of Hebron, the last of seven West Bank towns Israel agreed to hand over for Palestinian self-rule under peace deals negotiated by the previous Labour government.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who ousted Labour in elections last May, opposed the peace deals but has vowed to honour the Hebron redeployment once Palestinians agree to modifications aimed at safeguarding Jewish settlers in the town.</p>
<p>&quot;Bibi, most of the people are behind you...but the changes in the agreement which we are hearing about are not enough. They are cosmetic changes,&quot; said another speaker at the rally, addressing Netanyahu by his nickname.</p>
<p>Palestinians have refused to reopen the 1995 deal which envisaged an Israeli Hebron withdrawal by last March.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
