<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150474" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Britain to protest shooting by Turkish forces.</title>
<headline>Britain to protest shooting by Turkish forces.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shots were fired at two British soldiers who apparently strayed into Turkish-held northern Cyprus on Tuesday and a spokesman for the British troops on the island said Britain would protest.</p>
<p>Mervyn Wynne-Jones said the two soldiers came under fire from positions held by Turkish forces on Tuesday morning as they were checking pillars marking the boundary of the base.</p>
<p>&quot;It appears they may have strayed into the Turkish controlled area,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One bullet hit the vehicle the soldiers were driving but no-one was hurt, said the spokesman at the bases that Britain has retained since the sialnd gained independence in 1960.</p>
<p>&quot;British representations will be made in due course,&quot; Wynne-Jones told Reuters.</p>
<p>The two soldiers, members of the Royal Engineers, were on patrol on a link road within the eastern sovereign base area in southeastern Cyprus. The northern part of the road is manned by Turkish troops.</p>
<p>Some 30,000 Turkish troops are stationed in northern Cyprus, occupied by Turkey in 1974 following a short-lived coup in Nicosia backed by the military then ruling Greece.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
