<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150460" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Violence erupts after Palestinian boy's funeral.</title>
<headline>Violence erupts after Palestinian boy's funeral.</headline>
<dateline>HUSAN, West Bank 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli soldiers fired at Palestinian stone-throwers on Tuesday after the funeral of a 10-year-old boy allegedly beaten to death by a Jewish settler, witnesses said.</p>
<p>The Israeli military, making no mention of any gunfire, said only that soldiers used teargas to disperse the stone-throwers and sealed off the West Bank village of Husan where the burial and clash took place.</p>
<p>Palestinian witnesses said the Israeli army fired live ammunition, rubber bullets and teargas.</p>
<p>Four Arabs suffered teargas inhalation and one was hit in the head with a a teagas canister, the witnesses said. No Israelis were hurt in the stone-throwing, the military said.</p>
<p>The boy, Hilmi Shousha, died in an Israeli hospital on Monday one day after the security chief of a Jewish settlement adjacent to Husan beat him on the head with a pistol handle and stomped on him, villagers said.</p>
<p>The settler, Nahum Kurman, a resident of the settlement of Efrat, was detained on Sunday after the incident. Israeli police had earlier said there was no proof that Kurman had caused Hilmi's death. But an autopsy showed the boy died from a brain haemorrhage caused by a sharp blow to the neck.</p>
<p>An Israeli magistrates court in Jerusalem on Tuesday ordered Kurman held in police custody for three days pending an indictment.</p>
<p>Kurman's lawyer Avraham Gan-Zvi said his client had tried to resuscitate the boy.</p>
<p>&quot;He is the one who carried him on the jeep to the ambulance. He made sure that he would make it to the hospital...and in the end they arrested him,&quot; Gan-Zvi told Israel's army radio.</p>
<p>About 5,000 mourners marched in Hilmi's funeral carrying black flags of mourning, Palestinian flags and placards.</p>
<p>&quot;Get the Nazis out of our land,&quot; one placard read. Another said: &quot;The criminal settler must be hanged&quot;.</p>
<p>Clashes erupted when about 50 masked Palestinians began pelting Israeli vehicles travelling on a road below with stones.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HUSAN, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
