<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150674" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end up, feeders close mixed.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end up, feeders close mixed.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle ended with modest gains despite a $1.00 per cwt jump in the price of fed cattle and feeder cattle futures ended mixed, traders said.</p>
<p>Packers paid $71.00 for fed cattle in Oklahoma and Texas markets Tuesday, but traders said those gains had been anticipated by the market on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We had already priced in $71.00 trade, that's why the market didn't respond,&quot; one cattle trader said.</p>
<p>Some traders attributed the modest price action in futures to traders' reluctance to step back into the market following sharp gains on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Not everyone believes that rally was for real,&quot; one floor trader said. &quot;The beef is not acting that well.&quot;</p>
<p>At midday, the U.S. Department of Agriculture reported that most grades of wholesale beef were quoted up $0.19 to down $0.31 per cwt in moderate movement of 146 loads of fabricated cuts.  </p>
<p>Demand for beef at the retail level is expected to fall as retailers begin to book turkeys and hams for the upcoming Thanksgiving and Christmas holidays.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not exactly the time of year when beef demand goes through the roof,&quot; one cattle trader said.</p>
<p>One prominent feedlot was a noted seller in the cattle pit and traders said commercials were also lifting hedges. Commodity funds were early buyers, they said.</p>
<p>December live cattle contract's discount relative to cash prices also offered traders a reason to buy futures, sources said.</p>
<p>December live cattle settled unchanged at 66.675 cents per lb, versus the $71.00 price packers paid for cash cattle Tuesday. Other live cattle contracts were up 0.020 to up 0.100 cent. February cattle closed up 0.025 at 63.550 cent.</p>
<p>Feeder cattle futures followed cattle higher, but October could not shake off weakness from a big drop in the CME feeder cattle index. The CME average feeder steer price dropped 0.88 to $61.97 cwt.</p>
<p>	   --Anna Driver 312-408 8720</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
