<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150754" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton visits Ohio, seeking to tighten grip on Midwest.</title>
<headline>Clinton visits Ohio, seeking to tighten grip on Midwest.</headline>
<byline>Arshad Mohammed</byline>
<dateline>COLUMBUS, Ohio 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>One week till Election Day, President Bill Clinton sought to tighten his grip on the industrial heartland on Tuesday by visiting the crucial swing state of Ohio.</p>
<p>Bringing a message of higher school standards to a rally at Ohio State University, Clinton also sent a signal that despite his commanding lead in opinion polls he has no intention of neglecting the pivotal states of the Midwest.</p>
<p>Speaking to several thousand students at the university's basketball arena, which was only half full, Clinton outlined ideas to raise standards in public schools. About a dozen supporters of Republican candidate Bob Dole interrupted the rally, shouting &quot;Dole-Kemp&quot; and &quot;Tell the truth,&quot; a disruption that Clinton turned into an opportunity to flaunt his confidence and criticise his opponent.</p>
<p>&quot;I bet you they won't be doing that a week from today,&quot; he said, prompting laughter and cheers. &quot;They must not have any student loans -- Senator Dole voted against the aid to student loan programme,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not afraid of honest discussion and debate, so we don't have to shout our opponents down. But I might be screaming if I had that kind of record, either that or running for a rock to hide behind.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton offered several modest proposals to improve education, all at little or no cost to the federal government:</p>
<p>-- Urging states to issue &quot;report cards&quot; on public schools so parents can better judge their performance.</p>
<p>-- Calling on states to have clear, tough standards on promoting students from one grade to the next.</p>
<p>-- Encouraging the creation of more &quot;charter schools,&quot; which are run by parents and teachers.</p>
<p>&quot;The only way to get excellent education for everyone is to define it, to respect it, to demand it and then to measure it,&quot; Clinton said. &quot;We have to have high expectations.&quot;</p>
<p>All national opinion polls show Clinton holds an imposing lead over Dole one week before the Nov. 5 election. As a result, the president has had the luxury of campaigning recently in states that are not necessarily Democratic and of &quot;leaning away&quot; from parts of the country where his support is strong, aides said.</p>
<p>But in Ohio, Clinton was courting a state where elections are often won and lost. &quot;Ohio is a state that you never lean away from,&quot; remarked one of his top political advisers.</p>
<p>Clinton currently has a 14 percentage point lead according to the latest Cincinnati Enquirer poll of the state, which has 21 of the 270 electoral votes needed to win the election.</p>
<p>The president was to visit Pennsylvania, another swing state, in the afternoon, making a brief stop in Philadelphia before returning to Washington in the evening. On Wednesday he leaves for his final campaign blitz, culminating on election night in Little Rock, Arkansas.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBUS, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
