<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150807" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Ministers clear in German AIDS &quot;bad-blood&quot; scandal.</title>
<headline>Ministers clear in German AIDS &quot;bad-blood&quot; scandal.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two former German health ministers will not be criminally charged over an AIDS scandal in the 1980s when hundreds of people were infected by tainted blood and medicines, state prosecutors said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the state prosecutor's office in Bonn said an investigation had failed to uncover evidence that former health ministers Heiner Geissler and Rita Suessmuth were to blame for deaths caused by the tainted products.</p>
<p>Several victims of the scandal, including an AIDS patient and a man who lost both his sons to AIDS, had started legal proceedings against the two ministers in 1993 for failing to keep tainted blood off the market.</p>
<p>Hundreds of AIDS cases in Germany were caused by tainted medicines in the 1980s and could have been prevented if industry, doctors and regulators had been more alert, a parliamentary enquiry concluded in 1994.</p>
<p>At least 1,400 haemophiliacs were infected before German authorities ordered the blood products replaced by safer alternatives in the late 1980s.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
