<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150861" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures were saved by a rally in the U.S. bond market after weaker than expected U.S. statistics, which eroded earlier losses and left the contract little changed on the day.</p>
<p>The December bond future fell as low as 125.82, driven down by non-resident switching out of the French contract into the Bund futures, but then climbed to settle at 126.30, up 0.02 from Monday's close.</p>
<p>The 10-year yield spread between German and French bonds moved to minus one from minus four basis points yesterday.  </p>
<p>After resisting the weakness in the dollar most of the day traders said the franc was hit late on Tuesday by talk that the European Union Financial Accounts Working Party had refused to accept the French government's plan to reduce the budget deficit in 1997 with a transfer from France Telecom.</p>
<p>The franc fell as low as 3.3869 against the mark from a high for the day of 3.3772 and 3.3782 late on Monday. It was trading at 3.3838 at 1640 GMT.  </p>
<p>PIBOR contracts settled little changed, buoyed by the expectation that the Bank of France could cut its key intervention rate after Thursday's monetary policy council meeting.</p>
<p>In a Reuter poll, 15 out of 20 economists surveyed said they expected a cut in the intervention rate from 3.25 percent.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
