<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150911" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Oct 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Oct 29.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>Manin opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) is planning to announce a shadow cabinet shortly in conformity with the parliamentary system, party Secretary-General Abdul Mannan Bhuiyan said.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, now on a visit to USA, said on Monday her government was not willing to &quot;internationalise&quot; the Ganges water issue when bilateral negotiations with India were on.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>Water Resourcs Minister Abdur Razzak left Dhaka on Monday night for New Delhi to resume talks on sharing of Ganges water with Indian leaders.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina told a group of U.S. portfolio investors in New York that her government wanted to remove bureaucratic road-blocks to encourage foreign investment.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>Commerce and Industries Minister Tofael Ahmed left Dhaka on Monday for Rangoon to talk with Burmese leaders on promotion of business ties between Bangladesh and Burma.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>Ssangyong Corporation, a top South Korean company, has teamed up with Bangladesh's Summit Group to set up a $20 million plant for bottling liquified petroleum gas (LPG) in the country's south-western Khulna region.</p>
<p>-- Dhaka Newsroom 880-2-506363</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
