<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="150925" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Women protest Miss World contest with tar, dung.</title>
<headline>Women protest Miss World contest with tar, dung.</headline>
<dateline>BANGALORE, India 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sixteen women were arrested on Tuesday after smearing cow dung and tar on the outside walls of the Bangalore office of the Miss World beauty contest's official Indian sponsors, police said.</p>
<p>The pageant, which will be held in this southern Indian city next month, has attracted a storm of protests from women's groups, traditional militant organisations and Hindu nationalist politicians.</p>
<p>Some women have even threatened to commit suicide by self-immolation to stop the show coming to India.</p>
<p>In the latest protest the demonstrators spread the dung and tar over the windows and name plate of Godrej, the personal care products company which is sponsoring the beauty show being held in India for the first time.</p>
<p>Police arrested them while they were chanting slogans against Godrej and Amitabh Bachchan Corporation Ltd, the company which holds the licence for staging this year's pageant.</p>
<p>&quot;They were arrested for trespass and causing mischief. Security will be stepped up at the show's venue,&quot; a senior Bangalore police official said.</p>
<p>The organisers have already decided to stage the swimsuit stage of the contest in the Seychelle Islands in the Indian Ocean to avoid stirring up more trouble.</p>
<p>The 91 contestants arrive in India next week.</p>
<p>ABCL was targeted by protesters in Bangalore on Sunday, but they vandalised the wrong office, apparently unaware that ABCL had moved premises a month ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGALORE, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
