<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15108" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Tapie to quit French assembly seat as film opens.</title>
<headline>Tapie to quit French assembly seat as film opens.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former businessman and soccer boss Bernard Tapie said that he would give up his seat in the National Assembly by Wednesday, the day a film by Claude Lelouche in which he stars opens in France.</p>
<p>&quot;I will no longer be deputy by the time the film opens,&quot; he said in a broadcast interview.</p>
<p>&quot;Just about,&quot; he told Europe 1 radio when asked whether he had sent his letter of resignation to Assembly speaker Philippe Seguin. A Seguin spokeswoman confirmed that no letter or call had yet been received.</p>
<p>Tapie, 53, was resigning just ahead of expected government action to eject him from the Assembly following a finding by the Supreme Court that he was bankrupt and thus ineligible for public office for a five-year period.</p>
<p>Tapie, the target of a blizzard of legal actions over his now-destroyed business empire and the Marseille soccer team he once ran, has a starring role in Lelouche's &quot;Homme, femmes: mode d'emploi&quot; (Men, women: instructions for use).</p>
<p>He plays a power-hungry lawyer in the movie described as &quot;a tender and cruel comedy&quot; by Lelouche, who is making his 35th film.</p>
<p>&quot;I have paid too dearly for mixing two careers,&quot; Tapie said. &quot;In France, you cannot be a film artist and a national politician at the same time. That is why I will no longer be deputy by the time the film opens.&quot;</p>
<p>Justice Minister Jacques Toubon began last month the formal process of ejecting Tapie from the French parliament as well as stripping him of his seat in the European parliament.</p>
<p>The French procedure was expected to be completed before October 2, when the National Assembly is to reconvene after a summer break, but the European procedure was expected to take longer.</p>
<p>Tapie's lawyer has said he intends to appeal to the European Court of Human Rights in an effort to prevent or delay the loss of his European seat.</p>
<p>But such an appeal, even if the court were to accept the case, which it is not obliged to do, would not suspend enforcement of the French judgement against him.</p>
<p>Tapie faces a probable spell in prison after he loses his parliamentary immunity, since two appeal courts have confirmed jail sentences of eight and six months against him for tax fraud and rigging a soccer match. He is appealing in both cases to the Supreme Court.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
