<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151015" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: TCPL says Express oil pipeline faces delays.</title>
<headline>TCPL says Express oil pipeline faces delays.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 170,000-barrel-per-day Express oil pipeline to Wyoming from Alberta, now under construction, will be on stream about two months later than had been planned, TransCanada PipeLines Ltd chief financial officer Bob Hodgins said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;An in-service date for Express of about April 1, 1997 is now the expected date, and that's about two months later than previously expected,&quot; Hodgins told analysts in a telephone conference call.</p>
<p>He said the delays were attributable mostly to getting final regulatory approvals for the long-awaited project.  </p>
<p>Adding to problems for the C$530-million Express pipeline are operational difficulties in readying for use the Platte pipeline system, which will be used to transport Canadian oil to refineries in southern Illinois from Casper, Wyoming.</p>
<p>Platte was purchased by Express partners TCPL and Alberta Energy Co Ltd earlier this year as an extension.</p>
<p>&quot;This delay in the refurbishing of Platte will delay full flows for a period of some three to four months,&quot; Hodgins said.</p>
<p>The Express delays are expected to mean the pipeline will contribute far less to TCPL's earnings in 1997, he said.  </p>
<p>Hodgins said a previous estimated 1997 earnings contribution from Express of C$0.08 to C$0.10 per share has now been reduced to C$0.05 per share.</p>
<p>However, the partners are finished with the project's long regulatory process, which included approvals from the U.S. Department of the Interior and paying more than expected to cross Wyoming state lands, and the remaining challenges are operational in nature, he said.</p>
<p>Express has been touted as a way for Canadian oil producers to access new markets in the Rocky Mountain states and southern Illinois.  </p>
<p>TCPL, which operates Canada's main west-east natural gas pipeline system, on Monday reported a 5.6 percent improvement in third-quarter earnings to C$105 million or C$0.46 per share.</p>
<p>Hodgins said the company, which saw major gains in its non-regulated energy management division this year, could exceed analyst projections for earnings per share of C$1.80 in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;With a good fourth quarter, it may be even possible to do a little better than the target of C$1.80.&quot;</p>
<p>Shareholder returns, including stock price, dividends and capital appreciation, could be as high as 25 percent in 1996, up from 16 percent last year, if TCPL's share price holds until year end, he said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Calgary Bureau 403 531-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
