<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151332" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Jordan, Egypt say peace process still has own steam.</title>
<headline>Jordan, Egypt say peace process still has own steam.</headline>
<byline>Mona Eltahawy</byline>
<dateline>SHARM EL-SHEIKH, Egypt 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leaders of Egypt and Jordan said on Tuesday that the Middle East peace process might have hit a rough patch lately but it was irreversable and would eventually succeed.</p>
<p>Egypt's President Hosni Mubarak and King Hussein after talks at the seaside Sinai resort of Sharm el-Sheikh aimed at injecting new vigour into the stalled Arab-Israeli negotiations.</p>
<p>The two Arab leaders urged Europe to join the United States in pushing the process forward.</p>
<p>&quot;The wheel of the peace process has already moved...Nobody will be able to stop this wheel from moving forward. There may be some obstacles every now and then but nobody will be able to put more difficulties on the process,&quot; Mubarak said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is for the sake of the welfare of the people, nobody will be able to stop the peace process anyway,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The leaders, whose countries both have peace agreements with the Jewish state, met to find ways to bridge gaps between Israeli and Palestinian negotiators who have yet to seal an accord on a long overdue Israeli troop redeployment in the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>Israel and the Palestinians have failed in three weeks of U.S-brokered talks to seal a deal on security arrangements that would pave the way for the partial redeployment.</p>
<p>The West Bank town is the last to be handed over to Palestinian self-rule under a 1995 agreement between the Palestinians and the Israeli government in power before Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu took office in June.</p>
<p>Israel's security sources said defence chiefs told Netanyahu that the army needed more than $1 billion because of an increased chance of war with Syria.</p>
<p>&quot;We appeal to the Israeli government not to mention war from time to time as it will be harmful to both sides. It is a three-letter word but its effects are very dangerous,&quot; Mubarak said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu said on Tuesday the PLO was delaying a deal on redeployment confident Israel would be blamed. The U.S. said Palestinian President Yasser Arafat alone could not be blamed.</p>
<p>King Hussein agreed with Mubarak that there was no turning back from any peace started with Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;I agree with my brother totally,&quot; King Hussein said. &quot;I believe the momentum is there. We are facing a difficult moment but it does not cause us to despair,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Palestinian and Israeli officials said they would meet in Jerusalem on Tuesday to hash out remaining sticking points, after U.S. peace envoy Dennis Ross left the region for home at the end of his marathon sponsorship of their negotiations.</p>
<p>The Jordanian monarch said he and Mubarak agreed they saw a role for Europe to complement the U.S. sponsorship &quot;so that the moral weight of the world can be felt in pushing the peace process forward&quot;.</p>
<p>The European Union has pressed for a wider role in peace talks but Israel is not unconvinced of complete neutrality.</p>
<p>New EU Middle East envoy Miguel Angel Moratinos said on Tuesday he aimed to act as a political go-between, provide economic aid and calm the atmosphere.</p>
<p>&quot;I think its efforts (the EU's) would be a good help to the efforts by the United States and others for the peace to prevail all over the area,&quot; Mubarak said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHARM EL-SHEIKH, Egypt"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
