<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151597" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Handelsbanken rides high on lower rates.</title>
<headline>Handelsbanken rides high on lower rates.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's top commercial bank Svenska Handelsbanken posted on Tuesday a 19 percent rise in earnings for the first nine months of the year, saying the boost was due to higher income from commissions and an improved interest net.</p>
<p>Interest net is the difference between interest income and interest costs.</p>
<p>Handelsbanken's profit after loan losses increased to 4.52 billion crowns ($689 million) from the 3.79 billion shown for the first nine months of last year.</p>
<p>With the loan losses themselves down 30 percent to 1.24 billion crowns, attention has moved further up the profit and loss account to indications of underlying profitability.</p>
<p>Earnings before loan losses showed a less dramatic improvement, but were nonetheless a respectable 5.83 billion crowns, compared with the 5.56 billion reported for the corresponding 1995 period.</p>
<p>This in turn was the result of an improved interest net and a healthy 19 percent rise in income from commissions, mainly on Handelsbanken's investment banking services.</p>
<p>&quot;The net of commission interest and costs increased by 19 percent compared with the same period last year, largely due to high volumes both in share trading and in corporate finance and custodial services,&quot; Handelsbanken said in a statement.</p>
<p>As interest rates have fallen steadily throughout the year, demand for credits has recovered and lending volumes in the Swedish banking system have risen.</p>
<p>Not only that, the fact that short market rates have fallen further than long bond yields has benefited the banks, which tend to cover long lending such as mortgages with borrowing in short-term instruments.</p>
<p>The net contribution from financial transactions was unchanged at 906 million crowns, but Handelsbanken said an unrealised capital gain of over 600 million crowns on its bond portfolio had not been included in the result for the period.</p>
<p>Always in control of the cost side of its operations, Handelsbanken's total expenses increased by just five percent, of which two percentage points were attributable to depreciation on leasing operations.</p>
<p>Key ratios remain strong, with capital coverage running at 11.7 percent and the tier one capital ratio at 8.7 percent.</p>
<p>These figures have fallen from the 14.2 percent and 10.3 percent respectively reported at the same time last year, a fact Handelsbanken said was due to the divestment of its Nackebro property unit and higher business volumes.</p>
<p>($ = 6.557 Swedish Crowns)</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom, +46-8-700 1006</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
