<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151548" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Casino up on renewed merger speculation.</title>
<headline>Casino up on renewed merger speculation.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in retail group Casino rose in a falling market on Tuesday on renewed merger speculation triggered by an interview with the chairman of its biggest shareholder Euris.</p>
<p>Casino shares were up four francs at 234.50 at 1210 GMT, while the CAC index was down 1.48 percent.</p>
<p>Euris chairman Jean Charles Naouri said in an interview with Les Echos that Casino could develop independently but he did not rule out an alliance for the group, rekindling market talk of a merger amid a consolidation of the retail industry in France.</p>
<p>Shares in Promodes, a rumoured suitor, were down 1.33 percent at 1,411 francs.</p>
<p>&quot;The market sees Promodes as a buyer who would have to buy out minority shareholders, but that's all speculation,&quot; said a trader. He said he believed a share swap would be more likely.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the golden age of retail,&quot; he said, adding that the sector had surged in value since restrictive new laws were passed in France limiting the opening of new superstores.</p>
<p>Casino shares rose after Promodes chairman Paul Louis Halley said earlier this month that he saw an industry consolidation. But the group subsequently denied being in talks with Casino.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
