<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151542" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Xerox unit eyes digital document market.</title>
<headline>Xerox unit eyes digital document market.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Xerox Professional Document Services, part of Xerox Corp of the U.S., said on Tuesday it expected to increase its share of the growing digital document management industry to some $600 million by the year 2000.</p>
<p>David Jones, Vice President of marketing and communications at XPDS said in an interview that XPDS currently had around $100 million or five percent of the $2.0 billion annual market for handling electronic documents, a market expanding rapidly as personal computer networks spread around the globe.</p>
<p>&quot;I would be anxious to get to 15 percent by the end of the millenium,&quot; said Jones, in Amsterdam to attend a conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to go from five percent of $2.0 billion to 15 percent of $4.0 billion over the next four or five years,&quot; he said. &quot;It's an aggressive but not-out-of-court projection.&quot;</p>
<p>Jones said the electronic document handling market had barely existed three to four years ago but was rapidly burgeoning into a market that allowed users to cut costs and increase revenue by freeing workers to concentrate on their core tasks rather than supervising document flows.</p>
<p>Computer technology allows thousands of documents to be switched around the globe at the press of a computer key but that information still has to be managed and marshalled.</p>
<p>&quot;The document management market in its current form is three or four years old. It's only over that period that the combination of software technology and hardware affordability has made these kinds of things possible,&quot; said Jones.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a function of the PC becoming completely pervasive, it's also a function of things like improved digital communication lines,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Hans Kaashoek, of XPDS in the Netherlands, said structuring and managing clients' electronic document files could deliver big savings by cutting down the time workers spent looking for documents.</p>
<p>&quot;You can say (as a client) 'XPDS maintain my document infrastructure so that you guarantee me the availability of critical business documents any time any place in the world so I can concentrate on my business',&quot; said Kaashoek.</p>
<p>Jones said XPDS currently had under 100 clients in industries such as manufacturing, engineering, pharmaceuticals, finanical services and some government agencies.</p>
<p>This was increasing, he said, as word of mouth got around some industries and traditional Xerox customers paid more attention to the sector.</p>
<p>-- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
