<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151561" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: EU agrees to keep labour issues off WTO agenda.</title>
<headline>EU agrees to keep labour issues off WTO agenda.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union agreed on Tuesday to avoid the issue of labour standards at the world's biggest trade meeting in December, a move diplomats said would delight its Asian partners.</p>
<p>Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan said the EU would discuss labour at the World Trade Organisation (WTO) meeting in Singapore, but only to stress that the International Labour Organisation (ILO) was the best forum for the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;There is acceptance that the WTO has a legitimate interest in labour standards,&quot; Brittan told reporters after the General Affairs Council, &quot;...but only in taking account of the broader role of the ILO.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU has been divided over whether to raise the issue at the WTO meeting -- a move strongly opposed by developing nations which fear attempts by industrialised countries to apply western labour standards globally would increase production costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We reject all attempts to undermine the competitive advantage of lesser developed countries,&quot; Brittan said.</p>
<p>There was also disagreement among member states over the amount of leverage granted to the Commission to use the Singapore meeting to launch a new global trade round, but Brittan denied he had any hidden agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;Singapore is to focus on work in progress,&quot; he said. &quot;The conclusions of today's meeting display a unified, firm step in that direction ... to review and consolidate.&quot;</p>
<p>Nevertheless, he admitted having to bridge &quot;considerably divergant views&quot; in order to emerge from the meeting with a common European position for Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;To reach agreement unanimously inevitably requires compromise,&quot; Brittan said. &quot;But there was a spirit of compromise and, eventually, a precise position has been put forward.&quot;</p>
<p>The trade ministers also gave Brittan a mandate to move forward in trying for a global agreement on telecoms trade, and he said the EU would be making an improved offer in the next week.</p>
<p>Talks on the matter have stalled because the EU, the United States and other major telecoms product and service providers accuse each other of making paltry offers to liberalise trade.</p>
<p>Brittan said a new EU offer would be tabled with WTO officials in Geneva and he hoped Washington and Asian states would respond &quot;swiftly and in the right spirit&quot;.</p>
<p>The EU stance for Singapore will include a commitment to market liberalisation measures already agreed under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) regime.</p>
<p>GATT, the precursor to the WTO, obliges the EU to open up markets in textiles and other areas by the turn of the century despite opposition mainly from the bloc's southern states.</p>
<p>The EU also wants Singapore to finalise agreements on trade and the environment as well as give priority to establishing international product standards, protect intellectual property rights and define globally accepted public procurement practices.</p>
<p>Ministers also agreed that the Commission should press for further examination of regional and multilateral trade agreements so that they do not conflict with WTO aspirations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
