<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151678" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - British business press - Oct 29.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared by The Broadcast Monitoring Company for Reuters</p>
<p>DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>-- CITY SPLIT ON NEW REGULATION PLANS</p>
<p>The City is split over how it should be regulated following the latest consultative paper from Michael Taylor advocating a fundamental change in who applies the rules. Mr Taylor, the former Bank of England official turned academic says the current system should be abandoned to reflect the change in the financial services industry over the past 10 years.  His system would throw out The Securities and Investments Board and the regulatory functions of the Securities and Futures Authority, the Bank of England, Building Societies Commission and Investment Management Regulatory Organisation would be transferred to a new body.</p>
<p>-- FORSHEDA REBELS HIT AT TI</p>
<p>There was a further setback yesterday for TI Group's 189 million pounds stg recommended cash offer for Forsheda, the Swedish polymer engineering group.   Henderson Investors, which</p>
<p>is against the bid terms, said that shareholders speaking for 30 per cent of Forsheda would reject the offer.</p>
<p>-- DEFIANT TELEKOM CHIEF HITS BACK AT TARIFF PROTESTS</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom yesterday brushed off efforts by British Telecom and other rivals to challenge new alliances and reductions in tariffs.  Chief executive, Ron Sommer said that complaints to the EU and German regulatory authorities about 9 billion DM tariff cuts would not disrupt next month's flotation of 20 per cent of the company.</p>
<p>THE TIMES</p>
<p>-- ALLIANCE INVESTORS STAND TO GAIN 1,000 POUNDS EACH</p>
<p>The Alliance &amp; Leicester, the UK's fourth biggest building society, yesterday revealed plans to distribute 250 shares to each of its 2.4 million members after its forthcoming flotation. The society estimates that the shares would have been worth between 385p and 435p under the market conditions prevailing at September 30.</p>
<p>-- US UTILITY IN HOSTILE BID FOR NORTHERN</p>
<p>A 651 million pounds stg hostile bid for Northern Electric was made by the American utility CE Electric yesterday. If the bid succeeds then a third of the electricity industry in Britain will be in American control.  CE Electric, which is a partnership of the Nebraska companies, CalEnergy and Peter Kiewit, mounted the hostile move buying 12.7 per cent of Northern shares in early trading.</p>
<p>-- C&amp;W IN INTERNET CABLE LINK</p>
<p>MFS Communications, a provider of communication services for business, is to be partnered by Cable and Wireless in building and operating an advanced 315 million pounds stg transatlantic fibre optic communications cable.  The cable is thought necessary due to the growth in demand for multi-media and Internet services.  The new service will link London and New York and be able to carry 125,000 simultaneous telephone conversations and should be in service within 15 months.</p>
<p>THE GUARDIAN</p>
<p>-- GOVERNOR FIGHTS FOR RATE RISE</p>
<p>The Bank of England will renew its call for an immediate increase in interest rates at a meeting of the governor, Eddie George and the Chancellor, Kenneth Clarke, tomorrow.  Some analysts are suggesting that the meeting may be the Bank's last chance to change the Chancellor's mind before the next election. The Bank remains worried that despite the beneficial impact of sterling's strength on inflation, without a timely rise in rates the authorities  could be forced into more drastic action at a later date.</p>
<p>-- GERMANY INSISTS ON STRICT CURRENCY RULES</p>
<p>German finance ministry number two, Juergen Stark has warned that Germany will quit the European Union negotiations on a single currency &quot;stability pact&quot; unless the deal satisfies its insistence on fiscal rigour and penalties.  If the stability pact is watered down the German government will halt co-operation. It could then wait until early 1998 when it is decreed who will be in the single currency club, and conclude a pact with the &quot;ins&quot;, bypassing the EU framework and locking the non-single-currency EU countries out of the decision taking.</p>
<p>-- HOUSE PRICE RISES OFFER NO HOPE TO HARD CORE IN NEGATIVE EQUITY</p>
<p>It emerged yesterday that mortgage lending by Britain's major banks slowed down last month, denting hope that rising house prices will kill off the burden of negative equity. Figures from the British Bankers' Association revealed overall mortgage lending last month was down 12 per cent on the August figure. Mortgage lenders were surprised by the figures but dismissed fears that the housing recovery would permanently stall because prices have been artificially boosted by a shortage of properties on the market.</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>-- FIVE YEARS ON, BCCI CREDITORS GET 24 PER CENT PAYOUT</p>
<p>Creditors of the collapsed Bank of Credit and Commerce International are to be paid their first dividend of 24.5p in the pound on 10 December.  The payout which comes five years after BCCI collapsed in the summer of 1991 with debts of 10 billion dollars US has been held up by lengthy court procedures but the liquidators  Deloitte &amp; Touche are understood to have agreed a firm date for the dividend.</p>
<p>-- FRANCE ADDED TO BBC BID LIST</p>
<p>The French phone giant, France Telecom has emerged as one of the serious bidders for BBC Transmission, the arm of the public service broadcaster due to be privatised by the end of the year. The other bidders are NTL, the transmission company owned by International CableTel who are believed to have made a higher bid than that of France Telecom, also it is understood that a management buy-out group, with the backing of Mercury Asset Management are bidding.  Sources suggest that there are five companies on a shortlist for the sale after evaluation by the BBC and Lehman Brothers, which is handling the negotiations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
