<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151649" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Prosecutor wants trial of Berlusconi associate.</title>
<headline>Prosecutor wants trial of Berlusconi associate.</headline>
<dateline>PALERMO 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A public prosecutor has asked for the former head of Silvio Berlusconi's Publitalia advertising company to be sent for trial on charges of criminal association with the mafia, judicial sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The head of Palermo's public prosecutor's office, Giancarlo Caselli, and five other magistrates signed a 500-page indictment of Marcello dell'Utri, a parliamentary deputy for former prime minister Berlusconi's centre-right Forza Italia party.</p>
<p>The indictment, containing testimony from 17 former mobsters who have agreed to collaborate with investigators, alleges that Dell'Utri had acted as a go-between for the mafia and businessmen in Milan since the mid-1970s.</p>
<p>Investigators had also amassed evidence from phone-tappings, Dell'Utri's diaries and from testimony given by a former associate of Dell'Utri, Filippo Alberto Rapisarda, who is also under investigation for alleged ties with the mafia.</p>
<p>Dell'Utri, who resigned last year from Publitalia when the charges emerged, said in statement that the allegations were &quot;totally unfounded&quot; and had caused &quot;surprise and dismay.&quot;</p>
<p>Dell'Utri is already on trial in Milan on charges of false accounting and in Turin on charges of false billing and tax fraud while he was chairman of Publitalia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PALERMO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
