<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151806" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AWB Report-Australian wheat market &quot;sick&quot;.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AWB Report-Australian wheat market &quot;sick&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian wheat market has been &quot;sick across the board&quot; in reaction to the increased estimated of the crop by the Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE) and a cut in the Australian Wheat Board's (AWB) estimate of pool returns, the AWB said.</p>
<p>ABARE's crop estimate was increased by 900,000 tonnes to 20.9 million tonnes while the estimate of pool returns was cut by A$5.00 a tonne, the AWB noted in its weekly report.</p>
<p>Milling wheat prices were most affected, dropping by as much as A$13.00 a tonne in New South Wales (NSW) and up to A$8.00 a tonne elsewhere last week, the AWB said.  </p>
<p>Feed grain prices dropped dropped by A$5.00 or A$6.00 a tonne in Queensland but barley held firm in NSW, Victoria and South Australia (SA), it said.</p>
<p>Values for chick peas dropped in Queensland but were steady elsewhere. Lupins rose by A$5.00 a tonne in SA and the delivered Melbourne quiote for canola rose by A$4.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>The AWB's wheat indicator price delivered Newcastle fell by A$8.00 a tonne to A$136.75 over the past week. The indicator price for Durum fell by A$5.00 a tonne to A$190.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>The AWB said its next revision for the Australian wheat crop was expected on November 1.  </p>
<p>Significant tenders were called during the week by Egypt, Pakistan and Algeria.</p>
<p>Egyptian specifications call for Australian or French wheat, while Pakistan was calling for U.S. wheat on credit and Algeria is calling for French or Argentine wheat, it said.</p>
<p>Argentina continued to set the price in the global market at A$15.00 to A$20.00 a tonne less than other exporters, the AWB said. EU officials moved during the week to double the level of subsidy offered on wheat exports to about A$20.00 a tonne, bringing another complaint from the U.S.</p>
<p>The EU subsidy on feed barley continues at A$41.00 a tonne.  </p>
<p>Wheat Shipping:</p>
<p>		  Latest Week     Year to Date     Previous Year</p>
<p>    (tonnes)  153,310	   644,338	    440,733</p>
<p>NOTE: Shipping year starts October 1.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
