<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151825" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia in big property development deal.</title>
<headline>Malaysia in big property development deal.</headline>
<byline>Reme Ahmad</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Malaysian government on Tuesday signed an agreement with developers to build a 5-10 billion-ringgit ($2.5-$4 billion) commercial project in Kuala Lumpur that will be more than a mile long.</p>
<p>The 2.4-km (1.4-mile) long GigaWorld complex is part of the 12-km (seven-mile) KL LinearCity project that is to be built over and along the Klang River running through Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>The 10-storey, tube-like GigaWorld is to be built on stilts over the river. It will be construct in stages over the next 20-25 years.</p>
<p>The Malaysian government said it would be the world's longest building.</p>
<p>The agreements were signed between KL LinearCity Sdn Bhd and the Malaysian government, state property firm Syarikat Tanah dan Harta Sdn Bhd and the Kuala Lumpur City Council.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad, a strong backer of the project, witnessed the signing ceremony.</p>
<p>Under the agreements, the developers received a 99-year lease on 216.5 acres of government-owned river land for 611 million ringgit. A massive clean-up of the murky Klang River is also part of the deal, the developers said.</p>
<p>KL LinearCity is led by Chairman Kamarudin Jaffar, an advisor to Deputy Prime Minister and Finance Minister Anwar Ibrahim.</p>
<p>His board of directors includes Berjaya Group chairman Vincent Tan and Wan Adli Wan Ibrahim, executive chairman of Transwater Corp Bhd, which has a privatisation contract to run the nation's sewerage treatment systems.</p>
<p>KL LinearCity has paid-up capital of 50 million ringgit and authorised capital of 300 million ringgit.</p>
<p>In a statemment at the ceremony, KL LinearCity said the project was expected to be financed by a mix of shareholders' equity and commercial debt financing.</p>
<p>The company said it was preparing to secure a listing on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange under new rules introduced last year allowing new infrastructure projects to be publicly traded.</p>
<p>The government also signed an agreement awarding a 2.2 billion-ringgit contract to KL PRT Sdn Bhd to build a light rail system called the People-mover Rapid Transit system, which will partly run alongside the project.</p>
<p>($1=2.5 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
