<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151877" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen B index rises on gains by local stocks.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B index rises on gains by local stocks.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's B share index rose on Tuesday on demand for Shenzhen-based counters and the A share index fell slightly in record turnover, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B share index rose 0.99 points, or 1.10 percent, to 91.30, with turnover increasing to HK$18.21 million from HK$14.38 million on Monday.</p>
<p>Brokers said the rise was due in part to speculative buying of Shenzhen-based shares, such as Shenbao, which surged HK$0.62, or 29.81 percent, to HK$2.70 on a single trade of 100 shares, brokers said. The issue will definitely fall back in future sessions and in turn pull down the index, they added.  </p>
<p>Chiwan Petroleum was the second best performer on speculative buying, brokers said. The issue soared HK$0.25 or 7.35 percent to HK$3.65 on thin volume of 10,000 shares.</p>
<p>Konka, which fell sharply on Monday, rallied HK$0.44, or 6.98 percent, to HK$6.74, with 8,000 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>The counter is due to go ex-rights on October 30, the Shenzhen bourse has said.</p>
<p>Building materials producer Fangda rose HK$0.35, or 6.14 percent, to HK$6.05 on trade of 421,700 shares. Brokers said the counter's recent steady advance was due to investor confidence in the firm's results this year.  </p>
<p>Dadonghai was the most active issue and rose HK$0.04 to HK$1.37 on volume of 974,900 shares.</p>
<p>Shenzhen SEZ Real Estate rose HK$0.03 to HK$3.06 in trading of 402,400 shares. Demand for Shenzhen-based property from Hong Kong should pick up after mid-1997 when the territory is handed back to China, which would benefit the company, analysts said.</p>
<p>Hainan Pearl River, the sharpest loser, dropped HK$0.05 or 2.50 percent to HK$1.95, on trade of 23,700 shares, in speculative selling, brokers said.  </p>
<p>The A share market retreated slightly on profit-taking late in the afternoon session, brokers said.</p>
<p>The A share index inched down 0.16 points, or 0.04 percent, 391.03 as turnover swelled to a record 16.40 billion yuan from 14.77 billion the previous session. The composite index edged up 0.02 points, or 0.01 percent, to finish at 363.89.</p>
<p>Financial issues were among the biggest gainers on buying triggered by a report in the China Securities newspaper Beijing is considering a cut in bank reserve ratios, brokers said.</p>
<p>Shenzhen Development Bank surged 1.19 yuan, or 7.14 percent, to 17.85 yuan on massive trade of 88.49 million shares.  </p>
<p>The newspaper quoted central bank president Dai Xianglong as saying Beijing plans to reduce bank reserve requirements in the future. But he did not provide a timetable for the cut.</p>
<p>Sports shoe maker Qingdao Doublestars, which had performed strongly over the past few sessions, slumped 1.35 yuan or 7.11 percent to 17.65 yuan.</p>
<p>Heilongjiang-based Mudanjiang Petrochemical Co Ltd, which listed 66 million A shares in Shenzhen on Tuesday, closed the session at 13.86 yuan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
