<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151865" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China cobalt powder venture says output rising.</title>
<headline>China cobalt powder venture says output rising.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A joint venture between a Chinese-state firm and Belgian non-ferrous metals group Union Miniere SA is doubling production of cobalt powder every month, general manager Stephan Csoma said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Shanghai Blue Lotus Metals Co Ltd, a venture with a subsidiary of the China National Nonferrous Metals Industry Corp, began production at the end of April, Csoma told Reuters.</p>
<p>The plant's annual capacity exceeds 100 tonnes. Csoma, however, declined to give production figures but said output was rising fast.</p>
<p>&quot;Every month, we are doubling production and increasing dramatically our sales volume,&quot; Csoma said.</p>
<p>The joint venture intended to dominate the market, he said. &quot;(We intend) within a year or two to get 50 percent of the market and then we can control it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the venture so far faced no international competition in the Chinese market. &quot;We intend to be big enough to scare them away,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Union Miniere hoped to increase its investment within 1-1/2 years to expand production, Csoma said but gave no further details.  </p>
<p>The total Chinese market for cobalt powder, which is used to make hard cutting edges, was estimated at around 500-800 tonnes. &quot;We believe it is growing,&quot; Csoma said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
