<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151830" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Manila call loan rate unchanged in liquid market.</title>
<headline>Manila call loan rate unchanged in liquid market.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>---------------------- Oct 29 --------------------------</p>
<p>* Lenders outnumber borrowers 27 to 20</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Philippine interbank call loan rates stayed unchanged at an average of 11.09375 percent on Tuesday in a liquid market, traders said.</p>
<p>Dones rates were at 11.25 percent to 11.03125, with volume thinning to 11.621 billion pesos from 22.308 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;We had expected rates to go up,&quot; said a foreign bank dealer, since the Central Bank stepped up its sales of reverse repos.</p>
<p>&quot;But this was offset by maturities,&quot; said the same dealer.  </p>
<p>Another dealer said banks had remained liquid because they had not been investing heavily in government securities.</p>
<p>Banks had adopted a wait-and-see attitude in anticipation interest rates would go up due to the recent increase in domestic oil prices, she said.</p>
<p>In mid-October, the government raised fuel prices by an average of 30.72 centavos per litre. Analysts expected the fuel price hike to spur inflation.</p>
<p>In the secondary market trading of T-bills, traders said banks were selling their short-term bills in favour of the one-year bills which carry more attractive rates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
