<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="151939" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia manufacturers' sales up 2.0 pct in Aug.</title>
<headline>Malaysia manufacturers' sales up 2.0 pct in Aug.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's manufacturing industries recorded combined sales worth 15.1 billion ringgit in August, up 2.0 percent on July and 10.2 percent over August 1995.</p>
<p>The figures, which resulted from a survey of 58 manufacturing industries involving 2,598 establishments, were released by the Statistics Department on Tuesday, the national Bernama news agency reported.</p>
<p>The sales value for the first eight months of the year was 116.8 billion ringgit, up 14.2 percent over the corresponding period a year earlier.</p>
<p>The department said 29 industries reported sales exceeding 800 million ringgit each for the January-August period. These included the manufacture of semi-conductors and communication equipment, radio and television sets, and motor vehicles.</p>
<p>Products showing big year-on-year output increases in the first eight months this year included welded iron and steel pipes, passenger cars, plywood and rubber gloves.</p>
<p>The establishments surveyed said they employed 846,336 workers at the end of August 1996, an increase of 8.0 percent over the same period last year.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
