<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15224" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Foster's defends Asian strategy after strong profit.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Foster's defends Asian strategy after strong profit.</headline>
<byline>Justin McCamish</byline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foster's Brewing Group Ltd on Monday forecast continued solid earnings growth after posting a strong annual profit, expressing satisfaction at its performance at home and dismissing concerns about its overseas strategy.</p>
<p>Foster's reported a two percent rise in net profit to A$293.3 million for the year to June 30, despite the absence of income from former British brewing unit Courage, which was sold last August to Scottish and Newcastle.</p>
<p>Courage once accounted for 40 percent of the group's earnings before interest and tax.</p>
<p>Foster's better than expected result included a 16 percent surge in the earnings of its core Australian brewer Carlton and United Breweries (CUB) to A$327 million before interest and tax, on increased market share of 54 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a very solid earnings base and great growth prospects, particularly from CUB and (Australian winemaker) Mildara Blass,&quot; chief executive Ted Kunkel said.</p>
<p>The group result exceeded the average market forecast for a pre-abnormal net profit of around A$270 million and confirmed CUB as the groups' growth engine.</p>
<p>Mildara Blass, bought by Foster's in February for A$487 million as part of a foray into the wine business, contributed A$16.1 million to group profit in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Foster's has since used Mildara to take a majority stake in another winemaker, Rothbury Wines Ltd, through a 70 cents per share takeover offer.</p>
<p>&quot;Mildara is on a strong growth track which should see earnings before interest and taxes increase substantially over the next five years and that will be done without the need for further acquisitions,&quot; Kunkel said.</p>
<p>But a weak performance from Foster's 40-percent-owned Canadian operation, Molson Breweries, and a A$17.4 million loss on its three Chinese breweries took some of the gloss off the overall result, stock analysts said.</p>
<p>Kunkel called Molson's result an aberration but said competition in the North American beer market remained tough.</p>
<p>&quot;However, Molson has been reorganised and cost have been reduced significantly. This will help our profitability in the future,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>One Sydney-based analyst said the market was also anxious to see Foster's Chinese breweries show signs of improvement.</p>
<p>&quot;Foster's Asia was a much bigger loss than had been flagged,&quot; she told Reuters. &quot;They can wear losses, but we don't want to sit around and wait forever.&quot;</p>
<p>Kunkel defended Foster's Asian strategy, but said the Chinese breweries were now not expected to turn a profit until 1999/2000.</p>
<p>&quot;Our internal expectations would have had us making a profit in 1998, but I think that's probably been put off by at least a year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also confirmed the group's interest in opportunities in India and Vietnam. &quot;We have said quite consistently that we were looking at Asia as a whole and the markets that  were most attractive to us...were India and Vietnam,&quot; he said</p>
<p>Asked if Foster's was close to a deal in either country, he replied: &quot;We have made some progress.&quot; He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Shaw Stockbroking analyst Michael Heffernan told Reuters Foster's was a world-class brewing business but it needed a major offshore acquisition to ensure long-term growth.</p>
<p>&quot;They have done extremely well in a mature market, but where are they going to get the growth (in Australia), because Lion Nathan are not going to give it to them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>New Zealand brewer Lion Nathan is Foster's chief rival in the Australian beer market.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
