<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="152314" id="root" date="1996-10-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: EU trade ministers meet to map out Singapore plans.</title>
<headline>EU trade ministers meet to map out Singapore plans.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union ministers on Tuesday began gathering to finalise plans for the 15-nation bloc's role in the world's biggest trade meeting in December.</p>
<p>With the World Trade Organisation ministerial meeting in Singapore now less then two months away, some diplomats are concerned that the European Commission -- the EU's executive -- may have fallen behind schedule.</p>
<p>&quot;We probably should be closer to a common position than we are,&quot; one senior diplomat said. &quot;Today is almost our last chance to get things settled.&quot;</p>
<p>Diplomats said while there were no &quot;showstoppers&quot;, concern was mounting at Britain's insistance on the EU raising the issue of labour rights at the Singapore meeting.</p>
<p>The other 14 EU nations agree with Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan that it should be kept off the main agenda.</p>
<p>Brittan is due on Tuesday to make a presentation of what he believes the EU should take to Singapore, after which trade ministers from the 15 nations will state their positions.</p>
<p>Among the matters to be discussed are trade and investment, trade and the environment and trade and development, including new proposals to help the world's poorest countries.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the meeting was likely to be split among north/south lines, with the former arguing for more trade liberalisation and the latter for protectionism -- particularly in agriculture and textiles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
