<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="152522" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends higher after bounce back.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends higher after bounce back.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper ended sharply higher as the market bounced back to recover half the ground lost in Tuesday's speculative-led five-cent selloff.</p>
<p>COMEX defied a cent lower opening call to begin trading only slightly down, and then began trading higher, helped by shortcovering on LME.</p>
<p>Craig Dubitsky of Smith Barney said the market was still confused by the market's rapid plunge Tuesday and Wednesday's bounce back.</p>
<p>&quot;There are people looking at things through a microscope. If they stand back and see where the price is, it's not like we have broken out of some big range,&quot; Dubitsky said.</p>
<p>December COMEX settled 2.10 cents firmer at 92.80 cents per pound, traded 92.90 to 90.15 cents. Spot November went out 2.80 cents higher at 93.90 cents.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 17,000 lots, up from Tuesday's heavy 25,543 lots.</p>
<p>COMEX warehouse stocks continue to rise, up 947 short tons on Wednesday to 29,821 short tons.</p>
<p>Traders noted a widening arbitrage, or COMEX premium over LME, was also having an influence on prices.</p>
<p>The market was, to some extent capped by producer selling into 1997 because, following the Sumitomo debacle, over the counter put options have become too expensive for producers to buy to cover price, traders said.</p>
<p>Dubitsky said people were nervous because they could not pin the blame for any volatility on Sumitomo's former trader Yasuo Hamanaka, and pointed to others such as Canada's influential scrap dealer Herbert Black or the Chinese.</p>
<p>&quot;There is now a Herbinaka situation... Everyone looks for a scapegoat,&quot; Dubitsky quipped.</p>
<p>U.S. government figures painted a mixed picture in copper's two key consuming sectors, construction and automotive.</p>
<p>The National Association of Home Builders said U.S. housing starts in 1996 should reach 1.46 million units, eight percent above the 1995 level. However, housing starts would decline in 1997 to 1.35 million units.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, U.S. Commerce reported that single family homes sales fell 0.5 percent in September from the previous month, to an annual rate of 816,000 units.</p>
<p>Meanwhile weaker consumer spending on new cars and other goods, along with a pullback in government outlays, slowed U.S. gross domestic production sharply to 2.2 percent in the third quarter, compared to a GDP growth of 4.7 percent in the second quarter.</p>
<p>-- Huw Jones, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
