<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="152770" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER SHOWCASE-MIDDLESBROUGH PENPIX.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-MIDDLESBROUGH PENPIX.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pen pictures of the Middlesbrough players most likely to play against Newcastle United in Sunday's English premier league match at St James' Park:</p>
<p>Gary Walsh, goalkeeper, 28. Returned to the side last week in a league cup match against Huddersfield after injury. Missed the first 12 games of the season.</p>
<p>Alan Miller, goalkeeper, 26. Signed from Arsenal for 400,000 pounds ($640,000) in 1994. A highly-rated former Under-21 international whose challenge to take the keeper's jersey from Walsh seems to be over as he is on the transfer list.</p>
<p>Nigel Pearson, defender, 33. Taken to hospital with concussion after an accidental clash of heads with a Wimbledon player last week. Formerly at Shrewsbury and Sheffield Wednesday.</p>
<p>Steve Vickers, defender, 29. Had the chance of joining Middlesbrough from school but went to Tranmere instead where he played 350 matches. Finally joined the club for 700,000 pounds ($1.1 million) in December 1993. Tall, comfortable on the ball.</p>
<p>Derek Whyte, defender, 28. Scottish international who joined from Celtic for a then club record fee of 900,000 pounds ($1.45 million) in 1992. Usually plays in the centre of defence but can also play on the left.</p>
<p>Neil Cox, defender, 26. Middlesbrough's first million-pound signing when he joined from Aston Villa 1994. Started at his home town club of Scunthorpe before moving to Villa. Plays at right back.</p>
<p>Curtis Fleming, defender, 28. Manchester-born Ireland international who was out for nearly a year with a leg injury but who has established himself this season.</p>
<p>Robbie Mustoe, midfield, 28. Ball-winning midfielder who joined Middlesbrough six years ago from Oxford United for 375,000 pounds ($600,000).</p>
<p>Emerson, midfield, 26. Brazilian international signed from Porto for four million pounds ($6.4 million). Has made a stunning impact with some excellent performances and superb goals. Excellent ball-winner with a wonderfully accurate touch.</p>
<p>Juninho, midfield/forward, 23. Young Brazilian international who heralded a new era in Middlesbrough's history when he signed for 4.75 million pounds ($7.6 million) from Sao Paulo a year ago. Made a bright start but has not quite lived up to expectations yet.</p>
<p>Phil Stamp, midfield, 20. Locally-born with a promising future. Likes to get forward and score whenever he can. In and out of the side.</p>
<p>Alan Moore, midfield, 21. Another youngster but, with over 100 matches behind him, is maturing well. Dublin-born, joined Middlesbrough as a trainee and mainly used as a substitute.</p>
<p>Fabrizio Ravanelli, striker, 27. Italian who joined Middlesbrough for seven million pounds ($11.25 million) from Juventus in one of the most remarkable transfer deals of all time. Scored 41 goals in four seasons for Juve including one in the European Cup final in May. Scored a hat-trick on his debut against Liverpool in August and is currently top league and cup scorer in England with 13 goals.</p>
<p>Jan-Aage Fjortoft, forward, 29. Norwegian international who has scored regularly for Middlesbrough since joining from Swindon but who now finds himself out of favour, transfer-listed and looking for a move.</p>
<p>Mickel Beck, forward, 23. Dane who joined Middlesbrough from Fortuna Cologne in April but did not make his debut until last month when he scored against Hereford in a league cup tie.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
