<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="152737" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-PANTIC INSPIRES ATLETICO TO 2-1 WIN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PANTIC INSPIRES ATLETICO TO 2-1 WIN.</headline>
<dateline>DORTMUND, Germany 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Atletico Madrid struck twice late in the first half on their way to a 2-1 win over Borussia Dortmund 2-1 on Wednesday, avenging a home defeat in the European Champions' League two weeks ago.</p>
<p>The victory took them to the top of group B on goal difference.</p>
<p>Atletico had their Yugoslav striker Milinko Pantic to thank for a scintillating spell just before halftime which unhinged Dortmund's badly depleted defence. From then on the German champions rarely looked like repeating their 1-0 win in Madrid.</p>
<p>Dortmund could have guaranteed themselves a place in the last eight with a win. Both sides have now won three of four games played.</p>
<p>&quot;We had enough fit players to take up the baton but after 30 minutes they just handed it to Atletico,&quot; said disappointed Dortmund coach Ottmar Hitzfeld.</p>
<p>&quot;Our problem was mental, not physical. At this level you have to make the running for 45 minutes in the first half and not let your opponents take over.&quot;</p>
<p>Initially, Dortmund, missing defensive linchpin Matthias Sammer with an injury and suspended international full back Juergen Kohler, looked able to control the game by sitting back and counter-attacking.</p>
<p>Heiko Herrlich gave Madrid's offside trap the slip from a pass by Julio Cesar in the 17th minute to drill a low shot past goalkeeper Jose Francisco Molina.</p>
<p>The German champions could have had more but for some desperate tackles and fouls by Atletico's stretched defence.</p>
<p>But on the half hour Atletico exploded into life, making their individual skills pay against an inexperienced Dortmund defence.</p>
<p>Yugoslav striker Milinko Pantic had Dortmund goalkeeper Stefan Klos at full stretch from a free kick, then left his marker Paul Lambert for dead to whip a shot against the far post from an acute angle.</p>
<p>Eight minutes from halftime stand-in defenders Knut Reinhardt and Steinar Pedersen, making his debut in European competition, allowed Roberto a free header from a corner to give Atletico the equaliser.</p>
<p>Five minutes later, from a free kick near the corner flag, Pantic got the reward his flashes of brilliance deserved as he curled the ball around Klos and in off the far post.</p>
<p>The second half lacked the excitement of the first.</p>
<p>Dortmund substitute Lars Ricken had a chance to equalise in the 72nd minute, four minutes after joining the action. But with Molina out of his goal, Santi was in the right place to clear Ricken's full-blooded drive off the goal-line.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Borussia Dortmund - 1-Stefan Klos, 7-Stefan Reuter, 25-Steinar Pedersen, 5-Julio Cesar, 23-Rene Tretschok (18-Lars Ricken 68), 14-Paul Lambert (22-Jovan Kirovski 82), 10-Andreas Moeller, 8-Michael Zorc, 2-Knut Reinhardt, 11-Heiko Herrlich, 9-Stephane Chapuisat</p>
<p>Atletico Madrid - 1-Jose Francisco Molina, 20-Delfi Geli (5-Juan Manuel Lopez 60), 6-Santi, 4-Roberto Solozabal, 3-Toni, 18-Roberto, 24-Radek Bejbl, 10-Milinko Pantic (15-Carlos Aguilera 84) 8-Juan Vizcaino, 9-Juan Esnaider (2-Pablo 78), 19-Kiko</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DORTMUND, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
