<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="152829" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLAND TO KEEP NO GRAIN IMPORT DUTY UNTIL JULY 97.</title>
<headline>POLAND TO KEEP NO GRAIN IMPORT DUTY UNTIL JULY 97.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland will extend its zero-duty on imported grain to the end of July 1997 from the end of this year, Agriculture Minister Roman Jagielinski said on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>&quot;The council of ministers has suspended duty on grain imports unitl the end of July 1997,&quot; Jagielinski told a news conference.</p>
<p>He also said that total grain production this year, earlier estimated at between 24.0 and 24.5 million tonnes, was likely to fall near the lower end of the band.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have about 24 million tonnes of grain,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jagielinski said that with domestic consumption at about 25.2 million tonnes and production at about 24 million tonnes Poland would need to import some 1.5 million tonnes, including high gluten wheat not produced in Poland, to fill the gap.  </p>
<p>Jagielinski also said food prices, which economists consider one of the main sources of inflation in Poland, would not rise more than four percentage points until the end of the year and saw their growth throughout 1996 at 15-16 percent.</p>
<p>According to data released by the Central Statistical Office for September, food prices since the start of the year have grown 12.4 percent.</p>
<p>-- Wojciech Moskwa +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
