<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153021" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Rand fall batters South African shares.</title>
<headline>Rand fall batters South African shares.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African shares have followed the rand down as speculation has driven the currency to new lows.</p>
<p>Although it was steady on Wednesday, showing small gains after a strong Wall Street performance, on Tuesday the Johannesburg Stock Exchange's all-share index shed 96.3 points, or 1.4 percent.</p>
<p>On October 15 the all-share index soared to a record close of 7,073.1, but investors burned their fingers when the rand weakened further last week.</p>
<p>Fresh speculation on Wednesday sent the sickly rand below 4.70 to the dollar for the first time -- a loss of 30 percent since mid-February -- further testing investor confidence in South African shares.</p>
<p>&quot;It has really rattled the nerves of most investors. Local confidence has been battered and it is also a reflection of what overseas investors think of us,&quot; said David Shapiro, a managing director at brokerage Frankel Pollack.</p>
<p>&quot;Any genuine investors are losing out. There are a lot of other markets in the world where you can make money,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The currency's fall has been triggered by South Africa's balance of payments difficulties and dangerously low foreign reserves, which stood at 10.0 billion rand at the end of September, equivalent to four weeks import cover.</p>
<p>A weak rand can be good for shares as rand hedged stocks can benefit and manufacturers can boost exports as their goods become cheaper to overseas buyers.</p>
<p>But analysts said the recent rand speculation has been coupled with a generally weak bullion price and rising commodity prices, only adding jitters to an already nervous market.</p>
<p>&quot;Last time the rand had a collapse at least we had a firming gold price,&quot; said Carmen Maynard, managing director of Fleming Martin Asset Management.</p>
<p>Economists said all market eyes were on the government and Reserve bank governor Chris Stals to see how they would deal with the crisis.</p>
<p>Market optimism earlier this year that 1997 would see three interest rate cuts, each taking a point off the cost of borrowing, has been replaced by a belief that cuts will be postponed and the next move could be up.</p>
<p>Economists said there had been market talk of an interest rate rise to help the rand, although Stals might try to weather the speculation. Any rise in rates would see a serious fall on the JSE, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;The signs are they'll stay the same...if interest rates go up again we are in a lot of trouble,&quot; one economist said.</p>
<p>Maynard said Britain's 1992 fiasco over devaluation of the pound -- when rates were hiked in a futile bid to combat massive speculation only to be lowered again hours later -- showed such tactics did not work.</p>
<p>She added that any interest rate rise would jeopardise growth targets next year as the economy had already started to slow.</p>
<p>&quot;The business cycle already peaked last year...are we going to get any growth next year if interest rates don't come down?&quot;</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
