<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153035" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Rwanda says war looming with Zaire.</title>
<headline>Rwanda says war looming with Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwanda's military strongman Vice President Paul Kagame warned on Wednesday that his country was edging closer to war with Zaire and threatened retaliation against Zairean shelling of Rwandan border areas.</p>
<p>Kagame told a news conference at his office in the Rwandan capital Kigali that Zairean troops had killed and wounded many people and destroyed property in their shelling of the southwest Rwandan border town of Cyangugu on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If Zaire brings the war to us we shall fight Zaire. That is not a big problem for me. We are ready to fight even though we seek no war with Zaire,&quot; said Kagame, who is also defence minister and led Tutsi rebels to power in Rwanda in 1994.</p>
<p>Asked whether Rwanda was edging closer to war with Zaire, Kagame replied: &quot;Going by the declarations made by Zaire there is every indication that we are going in that direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Rwandan and Zairean troops traded mortar and machinegun fire across their common border between the Rwandan town of Cyangugu and Bukavu on the Zairean side on Tuesday. Aid workers reported exchanges of artillery fire there on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>Kagame said an army barracks in Cyangugu was directly hit by Zairean shelling on Tuesday and three soldiers were wounded. He had no immediate information on numbers killed in shelling of the town centre.</p>
<p>A Rwandan army commander in Cyangugu told reporters he sent &quot;a good-sized force&quot; of troops into Zaire on Tuesday night in retaliation for the Zairean firing and they had returned the same night.</p>
<p>Zairean Foreign Minister Kitidwa Tumansi appeared on state television after Tuesday's clashes to repeat Zaire's warnings against Rwanda of territorial ambition.</p>
<p>Zaire accuses the Tutsi-dominated Rwandan army of supporting ethnic Tutsi Banyamulenge rebels who are fighting the Zairean army in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Kagame reiterated Rwanda's denial of such accusations but admitted for the first time that a few Banyamulenge officers who had served in the Rwandan army had gone back to Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;Rwanda is not in Zaire. We are not helping the Banyamulenge although the Banyamulenge do need help from everybody, from myself, from the media and from the international community,&quot; Kagame said.</p>
<p>Rwanda would not allow Zaire to uproot the Banyamulenge and send them back to Rwanda, a land they left over 200 years ago, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;People who want to exterminate others must be resisted. The issue of Rwanda's involvement is not a problem. The problem is that the Banyamulenge are being exterminated and this is what people should look at, not wheter we are involved or not.&quot;</p>
<p>Kagame led his Tutsi rebel army to power in 1994 with the help of Uganda, driving out forces of the previous Hutu-led government which instigated the genocide of hundreds of thousands of minority Tutsis.</p>
<p>Analysts fear a widening conflict in Central Africa could drag in the Tutsi military junta in neighbouring Burundi, and even Uganda and Tanzania.</p>
<p>The fighting in eastern Zaire this month has already driven some half a million Rwandan and Burundian Hutu refugees out of camps just inside the Zairean border.</p>
<p>The Tutsi-dominated governments in Rwanda and Burundi see the Hutu refugees, thousands of whom are former soldiers of the ousted Rwandan government, as a potential threat.</p>
<p>Kagame said the Banyamulenge totalled some 400,000 people in eastern Zaire, of whom 4,000 to 6,000 were fighters. The Banyamulenge say they are fighting to regain Zairean citizenship and resist ethnic discrimination and violence against them.</p>
<p>Rwanda's army is about 54,000-strong. Its troops are well armed and well disciplined.</p>
<p>Zaire, although it dwarfs Rwanda in size, can muster only some 50,000 troops. Its soldiers, some owed months of pay, are known for their lack of discipline and propensity for looting.</p>
<p>At the press conference Rwandan officials distributed a pamphlet from the president's office calling for a Berlin Two conference of former colonial powers in the region -- France, Germany and Belgium -- to take a renewed look at territorial boundaries and the question of the Banyamulenge.</p>
<p>It was at a conference held in Berlin from 1884 to 1885 that Belgium set up the Congo Free State, later to become Zaire, under its king Leopold.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
