<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153054" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Oct 30.</headline>
<dateline>BLANTYRE 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Malawi press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- Two people were injured when the ruling United Democratic Front (UDF) party supporters on Tuesday afternoon clashed with the opposition Alliance for Democracy (AFORD) at a by-election campaign rally in a Blantyre township.</p>
<p>- John Carter, group chief executive for Press Corporation, the country's biggest conglomerate, has been dismissed with immediate effect. Carter said, however, that he had resigned on his own and was intending to leave the country anytime.</p>
<p>The government is involved in a Supreme Court action against the main opposition Malawi Congress Party (MCP) in a bid to take over the corporation's trust from former president Kamuzu Banda who claims its ownership.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- The newly formed United Council for Dialogue (UCD) comprising nine opposition parties not represented in parliament condemned the ruling UDF for hiring expensive foreign lawyers to help government in its court action over the Press Trust.</p>
<p>- Police headquarters on Tuesday confirmed there were salary and allowance grievances among junior police officers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLANTYRE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
