<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153354" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Peru, Ecuador to begin full-scale border talks.</title>
<headline>Peru, Ecuador to begin full-scale border talks.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru and Ecuador will start serious talks for a final settlement to their Amazon border dispute by the end of the year, the two countries said on Tuesday after a round of negotiations in Chile.</p>
<p>The two neighbours, who went to war briefly in January, will meet in the Brazilian capital to iron out the remaining &quot;impasses&quot; that have blocked an agreement, their foreign ministers said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Ecuador and Peru will open conversations of a substantive nature in Brasilia before the end of 1996, with the purpose of reaching an overall and definitive solution,&quot; said the statement.</p>
<p>Dubbed the Santiago Agreement, the accord appeared to mark a major step toward solving the simmering border conflict between Peru and Ecuador over a remote stretch of Amazon jungle.</p>
<p>The two sides set the frontier under a 1942 peace treaty but Ecuador later renounced the pact, saying it signed under pressure.</p>
<p>Ecuadorean Foreign Minister Galo Leoro and his Peruvian counterpart Francisco Tudela signed the accord at a ceremony with Chilean President Eduardo Frei, along with representatives of the 1942 treaty's guarantors Chile, Argentina, Brazil and the United States.</p>
<p>The Brasilia talks will take place &quot;in a spirit of reciprocal understanding and friendly respect,&quot; said the agreement, in sharp contrast to the blistering nationalistic rhetoric that has characterised the conflict on both sides.</p>
<p>The four guarantor countries will name a follow-up committee to assist the talks, though the committee's exact role was not made clear.</p>
<p>But in a clear sign the 1942 treaty will stay in force -- a long-standing Peruvian demand -- the agreement said the talks will take place in &quot;conformity&quot; with that treaty and three accords negotiated since early 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;The conversations will be carried out in a nonstop and continuous way until their final conclusion,&quot; said the agreement, adding they will mean concessions on both sides.</p>
<p>The Peru-Ecuador conflict, which has occasionally flared up into shooting throughout this century, is currently the most delicate of about half a dozen border rows lingering around Latin America.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
