<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153348" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: FEATURE - Peru's economy stays anchored to dollar.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Peru's economy stays anchored to dollar.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Cawthorne</byline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ten years ago, financially shrewd Peruvians seeking cheap U.S. dollars would make the dangerous trip to the drug-growing and guerrilla-controlled Huallaga Valley in the north-eastern jungle.</p>
<p>There, an influx of Colombian drug-traffickers, with planes full of cash to offload in exchange for coca leaves (the raw material for cocaine), drove the dollar's price lower than anywhere else in the country.</p>
<p>Now, with a credit boom at bank counters, the opening of the economy to foreign capital and the continued abundance of &quot;narco-dollars,&quot; Peruvians need go no further than their street corner to find a large supply of cheap dollars.</p>
<p>While there are few public complaints about the abundance of dollars -- which accounts for 63 percent of all money circulating or deposited in Peru -- the government is increasingly convinced the country must &quot;de-dollarize&quot; for the economy's long-term health.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollarization of the economy weakens the power of central government, specifically the Central Reserve Bank, to set monetary policy and therefore guide the economy,&quot; said Adrian Armas, head of the central bank's monetary policy analysis department. &quot;That is our main concern.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1980, only 28 percent of currency circulating and deposited here was in dollars -- a normal level for a Latin American country.</p>
<p>This edged up to 30 percent in 1985, then jumped to 47 percent in 1990 during the hyper-inflation and economic chaos that characterised populist social democratic President Alan Garcia's administration between 1985-1990.</p>
<p>The &quot;dollarization&quot; process continued after Garcia's government, however, as President Alberto Fujimori's economic reforms encouraged Peruvians to bring back money deposited abroad, brought an influx of foreign capital for investment, and provoked a banking sector boom that created a flood of new credit in foreign currency.</p>
<p>LEVEL BELIEVED HIGHEST AFTER PANAMA</p>
<p>Today's level of 63 percent is believed to be the highest level in Latin America after Panama, which is 100 percent dollarized.</p>
<p>&quot;The basic problem is that we still don't trust our own currency,&quot; said Oscar Jasaui, head of the Lima chamber of economists. &quot;It's not because we have a weak currency. We have a stronger currency than ever. But we have long memories. And our memories remind us of inflation and devaluation risks in our own currency, even though those risks are now very low.&quot;</p>
<p>Most analysts agree that the hyper-inflationary years of the late 1980s -- peaking at 7,650 percent in 1990 -- were the main cause for the dramatic dollarization of Peru.</p>
<p>Inflation is now down to just over 10 percent annually, but the fear remains.</p>
<p>The steady flow of &quot;narco-dollars&quot; has continued to grab headlines, but is now a relatively small factor in the dollarization of the economy, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;The influence of the narco-dollars was important in the years when the economy was closed, but now the capital flows (for investment) are more important,&quot; said Central Reserve Bank president German Suarez.</p>
<p>He estimated that narcotics trafficking currently brings $600 million a year into the Peruvian financial system. Local economists are more vague, saying the figure could be anywhere between $400 million and $1.2 million.</p>
<p>The focal point is still the jungle lowlands of the Huallaga Valley -- where Colombian and, increasingly, Mexican drug-lords continue to shift large quantities of cash and drugs -- but the levels of money involved are about half what they were a decade ago.</p>
<p>IMPORTANCE OF DRUGS MONEY EXAGGERATED</p>
<p>&quot;This is still a factor in the dollarization of the country, but its importance has been exaggerated,&quot; said Pablo Secada, a macroeconomic analyst with the local investment house Santander SAB. &quot;It's miniscule when you compare it to the levels of money coming in from abroad for privatisations and other investments following the liberalisation of the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>The government's direct measures to de-dollarize Peru have so far been limited and without strong effect.</p>
<p>The principal move was to reduce on September 16 the interest paid on commercial banks' dollar deposits at the central bank from the three-month LIBOR rate to the same level minus one percentage point.</p>
<p>This was intended to encourage more saving in the local currency, the sol, and a reduction in dollar account interest rates at banks, which are required to deposit 45 percent of their dollar deposits at the central bank.</p>
<p>&quot;My impression is that it has had a small effect. But there is not much more the government can do,&quot; Secada said.</p>
<p>GOVERNMENT HAS MORE DRAMATIC OPTIONS</p>
<p>The government theoretically has the option of taking more dramatic measures, such as restricting foreign capital flows or returning to the exchange controls introduced by General Juan Velasco Alvarado's military regime in the 1970s but lifted completely by Fujimori in 1990.</p>
<p>Such measures are highly unlikely, however, as they would fly in the face of the Fujimori administration's free-market, investor-friendly economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;You can theoretically use other measures, for example exchange controls,&quot; said Armas. &quot;(Exchange controls) are a way, but not a market way. It is not a realistic measure.&quot;</p>
<p>He added that the solution would have to come from &quot;natural&quot; sources like the long-term defeat of inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The key issue is to control inflation. If people really believe we will keep inflation low, they will demand soles instead of dollars. So de-dollarization is not our main aim, but a consequence of anti-inflation policy.&quot;</p>
<p>He stressed, however, that &quot;de-dollarization&quot; was a long- term goal. &quot;The central bank will take several or many years to de-dollarize. It will take time. We don't feel desperate.&quot;</p>
<p>Peruvian economist Arnoldo Rozenberg argued that the central bank has failed to use other means at its disposal to prevent the run to dollars, such as reducing the private banks' access to foreign credit lines.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though the process of de-dollarization is complex and difficult in a free exchange system in which the dollar is the main currency of foreign trade and reserves, the central bank, adequately using all its instruments for intervention, can encourage the economic agents to save and invest more in soles,&quot; he argued in the financial daily Gestion.</p>
<p>Other analysts say the natural slowing of Peru's economic boom, and the levelling off of the financial sector after the rapid expansion of recent years, should help encourage a return to soles in coming years.</p>
<p>And they insist the government can help itself further by keeping a tight rein on public spending and fiscal policy.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy has to de-dollarize naturally. I think the process will start going forward within two or three years, but it is going to be a very gradual process,&quot; said Secada.</p>
<p>Jasaui, however, questioned the need to &quot;de-dollarize&quot;, saying the preponderance of U.S. currency provided a &quot;buffer of stability&quot; for the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that we have so many dollars in the economy helps guard against any sort of shock,&quot; he said, adding that increased use of soles would heighten the risk of inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, you can do almost anything here with soles or dollars. Taxes are one of the few reasons that Peruvians change dollars.&quot;</p>
<p>Most Peruvians are unaware of the government's concern and are taking advantage of the estimated 10 to 20 percent over-valuation of the sol both to stock up on their dollar savings and to use the U.S. currency in their daily transactions.</p>
<p>&quot;Peru is so much more unstable than the United States. It's natural that we prefer dollars to soles,&quot; said Lima fruit- seller Martha Lopez, gratefully accepting a $5 bill for a bunch of apples.</p>
<p>&quot;We can sleep calmly knowing that the value of this (dollar) note will not disappear overnight,&quot; she added, carefully handing the change back in soles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
