<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153851" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: Farm ministers agree BSE aid package despite German grumble.</title>
<headline>Farm ministers agree BSE aid package despite German grumble.</headline>
<byline>Peter Blackburn</byline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union farm ministers agreed on Wednesday, despite German opposition, on a package of measures cutting beef surpluses and providing 500 million Ecu ($635 million) extra aid for farmers hit by the mad cow crisis.</p>
<p>France, Germany and Britain will get over half the aid, to be financed from savings within the bloc's 41-billion-Ecu farm budget.</p>
<p>&quot;Important steps have been taken to curb production. Important compensatory decisions were taken,&quot; Ivan Yates, Irish Farm Minister, told a news conference after a three-day meeting.</p>
<p>Yates, whose country holds the rotating EU Presidency, said the aid supplements 850 million Ecus ($1.1 billion) aid agreed by EU leaders in Florence in June and that further aid was likely under long term beef reforms due in 1997.</p>
<p>Despite winning important concessions, Germany voted against the package because it contained measures, such as incentives for traditional grass-fed herds, which it said would weaken efforts to make structural changes to cut output.</p>
<p>German demands to improve the terms of an EU scheme to cut beef production by marketing calves earlier and a higher premium for bulls were also met.</p>
<p>&quot;I have always wanted this (Farm) Council to take only short-term decisions to remove surpluses,&quot; German Farm Minister Jochen Borchert told reporters.</p>
<p>But EU Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler said the measures, including curbs on the number of male cattle and suckler cows eligible for EU aid, would help prepare for a long term cut in herds and beef production.</p>
<p>&quot;Without these reforms we would have even more serious difficulties,&quot; he told the news conference.</p>
<p>France, the EU's main beef producer, welcomed the agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good package...it includes young cattle and encourages extensive farming methods,&quot; French farm minister Philippe Vasseur told reporters after the meeting.</p>
<p>Farmers will be able to sell beef from young cattle aged between seven and nine months into EU stores in autumn 1997.</p>
<p>The mad cow crisis was triggered by a British government statement in March that the fatal cattle brain disease, bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), might be transmitted to people.</p>
<p>EU beef demand has since fallen 11 percent and some 400,000 tonnes of unwanted beef have been put into storage.</p>
<p>Under Wednesday's agreement, ministers raised the limit on purchases of surplus beef into public storage by 90,000 tonnes to 550,000 tonnes in 1996 although this was much less than the original proposal for 720,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Britain said it was also pleased with the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;This further substantial aid package should be very welcome to (farmers),&quot; British Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg said in a statement, noting that they will get 50 million pounds, or 13.1 percent of the extra aid.</p>
<p>The Irish presidency noted that of the 500 million Ecus aid, 230 million payable to beef producers in 1997 had already been brought forward to 1996 under an agreement drafted by EU farm ministers in September.</p>
<p>Fischler stressed that 270 million Ecus in savings had to be made in the 1997 budget because the aid package must not overshoot the spending limit.</p>
<p>France with 23.8 percent, Germany with 20 percent and Britain with 13.1 percent will get the lion's share of the exta 500 million Ecus aid.</p>
<p>Italy will receive 9.0 percent, Ireland 7.5 percent, Netherlands 6.6 percent, Spain 5.8 percent, Belgium 4.5 percent, Denmark 2.5 percent, Austria 2.1 percent, Sweden 2.1 percent, Portugal 1.2 percent, Finland 1.2 percent, Greece 0.3 percent and Luxembourg 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>Commission plans to slash payments to cash-rich cereal farmers to help pay for the beef package will be delayed until at least 1998 after opposition from nearly all member states.</p>
<p>Instead there was agreement, pending the opinion of the European Parliament, to defer 65 percent of the advanced payment to oilseed producers from the 1997 crop onwards.</p>
<p>But Fischler said, &quot;The arable premium cuts are only in abeyance and we have to see how the 1998 budget works out.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
