<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153929" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - Investment banker to take top Deutsche job.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Investment banker to take top Deutsche job.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG said on Wednesday that Rolf Breuer, a cosmopolitan investment banker, would succeed chief executive Hilmar Kopper next year to take on one of the most powerful posts in the German economy.</p>
<p>Continuing a rigorous management reorganisation launched earlier this year, Germany's largest bank also said former president of Credit Suisse, Josef Ackermann, will immediately replace management board executives, Ellen Schneider-Lenne and Ulrich Cartellieri.</p>
<p>Kopper, Cartellieri, 59, and Schneider-Lenne, 54, were leaving the management board at their own request, the bank said in a statement released after a supervisory board meeting.</p>
<p>Kopper, 61, who has been at the helm since 1989 when his predecessor Alfred Herrhausen was murdered by left-wing guerrillas, steps down on May 20 and looks likely to become the bank's new supervisory board chairman.</p>
<p>Cartellieri was known to want to quit the management board at the age of 60. Schneider-Lenne, who was responsible for credit risks and leaves at the end of the year, reportedly has health problems.</p>
<p>Analysts said Wednesday's reshuffle, which effectively cut the board to 10 members from 12, slotted in with a revamp in July when management responsibility was split into four new operating areas and a &quot;group executive committee&quot; was formed.</p>
<p>Deutsche plans to propose Cartellieri, who oversaw credit risks, treasury and economics divisions, for election to the supervisory board when he leaves the management board on May 20. The bank holds its annual general meeting on that day.</p>
<p>Breuer, Kopper's eloquent 58-year-old successor, has been with the bank for 30 years and on the management board since 1985. He is one of three management board members in charge of the quickly expanding investment banking division.</p>
<p>Because of Breuer's link with investment banking, analysts said his appointment made strategic sense, given Deutsche's determined expansion in that business, which is concentrated in London at subsidiary Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;It's only a logical step to put someone in the top job who comes from investment banking if the bank is expanding in that business,&quot; said Andreas Thielen, banking analyst at Enskilda Securities in London. &quot;It's positive for the bank.&quot;</p>
<p>Deutsche's share price rose on the news and closed up 0.49 marks at 70.85 marks in floor trade.</p>
<p>But Breuer is best known for his attempts to get Germany's financial centre in shape to rival London.</p>
<p>As supervisory board chairman of stock exchange holding company Deutsche Boerse, he has constantly exhorted his fellow bankers to adopt Anglo-Saxon concepts of shareholder value, transparency and investor relations.</p>
<p>Breuer will tread in the footsteps of leading banking figures like Hermann Josef Abs, who as Deutsche chief executive was instrumental in reestablishing Germany's banking and financial system, shattered after the Second World War.</p>
<p>But a Deutsche chief executive's influence extends far beyond banking and finance. With its numerous shareholdings in top companies like Daimler-Benz AG, the bank has tremendous clout in German industry, a level of power shareholder groups and politicians regularly criticise as excessive.</p>
<p>Though pleased with Breuer's appointment, analysts said Kopper's departure was surprising because he said in July he had extended his contract for another year.</p>
<p>Under Kopper, Deutsche underwent the most fundamental overhaul of management structures in the bank's 126-year history while shovelling in profits of unprecedented size.</p>
<p>He is credited with launching a drive to become a global investment bank, but the plain-speaking Kopper also plunged Deutsche into controversy at times, most notably in 1994 when he described as &quot;peanuts&quot; millions of marks in losses to tradesmen caused by the collapse of the Schneider real estate empire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
