<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="153920" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Hamburg seed crusher expects first gene-soya load.</title>
<headline>Hamburg seed crusher expects first gene-soya load.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major German seed crusher Oelmuehle Hamburg AG (Oelag) said it expected the first shipload containing U.S. new crop soybeans in a 65,000 tonne cargo on the freighter Ideal Progress next Monday or Tuesday.</p>
<p>Oelag board chairman Arnd von Wissel confirmed this in response to an enquiry.</p>
<p>About two thirds of the cargo would be new crop, which may or may not include genetically modified beans, as they account for one or two percent of the total U.S. 1996/97 crop.</p>
<p>The company would await and assess possible consumer opposition in coming weeks to decide on any necessary reaction.</p>
<p>&quot;The next four or five ships have been ordered, it will all depend on how the food industry and raw materials markets react,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A campagin by the German branch of environmentalist group Greenpeace, consumer organisations and others against the beans has resulted in concern among food industry processors.</p>
<p>Greenpeace said on Wednesday it would protest at the arrival of the new beans next week.</p>
<p>The campaigners say risks to human health and the environment from the beans, which have been genetically modified to resist a weed killer in a technology developed by U.S. chemical company Monsanto, cannot be ruled out.</p>
<p>Von Wissel, who is deputy chairman of German seed crusher organisation VDO, said the association believed the beans were safe and their products identical with traditional beans.</p>
<p>He regretted, but respected, decisions by major food companies Nestle and Unilever whose German offices said they would use alternative oilseeds to avoid immediate consumer opposition to soya in their products.</p>
<p>Oelag, controlled by ADM Archer Daniels Midland Co, crushed 2.66 million tonnes of soybeans, rapeseed and sunseed at its main Hamburg and Leer facilities in 1995 out of a total German crush of seven million.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
