<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15391" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: E.Asian Grain - Japan sees freight up, buys corn.</title>
<headline>E.Asian Grain - Japan sees freight up, buys corn.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese grain importers are expected to remain active buyers of U.S. corn this week in anticipation of a further rise in trans-Pacific freight rates, local traders said on Monday.</p>
<p>U.S. Gulf to Japan grain freight rates are currently quoted at above $22 a tonne, up by between two to three dollars since the end of July.</p>
<p>&quot;I think freight rates have hit their bottom and now it's better to buy ahead of further rises,&quot; one corn trader said.  </p>
<p>Japanese buyers are currently covering U.S. corn for January-March shipment and have bought up to 50 percent of their requirements, the traders said.</p>
<p>Tokyo dealers quoted U.S. corn premiums at about 103 U.S. cents a bushel C&amp;F over the Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) March futures contract.</p>
<p>In the oilseeds market, Japanese soybean importers have almost finished buying U.S. crop for October shipment and are waiting for the right timing to start covering for November shipment, they said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've almost covered U.S. soybeans for October shipment. But we're not in a hurry to buy for November, and want to wait for the right timing,&quot; a senior soybeans trader said.</p>
<p>Last week one trade house bought a 30,000-tonne cargo of U.S. soybeans for November shipment, traders said.</p>
<p>They said they would hesitate to buy soybeans until local oil crushers and feed makers agree on soymeal sales prices for the October/December period this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Domestic soymeal prices will be a key factor in negotiating soybean import prices. We can't act before they agree,&quot; another soybean trader said.  </p>
<p>U.S. soybean premiums were quoted at up to 120 U.S. cents a bushel C&amp;F over CBOT November futures, the traders said.</p>
<p>In South Korea, corn importers are expected to continue to withold purchases as they have covered their requirements up to February shipment, local traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The South Korean market will be quiet again. But if corn prices fall to around $160-$165 a tonne, they will return to the market,&quot; a Seoul-based Japanese trader said.</p>
<p>U.S. corn was quoted at $173 a tonne C&amp;F South Korea, up slightly from $172 a week ago.  </p>
<p>The trader expected corn prices to drift for a while, unless there was marked change in U.S. weather conditions which might affect the corn crop.</p>
<p>Local flour mills are likely to buy one cargo of U.S. wheat for shipment in November, a trader at a flour mill firm said.</p>
<p>EAST ASIAN GRAIN AND OILSEEDS PRICES:</p>
<p>JAPAN (yen)				Aug 26		   Aug 19</p>
<p>Wheat, a tonne (Canada)*	     54,680		   54,680</p>
<p>Wheat, a tonne (U.S.)*		 49,280		   49,280</p>
<p>Soybeans, a tonne (U.S.)	     63,100		   63,000</p>
<p>Corn, a tonne (U.S.)		  240,000		  239,000</p>
<p>SOUTH KOREA (US$) Corn, C&amp;F a tonne+			173			172</p>
<p>HRW wheat, FOB+			   200			200</p>
<p>Soybeans, C&amp;F a tonne#		  330			325</p>
<p>PHILIPPINES (Pesos) Wheat flour, per 25 kg bag, Manila  315			315</p>
<p>Corn, per kg, Manila		   10.18		    10.35</p>
<p>TAIWAN (NT$) Soymeal, per kg, Taipei		 9.60		     9.40</p>
<p>Wheat flour, per kg, Taipei	  14.55-15.68    14.55-15.68</p>
<p>Corn Flour, Per Kg, Taipei	    7.18		     7.18</p>
<p>* Rates quoted to end-users by Japan's food agency.</p>
<p>+ December shipment</p>
<p># Early November shipment</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
