<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154077" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: States object to British Airways-American deal.</title>
<headline>States object to British Airways-American deal.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Officials from several states raised concerns Wednesday about a proposed alliance between British Airways and American Airlines, saying the deal would curb competition and raise fare prices.</p>
<p>The attorneys general for California, Florida, Illinois, Iowa, New York and Pennsylvania wrote a letter to Transportation Secretary Federico Pena to urge a full review of the competitive impact of the proposed alliance.</p>
<p>The British Airways and American Airlines alliance would control all flights between London's Heathrow Airport and Boston and all flights between Heathrow and Miami, the letter said. The alliance would also control 85 percent of flights between Heathrow and Chicago and half of the air traffic between Los Angeles and Heathrow, the officials wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;If the alliance were to use this apparent market power to raise prices, it could substantially impact consumers,&quot; the letter said.</p>
<p>The state officials said that even with a so-called &quot;open skies&quot; agreement between the two countries, which would open the trans-Atlantic market to free competition, a limited number of slots at Heathrow would provide an unfair competitive advantage to alliance.</p>
<p>U.S. and British officials are set to resume &quot;open skies&quot; talks next week. An agreement to remove restrictions in the trans-Atlantic air travel market would clear the way for U.S. approval of the British Airways-American Airlines deal.</p>
<p>Officials of Britain's Department of Transport are to meet their U.S. counterparts for a two-day session in Washington on Nov. 6-7.</p>
<p>Washington has made any approval of the BA/American alliance conditional on getting open skies with Britain, and in particular on getting open access for all U.S. carriers to London's Heathrow, Europe's most popular airport.</p>
<p>But rival U.S. and British carriers say Heathrow is so overcrowded that open access would be meaningless unless they were granted some of British Airways' 38 percent share of existing takeoff and landing slots.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
