<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154111" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST - Canada - October 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Canada - October 30.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top headlines from selected Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Ontario Municipal Affairs Minister Al Leach backs single big Toronto: Local politicians balk at idea of amalgamating borough, five cities.</p>
<p>- Stable immigration levels reflect backlash in Canada: Investors preferred over family class.</p>
<p>- Quebec Premier Lucien Bouchard bids to counter province's language split: Sovereignty not mentioned as economic renewal stressed.</p>
<p>- Nazis' goes on block in Austria: Art sale closes Holocaust chapter.</p>
<p>- Chippewas cash in on casino gamble: Poor U.S. tribe that risked jail for running blackjack tables has used its money to build a major business operation.</p>
<p>REPORT ON BUSINESS Section</p>
<p>- New bidder for mutual fund company Altamira sought: Shareholder trying to fend off Manulife takeover.</p>
<p>- Canadian government issues wireless cable licences: Services planned by three companies will create alternative to local telephone, cable TV, government says.</p>
<p>- School buses to get advertising: Boards in Ontario, Alberta see lucrative revenue potential.</p>
<p>- Inmet Mining Corp takes massive writedown: New CEO's action shocks Bay Street.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- Manulife takes control at mutual fund company Altamira, seeks more control.</p>
<p>- Phone and cable rival is born: Ottawa gives OK to 'third force' technology to take on giant communications firms.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
