<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154100" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Political experts see Republicans keeping Congress.</title>
<headline>Political experts see Republicans keeping Congress.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Alan Elsner,U.S. Political Correspondent</p>
<p>Republicans should retain control of the Senate with a more-or-less unchanged majority and keep a wafer-thin edge in the House of Representatives, according to political scientists surveyed by Reuters.</p>
<p>Some 34 political science professors at universities around the nation took part in the survey conducted on Tuesday and Wednesday. The poll is unscientific but an effort was made to include experts from different regions of the country.</p>
<p>Just under two thirds of those surveyed, 22, predicted that Republicans would keep control of both houses of Congress. Eight, or 24 percent, thought Democrats would take control of the House but not the Senate. Three, slighly less than 9 percent, expected the Democrats to win both houses. One said the Democrats would win the Senate but not the House.</p>
<p>Many of those surveyed said the struggle for control of the House was extremely tight and could tilt either way in the six days before Election Day.</p>
<p>&quot;Republicans keep the Senate, and let me get a coin out for the House,&quot; said Steven Wayne of Georgetown University.</p>
<p>Expressing the views of many, Ed Renwick of Loyola University in New Orleans said: &quot;The House is so close I really don't know. If I had to guess I'd say the Republicans keep control, but I wouldn't bet my lunch on it.&quot;</p>
<p>Others made the point that the margin of President Bill Clinton's expected victory over Republican Bob Dole would be crucial. &quot;If Clinton wins by 10 percent or more, the Democrats have a good chance of taking the House,&quot; said John Splaine at the University of Maryland.</p>
<p>Another vital factor highlighed by many of the experts was voter turnout. &quot;It will depend on weather and turnout. Dame fortuna will tip the balance,&quot; said Lief Carter of Colorado College in Colorado Springs.</p>
<p>Many experts believe turnout will be relatively low after an uninspiring presidential campaign. High voter participation is usually thought to benefit Democrats but Dole's failure to energise Republicans could depress Republican turnout and hurt his party's candidates all the way down the ticket, Steven Graham of the University of Indiana said.</p>
<p>John Pitney of Claremont McKenna College in California said Democrats appeared to have an edge in campaign funds in many key House races.</p>
<p>Republicans won control of both houses of Congress two years ago for the first time in 40 years. They hold a 53-47 majority in the Senate and a 235-197 majority in the House, with one independent and two seats vacant.</p>
<p>But many Republicans who swept into office on the 1994 anti-Clinton surge are highly vulnerable as that tide ebbs.</p>
<p>Roll Call, a newspaper that focuses on Congress, rated as many as 12 of the 34 Senate races as too close to call. Dozens of House seats were in the same category.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
