<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15430" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: N.Korea says hunger strikers withstanding ordeal.</title>
<headline>N.Korea says hunger strikers withstanding ordeal.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two South Korean students who started a hunger strike at the Korean truce village of Panmunjom last week have lost weight but are so far withstanding their ordeal, North Korean state media reported.</p>
<p>&quot;Their blood pressure has dropped and their weight decreased by more than two kg (four pounds) each, but they are withstanding because of their strong will,&quot; the Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) said in a report late on Sunday.</p>
<p>KCNA, monitored in Tokyo, said Ryu Se Hong and To Jong Hwa, started their hunger strike last week on the North Korean side of the divided border town of Panmunjom to protest the arrest of South Korean students involved in pro-North demonstrations.</p>
<p>Riot police stormed Seoul's Yonsei University last week to end a seven-day occupation by students calling for reunification with North Korea and the withdrawal of U.S. troops stationed in the South.</p>
<p>Police arrested about 3,200 students in breaking up the protests.</p>
<p>KCNA said the two hunger strikers held a news conference on Sunday at Panmunjom in which they denounced the South Korean authorities for their crackdown on students and urged international organisations to dispatch fact-finding groups to Seoul for &quot;a fair settlement of the problems&quot;.</p>
<p>On Friday, KCNA reported that North Korean and overseas Korean students had joined in the hunger strike.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
