<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154645" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - New York Times front page - Oct 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - New York Times front page - Oct 30.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York Times reported the following stories on its front page Wednesday:</p>
<p>- As he becomes Germany's longest serving chancellor since Bismarck, Helmut Kohl acknowledges the high price of footing the bill of reunification.</p>
<p>- A U.S. federal grand jury is investigating whether aircraft maker McDonnell Dougals or the Chinese government knowingly violated U.S. export-import laws two years ago in a $1.6 billion order for 40 airplanes.</p>
<p>- Former analysts of the Central Intelligence Agency say the agency knew that thousands of U.S. soldiers had been exposed to nerve gas and other chemicals when they blew up an Iraqi arms depot during the Persian Gulf War.</p>
<p>- Republican presidential candidate Bob Dole believed his sole promise of cutting taxes by 15 percent will get him elected to the White House next month.</p>
<p>- U.S. President Bill Clinton made one of the most direct attacks against election rival Dole by criticising the former senator's voting record in Congress.</p>
<p>- New York City saluted its Yankees baseball team in a ticker tape parade after the team won the World Series last weekend.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
