<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154798" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Focus - LVMH to buy duty free firm.</title>
<headline>Focus - LVMH to buy duty free firm.</headline>
<byline>Christine Tierney</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>French luxury goods flagship LVMH said on Wednesday it had struck an agreement to buy 59 percent of San Francisco-based duty free chain DFS for 12.6 billion francs to boost its presence along the affluent Pacific Rim.</p>
<p>Investors applauded the deal, which marks an unusual foray for LVMH Moet Hennessy Louis Vuitton into the retail industry to expand its activities from production of designer handbags, perfumes and expensive drinks to marketing and sales.</p>
<p>The company said DFS was the world's largest luxury products distributor with annual sales of more than 15 billion francs, 180 boutiques and 20 years' experience in retailing in Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;Thanks to this acquisition, LVMH will increase its presence in the Asia-Pacific region and emerging countries, a future growth area,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>The group generated more than half its sales of 29.8 billion francs last year in the United States and the Far East.</p>
<p>&quot;This deal has fabulous development potential for us. It's a diversification that's linked directly to our business,&quot; a company spokeswoman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Shares in LVMH, one of the bluest chips on the Paris bourse, were up 3.9 percent at 1,158 francs at 1030 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very good deal,&quot; one trader said. But he added that the market had few details. The company was hosting a meeting of analysts in the French town of Cognac on Wednesday morning.</p>
<p>It said in its statement that it would keep DFS's management team in place and that the chain would be managed independently of LVMH's other businesses, which include Moet &amp; Chandon champagnes, Hennessy cognacs, Christian Dior and Guerlain perfumes and beauty products and Louis Vuitton designer luggage.</p>
<p>Another trader said his brokerage firm was waiting for more information before re-examining its earnings forecasts and stock rating.</p>
<p>&quot;This is unusual for them,&quot; he said, referring to their entry into retailing. &quot;Apparently, though, most people think it's good.&quot;</p>
<p>LVMH said the acquisition of 58.75 percent of DFS hinged on certain conditions but did not elaborate. &quot;We can't say any more until the deal is finalised,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Industry sources said LVMH is waiting for a resolution of a dispute among DFS's owners being handled by a U.S. mediator, but that LVMH has clinched an agreement with the majority.</p>
<p>The New York Times reported on Wednesday that billionaire Robert Miller, who owns 38.75 percent of the DFS duty-free store empire, was trying to block a sale by his partners. It reported Miller said the deal would violate the terms of an agreement he signed in 1991 with his partners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I44000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
