<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154954" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Evans Halshaw to restructure, take charge.</title>
<headline>Evans Halshaw to restructure, take charge.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Evans Halshaw Holdings Plc said on Wednesday it planned to restructure and expected to have 11 million stg in costs in the current year for the reorganisation.</p>
<p>The company also said it would make a goodwill adjustment of 8.8 million stg.  </p>
<p>The car distributor said it had identified 19 dealerships that would be sold or closed because they were unlikely to meet its target rates of return.</p>
<p>Collectively, the businesses were expected to lose 1.3 million stg during the current year, Evans said in a statement.</p>
<p>Evans expected the sale and closure of the 19 dealerships to generate 18 million stg in cash, net of costs, over the next two years for further investment in marketing areas.</p>
<p>Following the review, the group will continue to operate 69 dealerships. The company said it had already sold three additional dealerships and closed four earlier this year.  </p>
<p>Due to closure costs, the company said it expected negative cashflow in the current year but predicted it would have sufficient cashflow to cover its investments.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the decline in the group's new car volumes during the third quarter has partly been offset by an increase in used car volumes, margins remain under pressure and the group's trading results for the full year will reflect this,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>As a result, Evans said the board would recommend an unchanged final dividend in the current year.  </p>
<p>Evans said the overall new car market was up four percent in the first nine months on the previous year, but the rate of growth in the August and September markets had slowed, particularly in the retail sector.</p>
<p>Volume manufacturers, which currently account for 62 percent of the group's new car sales, also had declining volumes during this period, Evans said.</p>
<p>The company also said it had identified 3.0 million stg in savings after a review of its cost structure and expected to reap the full benefit of those savings in 1997.</p>
<p>Evans said it was developing marketing areas that would result in larger territories and improve returns.</p>
<p>It added that it expected to complete shortly the purchase of three dealerships for a total cost of about 2.4 million stg.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
