<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154909" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: RABOBANK SAYS SALE OF TELEKOM OPTIONS WAS HINDERED.</title>
<headline>RABOBANK SAYS SALE OF TELEKOM OPTIONS WAS HINDERED.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German unit of the Dutch bank Rabobank alleged on Tuesday that members of the Deutsche Telekom AG flotation syndicate had hindered its selling of options on Telekom stock.</p>
<p>Co-operative bank Rabobank, which is not part of the consortium behind the Telekom sell-off on November 18, issued 12 million American-style call and put warrants on Telekom shares on Monday, which it said had sold &quot;with great success.&quot;</p>
<p>A couple of hours later, however, many of the options were cancelled simultaneously and inexplicably, with most of the cancellations coming from banks within the Telekom syndicate, a Rabobank board spokesman said in a statement.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Deutsche Telekom was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Rabobank said that it was not accusing Deutsche Telekom directly or any particular banks in the syndicate for the cancellation of the option orders.</p>
<p>However, a spokesman for the Rabobank board added: &quot;Rabobank views this practice as unusual hindrance of our ability to do business.&quot;</p>
<p>As Rabobank was not a member of the Telekom consortium it was under no obligation not to issue Telekom options during the current book-building phase, which goes on until the weekend after next, the board said.</p>
<p>On Friday, Deutsche Bank AG , one of the lead sponsors in the Telekom sell-off, issued options on Deutsche Telekom, which it later withdrew as it was told that the flotation contract prevented it from issuing such options.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
