<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="154935" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK Labour's Brown urges government to cut VAT on fuel.</title>
<headline>UK Labour's Brown urges government to cut VAT on fuel.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British Labour government would cut the level of Value-Added-Tax levied on domestic fuel, the Labour Party's finance spokesman Gordon Brown said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Brown threw down the gauntlet to Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke, less than one month before his budget, and urged him to cut VAT on fuel from eight percent to five.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason I'm doing it now is that I think the Chancellor should include it in his budget,&quot; Brown told BBC radio.</p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke will unveil his budget of fiscal measures for the year ahead on November 26.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a matter of principle for us that it should never have been introduced,&quot; Brown said. &quot;VAT on fuel has discouraged many pensioners from turning up their heating when they should do so.&quot;</p>
<p>He said five percent was the minimum level that VAT could be reduced to, because of European Union rules, and said Clarke could do it within existing resources.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally would prefer to...abolish it altogether but that cannot be done,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>The UK Press Association said Brown's comments added up to Labour's first manifesto pledge on taxes.</p>
<p>Brown said he would decide about income tax after the budget but in time for inclusion in the Labour Party manifesto.</p>
<p>Both Brown and Chancellor Clarke will make keynote speeches in parliament later on Wednesday where the issue of VAT on fuel will be aired again.</p>
<p>But Clarke will be unable to show his hand and comment on fiscal policy specifics ahead of the budget.</p>
<p>Clarke followed Brown on to BBC radio on Wednesday morning. &quot;I obviously can't say what I will do in my budget but on domestic fuel he was using the worst possible argument.&quot;</p>
<p>When VAT on domestic fuel was introduced, pensions and benefits were raised by more than fuel prices, he said.</p>
<p>Clarke is likely to use his speech in the House of Commons to spotlight the health of the British economy. He told BBC radio he was confident of hitting his 2.5 percent target for underlying inflation. &quot;My target is 2.5 percent. I've always said I will set policy to achieve that target and I'm confident that we will get to that target.&quot;</p>
<p>Underlying inflation, excluding mortgage interest payments, edged up to 2.9 percent in September. &quot;I won't hesitate to take whatever measures are necessary to get there,&quot; Clarke said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important as this (economic) recovery accelerates that I stick to my 2.5 percent target. I never speculate about what I would do. I never tell people I will put interest rates up, down or keep them the same but...that 2.5 percent inflation target is a key part of policy-making.&quot;</p>
<p>Clarke meets Bank of England Governor Eddie George for their monthly discussion of monetary policy later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>At recent meetings, George has called for official interest rates to be put up to 6.00 percent, from 5.75 now. But with elections approaching by May 1997, Clarke is not expected to give way.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
