<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15522" id="root" date="1996-08-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Prodi says won't seek Maastricht re-think - paper.</title>
<headline>Prodi says won't seek Maastricht re-think - paper.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Prime minister Romano Prodi on Monday was quoted as saying he had no intention of seeking changes in the criteria established by the Maastricht Treaty for European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;We can't ask for a revision of the Maastricht criteria. Italy cannot and does not want to do it,&quot; Rome's La Repubblica newspaper quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't and don't want to for a very simple reason -- our (1997) budget...is a message the markets need, the message they have to receive so that interest rates fall,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prodi spoke a day after his deputy prime minister, Walter Veltroni, said Italy and other European countries should consider the possibility of re-thinking the criteria.</p>
<p>His comments prompted a lively debate in Monday's newspapers, with most politicians saying Italy had to stay on track for EMU, with the single European currency due to be introduced in 1999.</p>
<p>Veltroni told the Corriere della Sera newspaper Italy should not take any unilateral moves to delay joining the single currency, but added that a recession in Europe had made the task of meeting criteria harder for a number of countries.</p>
<p>In his interview, Veltroni, a member of the ex-communist Democratic Party of the Left (PDS) -- the largest component in the centre-left coalition -- said countries were having difficulties with unemployment.</p>
<p>&quot;We must see if it might not be the right thing to sit around a table to rediscuss the criteria or their interpretation or maybe even the timing of monetary union,&quot; Veltroni said.</p>
<p>Under the Maastricht Treaty on European integration, governments must bring their 1997 budget deficits close to three percent of total output and put their outstanding debt levels on a sustainable path towards 60 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>Prodi had already said earlier this month that Italy would be following the Maastricht criteria and was not worried if Italy enters a bit late.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
