<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="155377" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Juldis focuses on rural Thailand.</title>
<headline>Juldis focuses on rural Thailand.</headline>
<byline>Suthep Chawla</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Faced with steep land prices, an oversupply of housing and fierce competition in Bangkok, Thai property developer Juldis Develop Plc is shifting its focus away from the urban market to rural areas.</p>
<p>Senior company executives told Reuters in an interview that Juldis Develop had adopted the tactic because land prices were at least 10 times cheaper and competition less intense outside the Thai capital.</p>
<p>&quot;Bangkok is now facing a huge oversupply of houses, most developers are focusing their businesses in the city and its outskirts and land prices are high,&quot; said Jesada Kanjanabose, director and executive vice-president.</p>
<p>&quot;Our new business tactic is to move out of the city into the rural areas where land is much cheaper,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In one of its forays out of the city, the firm has completed a 170-unit, low-rise condominium in the northeastern mountain resort of Khao Yai. Seventy percent of the units have been sold, said Terapot Charoonsri, the firm's chief executive.</p>
<p>Established in February 1987, Juldis is a medium-sized developer with 550 million baht ($22 million) in registered capital, of which 450 million is already paid up.</p>
<p>About 30 percent of the company's revenue is generated by its management of a hotel and other projects.</p>
<p>Major shareholders of the company include privately owned BLC Holding Co Ltd, which holds 6.44 percent, Sikarin Plc with 4.84 percent, Securities One Plc with 4.73 percent, and the Thai Royal Household with 4.0 percent.</p>
<p>The company this week denied market talk that it was facing cash-flow problems and said it had not borrowed any money. It said it had raised funds through the issue of 10-year Euro convertible debentures with seven years left to repay $60 million dollars raised via bonds.</p>
<p>Analysts said Juldis' recurring income had kept cash flow moving along at a time when other Thai property developers were facing liquidity problems in Thailand's slowing economy.</p>
<p>&quot;If the economy does not improve next year, Juldis may be in trouble. It's better for the company to speed up selling their houses first before embarking on a new project,&quot; said analyst Kasem Prunratanamala of James Capel Asia.</p>
<p>Analysts advised investors to be cautious in buying property stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole property sector is now in trouble due to market talk on cash-flow problems faced by several companies and over-supply of houses,&quot; said Thanadech Mahapokai of Book Club Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>Juldis has faced some difficulty in getting loans from Thai financial institutions to finance development projects, and like others in the business it has been forced to seek foreign loans.</p>
<p>&quot;Property developers have to seek overseas loans to finance projects as it's very difficult to get them from local financial institutions after stiff central bank measures were issued earlier this year,&quot; said Jesada.</p>
<p>Before the Bank of Thailand measures came into force, developers could seek loans from Thai financial institutions worth between 60 and 70 percent of the total value of their collateral.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, most property developers have to look for offshore loans,&quot; Jesada said.</p>
<p>Terapot said Juldis won a 15-year concession to rent a piece of land on which it plans to build an educational centre in one of Bangkok's prime business areas, Siam Square. Juldis hopes to make a net profit of at least 50 million baht annually from the project.</p>
<p>($1=25 baht)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
