<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="155424" id="root" date="1996-10-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Oct 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Oct 30.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Thai press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- The coalition government has launched an all-out offensive against the Democrat Party when Justice Minister Chalerm Yoobamrung appeared on a special TV programme to reopen the wounds caused by a land reform scandal in the southern resort of Phuket. Chalerm also fiercely attacked the Attorney General's office, implying it had delayed progress of the Phuket case to benefit the Democrats. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Teachers, parents and students of Mater Dei school have begun to take action against Tanayong, the concessionaire of the elevated train, after a year of fruitless talks with the company to relocate a station from in front of the school. Nearly 2,000 students plan to hold a gathering next month in the front yard of the school to protest the elevated train company's planned station. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Police have been ordered to watch Japanese gangs producing counterfeit U.S. dollars as part of preparations for President Bill Clinton's visit next month. The gangs, believed to be hiding along border provinces, have produced fake U.S. banknotes. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>	 + + + +</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- The Petroleum Authority of Thailand (PTT) says the Burmese government has confirmed a sharp rise in natural gas reserves at its Yadana field to 9.6 trillion cubic feet from 5.7 trillion cubic feet, a development that could slow Thailand's negotiations to buy gas from other countries. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- The cabinet has avoided making a decision about liberalising trucking services at the Bangkok port by calling on the National Economic and Social Development Board to find a solution. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Police say they have detected a link between the activities of Somprasong Land Plc and an earlier attempt by financier Rakesh Saxena to take over Bangkok Bank of Commerce. Police began monitoring Somprasong Land closely after receiving complaints when the bank scandal surfaced early this year. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
