<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="155920" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS - Volatility expected to increase.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS - Volatility expected to increase.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Volatility in U.S. stock indices has slipped over the last several days as volumes declined ahead of key economic data, but analysts said volatility will likely increase from Friday on.</p>
<p>The key U.S. employment report for October is scheduled for release Friday before the market opens. Nonfarm payrolls are expected to increase by 212,000 according to a Reuters poll, compared with a decline of 40,000 in September.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers are so important and unless they are right at expectations, which is unlikely, you'll see some sort of reaction,&quot; said Chris Cadbury at Cadbury Fax Service.  </p>
<p>Cadbury said the high level of pessimism suggests that whatever the numbers, the market is likely to move higher.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a fair amount of pessimism around,&quot; he said. &quot;A lot of puts have been trading relative to calls. My work gave a buy signal on the Nasdaq on Tuesday and we're approaching that on the overall market.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1035 CST (1635 GMT), the Nasdaq composite index .IXIC was up about five points at 1,211. The blue chip Dow industrial average .DJI was ahead 13 at 6,006.</p>
<p>Among broader indices, the S&amp;P 100 was up 1.22 at 676.82 and the S&amp;P 500 added 1.16 to 702.06  </p>
<p>Todd Salamone, senior analyst at Investment Research Institute in Cincinnati, said put premiums have risen over the last few days in anticipation of more volatility.</p>
<p>In particular, the Chicago Board Options Exchange's (CBOE) volatility index has risen through the 20 level from a recent low around 16, he said.</p>
<p>At 1035 CST (1635 GMT), the VIX was up 0.48 at 19.86, having reached an intraday peak at 20.19, its highest level since September 5.</p>
<p>Cadbury said while volatility and volume are likely to increase, any rally may not push the market much higher.  </p>
<p>&quot;It looks like we're going to go up for a bit but then we have to see if cash starts coming into (mutual) funds. It didn't last week,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>If investors continue to hold back new fund purchases, &quot;the rally will be probably like a two percent variety rather than five percent or more type,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Salomone said the market may get a boost early next week in the wake of next Tuesday's U.S. presidential election.</p>
<p>A consensus has developed that if the Democrats win the presidency and regain control of one house of Congress, the market may sell off, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;If it happens, the initial reaction could be negative since there's already talk it will happen,&quot; Salamone said.</p>
<p>&quot;If a lot of it is factored into the market already and you don't have that sweep, I think you will get a rally,&quot; he added. &quot;But certainly talk is you're going to get a negative jolt on a Democratic sweep.&quot;</p>
<p>In morning trading Thursday, stock index options trading continued its recent thin trend, with the underlying indices bouncing around unchanged, traders said.</p>
<p>--Gregory Crawford, (312) 408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
