<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="155960" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-AJAX STILL LOOK A THREAT DESPITE CHANGING TIMES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-AJAX STILL LOOK A THREAT DESPITE CHANGING TIMES.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>GLASGOW 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ajax Amsterdam may be in a period of transition, but that is no reason for their rivals for the European Cup to discount them as serious contenders trophy.</p>
<p>Although beating a heavily-depleted Glasgow Rangers side 1-0 was not the toughest test Ajax will face this season, it did prove a number of points.</p>
<p>Their defence withstood a spirited second-half battering, their midfield, with Ronald de Boer outstanding, never lost their shape and although Patrick Kluivert squandered a number of chances up front, plenty of openings were created for him and he can only improve following his lengthy injury layoff.</p>
<p>The victory also emphasised that though key players like Michael Reiziger, Finidi George, Edgar Davids and Nwankwo Kanu have all left from the team that reached the European Cup final last season, Ajax are still producing top-class replacements.</p>
<p>Like Rangers, Ajax were also hit by injuries on Wednesday and coach Louis Van Gaal was without long-term absentees Danny Blind and Jari Litmanen, as well as Winston Bogarde, Peter Hoekstra and Mariano Juan.</p>
<p>But his side coped well without them, controlled the match for the first hour and though never dominating as they did when they beat Rangers 4-1 in Amsterdam two weeks ago, neither did they look like losing.</p>
<p>Rangers, without four suspended players including Paul Gascoigne and skipper Richard Gough, may have fielded a weakened side, but there was no doubting the passion and enthusiasm of the youngsters coach Walter Smith drafted in, and in the end Ajax had done well to get three points from a far tougher encounter than they had expected.</p>
<p>&quot;We were very good in the first half and created a lot of opportunities,&quot; said Van Gaal, &quot;I would have been happier if we had gone ahead 2-0 at halftime, but we didn't. We were a little too nonchalant in the second half and allowed Rangers back into the game, but we defended very well. Rangers only had one-and- half chances all match.&quot;</p>
<p>Van Gaal, who is leaving at the end of the season, is attempting to end his five-year spell as coach by taking Ajax to their third successive European Cup final and the fact that their league form is improving and they have won three of their four champions' league matches is encouraging.</p>
<p>When Blind, Litmanen and the others return and Kluivert regains his touch and pace, Ajax look as if they do not need much more than a little fine-tuning to again pose awkward questions for their opponents.</p>
<p>On Wednesday's evidence at least the fulchrum of twins Ronald and Frank de Boer looks as solid as a rock, and with youngsters like 19-year-old Mario Melchiot and 20-year-old Portuguese import Dani on the fringes of the team, the European future is looking brighter than it may have appeared at the start of the season.</p>
<p>Which is more than can be said for Rangers -- weakened or otherwise. Dominant in Scotland where they are chasing their ninth successive title, Rangers are simply out of their depth among Europe's elite.</p>
<p>They have now gone 12 matches since March 1993 without a win in the champions league and although their patched-up side played with a rare determination in front of a 42,000 crowd, Rangers only had one clear-cut chance to score, wasted when German Joerg Albertz shot high and wide from close range after an hour.</p>
<p>The only goal came after 39 minutes when Arnold Scholten drove a low 25-metre shot past compatriot Theo Snelders, the Rangers goalkeeper.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GLASGOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
