<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156194" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FOCUS-Currency bulls favor Canadian dollar.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Currency bulls favor Canadian dollar.</headline>
<byline>Paul Casciato</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The global appetite for Canada's dollar is growing amid a decline in Canadian interest rates and receding concerns about Quebec separatism.</p>
<p>A year after Quebec separatists narrowly lost an independence referendum and in the face of repeated cuts that have pushed interest rates to their lowest levels in more than 30 years, banks and brokerages are applauding Canada's economic outlook.</p>
<p>Many are predicting Canada's dollar will climb further by more than two U.S. cents from its current C$1.3382 (US$0.7472) level on Thursday -- the best rate in over a year.</p>
<p>&quot;Our forecast is 12 months at C$1.30 (US$0.7692) and even at that, the currency remains somewhat undervalued,&quot; said Mark Chandler, senior economist at Goldman Sachs in Toronto.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Goldman's chief foreign exchange economist called  Canada's dollar the &quot;best place to be&quot; among the Canadian, Australian and New Zealand currencies.</p>
<p>Economists cited Canada's Liberal government's success in cutting the federal budget deficit and a C$1.15 billion (US$859 million) current account surplus in the second quarter as the main reasons for dollar's bright prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;My target for the middle of next year is C$1.2850 (US$0.7782),&quot; said Andrew Spence, senior economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in Toronto.</p>
<p>Canada's Finance Minister Paul Martin said on October 9 that the federal government was on track to a balanced budget and projected a 1998/99 budget deficit of C$9 billion (US$6.72 billion) or one percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Canadian bonds have since outperformed their U.S. counterparts. The spread on Canada's 30-year benchmark bond has narrowed to an 11-year low of 23 basis points over the U.S. benchmark from 66 basis points on October 8.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of investors globally missed the Canadian bond market rally and many of them are determined not to miss the currency rally,&quot; Spence said.</p>
<p>Ironically, Quebec Premier Lucien Bouchard, whose charisma nearly tipped the balance in favor of Quebec separation in the referendum on sovereignty a year ago, has come under fire for embracing deficit-cutting programs.</p>
<p>Bouchard has said he will address the province's C$3.275 billion (US$2.45 billion) deficit and more than C$100 billion (US$74.73 billion) in debt before entertaining another push to pry Canada's French-speaking province from Canada.</p>
<p>Despite being burned in effigy in front of television crews this week by the most zealous of his separatist followers, Bouchard held a three-day economic conference in Montreal to woo business leaders with the promise of holding off on another referendum in favor of debt reduction.</p>
<p>&quot;We know, given the state of Quebec's books, that pursuing fiscal reform is going to be a difficult and lengthy process,&quot; Spence said. &quot;It doesn't look as if they can even think about gearing up for another push for sovereignty for at least another two to three years.&quot;</p>
<p>The province of 7.1 million people is struggling with a sluggish economy, a 12.6 percent unemployment rate, deep cuts in government programs and renewed tensions between its French and English-speaking residents.</p>
<p>&quot;For the good of the people what you have to do is work on the economy,&quot; Chandler said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
