<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156150" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: United effort needed to prevent Zaire tragedy - U.N..</title>
<headline>United effort needed to prevent Zaire tragedy - U.N..</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior U.N. official said on Thursday only a concerted effort by the United Nations and African countries could avert a catastrophe in eastern Zaire, where more than a million refugees are caught up in fighting.</p>
<p>&quot;Short of a political solution, coupled with very intense diplomatic efforts, we may not make much progress,&quot; said Augustine Mahiga, head of the U.N.'s refugee operations in Rwanda, Zaire and Burundi.</p>
<p>&quot;It has to come from all over, from the Security Council, from the secretary-general, from the Organisation of African Unity, from neighbouring countries, but it has to be done in a concerted fashion so that it's all focused and coordinated,&quot; he told BBC television.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly there has to be more than one actor to tackle this problem... We don't have much time and the crisis is getting deeper and is turning into a humanitarian catastrophe.&quot;</p>
<p>Battles between troops and Tutsi rebels raged near the eastern Zairean city of Goma on Thursday and aid agencies responsible for feeding more than a million Hutu refugees were preparing to evacuate, aid officials said.</p>
<p>International attention has focused largely on the plight of the refugees in Zaire. Hutus massacred nearly one million Tutsis in Rwanda in 1994 and then fled en masse to Zaire.</p>
<p>A swathe of eastern Zaire close to Rwanda and Burundi is outside government control after a campaign by Tutsi guerrillas.</p>
<p>The human rights group Amnesty International appealed on Thursday to all combatants in the region not to attack civilians and called on Kinshasa to stop its troops and local officials violating human rights.</p>
<p>&quot;Officials known to have ordered or incited human rights abuses should immediately be brought to justice -- only then will the cycle of impunity end,&quot; Amnesty said in a statement.</p>
<p>Mahiga said the crisis could have been avoided if outside powers had acted more quickly to ease underlying tensions in the region.</p>
<p>&quot;It is indeed very frustrating because all the signs have been there for quite some time and everybody knows this part of Africa, the Great Lakes region, is very volatile and has complex problems: humanitarian, political, security -- you name it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
