<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156236" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberia's war closely linked to Taylor's ambition.</title>
<headline>Liberia's war closely linked to Taylor's ambition.</headline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Liberian warlord Charles Taylor, who escaped an assassination attempt on Thursday, seven years ago launched the civil war that has killed more than 150,000 people in the West African country.</p>
<p>The 48-year-old former civil servant is head of the largest military faction, the National Patriotic Front of Liberia (NPFL).</p>
<p>Taylor's ambition to head the country founded by freed American slaves has fuelled the bitter war that he began from Ivory Coast on Christmas Eve 1989.</p>
<p>Himself a descendant of freed American slaves who set up Liberia as Africa's first independent republic in 1847, Taylor is a vice-chairman on the ruling Council of State set up under a peace deal agreed by Liberia's warlords and politicians in Nigeria's capital Abuja last year.</p>
<p>Having tried and failed to take the capital militarily in 1990 and 1992, Taylor returned to the city in triumph in 1995 after the Abuja deal smoothed differences with Nigeria, which commands and provides most troops to the peacekeeping force.</p>
<p>The deal, outlining disarmament and elections within a year, raised hopes of ending the war.</p>
<p>But it took a serious blow when Taylor's men and his allies tried to arrest Krahn warlord Roosevelt Johnson in April 1996 after the council sacked him from the cabinet and ordered his arrest on murder charges.</p>
<p>After seven weeks of fighting in Monrovia that killed several hundred people, Taylor abandoned plans to arrest Johnson.</p>
<p>Born on January 29, 1948 and educated at Bentley College outside Boston, with a degree in economics, Taylor was active in a U.S.-based Liberian student movement.</p>
<p>Taylor fled Liberia in 1983 to escape charges of embezzling $900,000 in government funds in a deal to buy bulldozers that his critics said did not exist.</p>
<p>The Liberian government sought his extradition from the United States, but Taylor escaped from a U.S. jail using a hacksaw and bedsheets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
