<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156218" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Roller-coaster rand bounces back after new low.</title>
<headline>Roller-coaster rand bounces back after new low.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African rand took a roller-coaster ride on Thursday, slumping to new all-time lows in early trade before bouncing back seven cents as speculators rushed to take profits.</p>
<p>Dealers said investors who had sold the rand short earlier in the week scrambled to pocket their gains after it hit a lowest ever 4.7670/7720 against the dollar.</p>
<p>In just over two hours a buying frenzy swept the unit back through the 4.70 level, where it once again became a target of sales by banks and companies seeking dollars to pay for imports.</p>
<p>The rand ended the day at 4.7020/7070.</p>
<p>Peter Lane, head of treasury at UAL Merchant Bank, said some big overseas operators had already started to sell dollars for rand on Wednesday and the bandwagon gathered momentum on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday we started seeing some of the smarter London players taking profits...the dollar selling pressure built up and then there was a massive scramble among speculators to cover their positions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The rand's recovery helped stocks and bonds with the Johannesburg Stock Exchange all-share index jumping 1.2 percent and long bond yields pushing back below the psychological 16 percent level.</p>
<p>Dealers said Thursday's recovery suggested the rand was at least pausing in its previously seemingly inexorable slide, which has seen the currency shed 30 percent of its value against the dollar since mid-February.</p>
<p>The currency recovered to 7.6429/6557 against the British pound after touching a fresh low of 7.7824.</p>
<p>But anxieties remain about the balance of payments, low foreign reserves and the government's ambivalence on the lifting of exchange controls.</p>
<p>South Africa's two business newspapers on Thursday called on the government to bite the bullet and scrap exchange controls immediately, taking a loan from the International Monetary Fund as a safety net.</p>
<p>&quot;(Finance Minister Trevor) Manuel and (Reserve Bank Governor Chris) Stals cannot delay the complete removal of exchange controls if further damage to the currency and the economy are to be avoided,&quot; Business Day said in an editorial.</p>
<p>Business Report said the possible one-off fall in the rand with the scrapping of controls was preferable to continued speculative attacks.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, lifting exchange controls would stop the rot by collapsing the rand to a real floor. Surely that has to be preferable to the drip-drip of water torture by speculation.&quot;</p>
<p>But economists said a total abolition of exchange controls remained unlikely.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it is most unlikely that they will go ahead and abolish controls totally,&quot; said Dennis Dykes, chief economist at Nedcor bank.</p>
<p>&quot;But what I am hoping is that they will set out a proper unconditional timetable on dismantling at least certain aspects of exchange control.&quot;</p>
<p>Stals has said on several occasions in recent days that calls for the immediate scrapping of controls were unreasonable while reserves remain precariously low.</p>
<p>Manuel told parliament on Wednesday the only proper response to the fall of the rand lay in the steady implementation of the government's announced macro-economic strategy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
