<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156384" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romanian Brasov city to launch municipal bonds.</title>
<headline>Romanian Brasov city to launch municipal bonds.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's city of Brasov has signed an arrangement to launch municipal bonds through a consortium linking Salmon Brothers and local securities company SIRA Invest SA, a SIRA official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Transylvanian town plans to raise up to $150 million in municipal bonds under a deal similar with an arrangement previously signed with the city hall of Romania's Black Sea port of Constanta, the official said.</p>
<p>The deal involves up to $50 million in a private placement and a public issue of about $100 million Eurobonds. The issue targets local and foreign investors and are expected to hit the market in the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>In August, Romania's capital Bucharest announced plans to raise about $200 million in bonds through Merrill Lynch International to upgrade the city's infrastructure.</p>
<p>The city hall of Sinaia, a ski resort north-west of Bucharest and close to Brasov, also said it would launch domestic bonds worth 200 billion lei ($60 million) in the last quarter of 1996.</p>
<p>Romania won its first credit ratings from major agencies in March. Japan Credit Rating agency awarded it a BB-plus score, somewhat higher than the BB- minus ratings of Standard and Poor's and IBCA and BA-three from Moody's Investors Service. -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
