<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156369" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland offers to cut fuel import duties from 1997.</title>
<headline>Poland offers to cut fuel import duties from 1997.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Warsaw has suggested a compromise with the EU, under which Poland would gradually lower import duties on fuels to zero in 2001 and remove limits on the amount of fuels it imports from 1997, newspapers and officials said.</p>
<p>Rzeczpospolita financial daily and the biggest-circulation Gazeta Wyborcza on Thursday quoted a draft document, signed by the Polish government and the EU, containing a timetable for lowering Polish duties on petrol and diesel fuel.</p>
<p>A row over Poland's protection of its fuels sector, which it regards as undergoing transformation, is among the most serious of several trade disputes to trouble Poland's relations this year with the European Union which it hopes to join soon.</p>
<p>European Commissioner Hans van den Broek visited Poland in mid-October and signed a joint working document on these issues.</p>
<p>The newspapers said that under the EU-Poland document, yet to be approved by the European Commission, Poland would cut petrol import duties to 11 percent in 1997 from 15 percent this year.</p>
<p>Further reductions would take duties down to nine percent in 1998, seven percent in 1999, four percent in the year 2000 and to zero in 2001, they reported.</p>
<p>Diesel fuel duties would be cut to 20 percent in 1997 from 25 percent this year and then to 15 percent in 1998, 11 percent in 1999, four percent in 2000 and be scrapped in 2001.</p>
<p>The working document also envisages that Poland would set a date for freeing its fuel prices, now controlled by the finance ministry, by the end of this year, the newspapers said.</p>
<p>Rzeczpospolita quoted unnamed sources as saying that under the final version of the document, fuel prices in Poland would be freed if prices on world markets stabilised for one month.</p>
<p>Western diplomats said the freeing of prices was the key issue which might determine whether the deal was accepted by EU members or not. At present, Poland controls the margin than importers can charge, severely squeezing their profits.</p>
<p>Gazeta Wyborcza also said the document obliged Poland to prepare a privatisation memorandum on its seven refineries by the end of this year and increase strategic fuel reserves, which at present would not last more than 30 days.</p>
<p>Polish industry ministry spokeswoman Beata Nawracka, asked to comment, said the document was not a final agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;This cannot be seen as an agreement. It...concerns changes and aims proposed by Poland concerning the fuels sector and its privatisation,&quot; she told Reuters, but declined to confirm any specific figures.</p>
<p>She said the document would now be submitted to European Union member countries and the European Commission might secure a common stance on the issue.</p>
<p>-- Jan Strupczewski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
