<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15648" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY (11 OF 13).</title>
<headline>REUTER EC REPORT LONG-TERM DIARY (11 OF 13).</headline>
<text>
<p>THURSDAY, DECEMBER 5</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Research Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Financial supplement to the fourth framework programme/task force.</p>
<p>- Action plan on follow-up to the green paper on innovation.</p>
<p>- Fifth RTD framework programme.</p>
<p>- Presidency initiative on the contribution of research to drug detection and prevention of abuse.</p>
<p>- International cooperation in the RTD field:</p>
<p>- Science and technology cooperation strategy with central and eastern European countries;</p>
<p>- (possibly) Bilateral S/T agreements with several third countries.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on the EU and space.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on agronomic research for development.</p>
<p>- SMEs.</p>
<p>- (possibly) Fusion:</p>
<p>- ITER;</p>
<p>- Evaluation report from the Commission on the fusion programme.</p>
<p>- High flux reactor (HFR) programme.</p>
<p>CASABLANCA - Euro-Mediterranean summit of industrial federations.</p>
<p>FRIDAY, DECEMBER 6</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - General Affairs Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Preparation of Dublin European Council.</p>
<p>- Discussion of 53rd U.N. Commission on human rights (including definition of EU position on China).</p>
<p>- Approval of policy document on peacekeeping operations.</p>
<p>- Submission of report on European armaments policy.</p>
<p>- Adoption of common position on U.N. register of conventional arms.</p>
<p>- Former Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- Middle East.</p>
<p>- Mediterranean policy:</p>
<p>- Report on the follow-up to the Barcelona Conference;</p>
<p>- Algeria and Egypt: decision to sign agreements;</p>
<p>- Syria: Commission proposal for a negotiating mandate.</p>
<p>- Preparation of EEA ministerial council.</p>
<p>- Internal financial regulation on ACP.</p>
<p>- Radiation protection of persons undergoing medical examination or treatment.</p>
<p>- Negotiating directives for a nuclear cooperation agreement between EURATOM and Japan.</p>
<p>- Approval of mandate to negotiate an agreement on wine with Slovakia, Slovenia and the Czech Republic.</p>
<p>- Agreement on steel with central and eastern European countries.</p>
<p>- Approval of negotiating mandate for a partnership and cooperation agreement with Turkmenistan.</p>
<p>- Asia:</p>
<p>- Decision to sign a protocol relating to the accession of Vietnam to ASEAN;</p>
<p>- Preparation for EU-ASEAN ministerial (February 1997);</p>
<p>- Follow-up to Bangkok ASEM and preparation for Singapore ministerial.</p>
<p>- Decision to sign framework agreement with Australia.</p>
<p>- Decision to sign mutual recognition agreements with Australia and New Zealand.</p>
<p>- Decision on signature of free trade agreement with South Africa.</p>
<p>MONDAY, DECEMBER 9</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Inaugural World Trade Organisation (WTO) ministerial conference (To December 13).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Review of the implementation of Uruguay Round commitments.</p>
<p>- Endorsement of results of negotiations on services.</p>
<p>- Report from the committee on trade and environment.</p>
<p>- Any other trade-related issues.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Environment Council (To December 10).</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>- Proposal for a decision of the European Parliament and of the Council on the review of the European Community programme of policy and action in relation to the environment and sustainable development &quot;Towards sustainability&quot;.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive amending directive 90/219/EEC on the contained use of genetically modified micro-organisms.</p>
<p>- Auto oil:</p>
<p>a) Draft directive relating to the quality of petrol and diesel fuels;</p>
<p>b) Draft directive on measures against air pollution by emissions from motor vehicules - amendment of directives 70/229//EEC and 70/156/EEC.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council directive concerning the quality of water intended for human consumption.</p>
<p>- Commission communication on waste policy.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation amending Council regulation (EEC) No 3254/91 prohibiting the use of leghold traps in the Community and the introduction into the Community of pelts and manufactured goods of certain wild animal species originating in countries which catch them by means of leghold traps or trapping methods which do not meet international humane trapping standards.</p>
<p>- Proposal for a Council regulation establishing common rules and procedures to apply to the shipments to certain non-OECD countries of certain types of waste.</p>
<p>- Follow-up to the conference on climate change.</p>
<p>- Fifth session of the Commission on sustainable development.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (To December 13). END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
