<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156404" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: CESI index expands, includes Ljubljana, Bratislava.</title>
<headline>CESI index expands, includes Ljubljana, Bratislava.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Budapest Stock Exchange (BSE) modified the share basket of the Central European Share Index (CESI) effective Thursday to include selected Slovenian and Slovak stocks in addition to Hungarian, Czech and Polish papers.</p>
<p>&quot;The basket will also include stocks listed on the Ljubljana and Bratislava stock exchanges,&quot; the BSE said in a statement on Thursday.</p>
<p>The expanded index basket will contain 73 shares against 50 stocks hitherto, the BSE said, and added that the shares were chosen from among the most highly capitalised and most liquid issues.</p>
<p>The basket will contain 11 Hungarian, 20 Czech, 24 Polish, eight Slovak and 10 Slovenian shares, the BSE said earlier this month.</p>
<p>Hungarian shares have an 18 percent weight in the index, Czech stocks have 43 percent, Polish shares have 31 percent, Slovak shares have six percent and Slovenian stocks have two percent.</p>
<p>It also said that these 73 stocks accounted for 76 percent of the total share market capitalisation of their five bourses at the end of September.</p>
<p>The BSE announced that the value of the &quot;K&quot; corrective factor, which allows comparison with the previous CESI indices, is 1.254814.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
