<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156471" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Plane with 95 crashes in Sao Paulo, all feared dead.</title>
<headline>Plane with 95 crashes in Sao Paulo, all feared dead.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Dickson</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Fokker-100 aircraft operated by Brazil's TAM airline crashed soon after take-off into a densely populated area of Sao Paulo on Thursday, and all 95 people on board were feared dead, authorities said.</p>
<p>Television news footage showed burning wreckage of the plane strewn amid three blocks of homes in the middle-class southwest neighbourhood of Parque Jabaquara.</p>
<p>Firemen removed the dead from the wreckage and at least 30 bodies were lined up near the site of the crash.</p>
<p>Authorities at the scene said it was unlikely that anyone survived the Rio de Janeiro bound flight 402, which crashed just before 8:30 a.m./5:30 a.m. EST (1030 GMT) shortly after taking off from Sao Paulo's Congonhas regional airport.</p>
<p>A TAM spokesman said the plane was carrying 89 passengers and six crew members.</p>
<p>Firemen said there appeared to be several dead in homes struck by the plane.</p>
<p>Authorities said the plane skidded over several rooftops, tore through the second floor of a neighbourhood store and then ploughed directly through several homes before coming to a stop.</p>
<p>&quot;Parts of the plane fell on my roof and in my backyard. We heard a big crash and then windows and glass went flying all over the place,&quot; said housewife Eusa da Silva.</p>
<p>&quot;We ran outside and all the neighbours were out screaming. Nobody knew what was going on,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Chunks of fuselage, mortar and brick were strewn throughout a three block area where the plane came down, some 2 miles (3.2 km) from the airport.</p>
<p>The plane barrelled through the neighbourhood, as residents were on their way to work.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
