<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156648" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Futuris to focus on boosting EPS.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Futuris to focus on boosting EPS.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diversified manufacturer Futuris Corp Ltd will not be making any more major acquisitions for at least the next two years, Futuris's chief executive officer Alan Newman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Newman told the annual meeting that the merger of Elders Australia Ltd into the Perth-based company had to all intents and purposes been successfully completed and the future focus of the group would be on improving earnings per share.</p>
<p>In his prepared address Newman said that he believed it was possible to substantially lift earnings.  </p>
<p>But in response to a shareholder's question, he said his personal ambition was to double earning per share, currently about 10 cents, in the next five years.</p>
<p>After the meeting he told journalists the five year timeframe reflected his belief that he would then be able to hand over the CEO job &quot;to someone else in the group&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;My personal ambition in my time as chief executive is to see that (earnings per share) double,&quot; Newman said during the meeting.  </p>
<p>&quot;That is just a personal goal and I believe it is a modest one. It is not a big ask. The assets are in place to do it with fair markets (and with fair prices for the commodities in which Elders deals.&quot;</p>
<p>In his prepared address Newman also:</p>
<p>* announced that Futuris's automotive subsidiary Air International has been placed on General Motor Corp's worldwide bidding list.  </p>
<p>* said Futuris' Chinese joint venture was going to build a new A$25 million factory that will boost the company's process of vertical integration by enabling it to begin manufacturing heat exchangers.</p>
<p>* cautioned the Federal government not to further reduce the level of tariffs on imported motor vehicles or reduce the tax advantages of research and development.</p>
<p>* position Elders to participate in the gradual reform of the rural services market through the pursuit of operating efficiences, the sale of unproductive assets and the investment of funds into assets which can achieve a high return.  </p>
<p>&quot;In summary, we have a very sound position (for) a year of what I consider to be consolidation,&quot; Newman said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of costs associated with the (Elders) merger. Our focus is to build on our wealth from this base. In that process I am fairly confident we can substantially lift the earnings per share.</p>
<p>&quot;In the process we will generate high levels of cash and our intention is that is the case is to lift our dividend payout rates to the more traditional levels of fifty percent.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
