<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156718" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Asia concerned, or mute, over Wang Dan's fate.</title>
<headline>Asia concerned, or mute, over Wang Dan's fate.</headline>
<byline>Kenneth Barry</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reaction to China's sentencing of dissident Wang Dan among Asia-Pacific countries on Thursday ranged from concern to silence to an attitude that China can do what it wants with its own citizens.</p>
<p>Malaysia Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad, differing with the United States' &quot;deep concern&quot; over Wang's sentencing on Wednesday, said: &quot;We make our own assessment. China has the right to act against its own nationals.&quot;</p>
<p>Wang, 27, a student leader of the pro-democracy movement, received 11 years' imprisonment on charges of plotting to subvert the government.</p>
<p>Hong Kong, which reverts to China from Britain in 1997, and Australia voiced concern over Wang's fate.</p>
<p>&quot;I recognise the very considerable concern that many people in Hong Kong, and many people around the world, feel about a sentence imposed on a young man for activities which in most places, including Hong Kong, would be entirely legal,&quot; Governor Chris Patten said.</p>
<p>In Canberra, a spokesman for Foreign Affairs Minister Alexander Downer told Reuters: &quot;The Australian government, past and present, has a long-standing policy of seeking to engage China in a constructive way on human rights issues. In this context, the government will take appropriate steps to register concerns about the treatment of Wang Dan and the government in China.&quot;</p>
<p>There was no immediate reaction from the Philippines, Singapore, South Korea and others in the region.</p>
<p>A commentary in the pro-government Straits Times of Singapore suggested Beijing's motive was to make an example of Wang and intimidate lesser-known dissidents.</p>
<p>&quot;Ordinary people who do not see themselves as China's critics will find it hard to agree that writing letters expressing dissenting views to Chinese leaders or that holding telephone conversations with overseas Chinese pro-democracy activists constitutes 'subversion',&quot; the article written by Jiang An said.</p>
<p>&quot;They will also not understand how a sickly, defenceless and closely watched 27-year-old man, with no organisational back-up, is capable of 'toppling the government'.&quot;</p>
<p>ASEAN, a group of seven Southeast Asian countries, has a non-interference policy towards neighbours accused of anti-democracy activities, Rustam Sani, a political analyst in Malaysia, said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think while it is true certain things should be considered an internal matter, I think there's also a higher moral consideration to think about.&quot;</p>
<p>In Hong Kong, there is concern that wide-ranging freedoms will be jeopardised after the handover next year.</p>
<p>The South China Morning Post, in an editorial, urged clarification of the future law that will govern the territory.</p>
<p>&quot;The need to clarify what will constitute subversion and sedition here is becoming all the more pressing so that Hong Kong can know where it stands -- and can be assured its dissenters will not suffer the fate of Wang.&quot;</p>
<p>Robin Munro, director of the Hong Kong office of Human Rights Watch Asia, said: &quot;What more evidence does the international community now need before it will wake up to the fact that (Beijing) is not advancing towards a more liberal regime...but is becoming less tolerant of peaceful political opposition and absolutely determined to silence critics by any means possible?&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
