<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156712" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Kohl asks regional trade blocs to work closely.</title>
<headline>Kohl asks regional trade blocs to work closely.</headline>
<byline>Ramoncito dela Cruz</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl said on Thursday regional trade blocs should work together to create a new and balanced world economic order.</p>
<p>&quot;I very much like the concept of ASEAN because it (not only) opens up new opportunities of cooperation among the member countries, but also cooperation between other organisations, APEC and the European Union,&quot; Kohl told a meeting of Filipino and German businessmen.</p>
<p>&quot;... With the different regional bodies working together, then we will have a more sensible kind of balance than had ever existed before,&quot; Kohl said.</p>
<p>ASEAN (Association of South East Asian Nations) groups Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
<p>The APEC (Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation) comprises 18 economies including the United States, Japan and China.</p>
<p>Kohl said regional blocs opened up trade and investment but warned they should not exclude others from benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;Some people may opt for closing the windows and the doors because it is warm and comfortable inside. (But) people don't understand, don't realise that the air becomes close inside. I believe this can apply to economies as well,&quot; Kohl said.</p>
<p>Kohl ended his three-day visit to the Philippines and left for Tokyo on Thursday on the last leg of his Asian tour. He had earlier visited Indonesia.</p>
<p>On his way back to Germany on Saturday, Kohl will stop over in Moscow to hold talks with Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin.</p>
<p>&quot;On my way back from Tokyo, I will have a stopover for two hours. I shall meet with the prime minister at the airport. And we shall have the opportunity to talk about Boris Yeltsin's health,&quot; Kohl said.</p>
<p>During the visit to the Philippines, the first by a German head of government, Kohl witnessed the signing of several business deals between German and Filipino businessmen. Officials said deals worth nearly $1 billion were signed.</p>
<p>The biggest of the deals was an agreement by Siemens AG with the Philippines' First Gas Holdings Corp to build a gas-fired, 990-megawatt power plant near Manila. The project is worth $650 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
