<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156865" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX natgas ends down sharply, longs bail.</title>
<headline>NYMEX natgas ends down sharply, longs bail.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures ended lower across the board Thursday in a quiet, post-bidweek session, with front months down sharply on profit taking and long liquidation after recent gains, industry sources said.</p>
<p>December tumbled 13.6 cents to close at $2.728 per million British thermal units. January settled 13 cents lower at $2.698. Other deferreds ended down by one to 11.6 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;We stalled out early and a lot of specs (speculative longs) had to get out,&quot; said one Midwest trader, referring to December's failure to pierce the new contract high of $2.88 set last night on ACCESS.  </p>
<p>While most agreed the longer-term technical trend was still higher, some floated the possibility of a technical reversal today after December hit a new contract high and closed sharply lower.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see a crash, but I wouldn't be surprised to see a pullback into the $2.60s (basis December),&quot; said an East Coast trader.</p>
<p>The Midwest trader agreed. &quot;We're still in a uptrend, but I think we'll see a test of the $2.661 pivot. The key is (cold) weather and if we don't get it, we'll break down.&quot;</p>
<p>December resistance was seen at the $2.88 contract high and at $2.92 and $2.98, two prominent spot continuation highs set in late June and early July.</p>
<p>Cash sources said most physical traders were sidelined Thursday waiting for November flows to begin tomorrow. Notionally, Gulf Coast swing gas firmed several cents to the mid-to-high $2.70s on prospects for colder East Coast weather. Midcon pipes notionally were down slightly to the low-to-mid $2.70s.</p>
<p>The 12-month Henry Hub strip slumped 6.3 cents to $2.216. NYMEX said 30,363 Hub contracts traded, down from Wednesday's revised tally of 35,274.</p>
<p>NYMEX December Alberta natgas closed one cent higher at a new contract high of $1.24, while deferreds finished up by 2.5 to five cents. NYMEX said 112 Alberta contracts traded compared with 16 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>NYMEX December Permian natgas ended down by eight cents at $2.61, while deferreds were untraded. NYMEX said 65 Permian lots changed hands versus 45 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, December finished 12 cents lower at $2.59, while deferreds settled down by one to 10 cents. The December East/West spread narrowed by 1.6 cents to 13.8 cents (NYMEX premium). KCBT said 212 contracts traded, down from Wednesday's total of 502.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
