<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156897" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas producers protest U.S. plan for royalties.</title>
<headline>Natgas producers protest U.S. plan for royalties.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major U.S. natural gas producers said Thursday they had protested a plan by the Minerals Management Service to change the way it calculates royalties owed for gas produced on federal and Indian lands.</p>
<p>MMS had proposed to base the royalties on prices of natural gas after it has been processed, rather than at the wellhead.</p>
<p>In an October 30 letter to the agency, members of the Natural Gas Supply Association (NGSA) said they were &quot;deeply troubled&quot; by the plan that would include marketing costs in gas price valuations, and urged MMS to withdraw the proposal.  </p>
<p>&quot;Marketing costs are not production costs,&quot; NGSA said in the letter released Thursday.</p>
<p>The group added that tracking natural gas sales from the wellhead to the burnertip would entail heavy administrative costs for the industry.</p>
<p>The agency expects to come out with a new proposal or a final rule no earlier than mid-1997, based on comments from the industry and other parties, an MMS spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a possibility they might have to come out with another proposed rule,&quot; because of strong opposition voiced in comments, which were due in August, the spokesman said.  </p>
<p>The agency's proposal made in July came on top of another rule change in progress for calculating royalties based on published index prices, a plan which it had negotiated with the industry.</p>
<p>MMS, which collects about $4 billion a year in oil, gas and mineral royalties, has been under pressure from Congress and a watchdog group to pursue royalties more aggressively.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300014">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
