<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156847" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. not denying reports of China rights deal.</title>
<headline>U.S. not denying reports of China rights deal.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Thursday declined to deny news reports that it was discussing with China a package of measures intended to defuse tensions over human rights.</p>
<p>&quot;I simply can't confirm, will not confirm, don't want to confirm any of these stories,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said, adding: &quot;I'm not in a position to confirm it or deny it.&quot;</p>
<p>The New York Times reported on Thursday that Washington was talking to Beijing about a package on human rights that could include release or medical parole of noted dissidents, prison visits to Chinese detainees by the Internatonal Committee of the Red Cross and a &quot;more structured channel&quot; to raise rights issues with China.</p>
<p>Some of these were agreed to before but not implemented due to a sharp downturn in Sino-American relations after the United States in 1995 granted a visa to Taiwan President Lee Teng-hui, outraging Beijing.</p>
<p>In exchange for the human rights moves, the United States might be willing to drop its co-sponsorship of an annual United Nations resolution condemning Chinese human rights practices, the New York Times said.</p>
<p>The newspaper also reported that in June, President Bill Clinton sent a private letter to Chinese President Jiang Zemin offering to grant China permanent &quot;most favoured nation&quot; trading status in return for a concession on improving Beijing's human rights record.</p>
<p>Concerning U.S. intentions on the annual U.N. resolution, Burns said: &quot;...we evaluate the human rights situation in China on an on-going basis. And we'll continue to evaluate it on an on-going basis, to determine whether or not resolutions are helpful or not helpful, important or not important.&quot;</p>
<p>He reiterated that Secretary of State Warren Christopher planned to go ahead with a trip to Beijing next month despite China's sentencing to 11 years in prison on Wednesday of well-regarded pro-democracy activist Wang Dan.</p>
<p>He also reasserted that Christopher plans to raise with senior Chinese officials Wang and other rights cases.</p>
<p>But Burns declined to say for sure if Clinton -- if he is re-elected next Tuesday -- would go ahead with a proposed exchange of summits with Jiang.</p>
<p>Christopher several months ago called for an exchange of high-level visits -- his trip on Nov 18-21 is part of that series -- including summits. He argued the need for engaging, rather than isolating, China, whose importance is viewed as growing in the 21st century.</p>
<p>Whether a U.S.-China summit is held &quot;is up for the president to decide after the (U.S.) election,&quot; Burns said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
