<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15693" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Shaky sellers see Australian stocks end down.</title>
<headline>Shaky sellers see Australian stocks end down.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian sharemarket closed lower on Tuesday with losses steepening in the afternoon as nervous investors trimmed positions ahead of the U.S. opening.</p>
<p>At the close, the All Ordinaries index was down 19.8 points at 2,262.3. The September share index futures slid 21 points to 2,266 and was at a 3.7 point premium to the underlying index.</p>
<p>Brokers said selling emerged following weakness in both local and U.S. bond markets with investors worried U.S. yields would continue to rise after nudging seven percent on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's taken a dive today,&quot; said a Sydney-based dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;There are plenty of sellers about although volumes are not exceptional,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Turnover at A$641 million was substantial, though suggestive of a hedging of positions rather than a wholesale selldown.</p>
<p>&quot;Commonwealth Bank going ex-dividend had an effect but overall it's been taken down by selling from people worried about U.S. (interest) rates. Positions are being cut while things are sorted out over there,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Others saw things in the same light, saying a lack of positive inspiration had seen recent strong profits cashed in.</p>
<p>&quot;With no guidance people have sold off and taken some profits,&quot; said dealer Peter Struk of brokerage Reynolds and Co.</p>
<p>In corporate features, aluminium producer Comalco continued to slide after Monday's disappointing profit result. Its 67 percent shareholder, CRA, saw its shares soften in sympathy.</p>
<p>Engineering and hardware group Howard Smith bucked the trend to finish stronger after reporting a 12 percent higher full year net profit of A$86.13 million.</p>
<p>Falls outnumbered rises by a ratio of about nine to seven, while about 33 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
