<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156918" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot propane takes a beating from NYMEX.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot propane takes a beating from NYMEX.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot propane prices took a beating in quiet late trade on Thursday as NYMEX futures plunged on Iraqi news, players said.</p>
<p>NYMEX December crude oil futures ended down 93 cents at $23.35 a barrel following news rival Kurdish factions have agreed to extend a U.S. brokered cease-fire that ended two months of clashes in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>The extension renewed hopes that a long awaited Iraqi oil-for-food deal will finally be implemented.</p>
<p>Crude oil pulled the rest of the energy complex down.</p>
<p>In the U.S. Gulf Coast, Mont Belvieu, Texas, spot propane fell about one cent in thin talk to between 52.25 cents and 53.00 cents a gallon. The market was difficult to gauge because there were few buyers, players said.</p>
<p>In the Midwest, Conway, Kansas, hub material shed one cent to 54.50/55.00 cents. Traders said there were few sellers in that hub.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of sellers think the market is going to pop back up,&quot; said one Conway trader.</p>
<p>Belvieu normal butane was also assessed lower, down 1.75 cents to 54.00/54.50 cents. Conway material was a quarter cent higher.</p>
<p>-- Laney Salisbury, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1631</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
