<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="156943" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - up 1/2, Midway reprices.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - up 1/2, Midway reprices.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bond prices strengthened in afternoon trading Thursday, finishing the day up about 3/8 to 1/2 point ahead of Friday's jobs data.</p>
<p>Amid the stronger tone, JP Morgan Securities repriced a $254 million Chicago Midway Airport deal, adjusting yields in several maturities and lowering the top yield in 2029 to 6.02 percent from 6.05 percent.</p>
<p>The afternoon gains tracked trends in the Treasury market, where the long bond was up 25/32 at 101-11/32 to yield 6.64 percent heading into the New York close.  </p>
<p>The T-bond was about 1/4 point higher at midday.</p>
<p>In the muni secondary, bids on Cook County, Ill., FGIC 5-7/8s of 2022 were up 3/8 to 99-7/8. Yields dropped nine basis points, to 5.63 percent, on Texas Turnpike Authority FGIC 5-1/4s of 2023.</p>
<p>Futures also ended higher. The December municipal contract ended up 20/32 at 115-28/32, while December T-bonds rose 13/32 to 113. The MOB spread between the two contracts widened to 92 ticks from 85 ticks Wednesday.  </p>
<p>In other repricings Thursday, EVEREN Securities Inc restructured West Ottawa Public Schools, Mich.'s $71 million bond deal but left the top yield in 2026 unchanged at 5.83 percent. </p>
<p>The closely watched employment report, which has rocked the market with surprises over the past several months, is set for release at 0830 EST Friday.</p>
<p>Other Friday data include leading indicators and factory orders for September at 0830 EST. At 1000 EST, the market is set for the National Association of Purchasing Management index, which is expected to show a 51.0 reading.</p>
<p>--Steven Dickson, 212-859-1652</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
