<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157027" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. bulk millfeeds - Prices weaker on CBOT slide.</title>
<headline>U.S. bulk millfeeds - Prices weaker on CBOT slide.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. millfeed prices were mostly steady to lower on Thursday in line with declining CBOT corn and soybean prices and an easing of nearby supply tightness, dealers said.</p>
<p>With the corn market down, midds were slightly off, a Carolinas dealer said. The price of midds are too high. &quot;They are going to break. It is a question of when and how far,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is dead quiet and until the feed business gets better, the market is definitely top heavy,&quot; one St Louis dealer said. &quot;There is more feed around than what the market needs.&quot;  </p>
<p>Spot Kansas City prices dropped $1.00 to bid at $96.00 a ton and offer at $98.00 and Chattanooga values fell $3.00 to bid at $90.00 and offer at $94.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still in this holding pattern,&quot; a Minneapolis dealer said. &quot;Buyers are waiting for the midds to go as low as they can go.&quot; Minneapolis spot values were off $2.00 to bid at $85.00 and offer at $90.00.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the nearby supply tightness is gone,&quot; he added. &quot;You can get feed if you need it.&quot;</p>
<p>Millfeed prices appeared to be high, a dealer said.</p>
<p>He noted two factors that will maintain millfeed prices, cold weather demand and a seasonal cutback in mill run times as they get beyond the middle of November. &quot;Too many people will be going to corn and away from midds,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
