<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157145" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: LGT completes buy of Chancellor Capital.</title>
<headline>LGT completes buy of Chancellor Capital.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Private bank and fund manager Liechtenstein Global Trust AG (LGT) said it had completed its acquisition of Chancellor Capital Management Inc, increasing its assets under management to more than $80 billion.</p>
<p>The total purchase price for Chancellor could reach a maximum of $300 million, contingent upon the level of growth in the business over the next five years, LGT said in a statement.</p>
<p>Significant long-term incentives are included to retain key employees, it added.  </p>
<p>After the acquisition, the North American investment advisor of LGT will be known as Chancellor LGT Asset Management and serve institutional and individual clients that invest in the GT Global Mutual Funds.</p>
<p>Chancellor LGT Asset Management, based in New York and San Francisco, specialises in public and private U.S. and international equity and bond portfolio management.</p>
<p>Chancellor, with a product range in U.S. equity, U.S. fixed income and alternative assets, manages $33 billion in assets for pension funds, insurers and charities.</p>
<p>Before the LGT deal, Chancellor was 51 percent owned by a management group headed by company president and chief executive Warren Shaw.</p>
<p>Shaw has been named LGT's Global Chief Investment Officer.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIECHT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
