<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157155" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Sketches of Bundebank council members.</title>
<headline>Sketches of Bundebank council members.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Council members of Germany's powerful central bank have been publicly airing seemingly contradictory views on European monetary union that have unnerved financial markets.</p>
<p>Following are brief sketches of the 16 members of the Bundesbank's decision-making Council and what they stand for. The council is made up of two groups -- permanent senior officials who are members of the Frankfurt-based executive Directorate that conducts open markets operations and presidents of the regional central banks in federally-structured Germany.</p>
<p>HANS TIETMEYER, 65, president whose term expires in August 1999. Tietmeyer, a Christian Democrat (CDU), is a top ally of Chancellor Helmut Kohl. Known as a monetary policy centrist, he joined the bank board in January 1990 after a career in Bonn ministries. Named president in October 1993, he wants a strict interpretation of the Maastricht Treaty and has pushed for a powerful stability pact for the future single currency. He also believes Exchange Rate Mechanism (ERM) membership is needed to join the currency union and is critical of &quot;window-dressing&quot; finance measures to meet EMU criteria.</p>
<p>JOHANN WILHELM GADDUM, 66, vice president whose term expires in June 1998. Gaddum, a CDU member and former president of the Rheinland-Palatinate bank, joined the Directorate in 1986 and was appointed to his current job in October 1993. A centrist, he is an expert on capital markets but has limited international exposure. Gaddum is sympathetic to public fears about the euro and favours strict treaty interpretation. He favours a stability pact with automatic sanctions and converting existing German debt into euro debt as soon as possible.</p>
<p>OTMAR ISSING, 60, chief economist. Issing, a professor who has no political affiliation, joined the council in October 1990 and is seen as a centrist on monetary issues. A proponent of the EMU stability pact, he warns against softening EMU entry criteria. He is also critical of &quot;creative accounting&quot; to fulfill fiscal critiera and cannot rule out Germany falling short of EMU targets in 1996.</p>
<p>WENDELIN HARTMANN, 59, Directorate member for payment systems and controlling. Hartmann, a technical banking expert with no political affiliation, joined in 1964 and was appointed to the Directorate in June 1992. He chairs a working group at the European Monetary Institue, the precursor to a European central bank, on coordinating cashless payments under EMU. Hartmann is seen as a &quot;hawk&quot; on monetary policy who would favour interest rate hikes if necessary. He believes a transition period between the euro's introduction and physical distrubition should be shortened.</p>
<p>HELMUT SCHIEBER, 58, directorate member for international relations who has no political affiliation. Joined in 1964 and the directorate in June 1992. A centrist on rate policy, he believes the EMU target start date of January 1999 will be hard to meet and entrance criteria should not be relaxed. He also believes EMU members should not be selected before March 1998.</p>
<p>PETER SCHMIDHUBER, 65, Directorate member for legal and administrative issues. A Christian Social (CSU) member, he is an ally of Finance Minister Theo Waigel. Viewed as monetarist hawk, he joined the Directorate in March 1995. He believes a timely start to EMU is possible if steps are taken to ensure stability and a delay could endanger the whole project.</p>
<p>EDGAR MEISTER, 56, Directorate member in charge of banking supervision. Meister, a Social Democrat (SPD), joined the Directorate in 1993 and is considered a favourite to replace Gaddum. A monetarist dove, he wants clear interpretation of EMU entry criteria. He notes public confusion on how the criteria will be interpreted and fears political pressure may push through the introduction of the new currency at any price.</p>
<p>KLAUS-DIETER KUEHBACHER, 53, President of Berlin and Brandenburg state central bank. A former Bundestag member viewed as an outspoken SPD politician and expert on fiscal policy, he was named in September 1995 to his position. A monetarist dove, he wants EMU to start on time with a small group of nations rather than risk delay or softening criteria.</p>
<p>FRANZ-CHRISTOPH ZEITLER, 48, President of Bavaria state central bank. A CSU member viewed as a monetary centrist who was appointed to his post in 1995. He oversaw in 1991 introduction of a &quot;solidarity surcharge&quot; to pay for German unification. He is critical of nations using gimmicks to meet entry criteria.</p>
<p>REIMUT JOCHIMSEN, 63, President of North-Rhine Westphalia state central bank. An SPD member and former professor, he was economics minister of North-Rhine Westphalia before taking up his current position in August 1990. He, a monetarist centrist to dovish who criticised France for its budget moves, says Germany will not accept the euro if criteria are eased. He believes five states seek to join EMU by fudging criteria.</p>
<p>HANS-JUERGEN KOEBNICK, 58, President of Saarland and Rheinland-Palatinate state central bank. A former journalist and SPD mayor, he was named to his position in 1991 and as Rheinland-Pfalz bank president in 1993. A monetarist dove, he says forecasts that Germany may miss EMU criteria in 1997 are realistic and an EMU delay could be useful. He said Italy, Spain and other &quot;Club Med&quot; nations were unlikely in the first group.</p>
<p>GUNTRAM PALM, 65, President of Baden-Wuerttemberg state central bank. A CDU member, he was state minister before being being named to his current job in April 1992. Palm, a monetarist hawk, warns against using tricks to join EMU. Favours criteria interpretation aimed at stability and wants stability pact.</p>
<p>ERNST WELTEKE, 54, President of Hesse state central bank. A SPD member and former state economics and finance minister, he was named to his job in 1995. He, a monetarist dove, says an EMU delay to enlarge the group is unwise and could threaten the project. He sees some leeway in budget criteria but not laxity.</p>
<p>OLAF SIEVERT, 63, President of Saxony and Thuringia state central bank. A non-party professor named to his job in January 1993. A monetarist dove, he says an EMU delay would be the beginning of the end and favours a small group. He sees the euro helping to solve unemployment problems in Europe.</p>
<p>HANS-JUERGEN KRUPP, 63, President of Schleswig-Holstein and Hamburg and Mecklenburg-Vorpommern state central bank. A SPD member and monetarist dove, he was president of DIW institute and named to his current post in December 1993. He says nations do not need to hit debt criteria exactly to qualify and sees room for manoeuvre, particularly on public debt.</p>
<p>HELMUT HESSE, 62, President of Lower Saxony and Bremen and Saxony Anhalt bank. He has no political affiliation and is a Club of Rome member. He was named bank president in December 1988 and given responsibility for more regional banks in November 1992. Hesse has made little public commentary on currency union but is considered a monetary centrist to hawkish.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
