<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157196" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Madrid stocks end flat ahead of All Saints holiday.</title>
<headline>Madrid stocks end flat ahead of All Saints holiday.</headline>
<text>
<p>MADRID, Oct 31 (Reuter) 1615 GMT - Madrid stocks ended flat on Thursday after a listless day's trade ahead of Friday's All Saints' public holiday.</p>
<p>The tone was cautious as dealers closed positions ahead of the long weekend and key U.S. payroll data, also due on Friday. * General index down 0.16 points, 0.04 percent, to 375.73 * Ibex down 2.03 points, 0.05 percent, to 4,306.74 * Argentaria limited losses via a large buy order just before the close. Ended off 50 pesetas at 5,000 in heavy trade after posting on Wednesday a 13.1 percent fall in net profit for the nine months to September, well below analyst expectations. * Telefonica continued to retrace part of its large recent gains, ended down 20 pesetas at 2,560.  </p>
<p>&quot;The session has been prudent on the part of most dealers,&quot; said a trader, adding that this was reflected in low volumes and a thin trading range.</p>
<p>Argentaria was subject to selling on disappointing results which prompted talk of a possible share buyback and restructuring, dealers said.</p>
<p>Other banks were mostly higher, but trade was subdued. BBV added 409 pesetas to 6,200 and Santander rose 10 pesetas to 6,650.</p>
<p>Turnover totalled 34.135 billion pesetas.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
