<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15710" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam sees open market operations in early 1997.</title>
<headline>Vietnam sees open market operations in early 1997.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam's State Bank, the central bank, will launch open market operations from early next year as part of moves to reform the country's creaking banking system, governor Cao Si Kiem said in an interview on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Kiem was quoted by the Saigon Times Daily as saying the move would pave the way to &quot;eradicate regulations on ceiling interest rates&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to apply the new operation in early 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reaction on Tuesday among foreign economists and bankers in Hanoi was generally positive.</p>
<p>&quot;Vietnam is getting more sophisticated,&quot; said a senior economist who declined to be named. &quot;There comes a time when you have to move away from direct control over credit ceilings and interest rates. That's what Vietnam is doing.&quot;</p>
<p>Other bankers said further steps were still required to ensure the necessary framework was in place and indicated that the early 1997 date might therefore be optimistic.</p>
<p>&quot;There are issues such as whether the instruments to do this...treasury bills, for example...are there in sufficient numbers. I would have thought the introduction of open market operations would have to be gradual rather than sudden,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>The Saigon Times report said a central bank &quot;open market steering committee&quot; would meet early each day to assess foreign exchange trading and decide whether bonds should be sold or bought to maintain market stability.</p>
<p>Plans to buy or sell stocks would then be announced to participating banks and finance companies along with details of the value of stocks, the time of deals, and modes of settlement, the report said.</p>
<p>Traders would also be allowed to announce the amount of stock they want to trade.</p>
<p>Kiem said the State Bank and International Monetary Fund were cooperating to get the system up and running and a trial period was likely to precede full open market operations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
