<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157279" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka capital placed on alert for rebel bombers.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka capital placed on alert for rebel bombers.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombo police on Thursday warned the public to be on the alert for suspected Tamil suicide bombers who may have infiltrated the city's defences, Colombo police chief D.M. Dissanayake said.</p>
<p>The warning came as 22 suspected Liberation Tigers of Tamil Eelam (LTTE) activists escaped from a high-security prison in Trincomalee, 240 km (150 miles) northeast of Colombo, military officials said.</p>
<p>Ten activists were killed or captured, while 12 remained at large, military officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are told that many (rebels) have infiltrated Colombo,&quot; Dissanayake told Reuters. &quot;They will try their level best to do things. So we have warned the public to be on the alert.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier this week police headquarters issued posters and stickers urging the public to cooperate with security forces, mainly by being on the lookout for suspicious characters, he said.</p>
<p>Security has been tight in the Sri Lankan capital since January when the rebels, fighting for independence in the island's north and east, detonated a truck bomb outside the central bank, killing about 100 people.</p>
<p>In July, they set off bombs in a crowded passenger train in a Colombo suburb, killing 57.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, police arrested a group of 20 suspected rebel suicide bombers near President Chandrika Kumaratunga's official residence.</p>
<p>Military officials in Trincomalee said the LTTE suspects broke out of jail shortly before midnight on Wednesday after grabbing a guard's gun.</p>
<p>Soldiers gave chase, shooting five of them dead and arresting five more, they said. Two military policemen were killed in the shootout. The other 12 suspects are at large.</p>
<p>The Sri Lankan government says more than 50,000 people have been killed in the ethnic conflict, which is in its 14th year, while the LTTE says a much higher number have perished.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
