<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157254" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - October 31.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - October 31.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi.</p>
<p>Tel:3326806, 3326813, 3326849  Fax:+91-11-3351006 E-mail:</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>Indian Express</p>
<p>RAO FACES CRIMINAL CHARGES</p>
<p>Former Prime Minister Narasimha Rao appeared before a special court in Delhi as a co-accused in the St Kitts forgery case. Rao and former minister K.K.Tewary, another accused, moved regular bail applications. Their bail pleas were opposed by the investigating agency. The hearing is continuing. Rao is the first former prime minister to face criminal charges.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Pioneer</p>
<p>FORMER PRIME MINISTER INDICTED IN BRIBERY CASE</p>
<p>The Central Bureau of Investigation (CBI) indicted former prime minister Narasimha Rao along with six others, including two of his former cabinet ministers, in the Jharkhand Mukti Morcha payoff case. Rao was also identified as the prime accused in the chargesheet. The chargesheet, filed before a special court, elaborated on an alleged 35 million rupee political donation on the eve of the no-confidence motion in the Rao government in 1993.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>DELHI AIRPORT TERMINAL GUTTED IN FIRE</p>
<p>The domestic departure terminal of Indian Airlines at Delhi airport was gutted by fire. There were no casualties. The fire led to the disruption of flight schedules. The fire was believed to have started in a restaurant kitchen.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>HALT TO FRESH INVESTMENT BY RAILWAYS</p>
<p>A committee of secretaries, reviewing the performance of core sector projects, banned the railways from clearing any fresh investment until completion of old projects. The railways' clearance of projects without providing for required funds has drawn criticism. There are 97 pending railway projects that need an investment of about 190 billion rupees to be completed. The committee asked the railways to indicate the source of funding before clearing any new project.</p>
<p>HUGHES, BPL PROPOSALS APPROVED</p>
<p>The Cabinet Committee on Foreign Investment (CCFI) has cleared Hughes Ispat's proposal to increase foreign equity from 40 percent (eight billion rupees) to 49 percent (9.8 billion rupees) for the Maharashtra circle. The CCFI also cleared the holding company proposals of BPL and Sanmar Electronics. The committee also cleared a $31 million payout by Gail to the Spic Capag-led consortium. The CCEA is understood to have cleared the revised cost estimates of Mangalore Refinery and Petrochemicals Ltd from 11.6 billion rupees to 26.96  billion rupees.</p>
<p>BRITISH TELECOM MAY PICK UP STAKE IN AIRTEL</p>
<p>British Telecommunications Plc (BT) is close to acquiring a stake in India's largest cellular operator, Airtel. BT is negotiating with two companies, SFR of France and the UK's Mobile Systems International, to buy 27 percent of the foreign holding in Bharti Cellular Ltd (BCL), which owns the Airtel brand. BCL has the cellular licence for the Delhi circle. The 27 percent stake BT proposes to buy in BCL is worth between $70-81 million.</p>
<p>INDUSTRIAL FINANCE CORP CUTS MAXIMUM LENDING RATE</p>
<p>The Industrial Finance Corporation of India (IFCI) board has reduced its maximum lending rate to 19.5 percent. The IFCI did not rule out a further cut in its lending rates. The IFCI move is part of the interest rate war going between financial institutions (FIs). Other FIs, IDBI, ICICI have fixed their maximum lending rates at 20 percent. The IFCI has retained its prime lending rate at 16 percent and has fixed the interest rate band at 3.5 percent. This makes the IFCI lending rate more attractive than other FIs which have their fixed PLR at 16.5 percent with an interest rate spread of 3.5 percent.  </p>
<p>MAJOR RAIL PROJECTS FOR NORTH -EAST INDIA</p>
<p>The railway minister announced two major projects worth 15.5 billion rupees for northeastern states. The projects would be outside the railway budget and fully funded by the central exchequer. These are part of the 61 billion rupee economic development package announced by Prime Minister Deve Gowda last week. The two projects are the 10 billion rupee Kumarghat-Agartala link and the 5.5 billion rupee Bhogibhil Bridge.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>COMPANY LAW BOARD MAY GET POWER TO CLEAR MERGERS</p>
<p>The government may arm the Company Law Board (CLB) with powers to approve mergers and acquisitions of companies. A committee currently drafting the Companies Bill, likely to be before parliament in January, 1997, decided to introduce amendments to speed up the restructuring and winding up procedures of companies. The working group, set up to prepare a new Companies Bill, is expected to include provisions that will give the CLB more powers. The CLB earlier had asked the department of company affairs to entrust it with powers to regulate mergers and acquisitions.</p>
<p>SIEMENS TO TRANSFER TELECOMMUNICATION OPERATIONS</p>
<p>Siemens Ltd may hive off its telecommunications operations to a new, majority owned company of its parent company Siemens AG. The move is aimed at transferring the losses of the telecommunication operations of Siemens to its parent, which has the capacity to absorb such losses. According to Siemens' sources, transfer of the telecommunication operations to a new company will help improve the bottom line and image of the company. Siemens is in the midst of major expansions in areas such as power, EPC (engineering, procurement and construction) and information technology.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>DRAFT ENERGY CONSERVATION BILL SENT TO STATES FOR APPROVAL</p>
<p>The government is circulating a draft energy conservation bill among state governments for their approval. The proposed bill, if implemented, will play a significant role in demand side management of power shortages. On the supply side, the thrust will be on optimum use of regional energy surpluses by building inter-regional transmission lines. This will help harness seasonal and off-peak energy to deficit regions. The bill also provides for identifying major industrial consumers and imposition of a statutary energy audit on them.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer</p>
<p>MORE DEREGULATION SEEN LIKELY</p>
<p>Further deregulation of the telecommunication, ports, roads, power sectors appear to be on the government's agenda. Indicating this, Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said these sectors had long been under-performing due to too many regulations. Chidambaram reiterated the government's keenness to inject competition to improve efficiency of infrastructure facilities and called for enhanced private investment in this sector. He affirmed the government would go ahead with insurance reforms and also tap pension funds to finance the country's infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>MINISTRY TO SUPPLY NAPHTHA FOR POWER GENERATION</p>
<p>The Ministry of petroleum and natural gas decided to make available naphtha for electricity generation of up to 10,000 mw for over 200 independent power producers in the ext two years. According to the decision, the Petroleum ministry is committed to make regular naphtha supplies to power producers only for two years. During the past 2-1/2 years, the power ministry signed some 300 pacts (MoUs) with the independent power producers for setting up naphtha-based power projects to generate 30,000 mw of electricity. However, not a single project could be executed because the ministry failed to supply the raw material.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
