<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157227" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Analysts detect no Buba rift from recent remarks.</title>
<headline>Analysts detect no Buba rift from recent remarks.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unnerved by an onslaught of seemingly contradictory comments from German central bank officials, traders fear the Bundesbank's facade may be crumbling, revealing deep divisions over currency union.</p>
<p>The latest evidence, traders said, flashed across screens on Thursday morning when state central bank president Hans-Juergen Krupp said the Maastricht Treaty does not require states to hit the reference criteria exactly to join Europe's monetary union.</p>
<p>After most Bundesbank officials have repeatedly demanded a strict interpretation of the entry criteria, Craig Shute, fixed income analyst at Bear Stearns in London, said, &quot;The Krupp comments hint the Bundesbank may be softening its stance.&quot;</p>
<p>But other economists disagree, arguing the Bundesbank's 16 council members agree, in principle, on the best way to reach Europe's planned monetary union and that comments merely reflect small political differences and various personalities.</p>
<p>&quot;When you count who has said what recently, a clear trend emerges that the Bundesbank is backing a strict interpretation of the Maastricht Treaty criteria,&quot; said Hermann Remsperger, chief economist at BHF Bank in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The Maastricht Treaty on European Economic and Monetary union (EMU) puts the reference values for nations' planned or actual government deficit and debt to gross domestic product as three percent and 60 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>Political leaders will determine in 1998 which nations can join EMU after reviewing their 1997 economic data.</p>
<p>Confusion over the Bundesbank's ideas of Europe's currency union and even its own interest rates may stem from heightened market interest in the topics as well as the fact officials are telling the market things it does not want to hear.</p>
<p>&quot;So far, the market has been happy playing the spreads. Hearing comments suggesting only a small group of nations will enter the currency union in 1999 is not to their liking, and consequently, there is worry,&quot; said Klaus Holschuh, head of trading research at Commerzbank.</p>
<p>But he also emphasized that &quot;there is only one Bundesbank policy line and no rift.&quot;</p>
<p>While traders claim confusion about who is saying what and liken the Bundesbank comments flickering across their screens to a popularity contest with one official trying to upstage another, analysts said the confusion may also be self-serving.</p>
<p>&quot;The interpretation of comments always depend on a trader's vantage point,&quot; Holschuh said.</p>
<p>Although economists agreed President Hans Tietmeyer, Vice-President Johann Wilhelm Gaddum and Chief Economist Otmar Issing's comments may still be slightly weightier than others', they said no one member should really be discounted.</p>
<p>&quot;Every Bundesbank official's word is being weighed very, very carefully now,&quot; said Stephan Schneider, economist at Banque Paribas in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>&quot;I really don't think there is a two class system there,&quot; said Paribas' Schneider, saying each member had his vote and posseses enough self-confidence to vote the way he sees fit.</p>
<p>And apart from each member's different personal thrust, economists agreed that for all there is a bottom line. &quot;I think all members want a stability pact, strict fulfilment of the entry criteria,&quot; Schneider said.</p>
<p>Analysts also said it is not unsual to have the number of comments pick up at this time of year because central bankers were now speaking at a variety of conferences that did not take place during the traditional, summer lull.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
