<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15733" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan-China trade edges up in Jan-June yr/yr.</title>
<headline>Taiwan-China trade edges up in Jan-June yr/yr.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's trade with China grew only 0.1 percent year-on-year to US$10.44 billion in the first six months of 1996, a period of acute tension across the Taiwan Strait, the Board of Foreign Trade said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Taiwan's exports to China rose 1.5 percent to $8.98 billion, accounting for 15.9 percent of Taiwan's total exports, the board said in in statement.</p>
<p>Imports from China declined 7.9 percent to $1.46 billion, accounting for 2.9 percent of the island's total imports. It was the second month in a row that imports from China showed negative growth.</p>
<p>During the January-June period, Taiwan enjoyed a trade surplus of $7.52 billion with China, up 3.6 percent from the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>The board attributed the slow trade growth to a reduction in China export rebate tax rate in January, which caused Taiwan-owned factories in China to advance their exports to before January.</p>
<p>The cut led in turn to a slowdown in Taiwan's processing material exports to China.</p>
<p>China, which has regarded Taiwan as a renegade province since a civil war separated them in 1949, held war games in the Taiwan Strait during the island's historic direct presidential elecion on March 23 to warn voters not to support independence.</p>
<p>Officials have said the war games affected Taiwan firms' willingness to invest in China.</p>
<p>Some 30,000 Taiwan firms have poured US$20 billion in investments in China so far.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (2-5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
