<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157366" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks, bonds rally on oil price drop.</title>
<headline>Stocks, bonds rally on oil price drop.</headline>
<byline>Chris Stetkiewicz</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stock and bonds rallied Thursday as the prices of oil and other commodities fell and weak economic data suggested interest rates will remain low.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 36.15 points at 6,029.38. In the broader market, advancing issues led declines 1,462 to 929 on heavy volume of 482 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>In the bond market, the 30-year Treasury bond gained more than three-quarters of a point and its yield fell to 6.64 percent -- its lowest level since April 3 -- from 6.71 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers that came out made the bond market happy,&quot; said Peter Canelo, chief investment strategist at Dean Witter.</p>
<p>&quot;With the GDP numbers yesterday on the soft side, and the unemployment claims today, the feeling is that the economy is soft, and the Fed won't do anything about interest rates,&quot; Canelo said.</p>
<p>The Labour Department said initial jobless benefit claims jumped to 342,000 in the week ended Oct. 26 compared with a revised 319,000 in the previous week.</p>
<p>In another report, consumer spending on goods and services rose a scant 0.1 percent to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of $5.18 trillion in September, after a 0.5 percent gain in August.</p>
<p>This followed news Wednesday that economic growth slowed to a 2.2 percent rate in the third quarter, from a 4.7 percent rate in the second quarter because consumer spending slowed to a near standstill.</p>
<p>The technology-laden Nasdaq Composite index rose 15.28 points to 1,221.51.</p>
<p>In currency markets, a weaker Swiss franc helped the dollar rise against European currencies, but the dollar failed to advance on the Japanese yen.</p>
<p>The Swiss currency slumped amid renewed focus on Switzerland's weak economy and concern that an investigation into wartime deposits in Switzerland might lead to the erosion of its bank secrecy laws.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to 1.5180 German marks from 1.5114 marks late Wednesday and edged lower to 114.03 yen from 114.13.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, crude oil for December delivery plunged 93 cents to $23.35 a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange after rival Kurdish factions agreed to extend a U.S. brokered ceasefire that ended two months of clashes in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>November heating oil fell 2.12 cents a gallon to 66.34 cents.</p>
<p>Record low heating oil inventories had sent heating oil and crude prices to new post-Gulf War highs this month, but the belief that heating oil stocks were being replenished has been pushing oil prices lower the past two weeks.</p>
<p>The fall in energy prices also triggered a steep retreat in the Knight Ridder Commodity Research Bureau index -- an inflation barometer. The CRB tumbled 3.83 to 237.83.</p>
<p>Overseas, London's FTSE 100 rose 15.2 points to 3,979.1 and Tokyo's benchmark Nikkei 225 fell 214.81 or 1.04 percent to 20,466.86, its lowest point close Sept. 12.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
