<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157820" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Chinese business delegation cancels Israel visit.</title>
<headline>Chinese business delegation cancels Israel visit.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy Chinese Prime Minister for Education and Trade Li Lanqing cancelled a visit to Israel planned for November at the head of a business delegation, an Israeli Foreign Affairs Ministry spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The spokesman denied a report in Israel's Haaretz newspaper the cancellation was politically motivated. The spokesman said the dates were inconvenient and the Chinese had expressed interest in rescheduling the visit.</p>
<p>The director of the international affairs department at the Federation of Israeli Chambers of Commerce, Ronnie Reiber, said a trade delegation from Poland recently cancelled a scheduled visit to Israel over the political situation.</p>
<p>Many foreign investors are taking a &quot;wait-and-see&quot; attitude towards Israel in light of heightened tension between Israelis and Palestinians and the stalled Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>But Reiber said the federation was &quot;flooded&quot; by delegations all the time: &quot;Just last week we had two delegations from China with a third expected next week.&quot;</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
