<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157848" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton's lead widens to 18 points in California poll.</title>
<headline>Clinton's lead widens to 18 points in California poll.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton's lead in California has widened to a commanding 18 points despite Republican rival Bob Dole's aggressive campaign in the key state, according to a poll published on Thursday.</p>
<p>With less than a week before the election, the poll by the independent Field Institute showed Clinton leading Dole 52 percent to 34 percent in California, the most populous state and biggest electoral prize.</p>
<p>The poll is a blow for Dole, who had decided to make an all-out push in the final weeks of the campaign to capture California's 54 electoral votes after earlier polls appeared to show him narrowing the gap on Clinton in the state.</p>
<p>Dole has spent several days campaigning up and down California in the last few weeks.</p>
<p>Clinton's lead was up sharply compared with a Field Poll carried out from Oct. 7-9 which showed him with a 10-point lead.</p>
<p>In the latest poll, carried out Oct. 25-28, Reform Party presidential candidate Ross Perot was preferred by six percent of likely voters while Ralph Nader of the Green Party had the support of three percent. Five percent were supporting others or were undecided, the poll found.</p>
<p>The Field poll also found that 90 percent of each candidate's supporters were now very certain of their choice.</p>
<p>Despite Dole's efforts, the Field poll found that Dole's image in the state is more unfavourable than favourable. Forty-two percent of likely voters said they believed Dole has been &quot;very negative&quot; in his campaign, while just 10 percent said that about the Clinton campaign.</p>
<p>Overall, the Field Institute said Dole's level of support has stayed in a very narrow range since August -- 33 percent to 38 percent. Clinton's support has varied more widely, from 45 percent to 55 percent during the fall campaign.</p>
<p>Men have wavered somewhat in their preferences in the race, but now prefer Clinton by an 11-point margin. On the other hand, women have been unwavering in their support for Clinton and now give him a 24-point lead over Dole.</p>
<p>Clinton has the overwhelming support of Hispanics, Blacks and Asians, the Field poll found.</p>
<p>The poll was based on a representative statewide sample of 824 likely voters in next week's presidential election. The margin of error from the overall sample was plus or minus 3.5 percentage points, the Field Institute said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
