<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157927" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Shareholders file suit to block Safeway offer.</title>
<headline>Shareholders file suit to block Safeway offer.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of shareholders filed a lawsuit Wednesday seeking to block Safeway Inc's proposed $2.3 billion takeover of supermarket chain Vons Cos Inc on the grounds the deal is unfair to Vons' shareholders.</p>
<p>The purported class action suit, filed in Los Angeles Superior Court, alleges the &quot;intrinsic value&quot; of Vons exceeds the $58 per share offer by Safeway, in light of Vons' potential growth and profitability.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the plaintiffs charge Safeway's 35.4 percent stake in Vons gives Safeway an unfair advantage over other potential bidders.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of Safeway's 35 percent equity power, four board seats and overwhelming control over Vons, all of Vons directors who will be considering the offer, and the entire board of directors, no third party as a practical matter can attempt any competing bid for Vons as the success of any such bid would require the consent and cooperation of Safeway,&quot; the complaint said.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact, because of the predominant control of Vons by Safeway, it is a foregone conclusion that whatever Safeway may offer, such offer will be accepted.&quot;  </p>
<p>Earlier, Safeway proposed to acquire Vons in a stock swap valued at about $2.3 billion, including debt. Vons said it would consider the offer and respond in due course.</p>
<p>Representatives from Safeway and Vons were not available to comment on the lawsuit.</p>
<p>California-based Safeway operates 1,050 stores in the United States and Canada. Vons' 325 stores are mostly in southern California.</p>
<p>The combination of Safeway and Vons would create the second-largest grocery store chain in North America.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
