<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157902" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Texas race a bellwether for Democrats in Congress.</title>
<headline>Texas race a bellwether for Democrats in Congress.</headline>
<byline>James Pierpoint</byline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A freshman Republican's battle to hold onto a seat in Congress from a blue-collar district along the Texas Gulf coast has become a bellwether race in the Democrats' bid to regain a majority in Congress.</p>
<p>Labelled &quot;Congressman Clueless&quot; by a Texas magazine and attacked for his militia ties following the Oklahoma City bombing, Representative Steve Stockman has come under intense fire from labour, environmentalists and two Democratic opponents in the race in Texas' 9th Congressional district.</p>
<p>&quot;(Stockman) doesn't have any margin for error in that district,&quot; said Rice University political scientist Earl Black. &quot;It's a district that's going to be pretty hard for the Republicans to keep.&quot;</p>
<p>Located in the heavily industrialised gulf coast region stretching from Houston to the Louisiana border, the Texas 9th was drawn for longtime Democratic Representative Jack Brooks, a House Judiciary Committee chairman who spent 42 years in Congress.</p>
<p>Stockman was swept into Congress on anti-Clinton sentiment in the 1994 mid-term elections, unseating Brooks and joining a 235-197 Republican majority in the House of Representatives.</p>
<p>In his re-election bid this fall, Stockman squared off against Beaumont tax assessor Nick Lampson, who won the Democratic primaries, and kindergarten teacher Geraldine Sam, a Democrat who placed third in the party primary but jumped back into the race after a court redrew 13 congressional districts in Texas and opened the November elections in those districts to all comers.</p>
<p>Stockman's campaign has been a study in contradictions. Labelled one of the &quot;dirty dozen&quot; Congressmen by environmentalists, Stockman ads pledge &quot;clean air, clean water, jobs.&quot; Elected on promises of ending business as usual in Washington, Stockman accepted contributions from the banking industry and took credit for $1.8 billion in new investment in the region by oil companies.</p>
<p>Union activists representing workers at the 87 local refineries and chemical plants have thrown their support behind Lampson, and the AFL-CIO is expected to outspend all three candidates in a battle to win back the seat from this largely blue-collar district.</p>
<p>A target of the AFL-CIO's $35 million nationwide ad blitz against freshmen Republicans, Stockman filed a libel lawsuit against the union, but a Houston federal court this week refused to block the ads from airing locally.</p>
<p>&quot;The Washington union bosses have gone beyond the point of credibility by rehashing totally false and misleading charges in order to scare senior citizens.&quot; Stockman said of the so-called MediScare media blitz mounted by the national union.</p>
<p>Lampson aides allege Stockman was somehow behind the candidacy of Gary Brooks, a construction worker who asked to be listed on the ballot as G. &quot;Jack&quot; Brooks even though his wife said he never went by that name.</p>
<p>Democrats feared the admitted gimmick campaign by Brooks -- who was banking on voters confusing him with the longtime Texas Congressman -- would have drawn votes away from Lampson.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
