<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="157943" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA weatherman says week to assess wind damage.</title>
<headline>USDA weatherman says week to assess wind damage.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-10-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Agriculture Department meteorologist Mark Russberg said Wednesday it would take about a week to assess how severe and widespread the damage was after strong winds gusted through key corn-growing states late Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to know for a week or so exactly how bad things are, but we've already had local reports of lodging, and the potential is there for lodging over many of the states in this area, especially in the sections where they had the heavy rain,&quot; Russberg told USDA radio.  </p>
<p>He said lodging of the crop could be worse than normal because there was heavy rain on top of already soggy soil.</p>
<p>&quot;The chance is that the rooting system isn't as deep as it normally would be,&quot; said Russberg. &quot;If you have a shallow rooting system in wet soils and winds of 50 or 60 miles-an- hour or higher, you have the potential for some of the crops laying down.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is potentially a very serious problem, at least on a local level and is something that the local USDA offices are going to have to take a close look at,&quot; the weatherman said.</p>
<p>Gusts of 60 miles-an-hour and more hit key corn growing areas late Tuesday and continued in some areas Wednesday.</p>
<p>The corn harvest had already been slowed by wet weather. In its report on October 27 conditions, the USDA said 45 percent of the crop was harvested compared with 30 percent a week earlier and the five-year average of 60 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
