<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158273" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Bomber targets Sydney railway toilets.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Bomber targets Sydney railway toilets.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>An unknown bomber blew up a men's toilet cubicle on a Sydney underground railway line on Thursday in the third such attack in a week, police and rail officials said.</p>
<p>They said no-one was injured in the attack, in which a crude explosive device tore through a cubicle wall and caused extensive damage to a row of toilets.</p>
<p>No-one was in the room at the time.</p>
<p>&quot;It appeared to be a pretty crude type of bomb. No persons were injured and the trains continued to run throughout,&quot; said Ron Hall, a spokesman for transit authority, Cityrail.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said the bomb appeared to be a home-made devices and could even have been put together using instructions available on the Internet computer network.</p>
<p>Australian media said the bomber used plastic bottles filled with chemical accelerants or fertilisers to blow up the toilets at the St James Cityrail station.</p>
<p>One witness, 19-year-old shopworker Felicia Karangis, said she was walking along the platform when she heard a &quot;fairly loud&quot; explosion.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone was in shock,&quot; she said. &quot;There were a few screams by women ... I was quite frightened.&quot;</p>
<p>Similar attacks have been made on two other Sydney railway station toilets in the past week, although causing less damage.</p>
<p>CityRail spokesman Hall said the authority was increasing security patrols and would be closing all toilets on its city circle and eastern suburbs lines.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
