<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158438" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia to work on a benchmark for bond market.</title>
<headline>Indonesia to work on a benchmark for bond market.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's central bank governor said on Thursday the bank was working with the International Finance Corporation (IFC) to set up a benchmark for its local bond market.</p>
<p>&quot;The needs are .. pressing for a benchmark. We hope that it will be filled by multilateral agencies .. something which we later on can approve,&quot; Bank Indonesia Governor Sudradjad Djiwandono told an international business conference.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been discussion for more than a year between us and IFC about issuing rupiah bonds,&quot; Djiwandono said.</p>
<p>He told the conference if the agency could issue bonds on a regular basis to finance its projects in Indonesia, they could be used as a benchmark for corporate bonds.</p>
<p>He later told reporters that there was no bond market in Indonesia as locally issued bonds were bought &quot;for keeps&quot; and not traded because of the lack of a benchmark.</p>
<p>IFC, the International Finance Corporation, is a member of the World Bank Group focusing on loan financing for private sector projects in developing countries.</p>
<p>Djiwandono said, however, the government itself had no plans to issue bonds domestically because Indonesia's budget was always balanced by law, since 1967.</p>
<p>He said the government can issue bonds in offshore markets, as it did in July with a $350 million issue in New York, but not in the domestic market.</p>
<p>He added there were some 50 corporations in Indonesia which had issued bonds, but the secondary market was still inactive.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of a benchmark, the lack of liquidity, the absence of a central clearing and custody body as well as various other problems still impede its progress,&quot; Djiwandono said.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
