<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158410" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Prudential Singapore fund to double in year.</title>
<headline>Prudential Singapore fund to double in year.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prudential Assurance Company Singapore Pte Ltd is confident its policyholders' investment-linked funds will double to Singapore $1 billion over the next year, chief executive Tan Suee Chieh said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Tan told a news conference Prudential Singapore's current funds had taken four years to build to about S$500 million.</p>
<p>&quot;I am generally confident that within the next 12 months we will expect to see equity, managed and cash funds pass the S$1 billion level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Prudential Singapore is a unit of London-listed Prudential Corp Plc.  </p>
<p>Tan said future reforms to Singapore's Central Provident Fund (CPF), effective from January 1 1997, would be &quot;a major contributory factor&quot; in managed funds growth.</p>
<p>The reforms seek to harmonise the CPF Basic and Enhanced Investment Schemes, reducing the threshold at which individuals can invest surplus compulsory CPF deposits in alternative products to S$8,000 from the current S$50,000.</p>
<p>About 30 percent of Prudential Singapore's $500 million investment-linked portfolio currently comprises surplus CPF investments, said Tan.  </p>
<p>Tan was speaking at a press conference to mark the first anniversary of the PruLink Equity Fund, a multiple option fund that invests in the Hong Kong, Thailand, Malaysia, Philippines, Indonesia and Singapore markets.</p>
<p>-- Nick Edwards, Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
