<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158444" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: RESEARCH ALERT - FJ Benjamin recommended by Fraser.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - FJ Benjamin recommended by Fraser.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fraser Securities recommended investors to subscribe to the shares of fashion retailer FJ Benjamin Holdings Pte Ltd (FJB) on its strong track record.</p>
<p>Fraser said in a statement made available to Reuters on Thursday that in spite of a retail slump, FJB had managed profit growth of 693 percent over the last three years to S$10.9 million for financial year ended June 1996 from S$1.4 million in June 1993.</p>
<p>Fraser said FJB's success came from effective brand promotion and its establishment as an effective niche player.</p>
<p>It said due to FJB's extensive Asia Pacific network, the company enjoyed economies of scales in purchasing, marketing and communications.</p>
<p>&quot;We are forecasting earnings to grow by about 20 percent annually for the next three years,&quot; Fraser said.</p>
<p>Fraser put FJB's prospective price earnings ratio for fiscal 1997 at 12.2 times compared to an historical 11 times on its initial public offer price of Singapore $0.80 each.</p>
<p>FJB launched 50 million shares at an initial public offering in Singapore on Tuesday. The offer will close on November 12 and trading starts on November 14 on a when-issued basis.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703080) at jn</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
