<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15850" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: ICE HOCKEY-FOUR-GOAL BLITZ HELPS FINNS BEAT CZECHS.</title>
<headline>ICE HOCKEY-FOUR-GOAL BLITZ HELPS FINNS BEAT CZECHS.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A four-goal blitz inside three minutes helped Finland to a 7-3 victory over reigning world champions the Czech Republic in their ice hockey World Cup opener on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Czechs took the lead in the seventh minute, Radek Bonk picking up a stray pass from Finnish defender Jyrki Lumme.</p>
<p>But spearheaded by North American Hockey League forwards Saku Koivu, Ville Peltonen, Juha Ylonen and Teemu Selanne, Finland equalised and then went 3-1 up inside 40 seconds.</p>
<p>Koivu, of the Montreal Canadiens, set up the crucial equaliser with a brilliant pass from behind the Czech goal.</p>
<p>Frustrated Czech goaltender Roman Turek left the ice after the three-goal barrage, but his replacement Petr Briza fared little better, failing to save a shot by Lumme less than two minutes later.</p>
<p>In the second period, Janne Ojanen netted for Finland to make the score 5-1 before the Czechs pulled one back through a Robert Reichel penalty shot.</p>
<p>With the result beyond doubt, the third period lacked the pace and energy of the previous two, and both teams were content to play at half-speed, saving strength for the tight World Cup schedule to come.</p>
<p>In the European group, Finland play Germany on Wednesday in Helsinki. The Germans were beaten 6-1 by Sweden in their opening match on Monday. The Czech Republic play Sweden in Prague on Thursday.</p>
<p>Canada, the United States, Russia and Slovakia meet in the other group, known as the North American group.</p>
<p>The World Cup is the successor to the Canada Cup, which was played in 1976, 1981, 1984, 1987 and 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
