<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158667" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines signs repo deal with Bank of Japan.</title>
<headline>Philippines signs repo deal with Bank of Japan.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine Central Bank governor Gabriel Singson said on Thursday the bank had signed a dollar repurchase agreement with the Bank of Japan.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Central Bank), in a move to promote monetary cooperation among the region's central banks and further bolster their capability to ward off currency speculation, has signed a repurchase agreement with Bank of Japan,&quot; Singson said in a statement.</p>
<p>The deal was the sixth Manila has signed with other central banks in the region. The agreements now total $3.5 billion.  </p>
<p>The Philippine Central Bank recently signed similar deals with monetary authorities of Hong Kong, Singapore, Malaysia, Thailand and Indonesia.</p>
<p>The agreements allow the Central Bank to borrow U.S. dollars from other central banks using its U.S. Treasury bills and notes as collaterals, with a proviso that it will buy back the U.S. government securities at a later date.</p>
<p>&quot;Formulated in the aftermath of the Mexican crisis that triggered currency speculation in the emerging markets worldwide, the agreements in effect provides a multibillion-dollar quick disbursing facility to the region's central banks,&quot; Singson said.</p>
<p>Singson said the bank was finalising details of a similar agreement with another Asian central bank, which he declined to name. - Manila newsroom 63 2 8418938 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
