<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158625" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Lawyer says Japan copper trader helping officials.</title>
<headline>Lawyer says Japan copper trader helping officials.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former star copper trader Yasuo Hamanaka is voluntarily cooperating with Japanese prosecutors investigating Sumitomo Corp's trading losses of $2.6 billion, one of his lawyers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Hamanaka told me he's now spending about eight hours a day on the investigation with the prosecutors. He is voluntarily cooperating,&quot; said Toru Yoshiki, one of the three lawyers representing Hamanaka.</p>
<p>Hamanaka was arrested last week after Sumitomo filed a complaint saying he forged documents to give himself authorisation to conduct certain copper trades.</p>
<p>The giant trading house has accused Hamanaka of racking up the huge losses from unauthorised copper trading.</p>
<p>Before Sumitomo fired him in mid-June, Hamanaka was considered the most influential and controversial player in the world copper market.</p>
<p>Traders called him &quot;Mr Five Percent&quot; because of the chunk of the global copper market that he was said to control.</p>
<p>Hamanaka is being held in a Tokyo detention centre. &quot;His family sent some clothes and food, but has had no opportunity to meet him so far,&quot; Yoshiki said. -- Tokyo Commodities Desk +81-3-3432-7391</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
