<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158673" id="root" date="1996-10-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China considers more reform of treasury bond issue.</title>
<headline>China considers more reform of treasury bond issue.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-10-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's Financial Ministry is considering further reforms to its method of issuing treasury bonds after a series of changes this year, the China Securities newspaper on Thursday quoted a senior official as saying.</p>
<p>New measures will include a gradual introduction of a few fixed methods of issuing T-bonds instead of a variety of ways used this year, establishing a national T-bond clearing house and opening an underwriting business to individuals, the newspaper quoted Gao Jian, director of the ministry's state debt department as saying.</p>
<p>Gao was addressing a meeting for the underwriting of the nation's first seven-year T-bond in Shenzhen on Wednesday, the newspaper said but gave no further details of the new reforms.</p>
<p>Gao said China had this year reformed its T-bond issue by making it more market-oriented. The bulk of bonds issued were given to underwriters on the basis of public tender instead of by administrative edict, as in the past.</p>
<p>Prices have largely been set by the market through these tenders instead of being fixed by the ministry as before, Gao said. More bonds were issued through computers instead of in paper form, helping to raise efficiency of the issue.  </p>
<p>Varieties have been increased with the first issue of three-month and seven-year bonds, and the issue of 10-year bonds for the first time in a decade, Gao said.</p>
<p>The ministry continued to issue six-month, one-year, three-year and five-year bonds, Gao said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-10-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-10-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
