<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="158984" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: BHP says diamond mine to cost C$900 million.</title>
<headline>BHP says diamond mine to cost C$900 million.</headline>
<dateline>YELLOWKNIFE, Northwest Territories 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's Broken Hill Proprietary Co Ltd said Friday that its Lac de Gras diamond mine in Canada's Arctic is projected to cost C$900 million by the time it goes into production in the second half of 1998.</p>
<p>Jim Excell, BHP's manager for the project, told reporters that figure includes C$200 million spent so far, partly on exploration costs. A further C$700 million will be spent to develop the mine. BHP has 51 percent of the project and Dia Met Minerals Ltd of Canada has 29 percent.  </p>
<p>BHP expects to spend about C$30 million a month, Excell said. The company previously put the cost of the mine project at C$860 million.</p>
<p>Canada's federal government granted final approval to the diamond mine earlier at a ceremony in Yellowknife.</p>
<p>Clarifying an earlier comment, Excell said full production was expected between June and December 1998.</p>
<p>Preliminary construction work has already started and is expected to get underway in earnest next summer. BHP hopes to receive a water license in early to mid-December and an updated land use permit next April, he said.  </p>
<p>Don Morin, premier of the Northwest Territories, said BHP is supporting a plan to establish a valuation center for the diamonds in the Northwest Territories. The issue has been a politically sensitive one with northerners arguing that they should reap downstream spin-off benefits from the project.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a commitment it will happen in the north...These diamonds are coming from our land,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ron Irwin, the federal minister responsible for the North, said a final decision had not yet been made but he hopes the valuation center will end up in the North. &quot;Cost factors&quot; will determine the final decision, he said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YELLOWKNIFE, Northwest Territories"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
