<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159152" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: COMEX copper ends higher after choppy session.</title>
<headline>COMEX copper ends higher after choppy session.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>COMEX copper ended higher after a volatile session as the market absorbed another healthy but less-expected dip in LME stocks Friday.</p>
<p>LME stocks fell 8,650 tonnes to 123,700 tonnes. Stocks in Long Beach fell to 34,525 tonnes, down 2,275 tonnes.</p>
<p>On Thursday conflicting views appeared as to which direction LME stocks would go. In recent weeks until Thursday, traders largely agreed that stocks would continue falling.</p>
<p>COMEX stocks continue to rise in recent weeks but were up only a nominal 12 short tons Friday to 30,805 short tons.</p>
<p>Traders said much of the extra metal is from Long Beach.</p>
<p>Bette Raptopoulos of Prudential Securities said comments by ASARCO's chairman, Richard De J Osborne to analysts in New York Friday helped to support the market.</p>
<p>Although some of the stock drawdown from LME may be part of tactics by one or two big players to confuse the market, much of the metal taken out was being consumed.</p>
<p>Osborne also forecast only modest supply surpluses in 1997 and 1998, contrary to what many analysts expected.</p>
<p>December COMEX settled 1.35 cents firmer at 92.65 cents, traded 92.75 to 90.05 cents. Volume was estimated at 9,000 lots, down from the heavily traded sessions of late.</p>
<p>&quot;Osborne stuck his neck out to say the LME stock drawdowns were indeed consumption related,&quot; Raptopoulos said.</p>
<p>-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
