<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159122" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Monarch had Q3 loss on low shipments.</title>
<headline>Monarch had Q3 loss on low shipments.</headline>
<dateline>SIDNEY, Ohio 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Monarch Machine Tool Co said on Friday it had a third quarter loss due primarily to low shipments and continuing losses at its lathe division as well as losses at two overseas divisions caused by low shipments and higher than anticipated start-up costs for a large coil processing line.</p>
<p>The company reported a third quarter loss of $412,000, or $0.11 per share, after an after tax gain of $237,000, or $0.06 per share, compared to a year ago profit of $345,000, or $0.09 per share.  </p>
<p>Monarch said the gain resulted from the sale of all remaining property related to the discontinuance of operations at its Dean Smith &amp; Grace subsidiary in Keighley, England.</p>
<p>Third quarter sales dropped to $24.4 million from $31.4 million. Nine month sales of $76.9 million compared with $82.1 million in 1995.</p>
<p>The third quarter loss left it with a nine month loss of $822,000, or $0.22 per share, compared with a profit of $480,000, or $0.13 per share a year earlier.</p>
<p>The company said new orders for the first nine months of 1996 fell to $82 million from $103 million in 1995.  </p>
<p>Backlogs at the end of the third quarter were $64 million, up from $60 million at the beginning of the year but down from the $70 million level of one year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;For the year, the Stamco Division has experienced reduced income due to poor margins in the first quarter and a temporary hold on shipment of a very large order to an overseas customer which affected mid-year performance,&quot; the company said. Stamco's operating results were positive in the third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;The Cortland Division experienced lower than anticipated shipments during the first half but also showed positive operating results in the third quarter,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The company added that the search for a permanent chief executive &quot;is being pursued diligently, with full awareness of the importance of this selection to our shareholders.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SIDNEY, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
