<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159138" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. December S&amp;P 500 futures finish lower.</title>
<headline>U.S. December S&amp;P 500 futures finish lower.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. December Standard and Poor's 500 futures ended lower, never recovering from a weak tone in Treasury bond futures and pre-weekend profit-taking.</p>
<p>The market had gained early after U.S. economic data painted a picture of a slowing economy that powered a rally in Treasury bonds. But as T-bond gains faded, profit-taking took center stage in stock index futures.</p>
<p>December S&amp;P 500s rallied to 712.30 before turning lower and hitting a session low in afternoon trade at 704.05.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a nervous week,&quot; one S&amp;P 500 futures trader said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the Nasdaq was calling the shots a little bit and with the bonds making those lows at 112-21/32 we were able to put new lows in too,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Still, December managed to eke out some gains late in the afternoon to close off the low.</p>
<p>Traders said indecision had ruled all week amid mixed technical signals and nervousness before key data. Before S&amp;Ps opened, U.S. October nonfarm payrolls were reported up 210,000, very close to expectations, compared with a revised September decline of 35,000 jobs.  </p>
<p>The National Association of Purchasing Management's index of October manufacturing activity fell to 50.2 from 51.7 in September. Economists had forecast a 51.0 NAPM reading. September factory orders rose 2.7 percent, the largest increase since August 1994.</p>
<p>Traders pegged support for Monday at the day's 704.05 session low and at 702.55 to 702.70, a band of recent session lows.</p>
<p>December S&amp;Ps closed down 3.15 points at 706.50, New Composites lost 1.65 at 374.95, Value Lines fell 1.65 at 646.15, Nikkeis rose 100.0 points to 20,670 and Midcap 400s were up 0.15 at 244.20. -Derivatives Desk(312)408-8750/E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
