<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159247" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Foster Wheeler to appeal lawsuit dismissal.</title>
<headline>Foster Wheeler to appeal lawsuit dismissal.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>- Foster Wheeler Corp, the developer of a bond-financed incinerator in Robbins, Ill., will appeal a U.S. District Court ruling dismissing its lawsuit against Illinois state officials, a company attorney said Friday.</p>
<p>Tom O'Brien, Foster Wheeler's chief counsel, said an appeal would be filed in the U.S. Court of Appeals, while the company also considers filing another lawsuit in state court and seeks administrative relief from state agencies.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're committed to the lawsuit,&quot; he said, adding that the ruling by U.S. District Court Judge James Zagel was made strictly on procedural grounds.</p>
<p>Zagel dismissed the lawsuit on the ground that the 11th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution precludes lawsuits against states dealing with public funds.  </p>
<p>In his 13-page ruling, Zagel said the defendants -- Illinois Gov. Jim Edgar and the members of the Illinois Commerce Commission -- were immune under the amendment. While the claims in the lawsuit &quot;may very well have merit,&quot; they should be litigated in state court, not federal court, the judge ruled.</p>
<p>The lawsuit, filed by Foster Wheeler, its Illinois subsidiaries and the village of Robbins, had charged the state's repeal of a 1987 state subsidy for incinerators resulted in the unconstitutional impairment of contract.  </p>
<p>The repeal also violated various U.S. constitutional provisions, including equal protection and due process, the lawsuit alleges.</p>
<p>Clinton, N.J.-based Foster Wheeler filed the lawsuit shortly after the Illinois governor in March signed into law a bill repealing the Retail Rate Act, which allowed incinerators to sell their electicity to utilities at a higher rate subsidized by the state.</p>
<p>A comment from Gov. Edgar on Zagel's ruling was not immediately available.  </p>
<p>The dismissal of the lawsuit was the second legal blow to strike three waste-to-energy incinerators in Illinois in just over a month. On September 30, a Cook County, Ill., Circuit Court judge dismissed bondholders from a lawsuit brought by the developers of incinerators in Ford Heights and Fulton. Judge Edwin Berman also dismissed part of the incinerator developers' lawsuit.</p>
<p>Only one count against Illinois Commerce Commission officials -- claiming the subsidy repeal was an illegal retroactive act -- remains alive. Oral arguments on that count are expected to take place by yearend.</p>
<p>Almost $500 million of tax-exempt, non-rated revenue bonds were sold for incinerator projects in Robbins, Ford Heights and Fulton between 1994 and December 1995.</p>
<p>On October 15, Robbins completed a tender of nearly $320 million of bonds it sold in 1994 for the incinerator. Holders of 99.92 percent of the bonds accepted the tender offer that exchanged their bonds for restructured bonds featuring a lower interest rate, some extended maturities, additional credit support from Foster Wheeler, new convenants and different redemption provisions.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
