<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159236" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Electronics in PCS pact with NextWave.</title>
<headline>Electronics in PCS pact with NextWave.</headline>
<dateline>FAIRFIELD, N.J. 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electronics Communications Corp said on Friday its wholly owned subsidiary, Personal Communications Network Inc (PCN), entered a strategic resale agreement with NextWave Telecom Inc.</p>
<p>As part of the 10-year pact, PCN will sell wireless personal communications system services nationwide except in the metropolitan New York area where Electronics Communications is a cellular telephone service agent for Bell Atlantic NYNEX Mobile, a joint venture of Bell Atlantic Corp and NYNEX Corp.  </p>
<p>The resale of five billion PCS airtime minutes is equal to &quot;several hundred million dollars in additional revenue&quot; for both Electronics Communications and NextWave, the company said.</p>
<p>The company said it is continuing its discussions with NextWave to collaborate on PCS network design, construction and equipment purchasing in New York, Vermont and Maine.  The companies also have started preliminary talks regarding network systems support, roaming and access to other wireless infrastructure requirements.  </p>
<p>&quot;By purchasing wholesale airtime from NextWave, Personal Communications Network will be able to offer competitively priced and customized services without making a substantial capital investment in network infrastructure,&quot;  said PCN president William Taylor.</p>
<p>Electronics Communications is an FCC licensed paging services provider which operates a digital paging network serving customers in New York, New Jersey, Philadelphia and Connecticut. It is also an FCC-licensed two-way radio services provider, operating a 470 MHz dispatch radio system in the New York metropolitan area.</p>
<p>NextWave is a private company based in San Diego and New York. It was the largest bidder in the U.S. Federal Communications Commission's auctions for &quot;C-band&quot; wireless radio spectrum held earlier this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FAIRFIELD, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
