<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159278" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Calif. towns to seeks bids for deregulated power.</title>
<headline>Calif. towns to seeks bids for deregulated power.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A coalition of local governments in the San Francisco Bay area of northern California will seek bids next week for electricity supplies after the state initiates deregulation in January 1998.</p>
<p>McCullough Research has been retained by the Association of Bay Area Governments (ABAG) to conduct the request for proposals. Potential suppliers are asked to meet Friday at ABAG offices in Oakland, said Robert McCullough.</p>
<p>He noted that the aggregate load of ABAG members, who are currently served by Pacific Gas and Electric Co, is 6,000 megawatts (MW), but initial indications are that a load of 200 MW will be served under the restructured market.</p>
<p>McCullough added that the bidders' prices will also be subject to &quot;competitive transition charges&quot; which California will allow investor-owned utilities to collect from current customers during a five-year transition period.</p>
<p>He noted that finalists in the bidding process are expected to be selected in February.</p>
<p>ABAG's 127 members include cities such as Alameda, Berkeley and Oakland as well as San Francisco.</p>
<p>--Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
