<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159538" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE coffee rebounds to end up on tender news.</title>
<headline>LIFFE coffee rebounds to end up on tender news.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee futures rebounded from early lows to end mostly up on industry buying after a lower-than-expected tenders on the first notice/tender day for the spot November contract, traders said.</p>
<p>Earlier in the day, stop-loss selling drove prices to the day's low of $1,365 a tonne basis second-month January and near the immediate key $1,360 support.</p>
<p>Traders said a meagre of 21 lots were tendered on Friday, a level well below what some people had anticipated.</p>
<p>&quot;People were expecting more tenders and there were only 21 lots and the market bounced,&quot; said one floor trader.</p>
<p>Traders said there could be more coffee being tendered against November in the coming weeks to reap the high November premium.</p>
<p>By the close, January stood $9 up at $1,394. It had earlier climbed to a high of $1,400 on the back of scale-down industry price-fixing.</p>
<p>Other back months also attracted light roaster industry interest.</p>
<p>Front-month November scooped a hefty gain of $32 on the day to close at $1,495 and widened the closely-watched Nov/Jan spread to a high of $110 from $78 at Thursday's close.</p>
<p>Volume on the exchange reached a modest 2,432 lots.</p>
<p>Traders said London's gains were also capped by New York's reluctance to push higher.</p>
<p>&quot;It's at its lows at the moment. It's a bit of a struggle,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>On the fundamental side, traders said fresh robusta origin supplies were ample and poised to make their way to western markets soon.</p>
<p>&quot;The bumper crops are coming out from everywhere. There are a lot of grading coming through...a lot of Indonesians, Ivorians, Madagascars, Ugandans,&quot; another said.</p>
<p>&quot;They're all coffee that is probably going to hit the market and more is coming,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Technically, analysts said coffee could test a key downside target at $1,300 in the short term with the market firmly entrenched in its current long downtrend.</p>
<p>&quot;Stay short, no doubt about it,&quot; said David Charters of Investment Research of Cambridge.</p>
<p>-- Jalil Hamid, London newsroom +44 171 542 4985</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
