<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159654" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Third World leaders meet for trade promotion.</title>
<headline>Third World leaders meet for trade promotion.</headline>
<byline>Emelia Sithole</byline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders from 15 developing countries meet in Harare from Sunday to map out strategies for promoting trade among them and for boosting growth in the world's poorest regions.</p>
<p>Organisers of the Group of 15 (G-15) developing countries said eight heads of state and government had so far confirmed their attendance at the November 3 to 5 summit but declined to name them, citing security reasons.</p>
<p>They said the summit would look at ways of forging a common front among African, Asian and Latin American states to give them a stronger voice in a world moving towards free trade.</p>
<p>&quot;By far trade issues are going to top the agenda of the meeting,&quot; said Tichaona Jokonya, Zimbabwean President Robert Mugabe's special representative to the G-15.</p>
<p>&quot;The globalisation of world trade is a phenomenon that has gripped the world and the primary responsibility for the development and integration of our countries into the global system rests with ourselves,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Jokonya said the G-15, which was set up in 1989 along the lines of the Group of Seven most-industrialised nations, was concerned at the manner in which global trade systems were evolving, particularly under the World Trade Organisation (WTO).</p>
<p>He said the WTO was heavily tilted in favour of industrialised countries largely due to a lack of expertise and capacity among developing nations to influence decisions taken during the Uruguay Round which gave birth to the WTO.</p>
<p>&quot;The main concern of the G-15 is how the concept of free trade must be carried out without conditionalities. Some countries, like the United States are putting conditions, like its insistence on equal labour standards, which are hindering free trade,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jokonya said the Harare summit would try to hammer out a common position for the G-15 countries ahead of the WTO ministerial meeting in Singapore from November 8 to 13 so that its concerns would be taken into account.</p>
<p>&quot;Our only source of hope to influence change in world trade arrangements is our unity in areas we have common interest. If we can enhance our development and economic viability through South-South cooperation it gives us a chance to counterbalance bullish decisions that are made by developed countries,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said a trade exhibition -- showcasing products from the G-15 which comprises Algeria, Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Egypt, India, Indonesia, Jamaica, Malaysia, Nigeria, Senegal, Peru, Venezuela, Yugoslavia and Zimbabwe -- would run alongside the summit.</p>
<p>----Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
