<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159661" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: GFSA shareholders seen hungry for change.</title>
<headline>GFSA shareholders seen hungry for change.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Disappointing third quarter results from Gold Fields of South Africa have jangled the nerves of major shareholders and they could push for a restructuring or a takeover of the group, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>Gold Fields recently posted earnings before capital spending of 274.41 million rand for the third quarter -- sharply down from 355.86 million rand in the second quarter.</p>
<p>The company attributed its profit fall to underground fires at some of its mines and a spate of violent industrial action, which halted production.</p>
<p>But analysts have slammed the group's management saying the problem with the firm is the way it's being run, not the quality of the assets or the negative impact of outside events.</p>
<p>&quot;Its poor performance makes it a question mark, because it has got world class assets. If there is a co-ordinated attack of major shareholders then it (a takeover or restructuring) could happen,&quot; an analyst who asked not to be identified said.</p>
<p>Analysts said shareholders could be itching for change in Gold Fields too. &quot;The shareholders must be getting a bit edgy and pushing for something to happen,&quot; another analyst said.</p>
<p>The group is well secured from attack as it owns 40 percent of its major shareholder Gold Fields Holdings. The balance is held by Rembrandt with 40 percent and Liberty Life with 20 percent.</p>
<p>A Gold Fields spokeswoman said the firm was not aware of any shareholder pressure for change, nor had it received any offers for the firm. &quot;We are not aware of any bids or any decision to restructure,&quot; the spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>Rembrandt and Liberty were also keeping tight-lipped.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't comment on areas where we have investments,&quot; a Rembrandt spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Gold Fields has been a centre of speculation for years but recent rumours have seen the stock jump from 124 rand on October 21, hitting a year high of 153.50 on Thursday, before easing slightly to 147.50 rand at 1110 GMT on Friday.</p>
<p>Analysts said there was nothing especially new about the current crop of rumours which have named a host of suspects including U.S. firm Newmont, Gencor, Anglo American Corp of South Africa Ltd and Randgold and Exploration Co Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been rumours around for a long time. It just depends what direction you listen in as to who is trying to take them over,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Earlier Gold Fields deputy chairman Alan Wright told Business Day newspaper that the increase in the share price was probably attributable to the group's unhedged policy which meant it would benefit from a higher rand gold price following the latest fall in the currency.</p>
<p>Analysts said local firms did stand to benefit from the rand gold price. &quot;The rand gold price means the local gold firms will be in for a good (fourth) quarter,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>However, the gold index was down 10.8 points to 1721.5 at 1000 GMT as the sickly bullion price slipped below $380 an ounce, pulling some overseas investors out of the shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The bears are firmly in control at the moment. There isn't anything pushing investors or the funds in North America to get into golds at this stage,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
