<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159611" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire parliament votes break in ties, Tutsi purge.</title>
<headline>Zaire parliament votes break in ties, Tutsi purge.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's transitional parliament has voted to sever diplomatic relations with neighbours Rwanda, Burundi and Uganda and has called for a purge of ethnic Tutsis from the army, state companies and public administration.</p>
<p>State radio said on Friday the assembly voted for the steps, which take the form of recommendations to the government, at the end of a marathon debate in which Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo accused the three eastern neighbours of waging war on Zaire.</p>
<p>The government was meeting on Friday with the measures, overwhelmingly approved by parliament late on Thursday, on its agenda, government sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Parliament as the legislative organ has done its duty. It has given instructions to the government. It's up to the government, the executive, to study the applicability of these measures,&quot; one parliamentary source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Parliament spoke only of &quot;aggressor countries&quot; but Kengo has accused Rwanda, Burundi and Uganda by name of waging war against Zaire in its volatile eastern refugee zone where Zairean troops are battling ethnic Tutsi Banyamulenge rebels.</p>
<p>The fighting has put to flight hundreds of thousands of Hutu refugees from Rwanda and Burundi, who were camped in eastern Zaire. Zairean civilians have joined the exodus.</p>
<p>&quot;The High Council of the Republic (parliament) has recommended the suspension of diplomatic relations with the aggressors of Zaire,&quot; state radio said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has also demanded dismissal of all Tutsis from public companies, the civil service and the army.&quot;</p>
<p>The radio said parliament had also recommended a suspension of payment of arrears owed to the International Monetary Fund &quot;to help support the war effort&quot;.</p>
<p>President Mobutu Sese Seko, who seized power in 1965, has been in Switzerland since August after prostate cancer surgery.</p>
<p>Mobutu, who ruled virtually unchallenged until 1990 when pressure within Zaire and from foreign partners forced him to bow to calls for democratic change, declared a state of emergency in the east last weekend.</p>
<p>But the government and Kengo, whose father was Polish and whose mother was half Zairean and reputedly half Rwandan Tutsi, have taken the lead in handling the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will not undertake any negotiation, will not participate in any regional conference while a part of national territory is occupied by foreign forces,&quot; Kengo told Thursday's emergency parliamentary session.</p>
<p>&quot;This war which the combined forces of Uganda, Burundi and Rwanda are waging against Zaire has brought to broad daylight Rwanda's intention not to welcome on its territory its nationals living in Zaire and to pursue its insane plan of annexing a part of our territory.&quot;</p>
<p>In Nairobi, a Kenyan official said a summit of at least seven African states in Kenya on November 5 would focus on the war in eastern Zaire. David Kikaya of the foreign ministry said Kenya had invited Zaire but had no official response yet.</p>
<p>Tutsi-led Rwanda had earlier accused Zaire of letting Hutu hardliners blamed for the 1994 genocide of Tutis in Rwanda use its territory to launch attacks on Rwandan territory.</p>
<p>The fighting in eastern Zaire and Mobutu's illness have feuled speculation that the sprawling and chaotic Central African nation could disintegrate.</p>
<p>Zaire's sometimes bloody democratic transition, repeatedly extended, is due to be completed by July 1997 -- with Mobutu among those expected to stand in multi-party presidential elections. Legislative elections are also planned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
