<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159791" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria c.bank seen capping downside for lev.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria c.bank seen capping downside for lev.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian lev eased to 242-244 per dollar in light morning trade from Thursday's close of 242-243 with the central bank supporting the lev near 243 to prevent a fall after a interest rate cut, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is calm and dollar demand is low despite the second cut of the main interest rate in as many weeks,&quot; a commercial bank dealer said.</p>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) has been offering small foreign currency volumes around 243 levs per dollar to final clients since opening, dealers said.</p>
<p>Central bank officials declined comment.</p>
<p>Dealers said they did not expect the lower central interest rate (CIR) to cause a sharp lev fall.</p>
<p>&quot;The BNB will try to support the lev through active dollar sales amid low foreign currency demand as most financial inctitutions have already squared forex positions after the previous rate cut two weeks ago,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>The BNB last night said it cut the monthly CIR to 15 percent from 20 percent or 180 percent annually from 240, to take effect on Monday, due to slowing consumer price inflation in the past two weeks and a rise in its forex reserves. @</p>
<p>BNB foreign exchange reserves stood at $506 million at the end of September. The BNB has not yet announced this month's level of reserves.</p>
<p>After the CIR was cut to 20 percent monthly from 25 percent on October 18 the lev slumped to a record low of 256-258 per dollar due to a rise of foreign currency demand because financial institutions began to square forex positions they have pared under the previous record high CIR.</p>
<p>Between September 23 and October 17 when the CIR stood at its all-time high of 25 percent monthly or 300 percent annually the lev traded fairly stable between 218-222 per dollar. -- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
