<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="15973" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY State Electric to challenge rate delay.</title>
<headline>NY State Electric to challenge rate delay.</headline>
<dateline>BINGHAMTON, N.Y. 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York State Electric &amp; Gas Corp said it will challenge Monday's New York State Public Service Commission order, which put on hold, through December 30, 1996, plans for the utility to increase electric rates this year and again next year.</p>
<p>&quot;We will file a petition for rehearing on this matter and take whatever additional action may be necessary to ensure the terms of the (rate agreement reached last year) are upheld,&quot; the utility said in a statement released late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Spokesman Clayton Ellis said the order means there will be no further consideration of the rates this year.  </p>
<p>&quot;It is difficult to understand the reasons for the PSC delaying a rate increase it approved only a year ago,&quot; the utility said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're confused by it,&quot; Ellis added, explaining the commission still has to approve the rate design to implement the agreed to rate increases.</p>
<p>&quot;Plans for implementing the increase have undergone extensive review since January, and a final plan was issued for PSC action three months ago,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We fully expect the PSC to honor commitments it made under the existing agreement and to approve the second- and third-year increases.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the terms of the agreement approved last year, NYSEG said, it was to have received a $45.3 million, or 2.8 percent, annual electric rate increase on August 1, 1996, and a $45.5 million, or 2.7 percent, electric rate increase on August 1, 1997. NYSEG received a $45.1 million, or 2.9 percent, electric rate increase on August 1, 1995.</p>
<p>It said the proposed rate design for years two and three of the electric rate agreement includes a price freeze for about 1,600 industrial and high load factor commercial and public authority customers; an average increase of 2.8 percent for most other nonresidential customers; and an average increase of 3.7 percent for residential customers, mostly collected through an increase in the basic monthly service charge. -- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BINGHAMTON, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
