<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159710" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgarian refinery maintains steady output.</title>
<headline>Bulgarian refinery maintains steady output.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's biggest oil refinery, Neftohim, which supplies the whole domestic market, plans to process 600,000 tonnes of crude this month and a total of six million tonnes this year, plant officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Neftohim's executive director Nikola Karagyozov said production, which totalled some 630,000 tonnes last month, was steady and daily refining volumes were about 20,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that now we meet 100 percent of the needs of the domestic market,&quot; Karagyozov told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>He said part of the oil deliveries this month would come from Rosbulneft, a Bulgarian-Russian joint venture between Neftohim and Rosneft.</p>
<p>He declined to name the other suppliers.</p>
<p>Karagyozov said the plant processed 5.4 million tonnes of crude in the first 10 months of the year.</p>
<p>Neftohim's initial plans were to raise total output this year by 310,000 tonnes to 7.65 million tonnes. But officials said the plant was expected to refine a total of six million tonnes this year.</p>
<p>Foreign firms, including South Korean companies, have offered to build a catalytic reformer, which is crucial for the enlargement of the plant's output, officials said.</p>
<p>The 31-year-old plant at the Black Sea port of Bourgas is now Bulgaria's only operating refinery after the sale of the Pleven-based plant Plama earlier this year. Last November Plama suspended production due to cash shortages.</p>
<p>Plama's new owner, Bulgaria's Euroenergy, said it planned to resume output in November.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
