<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159789" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Nov 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Nov 1.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Financial bottlenecks in the economy were caused, in part, by the gap between the rise in real prices, triggered by the higher costs of energy, and the prices &quot;adjusted&quot; for political and social reasons.</p>
<p>- Construction company  Impact SA will join in bourse trading next week.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- The municipalities of Constanta and Brasov will launch municipal bonds on the international market. The planned raising totals $300 million.</p>
<p>AZI</p>
<p>- Sweden's Ericsson plans to install a fibre optic network extending to 1,800 km in Moldova.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- The leu currency continues to depreciate. Retail currency shops traded the leu at around 4,300 to the dollar on Thursday.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Romania's 1997 wheat crop is expected to drop from this year's level as sowing work was not completed on time.</p>
<p>VOCEA ROMANIEI</p>
<p>- Ruling Party of Social Democracy has denied media reports that fuel prices are expected to rise before end-1996.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- The Central Electoral Bureau has banned the press and local observers from attending the ballot count. &quot;Preparation for rigging elections is quietly moving on,&quot; it says.</p>
<p>- Although he is not yet Prime Minister, Radu Vasile, of the National Peasant Party, says his party would try to change the central bank management after the polls.</p>
<p>COTIDIANUL</p>
<p>- &quot;All sing, laugh and dance in Bucharest,&quot; says a report on the Democratic Convention bloc's last rally on Thursday.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- The ex-director of France's DST secret services says Mihai Caraman, who led Romania's SIE counter-intelligence services under Prime Minister Petre Roman, was the one who gave away Hernu as a French spy-minister.</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- The newspaper prints numbers for telephone hotlines to denounce fraud and irregularities at the polling stattions.</p>
<p>- Sunday night will be busy for Romanian state television - first projections aired after midnight, followed by talk shows with leading commentators, around 1.15 a.m. local studios (Iasi, Cluj, Timisoara and Craiova) will comment on regional voting patterns, followed by dispatches on how Romanians voted in Israel, Hungary, France, Belgium, Germany and Italy.</p>
<p>- The top three contenders for president according to the IRSOP projections will arrive at TVR state television studios around 1.30 a.m. Political analysts will discuss the projections and leading personalities will offer opinions.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Newspaper publishes a list of possible irregularities which might be noticed at polling stations, saying voters should report them to the head of the polling station.</p>
<p>- Exit polls cannot be broadcast before Sunday midnight, says CNA media regulator. Opinion polls cannot be printed 48 hours before the polls and on the day of voting.</p>
<p>- Observers and journalists can watch conscripts voting following approval from military barracks officers in command.</p>
<p>- There are 15,117 polling stations in Romania, with 13,490 monitors accredited by local non-government organisations.</p>
<p>- The number of Romanian voters is 17,253,093.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- On Sunday night from midnight to 3 a.m. local Romanian state television (TVR) will broadcast the most dramatic show since the revolution, says the newspaper.</p>
<p>- &quot;A deadly bore,&quot; writes Ion Cristoiu in his editorial about the campaign on state television. Cristoiu says last night's marathon show with the 16 presidential contenders confirmed his headline.</p>
<p>- Hernu' spy file was passed over to France by a member of Romania's secret services in 1992.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- Codename &quot;Dinu&quot; -- the poisoned agent, writes the newspaper on the way in which French former defence minister Charles Hernu was manipulated by France's secret services.</p>
<p>TINERETUL LIBER</p>
<p>- Nearly two million Romanians aged 18 to 26 are expected to vote on Sunday. Where does young vote go, asks the daily.</p>
<p>JURNALUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Hospitals and medical clinics will work round the clock on Sunday to treat &quot;emotions&quot; caused on voting day, paper says.</p>
<p>- Let there be ink for the stamps, because we shall learn how to vote, the paper says, explaining how to vote with rubber stamps provided at polling stations. -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
