<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159971" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan subway sect leave their inner sanctum.</title>
<headline>Japan subway sect leave their inner sanctum.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>KAMIKU ISSHIKI, Japan 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some smiling, some covering their faces, members of the doomsday cult accused of the Tokyo subway gas attack on Friday finally left the inner sanctum where police say the crime was planned.</p>
<p>A sad litter of personal belongings and the debris of a cult that went wrong greeted journalists when they were allowed for the first time into the lair in the foothills of Mount Fuji.</p>
<p>The three-storey, dormitory-like building in remote dairy farming country was taken over by bankruptcy officials winding up the affairs of Aum Shinri Kyo (Supreme Truth Sect).</p>
<p>The group faces hundreds of millions of dollars in claims from victims of the March 20, 1995, sarin nerve gas attack in Tokyo's subway system.</p>
<p>The attack killed 12 people and made thousands ill.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the end of us. This was our symbol,&quot; sect spokesman Hiroshi Araki told dozens of reporters who picked through monk-like cells where top sect followers lived with their guru Shoko Asahara.</p>
<p>Police, who raided the building two months after the attack, arrested Asahara hiding in a secret room between the second and third floors.</p>
<p>He and his top followers are on trial for murder in what prosecutors say was a plot to bring down the Japanese government and install Asahara as the nation's leader.</p>
<p>About 30 sect members spent the last hours in what was called &quot;Satyam 6&quot; conducting an overnight prayer vigil.</p>
<p>The sect, which once had about 10,000 members and tens of millions of dollars in assets, has dwindled to only several hundred who remain faithful to their leader.</p>
<p>After ending the prayers, the last group got into cars, trucks, including one equipped with a mobile crane, and vans crammed with clothing and other personal belongings.</p>
<p>Each vehicle was stopped and inspected by police before being allowed to leave.</p>
<p>Some vehicle occupants smiled at the horde of reporters and photographers but many more, including several weeping, buried their faces in their hands.</p>
<p>&quot;We never thought this day would come. This was our home for seven years,&quot; Araki said.</p>
<p>When the final vehicle departed, local authorities in the building unfurled a banner proclaiming the end to what they said had been a nightmare for local residents.</p>
<p>&quot;Finally, they are all gone,&quot; said Toru Egawa, head of a residents' group which had fought for the cult's removal ever since they arrived. &quot;Our earnest prayers have been answered.&quot;</p>
<p>The unfurling of the banner signalled a rush into the complex by journalists seeking any new insights into the sect's operations.</p>
<p>There was little to find after months of police work and a last cleanup by the sect's diehard followers.</p>
<p>Thousands of posters, booklets and cassette tapes -- all with the image or voice of Asahara on them -- were strewn around.</p>
<p>Clothing, a rag doll, cassette players, the belongings of sect followers who walked away months ago, littered the concrete building where Asahara once held court predicting the future to the slavish attention of his devotees.</p>
<p>&quot;We never want to see their like again,&quot; said Egawa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KAMIKU ISSHIKI, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
