<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="159944" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks seen down next week on risk concerns.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks seen down next week on risk concerns.</headline>
<byline>James Mclean</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks are expected to fall next week amid political uncertainty ahead of a November 17 general election, a perceived increase in market risk, and a lack of fresh positive news, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;I would have thought trade will be very light, there won't be a lot of company results and a lot of people are sitting back waiting,&quot; said Richard Henderson, head of research at Krungthai Thanakit Plc.</p>
<p>The SET Index closed at 912.52 points Friday after falling 25.78 ponts over the week on sluggish trade worth 13.16 billion baht.</p>
<p>Trading in the latter part of the week was dominated by concerns surrounding liquidity in the property sector which heightened Wednesday after developer Somprasong Land Plc's president was released on bail by police after being charged with fraud.</p>
<p>Analysts said some investors now perceived Thailand to be carrying a higher degree of systemic financial risk.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's a country risk concern that is probably an overreaction,&quot; said Bob McMillen, head of investment banking at General Finance, &quot;But I think most of the bad news is out there already.&quot;</p>
<p>Kanjanee Kangwanpornsiri, head of research at Thai Fuji Finance and Securities, said she believed there were now two schools of thought developing among foreign investors.</p>
<p>&quot;One group believe the economic fundamentals are still sound and they are waiting for the general election and hoping the outcome will be satisfactory and will then buy the market,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;But there is another group that believes the economic fundamentals don't look so bright.&quot;</p>
<p>Figures released Thursday by the central bank showed the current account deficit had narrowed in August, but the trade deficit had widened.</p>
<p>The Commerce Ministry on Friday said the year-on-year rate of inflation grew at its slowest rate in three years in October to 4.3 percent against 4.6 percent in September and 6.6 percent last October.</p>
<p>Kanjanee said investors were expected to be sidelined next week based on the political uncertainty over what type of government may emerge from the polls.</p>
<p>But she added that the market offered good opportunities for long term investors or for speculators betting on a positive election outcome and a year end rally.</p>
<p>Other analysts said bargain hunting might be encouraged with some key stocks looking reasonably cheap.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
