<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160099" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC agency says welfare poses big budget challenge.</title>
<headline>NYC agency says welfare poses big budget challenge.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City's new Independent Budget Office has said that while Albany is in the driver's seat on welfare reform, the new federal welfare reforms pose &quot;tremendous budgetary challenges&quot; for the city.</p>
<p>The fledgling agency, set up earlier this year under the city charter to serve the same sort of functions as the Congressional Budget Office, said little effect will be seen in the 1998 budget, in a report released on Thursday.</p>
<p>But after that, costs could skyrocket.</p>
<p>Citing  uncertainity over the program Republican Gov. George Pataki will propose, the Independent Budget Office gave a wide range of estimates, saying from 1997 to 2002 the city might have to spend from $200 million to $4.3 billion more than budgeted.</p>
<p>How much extra that the city might have to spend also varies sharply with changes in economic conditions and how welfare recipients respond to the new law, it said.</p>
<p>New York City is particularly vulnerable under the new rules as it has so many of the state's immigrants and poor, who account for about 66 percent of the state's  caseload.</p>
<p>The Republican Pataki Administration has said it likely will submit its detailed new welfare plan shortly after the November 5 polls. In mid-October, it sent a brief outline to Washington, to ensure that it would qualify for the full block grant, though by doing so it started the clock running on new federal time limits, like a five-year lifetime maximum.</p>
<p>The city will bear the fiscal risk if caseloads rise as it will have to pay for what the new agency called &quot;huge&quot; new work and childcare programs required by the new federal rules.</p>
<p>New York State is expected to get a bigger block grant, estimated at $2.4 billion, in the first year of the new law.</p>
<p>But City Hall sources fear that the state might be tempted to use the first-year surplus, estimated at $300 million to $500 million, to help close budget gaps instead of investing the windfall in programs to help people find jobs.</p>
<p>The new budget office highlighted the risk that the city will get less state aid than it needs. &quot;The overall costs to the city under the (federal) Act over the next six years greatly exceed the city's share of the new Temporary Assistance for Needy Families block grant under all scenarios considered,&quot; said Douglas Criscitello, in prepared remarks.</p>
<p>City Council Speaker Peter Vallone has asked Pataki to apply for a Food Stamps waiver, saying failing to do so could cost the city up to $168 million over the next three years.</p>
<p>Under the new federal welfare rules, unemployed people from 18 to 50 years old, who are not caring for minor children, only get Food Stamps for three months within a 36-month period. But these rules can be waived in areas where unemployment exceeds 10 percent, or there are insufficient jobs for welfare recipients, Vallone wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;If local economies do not create jobs for all participants in the Food Stamp program, we should not allow the result of that failure to be the loss of Food Stamp benefits for those who are actively looking for employement.&quot;</p>
<p>The deadline for applying for a waiver from the Food Stamps program, which is paid for by the federal goverment, is November 22, and a New York State budget official last month said that the state has no plans to ask for a waiver.</p>
<p>The spokesman on Thursday, noting that there are no areas in the state where unemployment exceeds 10 percent, said &quot;In a couple of weeks the governor will come out with his welfare proposal and all the broad issues will be addressed.&quot;</p>
<p>Pataki has said he planned to call a special legislative session in December to act on his new welfare bill.</p>
<p>One of the issues the governor's staff is trying to resolve includes how much control to give individual counties over their own programs. There is a risk in giving too much power to the counties, as sharp differences might influence where people choose to live.</p>
<p>The Westchester County Department of Social Services this week estimated that under the new federal welfare rules, homeless people stand to lose the most.</p>
<p>For example, a homeless family of three, who will have to include the shelter allowence as income when computing Food Stamps, will see this benefit drop by an average of $122 a month. A homeless single person will see their benefits cut by $57. But a family of three who is not homeless will only see the average Food Stamp benefit fall $14 and a person who collects Home Relief, a state program, will see their benefit drop by $7 on average.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
