<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160021" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton wants campaign finance reform; Dole tours.</title>
<headline>Clinton wants campaign finance reform; Dole tours.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton tried to minimise damage from late-breaking political finance charges on Friday but Bob Dole pressed the attack, buoyed by signs Clinton's poll leads were shrinking as the race entered its final weekend.</p>
<p>At a campaign stop in California, Clinton finally addressed allegations the White House has encouraged improper Democratic Party fund-raising among Asian business interests. He said the U.S. system has forced both parties into over-intensive fund-raising and reforms were long overdue.</p>
<p>He conceded no wrongdoing, claimed the Republicans had thwarted his earlier efforts to tighten campaign finance laws and said reforms should include bans on political donations both from foreign-owned U.S. firms and non-American citizens.</p>
<p>The issue of election financing has gathered force in the waning days before next Tuesday's election, and a new Reuters daily tracking poll suggested it was now hurting Clinton.</p>
<p>The poll of 1,200 likely voters released on Friday showed Clinton's lead was just 5.5 percentage points at 42 percent to 36.5 for Dole. Five days ago Clinton had a 13-point lead.</p>
<p>Reform Party candidate Ross Perot, who has also hit Clinton hard on the fund-raising issue, had 8.4 percent with 11.2 percent undecided. The poll's margin of error is 3 points.</p>
<p>Dole, who commenced a marathon 96-hour cross-country campaign finale in Ohio, also got some good news in polls of states that will play key roles in Tuesday's balloting.</p>
<p>He had opened a five-point lead, 47 percent to 42 percent, in Texas according to a poll published on Friday in the Dallas Morning News and the Houston Chronicle.</p>
<p>And in Georgia, one of four Southern states Clinton carried in 1992, a survey of 925 likely voters published in the Atlanta Journal-Constitution showed Clinton's lead had shrunk to three points from 15 points a month ago.</p>
<p>The campaign finance controversy centres on a senior Democratic party fund-raiser who raised hundreds of thousands of dollars from powerful Asian business interests while also paying regular visits to the White House, which has refused to discuss the visits in detail. Dole, Perot and others say this raises questions of illegal foreign influence peddlling.</p>
<p>Clinton ignored the specifics of these charges but tried to defuse the issue by saying both his Democratic Party and Dole's Republicans had been force to raise hundreds of millions of dollars to run effective campaigns.</p>
<p>&quot;Special interests still have too much say&quot; he said in his speech in Santa Barbara, California. &quot;Everybody knows the problems with campaign money: there's too much of it; it takes too much time to raise; and it raises too many questions.&quot;</p>
<p>Dole, launching his gruelling final campaign run in Columbus, Ohio, wryly questioned Clinton's motivation for urging reform less than five days before the general election.</p>
<p>&quot;The administration is in the midst of a growing scandal involving a flow of foreign money into the Democratic Party that bought access to the White House. So now Bill Clinton decides to talk about campaign finance reform,&quot; Dole said.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have seen from this administration in the last few weeks is the reason we need campaign finance reform.&quot;</p>
<p>After a televised send-off by former Presidents George Bush and Gerald Ford in Columbus, the 73-year-old Dole started a 96-hour &quot;victory tour&quot; slated to allow only &quot;shower stops&quot; as it roars through 14 states in four days.</p>
<p>It began in the must-win heartland state of Ohio and would wind through the Midwest and the western Plains states and California before landing him in his boyhood home of Russell, Kansas, to vote on Election Day, Nov. 5.</p>
<p>&quot;How do you feel?,&quot; Dole was asked as he left his hotel early on Friday for a rally at Capital University. &quot;Feel great -- not so sure about tomorrow morning,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have four big days,&quot; Dole said. &quot;We're going to win this election ... this is a fight for America, to elect a president we can trust, and one who will give us an economy that will give us hope.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
