<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160197" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: No conclusion yet on Saudi bombing - Perry.</title>
<headline>No conclusion yet on Saudi bombing - Perry.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States has not yet determined who was responsible for the June 25 bombing in Saudi Arabia that killed 19 U.S. airmen, U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have reached no conclusions about who was responsible for this,&quot; Perry told reporters in response to questions on a Washington Post report that Saudi authorities had arrested 40 people and were convinced that Iran backed a broad conspiracy in the attack.  </p>
<p>Perry refused to discuss details of the investigation of the truck bombing at Khobar Towers housing complex in Dhahran being conducted by the Saudis and the U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation, but said he had made clear to Saudi officials that they must cooperate fully with Washington in the case.</p>
<p>&quot;This investigation is still under way and I cannot comment on the status of this or any other investigation still being conducted,&quot; he said during a news conference with South Korean Defence Minister Kim Dong-jin.</p>
<p>Published reports have indicated that the United States was not satisfied with Saudi cooperation in connection with the June bombing and another last Nov. 13 that killed five Americans and two Indians in Riyadh. Perry was asked if he was satisfied with that cooperation.</p>
<p>&quot;In my discussions with the senior Saudi officials, I have made very clear the importance to our defence departments of full cooperation in this investigation,&quot; he said. &quot;They have promised us at the highest levels of the Saudi government full cooperation. Any further comments on that would have to come from the FBI.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
