<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160107" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT Dec wheat ends up on fund buying, Mar set low.</title>
<headline>CBOT Dec wheat ends up on fund buying, Mar set low.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT wheat futures closed mixed with nearby December higher on fund buying, traders said.</p>
<p>March ended higher but a new low was set early in that contract at $3.65-1/2 per bushel, down from the previous low of $3.67 set Thursday.</p>
<p>LIT America bought three million bushels of December, Rosenthal Collins bought 1.5 million December and Lehman Brothers bought 1.5 million December, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders said the late recovery in the nearbys was tied to signals the market was technically oversold and due for a bounce.</p>
<p>The short term nine day relative strength index (RSI) for December closed at 24.3 points, well below the 30 level which is an area generally considered an oversold mark.</p>
<p>Traders said the stiff competition worldwide for wheat export business and renewed concern about the karnal bunt fungus continued to limit market rallies.</p>
<p>There was news Thursday that karnal bunt had been found in some Tennessee wheat which triggered concerns the fungus might surface in other soft red winter wheat areas.</p>
<p>Wheat closed 3-1/2 cents a bushel higher to 4-3/4 lower, with December up 3-1/2 at $3.74-3/4.</p>
<p>&quot;Karnal bunt didn't help wheat any,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds.</p>
<p>Declines in soybeans also continued to limit attempts to rally the wheat market.</p>
<p>Wheat futures volume was estimated at 13,000 contracts, down from 19,782 Thursday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In wheat options FIMAT Futures bought 1,000 March $4.30 calls at 1-1/2 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Wheat options volume was estimated at 5,000 contracts, down from 7,089 Thursday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
