<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160189" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dean Witter tells MSRB of contribution &quot;error&quot;.</title>
<headline>Dean Witter tells MSRB of contribution &quot;error&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dean Witter Reynolds Inc said Friday it refunded a political contribution that an employee made to a North Carolina official earlier this year, in what could bar the firm from negotiated bond underwritings with that state for two years.</p>
<p>&quot;The contribution was an inadvertent error,&quot; Suzanne Platenic, vice president of media relations at Dean Witter, said in a telephone interview with Reuters. &quot;We have audit procedures in place and these audit procedures caught this error.&quot;</p>
<p>Platenic would not comment on whether the firm will refrain from negotiated underwritings with North Carolina state authorities as a result of the contribution.</p>
<p>She said, however, the contribution &quot;had nothing to do with the municipal finance department or municipal finance employees&quot; at Dean Witter.</p>
<p>Dean Witter disclosed the contribution in a quarterly report to the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board as required by the board's &quot;pay-to-play&quot; rule G-37. Quarterly reports were due at MSRB on October 31.</p>
<p>Dean Witter's report, obtained by Reuters, says the firm got a &quot;refund&quot; in September of a &quot;contribution&quot; that one of its employees inadvertently made last quarter to a North Carolina official.</p>
<p>The report does not identify the state official or who at Dean Witter made the contribution.</p>
<p>Rule G-37 bars muni dealers that make contributions to issuer clients from doing negotiated bond business for two years with those governments.</p>
<p>Employees may be covered by the rule even if they are not primarily involved in muni market activities, the MSRB says. If they solicit municipal securities business they may be covered, MSRB says.</p>
<p>Brian Devlin, senior vice president for Dean Witter, said of the contribution, &quot;It had nothing to do with the municipal division. It was another area of the firm. Someone inadvertently made a contribution to North Carolina which we felt could have violated rule G-37.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We asked that the contribution be returned, and it was, from the North Carolina official. We made an amended second quarter filing reflecting the fact that there had been a contribution and that the check had in fact been sent back,&quot; Devlin said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Christopher Taylor, MSRB executive director, said refunding a contribution does not excuse a firm from the G-37 ban.</p>
<p>&quot;So what?&quot; Taylor said. &quot;The contribution (may) still result in a ban unless the National Association of Securities Dealers grants a waiver,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dean Witter is not the only major firm that reported compliance problems with rule G-37 this week, according to the quarterly filings on view at MSRB's annex in Alexandria, Va.</p>
<p>Rauscher Pierce Refsnes Inc will not do negotiated bond underwriting for the town of Azle, Texas in the coming months because of a $150 contribution by an employee before that employee came on board at the firm, a company official said.</p>
<p>Rule G-37's ban on business applies even to contributions made by employees before they were hired.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
