<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160296" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bombay shares fall on end-of-account selling.</title>
<headline>Bombay shares fall on end-of-account selling.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices closed lower on Friday at Bombay bourses on end-of-account selling after the market opened on a promising note, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said position-squaring and lack of follow-up support spoiled the upsurge which was driven by better first half results announced by top firms.</p>
<p>&quot;The results were very positive...better than our expectations,&quot; said trader Ramnik Parikh. &quot;But, there were few buyers.&quot;</p>
<p>The 30-share Bombay Stock Exchange index ended 15.21 points lower at 3,148.57 after rising to 3,190.82.</p>
<p>The 50-share National Stock Exchange (NSE) index dropped 2.61 points to 906.68. The net traded value was 9.8 billion rupees in 48.57 million shares.</p>
<p>The 500-stock CRISIL index eased 2.44 points, or 0.40 percent, to a provisional 604.55.</p>
<p>TISCO finished 4.50 rupees lower at 176.75 after hitting 186.50. The steel firm said late Thursday its net profit went up 25 percent to 2.52 billion rupees after providing 373.5 million for new minimum tax against nil in the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>The share closed 2.8 rupees down at 178.75 on the NSE.</p>
<p>Truck maker TELCO rose 2.0 rupees to 413 at the BSE. After the market closed the company said its net profit jumped 46 percent to 3.3 billion rupees in the six months to September 30, 1996.</p>
<p>ACC said its board will meet on November 26 to finalise the six-month results. The share fell 21 rupees to 1,508.25.</p>
<p>Reliance fell 8.0 rupees to 194.50, Bajaj Auto 7.75 to 948.50, ITC 5.0 to 299 and Grasim 5.0 to 414.25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
