<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160708" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli general off peace team for now.</title>
<headline>Israeli general off peace team for now.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Israeli general who met leaders of the main opposition Labour party behind the government's back was removed from Israel's peace negotiating team with the PLO on Friday pending an investigation.</p>
<p>But in a statement, the Defence Ministry said Major-General Oren Shahor would remain Israel's so-called chief coordinator of government activities in the West Bank and Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>&quot;In parallel, the defence minister and prime minister decided (he) would be suspended from his post as head of the Israeli team in the talks on civilian issues with the Palestinian Authority until the end of an investigation of (his) meetings with leaders of the opposition,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Labour reaction was swift and harsh.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems to me the prime minister (Benjamin Netanyahu) has lost his mind. It reminds me of his tape, of the tunnel. This man cannot be the prime minister of Israel,&quot; former Labour minister Yossi Beilin told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>In 1993, Netanyahu admitted adultery after he said someone called his wife threatening to release a videotape. Last month Netanyahu allowed a second entrance to be opened to a tourist tunnel near Moslem holy sites in Jerusalem spurring Israeli- Palestinian clashes in which more than 70 people died.</p>
<p>&quot;He is throwing rocks at a glass house because he himself met army generals without any special permit in a private way,&quot; Beilin said of Netanyahu, who led parliament's opposition until he ousted Labour in May elections.</p>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian negotiators discussing civilian issues related to implementing Israel's long-delayed troop withdrawal from the West Bank town of Hebron have said they have nearly wrapped up a deal.</p>
<p>But the two sides still differ over security arrangments in the flashpoint town, home to 100,000 Palestinians and 400 Jewish settlers.</p>
<p>Shahor drew political fire after an Israeli newspaper published a front-page photo on Thursday showing him leaving the home of former Labour Prime Minister Shimon Peres and reported he also had met Beilin. The general had been a peace negotiator under Peres.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's office said the prime minister had not known about Shahor's meetings with Peres.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Shahor confirmed the meetings but said the general had not asked for official permission since they were merely social calls and had no connection to the negotiations with the Palestinians.</p>
<p>The affair underscored the traditionally close relations between Israel's political leaders and its generals.</p>
<p>Defending Shahor earlier on Friday, Peres told Israel Radio: &quot;Since the establishment of Israel, generals have met with civilians -- from the opposition and the government. When I was prime minister I knew that General Shahor met with other friends from the opposition. It didn't bother me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
