<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160882" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: UN says no final decision on east Zaire evacuation.</title>
<headline>UN says no final decision on east Zaire evacuation.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. refugee agency said on Friday that it had not taken a final decision to evacuate its staff members from the eastern Zairean town of Goma, scene of gun battles between Zairean troops and ethnic Tutsi fighters.</p>
<p>Spokeswoman Ruth Marshall also told a Geneva briefing that her agency had no confirmation that refugees were fleeing Katale camp, home to 210,000 people, 45 km (28 miles) north of Goma.</p>
<p>In Goma, a World Food Programe spokeswoman said the entire population of Katale had fled.</p>
<p>But Marshall said: &quot;Our staff in Goma cannot confirm that refugees are on the run from Katale.&quot;</p>
<p>Half a million Rwandan and Burundian Hutu refugees are on the run in eastern Zaire. Aid workers speak of total chaos.</p>
<p>Reports are conflicting because Western aid workers in Goma town are holed up in offices in the centre or houses and have little means of finding out what is going on in the terrain.</p>
<p>&quot;It's complete chaos in Goma. There are checkpoints on the streets and lots of people with arms,&quot; said spokesman Rolin Wavre of the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC).</p>
<p>ICRC had not decided to evacuate seven Swiss staff members stranded in a house in Goma. &quot;The fact that we can't work is not because of fighting but because of looting,&quot; Wavre said.</p>
<p>Unruly Zairean soldiers have seized aid agency vehicles including six from ICRC and looted at least one agency office in the past two days.</p>
<p>Goma region is home to 700,000 Rwandan Hutus who fled in fear of reprisal for 1994's Hutu-led genocide of Tutsis.</p>
<p>UNHCR officials on Thursday announced plans to evacuate their 14 international staff members in Goma.</p>
<p>But Marshall said the situation had calmed down. &quot;No final decision has been made to evacuate people. We're looking at this hour by hour, but our staff would like to stay as long as they can,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Bukavu, about 120 km (75 miles) south of Goma, was the scene of some of the fiercest fighting in eastern Zaire and the Roman Catholic archbishop Christophe Munzihirwa was killed on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Marshall said UNHCR was trying to confirm reports of an ambush on vehicles carrying family members of local UNHCR field officers in Bukavu by unidentified attackers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>ICRC's Wavre said Zairean Red Cross volunteers in Bukavu had buried at least 100 dead collected from the streets last week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
