<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160826" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Court reserves judgment in Danish EU dispute.</title>
<headline>Court reserves judgment in Danish EU dispute.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>A court setting the boundaries for a legal challenge to Denmark's European Union membership adjourned on Friday without giving a ruling.</p>
<p>It said it would deliver a judgment next week, on a day to be announced later. The case was brought by 11 Danes who say assignment of national authority to EU institutions contravenes the country's constitution.</p>
<p>At Friday's hearing lawyers for the challengers asked for transcripts of cabinet and parliamentary debates and decisions dating back throughout Denmark's EU membership to be entered as evidence.</p>
<p>The government, which wants debate confined to events subsequent to the 1992 Maastricht acccord, said that assembling and examining such a mountain of documents would delay proceedings until the year 2010 and was in any case unjustified.</p>
<p>&quot;The appellants are simply trying to go on a fishing expedition,&quot; government lawyer Karsten Hagel-Soerensen told the court.</p>
<p>Ultimately at stake in the case, expected to last at least two years, is whether Denmark can carry on as a member of the EU under existing terms, or must choose between renegotiating membership and attempting to amend the constitution.</p>
<p>Lawyers say that whoever wins the opening procedural stage will have an advantage when the substantive case comes to court next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
