<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160950" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain's Fergie once talked of suicide - report.</title>
<headline>Britain's Fergie once talked of suicide - report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Duchess of York once told a confidant that she would have committed suicide but for her small daughters, Princesses Beatrice and Eugenie, the Daily Mail reported on Friday.</p>
<p>It quoted Dr Allan Starkie, who has written a controversial book about the flame-haired duchess, as saying she had been distraught and stranded between her husband Prince Andrew and her American financial adviser and lover John Bryan.</p>
<p>He said the duchess told him: &quot;If it weren't for the children, the only answer would be to kill myself.&quot;</p>
<p>The duchess, now divorced from Queen Elizabeth's second son, attempted to block publication of Starkie's book &quot;Fergie: Her Secret Life&quot;, but she gave up her legal battle when she had to put up a 500,000 pound ($814,200) surety and faced cross-examination in court.</p>
<p>The duchess, popularly known as &quot;Fergie&quot; from her maiden name Sarah Ferguson, married Andrew in 1986. The marriage broke down in 1992 and the couple divorced earlier this year.</p>
<p>The Daily Mail, which is serialising the book, quoted Starkie as saying the free-spending duchess was a woman &quot;driven by fear and lust&quot;.</p>
<p>Starkie said he saw her transformed &quot;into a woman no longer quite in control, drinking and smoking too much.</p>
<p>&quot;At night she would down a handful of sizeable vodkas, then take to the wine. Her cigarette butts littered the house despite her desperate efforts to give up... She looked as though her soul had gone.&quot;</p>
<p>Starkie wrote: &quot;The Duchess is very complicated and very wilful. But the bottom line is I feel very sorry for her and wish her well.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
