<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160912" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary says EMU membership possible by 2005.</title>
<headline>Hungary says EMU membership possible by 2005.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary is likely to be ready for European Union membership by around 2000 but its high inflation rate will probably not qualify it for European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) before 2005, a top official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Hungary's economy will allow it to become a stable EU member by the turn of the millennium, or one or two years later,&quot; Deputy Secretary of State Tamas Tetenyi told a business conference.</p>
<p>&quot;But according to calculations related to inflation, we cannot reach a position to meet the (EMU's) Maastricht criteria before 2005,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Hungary is one of several EU associate members in eastern Europe which are building a market economy and hope to reach full EU membership by around 2000.</p>
<p>Tetenyi said Hungary took a large step towards the EU and EMU in 1995 when it reached what he called an economic breakthrough as an austerity programme and a surge of privatisation revenues helped it reverse the rapid expansion of state debt.</p>
<p>However, state debt is still around 80 percent of gross domestic product (GDP), compared with an EMU requirement of a maximum 60 percent, and privatisation revenues will soon dry up as sell-offs are completed in 1998, he said.</p>
<p>Tetenyi added that consequently Hungary's only way to reduce state debt further was to speed up economic growth.</p>
<p>If the growth rate increased to three percent in the short term and five percent by around 2000 from around one percent now, and income policies remained firm, Hungary would be able to meet the Maastricht treaty's debt criterion within a few years, he said.</p>
<p>However, inflation, currently over 20 percent, is also well above EMU requirements. This will force Hungary to continue its crawling-peg devaluation policy for several years in order to preserve the competitiveness of companies, Tetenyi said.</p>
<p>A country can only join EMU if it has not devalued its currency for two years.</p>
<p>By around 2000, the forint currency will be ready to integrate into the European monetary system, although inflation will still be above that of other EU states, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hungarian currency has a small volume. So it will be relatively easy to hold it within the European monetary system on an intervention basis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Once it is in the EU, Hungary, with EU help, will probably reduce its inflation rate more easily than now in order to meet EMU inflation and interest rate requirements, he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
