<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160998" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Elderly suffered most in Japanese quake - study.</title>
<headline>Elderly suffered most in Japanese quake - study.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 1995 earthquake that heavily damaged the Japanese city of Kobe hit the elderly especially hard, mostly because they were too shy to seek help, doctors reported on Friday.</p>
<p>More than 6,000 people died in the quake, most of them elderly, Noritoshi Tanida of the Hyogo College of Medicine reported in the British Medical Journal.</p>
<p>&quot;More than half the fatalities were among those over 60 years old, and in this age group female fatalities were almost double those of men,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>The old suffered not only in the quake itself -- 77 percent of the fatalities were crushed to death -- but also from its after-effects, Tanida reported.</p>
<p>Although children and the elderly are usually cared for first after a disaster, the Hanshin earthquake was so devastating that society itself fell apart for a while, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The earthquake had destroyed local communities, and elderly people were left with no one they dared ask for help.&quot;</p>
<p>Their polite manners meant older people could be overlooked.</p>
<p>&quot;Elderly people tended not to proclaim their problems unless they were questioned specifically,&quot; Tanida wrote.</p>
<p>&quot;Elderly people restricted their own consumption of food and water, partly because they felt constrained to give way to younger people and partly because toilet facilities were scarce,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He painted a sad picture of an older generation left completely bereft by the disaster.</p>
<p>&quot;Suicide by elderly victims occurred at a rate of almost once a month. In addition, some elderly people were found dead in a ditch, presumably because they were lost in a new territory.&quot;</p>
<p>The next time a disaster hits, Tandia recommended, rescue workers should keep a special eye out for the elderly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
