<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="160966" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BSkyB first quarter profit climbs 31 pct.</title>
<headline>BSkyB first quarter profit climbs 31 pct.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>British pay television operator BSkyB said on Friday that its first quarter pre-tax profit had risen by 31 percent to 66 million pounds ($107.5 million).</p>
<p>The company, in which Rupert Murdoch's News Corp is the leading shareholder, said that total paying subscribers had reached 5.65 million at 30 September, a net increase for the quarter of 146,000.</p>
<p>&quot;The company has performed strongly in the first quarter and has achieved significant growth in both revenue and profits,&quot; said BSkyB chief executive Sam Chisholm.</p>
<p>&quot;Our increased investment in all areas of programming and the quality and choice we offer our subscribers will maintain our impetus,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Operating revenues for the three months to September 30 increased to 266 million pounds, a rise of 24 percent.</p>
<p>Earnings per share were 3.9 pence, 30 percent up on the same period a year ago.</p>
<p>BSkyB said it would show its second pay-per-view event on November 9 when Mike Tyson and Evander Holyfield meet in Las Vegas for the WBA Heavyweight Boxing crown.</p>
<p>BSkyB first experimented with pay-per-view when Tyson fought Briton Frank Bruno earlier this year. ($1=.6141 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741110">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
