<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161091" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Furukawa sees big Thai copper tube need.</title>
<headline>Furukawa sees big Thai copper tube need.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Furukawa Metal (Thailand) Plc, a unit of Furukawa Electric Co Ltd, is to go ahead with listing plans despite the sluggish stock market because it is confident there is demand for its copper tubes.</p>
<p>Company managing director Tomio Minami told Reuters on Friday the firm would use the proceeds from the initial public offering (IPO) to fund expansion and meet rising demand for seamless copper tubes.</p>
<p>He said production of air-conditioners and refrigerators in Thailand, which use the tubes, was expected to reach 8.6 million units in 2000 from 5.5 million units in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand for air-conditioners and refrigerators, especially in Southeast Asia and Middle East, is very strong as people are more affluent,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts forecast that demand for air-conditioners and refrigerators in Southeast Asia will reach 9.3 million units this year from about three million units in 1988. In the Middle East, the figure is set to rise to 1.4 million units from 940,000.</p>
<p>Furukawa Metal will float 14.5 million shares at 45 baht ($1.8) each. A total of 7.4 million shares will be offered to local investors and the rest to foreign investors.</p>
<p>This places the shares on a price-earnings ratio of about 7.4 times compared with a sector average of 8.64 as of October 30, according to Thana One Securities. Thana One and Capital Nomura Securities have been appointed co-underwriters of the issue.</p>
<p>The company expects to raise 652.5 million baht from the offering to fund its 980 million baht expansion project. This will raise production capacity to 18,000 tonnes a year from 10,560 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>The rest of the project's funds would come from loans, Minami said, adding that the new capacity would be achieved during the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Kulwadee Kawayawong, general manager of Capital Nomura Securities' investment banking department, said she was confident that the Furukawa Metal's IPO would be successful as the company had strong fundamentals and outlook.</p>
<p>The company expects to post a 219 million baht net profit in 1996 against 132 million in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;But during the first half of this year, the company already made 150 million baht in net profit,&quot; Kulwadee said. &quot;Moreover, demand for refrigerators and air-conditioners is likely to grow by 15 percent for the next three to five years.&quot;</p>
<p>There are only two seamless copper tube producers in Thailand -- Furukawa Metal with a 43 percent market share and Bangkok Metal Industry with 25 percent. Imports account for the remaining 32 percent.</p>
<p>Minami said he was confident that Furukawa Metal would be able to increase, or at least maintain, its market share in the next five years despite tougher competition.</p>
<p>Mitsubishi Materials is expected to enter the market and start producing similar products in mid-1988 with a capacity of 12,000 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment, local demand exceeds production. The new producer will take some imported product market share but not ours,&quot; Minami said.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32840">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
