<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161025" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Di magic fading on trip Down Under.</title>
<headline>Di magic fading on trip Down Under.</headline>
<byline>Philippe Naughton</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>When she came to Australia in the 1980s, tens of thousands of admirers and royal watchers lined the streets for a glimpse of Britain's Princess Diana.</p>
<p>Amid the full fanfare of a royal tour and with her husband at her side, the princess managed to persuade even hardened Australian republicans to forget their historical grudge.</p>
<p>But that was at the height of her celebrity, when her beauty made her the world's most photographed woman, and before a messy divorce from heir-to-the-throne Prince Charles.</p>
<p>This time, on a four-day charity visit, Diana is still a princess but no longer a royal -- and the Di magic seems to be fading.</p>
<p>The crowds have been disappointing. She was rudely crowded by other dancers at a socialite dinner. And, worst of all, a mere American actress snapped up the best hotel suite in town.</p>
<p>The main aim of Princess Diana's trip to Sydney, which she visited as a relatively new bride in 1983 and again in 1988, has been to raise money for a cardiac research institute.</p>
<p>More than 800 of Sydney's social and business elite paid A$1,000 ($790) each to join the princess at a fund-raising dinner after her arrival on Thursday and several hundred fans waited outside to see her. However, 190 tickets went unsold.</p>
<p>Diners had already been briefed that the princess was no longer &quot;Your Royal Highness&quot; -- plain &quot;Ma'am&quot; or &quot;Princess&quot; would do -- and that curtseys were not required.</p>
<p>But the compere had to ask guests to give her space as she began her first dance and reporters at the dinner said Diana was constantly being approached by diners from other tables. She left the dinner about 45 minutes early, pleading tiredness.</p>
<p>&quot;The organisation has been disastrous,&quot; said one veteran royal-watcher on Friday, noting that Diana had brought only two staff on the trip and there had been no pre-tour inspections by Scotland Yard and British diplomats.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is she no longer has the palace behind her, organising everything and making sure it all goes smoothly.&quot;</p>
<p>Another Fleet Street journalist, who broke off from covering a state visit to Thailand by Queen Elizabeth for Diana's trip to to Sydney, said the two trips could not be compared.</p>
<p>&quot;The Thailand visit was prepared for two years. Embassy officials had walked along every step of her route,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Diana's trip to Sydney was organised rather more quickly -- plans to put her in the best suite at a top Sydney hotel had to be changed because Priscilla Presley, widow of the king of rock and roll Elvis Presley, already had it booked.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
