<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161082" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: PRESS DIGEST - S.Korean newspapers - Nov 1.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - S.Korean newspapers - Nov 1.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a summary of major South Korean political stories in leading newspapers, prepared by Reuters in Seoul. Reuters has not checked the stories and does not gaurantee their accuracy. Telephone: (822) 727-5650. Fax: (822) 727-5666.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>HANKOOK ILBO</p>
<p>- Seoul city government studies a plan to lower intra-city bus fares in wake of an embezzlment scandal involving 17 bus company owners.</p>
<p>- Former president Choi Kyu-hah expected to be forced to testify in appeal trial session involving ex-presidents Chun and Roh, who have been sentenced to death and life term on treason and rebellion charges, respectively. Choi, considered a key figure who witnessed the turbulent developments during the 1979 military coup and bloody crackdown, has consistently refused to testify on the case.</p>
<p>-----</p>
<p>DONG-A ILBO</p>
<p>- Korea becomes board member of the U.N. economic and social council by winning 128 votes in the second voting at the UN general assembly.</p>
<p>-----</p>
<p>SEGYE TIMES</p>
<p>- Investigation begins against mid-level public servants involved in various irregularities.</p>
<p>-----</p>
<p>JOONG-ANG ILBO</p>
<p>- Gasoline price hiked to 730 won per liter from 711 won, effective today.</p>
<p>-----</p>
<p>KOREA TIMES</p>
<p>- Stability on Korean peninsula depends on reform in North Korea, said the chairman of the ruling New Korea Party.</p>
<p>- South Korea and the United States agree to quicken deployment of advanced arms to blunt North Korean threat.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
