<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161064" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian wool mainly unchanged in week.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian wool mainly unchanged in week.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian wool prices were largely unchanged this week at sales in Sydney, Geelong and Fremantle, the Australian Council of Wool Exporters said.</p>
<p>The eastern market indicator rose one cent over the week to 576 cents a kg clean, while the western market indicator was steady at 535 cents a kg. A total of 65,796 bales were offered, with a pass-in rate of 8.6 percent.</p>
<p>The council said indicators suggest the market was fairly solid, but exporters state that there is not much depth in the market at present and believe that the relatively small offering for the week helped to maintain prices at their current levels.  </p>
<p>&quot;China remains the backbone of the market, although Japanese indent orders continue to add support with their sales of top and yarn apparently at levels better than originally expected, and corresponding stocks at manageable levels,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Wool International said its sales of stockpile wool were fairly modest in the week ended Thursday with 5,959 bales sold, mostly for December quarter delivery.</p>
<p>The stockpile now stands at 2,035,702 bales.</p>
<p>In the futures market, a total of 138 contracts were traded in the 21 micron contract in the week ended October 31.  </p>
<p>The near December contract closed 10 cents down at 691 cents a kg clean and total open interest declined by 20 contracts to 870, Wool International said.</p>
<p>Sales next week are in Newcastle, Melbourne and Fremantle with a total of about 91,600 bales on offer.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
