<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161079" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Stanchart bank ordered to pay damages in Jakarta.</title>
<headline>Stanchart bank ordered to pay damages in Jakarta.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Indonesian court on Friday ordered Standard Chartered Bank to pay a Hong Kong businesswoman 247.9 million rupiah ($106,440) after she sued the bank's Jakarta branch for freezing her account.</p>
<p>Judge Zulkifli Lubis of the Central Jakarta State Court ordered the bank to pay Yee Mei-Mei 150 million rupiah for &quot;moral losses&quot; and 97.9 million rupiah in interest for the frozen funds.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to protect the rights of the community when depositing money,&quot; Lubis said in handing down his verdict.</p>
<p>In a statement issued following the judgement, the bank said it was considering its position.</p>
<p>&quot;Standard Chartered Plc has maintained throughout this court case that it acted properly and in accordance with both regulatory obligations and best banking practice,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Yee, a representative of Dragon Bank International of Vanuatu, obtained a temporary court order against Standard Chartered's Jakarta Branch in April after it refused to honour five cheques totalling about 979 million rupiah.</p>
<p>She had also asked for $300 million in damages because she claimed the bank had defamed her by freezing the money after its internal money-laundering procedures had been alerted.</p>
<p>The bank said in its statement that a court decree attaching certain assets of the Jakarta branch had been revoked.</p>
<p>Lubis said the case was a personal one and refused to recognise that the Dragon Bank had suffered any losses.</p>
<p>Indonesia's Investment Coordinating Board said in June it had cancelled Dragon Bank's investment licence because its operations were not in line with its licence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
