<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161635" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Wild ride for shareholders aboard Stagecoach.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Wild ride for shareholders aboard Stagecoach.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Huddart</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in the acquisitive public transport group Stagecoach have doubled in price in less than a year on the back of its ambitious takeover of privatised train and bus services in Britain and now around the world.</p>
<p>A brother and sister team from Scotland have turned a shoestring operation running two second-hand buses between London and Dundee into an international transport powerhouse.</p>
<p>Floated publicly in 1993 to fund Ann Gloag and Brian Souter's ambitious expansion plans, interest in Stagecoach was relatively limited until last year when it exploited the privatisation of British Rail to move into railways.</p>
<p>Its success in winning the first British private train operating franchise in December -- for South West Trains -- heralded the start of an explosive phase for its share price.</p>
<p>From 274 pence in mid-December 1995 the price surged throughout 1996 to a year high of 583 pence on October 28, boosted by a warm response to its moves to buy a rail leasing company.</p>
<p>The move into British railways is one of the more controversial elements of Stagecoach's voracious growth since Gloag and Souter launched the company in 1980 using the two second-hand buses on a single route.</p>
<p>HITCHED WAGON TO PRIVATISATION</p>
<p>On the back of Britain's Conservative government sell-off of both the bus industry and the railway network, Stagecoach Holdings Plc has expanded at breakneck speed.</p>
<p>It now runs dozens of bus companies around Britain, has urban and intercity bus firms in Kenya, Malawi, New Zealand, Portugal and Sweden, and operates two British train lines.</p>
<p>October saw the British government saying it would probably accept Stagecoach's latest gambit, to buy Porterbrook, a leasing company that owns a third of Britain's passenger railway rolling stock, for a total of about 825 million pounds ($1.32 billion).</p>
<p>With this deal, which unfolded just as Stagecoach announced its biggest foreign acquisition to date, paying 2.4 billion crowns ($365 million) for Swedish-based Swedbus, the company once again demonstrated its taste for risk and controversy.</p>
<p>Share analysts say this deal, in particular, has drawn new investor interest to the stock but they now believe the 16-year-old firm may start slowing its fevered expansion.</p>
<p>Outside the financial community, Stagecoach's notable competitive spirit has been appreciated less warmly.</p>
<p>Perhaps because of the inherently novel nature of its business -- running public transport services with an unabashed profit motive -- the company has attracted frequent criticism.</p>
<p>Bus and rail privatisation have been politically charged.</p>
<p>COWBOYS OR VISIONARIES?</p>
<p>Before it was floated in April 1993, and from time to time since, Stagecoach's strategy aggressively to build its share of Britain's regional bus market often drew fire from the media and sparked conflicts with fair trade and competition regulators.</p>
<p>Headlines like &quot;Bus Wars On The High Street&quot; and television programmes characterising Stagecoach as a throwback to the bare-knuckled commercial values of the American Wild West gave the company a rough-edged public image it did little to dispel.</p>
<p>The Stagecoach name, the idea of Souter's brother David, has made it easy for rivals and newspaper headline writers to portray the company as something of a &quot;cowboy&quot; operation.</p>
<p>According recent newspaper article, Souter, now the group's executive chairman, has lost count of how many British bus companies he has bought and sold -- but it is at least 45.</p>
<p>Yet, with the stormiest phase of the haphazardly organised privatisation of the country's buses now over and the prospect of more comprehensive regulation if the opposition Labour Party wins the general election next spring, this era appears to have closed.</p>
<p>An altogether more sophisticated railway privatisation process, in which the government has lavished tens of millions of pounds on lawyers' and advisers' fees, has clearly brought out a more calculated side of the Stagecoach character.</p>
<p>&quot;Two things seem to have happened -- the rail industry has got much more complete regulation than the buses ever had and Stagecoach has calmed down a bit,&quot; one transport analyst said.</p>
<p>STAGECOACH FOR LONG HAUL</p>
<p>Experts say Stagecoach now faces a different trial, to see if it can prove itself capable of delivering controlled and growing earnings from more mature transport businesses. Bullish share analysts say they base their optimism on the company's ambitious expectation of sharp profit growth over the next three years despite the pressure of heavy new debts.</p>
<p>Stagecoach has said it does not plan to expand its British bus business with the same rapid acquisitions as in the past, but rather to move steadily forward and concentrate on margin growth in its existing portfolio of companies.</p>
<p>After reporting a 33.7 percent rise in its full-year pre-tax profits to 43.6 million pounds for the 1995/96 year this July, Souter said the group wanted now to slowly build its share of the national bus network to 25 percent from 17 percent. In doing this, it says its scale will bring opportunities to make economies in purchasing, insurance, capital and network provision and therefore maintain its competitive position.</p>
<p>&quot;We compete on the basis of low-cost efficiency and not predatory pricing,&quot; the company said in a recent policy paper.</p>
<p>Other analysts are a more sceptical that the near-term earnings boom, which will be driven largely by the new contributions from Porterbrook, can justify further share gains.</p>
<p>&quot;If there were no more deals done from here, I wouldn't expect the share price to continue rocketing up,&quot; said another analyst, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;It is possible to argue that the 1998 p/e rating (the ratio of the current share price to expected earnings) is already a touch too high, but it all hinges on how they realise value from Porterbrook and the bus businesses,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts are generally less excited about the potential for Stagecoach to raise profits a lot more by winning further rail franchises, especially as each contract has a fixed length.</p>
<p>According to one recent press report, Souter has also switched to a calmer view of the British rail industry and now fears the prices being bid for the remaining franchises reflect over-optimistic expectations of revenue growth.</p>
<p>As an indication of the market's view, the current consensus estimate for the year to April 1998 is for pre-tax profits to almost triple to 150 million pounds, of which 14 million could be contributed by SWT and nearer 60 million by Porterbrook. (1$=.6260 Pound) ($1=6.575 Swedish Crown) ($1=.6141 Pence)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
