<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161687" id="root" date="1996-11-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FIGURE SKATING-KWAN LEADS AFTER SHORT PROGRAM.</title>
<headline>FIGURE SKATING-KWAN LEADS AFTER SHORT PROGRAM.</headline>
<dateline>SPRINGFIELD, Massachusetts 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>World champion Michelle Kwan of the United States lived up to her role of favourite at Skate America International on Friday, taking the lead after the short programme.</p>
<p>With Saturday's free-skating programme remaining, Kwan positioned herself to win the first major event of the international skating season.</p>
<p>The competition crowns champions in the men's, women's, pairs and ice dancing competition Saturday. At stake are prize money and points in the Champions Series, a six-event competition with this the only U.S. stop in the series.</p>
<p>World champion Todd Eldredge of the United States was leading the men's competition after Thursday's short programme.</p>
<p>The U.S. team of Shelby Lyons and Brian Wells had a surprising lead in pairs with the Russian team of world silver medallists Oksana Kazakova and Artur Dmitriev second.</p>
<p>Kwan earned at least a 5.8 on all the judges' cards except one 5.7. The United States garnered the top three spots in the women's programme, with Tonia Kwiatkowski second and Sydne Vogel third.</p>
<p>Hanae Yokoya of Japan and Julia Lautowa of Austria were fourth and fifth entering the free programme.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't say it was perfect. I made a lot of mistakes like head moves, arm movements, even my finger was bent,&quot; Kwan said. &quot;But it was pretty good for the beginning of the season.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;All our strategy was just to get through it cleanly and be consistent,&quot; said Frank Carroll, Kwan's coach. &quot;I was very pleased for this early in the season.</p>
<p>One of Kwiatkowski's coaches, Glyn Watts, said his skater's performance was also solid. Many fans thought she should have been given higher marks, but Watts didn't dispute the judging -- at least not directly.</p>
<p>&quot;The rules have changed so much this year that I think the judges are still trying to figure out what they're judging,&quot; he said. &quot;When the marks are initially put up, you do wonder what they saw.&quot;</p>
<p>In ice dancing, the Russian team of world silver medallists Anjelika Krylova and Oleg Ovsiannikov remained in the lead after the original dance. Saturday's free dance, accounting for 50 percent of the total score, was to complete the three-part competition.</p>
<p>Irina Lobatcheva and Ilia Averbukh, also from Russia, remained in second place.</p>
<p>The French team of Sophie Moniotte and Pascal Lavanchy, on the comeback trail now that Moniotte has recovered from an ankle injury, stood in third place.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SPRINGFIELD, Massachusetts"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
