<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161618" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Hanjung says plans $600m investment in Sri Lanka.</title>
<headline>Hanjung says plans $600m investment in Sri Lanka.</headline>
<byline>Prithi Kodagoda</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Korea Heavy Industries &amp; Construction Co (Hanjung) announced on Wednesday plans to invest $500-600 million to build a steel mill, power plant and oil refinery complex in Sri Lanka in the next three to five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to use this country as a base camp to penetrate neighbouring Southwest Asian countries,&quot; Park Un-suh, the company's chairman and president, told a news conference in Colombo on Friday.</p>
<p>Park was in Colombo to sign on Thursday the share sale and purchase agreement for Ceylon Steel Corp, which was privatised by selling 90 percent to Hanjung for $15 million.</p>
<p>State-owned Hanjung, South Korea's biggest manufacturer of heavy industrial plant and equipment, hopes to complete by June 1997 an economic and technical feasibility study for building the Sri Lankan oil, power and steel complex, Park said.</p>
<p>The ideal location for the project would be about 700 acres (280 hectares) of land near a port, and suggestions have so far included Galle and Hambantota in the deep south, and Trincomalee in the east.</p>
<p>&quot;A final decision on location will be taken after looking at the overall situation,&quot; said Shin Sang-hong, a senior vice president. He was referring to the security situation in Trincomalee, which is near a war zone where Tamil separatists are fighting government troops.</p>
<p>The steel mill, which would have annual capacity of 300,000 tonnes, would cater to Sri Lanka's expected fast-growing usage regional export markets, Park said.</p>
<p>As a first step, Hanjung plans to invest a further $10 million to modernise Ceylon Steel's 30-year old plant and raise annual output to at least 75,000 tonnes by the end of 1997 from 55,000 currently.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to work towards supplying at least half Sri Lanka's local annual demand of 200,000 metric tonnes, and diversify into steel fabrication and do import substitution,&quot; said Park.</p>
<p>The oil refinery, using residual fuel, will have a daily capacity of 50,000-75,000 barrels. It could also supply refined oil to the state-owned Ceylon Petroleum Corp.</p>
<p>The 280 megawatt power plant will have about 170 megawatts of power to supply the national grid, Park said.</p>
<p>Due to new ventures and expansions at Ceylon Steel, Hanjung can follow the government's policy of not allowing layoffs in privatised ventures, Park said.</p>
<p>Ceylon Steel's workforce of 1,400 would be retained and the company would probably need more workers once capacity is enhanced in 1997, Park said.</p>
<p>Hanjung will also rotate local workers to plants in South Korea, Indonesia and Vietnam to give them foreign exposure, he said.</p>
<p>Hanjung has 7,650 employees and issued capital of $651 million. It has built 92 power plants generating 17 million kilowatts in South Korea in the last few decades, Park said.</p>
<p>The firm has 21 more power plants with a generating capacity of 20 million kilowatts under construction in South Korea.</p>
<p>Hanjung is also planning new projects in Indonesia, China, Malaysia, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates and Qatar, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
