<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161607" id="root" date="1996-11-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: FEATURE - Sri Lanka hopes to promote tea as health drink.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Sri Lanka hopes to promote tea as health drink.</headline>
<byline>Rohan Gunasekera</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-11-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka, the world's leading tea exporter, hopes to promote tea as a health drink in its drive to capture a larger share of the multi-million dollar beverage market, officials and experts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today the world is going green,&quot; tea expert Maxwell Fernando, author of a new book on trading in Ceylon tea, told Reuters in an interview. &quot;People are looking forward to health drinks. There's nothing more amiable to the public than tea.&quot;</p>
<p>The director-general of the Sri Lanka Tea Board, Ranjith Maligaspe, recently said tea needs to discard its staid image and use the sort of snappy marketing techniques that make soft drinks attractive to younger consumers.</p>
<p>He told an Asia Tea Industry conference in Singapore it was vital to develop a new image and new markets for tea because global output is rising while consumption has been stagnant.</p>
<p>The conference even heard calls from industry leaders for big tea producers like Sri Lanka to restrict exports to boost prices because of stagnant demand.</p>
<p>The world's tea crop in 1994 was 1.74 million tonnes while consumption was 1.70 million tonnes, according to the U.N.'s Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO). The crop is forecast to reach 2.81 million tonnes (6.19 million lbs) by 2005.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka's tea exports are expected to hit a record 250 million kg this calendar year.</p>
<p>However, prices for the Indian Ocean island's main export crop appear to have peaked in mid-October, and brokers say they are concerned about Sri Lanka's heavy dependence on the markets of Russia and other former Soviet republics.</p>
<p>Officials of Sri Lanka's Plantations Industry Ministry said the tea industry should learn from the way soft drinks giants like Coca-Cola and PepsiCo aggressively pitch their products to young people around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Coke and Pepsi spend millions of dollars on advertising,&quot; a ministry official said. &quot;It is difficult for us to compete as we have only a limited amount of money.&quot;</p>
<p>But research into the health benefits of tea drinking could give the industry an ideal marketing tool to compete with the beverage giants in the long term, he said.</p>
<p>Current research, mostly on green tea, has shown it has properties which fight cancer and cardio-vascular diseases, he said. About 70-80 percent of world trade is in black tea.</p>
<p>Producers should promote tea as a healthy alternative to sugary soft drinks while shedding its image as only a hot drink, the official added.</p>
<p>Anil Cooke of tea brokers Forbes and Walker said early results of the research were positive and well-received by the public and could help expand tea's share of the beverage market.</p>
<p>&quot;The entire tea world is quite convinced of the likelihood that research will reveal clearly there is a link between health and tea,&quot; Cooke said. &quot;It's just that one cannot print these on labels until proved beyond any reasonable doubt.&quot;</p>
<p>Plantations Industry Ministry officials said big tea producers like Sri Lanka, India, Kenya, and Indonesia had joined with consumer countries like the United States, the United Kingdom and Canada to fund research on tea's healthful properties.</p>
<p>The research project, under the U.K. Tea Council and sponsored by the FAO, is partly supported by the Common Fund for Commodities, a U.N.-affiliated inter-governmental organisation based in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the right product at the right time,&quot; Cooke said of tea. &quot;This fits in perfectly well with the trend towards a healthier lifestyle.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42390">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
