<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161764" id="root" date="1996-11-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Quebec premier thinks economy, not separation.</title>
<headline>Quebec premier thinks economy, not separation.</headline>
<byline>Robert Melnbardis</byline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-11-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Quebec's popular Premier Lucien Bouchard appears ready to risk alienating his separatist allies in a drive to revive the French-speaking Canadian province's flagging economy.</p>
<p>One year after leading separatists to near-victory in a referendum on Quebec sovereignty, Bouchard is drawing praise from the most unlikely sources -- business leaders who usually are deeply suspicious of his Parti Quebecois government.</p>
<p>They are applauding his pledge to reduce Quebec's C$3.9 billion ($2.9 billion) budget deficit to zero by 2000, stop the growth of the province's C$76 billion ($57 billion) public debt, and lower its 12.6 percent unemployment rate.</p>
<p>Traditional supporters of Quebec independence, however, are upset that Bouchard appears to be straying from his party's traditional social-democratic values in a determined bid to clean up the province's public finances.</p>
<p>On Tuesday night, while Bouchard opened a high-profile three-day Summit-Conference on the Economy and Unemployment, demonstrators outside the venue burned an effigy of him and pelted riot police with eggs.</p>
<p>Jacques Parizeau, who last year handed leadership of the separatist referendum campaign and eventually his premiership to Bouchard, criticised the premier's deficit-cutting plans.</p>
<p>In an essay published in a Montreal newspaper on the first day of the summit, Parizeau said Bouchard's attempt to help Quebec catch up with deficit-cutting programmes in Ottawa and in the nine other provinces risked damaging the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We risk entering a well-known spiral. You cut, foreseen revenues drop, you cut again, they fall again,&quot; he wrote.</p>
<p>Bouchard had a cool response to the sniping from his former separatist ally. &quot;I will not comment on this man's views,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the summit, some of the groups representing students, women and the province's burgeoning ranks of poor people, walked out. The students demanded guarantees school fees would not be hiked, while the head of a women's group left because the summit did not endorse a &quot;zero poverty&quot; resolution.</p>
<p>&quot;Poverty is not negotiable,&quot; said Francoise David, president of the Quebec Women's Federation.</p>
<p>By contrast, business leaders came away from the summit beaming with victory even though they were unsuccessful in pressing Bouchard to declare a moratorium on holding any more referendums on separation from Canada.</p>
<p>An agreement between the government, business and Quebec's big public-sector unions on fighting unemployment called for only voluntary measures on the part of the corporate sector.</p>
<p>Bouchard also agreed to act on a recommendation from a task force led by Brian Levitt, chief executive of Imaso Ltd., Canada's largest tobacco maker, that steps be taken to promote Montreal as a metropolis where English-speaking professionals can have a prosperous future.</p>
<p>After the summit, Bouchard told reporters the three days of meetings were not a publicity stunt aimed at giving his independence drive economic and fiscal credibility.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not devoted to helping the separatist cause. It was devoted to helping Quebec, all Quebecers,&quot; Bouchard said.</p>
<p>With polls showing that separatist fervor has slipped from the 49.4 percent vote it drew in the Oct. 30, 1995, referendum on sovereignty, the next test of Bouchard's leadership will come at a Parti Quebecois convention later this month.</p>
<p>There, Bouchard is expected to face more opposition to his deficit-cutting plans and criticism of his refusal to toughen language laws that restrict the use of English in Quebec. With the Canadian dollar at a year-high, interest rates at historical lows, and most of the provinces heading for budget surpluses, Bouchard does not want Quebec to be left behind.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
