<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="161862" id="root" date="1996-11-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PAL strikers defy return-to-work order.</title>
<headline>PAL strikers defy return-to-work order.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine Airlines ground crew defied a return-to-work order by the labour department whose deadline expired at midnight on Friday, a union officer said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still on strike,&quot; PAL Employees' Association officer Jun Limor told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The national carrier had earlier warned workers who did not return to work by Friday midnight that they would be sacked.</p>
<p>Limor said union officers and PAL managers were still talking at the Department of Labour and Employment office to find a solution to the strike which started on Wednesday evening over a new wage package.</p>
<p>Talks have been going on since Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>PAL said eight international and 36 domestic flights were cancelled on Saturday. Strikers include those taking flight reservations and baggage and cargo handlers.</p>
<p>&quot;(We) will continue maximising available manpower in order to mount as many international and domestic flights as possible,&quot; PAL said in a statement.</p>
<p>The workers are asking for a wage package worth 3.2 billion pesos ($121 million) over the next two years.</p>
<p>PAL has rejected the package and instead offered to sell employees PAL shares worth 477 million pesos at five pesos per share.</p>
<p>It is the third strike to hit financially troubled PAL in two years. The employees' association struck twice in 1994, the first stoppage lasting a day and the second nine days.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
