<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16212" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Locals scramble to buy remote Scottish isle Eigg.</title>
<headline>Locals scramble to buy remote Scottish isle Eigg.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 63 inhabitants of the island of Eigg off the coast of Scotland prepared on Tuesday to launch a worldwide appeal for money to realise their dream of making its 7,534 acres (3,502 hectares) their own.</p>
<p>The hardy crofters and fishermen will use the Internet as well as approaching businesses and individuals and Britain's National Lottery in an attempt to raise 800,000 pounds ($1.25 million).</p>
<p>They believe the money could be enough to purchase the island, seven miles (10 km) from the north-west mainland port of Mallaig, from the latest of a series of absentee landlords -- German artist Marlin Ekhart Maruma.</p>
<p>Maruma, who has owned the island of moorlands, fertile fields and spectacular beaches for just 18 months, has put Eigg up for sale with a price tag of two million pounds ($3.1 million), a figure the inhabitants see as unrealistic.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined to take our destinies in our own hands. This is the best chance we will ever get to make a go of things on Eigg,&quot; said Maggie Fyffe, secretary of the inhabitants' Isle of Eigg Trust.</p>
<p>Absentee landlords have been resented in the Scottish highlands ever since the 19th century &quot;Clearances&quot; in which whole villages were forced to emigrate when &quot;lairds&quot; decided arable land should be used as grazing for sheep.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
