<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162184" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BT, MCI and shareholders wait for merger approval.</title>
<headline>BT, MCI and shareholders wait for merger approval.</headline>
<byline>Kirsten Ridley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Telecom, MCI Communications and their shareholders must now wait and see if U.S. and British regulators will bless their proposed transatlantic mega-merger.</p>
<p>British Telecommunications Plc's planned deal with MCI -- the number two U.S. long-distance phone company after U.S. telecoms giant AT &amp; T Corp -- creates a $54 billion group to be called Concert Plc.</p>
<p>It will have 43 million business and residential customers in 70 countries, taking advantage of growing liberalisation in world markets.</p>
<p>BT executives poured champagne as they made their announcement on Sunday, confident that the U.S. Federal Communications Commission (FCC) and Britain's Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) would approve the deal.</p>
<p>Analysts were also upbeat about the possibilities for the new communications colossus.</p>
<p>&quot;MCI is very profitable and very highly regarded. A lot of the European companies have no track record as they are monopolies,&quot; said John Clarke, telecoms analyst at brokers Daiwa Europe. &quot;I think this will be quite well received.&quot;</p>
<p>AT&amp;T, broken up by U.S. regulators in 1984, stands to lose the most from the powerful new addition to the world telecommunications scene. It said it was confident the deal would receive proper FCC scrutiny.</p>
<p>The FCC must okay every deal involving more than 25 percent foreign ownership of a company, and this agreement marks the biggest single British move in the U.S. market.</p>
<p>But U.S. law has just this year become more favourable to such bargains.</p>
<p>The Telecommunications Act, signed by President Bill Clinton in February, backtracks a bit on the policy that caused AT&amp;T's break-up by removing barriers among cable, local and long-distance phone services.</p>
<p>Under the new law, seven regional &quot;Baby Bell&quot; operators spun off from AT&amp;T can compete with long-distance carriers in the $200 billion U.S. market. It also lets AT&amp;T, MCI and Sprint, the three dominant long-distance carriers, have access to the local- call market.</p>
<p>And in January the FCC allowed the French and German carriers -- France Telecom and Deutsche Telekom AG -- to take stakes in Sprint Corp to form Global One.</p>
<p>Britain has been following in Washington's footsteps.</p>
<p>In June, the British government said it was ending the domination of the international carrier market by BT and Cable and Wireless's Mercury unit by inviting applications to provide international services.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T immediately leapt at the chance, saying it looked forward to getting a licence.</p>
<p>The new telecoms giant, which will have annual cash flow of about 7.5 billion pounds, will be incorporated in Britain with headquarters in London and Washington and operate under the BT and MCI brand names in Britain and the United States.</p>
<p>One analyst, when asked what BT shares might do on Monday, predicted they were unlikely to soar. He noted that taking on the U.S. market increased risk for BT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
