<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162240" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: OAU mission arrives in Rwanda for talks on Zaire.</title>
<headline>OAU mission arrives in Rwanda for talks on Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Organisation of African Unity (OAU) peace mission arrived in Rwanda from Zaire on Sunday and Rwanda's president visited Uganda as diplomatic activity over fighting in eastern Zaire stepped up.</p>
<p>The OAU mission led by assistant secretary-general Tiaendre Beogo landed in Kigali from Zaire's capital Kinshasa after talks with Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo and other officials.</p>
<p>Joe Felli, OAU ambassador to the Great Lakes region, told Reuters the team was trying to lower tension between Kigali and Kinshasa over Zairean accusations that Rwanda backs Banyamulenge Tutsi rebels who have seized a swathe of eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>He said the OAU delegation would try to arrange a ceasefire between the rebels and Zaire and head off a looming humanitarian catastrophe for the more than one million refugees in the war zone.</p>
<p>The OAU mission would also attempt to build a framework for dialogue between Rwanda and Zaire, whose relations are at an all-time low, before a regional summit in Nairobi on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This mission is an African initiative to contain a volatile situation in the Great Lakes region,&quot; Felli said.</p>
<p>He said the cash-strapped OAU, which has been powerless to prevent or halt conflicts on the world's poorest continent, was supplementing efforts by regional leaders to end the fighting in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>The OAU team was due to meet Rwandan President Pasteur Bizimungu, a Hutu, and military strongman Major-General Paul Kagame, a Tutsi who holds the posts of defence minister and vice-president.</p>
<p>Diplomats in Kigali however were sceptical about chances of success for the OAU, saying it lacked the political muscle to bring the warring sides to the negotiating table.</p>
<p>&quot;I doubt the OAU will achieve anything. The problem is beyond the capacity of the OAU,&quot; said an African diplomat.</p>
<p>The OAU team arrived in Kigalio shortly after Bizimungu was driven to Mbarara, western Uganda, for consultations with Ugandan President Yoweri Museveni on the war in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Zaire's government accuses Rwanda, Burundi and Uganda of sending troops to invade its territory and back the rebels and its transitional parliamenent has vowed to sever diplomatic links with them.</p>
<p>All three countries have denied Zaire's charges but troops of Rwanda's Tutsi-dominated army made a brief incursion into Zaire near Bukavu on Tuesday night and sent troops into Goma city on Friday and Saturday.</p>
<p>Officials said both Museveni and Bizimungu would attend Tuesday's summit being organised by Kenyan President Daniel arap Moi.</p>
<p>Zaire, which is the key to the success of the summit, says it will not attend until Rwandan troops withdraw from its territory and the European Union is pushing for such a pullout.</p>
<p>Museveni has close relations with the Rwandan government which was formed after Tutsi rebels under Kagame seized power in July 1994 and put an end to the Hutu genocide of up to a million Tutsis and Hutu moderates.</p>
<p>Kagame and other Rwandan Tutsi rebels fought in the rebel army that took Museveni to power in 1986 after a five-year war.</p>
<p>Diplomats in Kigali said European Union special envoy Aldo Ajello was due to meet Museveni on Sunday after two days of meetings in Kinshasa which failed to persuade Zaire's government to attend talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
