<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162296" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria's gypsies see no hope in election.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria's gypsies see no hope in election.</headline>
<byline>Galina Sabeva</byline>
<dateline>FILIPOVTSI, Bulgaria 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's 300,000 Gypsies, destitute and despised in the land they have lived in for centuries, are the most cynical of Sunday's voters.</p>
<p>Overwhelmed by a sense of the futility of politics, most see the presidential run-off as a charade.</p>
<p>In this Gypsy ghetto on the outskirts of the capital, where many of the 3,000 inhabitants live crammed 10 to a room, the future is remorselessly bleak, whoever wins.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing is going to change here,&quot; said Kostadin Ferdinandov. &quot;Those who manage to survive the coming winter will regret it in the spring -- all they'll have is yet more misery to look forward to.&quot;</p>
<p>Bulgaria's Gypsies are thought to have first come from the Punjab region of India around the 10th century.</p>
<p>They were nomadic until the 1960s, when the communist authorities began a campaign of forcible assimilation, severely curbing their religious and culture habits.</p>
<p>They were made to settle in Soviet-style collective farms, or in special housing projects like Filipovtsi.</p>
<p>After years of neglect, the district is now little more than a shanty-town, with many of its small houses in ruins and no paved streets or running water.</p>
<p>&quot;You can feel the sense of the desperation in each house,&quot; said Marin Borisov who has lived all his 34 years there.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't see any difference between the candidates,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;They come when there are elections, they promise the earth and then they desert us,&quot;</p>
<p>Vassil Mitakov added: &quot;I was born here, my children were born here and my grandchildren will be -- the election has no meaning for us as we are doomed to live in misery.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of Bulgaria's Gypsies are unemployed and say nobody wants them even for the dirtiest work.</p>
<p>Living in the margins of society, Gypsies have traditionally aroused deep suspicion among ordinary Bulgarians.</p>
<p>Scattered through all the big towns, uneducated and unemployed, many live on theft, prostitution, gambling and begging.</p>
<p>Two years ago, police estimated they were behind some 33 percent of crime in Bulgaria where they make up just 3.4 percent of the population.</p>
<p>That image has helped push the Gypsies to the bottom of the social pile in a country where resources are scarce and likely to become even more so during the coming winter.</p>
<p>With even relatively well-off Bulgarians facing possible food and fuel shortages in the coming months, the outlook for Filipovtsi looks grim.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing has changed during all those years here, and I doubt anything is going to happen now,&quot; said Eleonora Kadelieva, a doctor who has worked in the area for 18 years.</p>
<p>&quot;They just don't believe any more&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FILIPOVTSI, Bulgaria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
