<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16220" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Aug 28.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian Sports News - Aug 28.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett has entered the Hawthorn-Melbourne Australian Football League merger debate by urging the League to allow those lobbying to retain independent clubs to put their case to members. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Brisbane Bears have thwarted AFL newcomers Port Power again by signing star goalkicking utility Craig McRae for another four-years. Last week the Bears fended off a Port Power attempt to offer star rookie Clark Keating a lucrative contract. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Canberra Raiders have reinstated prop John Lomax for Sunday's Australian Rugby League clash against South Queensland after it was revealed the fracture in his hand was only minor. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>NSW Rugby Union Coach Chris Hawkins reign is over following last night's surprise announcement by NSW Rugby Union saying it and Hawkins had mutually agreed the coach will not continue the second year of his contract due to Hawkins' other commitments. Page44.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sydney Swan's star Tony Lockett may still be in doubt for Saturday night's AFL clash against West Coast following a flare-up of a recurring knee-injury. Coach Rodney Eade has given Lockett a 60/40 chance of having a kick this weekend. Page 44.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Basketball League's Sydney Kings have decided to focus on improving their last few minute's play after losing a number of close matches this season. Star player Isaac Burton feels losing to Hobart last week by a point has driven the point home that the team needs to be stronger in the final stages. Page 44.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Australian Football League had dramatically increased pressure on Joseph Gutnick and the International Management Group to stop them from separately funding clubs Hawthorn and Melbourne and scuttling any merger moves. Page C20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Football League, amongst other things, yesterday slugged the Sydney Swans a total of $4000 in fines following club director Ron Barassi breaking an AFL ruling and making comments about the Tony Lockett incident before it went to Monday's trbunal. Page C20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Steve Waugh's top-score of 82 off 70 balls added to Australia's 125-run win over Zimbabwe in the Singer Cup in Columbo yesterday. Zimbabwe with 138 all out in 41 overs lost to Australia's 7/263. Page C18.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Australian Football League Operations chief Ian Collins fears his public fallout with former league investigator Martin Amad will result in being over-looked for the leagues top job after the retirement of Ross Oakley. Page 88.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Carlton will discover today whether AFL veteran star Greg Williams will be sidelined for the rest of the 1996 season following Williams' chronic knee complaint. It is believed the centreman will decide today to undergo surgery on his right knee. Page 86.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Basketball League club-owners and executives will begin crucial talks today for a three-day conference on the future of the sport in Australia. The prospect of a summer basketball competition has for 1997 has already been vetoed by clubs. Page 86</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>NSWRU has parted ways with Waratah's coach Chris Hawkins. It is believed both parties expired Hawkin's 1997-expired contract mutually. Matt Williams, the teams full time manager is being tipped to take over from Hawkins. Page 76.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Sydney is being considered as the permanent home for the Sport Australia Hall of Fame. The Sport Australia Hall of Fame trust is currently assessing potential sites near Homebush Olympic Stadium and Darling Harbour. Page 74.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Manly forward Solomon Haumono has had to undergo microsurgery to repair the powerful Australian Rugby League forward's career-threatening arm injury. Haumono will be sidelined following a cut in his arm which severed tendons in his right forearm. Page 70.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
