<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162347" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Pasminco sees higher lead production.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Pasminco sees higher lead production.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Base metals group Pasminco Ltd said on Monday it expected to increase annual lead production to 250,000 tonnes from the current 220,000 tonnes at its Port Pirie smelter in South Australia by the end of the century.</p>
<p>Lead production at the smelter has grown steadily in recent years largely as a result of productivity improvements, said Bryan Davis, Pasminco's executive director for mining.</p>
<p>Davis, speaking at an industry conference, said he expected lead prices to trade above US$700 tonne for the next several years.  </p>
<p>&quot;Notwithstanding an increase in stock levels during the northern summer period, total metal stocks have fallen significantly during recent years and have been below five weeks consumption thoughout 1996,&quot; Davis said.</p>
<p>Davis said that by the year 2000 Australia would produce 30 percent of the western world's lead mine production compared with 21 percent currently.</p>
<p>&quot;Australia's major role in world lead mine production is not reflected in concentrate shipments since the major portion of the lead mined is processed into metal domestically,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Western world demand for lead has grown at an average rate of 1.4 percent per year in the last fifteen years,&quot; Davis said.</p>
<p>Davis said Pasminco was confident the growth rate in lead would accelerate due mainly to increases in worldwide automobile fleet leasing.</p>
<p>About 70 percent of the lead produced annually is used to make vehicle batteries.</p>
<p>In Asia, where 30 percent of western world lead was consumed, demand would continue to outstrip other regions, Davis said.  </p>
<p>He estimated growth in Asia would average about 4.5 percent a year, equal to an additional 70,000 tonnes annually.</p>
<p>&quot;This represents the equivalent of one new lead smelter every 18 months,&quot; Davis said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22471">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
