<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162406" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China takes no chances in Hong Kong leadership race.</title>
<headline>China takes no chances in Hong Kong leadership race.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 400 prominent Hong Kong citizens anointed by China to shape the leadership of the territory once the British depart next year can look forward to a few glorious weeks of being feted, flattered and cajoled.</p>
<p>But they can also expect to find themselves the target of vituperative abuse from pro-democracy activists in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>As the China-appointed Preparatory Committee met in Beijing on Saturday to announce the appointees to a Selection Committee, demonstrations flared in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Activists fear many of the freedoms now taken for granted will be lost when sovereignty of the British colony passes to China at midnight on June 30, next year.</p>
<p>Police were called to prevent about 40 protesters entering the Hong Kong office of the Preparatory Committee to petition against the Selection Committee which they call undemocratic.</p>
<p>The South China Morning Post described the Selection Committee's task as &quot;Elections Beijing-style&quot;.</p>
<p>The composition of the Selection Committee, charged with choosing Hong Kong's post-colonial Chief Executive and a controversial 60-strong provisional legislature to replace the existing elected chamber, surprised no one.</p>
<p>It leaned heavily towards Hong Kong's powerful big business community and drew widely from groups and individuals most vocal in demonstrating public support for Beijing.</p>
<p>Excluded -- to no great surprise -- were two serving members of the doomed elected legislature and one of the three members of the only pro-democracy party not to boycott the process.</p>
<p>&quot;In short, the selection of the first Chief Executive is firmly within Beijing's control with enough room for flexibility to give the impression that the process is fair and open,&quot; wrote the Post's political commentator, Chris Yeung.</p>
<p>The Selection Committee is scheduled to choose the Chief Executive-designate on December 11 and the provisional legislature on December 21.</p>
<p>Beijing, which intends to dismantle the existing elected chamber because it objects to the British sponsored democratic reforms which governed the elections last year, is taking scant notice of opposing voices.</p>
<p>It barred entry on Thursday to two Hong Kong politicians seeking to protest against the provisional legislature. Two others reached Beijing but were expelled on Friday.</p>
<p>Jostling for power and influence began well before the 400 names, pared from a list of 5,700 hopefuls, emerged, said Preparatory Committee member and academic, Lau Sui-kai.</p>
<p>&quot;The pro-China camp has expanded so much in the last 10 years that there is (now) a whole lot of different interest groups involved,&quot; he told Radio Hong Kong in Beijing.</p>
<p>Four candidates have emerged as frontrunners to fill colonial Governor Chris Patten's shoes in 240 day's time when the British furl their flag and depart.</p>
<p>Two are wealthy businessmen -- Tung Chee-hwa, 59, and Peter Woo, at 50, the youngest. Two are former judges -- Simon Li, at 74 the oldest candidate and Ti Liang Yang, 67, the only member of the quartet not to sit on the Preparatory Committee.</p>
<p>Li's personal assistant told journalists in Beijing that the former appeal court judge would cut back on media interviews and concentrate on Selection Committee members.</p>
<p>Tung's spokesman Stanley Shen said appointments to meet committee members were being pencilled in.</p>
<p>Opinion polls put Yang and Tung ahead of the pack, but public popularity is irrelevant because the winner will be selected by the 400-member caucus and not elected.</p>
<p>The polls also regularly showed all four candidates losing out to Hong Kong's top civil servant, Anson Chan, in the popularity stakes, but she has ruled herself out of the race.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
