<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162483" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan stocks activity buoyed by select trade.</title>
<headline>Jordan stocks activity buoyed by select trade.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian stocks were barely changed on Sunday in higher turnover dominated by select trade on bluechip Arab Bank and leading industrials, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Amman Financial Market 60-share index fell a marginal 0.02 percent to 147.94 points in moderately high turnover worth 628,422 dinars ($963,873).</p>
<p>&quot;The market at the beginning was going down but close to the end of trade improved on some select trade in drug and industrial shares with some outside buying,&quot; said one broker.</p>
<p>Brokers said Arab Bank woke up dormant trade on the market with a trade in the heavyweight stock, with 420,655 dinars changing hands.</p>
<p>Leading bluechip Jordan Cement, which may divest a 20 percent state-owned share of its 60 million dinar equity, was again one of the market's top gainers with a 0.10 dinar rise to 3.32 dinars.</p>
<p>For the second day, little traded General Investment was the market's biggest climber, rising 4.95 percent to 3.18 dinars with a marginal 200 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>The Amman bourse slipped below 136 points in July before rebounding above 152 points in September, buoyed by government pledges of commitment to economic reform.</p>
<p>But in October it moved less than a point either side of 147.50 points. Brokers said stalled self-rule talks between Israel and Palestinians and growing doubts that neighbouring Iraq will export oil in 1996 had added to domestic worries over high interest rates and paralysed the bourse.</p>
<p>Limited trading in a handful of shares has kept the market ticking over.</p>
<p>Overall 22 shares fell, seven rose and another 10 traded but closed unchanged.</p>
<p>-- Amman newsroom, 962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
