<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162518" id="root" date="1996-11-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton preaches unity, urges votes.</title>
<headline>Clinton preaches unity, urges votes.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>UNION, N.J. 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton sounded like a preacher on Sunday as the campaign for the White House nears its judgment day, delivering sermon-like appeals for reconciliation, unity and votes.</p>
<p>Clinton, clearly confident that he will win Tuesday's election, struck a tone that was more inspirational than filled with stinging political rhetoric for Bob Dole, his Republican challenger.</p>
<p>&quot;We must decide that we really believe down deep inside that there are things that we must do together, and that we will all be better off if we give our people not a guarantee but a chance to become what God meant them to be,&quot; Clinton told a New Jersey rally.</p>
<p>His campaign aides said they believed New Jersey was safely in Clinton's fold but that he wanted to campaign in the state in hopes of swaying voters to back the Democratic Senate candidate, Bob Torricelli. He had the same goal at a stop later in Massachusetts, where Sen. John Kerry is caught in a close re-election fight.</p>
<p>Earlier, in Tampa, Florida, Clinton spoke from the pulpit of St. Paul's African Episcopal Methodist Church, where civil rights leader Martin Luther King once preached.</p>
<p>&quot;We will never be what we ought to be if we allow our country to be led by those who believe we are better off on our own, and who seek to pursue that path by driving wedges between us and exploiting our fears and convincing us that our brothers and sisters of different races, different faiths, different walks of life, are our inherent enemies,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a prescription for disaster,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>After the pastor, the Rev. Leroy Washington Jr., introduced him with a plea to the congregation to vote on Tuesday, Clinton said, &quot;I know I'm preaching to the choir today, but in the next two days we need the choir to preach.&quot;</p>
<p>With Election Day so near and most opinion polls showing him with a commanding lead over Dole, Clinton has been delivering a pointed message cloaked in lofty themes as he reaches out to voters across the country.</p>
<p>While Dole was criss-crossing the country attacking Clinton, the president sounded more like a Sunday school teacher, quoting from the Bible as he preached about the need for tolerance in America.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that there are still too many white people who wouldn't feel as comfortable as I do sitting in this church,&quot; Clinton told the black congregation. &quot;They read the same Bible you do. They claim the same saviour you do. They ought to feel at home here.&quot;</p>
<p>The church where he spoke was across Tampa Bay from St. Petersburg -- a community torn by racial rioting earlier this month.</p>
<p>After the service, Clinton met with St. Petersburg Mayor David Fischer and discussed the death of 18-year-old Tyron Lewis, a black who was shot and killed by a white police officer who stopped him for speeding.</p>
<p>The incident touched off rioting and has prompted the National Association for the Advancement of Coloured People and the Southern Christian Leadership Conference to call for an investigation by outside authorities.</p>
<p>Although polling conducted for Reuters shows Clinton's lead over Dole narrowing, Clinton campaign officials insisted their extensive polling shows the incumbent with a steady 12 to 15 percentage point lead.</p>
<p>White House Press Secretary Mike McCurry said Clinton had already set off a process to review potential staff changes if he is re-elected. He said Clinton would move quickly to reshape his administration, including some Cabinent officers.</p>
<p>Officials said there were no plans for a massive shakeup, although several key Clinton confidants are expected to leave. White House Chief of Staff Leon Panetta has said he planned to step down.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNION, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
