<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16267" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>LIBERIA: Liberia's Taylor offers demobilisation gesture.</title>
<headline>Liberia's Taylor offers demobilisation gesture.</headline>
<byline>Jackson Kanneh</byline>
<dateline>MONROVIA 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Faction leader Charles Taylor, the man who launched Liberia's civil war in 1989, has pledged to demobilise 3,000 fighters and disarm 500 others over the next two weeks to speed up the peace process.</p>
<p>Taylor, who has his sights set on presidential elections next year, also ordered his supporters to return any vehicles or equipment looted from aid agencies during militia battles in the capital in April and May.</p>
<p>&quot;As I said before, for Charles Taylor the war is over and I will lay claims to no territory,&quot; he told reporters on Monday shortly before leaving for Europe.</p>
<p>He said he would disarm his first battalion of 500 men and demobilise 3,000 other fighters over the next two weeks.</p>
<p>U.N. military observers estimate that Taylor has 30,000 fighters in his National Patriotic Front of Liberia.</p>
<p>Taylor invited West African ECOMOG peacekeepers and U.N. military observers into areas under his control to document the demobilisation and return of weapons. &quot;ECOMOG will move into these areas without requesting our permission.&quot;</p>
<p>The peacekeepers are overseeing implementation of the latest Liberia peace accord signed in Nigeria on August 17. It sets a timetable for disarmament by the end of January and elections on May 30, 1997.</p>
<p>West African heads of state have threatened sanctions against individual faction leaders to ensure compliance.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali warned Liberians on Monday that the international community could abandon Liberia if the peace deal fell apart again.</p>
<p>A ceasefire was supposed to come into force on August 20. Rival factions have spoken of breaches in the west and south east. Peacekeepers say they have no independent confirmation.</p>
<p>Freed American slaves founded Liberia in 1847. The war has killed well over 150,000 people. Hundreds more died during clashes in Monrovia in April and May between ethnic Krahn fighters and supporters of Taylor and Alhaji Kromah, his fellow vice-chairman on the ruling State Council.</p>
<p>&quot;I know some people have no chances of winning elections, so they might want to draw me into another mess so that Charles Taylor can be disqualified to run for elections,&quot; Taylor said, adding: &quot;I'm not going to let it happen.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONROVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LIBERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
