<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16273" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FOCUS - S.Africa's Stals walks tightrope on rates.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - S.Africa's Stals walks tightrope on rates.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>PRETORIA 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African interest rates remain under upward pressure but Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals said on Tuesday he was not convinced of the need for an immediate hike.</p>
<p>Walking a tightrope between approving an increase in already punitive rates and sanctioning a relaxation in monetary policy, Stals said the Bank faced conflicting pulls.</p>
<p>&quot;A rise in interest rates at this stage...is widely regarded as unacceptable because of its adverse effect on domestic spending,&quot; he told the central bank's annual meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;This limited view, however, disregards the even more disastrous consequences for the economy of not correcting a non-sustainable deficit in the overall balance of payments.&quot;</p>
<p>For the time being, however, Stals said an increase in the key Bank rate, currently 16 percent, did not appear necessary.</p>
<p>&quot;We just do not at this stage feel it is necessary to increase the bank rate right now,&quot; he said in separate comments to reporters.</p>
<p>South Africa's money market -- faced with a slump in foreign inflows in the wake of the rand's 20 percent fall this year -- is being squeezed as a deficit on the balance of payments effectively drains liquidity, hitting banks' margins.</p>
<p>That has lead to speculation Stals might be forced to hike, despite fears this could tip South Africa into recession next year.</p>
<p>Economists said Stals, who reiterated that &quot;unacceptably high&quot; money supply required a continued restrictive monetary policy, had played a shrewd hand in his closely-watched speech.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think he is going to really move on interest rates but he is keeping the market on its toes,&quot; said Herman van Papendorp of stockbroker SMK Securities.</p>
<p>The rand took heart from the address, gaining a cent against the dollar to 4.52.</p>
<p>Stals said there were already clear signals of a cyclical slowdown in South Africa's rate of economic growth.</p>
<p>Central Statistical Service data on Tuesday showed that gross domestic product increased by an annualised 3.5 percent in the second quarter, but for the full year Stals said it appeared that growth would total around three percent.</p>
<p>A significantly better performance was needed to dent unemployment, he said. In 1995, when GDP grew by 3.3 percent, total employment in the formal non-agriculture sector rose by only 0.6 percent.</p>
<p>But despite South Africa's balance of payment problems, acute unemployement and economic slowdown, Stals said foreign exchange dealers had over-reacted in selling the rand.</p>
<p>&quot;The exchange rate of the rand...now surely does not reflect the true economic potential of the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The central bank would continue to provide assistance to the foreign exchange market by selling foreign currency from the official reserves, supplemented by available foreign credit facilities if necessary, Stals said.</p>
<p>This had already resulted in an increase in the bank's net oversold foreign exchange position to over $15 billion after it had declined to only $8.1 billion at the end of February 1996.</p>
<p>In the present difficult conditions, Stals also warned that banks could run into trouble by over-lending to the private sector.</p>
<p>South Africa's accumulated household debt had risen to over 66 percent of personal disposable income. &quot;The situation... casts some doubt on the quality of the loan book of banking institutions,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRETORIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
