<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162785" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries end up on eve of election, refunding.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries end up on eve of election, refunding.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries ended higher on Monday, the eve of the U.S. election and a three-part $38.5 billion government refunding effort.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is remarkably firm,&quot; said John Wilson, executive vice president and chief economist at Bank of America. &quot;They're looking at the world as if it's Nirvana. Everything is going their way. Inflation is low. The fundamentals of the economy are an A+ by (Federal Reserve Chairman Alan) Greenspan &amp; Company.&quot;  </p>
<p>Even uncertainties with regard to the balance of power in the U.S. Congress after Tuesday's election did not seem to plague the market on Monday, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The election doesn't seem to be bothering them,&quot; said Wilson. &quot;The bond market assumes the Senate will remain Republican and that a Republican Senate would block any wild expenditure plans a Democratic House might make.&quot;</p>
<p>The 6-3/4 percent 30-year bond finished near its highest level of the day, ending at 101-4/32, up 7/32 to yield 6.66 percent.  </p>
<p>Raymond Worseck, chief economist at A.G. Edwards &amp; Sons Inc., said lower commodity prices aided the bond market. The CRB (Commodity Research Bureau) index ended at 236.52, down 0.78, on Monday.</p>
<p>But Worseck said what has generally supported the market has been &quot;the trio of reports that came out last week reflecting a slower growth, low-inflation economy -- the third-quarter Employment Cost Index (ECI), the third-quarter GDP (Gross Domestic Product) deflator and the (October) hourly earnings on Friday that showed no increase at all.&quot;  </p>
<p>Those reports caused Worseck to change his forecast for higher interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;We had thought yields would go up right away and after seeing these numbers, we said there was overwhelming evidence that while we might not be wrong in the long run, we were certainly wrong in the short run because inflation is not a clear and present danger,&quot; said Worseck.</p>
<p>Chris Rupkey, vice president and economist at Bank of Tokyo/Mitsubishi, said Monday's gain could be nothing more than a reversal of Friday's decline.  </p>
<p>&quot;A lot of times we reverse Friday's direction the following Monday,&quot; said Rupkey. &quot;We've had a lot of strong Fridays and people sell it off on Monday so this was the reverse. People sold on Friday and bought on Monday.&quot;</p>
<p>Rupkey said there was some buying in the three-year sector ahead of Tuesday's $18.5 billion three-year Treasury note auction, the first part of a three-legged refunding effort that will include a $10.0 billion sale of 10-year notes on Wednesday and a $10.0 billion auction of 30-year bonds on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Traditionally, the three-year note goes the best (of the three auctions,&quot; said Rupkey.</p>
<p>In when-issued trade, the three-year notes to be sold on Tuesday ended with a 5.9025 percent yield.</p>
<p>On Monday, three-month bill rates fell two basis points to 5.01 percent on Monday. Six-month bills and year bill rates each fell one basis point to 5.08 percent and 5.16 percent.</p>
<p>Two-year notes rose one basis point to 100-6/32 to 5.77 percent. Five-year notes finished up 3/32 to 100-22/32, yielding 6.09 percent.</p>
<p>Ten-year notes rose 7/32 to close at 101-4/32, yielding 6.34 percent.</p>
<p>--North American Treasury Desk, 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
