<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="162875" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Argentine opposition calls for political openness.</title>
<headline>Argentine opposition calls for political openness.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Argentine opposition leader said Monday that corruption existed at high levels of the country's government, and must be addressed to build public confidence and sustained economic growth.</p>
<p>Senator Graciela Fernndez Meijide of the center-left Frepaso alliance said Argentina needed to build public trust through governance based on increased transparency and concensus building.</p>
<p>&quot;The corruption we have today is a serious thing,&quot; Fernndez Meijide told an audience at the Americas Society here. &quot;Corruption reaches to very high levels.&quot;  </p>
<p>Corruption and &quot;mafias&quot; existed in public institutions, and the Argentine people have lost confidence in political institutions, Fernndez Meijide said. And the political leadership lacked a strong consensus to fight corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to change the arbitrary style of government,&quot; she said. &quot;Control of the fiscal deficit and inflation is not enough to bring sustained growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Fernndez Meijide said that former Economy Minister Domingo Cavallo, who last month accused two cabinet ministers of having manipulated judges and state prosecutors, had been well acquainted with the inner workings of the government.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if (Cavallo) has proof or not, but he knows what he's talking about,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The Frepaso leader said her party would seek to forge alliances going forward with social sectors, labor and environmental groups, Peronists not tied to President Carlos Menem, and the Radical party. &quot;We are thinking of a broad, large alliance,&quot; Fernndez Meijide said.</p>
<p>Noting that her party had grown at the expense of the Radicals, she said that Argentines would not forgive the two parties if they did not unite by the 1999 elections.  </p>
<p>&quot;For 1997, I think this alliance (with the Radicals) will be very difficult,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Frepaso would seek greater economic flexibility, and this could mean a departure from the Convertibility Plan that ended Argentina's hyperinflation, but only in a form that provided continued stability, Fernndez Meijide said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think anyone in Argentina is crazy enough to propose economic measures that would disrupt the benefits of Convertibility,&quot; she said. &quot;We are trying to find ways to leave Convertibility without provoking instability.&quot;</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212 859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
