<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163092" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECH PM'S PARTY, SOCDEMS FAVOURED IN SENATE - POLL.</title>
<headline>CZECH PM'S PARTY, SOCDEMS FAVOURED IN SENATE - POLL.</headline>
<byline>Klara Gajduskova</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus's Civic Democratic Party (ODS), and the leading opposition Social Democrats (CSSD) should send the most candidates into the final round of two-step Senate elections, a survey showed on Monday.</p>
<p>In the most extensive poll to date simulating the first Czech Senate races scheduled for later this month, the independent agency Factum forecast that 79 candidates of the ODS should make it to the second round, and 73 for CSSD.</p>
<p>The poll conducted for the daily Mlada Fronta Dnes, Czech Radio and TV Premiera asked a total of 12,000 Czech citizens comprising cross-sections in each constituency their voting preference in the first round scheduled for November 15-16.</p>
<p>The survey said 41 of the total 81 constituencies would most likely see a second-round battle between an ODS and a CSSD candidate, and no candidate is likely to be elected in the first round.</p>
<p>A total of 19 candidates of the junior partner in the centre-right ruling coalition, the Christian and Democratic Union (KDU-CSL), were forecast to go through, Factum said.</p>
<p>Another 16 candidates of the other coalition party, the Civic Democratic Aliance (ODA), would make it to the second round, as well as 10 nominated by the Communists (KSCM), seven independents, and one of the Moravia/Silesia Coaliton.</p>
<p>Factum is currently finalising results of a new survey, using the candidates forecast to go through from the first round, and asking whom voters would choose in the second round on November 22-23. That survey is to be released on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Senate elections are to fill the upper chamber of Czech parliament, which is primarily an advisory body with limited legislative powers.</p>
<p>But the vote will be the first test of the electorate since Klaus's three-party coalition lost its large marjority in parliament after a stronger-than-expected second place showing by the Social Democrats in June elections to the lower house.</p>
<p>According to Czech law, if no candidate in a constituency gets over 50 percent of votes cast in the first round, there is a second round with the top two candidates from the first poll.</p>
<p>In the survey released on Monday, Factum added third and fourth placing candidates in a handful of constituencies where the race is too close to call.</p>
<p>The Senate elections differ from the lower house poll which is done proportionally, based on nationwide party perference.</p>
<p>A total 29 political parties nominated candidates in the various constituencies.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
