<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163055" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-DELY VALDES HELPS PSG TO BRILLIANT RECOVERY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DELY VALDES HELPS PSG TO BRILLIANT RECOVERY.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Vignal</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Less than a week ago, Paris St Germain striker Julio Cesar Dely Valdes was rumoured to be on his way to Blackburn or elsewhere but the Panamanian then scored three goals in two matches to make clear he was staying put.</p>
<p>&quot;I've always wanted to stay here,&quot; said Dely Valdes after helping the Paris club shake off a looming crisis and reestablish themselves as a dominant force in European soccer.</p>
<p>On the eve of Thursday's Cup winners' Cup tie with Turkish side Galatasaray, press reports said Dely Valdes would certainly leave as Paris were about to sign Brazilian striker Luizao.</p>
<p>The Cup winners' Cup holders had lost the first leg 4-2 in Istanbul and were worried they might lose their trophy.</p>
<p>They were also in an uncomfortable situation in the domestic league after two poor results -- a 1-1 draw to champions Auxerre and a 2-1 defeat at Rennes.</p>
<p>But Dely Valdes woke up just in time, scoring one goal and playing a crucial part in his side's 4-0 demolition of Galatasaray which allowed Paris to book a place in the quarter-finals of the Cup winners' Cup.</p>
<p>Just three days later, he scored a double to help PSG crush Bastia 3-0 in the French league on Sunday and recapture the lead from main rivals Monaco.</p>
<p>Dely Valdes, by no means a genius but a powerful, useful scorers, is now looking forward to Wednesday's match at lowly Nice which should allow PSG to stay firmly in command.</p>
<p>With just two goals in 14 league matches until Sunday, Dely Valdes had not given satisfaction, to say the least. But now, PSG say they are not looking for anyone else.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that several european clubs were after him and it would have been easy for us to transfer him but we simply didn't want to&quot;, said Paris deputy chairman Michel Denisot.</p>
<p>Everybody at PSG was delighted after the win over Bastia, starting with midfielder Vincent Guerin, slowly recapturing his best form after a sluggish start to the season.</p>
<p>&quot;We had to recapture the lead in the league after our beautiful victory in the Cup winners' Cup,&quot; Guerin said. &quot;The season is far from being over and we will probably not always be in the lead but at the moment, we are so let's enjoy it.&quot;</p>
<p>Dely Valdes was not the only one to recapture his scoring instinct as fellow striker Patrice Loko struck twice in PSG's last two matches.</p>
<p>&quot;We're playing well at the moment because we have been training together for several days,&quot; said international Loko. &quot;I'm happy to have scored two goals in as many matches but the most important thing to me is the team as a whole.&quot;</p>
<p>Denisot said he was confident about the future of his side.</p>
<p>&quot;The three teams in front at the moment (PSG, Monaco and Auxerre) will battle it out for the title,&quot; he predicted. &quot;It's been a very, very good week for us. The group is very strong and I believe we will be strong all through the season. Maybe we will have less successful periods than this one but I see us going very far.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
