<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163038" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-EAGLES BEAT COWBOYS ON END-ZONE INTERCEPTION FOR TD.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-EAGLES BEAT COWBOYS ON END-ZONE INTERCEPTION FOR TD.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-11-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philadelphia Eagles beat the Dallas Cowboys 31-21 Sunday on the kind of play defences dream about: an end-zone interception, a run to daylight, a lateral and a 90-yard touchdown scamper.</p>
<p>Trailing 24-21, Dallas had the ball 1st-and-goal at the Eagles' 3-yard line with 1:16 to go in the fourth quarter. The Eagle defence held Emmitt Smith for just one yard on first down, then stuffed him for a one-yard loss.</p>
<p>On third down, linebacker James Willis intercepted a pass by Troy Aikman in the end zone, ran out to the 10, then lateraled to Troy Vincent, who raced 90 yards for a touchdown with 22 seconds left in the game.</p>
<p>&quot;It was my first interception,&quot; said Willis. &quot;That's big. I was too tired to keep it, though.&quot;</p>
<p>The win moved the Eagles (7-2) into a first-place tie with Washington in the NFC East, two games ahead of Dallas (5-4), and snapped Dallas's four-game win streak.</p>
<p>&quot;We fought them for four quarters,&quot; said Eagles coach Ray Rhodes. &quot;We talked about stepping up and making plays. The theme of our team is to find a way to win every week.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Today, we snatched defeat from the jaws of victory,&quot; said Cowboys coach Barry Switzer. &quot;I don't think there was anyone here that didn't think we would win the game with 40 seconds left and the ball at the 3-yard line.&quot;</p>
<p>Ty Detmer completed 19-of-33 passes for 217 yards and a touchdown, and ran for a score for Philadelphia. Ricky Watters rushed for 116 yards and a TD on 24 carries.</p>
<p>Aikman was 21-of-33 for 189 yards. Smith rushed for 113 yards and two touchdowns on 24 carries.</p>
<p>In Buffalo, Darick Holmes rushed for 122 yards and three touchdowns and Thurman Thomas added 107 yards and a score as the Bills ended the seven-game win streak of the Washington Redskins, 38-13.</p>
<p>Jim Kelly was 19-for-23 for 206 yards and also ran for a score for the Bills (6-3), who amassed 266 yards on the ground and stayed tied for the AFC East lead with New England. Buffalo had five rushing touchdowns, tying a team record.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess I'm not dead yet,&quot; joked Kelly, &quot;but seriously the running game with Darick and Thurman Thomas made it easy for me.&quot;</p>
<p>In Indianapolis, the San Diego Chargers intercepted Jim Harbaugh four times and John Carney kicked four field goals in a 26-19 victory over the Colts.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't get the job done,&quot; said Harbaugh.</p>
<p>Sean Salisbury made his second straight start at quarterback for the injured Stan Humphries and passed for 237 yards and two touchdowns with no interceptions for San Diego.</p>
<p>At New England, Drew Bledsoe threw for 419 yards and three touchdowns, two of them to tight end Ben Coates, and Curtis Martin added three scoring plunges as the Patriots beat the Miami Dolphins 42-23.</p>
<p>Bledsoe, who was 30-for-41, gave New England a momentum-building 21-17 lead midway through the third quarter when he hit Coates for a 23-yard score after a controversial fumble call against Miami's Karim Abdul-Jabbar, who ran for 104 yards on 29 carries.</p>
<p>In Green Bay, Brett Favre threw four TD passes -- two to Terry Mickens -- and spoiled the return of Don Majkowski to Lambeau Field as the Packers beat the Detroit Lions 28-18.</p>
<p>Majkowski, starting for the injured Scott Mitchell for Detroit, was quarterback of the Packers from 1987-92.</p>
<p>Green Bay (8-1) has won five straight.</p>
<p>In Atlanta, the Falcons (1-8) became the last NFL team to win this season, beating the Carolina Panthers 20-17 as Jamal Anderson ran for 109 yards and a touchdown.</p>
<p>In Seattle, defensive end Michael McCrary blocked a field goal, scooped it up and lateraled to Robert Blackmon, who returned it 61 yards for a touchdown with four seconds left to lift the Seahawks past the Houston Oilers, 23-16.</p>
<p>At Minnesota, Greg Hill ran for two touchdowns in a 25-second span late in the fourth quarter as the Kansas City Chiefs beat the Vikings 21-6.</p>
<p>Minnesota played without starting quarterback Warren Moon and running back Robert Smith.</p>
<p>At New York, Brad Daluiso kicked three field goals and back-up quarterback Danny Kanell, inserted when Dave Brown suffered back spasms after a first-quarter sack, threw his first career touchdown as the Giants beat the Arizona Cardinals 16-8.</p>
<p>In Pittsburgh, Jerome Bettis rushed for 129 yards and two touchdowns in his first game against his former team and quarterback Kordell Stewart added a pair of scoring runs as the Steelers crushed the St Louis Rams 42-6.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Raymont Harris ran for 118 yards and scored on a one-yard plunge midway through the third quarter, taking advantage of Errict Rhett's fumble, as the Bears edged the Tampa Bay Buccaneers 13-10.</p>
<p>In Baltimore, Doug Pelfrey's third field goal of the game, a 34-yarder as time expired, gave the Cincinnati Bengals a come-from-behind 24-21 triumph over the Ravens.</p>
<p>Cincinnati erased a 21-3 halftime deficit.  </p>
<p>:</p>
<p>In New Orleans, Jerry Rice reached another milestone with his 1,000th career reception and Steve Young ran and threw for touchdowns, leading the San Francisco 49ers to a 24-17 victory over the Saints.</p>
<p>Rice, who holds NFL records in catches, yards and touchdowns, caught a nine-yard pass before stepping out of bounds at the New Orleans 2-yard line for his 1,000th catch. On 4th-and-1, Young scored on a quarterback sneak to give the 49ers a 24-14 advantage 3:29 into the fourth quarter.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
