<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163096" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLSKA NAFTA OIL HOLDING SAYS REFINERY SALES URGENT.</title>
<headline>POLSKA NAFTA OIL HOLDING SAYS REFINERY SALES URGENT.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's oil industry holding group Nafta Polska SA, created to manage and restructure the state-owned sector, said privatisation of the country's seven oil refineries was its most urgent task.</p>
<p>&quot;Privatisation (of refineries) is urgently needed because of large demand for financial sources in the ever-less-attractive refining sector (as import barriers are lifted),&quot; Nafta Polska said in a statement outlining its strategy to the year 2000.</p>
<p>Nafta Polska said it would not only act as an owner of its subsidiaries but would also be implementing the government policy for the whole sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Nafta Polska is not a typical company seeking to maximise profits...it needs to create and initiate systems, laws and other regulations regarding the whole sector,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Nafta Polska reaffirmed its intention to sell between 20 and 30 percent stakes of the two biggest Polish refineries, based in the cities of Plock and Gdansk, which would serve as pillars under which the remaining refineries would be grouped.</p>
<p>It said it planned to sell a 100 percent stake in southern refineries, which concentrate on oil by-products, but said it had not determined whether these refineries would be grouped under the two pillars or with other foreign investors.</p>
<p>Under the government scheme, investors buying stakes would also gain access to the lucrative retail network of state-owned petrol distributor CPN SA, which is to join Nafta Polska by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>The investors would later be able to extend their stakes and Nafta Polska itself would eventually be privatised.</p>
<p>The holding was created in May to strengthen the oil sector ahead of the opening of Poland's fuels market to outside competition, due in the next few years.</p>
<p>All of Nafta Polska's strategic decisions now have to be approved by the government as the holding carries out the country's oil sector policy.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
