<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163280" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Sasol says not withdrawing from fuel market.</title>
<headline>Sasol says not withdrawing from fuel market.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sasol Ltd said on Monday that it had no intention of withdrawing from the fuels and lubricants markets and was currently looking into establishing a retail service station network.</p>
<p>The statement was made in response to newspaper reports which gave competing oil and fuels firm Engen Ltd's perceptions of Sasol's strategy and future plans.</p>
<p>&quot;Recent reports in the print media gave the impression that there is uncertainty about Sasol's future plans regarding the marketing of fuels and lubricants. This is not correct.</p>
<p>&quot;Sasol is surprised that a company (Engen) in the oil industry announced to the media their perceptions of Sasol's strategy and plans for the future,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Sasol said it had repeatedly stated its intention to fully integrate its crude oil refining activities, from exploration to retail marketing.</p>
<p>This, it said, could be achieved through Sasol Oil, the subsidiary in the Sasol Group which is responsible for the refining of crude oil at the Natref refinery.</p>
<p>&quot;Since Sasol does not presently market its fuels and lubricants through a fully fledged retail service station network, the establishment of such a network is presently being addressed.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
