<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163294" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Tanzania pins big hopes on investment forum.</title>
<headline>Tanzania pins big hopes on investment forum.</headline>
<byline>Mark Dodd</byline>
<dateline>DAR ES SALAAM 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The biggest investors' forum in Tanzania's history opens in the capital Dar es Salaam on Tuesday, underlining the impoverished country's ambitions to be a stable and competitive economic base in East Africa.</p>
<p>On the eve of the forum, President Benjamin Mkapa's office announced that Finance Minister Professor Simon Mbilinyi had resigned to pave the way for investigations of charges of corruption against him and other senior government officials.</p>
<p>&quot;Mbilinyi's was a test case. How would the minister face an international investor conference with charges of corruption on his head? How would that serve as a barometer for confidence. Mbilinyi had to go,&quot; a Western diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>Close to 300 foreign firms have confirmed their attendance at the November 5-8 forum, more than double the number originally expected, Trade Minister Abdallah Kigoda said.</p>
<p>Kigoda said the forum would be an important springboard for building investor confidence in Tanzania, one of the world's poorest countries, now trying to shake off the legacy of almost 30 years of debilitating socialist-inspired economic policies.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the important objectives for this forum is to tell the investors that Tanzania is a viable destination for investment,&quot; Kigoda said. He promised investors that Tanzania was a land of &quot;untapped potential&quot;.</p>
<p>Exhibits will cover sectors ranging from agro-industry to textiles, leather products, paper, printing products, chemicals, tourism, mining, pharmaceuticals, non-metallic minerals and infrastructure.</p>
<p>Despite a host of obstacles for potential foreign investors, diplomats and business analysts believe Tanzania is on the road to economic recovery and its efforts should be rewarded.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (Tanzania) is tremendously exciting. There seems now to be a possibility to really get things moving.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the very positive things about Tanzania is that there has been peace for such a long time and while political uncertainty remains around Zanzibar, the rest of the country remains amazingly stable,&quot; said a senior Nordic businessman.</p>
<p>The businessman said his multinational company, with an annual turnover worth tens of millions of dollars, had more than 20 years' experience in Tanzania. He hoped some lucrative deals would be sealed at the forum, sponsored by the U.N. Industrial Development Organisation.</p>
<p>Tanzania's infrastructure remains woefully inadequate. Rail links, roads and communications are in a pathetic state.</p>
<p>Visitors to the billing department in the Dar es Salaam office of state-run Tanzania Telephone Co Ltd would be forgiven for thinking they had arrived at a paper recycling dump.</p>
<p>Stoic customers queue for hours to enquire about bills or disconnections. Not surprising, mobile phone services provided by two private firms are thriving despite their hefty charges.</p>
<p>Potential investors will meet a daunting bureaucratic maze. To cut red tape, the International Monetary Fund (IMF) has made heavy cuts to the state payroll a precondition for Tanzania's eligibility for an Enhanced Structural Adjustment Facility.</p>
<p>Corruption has also emerged as an increasing problem. The government has repeatedly vowed to tackle corruption and Mbilinyi's departure will be a pointer.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea of rationalising our tax and tariff structure is one of the modalities we are using to reduce red tape and bureacracy which encourages corruption,&quot; said Kigoda.</p>
<p>One of Tanzania's strongest supporters, Sweden, whose taxpayers have spent more than $3 billion on aid in three decades, is spearheading support for the investment forum.</p>
<p>&quot;We're having 13 Swedish companies. It's very high-level. They really want to penetrate the market,&quot; said Swedish embassy spokeswoman, Jennifer Matafu.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAR ES SALAAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
