<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163392" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Belgrade bourse weekly turnover sharply up.</title>
<headline>Belgrade bourse weekly turnover sharply up.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Belgrade Stock Exchange (BSE) reported on Monday a 67.17 percent jump in its turnover during the week ending November 1, and traders attributed the rise to a big institutional investor appearing on the market.</p>
<p>Total turnover soared to 39.361 million dinars ($7.84 million) from 23.545 million dinars turned over during the previous week. The number of transactions rose to 190 from 156, the bourse said in its report.</p>
<p>Traders ignored Sunday elections and returned to routine with more or less unchanged liquidity. &quot;But one institutional investor comes to the market every month and buys a lot commercial paper,&quot; one trader told Reuters without divulging the investor's identity.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall the situation is no better but no worse than it was a week ago. Investors still withdraw money, they close positions and decide to stay away for a while, but companies seem to get around and find other sources of financing,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>With the reserve requirement up from 10 to 15 percent, the market will face a new wave of tightened liquidity, the trader said.</p>
<p>The bourse traded no central bank short-term bonds over the last week.</p>
<p>Commercial paper segment dominated with 160 transactions worth 27.643 million dinars.</p>
<p>Treasury bills traded 29 times for a volume of 6.559 million dinars.</p>
<p>Interest rate both on commercial paper and treasury bills slightly declined to range between annual 210 and 520 percent.</p>
<p>The bourse reported three deals in wheat selling forward contracts worth 4.8 million dinars. -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
