<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163348" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria's Socialists reel as opposition wins poll.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria's Socialists reel as opposition wins poll.</headline>
<byline>Gareth Jones</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposition candidate Petar Stoyanov swept to a decisive victory in Bulgaria's presidential election in what newspapers hailed on Monday as a powerful blow to the governing Socialist Party.</p>
<p>With most votes counted, official preliminary results gave the pro-reform lawyer of the anti-communist Union of Democratic Forces (UDF) 60 percent of the vote to Socialist Culture Minister Ivan Marazov's 40 percent.</p>
<p>Although the president is a largely ceremonial figure with limited powers, the scale of Stoyanov's victory threw the government onto the defensive and Prime Minister Zhan Videnov, battling a deep economic crisis, promised to take note.</p>
<p>Videnov, in power for nearly two years, said on Sunday a party congress could be held as early as January and did not rule out cabinet changes.</p>
<p>&quot;Petar Stoyanov's crushing victory is the biggest blow for Zhan Videnov since he became prime minister. He has to resign,&quot; said the daily Standart in a front-page editorial.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulgarians have decisively rejected a handful of incompetent officials who have pushed our country to the back of Europe's queue and have driven citizens to the bottom.&quot;</p>
<p>Videnov, often criticised for his secretive and authoritarian style of government, has presided over a big drop in living standards as Bulgaria struggles to meet huge foreign debt payments and kickstart its sluggish reform programme.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulgarians have declared their desire for change, even though the institution of president lacks any real power to alter the country's course,&quot; said the Novinar newspaper.</p>
<p>Outgoing president Zhelyu Zhelev, also a liberal who did not stand for reelection, has frequently wielded his veto over Socialist legislation, frustrating what he saw as the government's attempts to restore communist era practices.</p>
<p>Like Zhelev, Stoyanov has pledged to bring Bulgaria -- which still looks to Moscow, its historical patron, for guidance -- closer to the European Union and NATO.</p>
<p>Stoyanov was careful on Sunday night to avoid direct criticism of the Socialists and proposed a National Salvation Council of experts and respected public figures to advise the government on how to avert economic collapse.</p>
<p>Neighbouring Romania and Yugoslavia, which also held elections on Sunday, face similar difficulties but Bulgaria has the lowest level of foreign investment among the former communist states of eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has managed to privatise only five percent of state industry since the bloodless overthrow of its communist regime seven years ago this month.</p>
<p>This week Bulgarian officials will be locked in vital talks with a visiting mission of the International Monetary Fund, desperately trying to unblock loans to help tide the country through a winter of expected bread and power shortages.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
