<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163451" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugoslav '95 GDP far below govt estimate-Institute.</title>
<headline>Yugoslav '95 GDP far below govt estimate-Institute.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia's gross domestic product in 1995 was less than $10 billion, well below the government's figure of $15.9 billion, an economic think-tank said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our 1995 GDP was between $9 billion and $10 billion,&quot; Stojan Stamenkovic of the Institute of Economic Sciences (IEN) told a news conference and urged the government to review the way it calculated GDP.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia has not settled the issue of its external debt following the breakup of the former Yugoslavia, and a wrongly calculated GDP could affect its debt service terms and benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;Benefits are directly linked to a level of the country's development, and the key figure is its per capita income. The government claims it stands at $1,510 but we think it hardly reaches $1,000,&quot; Stamenkovic said.</p>
<p>Stamenkovic said the official calculation was based on an unrealistic average dinar-dollar rate. Instead of taking a dinar rate of 2.87 to the dollar, the government should have used a more realistic 3.68 dinars to the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;This correction alone would reduce the estimated GDP from $15.9 billion to $12.4 billion,&quot; Stamenkovic said.</p>
<p>When replacement costs of real estate, including housing, and the wrong calculation of inventories are taken into account, GDP falls to between $9 and $10 billion, he added.</p>
<p>The government may have been trying to hide its high public spending, he said. &quot;If their figures are accepted, public spending accounts for around 40 percent of GDP. But if our calculation is used, public spending jumps to 70 percent of GDP,&quot; Stamenkovic told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said IEN refrained from forecasting 1996 GDP because the effects of huge internal indebtedness and deep economic recession are yet to be calculated.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia's gross foreign debt amounted to some $9 billion, excluding so-called non-allocated debt.</p>
<p>&quot;Our whole GDP is indebted. This means we should have no budget and pay no salaries, but only service debts. But it does not happen like that in practice,&quot; Stamenkovic said.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia will have to reorganise its debt and negotiate new terms for debt payment. Meanwhile it will have to start paying interest, he added. &quot;We talk about some $600 million to pay back interest, and for that we need foreign help,&quot; Stamenkovic said.</p>
<p>-- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
