<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163495" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Nov 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Yugoslavia - Nov 4.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Belgrade press on Monday. Reuters has not verified them and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>POLITIKA</p>
<p>- Turnout at Yugoslavia's federal elections was 61%. The left coalition SPS-JUL-DS is overwhelmingly in the lead according to latest unofficial results.</p>
<p>- Montenegro's ruling Democratic Party of Socialists proclaims its victory at the republican elections which were held together with the federal and local elections.</p>
<p>- The country's foreign trade deficit should be reduced to $700 million from $1.2 billion by the end of the year says chairman of the assembly of the Serbian chamber of commerce Rajko Uncanin.</p>
<p>- U.S. human rights envoy John Shattuck says fulfilment of Dayton agreement is in the interest of all parties during his visit to Bosnian Serb town of Banja Luka.</p>
<p>NASA BORBA</p>
<p>- Yugoslavia's foreign debt is not a good investment according to a report of an influential investment bank in London.</p>
<p>- Serbian electricity company (EPS) is completing negotiations wiht the help of Beobanka Ad for a Czech loan of $100 million to continue construction of thermal power plant Kolubara B. It has almost secured an additional $60 million from other foreign partners.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVOSTI</p>
<p>- Vranje furniture factory Simpo registers good sales on domestic market and expects to earn $40 million from exports by the end of the year which is 20 percent higher than the previous year. -- Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
