<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163497" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo c.bank raises reserve requirement to 15 pct.</title>
<headline>Yugo c.bank raises reserve requirement to 15 pct.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Yugoslav central bank kept its discount rate for November unchanged at 4.5 percent, or 68.15 percent a year, but raised the reserve requirement by five points to 15 percent, a central bank official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We decided not to change the discount rate because we wanted to keep investor interest in dinar funds, and prevent flight to other currencies,&quot; central bank Vice-Governor Ratko Banovic told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, we decided to raise the reserve requirement from 10 to 15 percent, because the fourth quarter is normally more dynamic, and we need to act in advance to keep the monetary stability throughout the last quarter,&quot; Banovic said.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Yugoslavia (NBY) was closely watching monetary developments on a daily basis, he added.</p>
<p>The NBY Vice-Governor rejected bankers' appeals for a lower discount rate to enable more lending activity and reduce borrowing costs for companies.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank cut its discount rate sharply in June, but commercial lending rates remained unchanged,&quot; Banovic said.</p>
<p>Referring to the reserve requirement, Banovic explained that &quot;the end of every year is marked by surging liquidity within the banking sector, and we want to sop up surplus liquidity.&quot;</p>
<p>The reserve requrement went up also because it needed to make up for a low buying interest for the NBY short-term bonds sold via the Belgrade bourse.</p>
<p>The bonds, first launched late in November 1995, were aimed at regulating market liquidity. But they did not always live up to their task.</p>
<p>However, NBY was not worried by investors moving out of bonds, Banovic said, adding that producers began to invest more in raw material purchases to prepare for the coming season.</p>
<p>&quot;Instead of playing on the bourse, they put money into real production,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
