<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163400" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish official rates to ease in '97- budget bill.</title>
<headline>Polish official rates to ease in '97- budget bill.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's 1997 budget draft assumes a drop in the central bank's average nominal interest rates next year and a stabilisation of real interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1997 (interest rate) forecast is based on the assumption that the NBP will continue to conduct a cautious interest rate policy with their real-term level kept at levels observed in the past,&quot; the budget draft said.</p>
<p>It also said that the level of this year's average official interest rates used for calculations was based on the assumption that the NBP would cut its rates again before the end of this year if inflation keeps falling.</p>
<p>It said the average Lombard rate was likely to ease to 20.1-23.1 percent in 1997 from this year's expected average of 25.5 percent. The rate is now at 25 percent.</p>
<p>The government expects the average discount rate in 1997 to fall to between 17.1 and 20.1 percent from the expected average of 22.5 percent this year. The discount rate is now 22 percent.</p>
<p>The year-on-year consumer price index in September eased to 19.5 percent from 21.6 percent in December 1995 and the government said in the draft it expected it to fall to 17.8 percent next month.</p>
<p>The draft assumes a deficit of 2.6 percent of gross domestic product, unchanged tax levels in 1997 and a 5.5 percent GDP growth, was submitted to parliament last week.</p>
<p>But the final shape of the budget depends on the parliament's decision on 1997 taxes and the government signalled it would amend the draft and propose a 2.8 percent deficit if its planned moderate tax cuts won parliamentary approval.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Poland has said such a budget would require a tightening of its monetary policy and would call for a revision of the government's projections of interest rates.</p>
<p>-- Jan Strupczewski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
