<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163463" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Security tight around Yeltsin heart op hospital.</title>
<headline>Security tight around Yeltsin heart op hospital.</headline>
<byline>Chris Bird</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A tight security cordon was thrown around Moscow's Cardiology Research Centre on Monday, where Russian President Boris Yeltsin will undergo a heart bypass operation.</p>
<p>On a grey, foggy morning, militia officers patrolled the roads and entrances around the hospital, a series of nondescript buildings of concrete and glass amid silver birch trees to the west of the Russian capital.</p>
<p>A guard in combat fatigues led a sniffer dog on a leash over a Volga sedan car while another officer checked the underside of the vehicle with a mirror before letting its driver through iron gates into the compound.</p>
<p>More security guards wearing red armbands walked around the grounds inside. An official car, black with a blue light on top, raced past.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not too cold,&quot; said one officer, used to standing out in the city's sub-zero winter temperatures, a fur hat wedged on his head, a khaki anorak buttoned up tight. He pleaded with a television crew not to come too close.</p>
<p>Comments on the weather were all the tight-lipped security guards would volunteer.</p>
<p>A tired-looking doctor clutching a briefcase stopped before one of the gates and said he could not see what all the fuss was about.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just a bypass operation, it's routine for us,&quot; said the doctor who said he worked at the hospital but who declined to give his name.</p>
<p>Sofia Tsiplova, 59, and wearing a smart velvet hat, waited for a bus home outside the hospital after collecting medicines for her own heart condition.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he (Yeltsin) will be fine,&quot; said Tsiplova. &quot;He's not the first -- they also operated on (Prime Minister Viktor) Chernomyrdin and he runs about like anything now.&quot;</p>
<p>Tsiplova said she had noticed no extraordinary activity inside the hospital. &quot;They checked my documents carefully but it was quiet inside,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Only Valentina Gorshkova, another 59-year-old pensioner walking past the hospital with a bright purple coat that stood out in the damp grey weather, showed any concern: &quot;Of course we worry about his (Yeltsin's) operation...we're all human.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
