<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163412" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish zloty seen down 12-13 pct vs basket in 1997.</title>
<headline>Polish zloty seen down 12-13 pct vs basket in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty is likely to fall between 12 and 13 percent against a basket of currencies next year because the expected growth of official currency reserves will be small, the government said in its 1997 budget draft.</p>
<p>It said the monthly zloty devaluation mechanism, called the crawling peg, would account for the zloty's softening of 9.1 percent against the currency basket in 1997, against this year's 12.7 percent. The devalution rate is now at one percent.</p>
<p>The government expects the crawling peg rate, set by the independent central bank after consultations with the finance and foreign trade ministries, will not change this year. @</p>
<p>It said the zloty was also likely to weaken from its current position of some 1.7 percent from the trading band centre on the appreciation side to the depreciation side.</p>
<p>&quot;Due to the expected slow-down of the growth of official reserves next year, the zloty is likely to change position in within the trading band and at the end of next year will lean towards depreciation,&quot; the draft said.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking into account the monthly devaluation rate and the change of the zloty's position within the band the average devaluation of the zloty's market rate against the basket of currencies in 1997 will be 12-13 percent,&quot; it said. @</p>
<p>The government expects the zloty to end this year at about 1.3 to 1.7 percent on the appreciation side from the centre of the trading band against just under 2.0 percent on Monday.</p>
<p>It also said it expected the current trading band for the zloty, set at seven percent above and seven percent below the floating parity rate calculated daily by the central bank, would remain unchanged next year.</p>
<p>The draft, which targets a deficit of 2.6 percent of gross domestic product and assumes unchanged tax levels in 1997 was submitted to parliament last week. @</p>
<p>But the final shape of the budget depends on the parliament's decision on 1997 taxes and the government signalled it would amend the draft if its proposed moderate tax cuts won parliamentary approval.</p>
<p>-- Jan Strupczewski +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
