<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163507" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Nov 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Nov 4.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Monday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- Defence Minister Gojko Susak who has recently been on a working visit to Washington obtained guarantees that the U.S. would support reintegration of Eastern Slavonia into Croatia by June 1997 at the latest.</p>
<p>- From 1997, citizens should be able to get favourable thirty-year housing loans at a one percent annual interest, says Djuro Njavro, president's advisor for economy.</p>
<p>- Entrepreneur Luka Rajic, owner of the Dukat dairy, is poised to become a majority shareholder in another diary, Sirela, where he currenlty holds 42 percent.</p>
<p>- Mayor of Mostar, Croat Ivica Prskalo, has accused European Union special envoy in the town Sir Martin Garrod of bias against Croats.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Experts estimate prices of newly built flats might increase by 11 to 18 percent in January due to value added tax.</p>
<p>- &quot;I'll bring back Blaskic to Zagreb,&quot; says Anto Nobilo, newly appointed defence counsel of Bosnian Croat General Tihomir Blaskic, due to appear before U.N. war crimes tribunal in January.</p>
<p>- Local Serb and Croatian politicians are stalling the peaceful reintegration of Eastern Slavonia, says U.N. transitional administrator for the region Jacques Klein in an interview.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Our main aim is to enter Croatian parliament, says Croatian branch of Bosnia's ruling Moslem Party of Democratic Action (SDA) at a convention held in Zagreb.</p>
<p>- &quot;We'll create a strong army,&quot; says Joseph L. Allred, spokesman of Militry Professional Resources Inc., a firm in charge of the American 'Equip and Train' programme for Bosnia's Moslem-Croat federation.</p>
<p>- Heavy-weight boxer Zeljko Mavrovic defends the title of European champion, after he knocked out a Britih challenger in the second round. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
