<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163625" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: INP hopes to reach 90 pct of NZ's W&amp;H.</title>
<headline>INP hopes to reach 90 pct of NZ's W&amp;H.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Independent Newspapers Plc Managing Director of International Operations Brendan Hopkins said on Tuesday the Dublin-based group was hopeful of gaining 90 percent of New Zealand publisher Wilson and Horton through its current bid.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we'd be hopeful of getting to the 90 percent,&quot; Hopkins said in a television interview.  </p>
<p>Asked if INP would look at extending the bid, which expires on Friday, Hopkins said: &quot;Obviously our advisers are looking at that very closely at the moment. If we extend, we would have to give a 48 hour notice period. I think a lot of it depends on the flow of shareholder acceptances that are still coming in.&quot;  </p>
<p>Ninety percent is the level at which INP could compulsorily acquire the rest of the shares.</p>
<p>Hopkins said INP was currently at 69 percent but &quot;the acceptances are now accelerating quite significantly&quot;. He said most of the outstanding shares were held by institutions.</p>
<p>INP, through its unit Independent Press Communications Ltd, is bidding for all of Wilson and Horton at NZ$11.00 or 1.375 exchangeable INP shares for each W&amp;H share.</p>
<p>Independent Newspapers and family trusts linked to principal Tony O'Reilly held 45.15 percent of Wilson and Horton prior to the current bid.  </p>
<p>Wilson and Horton shares were trading up a cent at $11.01 on thin volume. -- Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
