<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163618" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Rising kiwi a billion-dlr burden - NZ Dairy Board.</title>
<headline>Rising kiwi a billion-dlr burden - NZ Dairy Board.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The rising value of the New Zealand dollar against the U.S. is a billion-dollar burden for the dairy industry, Dairy Board chairman Sir Dryden Spring said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Kiwi has appreciated 27 percent against the U.S. dollar in the last three years.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential, cumulative effect of that appreciation would be to wipe NZ$1.1 billion of the board's earnings over that period,&quot; Spring told Tuesday's annual meeting of the board in Wellington.  </p>
<p>Last week, wool industry executives said New Zealand's productive sector was being &quot;skinned alive&quot; by the continuing rise in the value of the dollar.</p>
<p>Spring said monetary policy was a &quot;blunt instrument&quot; for the Reserve Bank to be using against a tight target of inflation of 0-2 percent, and he called for an early review of the consumer price index (CPI) the bank used to benchmark inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are to have it, we need to be confident that our method of measuring inflation is accurate,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>There was evidence that the CPI suffered an upward statistical bias of nearly one percent as the quality of goods improved, and Spring said this meant that when the central bank aimed for a mid-point of one percent inflation, it was actually targeting close to zero inflation.</p>
<p>He was backed by caretaker Agriculture Minister Lockwood Smith, who said the CPI was a consumer price index and it made no sense for it to include the capital costs of residential real estate.  </p>
<p>&quot;With the Reserve Bank saying that house prices contributed so greatly to inflation...I suggest we should examine whether that is the case,&quot; Smith told the meeting.</p>
<p>Spring said the 27 percent rise was an average of almost 10 percent of the board's New Zealand dollar earnings each year.</p>
<p>&quot;No industry can expect to continue to increase its selling prices or reduce its costs to that extent on an ongoing basis,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Spring said last year the board's treasury had managed to offset the impact of the erosion of returns from currency appreciation by NZ$240 million. However, while exchange management techniques could delay the short term cost, the long term impact of currency appreciation on returns could not be avoided.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
