<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16383" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary Jewish cemetery vandalism biggest in years.</title>
<headline>Hungary Jewish cemetery vandalism biggest in years.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vandals destroyed more than 200 tombs in a Jewish cemetery in Budapest this month although police say they left no specifically anti-Semitic marks, such as swastikas or slogans painted on tombs.</p>
<p>Details of the vandalism, which occurred the weekend of August 17-18, have trickled out in Hungary's national press.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the biggest damage so far,&quot; Laszlo Garami, who oversees Jewish cemeteries on behalf of Hungary's 150,000-strong Jewish community, said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Newspapers quoted police officials as estimating the damage at five million forints ($33,300), while Jewish officials said it could be 10 times that much.</p>
<p>&quot;Such things happen in many cemeteries but we don't know the reason,&quot; a police spokeswoman said. &quot;It doesn't show that it has been an anti-Semitic action and we will only know if we can talk to those who did it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There is no sign that would indicate it was anti-Semitic but it happened in a Jewish cemetery.&quot;</p>
<p>Last April, vandals broke into another Jewish cemetery in Budapest and spray-painted swastikas and Stars of David on about 12 tombstones.</p>
<p>Earlier the same month, vandals toppled 79 tombstones in a Jewish cemetery in the northern town of Eger.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
