<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163882" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US soy to EU down, but not from gene fears - USDA.</title>
<headline>US soy to EU down, but not from gene fears - USDA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. soybean sales to Europe will be down this year from previous levels, but not because of consumer fears of genetically engineered soybeans, Agriculture Department officials and trade analysts said Monday.</p>
<p>Officials and trade experts pointed to a big European feed grains crop, high soybean prices earlier in the year, a slow U.S. soybean harvest this year and changes in Europe's Common Agricultural Policy all as reasons for the lower purchases of U.S. soybeans.</p>
<p>Consumer activist Jeremy Rifkin said Monday that U.S. soybean sales to Europe have dropped &quot;by at least 10 percent&quot; or $150 million worth because of Europe's concern over a new U.S.-grown biogenetically-engineered soybean developed by Monsanto Co. and grown commercially for the first time this year in the United States.  </p>
<p>Rifkin, who has been working to organize a consumer boycott of the soybeans in Europe, said that consumer response has been unexpectedly strong, and said major European soybean buyers have begun to cancel orders for U.S. soybeans due to consumer backlash.</p>
<p>Agriculture Department officials were skeptical of Rifkin's claims.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't rule out the impacts of genetically engineered soybeans, but I think it's a minor influence at this point,&quot; said a senior Agriculture Department analyst.</p>
<p>Just normal supply/demand stuff is going on here,&quot; said the analyst.</p>
<p>According to USDA, outstanding sales of U.S. soybeans to the European Union currently total 1.6 million tonnes, down 15 percent from last year's level of 1.925 million. Accumulated soybean exports to Europe this marketing year total 959,500 tonnes, down over 30 percent from 1.47 million last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Soybean exports to Euorpe have been declining since the early 1980's due to changes in the Common Agricultural Policy which has made it more feasible to use their own grain rather than using imported proteins,&quot; said Mark Ash, analyst at USDA's Economic Research Service.</p>
<p>Europe last year imported 8.9 million tonnes of U.S. soybeans, down from 10.1 million in the 1994-95 marketing year.</p>
<p>Total U.S. soybean sales this year are markedly ahead of last year's pace. As of the week ending October 24, outstanding soybean sales totalled 7.613 million tonnes, compared to last year's pace of 5.557 million, but exported shipments were running behind -- 2.272 million tonnes versus 3.508 million tonnes last year.  </p>
<p>USDA officials and others were skeptical that recent announcements by some European soybean users that they would not use the new gene-modified soybeans in some products would significantly decrease U.S. soybean exports.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not clear that this will cause any loss in soybean sales,&quot; said Tim Galvin, Associate Administrator of USDA's Foreign Agricultural Service.</p>
<p>Galvin rejected calls from Rifkin and other biotech critics that the genetically altered soybeans be separated from regular soybeans and labelled. &quot;As a practical matter, it's impossible to separate these products.&quot;  </p>
<p>Estimates are that about two percent of the new U.S. soybean crop contains the so-called transgenic soybeans.</p>
<p>The first shipment of new-crop U.S. soybeans, which may include some gene-modified crop, was scheduled to arrive in Hamburg, Germany, on Tuesday. Rifkin and others were planning to stage a demonstration against the new product at the port.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a major trade confrontation. This is not going to go away,&quot; said Rifkin in a telephone interview with Reuters. &quot;European consumers will not take genetically engineered soybeans.&quot;</p>
<p>Rifkin questioned Monsanto's logic in developing the controversial product, and said that the St. Louis-based agribusiness giant has misread the consumer.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that whoever is running Monsanto needs to get his head examined,&quot; he said. &quot;Their company is poised for tremendous losses.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Maggie McNeil, Washington Commodities, 202-898-8300</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
