<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163918" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mass. governor makes one last bid for Senate on TV.</title>
<headline>Mass. governor makes one last bid for Senate on TV.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Gevirtz</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican Gov. William Weld, who has fallen slightly behind incumbent Democratic U.S. Sen. John Kerry in recent polls, is set to appeal directly to Massachusetts voters on Monday night with a 30-minute television broadcast on two networks.</p>
<p>A Boston Globe/WBZ-TV poll on Monday shows Kerry holding on to a razor-thin lead of 48 percent to Weld's 43 percent with 6 percent undecided. The gap is within the KRC Communications Research Inc. poll's margin of error.</p>
<p>Weld will air a taped half-hour segment on both New England Cable News and WCVB-TV beginning at 8 p.m. EST, exactly the same time slot that Texas billionaire and Reform Party presidential candidate Ross Perot is using in his direct message to the voters on a rival station.</p>
<p>&quot;Perot backed Weld,&quot; noted Brandeis University political science professor Jeffrey Abramson. &quot;Now, they're competing against each other for the same audience.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if he (Weld) will be getting any undecideds from the broadcast, but it makes sense that if you have the money at this point and the race is this close, then you have nothing to lose,&quot; Abramson said.</p>
<p>The Federal Election Commission's latest report showed Weld had $660,000 in cash on hand &quot;and I'm sure he's raised more,&quot; said Jim Glaser, a political science professor at Tufts University. &quot;If he didn't do this and lost, then Weld would be kicking himself.&quot;</p>
<p>But Northeastern University political science professor Alan Schroeder said the 30-minute buy probably will not bring in any more votes and &quot;smacks of desperation ... I think most people have tuned off the election process at this point. The barrage of political advertising has deadened everyone's nerves and whether it's a 30-second, a 60-second or a 30-minute spot, it will probably fall on deaf ears.&quot;</p>
<p>In the meantime, both Weld and Kerry were criss-crossing the state to get out their supporters.</p>
<p>Massachusetts Secretary of State William Galvin has estimated 76 percent of registered voters in the state would cast ballots on Tuesday -- down from the 1992 presidential high of 84.22 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of that is we now have a record number of registered voters with the motor-voter law. So while we may get more people voting, it won't be a higher percentage,&quot; explained Glavin's spokesman, John McCarthy. He said 3.494 million voters were registered for Tuesday's election, as opposed to 3.351 million registered for the 1992 election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
