<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="163975" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stadium prop. stirs debate in Harris County, Texas.</title>
<headline>Stadium prop. stirs debate in Harris County, Texas.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>While supporters of a Harris County, Texas, stadium financing proposal say it would be an economic home run that leaves property taxes untouched, foes say the county could have its hands in taxpayer pockets well before the fat lady sings.</p>
<p>Proposition No. 1 would authorize Harris County to establish and operate new or renovated stadiums, arenas, and other facilities for professional baseball and football teams, according to the ballot. Key in the proposal is that no county real or personal property taxes would be spent to acquire, construct or equip the facilities.</p>
<p>But some question the measure. County Treasurer Don Sumners said the &quot;very general and vague&quot; ballot language would allow property taxes to be used for maintenance and operation, and possibly to guarantee the debt.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a blank check for all these projects that could easily cost up to $700 million,&quot; Sumners said.</p>
<p>The ballot language fails to discuss the proposed financing mechanisms the county plans to use to pay debt service on the proposed project's bonds. Sumners called those sources &quot;suspect.&quot;</p>
<p>Sally Lehr, media liason for Harris County Judge Robert Eckels, acknowledged that the ballot was &quot;very vaguely worded&quot; but the language had to be ready by September 5 to get on the ballot.</p>
<p>Shea Guinn, assistant to Judge Eckels, said the referendum &quot;explicitly prohibits the use of property taxes.&quot;</p>
<p>Guinn said, &quot;You can't be any more plain about it.&quot;</p>
<p>Projects under consideration amount to only $465 million - 265 million for a downtown Houston baseball stadium and $200 million for proposed improvements to the Astrodome for football soccer and rodeo, he said.</p>
<p>While it's legally possible that property taxes could be used for operation and maintenance at the Astrodome, the county's plan is to have a private operator bear those costs as it does right now, Guinn said.</p>
<p>For the baseball stadium, plans call for a sports authority to be created to issue the bonds.</p>
<p>That authority would never legally have any access to property taxes, he said.</p>
<p>Of the $265 million, $180 million would come from public funds; $37 million would come from the team, the Houston Astros; $15 million would come from personal seat licenses; and $33 million would come from local businesses. Of the $33 million, $18 million would go for construction and $15 million would go to buy land, Guinn said.</p>
<p>The $180 million of public money is projected to come from several sources--an auto rental tax, a tax increment zone surrounding the facility, a parking assessment and a ticket tax.</p>
<p>The tax increment zone, would entail a sales tax and a mixed beverage tax in and around the facility, he said. Guinn emphasized that taxes collected would be incremental, emanating from the new economic activity the stadium would bring.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be new tax dollars,&quot; he said</p>
<p>The Texas legislature, which convenes in January, would have to approve the auto rental tax, the tax increment zone and the tax on tickets, Guinn said. Parking could probably be assessed by the city, but all talks now seem to indicate that legislative approval would be sought for that as well, he said.</p>
<p>But Treasurer Sumners said the only financing mechanisms the public has been told about at this point were the car and truck rental tax and a state tax abatement. Under the abatement plan, the state would allow taxes it would have collected on liquor and sales in the stadium and surrounding area to the sports authority, he said.</p>
<p>Sumners said Judge Eckels acknowleged Thursday that Governor George Bush told him support for the tax abatement plan would not be forthcoming.</p>
<p>In addition, Sumners said the revenue sources the Proposition 1 supporters are envisioning for the stadium are linked to how well the stadium does.</p>
<p>&quot;All of the revenue sources except for that car rental tax are generated from the activity at the stadium,&quot; he said. &quot;And if the stadium gets in trouble, then the revenue source dries up.&quot;</p>
<p>Sumners and John Ebeling, a director of the Texas Car And Truck Rental and Leasing association, say Amendment 1 would unfairly burden Harris County residents who rent cars. A recent Texas CATRALA survey found that close to 60 percent of all car rentals in Harris County are by residents.</p>
<p>Dan McClung, a political consultant hired by a committee, called Harris County Citizens for Proposition 1 said the county will try to minimize the tax's impact on residents by basing the tax on length of stay. A short stay typically indicates business, while longer stays usually indicate local use.</p>
<p>Ebeling disagreed.</p>
<p>&quot;We rent a lot of cars to local residents whose cars are in the shop for a day or two,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sumners added that if the state indeed succeeds in reducing the burden car rental tax burden on local residents, &quot;it would greatly reduce the amount of revenue available.&quot;</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
