<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164085" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Mobutu leaves Switzerland for French Riviera.</title>
<headline>Mobutu leaves Switzerland for French Riviera.</headline>
<byline>Elif Kaban</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's stricken president Mobutu Sese Seko, an unwelcome guest in tranquil Switzerland, flew out secretly on Monday and landed in the French Riviera while his country edged towards war.</p>
<p>A Foreign Ministry spokeswoman in Berne told Reuters that Marshal Mobutu, who had been under medical treatment in the city of Lausanne since August after undergoing prostate cancer surgery, had left the country.</p>
<p>An official at Geneva's Cointrin airport said the Zairean leader flew out late in the afternoon with his entourage of more than 30 aides and bodyguards on board an ageing DC-8 airliner registered in the Bahamas.</p>
<p>A French airport spokesman said Mobutu's plane landed in Nice, near where the reputedly super-rich Zairean ruler has a villa. Swiss television reported late last month that the president may continue his treatment there.</p>
<p>Swiss doctors gave the green light for his departure and he was fit to travel, Swiss foreign ministry officials said.</p>
<p>Last week, former French internal affairs minister Charles Pasqua visited Mobutu in Lausanne, sparking speculation that Mobutu may be about to leave for France.</p>
<p>France had earlier barred Mobutu from visiting his villa at the Cote d'Azur resort of Cap Saint-Martin but softened its stance after he cooperated with a French military expedition to halt the ethnic slaughters in Rwanda in 1994.</p>
<p>With a leopard-skin cap and bird-handled ebony cane as his trademarks, the 66-year-old former journalist-turned-soldier seized power in his vast mineral-rich central African country in 1965 after several years of political turmoil.</p>
<p>Like an old-fashioned King, Mobutu's self-awarded titles include &quot;the all-powerful warrior who, because of his endurance and inflexible will to win, will go from conquest to conquest leaving fire in his wake&quot;, as well as &quot;Messiah&quot; and &quot;Liberator&quot;.</p>
<p>Mobutu made no public comment as the crisis in east Zaire spread, the U.N. lost contact with 500,000 refugees on the run and the West, the U.N. and aid agencies scurried to find a way out in recent days.</p>
<p>During his stay, Swiss government and hospital officials refused to comment on Mobutu's medical situaation but reports say he may be seriously ill. The well-informed French daily Le Monde said on Friday that cancer had spread to Mobutu's bones.</p>
<p>In the tranquil town of Lausanne, Mobutu checked out of his luxury Beau-Rivage Palace hotel on the shores of Lake Geneva earlier on Monday, hotel staff said.</p>
<p>A hotel official declined to comment on the president's departure in a black limousine but said he had paid all his bills. They totalled nearly one million Swiss francs. &quot;The bills were settled every three days,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>During his stay in Switzerland, Swiss secrecy and discreet security surrounded Mobutu -- an international pariah banned from much of Western Euroope and the United States who has more than $4 billion -- nearly the same size as Zaire's foreign debt -- stashed away in Swiss banks according to Swiss media.</p>
<p>Despite growing discontent over his presence in Switzerland, his Swiss visa was extended for the fourth time last week on medical grounds until November 27. The foreign ministry said he had not asked for a new visa.</p>
<p>Swiss authorities were understood to have asked Mobutu to avoid public appearances or interviews.</p>
<p>His departure came as preparations were under way for a special United Nations envoy, Raymond Chretien, to visit him in Lausanne later this week to discuss the crisis in his country and the fighting in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>A U.N. spokesman said the meeting could take place in another venue but could not give details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
