<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164008" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Turkey says will relax limits on US wheat -- USDA.</title>
<headline>Turkey says will relax limits on US wheat -- USDA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's Agriculture Ministry has said its recent zero-tolerance policy for diseases in imported wheat was mistakenly applied, and new policy would be announced soon, a U.S. agriculture official said Monday.  </p>
<p>Jonathan Jones, an official at the U.S. Agriculture Department's Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS), said the ministry informed the agriculture counsellor at the U.S. embassy in Turkey of its latest position.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministry met and then announced to interested parties that the regulations were not being applied properly,&quot; Jones told Reuters. &quot;They wanted it understood that the regulations do allow importation of wheat,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>APHIS will resume issuing export certificates for U.S. exporters as soon as it receives the new policy in writing from the Turkish ministry, Jones said.  </p>
<p>Turkey's zero-tolerance policy for wheat diseases correctly applies only to seed wheat, he said.</p>
<p>Turkey has for two weeks held up a 15,000-tonne shipment of U.S. milling wheat, saying it contained ergot fungus. U.S. officials have said it is virutally impossible to guarantee a complete absence of ergot.</p>
<p>The ministry told U.S. officials in Turkey that it planned to announce tolerances for ergot either on Monday or on Tuesday, Jones said.</p>
<p>The U.S. government was hoping that the new Turkish policy on ergot would not require special USDA certification, and that Ankara would leave it up to the U.S. grain industry to ship only wheat that met the tolerance levels, he said.</p>
<p>If certification was required for ergot, USDA's Federal Grain Inspection Service (FGIS) would be able to test the wheat for ergot and provide certificates, Jones said.</p>
<p>However, it was possible that Turkey would set tolerances for other wheat diseases, including flag smut, and this would present a problem for U.S. inspection services, he said.</p>
<p>-- Eddie Evans (202) 898-8489</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
