<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164050" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Mobutu leaves Switzerland, destination unknown.</title>
<headline>Mobutu leaves Switzerland, destination unknown.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's ailing president Mobutu Sese Seko, absent from his country when a major crisis errupted along its eastern border, left Switzerland on Monday on board a private plane.</p>
<p>The Swiss Foreign Ministry in Berne said he had gone but could give no immediate details. An official at Geneva's Cointrin airport said the Zairean leader flew out late in the afternoon. His destination was unknown.</p>
<p>The 66-year-old Mobutu, a one-time army sergeant who seized power in 1965, had been in Switzerland since August when he underwent surgery for prostate cancer at the University Hospital in Lausanne.</p>
<p>He had been living with his entourage of more than 20 at the city's luxury Beau-Rivage Palace hotel, but Swiss authorities were understood to have asked him to avoid public appearances or interviews.</p>
<p>A special United Nations envoy, Raymond Chretien, had been expecting to visit him in Lausanne this week to discuss fighting in eastern Zaire and the plight of a million Hutu refugees from Rwanda and Burundi.</p>
<p>Swiss television reported last month that a Mobutu-owned villa near Nice in the south of France was being prepared for use and he might continue his treatment there.</p>
<p>Last week former French internal affairs minister Charles Pasqua visited him in Lausanne.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
