<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164120" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Survey reveals catalogue of trade barriers for EU.</title>
<headline>Survey reveals catalogue of trade barriers for EU.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union companies face a maze of problems ranging from corruption to poor accounting when trading with non-EU countries, a survey by a leading business group shows.</p>
<p>An examination of non-tariff barriers by the Association of European Chambers of Commerce (Eurochambers) shows over a third of companies questioned experienced &quot;significant problems&quot; while trading with third countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Things have improved over the last few years but the study shows that problems remain,&quot; Hylko Oosterloo, a Eurochambers official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Although Oosterloo conceded the survey was not scientific, he said it was a useful exercise in gauging the range and type of hurdles that EU businesses face in trade outside the 15-nation bloc.</p>
<p>Some 700 companies were polled to find out how easy it was for them to do business with a range of non-EU countries. Belgian firms, for example, were asked about their relations with Israel; Spain with Colombia and Sweden with China.</p>
<p>&quot;The examples provided by this study show that many trade barriers persist worldwide,&quot; Oosterloo said. &quot;We hope that by highlighting the problems, efforts can be made to eliminate them.&quot;</p>
<p>Eurochambers has presented the results of its survey to the European Commission to include in wider studies of trade barriers.</p>
<p>The group has also made a series of recommendations to Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan, urging less interference as well as calling for the EU not to resort to retaliation as a means of solving disputes.</p>
<p>Eurochambers was also critical of some Commission trade moves and derided its &quot;key niche market policy&quot; as being meaningless.</p>
<p>The Commission said earlier this year that it wanted to promote the image of EU products and services in key niche markets, but Eurochambers asked: &quot;What is the definition of a key niche market and who will decide which will be supported. A risk exists that one country will benefit disproportionately&quot;.</p>
<p>In the survey on non-tariff barriers, Eurochambers said EU companies faced problems ranging from corruption in Saudi Arabia and Mexico to bureaucracy in Switzerland, the U.S. and Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not unusual that European countries simply have to bribe certain officials to get through customs,&quot; the survey said.</p>
<p>Poor handling of goods and local transport problems were also blamed for costing EU companies dearly, while labelling laws, insurance requirements and translation of documents added to costs.</p>
<p>Greek companies reported a total lack of information of Albanian laws and regulations in their efforts to trade with Tirana; Spanish firms said many Argentine banks did not deserve to have their credit guarantees recognised; and Ireland complained of pedantry by Canadian officials who refused to handle invoices containing even minor typing errors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
