<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164188" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan sets vote for Punjab ruler's fate.</title>
<headline>Pakistan sets vote for Punjab ruler's fate.</headline>
<dateline>LAHORE, Pakistan 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The governor of Pakistan's Punjab province on Monday set November 14 for the provincial parliament to vote on the political fate of its chief minister reinstated by a court on Sunday.</p>
<p>Governor Raja Saroop Khan asked Chief Minister Manzoor Ahmad Wattoo to get a vote of confidence from the 248-seat provincial assembly to stay in office, the official APP news agency said.</p>
<p>The Lahore High Court on Sunday reinstated Wattoo to his office 13 months after his ouster, in a move seen as a setback to Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto.</p>
<p>A three-judge bench of the court gave Wattoo, ousted in September 1995 on Bhutto's recommendation, 10 days to prove his majority in the assembly.</p>
<p>The bench said in its order that if Wattoo failed to win a vote of confidence, outgoing chief minister Arif Nakai, whose party is in Bhutto's federal governing coalition, would be returned to power in Punjab.</p>
<p>Saroop Khan, a retired army general and a Bhutto confidant, said in his order he was satisfied that Wattoo was holding office &quot;without commanding the confidence of the majority of members of the provincial assembly&quot; and, therefore, he required him to obtain the confidence vote on November 14.</p>
<p>In a separate move, Punjab assembly Speaker Mohammad Hanif Ramay called a session of the legislature on Sunday to consider a no-confidence motion against Wattoo moved by Nakai's People's Democratic Front (PDF).</p>
<p>But he set no date for a vote on this motion, which must be held after a minimum of three and a maximum of seven days.</p>
<p>Political sources said Wattoo's chances of winning a confidence vote so far appeared slim because the PDF commanded a majority in the assembly and the main opposition Pakistan Muslim League party of former prime minister Nawaz Sharif had not declared support for him.</p>
<p>President Farooq Leghari, acting on Bhutto's mandatory advice, suspended Wattoo last year after a revolt by most provincial ministers. Nakai later assumed power in the fertile, central province that borders India.</p>
<p>Wattoo's return to power would be a blow to Bhutto's government, which has been under pressure from intensifying opposition protests.</p>
<p>Bhutto, who won general elections in October 1993, gave Wattoo the top political post in Punjab in exchange for his opposition to Sharif as well as his party's support for her federal government and coalitions in two other provinces.</p>
<p>Bhutto later fell out with Wattoo, with her party and some of his deputies accusing Wattoo of corruption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAHORE, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
