<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164144" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norsk Hydro submits Troll C oil plan.</title>
<headline>Norsk Hydro submits Troll C oil plan.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway's Norsk Hydro ASA said on Monday it had formally applied to the Industry and Energy Ministry for permission to further develop oil production from the Troll field because recoverable reserves had been upgraded.</p>
<p>A Hydro statement said the plan called for a new floating production platform Troll C, modifications to the existing production platform Troll B and 50 new horizontally drilled production wells.</p>
<p>The development cost is estimated at 15.9 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Expected recoverable oil reserves from the Troll field is now 185 million standard cubic metres, or close to 1.2 billion barrels, Hydro said.  </p>
<p>In the so-called Troll West Oil Province, where the oil layers have a thickness of about 24 metres, the expected recoverable reserves are about 70 million standard cubic metres, or 440 million barrels, for a recovery factor of 45 percent.</p>
<p>In Troll West Gas Province, where the oil layers are about 12 metres, the expected recoverable reserves are 115 million standard cubic metres, or 724 million barrels, giving a recovery factor of 25 percent.</p>
<p>The oil production from the Troll field started in September 1995 and the production from Troll B today is about 250,000 barrels per day (bpd).</p>
<p>The Troll C platform will start its production in September 1999 and produce around 120,000 bpd, Hydro said. A plan for the construction and operation of a new oil pipeline to shore will be submitted to the authorities at a later date.</p>
<p>Den norske stats oljeselskap AS (Statoil) said in August a new line was required to supplement the Troll oil pipeline as a result of the Troll C platform plans.</p>
<p>The existing pipeline, which runs to Mongstad near Bergen on the west coast, only has capacity to transport crude output from the Troll B platform at a rate of about 250,000 bpd.</p>
<p>Partners in the Troll development are Statoil, Norsk Hydro, Norske Shell, Elf Aquitaine, Saga Petroleum ASA, DuPont's Conoco and Total.</p>
<p>-- Rolf Soderlind, Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
