<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16412" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Aug 27.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Leu's reference rate depreciated by 0.54 percent on week from August 19 to 26. Analysts see further depreciation likely.</p>
<p>TINERETUL LIBER</p>
<p>-  Renel RA electricity authority lacks funds to buy energy sources due to financial bottlenecks and trade unions see new electricity price rise as way to solve situation.</p>
<p>AZI</p>
<p>- Upgrading works on Nadlac and Varsand border crossing points are scheduled to be completed on September 30. Total worth of investment is 20.1 billion lei, up from initially envisaged 5.4 billion.</p>
<p>- Sugar factory at Zimnicea plans development to be able to process raw sugar as way to economic recovery.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Nuclear reactor at Cernavoda started tests at 75 percent of its full capacity of 660 megawatts.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Bucharest court is to decide on Tuesday fate of troubled Renasterea Creditului Romanesc Credit Bank SA. National Bank took Credit Bank to court after it failed to make payments for one month.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Civic Alliance, as representive of the civic society, said it would contest at Constitutional Court the candidacy of President Ion Iliescu for a new four-year presidential term in the November 3 polls.</p>
<p>- Teofil Pop, former post-revolutionary justice minister, asks President Iliescu not to run for a new term, which he says would be a third and unconstitutional. Pop says the parliament could initiate suspension proceedings of President Iliescu for &quot;breaking the constituion&quot; after the November polls, harming Romania's chances to join NATO and the EU.</p>
<p>- Gheorghe Funar, head of National Unity Party (PUNR) asks Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu to be sacked for having included the Council of Europe's 1202 recommendation in the draft Romanian-Hungarian treaty.</p>
<p>- Opposition Democratic Convention (CDR) bloc agrees the Romanian-Hungarian treaty must be signed as quick as possible, but threatens not to attend a meeting with President Iliescu unless the text of the treaty is not given to the parties ahead of the talks with parliamentary parties.</p>
<p>- Romania's jails are overcrowded, says a report by the Helsinki human rights defence committee.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Former Prime Minister Theodor Stolojan, member of the committee supporting President Iliescu in his candidacy for a new term, is likely to run also for parliament on the list of the ruling Party of Social Democracy (PDSR).</p>
<p>- President Iliescu is likely to ask next parliament to ammend the constitution on issues like government reshuffles, parliamentary immunity, duties of the government and public administration.</p>
<p>- Dan Martian, vice-president of ruling PDSR said report on measures taken by the party over the past month following its anti-corruption resolution is nothing but an &quot;exercice of self-satisfaction&quot;.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Two financial experts must end the checkings on the Caritas money spinning scheme which collapsed in 1994 sucking in savings worth $1.0 billion from some four million investors.</p>
<p>- CDR presidential candidate Emil Constantinescu visiting the southern county of Calarasi, had big success in the birth town of President Iliescu, the newspaper says.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- Opposition National Liberal Alliance (ANL) and National Centrist Union (UNC) signed political responsability pact saying they would support one another in electoral campaign for the November 3 parliamentary polls.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Treaty with Hungary, which keeps the door open for Romania to enter NATO, must be signed in September, said Foreign Minister Teodor Melescanu.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- Opposition CDR would insist on its programme and solutions and would not attack the contenders in the electoral campaign for Novermber 3 polls, said CDR leader Constantinescu.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Romanians and ethnic Hungarians are not enemies, have no contradictory but many common interests, says Gyorg Frunda, presidential candidate of Hungarian Democratic Union (UDMR) in a two-page interview.</p>
<p>- PUNR leader Funar proposes Romanian-Hungarian treaty to start functioning only after both countries have been admitted to NATO. ($=3,158 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
