<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164124" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Ahold bolsters global ambitions with Brazil deal.</title>
<headline>Ahold bolsters global ambitions with Brazil deal.</headline>
<byline>Christine Lucassen</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch food retailer Ahold NV underlined its global ambitions on Monday by announcing plans to take a 50 percent stake in Brazilian supermarket chain Bompreco, its first incursion into South America.</p>
<p>Ahold said Bompreco was the fourth largest food retailer in Brazil and market leader in the northeast of the country with 1995 sales of about $1.4 billion.</p>
<p>The Dutch group said it would finance the acquisition from its available funds but gave no further financial details.</p>
<p>It said the deal would not dilute earnings in the first year and was expected to enhance earnings per share thereafter.</p>
<p>Bompreco concluded an international share offering last week, selling nine million non-voting preferred shares to investors in Brazil, the U.S. and Europe at a price of $8.25 each. These shares are listed in Brazil and Luxembourg.</p>
<p>Ahold said it and Bompreco planned considerable expansion in the north and northeast of Brazil in the coming years.</p>
<p>The Brazilian company currently operates seven hypermarkets, 29 supermarkets, 11 minimarkets and three department stores which will be remodelled into hypermarkets.</p>
<p>Ahold has annual sales of about $24 billion in the U.S., the Netherlands and other European countries.</p>
<p>Earlier this year it roughly doubled its turnover in the U.S. by acquiring the U.S. supermarkets chain Stop &amp; Shop.</p>
<p>This year also marked Ahold's expansion into Asia where it has set up joint ventures in Thailand, Malaysia, Singapore and China.</p>
<p>Ahold board member Fritz Ahlqvist said the Brazilian deal reflected the company's plans to become one of the world's leading food retailers.</p>
<p>&quot;We already have very strong operations in Europe and the United States and have started in the emerging markets of Asia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This opportunity to join forces with a highly respected and successful Brazilian company provides a flying start for Ahold in Latin America,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Ahold's move caught analysts off guard.</p>
<p>&quot;We had been looking for further expansion through joint ventures, but not in Brazil,&quot; said John David Roeg, retail analyst with Bank Labouchere.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a surprising and daring move,&quot; said ING Barings' Dennis Jullens. &quot;With this step, Ahold has gained a foothold in Latin America's biggest and most developed market&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
