<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164126" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Ex-Sweden air cargo market set for rate rises.</title>
<headline>Ex-Sweden air cargo market set for rate rises.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air cargo rates from Sweden to the Far East showed signs of firming over the past month, while those to Europe and South America fell as several airlines announced surcharges to cover higher jet fuel costs.</p>
<p>All eyes were on Scandinavian flag carrier SAS to see if it would match moves by Deutsche Lufthansa and KLM Royal Dutch Airlines to increase cargo rates by about 10 U.S. cents per kg from November 1.</p>
<p>Most analysts expected SAS to follow suit.</p>
<p>&quot;We are considering it,&quot; SAS Cargo spokeswoman Gunilla Emthen told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody is talking about it or thinking about it,&quot; said Peter Sull, regional cargo and mail sales manager for Thai Airways.</p>
<p>Asked if Thai Airways would also raise its freight prices, Sull said: &quot;We will follow the national carrier or the market practice.&quot;</p>
<p>Forwarders and airlines agreed demand was sufficiently great to handle the increase in rates.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there will be any problems to increase the rates. I think everyone will accept it because it's directly linked to fuel costs,&quot; said Par Wahlstedt, manager of freight forwarder United Air Service.</p>
<p>&quot;Because the market is busy and there is a lot of cargo around, I don't see how anyone can afford not to impose the increase,&quot; said British Airways (BA) cargo manager for Northern Europe Anders Uddman.</p>
<p>BA would apply a six pence per kg surcharge on intercontinental freight from November 8 and a three pence surcharge per kg for freight on European and British routes.</p>
<p>&quot;There is so much export cargo that I don't think this will change the market at all. The market has to take these higher rates,&quot; said Bengt Lundell, Finnair cargo manager for Sweden.</p>
<p>Rates in general looked set to be higher by year-end.</p>
<p>&quot;In general I think all rates will go up by about half a crown in January, with the exception of Lufthansa and KLM which have take this action,&quot; Finnair's Lundell said.</p>
<p>&quot;The prices will eventually go up. It may take a week or it may take a month. But no doubt a month from now prices will go up because of this action (by Lufthansa and KLM),&quot; BA's Uddman said.</p>
<p>Freight forwarders and airlines were reporting heavy traffic volumes, especially to the Far East. They said the upturn was not only a matter of seasonal factors, but that the market was showing signs of growth.</p>
<p>&quot;It's booming. In short, that's what's happening,&quot; said Sven Ahlberg, Lufthansa Cargo regional director Sweden.</p>
<p>&quot;The pick up rate is a bit higher than normal. The increase now is a combination of the seasonal pick up and the general improvement of the market,&quot; Ahlberg said.</p>
<p>Rates to the United States were flat at 9.75 crowns per kg for New York. However, some players said it was possible to find significantly lower prices.</p>
<p>&quot;You might find rates of six crowns per kg in some circumstances,&quot; said a spokesman for one airline.</p>
<p>The rate to Chicago was flat at 11.30 crowns per kg and to Los Angeles it was steady at 12.70 crowns.</p>
<p>Market players said business to Far Eastern destinations was notably busy and high demand made the possibility of finding special low prices for one-off shipments unlikely.</p>
<p>A shipment to Hong Kong or Singapore averaged 13.30 crowns per kg, unchanged from the last report on October 9.</p>
<p>The rate to Bangkok was also the same at 13 crowns per kg.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lack of capacity (to the Far East). There are huge shipments, especially from Ericsson in Sweden. We are having some problems satisfying our customers,&quot; said Sull.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no ad hoc shipments due to the capacity shortage.&quot;</p>
<p>Rates to Japan rose marginally. The price per kilo rose to 19.40 crowns per kg from 19.30 crowns one month ago.</p>
<p>&quot;We are seeing an increase on the Japanese market,&quot; Goran Norell, traffic manager for cargo forwarder ASG Air &amp; Sea.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo reported new interest in shipments to India.</p>
<p>Rates to Dubai were unchanged at 10.25 crowns per kg.</p>
<p>A shipment to Johannesburg cost about 20.10 crowns per kg, slightly less than last month when it cost 20.20 crowns.</p>
<p>The average price to European cities fell slightly. Market players reported the average rate to London was now 7.50 crowns compared to 7.70 crowns and to Paris the average price edged down to 7.30 crowns from 7.50.</p>
<p>The average market rate to Sao Paulo fell to 20.80 crowns per kg from 21.80 crowns.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
