<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164282" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian shares focus on U.S. elections.</title>
<headline>Belgian shares focus on U.S. elections.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The prospect of U.S. elections on Tuesday will make for another day of quiet range trading in Belgian shares, with players unwilling to take up new positions until the outcome is known.</p>
<p>The Bel-20 index  .BFX of leading shares ended with a modest gain of 7.13 points or 0.40 percent on Monday, at the top of the day's 10-point range. Volume was a relatively light 1.4 billion francs worth of Belgian shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very sure (President) Clinton will win the game,&quot; one dealer said, adding Wall Street would continue to dictate the Belgian market trend in the short term.</p>
<p>Delhaize was a top gainer all day, closing 2.3 percent higher at 1,785 francs with 76,673 shares changing hands, after news over the long weekend that its U.S. unit Food Lion planned to buy Florida-based Kash n' Karry Food Stores.</p>
<p>Analysts said the deal should have benefits for Delhaize profit in the longer term.</p>
<p>&quot;This takeover gives Food Lion new potential - the two companies can be seen as complimentary,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>After the close of trade, credit agency Standard &amp; Poor's said it may cut some Food Lion debt ratings.  REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
