<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164351" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Southern not to block United/Atmos merger.</title>
<headline>Southern not to block United/Atmos merger.</headline>
<dateline>BRENTWOOD, Tenn. 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Cities Gas Co and Atmos Energy Corp said on Monday that Southern Union Co has agreed not to vote its United Cities stock against the proposed merger between United Cities and Atmos.</p>
<p>Southern Union, which holds a 6.5 percent stake in United Cities, had said in October it intended to vote against the proposed merger and to solicit proxies from other United shareholders to vote against it.  </p>
<p>But the companies said Southern Union has agreed not to exercise dissenters' rights over the merger and has agreed not to solicit United Cities shareholders to exercise their dissenters' rights to vote against the merger.</p>
<p>Southern Union was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>United Cities and Atmos said they have agreed to stop contesting the legality of Southern Union's ownership of United Cities shares.</p>
<p>The agreement also granted Southern Union a right of first offer over certain properties Atmos might choose to dispose of during the two years after the merger was consummated, the companies said. Atmos said it was not contemplating the sale of such properties at the moment.</p>
<p>United and Atmos shareholders were due to consider the proposed merger at meetings on November 12, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRENTWOOD, Tenn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
