<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164479" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: New Ulster police chief rules out early IRA truce.</title>
<headline>New Ulster police chief rules out early IRA truce.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northern Ireland's new police chief warned Britons on Monday to expect further IRA guerrilla attacks and ruled out any immediate prospect of a new ceasefire.</p>
<p>Ronnie Flanagan, who took over as head of the Royal Ulster Constabulary, predicted further headline-grabbing bomb attacks on prestige targets by republican guerrillas in Northern Ireland and mainland Britain.</p>
<p>The British government has denied Dublin press reports it was negotiating terms of a pre-Christmas IRA ceasefire with Gerry Adams, head of the guerrillas' political wing Sinn Fein.</p>
<p>&quot;We have nothing to suggest an imminent restoration of the IRA ceasefire,&quot; he told the BBC on his first day as Chief Constable. &quot;I sadly expect there will be further attacks both here in the province and on the mainland.&quot;</p>
<p>Flanagan said the Irish Republican Army (IRA) was debating its next step in a 27-year war against British rule of Northern Ireland but he was pessimistic it would restore a 17-month ceasefire the guerrillas ended in February.</p>
<p>He said the guerrillas may have held a recent policy meeting but could not confirm media reports that the IRA's top General Army Convention had been in session.</p>
<p>&quot;There is undoubtedly an internal debate going on within the republican movement. But we have nothing, as a result of what took place, to suggest a restoration of the cessation of violence is imminent.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he feared more IRA &quot;spectaculars,&quot; on major targets such as the twin car bomb assault at Britain's Northern Ireland army base on October 7 which klilled one soldier and injured 20.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's fair to say that they will be seeking targets of high impact - targets that will grab the headlines,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Flanagan took over amid reports that Irish nationalist leader John Hume had been in touch with Adams over a new IRA truce.</p>
<p>Hume, leader of the Social Democratic and Labour Party (SLDP) and Adams were architects of 1993 peace proposals to end the conflict by getting all sides to peace talks.</p>
<p>Their proposals were never published but Irish diplomats said some of their suggestions were incorporated into an Anglo-Irish initiative called the Downing Street Declaration which was unveiled in December 1993.</p>
<p>Hume, whose SDLP is taking part in Belfast peace talks, said he was keeping the British and Irish governments, which are joint sponsors of the negotiations, informed of his talks.</p>
<p>&quot;I have made publicly clear that I have maintained my contact with Gerry Adams, and, as a public representative, obviously I talk regularly to the Government,&quot; he told the BBC.</p>
<p>But he denied weekend newspaper reports that he was a go-between for Adams whose party is shunned by the British and Irish governments because of continued IRA violence.</p>
<p>The two governments banned ministerial-level talks with Sinn Fein when the IRA ended its truce in February with a series of attacks in Britain and the bombing of an army base in Germany.</p>
<p>Sinn Fein is also barred from the Belfast peace talks and can only join when a new IRA ceasefire is called, the two governments say.</p>
<p>British officials insist that there must be an initial verification period to ensure that the truce is genuine and Hume said the truce that he sought was &quot;for keeps.&quot;</p>
<p>But the IRA has demanded that Britain and Ireland drop any attempt to make a surrender of weapons a talks priority and give the negotiations a strict time frame, something vigorously opposed by Protestant pro-British Unionists at the talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
