<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164599" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanon economic activity rises further in August.</title>
<headline>Lebanon economic activity rises further in August.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lebanon's economic activity in August reached its highest level in more than three-and-a-half years, the Bank of Lebanon said on Monday.</p>
<p>The Bank said in its latest economic report that its coincident indicator of economic activity rose to 182.1 in August, its second consecutive record after July's high of 179.8. The indicator, which was created in January 1993, stood at 168.8 in June.</p>
<p>Construction activity, the main engine of July's jump, was relatively stable. It is measured by cement deliveries, dropping slightly to 391,639 tonnes in August from 395,465 tonnes a month earlier. Deliveries totalled 355,000 tonnes in June.</p>
<p>This improvement in economic growth follows a 12-month slowdown that began late last year and was accentuated by Israel's 17-day blitz on the country in April.</p>
<p>The indicator, which takes January 1993 as 100, combines 12 economic series including imports, exports, electricity output and airport and port activity. The Bank created it because of a lack of reliable data for calculating Gross Domestic Product (GDP).</p>
<p>Lebanon also registered its second biggest monthly balance of payments surplus in 1996 at $105 million. July's $142 million surplus was the highest in 12 months.</p>
<p>This brought the accumulated surplus for the first eight months of this year to $285.6 million compared with a $216.9 million deficit for the same period in 1995, the Bank said.</p>
<p>The accumulated balance of trade deficit for the year to date showed a slight improvement to $4.21 billion compared with $4.31 billion for the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>This was due to a 27 percent increase in exports to $645.4 million from $506.5 million. Imports declined by only 0.7 percent to $4,850.6 million from $4,818.4 million.</p>
<p>However, total public debt rose to 14,392.7 billion pounds from 14,089 billion in July, the Bank said. This was $9.2 billion compared with an estimated total GDP of $11.5 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
