<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16456" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>PARAGUAY: Paraguayan unions to strike on Wednesday.</title>
<headline>Paraguayan unions to strike on Wednesday.</headline>
<dateline>ASUNCION, Paraguay 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paraguayan unions and peasant groups will stage their fourth national strike against President Juan Carlos Wasmosy's economic policies on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The strike will last eight hours from 0730 local time (1130 GMT) and will include marches and demonstrations in the capital Asuncion as well as roadblocks on the country's main highways, union officials said.</p>
<p>The unions and peasant groups, which demand a 26-percent pay rise, changes in economic policy and land grants to peasants, also plan a series of acts building up to a 72-hour general strike in November.</p>
<p>The Wasmosy  government aims to cut government spending and privatise. While these plans are stalled by accusations of government corruption and other problems, they still have unleashed fierce union opposition.</p>
<p>Wasmosy's government has clashed regularly with unions since its election in 1993. There have been three general strikes since May 1994, with violence by both protestors and police increasing each time.</p>
<p>This time, the government has said it respects the right to strike but will deploy 10,000 police to respond if protesters break the law or deviate from authorised routes for their marches. Union leaders say their members will respond to any police violence.</p>
<p>Five demonstrators have died in the three strikes so far.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PARA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ASUNCION, Paraguay"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PARAGUAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
