<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164674" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Equitable/Iowa sees EPS in analysts' range.</title>
<headline>Equitable/Iowa sees EPS in analysts' range.</headline>
<dateline>DES MOINES, Iowa 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Equitable of Iowa Cos said on Monday it expects fiscal 1996 operating earnings per share to be within the range of analysts' estimates of $3.55 to $3.62.</p>
<p>It also said, &quot;Assuming a continuation of the current business environment, the company is comfortable that fiscal 1997 operating earnings per share will fall within the current range of analysts' estimates of $3.90 to $4.10.&quot;  </p>
<p>However, it said its effort to grow its variable business and broaden distribution of its fixed annuity business will require &quot;significant investments&quot; to build the infrastructure needed to support that growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The company expects to materially increase its capacity for variable and fixed business over the next two years and has already begun hiring and training wholesalers to increase its producer network, as well as establishing a company and offices to do business in New York starting in 1997,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very excited about the opportunities we are pursuing to expand our markets, but we expect it will take a year or two before earnings meaningfully reflect these efforts,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Equitable added that it &quot;continues to be on track for 1996 to reach the company's annual goals of 15 percent return on equity and one percent return on general account assets.&quot;</p>
<p>Equitable, based here, sells fixed and variable annuity and life insurance products nationwide.</p>
<p>Today it reported a 12.9 percent increase in third quarter operating income to $29.1 million, or $0.91 per share, up from $25.8 million, or $0.81 per share, a year ago.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DES MOINES, Iowa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
