<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164704" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-SGL Carbon profit up, plans divy hike.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-SGL Carbon profit up, plans divy hike.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German SGL Carbon AG on Monday reported a 35 percent rise in nine-month pre-tax profits and plans to raise its dividend payout for 1996 even though recent sluggish economic conditions weighed on results.</p>
<p>SGL Carbon, the world's largest carbon and graphite maker producing a range of products for the electrical, steel and semiconductor industries, said nine-month pre-tax profits totalled 223 million marks ($147.4 million)and operating profit surged 24 percent to 231 million marks.</p>
<p>In the third quarter however operating profit climbed only 4.4 percent to 71 million marks from year-ago levels and was significantly softer than first and second quarter operating profits of over 80 million marks, the group said.</p>
<p>Sales, dented by a slump in the steel industry, climbed only 10 percent to 1.29 billion marks in the first nine months of the year, showing more moderate growth after jumping 13 percent in the first six months.</p>
<p>&quot;Softer economic conditions, lower orders during the summer months and the unexpected slump in the steel industry left third quarter results slightly weaker, but we expect the fourth quarter to be better and partly offset the third quarter,&quot; SGL Carbon chief executive Robert Koehler told a news conference.</p>
<p>While 1996 is sure to be the most difficult in the group's four-year history, Koehler remained optimistic for the year, allowing the group to stick by plans to raise its dividend.</p>
<p>After paying a 1.67 marks per share dividend for 1995, Koehler said, &quot;we will pay a higher dividend without a shadow of a doubt in 1996,&quot; adding 1996 &quot;profits will be over 300 million marks and sales will grow by eight to 10 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Last year SGL Carbon, once a unit of German chemicals giant Hoechst AG, said pre-tax profit jumped 61 percent to 234 million marks while sales rose nine percent to 1.57 billion.</p>
<p>Looking further ahead, Koehler predicted &quot;next year profit growth will outpace sales growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Stronger results will be fuelled both by an upturn in the economy, which should translate into higher volume sales and room to raise prices, and planned takeovers, Koehler said.</p>
<p>During the first nine months of 1996 sales volume fell six percent while prices climbed six percent and structural changes contributed an eight percent increase to total turnover.</p>
<p>The group's carbon and graphite sales, making up 64 percent of total turnover, grew eight percent to 822 million marks in the first nine months while speciality graphite sales climbed five percent to 265 million marks.</p>
<p>Sales in the smallest business area, engineered products, jumped 36 percent to 193 million marks in the same period.</p>
<p>North America and Western Europe, excluding Germany, remained the group's leading markets generating 28 and 29 percent of nine-month sales respectively.</p>
<p>Sales in Germany stood at 16 percent, while sales in the Far East were nine percent and Eastern Europe stood at six percent, SGL Carbon said.</p>
<p>To expand in the U.S. market, home of SGL Carbon's biggest competitors, the group plans to acquire a privately-held group in the speciality graphite area posting annual sales of between 10 and 20 million marks, Koehler said.</p>
<p>This deal and possibly others may be done by year-end, Koehler said, adding the U.S. takeover target &quot;will post strong operating margins soon&quot; after it is merged with SGL Carbon.</p>
<p>The group's other recent acquisitions, Polish group Polgraph and French group Vicarb, however have proven to be slightly more difficult to integrate, helping create tougher conditions this year, Koehler said.</p>
<p>Shares in SGL Carbon, only the second German company to be listed on the New York Stock Exchange, dipped nearly 0.3 percent to 170.50 marks in Frankfurt bourse trade, while the broader DAX index dropped 0.50 percent to 2,669.96.</p>
<p>($1=1.5131 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
