<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="164889" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bombay shares end down, lacklustre trade.</title>
<headline>Bombay shares end down, lacklustre trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bombay shares posted losses in dull trade on Monday, with a majority of blue-chip stocks ending lower, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Trading was very dull. There is hardly any action in the market,&quot; said Ketan Jhaveri, chief dealer at Kotak Securities.</p>
<p>He said the market was likely to fall further, unless local institutions started bidding agressively.</p>
<p>The 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) closed 56.36 points, or 1.79 percent, lower at a provisional 3,092.1, against the day's high of 3,143.89.</p>
<p>ITC Ltd fell 11.50 rupees or 3.84 percent to 287.50 rupees with sellers dominating action in the counter, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;People have still not recovered from the arrests of officials,&quot; Jhaveri said.</p>
<p>Shares of ITC have plunged 10 percent in less than a week, pounded by news of a foreign exchange scandal, which was &quot;to the tune of over $100 million,&quot; according to the Finance Ministry.</p>
<p>Last week, India's Enforcement Directorate searched the firm's offices and arrested senior officials including two former chairmen.</p>
<p>&quot;The enormity and scale of this development, coupled with the fact that many senior management personnel may be involved, tremendously increases the risk profile of the company,&quot; analyst Rukhshad Shroff at Jardine Fleming India Broking said in a report.</p>
<p>The 500-share CRISIL index lost 8.86 points or 1.5 percent to end at a provisional 596.77.</p>
<p>SBI lost 8.75 rupees to 218.50 rupees, TISCO 4.75 to 172.0, Reliance 5.50 to 189.0, ACC 50.20 to 1,458.0, Bajaj Auto 19.20 to 929.25, MTNL 4.50 to 221.75 and M&amp;M 6.25 to 309.25.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
