<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16499" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's Minsa reports H1 sales of 993 mln pesos.</title>
<headline>Mexico's Minsa reports H1 sales of 993 mln pesos.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's second largest corn flour miller Grupo Minsa said on Tuesday that first half sales grew 60 percent compared with the first six months of 1995 to 993 million pesos.</p>
<p>Minsa said the sales increase was due to a 35 percent rise in sales volumes. The company gave no other details.</p>
<p>It said net profits grew 78 percent, but gave no peso figure or comparative. Minsa said operating profits increased 42 percent in the first half, again giving no other details or data.</p>
<p>The company said its market share in domestic tortilla sales, Mexico's corn flour pancakes, grew to 28.9 percent in July from 26.2 percent in July 1995.</p>
<p>Minsa said the company's installed corn flour milling capacity grew 38 percent in the first six months of the year because the company brought on line a new plant in Ramos Arizpe in the northern state of Coahuila, a new production line in its plant in Jaltipan in the state of Veracurz and other increases in existing plants.</p>
<p>-- Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
