<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16501" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil Senate panel puts off Brady buyback vote.</title>
<headline>Brazil Senate panel puts off Brady buyback vote.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Brazilian Senate panel on Tuesday put off a vote on a bill authorizing a Brady bond buyback and debt-swap program after it became clear an agreement could not be reached over two alternative proposals.</p>
<p>No new date was set for a vote by the Senate Economic Affairs Committee on the legislation.</p>
<p>The two senators who have drafted alternative bills were asked by the committee president to seek a compromise. One of the proposals would limit any buyback and swap program to $5.0 billion, while the other would set no limit.  </p>
<p>Three months ago, the central bank requested Senate authority to restructure all of its $57 billion of Brady bonds.</p>
<p>Senator Roberto Requiao, orginally appointed to draw up a draft bill, said he had not been convinced of the advantages of such operations. His proposed legisation would severely tie the central bank's hands.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, another senator, Vilson Kleinubing, presented an alternative bill that would meet most of the central bank's demands while maintaining tight Senate control.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom, 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
