<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165141" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China food processor Ruyi to launch IPO.</title>
<headline>China food processor Ruyi to launch IPO.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Food processor Lianyungang Ruyi Group Co Ltd said on Monday it was set to launch an initial public offer of 11.54 million A shares on November 6.</p>
<p>The offer has been approved by the China Securities Regulatory Commission and will be launched via the Shenzhen bourse's automated quotation system at 3.88 yuan per share, Ruyi said in a prospectus published in the official Securities Times.</p>
<p>The issue provides a P/E ratio of 20.97 times based on forecast per-share net of 0.19 yuan under diluted basis for 1996, it said.</p>
<p>Ruyi said it has also been given approval by the CSRC to list 960,000 staff shares, placed at one yuan per share in 1994, along with the A shares in Shenzhen.</p>
<p>Jiangsu Provincial Securities has been named the offer's chief underwriter and Ruyi's listing promoter, it said.</p>
<p>Ruyi said it plans to funnel the share offer proceeds into its core business, food processing.</p>
<p>It said it would use part of the money to set up a US$5.50 million frozen food venture with two Japanese companies with Ruyi holding a 30 percent stake in the project.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
