<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165104" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam daily says Communist Party under threat.</title>
<headline>Vietnam daily says Communist Party under threat.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam's official army newspaper warned on Monday that the ruling Communist Party is under threat from forces seeking to sow disaffection among groups including intellectuals, young people and the military.</p>
<p>A signed commentary in the official Quan Doi Nhan Dan (People's Army) paper said imperialist forces were taking advantage of Vietnam's open-door policy to penetrate deeper into society to cause social and political instability.</p>
<p>The daily catalogued a list of targets ranging from party cadres and managers to intellectuals, young people, disaffected people, and dissident groups with overseas connections. It said the military was a prime target.</p>
<p>&quot;...they (hostile forces) focus on measures to incite and cause disunity, create suspicion, carry out plots to use young cadres against old cadres, use 'communist son' against 'communist father'...&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The blunt commentary added that enemies of Vietnam were seeking to pit &quot;economic communists&quot; against &quot;military or police communists&quot;, and create a rift between the Party leadership and the military.</p>
<p>It did not elaborate.</p>
<p>The Quan Doi Nhan Dan newspaper is seen as representing the views of the military in Vietnam.</p>
<p>It has carried a number of articles this year warning of the dangers of backdoor subversion, or 'peaceful evolution', but Monday's was the strongest in months.</p>
<p>Vietnam's ruling Communist Party is the sole legal political force in Vietnam and is normally sensitive to suggestions of internal disunity or disaffection.</p>
<p>It survived the collapse of communism in Eastern Europe and the Soviet Union and has maintained a policy since the late 1980s of seeking overseas investment and building links with foreign governments, regardless of ideology.</p>
<p>However, a five-year plan unveiled earlier this year outlined a need for tighter internal controls and greater policing of Vietnam's open-door policy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
