<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165178" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Petron to invest $3 bln in refinery.</title>
<headline>Petron to invest $3 bln in refinery.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil refiner Petron Corp said on Monday it would invest $3 billion in a grassroots refinery and aromatics plant to be located in a new petrochemical park in Bataan, just northwest of Manila.</p>
<p>Petron chairman Monico Jacob told reporters the refinery, with a capacity of 100,000 to 200,000 barrels per day, was expected to be completed by 2001 or 2002.  </p>
<p>Jacob was speaking to reporters after a signing ceremony at which Petron agreed to locate the refinery in the new petrochemical park being set up by state-owned Philippine National Oil Co-Petrocemical Development Corp.</p>
<p>Jacob said the aromatics plant to be built with the refinery would produce polyester fibre for textiles. He did not mention how much the plant was expected to produce.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking at the possibility of entering into a partnership with a refinery operator and an aromatics operator,&quot; Jacob said, adding that Petron had considered some foreign companies for a joint venture. Jacob declined to name them.  </p>
<p>Petron, the Philippines' leading oil refiner is 40 percent owned by Saudi Arabia's Aramco Oil Co.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
