<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165282" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Bomb hits French post office before Spain summit.</title>
<headline>Bomb hits French post office before Spain summit.</headline>
<dateline>MARSEILLE, France 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bomb badly damaged the main post office in the southern French town of Aix-en-Provence early on Monday, a few hours before a top level Franco-Spanish meeting was to open in nearby Marseille.</p>
<p>Police said no one had claimed responsibility for the attack which caused no injuries.</p>
<p>Radio reports pointed the finger of suspicion at Corsican separatists who recently bombed the mayoral office of Prime Minister Alain Juppe in Bordeaux and law courts in Aix-en-Provence and the southern town of Nimes.</p>
<p>Reports said the separatists may have sought to use the Franco-Spanish talks to highlight claims of independence for the Mediterranean island but struck in Aix-en-Provence, 30 km (18 miles) north of Marseille, because security in Marseille itself was too tight.</p>
<p>Hundreds of police mounted a major security operation in the Mediterranean port as French President Jacques Chirac and Spanish Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar, with top cabinet ministers, prepared to begin a two-day meeting later in the day.</p>
<p>Spain, and to a lesser degree France, face a violent campaign by Basque separatists.</p>
<p>ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) guerrillas have killed hundreds of people in Spain. The smaller group Iparretarrak (Those of the North) has staged sporadic bomb attacks in France.</p>
<p>On Corsica, a bomb early on Monday destroyed a private car belonging to a conservative senator in the village where he is mayor. No one was injured.</p>
<p>The attacks appeared to be part of a bombing campaign by the hardline separatist &quot;Historic Wing&quot; of the Corsican National Liberation Front (FLNC) against elected officials on the island.</p>
<p>The Paris government vowed a crackdown on the FLNC after it bombed Juppe's office in Bordeaux.</p>
<p>Separatist movements have conducted a 20-year guerrilla campaign against central rule by authorities in Paris.</p>
<p>An opinion poll at the weekend said more than 40 percent of French voters, exasperated by endless Corsican separatist violence, were ready to grant the turbulent island independence.</p>
<p>The poll, conducted for Canal Plus television, said 42 percent of 990 people questioned would vote for Corsican independence with 30 percent against. The remainder of those polled were uncommitted or offered no answer.</p>
<p>Another poll conducted last month in Corsica itself showed 91 percent of the islanders opposed independence, seven percent were in favour and two percent had no opinion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARSEILLE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
