<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165231" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran dismisses allegations of role in Saudi bomb.</title>
<headline>Iran dismisses allegations of role in Saudi bomb.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran has said allegations in a U.S. newspaper of an Iranian role in the June bomb attack which killed 19 American airmen in Saudi Arabia aimed to sow discord among Moslems in the Gulf region.</p>
<p>The official Iranian news agency IRNA quoted foreign ministry spokesman Mahmoud Mohammadi as saying on Sunday that the Washington Post report was &quot;a new U.S. conspiracy to create internal conflict in Islamic-Arabic countries.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;He once again rejected any links between Iran and the explosion in Dhahran,&quot; said IRNA, monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation.</p>
<p>It said Mohammadi described the report as baseless.</p>
<p>Quoting unnamed sources close to the investigation, the Post said on Friday Saudi security officials were holding some 40 Saudi citizens for alleged involvement in the attack on a U.S. complex in Dhahran. The report said Saudi Arabia was convinced the attack was part of a broad conspiracy backed by Iran.</p>
<p>It said the Saudi government had obtained confessions from some of those arrested and other evidence implicating Iran as the instigator and sponsor of the attack.</p>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry said later that the U.S. has not found a culprit for the bombing. Asked about an alleged Iranian link, he said: &quot;We have reached no conclusions about who was responsible for this.&quot;</p>
<p>Saudi officials have refused to comment on the report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DUBAI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
