<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165288" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany favours renewed EU foreign policy &quot;troika&quot;.</title>
<headline>Germany favours renewed EU foreign policy &quot;troika&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel has said Bonn wants to restructure the three-minister troika which represents EU foreign policy to give the body more continuity.</p>
<p>The body currently comprises the foreign ministers of the past, present and future holders of the six-month rotating presidency of the European Union.</p>
<p>In a release of Monday's edition, the daily Handelsblatt quoted Kinkel as suggeting that the troika could comprise an EU external affairs commissioner, the foreign minister of the current EU president and a general-secretary for foreign and security policy.</p>
<p>EU members broadly agree that the current Intergovernmental Conference (IGC) on institutional reform should give birth to a foreign policy coordinator, and Kinkel's suggestion was similar to one made by France in September.</p>
<p>But France wants to see the third position filled by a higher-profile &quot;high representative&quot; to coordinate and personify the policy -- a political figure rather than the humbler coordinator Germany has in mind.</p>
<p>Kinkel also said Germany wanted to give more powers to the president of the European Commission, currently very much a &quot;first among equals&quot;, to boost the standing of the EU's executive body.</p>
<p>&quot;The counterweight to the Council of Ministers of an extended EU must be a strong Commission,&quot; Kinkel was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>He suggested that the Commission president could be elected by the European parliament before the other commissioners instead of simultaneously.</p>
<p>The president should be allowed more influence over the composition of the commission, perhaps by being allowed to name his colleagues from short-list put forward by member states, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
