<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165307" id="root" date="1996-11-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FEATURE - Russia deals make nice gains for Finn trader.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Russia deals make nice gains for Finn trader.</headline>
<byline>Sara Henley</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Never mind the quality, feel the price. Fancy a punt on 400 tonnes of frozen chicken legs, or 133,000 orange and purple Indian polyester blouses, going cheap? Maybe you should talk to Reima Tuomikoski.</p>
<p>Unfortunately the 20,000 tonnes of butter he had on special offer passed their sell-by date. But there are 44,000 packets of decent tea, and he was just now expecting 100,000 kg (220,500 lb) of orange juice powder, so you may have a deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Oh, it's legal,&quot; said Tuomikoski, known to his friends as Ray. &quot;I can easily make a good living. I'd never go near any mafia business -- you get very easily killed.&quot;</p>
<p>A 44-year-old entrepreneur formerly in the jeans trade -- and before that manager for a musician he called &quot;the Bob Dylan of Finland&quot; -- Tuomikoski has found a nice little earner in, or rather with, Russia.</p>
<p>Spy novels in the 1970s used to relish Finland's potential as an outlet for smuggled Russian icons or costly furs, but his is a much less glamorous business. One of his recent successes was a batch of empty chemical sacks destined for beyond Siberia.</p>
<p>The export-import Tuomikoski specialises in starts with inexperienced or careless exporters, mainly in the United States, India or Asia, who sell to Russian firms for advance payment, but neglect to demand the freight bill up-front.</p>
<p>They make up a tiny fraction of Finland's bustling transit trade with its eastern neighbour -- but it is enough to keep Tuomikoski's one-man operation busy.</p>
<p>When the goods arrive by container at Finnish ports and shipping companies find their fees have not been paid, their agents try to locate the buyer in Russia. But in that fast-moving economic jungle, they sometimes fail.</p>
<p>&quot;Most Russian buyers order something, and try to sell it for more while it's still on the ship,&quot; said Tuomikoski. &quot;If they can't -- that's usually where I come in.&quot;</p>
<p>Under Finnish law such &quot;distressed&quot; cargoes belong to the shipping company, and must be held or exported within a certain period of time -- usually a year but less if they are perishable. Then they go up for auction, or must be destroyed.</p>
<p>For instance: if Tuomikoski can find another buyer for 20,000 kg of distressed U.S. chicken frankfurters in bonded storage in the eastern port of Kotka, the shipping company could get its money and its containers back -- and Tuomikoski will keep any profit.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no risk to me,&quot; he says. Shipping companies faced with the risk of having to destroy such produce are often eager to salvage any earnings, and cut the cost of storage.</p>
<p>That's where his butter deal went soft. Anxious to re-use storage space, the company dumped it in a field, handing it over to Tuomikoski who raced in vain against the sell-by date to find a buyer. He must now pay to have it destroyed.</p>
<p>&quot;I've sold approximately 2-300 containers, and I've not been able to sell about 20,&quot; he said. &quot;One of my best deals was I had 10,000 really good-looking men's shirts -- the kind you wear with a suit and tie -- from India.&quot;</p>
<p>With none of the goods he handles cleared for sale in Finland or the European Union, Tuomikoski generally seeks buyers in Russia, Latvia or Estonia.</p>
<p>But in this case, by carefully exploring EU customs laws, he said he managed to sell the shirts to a passenger-ferry operator for sale in on-board duty-free shops: &quot;They're on sale till May 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>At Kotka, Finland's second biggest transit shipping port after Helsinki, container terminal head Jari Nylund said only a fraction of the almost 100,000 containers that go through the port each year end up stuck because of payment problems.</p>
<p>&quot;These are individual cases, when you consider the total amount of containers we handle,&quot; he pointed out.</p>
<p>But Tuomikoski says they have helped fund his red Chevrolet Corvette and support his expensive bachelor lifestyle. He is sparing with the exact financial details.</p>
<p>There have been a couple of less-than savoury trades: 20 tonnes of epoxy resin, used for mixing paint and in hazardous goods storage last May, which Tuomikoski later discovered had expired in December 1992. It was good for nothing.</p>
<p>&quot;It would have cost $40,000 to destroy, or we could give it to Latvia for nothing,&quot; he said. &quot;So I called a friend, who called a friend, and they decided to take a chance. It would have been a good deal if they could have used it.&quot;</p>
<p>He fears, however, that it ended up in a river in Russia.</p>
<p>Another involved a very expensive invoice from a Beverly Hills firm to a Russian company -- the goods fully paid for. The buyer did not exist and neither, it turned out, did the seller. For Tuomikoski, that pointed clearly to organised crime.</p>
<p>&quot;Inside the containers were a couple of old compressors -- useless,&quot; he said. &quot;I sold them to a scrapyard for $3-4,000. Pocket money.&quot;</p>
<p>He moves on briskly to more wholesome topics: &quot;There's 102 containers of beer in a field. I hope they can sell it because in Finland, they'll soon be frozen beers. And I've got this container of U.S.-made milk powder...&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
