<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165354" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Big Canada lumber producers see business as usual.</title>
<headline>Big Canada lumber producers see business as usual.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's big lumber producers see little change in their operations from a plan to allow small Canadian lumber producers to borrow from their 1997 quotas on softwood lumber shipments to the United States.</p>
<p>On Monday, a Ronald McDonald, parliamentary secretary to International Trade Minister Art Eggleton, said small Canadina lumber producers could ship this year up to 20 percent of their export quota for 1997.</p>
<p>That would mean that small producers who have already met their 1996 quota for U.S. shipments could continue shipping lumber without penalty.  </p>
<p>Don Roberts, analyst at Wood Gundy Inc, said such a draw forward would likely have little impact on market prices for lumber because it is restricted to mills producing less than 50 million board feet annually.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the mills are far, far larger than that, so it will have negligible impact,&quot; Roberts said.</p>
<p>Roberts said he suspects that none of the major Canadian lumber producers are at their quota limits.</p>
<p>Serge Mercier, vice president of finance at Uniforet Inc, said the measure won't affect the company's two mills, which produce about 500 million board feet a year.  </p>
<p>Mercier said the apparent confusion over the new export quota system in Canada has helped buoy lumber prices in the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;It's certain that the quotas are making the markets more nervous, and have contributed to boosting prices a little more than usual,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While Canada's large lumber producers carry on, there have been reports that smaller mills in British Columbia have been preparing to shut down to avoid costly penalities on quota over-shipments.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the higher lumber prices may prompt some lower-coast U.S. producers to restart idled sawmills, said Wood Gundy's Roberts. But those American producers still face the challenge of accounting for raw fiber costs that are higher than those in Canada.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
