<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165698" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-PIE AND PEAS AT HARTLEPOOL -- A DISH TO RESIST?</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PIE AND PEAS AT HARTLEPOOL -- A DISH TO RESIST?</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>HARTLEPOOL, England 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The townsfolk of Hartlepool have spent nearly 200 years living down the fact that their ancestors hanged a sodden, barely-alive shipwrecked monkey in the Napoleonic Wars because they thought he was a French spy.</p>
<p>But it is debatable whether they have received divine forgiveness. As punishment they appear to have been inflicted with Hartlepool United Football Club, a team currently heading for the rocks in soccer's cruel sea.</p>
<p>While neighbouring north-east giants Newcastle United, Sunderland and Middlesbrough have seen their fortunes revive in recent years, Hartlepool, after a few brief flirtations with life a division above the basement of English football, are back where they have been for most of their almost 90-year existence -- swimming for survival.</p>
<p>&quot;Money is a never-ending problem, or rather the lack of it,&quot; said commercial executive Frank Baggs.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not only in a different league to Newcastle, Sunderland and Middlesbrough, we're in a different world. Most of our money comes from the club lottery, dinners and bar takings and of course our sponsors.</p>
<p>&quot;We put some very good acts on at the dinners with good guests speakers. It's a hand-to-mouth existence but I've been associated with this club for too many years, far more than I'd like to remember, to stop it. We're not Newcastle or Sunderland. We are this town's club and that is very important to us.&quot;</p>
<p>Saturday's match programme advertises one of Frank's fund-raisers. This coming Friday there's a Fun Night in the Victoria Lounge with local band The Passion Killers. There's a pie and peas supper on offer for three pounds ($5). On the opposite page is an advert from The Samaritans, offering help to the suicidal, lonely and depressed.</p>
<p>For by Saturday night, that's how most of the 1,683 souls who watched their performance against Brighton must have been feeling as they saw Hartlepool lurch even closer to the jagged edge after a 3-2 home defeat by bottom-club Brighton, the only team below them in the third division.</p>
<p>While Newcastle beat Middlesbrough in a passionate north-east derby in front of nearly 40,000 fans on Sunday, Hartlepool's faithful had to endure a game with so many high balls it brought to mind the words of their first ever successful manager -- Brian Clough, who paved the way for them to gain promotion from the old fourth division to the third in the late 1960s.</p>
<p>&quot;If God had wanted football played in the air,&quot; Clough said once, &quot;he'd have put grass in the sky.&quot;</p>
<p>Still the aerial fare on offer allowed the fans at the back of the stand to look up and see the tankers turning on the North Sea visible on the horizon. Unfortunately, Hartlepool's horizons are a lot less expansive.</p>
<p>Brighton -- so immersed in off-field troubles they make Hartlepool seem safe and sound, which they most certainly are not -- made the long trek up from the south coast to Hartlepool's windswept Victoria Park and ended a run of 16 successive away defeats with a rare victory.</p>
<p>Most of the passes, when the ball came down out of the sky, were knee-high. And nobody, it seemed, had mentioned to the players the concept of trapping the ball before passing it.</p>
<p>It was all too much for the home fans. That was Hartlepool's seventh defeat in eight matches and 60 supporters let chairman Harold Hornsey know their feelings afterwards.</p>
<p>They were demanding the resignation of manager Keith Houchen, who as a player knew better days, scoring one of Coventry's three goals when they beat Tottenham to win the F.A. Cup in 1987. Houchen refused to come out and meet the fans, or the media afterwards.</p>
<p>He had been so disgusted by his team's performance he walked out of the dugout and into the dressing room -- before the match had even finished.</p>
<p>On Monday, the fans got their wish. Houchen was fired.</p>
<p>Hartlepool have survived plenty of tough times since their formation in 1908. Before automatic relegation and promotion was introduced into the English league from the semi-pro Vauxhall Conference, Hartlepool kept their place in the English league by being voted back into it by fellow members a record 11 times.</p>
<p>In 1959-60 they lost 29 of their 46 league matches and conceded 109 goals and between March 1937 and October 1938 failed to win any of 31 away matches. In 1963-64 some cynical fans held a celebration party -- as Hartlepool had finished 23rd -- one from bottom -- instead of last.</p>
<p>But if they finish bottom this time, who knows what the fates have in store? A club with their sizeable overheads could finally sink if sponsor and television money dried up.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARTLEPOOL, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
