<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165747" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: CRICKET-IN-FORM S.AFRICA FACE BIG TEST OF NERVE.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-IN-FORM S.AFRICA FACE BIG TEST OF NERVE.</headline>
<byline>Subhash Sham</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa, winners of all six preliminary matches in their run-up to the final of the Titan Cup triangular one-day series, face their toughest challenge from hosts India on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The South Africans, playing with clinical efficiency, have already beaten India comprehensively three times in the tournament. The Australians were eliminated after failing to win a single match in the series.</p>
<p>But the final day-night match in front of an anticipated 40,000 vociferous home supporters at Bombay's Wankhede stadium may put the visitors under immense pressure.</p>
<p>India, their confidence boosted by the sensational five-run, last-over victory against Australia on Sunday at Mohali, are expected to turn on their best showing at one of their favourite venues.</p>
<p>&quot;Our first job will be to keep the massive crowd quiet and then carry on as we have been doing so far,&quot; South African coach Bob Woolmer said.</p>
<p>Woolmer will be happy that two of his injured strike bowlers Fanie de Villiers and Brian McMillan are fit for the final.</p>
<p>With Lance Klusener, bowling fairly well and coming good with the bat, the South Africans face the problem of who to drop.</p>
<p>Poor form and injuries have forced frequent changes to the Indian side which will be without two of their leading batsmen -- Saurav Ganguly and Navjot Sidhu -- who are both injured.</p>
<p>Sidhu has been replaced by right-hand batsman Sanjay Manjrekar who will be skipper Sachin Tendulkar's fourth new opening partner.</p>
<p>Stability in the opening slot continues to be India's main worry but they can take heart from the manner in which the side's batting finally clicked at Mohali.</p>
<p>India rattled a formidable 289 for six to put pressure on Australia whose failure was a big disappointment in the series.</p>
<p>Though India's strength is their batting, they will persist with four specialist bowlers, expecting Robin Singh, recalled after a seven year absence, to serve as an all-rounder in the side.</p>
<p>South Africa, on the other hand, are arguably the best all-round side in one-day cricket, thanks in part to their outstanding fielding. They have won 25 of their 28 one-day matches this year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have won three tournaments recently and have beaten world cup champions Sri Lanka, Pakistan, Australia and India. That should make us the best side in the game today,&quot; said South African captain Hansie Cronje.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
