<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165734" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: TENNIS-EDBERG ENDS SINGLES CAREER ON EMOTIONAL NOTE.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-EDBERG ENDS SINGLES CAREER ON EMOTIONAL NOTE.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stefan Edberg received an emotional farewll as his tournament singles career ended on Tueday with a disappointing first-round defeat in the Stockholm Open.</p>
<p>In an 80-minute match in front of a packed arena, Nicklas Kulti defeated fellow Swede and former world number one Edberg 7-6 6-3.</p>
<p>Edberg, 30, said he has being playing quite well but admitted he felt the pressure as he took to the centre court for the last time in his 14-year singles career.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt a little slower than normal. There was a little tension when I walked out onto the court,&quot; Edberg told a news conference at Stockholm's Royal Tennis Club.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think I played too badly tonight but I played against a guy who was really hot.&quot;</p>
<p>Edberg said it was a bit disappointing to be knocked out in the first round of his last singles tournament before retirement.</p>
<p>He lost a tight first set after it went to a tie-break, which the big-serving Kulti took 7-5.</p>
<p>But Edberg's fate was sealed in the fourth game of the second set when Kulti broke his serve.</p>
<p>&quot;I had hopes coming into this tournament and felt quite good about myself,&quot; said Edberg, who was seated in a rocking chair at the news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a pity.&quot;</p>
<p>Although the Stockholm Open was Edberg's last singles tournament, he reaffirmed he was still hoping to be chosen for the Swedish squad to play in the Davis Cup final against France in Malmo, southern Sweden, in late November.</p>
<p>&quot;So it is not quite over,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Edberg announced his retirement from competitive tennis at the end of 1995. He wants to spend more time with his wife Annette and three-year-old daughter Emilie, with whom he lives in London, and pursue some other interests.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of things up in the air,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As he shook hands over the Stockholm net for the last time, the crowd rose in a standing ovation to the tennis player who has become a national sporting hero.</p>
<p>Edberg's first win was in Milan in 1984 after he was discovered by Percy Rosberg, who also coached compatriot Bjorn Borg.</p>
<p>He never looked back.</p>
<p>In 1,075 games, he has notched 806 wins, with 41 tournament victories including six Grand Slams -- Wimbledon in 1988 and 1990, the U.S. Open 1991 and 1992, and the Australian Open in 1987 and 1990.</p>
<p>Edberg was ranked world number one in 1990 and 1991, and has been on the Davis Cup-winning team three times, in 1984, 1985 and 1994.</p>
<p>His earnings from tennis have been estimated at $20.7 million from which Edberg has set up his own foundation in Sweden to help sponsor young, aspiring tennis players.</p>
<p>After his match ended, the crowd and officials paid tribute to Edberg, with drummers, flag bearers, and ball girls carrying red roses congratulating him before he left the court for a final time.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a little heartbreaking because there are so many emotions involved. There are so many things that rush through your head,&quot; Edberg said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time I was also a little relieved that this part of playing tournaments is over.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
