<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165856" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Funds say Pakistan government change is positive.</title>
<headline>Funds say Pakistan government change is positive.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Allen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dismissal of the government of Benazir Bhutto has removed political uncertainty overhanging the market and is likely to be positive overall because economic reforms will stay on track, fund managers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not particularly worrying,&quot; said Sam Mahtani, Asia fund manager at Foreign &amp; Colonial Emerging Markets (F&amp;C), who was in the country two weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the constitution the president does have the power to do this and we will now have an interim government of technocrats which is positive as they will address key issues.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This is a scenario which has been building up, and events have been forced by the business community,&quot; said Colin Kingsnorth, manager of the $15 million Regent Moghul fund. &quot;The mood changed dramatically about a month ago.&quot;</p>
<p>Most European portfolio investment into Pakistan is managed from Asian financial centres. Amongst U.K.-based fund managers Martin Currie and Perpetual, which both have Asia regional funds, said they had no exposure there.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan is cheap, at 10x this year and an estimated 8x next year. But it's likely to give you saddle sores,&quot; said a fund manager, referring to a wearying market &quot;ride&quot; for investors.</p>
<p>F&amp;C's Mahtani noted there had been talk for months about political corruption and growing pressure on Bhutto to tackle macro-economic issues.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem was really general macro-economic management or lack of it, and not achieving the targets set by the IMF (International Monetary Fund) a year or so ago.&quot; But investors hope the new government might show more energy in implementing the reforms. &quot;There is a precedent in 1992,&quot; said one fund manager. &quot;Reform picked up faster after the change of government and prompted an IMF programme for the country.&quot;</p>
<p>Mahtani said it was clear that the President had moved with the backing of the army and he had confidence that general law and order would be maintained. Other fund managers said there was a consensus among political parties for economic reform and noted that the current interim finance minister, Syed Naveed Qamar, was a former World Bank executive.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is already quite open to foreign investment but nothing spectacular is involved -- it's about $750 million to $1.0 billion a year in direct investment,&quot; said one. &quot;It's a smaller niche market for Asia which could move up the league.&quot; Mahtani noted that money had been moving out over the last few months on the back of the political uncertainty building.</p>
<p>&quot;But now I expect a short term rally in the stock market with sectors like telecoms and energy, which are resistant to economic swings, benefitting. The recent devaluation of the rupee has also helped them.&quot;</p>
<p>Regent's Kingsnorth agreed. &quot;It will react positively short term but there is a lot that needs to be done -- building up foreign reserves, sorting out revenue collection  and bad debts and spending on power and telecoms infrastructure.&quot;</p>
<p>The market was closed for a national holiday on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 6414</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
