<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16583" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Thai-backed bank opens HQ in Shanghai's Pudong.</title>
<headline>Thai-backed bank opens HQ in Shanghai's Pudong.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>TM International Bank, which is backed by Thai investors, on Tuesday opened its head office in the Pudong New Area of Shanghai, president Virachai Virameteekul told reporters.</p>
<p>The bank has registered capital of $100 million, with 20 percent to 30 percent invested by the Charoen Pokphand Group (CP) and its associate companies, 60 percent to 70 percent by the M Thai Group, and the rest by Thai Farmers Bank, he said.</p>
<p>The bank has a branch in Shantou, Guangdong province, and representative offices in Beijing and Guangzhou, and Virachai hopes to turn the Guangzhou office into a branch in 1997.</p>
<p>The bank's main customers will be CP group companies, most of them in Shanghai and Guangdong, and the bank will reinvest most of its profits in China, he said. The CP group is one of the biggest foreign investors in China.</p>
<p>Virameteekul said he hoped China's central bank would soon award the bank a licence to do business in renminbi, China's local currency.</p>
<p>The central bank has said that foreign banks with branches in Pudong would receive priority in getting renminbi licences.</p>
<p>Virachai gave no other details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
