<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165872" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IBCA cuts Credit National, BFCE.</title>
<headline>IBCA cuts Credit National, BFCE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>IBCA, the European credit rating agency, said on Tuesday it had cut the long- and short-term ratings of France's Credit National and Banque Francaise du Commerce Exterieur (BFCE) to A minus and A2, from A and A1 respectively.  </p>
<p>IBCA said the Credit National's (CN) individual rating was also cut to C/D from C previously, but affirmed the Legal rating of 2 for both banks as well as BFCE's Individual rating of B/C.  </p>
<p>&quot;The move reflects a number of factors which... have negatively affected the group's results for 1995 and the first part of 1996,&quot; IBCA said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Although CN-BFCE's short-term credit activities, its international operations and its trading results have kept up well, these were not enough to compensate for the fall in the medium/long-term credit business, which was sharper than expected,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>It said operating profits were also depressed by a high level of loan-loss previsions and write-downs of investments.</p>
<p>But IBCA added that profitability is expected to reach its lowest level in 1996 and the loss reported in the first half of the year could be partly attributed to the cost of restructuring.</p>
<p>&quot;A new organisational structure is about to be implemented which will merge the two banks into one, with a view to rationalise costs and reduce non-interest expenses,&quot; IBCA said.</p>
<p>&quot;It added that returns should improve as long as economic conditions do not deteriorate significantly.</p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
