<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165972" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAfrica Manuel hopes for Telkom cash in 1996/97 yr.</title>
<headline>SAfrica Manuel hopes for Telkom cash in 1996/97 yr.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said on Tuesday he hoped the partial privatisation of South Africa's Telkom telecommunications corporation would be completed within the fiscal year ending March 31.</p>
<p>Manuel told a news briefing the government would not adopt a rigid formula for the application of privatisation funds.</p>
<p>He said some of the proceeds would be applied to reducing the national debt, some would go to infrastructure and some might be retained within the corporation concerned.</p>
<p>&quot;Retirement of debt versus upgrading of infrastructure...It's something we would monitor fairly closely rather than adopt a knee-jerk 50-50 split between debt retirement and infrastructure,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Minister of Posts, Telecommunications and Broadcasting Jay Naidoo on Monday announced a shortlist of four foreign candidates to buy up to 30 percent of the state-owned telecommunications corporation.</p>
<p>Naidoo said on Tuesday he expected a decision on what will be South Africa's first major privatisation deal by late March or early April.</p>
<p>Naidoo has estimated that the package, likely to include a human resource development plan and a commitment to service delivery, is likely to include a cash component of up to six billion rand.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm hoping that we see that before the close of this fiscal year,&quot; Manuel said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He said the income would be divided amongst Telkom projects, debt redemption and other infrastructural needs.</p>
<p>&quot;Part of it has to be tied into the upgrading of the telecommunications capability (but)...there's other kinds of infrastructure needed that can unleash enormous economic potential,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
