<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="165946" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MADAGASCAR: Former president in second place in Madagascar poll.</title>
<headline>Former president in second place in Madagascar poll.</headline>
<byline>Honore Razafintsalama</byline>
<dateline>ANTANANARIVO 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former president Albert Zafy moved to second place on Tuesday behind former military ruler Didier Ratsiraka in partial results from Sunday's presidential election in Madagascar.</p>
<p>With results received from more than one-third of the 15,000 polling stations, Zafy, 69, took over second place to Ratsiraka from prime minister and interim president Norbert Ratsirahonana.</p>
<p>Ratsiraka, 59, had 38.45 percent of counted ballots while Zafy, whose impeachment by parliament in July forced the early presidential election, took 16.19 percent, the partial results showed.</p>
<p>They were followed by Ratsirahonana with 15.76 percent and U.S.-educated millionaire businessman Herizo Razafimahaleo with 14.77 percent.</p>
<p>Political analysts said it seemed unlikely that any of the candidates would win an outright majority in the first round.</p>
<p>Final official results were not expected for two or three weeks and a run-off would probably not take place before the start of the new year.</p>
<p>A total of 15 candidates including preachers, pharmacists and Marxists were vying to take charge as president of the vast island and its 14 million people who live in chronic poverty.</p>
<p>Zafy, who was charged by parliament with abusing his authority, was elected president in 1993 to succeed Ratsiraka.</p>
<p>Ratsiraka, who returned to the island from 19 months of voluntary exile in France at the end of September, had been reviled by many of his people in the early 1990s for using the army to resist the pro-democracy movement.</p>
<p>Following the start of voting on Sunday, Interior Minister Charles Sylvain Rabotoarison denounced what he said were attempts to sabotage the election, saying police in the capital had received reports of various irregularities.</p>
<p>He cited instances of &quot;phantom electoral lists&quot;, voters' cards for under-age people and people with three or four voters' cards and said the reports were being investigated.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANTANANARIVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MADAGASCAR"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
