<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166008" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Ex-ZCCM workers seek to reopen Kabwe mine.</title>
<headline>Ex-ZCCM workers seek to reopen Kabwe mine.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of former Zambia Consolidated Copper Mines (ZCCM) workers have signed a contract to buy the Kabwe lead and zinc mine which was closed in June 1994.</p>
<p>A ZCCM spokesman said Kabwe Power and Metal Ltd (KPM) would acquire 85 percent of the mine's assets for 1.1 billion kwacha (about $915,000).</p>
<p>The group then plans to pump in more than 60 billion kwacha to resuscitate operations.</p>
<p>KPM chairman Kizito Mumbi said the former mine employees had used their terminal benefits to procure the mine's assets and were now seeking international finance to develop the mine.</p>
<p>&quot;We have approached a number of international financial institutions, and three are very interested in the project. Two of them are European and one is American,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;They have not yet committed themselves to financing the project, but are very keen to conduct their own feasibility studies in the project.&quot;</p>
<p>The mines new owners plan to go into the production of lead and zinc, as well as offering engineering products and services.</p>
<p>KPM would process waste dump material at the rate of 240,000 tonnes of slag per year, producing 54,000 tonne of oxide material each year for between 25 and 30 years.</p>
<p>It expected to export 70 percent of its products.</p>
<p>KPM was formed by some 300 miners who were laid off when the loss-making mine was closed.</p>
<p>&quot;Immediately after the closure of the mine was announced, a team of Kabwe Mine employees saw an opportunity staring them in the face. Putting their heads together, they mooted a plan to take advantage of that opportunity,&quot; ZCCM director of human resouces, Urban Chishimba said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that the KPM will marshall their individual and collective technical expertise to make this venture a success story,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>-- Jowie Mwiinga, Lusaka newsroom +2601 222689</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
