<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166092" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania to announce GSM tender winners this week.</title>
<headline>Romania to announce GSM tender winners this week.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's Communications Ministry will announce this week the winners in a long-delayed tender for two lucrative licences to install and operate a new GSM digital cellular phone system in Romania, an official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The winners will be announced most probably on Friday,&quot; said the official, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Major Western companies are in the running. They include: Italy's Stet Spa, France's Bouygues,  Telecom Finland, Air Touch Communications Inc of the United States, France Telecom U.S. Telecoms group Motorola, Tele Danmark and Norway's Telenor.</p>
<p>September 26 was the deadline for entry to the competition.</p>
<p>The offers have been studied by a ministry commission, including foreign experts, the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;To be honest I don't know why it takes so long to make the announcement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The official said the delay was &quot;in no way related to the outcome of the vote&quot;, a reference to Romania's parliamentary and presidential elections last Sunday.</p>
<p>The tender requires companies to be able to cover at least 65 percent of Romania with the GSM system, to have solid operating experience and financial strength to back the costs of the project, expected to cost some $1.0 billion.</p>
<p>The project, expected to become opereational last year, was delayed by lack of free frequencies on the 900 MHZ waveband as well as by political turmoil in the ministry. -- Adrian Dascalu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
