<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166104" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria lev ends flat with central bank support.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria lev ends flat with central bank support.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The lev closed at 248.50-249.30 per dollar, virtually flat from opening at 248.50-249.50 thanks to support from the central bank and unmoved by talk that a pegged exhcange rate was being mulled by officials, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Dollar) demand was very low today compared to Monday and central bank dollar sales helped the lev to consolidate around opening levels in early trade,&quot; a commercial bank dealer said.</p>
<p>The central bank was selling small dollar volumes to final clients near 249 levs throughout the day, dealers said.</p>
<p>Central bank officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>&quot;Interbank trade was very thin because most banks have built up forex positions after the last interest rate cut and now are waiting to see what the outcome of talks with the IMF will be,&quot; another dealer said.</p>
<p>An IMF mission is now in Sofia to evaluate the government's reform performance under a funding deal signed in July.</p>
<p>Speculations that a currency board option, under which a country's money supply is directly proportional to hard currency reserves, was being discussed with the IMF mission have not had an impact on the local forex market so far, dealers said.</p>
<p>The central bank, under government pressure to make lending to a stagnant economy easier, last week cut its main interest rate to 15 percent monthly or 180 percent annually from 20 and 240 percent respectively, in force from Monday. -- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
