<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166246" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Peru says misplaced tape may be cause of air crash.</title>
<headline>Peru says misplaced tape may be cause of air crash.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA, Peru 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Peru's Transport Ministry said on Tuesday the air crash last month of a Boeing 757-200 airliner that killed all 70 on board might have been caused by adhesive tape covering altitude and speed sensors.</p>
<p>The obstruction of these instruments by maintenance workers &quot;could explain the erroneous and confused information about height and speed that was received by the pilots after takeoff,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.  </p>
<p>The tape, covering sensors used to measure atmospheric pressure, was found in the plane's main body in the Pacific Ocean where it crashed October 2 soon after taking off for Santiago de Chile from Lima in heavy fog.</p>
<p>&quot;We have observed that these (sensors) are covered with adhesive tape, a normal procedure in the maintenance of planes during polishing,&quot; the ministry said without explaining why they were not removed before flight.</p>
<p>Previously the Peruvian government had pinned the blame for the accident on technical faults which made the computers aboard the plane &quot;go crazy,&quot; leaving pilot, Eric Schreiber, without instruments as he struggled to return to Lima.</p>
<p>The 70 dead, in one of the worst disasters in Peru's aviation history, came from Chile, Peru, Mexico, Ecuador, the United States, Italy, Great Britain, New Zealand, Spain, Colombia and Venezuela.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA, Peru"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
