<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166235" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico stocks end up on Dow and rates forecast.</title>
<headline>Mexico stocks end up on Dow and rates forecast.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexican stocks closed higher Tuesday after what traders and analysts said was a more optimistic session, in which trading was buoyed up by gains in the Dow Jones and expectations that primary rates would fall.</p>
<p>&quot;Three things helped the bourse today: the possibilty that Cetes (Treasury bill) rates will fall at least 50 basis points (one-half percentage point), the Dow Jones rally and the IPC's breaking through resistance,&quot; said a floor trader.</p>
<p>The blue chip IPC index closed up 38.24 points, or 1.18 percent, at 3,285.95. Volume was much improved from Monday at 74.6 million shares traded.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones meanwhile closed up 39.50 points, or 0.65 percent, at 6,081.18.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of nine money market traders showed they expected the bellwether 28-day Cetes rate in this week's auction to average 29.13 percent, or 0.21 percentage points below last week's rate.</p>
<p>Other traders put the rally down to relative stability in the peso and favourable speculation about budget proposals to be made on Thursday.</p>
<p>The benchmark 48-hour peso closed 1.95 centavos softer than Monday, but much firmer than recent levels, at 7.9175 per dollar.</p>
<p>Traders said most buyers were locals, but some foreigners were present.</p>
<p>&quot;Volume picked up as the session went on. Foreigners stepped in later, mostly switching stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>On the broad market, 106 stocks were traded in all, of which gainers outnumbered losers by 71 to 18.</p>
<p>Blue chips were absent from the leading gainers with textile stock Synkro in first place, up ten centavos (1 cent) at 1.10 pesos (14 cents) but at minimal volume. In second place was infrequently traded financial stock Ixegf, which gained eight centavos (1 cent) to 1.50 pesos (19 cents).</p>
<p>Paper firm Kimber was a leading loser, down 7.10 pesos (90 cents) at 156.90 pesos ($19.81), after gaining substantially last week, traders said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
