<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166217" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Nov 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Estonia - Nov 5.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the reports carried by Estonia's newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these reports and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>ALL NEWSPAPERS</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Siim Kallas said he would leave for a meeting with Yevgeny Primakov in an optimistic mood, hoping that a border agreement would be signed in a month.</p>
<p>- Students are unhappy about a government decision to stop subsidies which allow them to buy half-price bus and train tickets. A protest letter with 3,500 signatures will be delivered to the government today and demonstrations on the roads are planned in the southern city of Tartu.</p>
<p>POSTIMEES</p>
<p>- Postimees asked for MPs' opinions on the border agreement with Russia. Opinions differ greatly and there is no firm conviction that the parliament would ratify the agreement.</p>
<p>EESTI PASEVALEHT</p>
<p>- Parliament's financial commission said most of the changes they had received for the 1997 draft budget were populist and unrealistic.</p>
<p>- Police on Friday found and defused a bomb with three kg of explosive in a hamburger bar in the northeastern town of Johvi and said a catastrophe was narrowly avoided.</p>
<p>ARIPAEV</p>
<p>- Tallinn city court overruled a government decree from 1995 on non-return of property and decided that one of the leading hotels in Tallinn, the Hotel Palace, should be returned to its legal owner.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom +371 7 22 66 93</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
