<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166358" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil publishes cellular concession rules.</title>
<headline>Brazil publishes cellular concession rules.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil's Communication Ministry published on Tuesday rules for private companies operating cellular telephone services.</p>
<p>The rules, published in Brazil's official Daily Gazette, stated that concessions to run cellular services will be valid for 15 years and are renewable after that.</p>
<p>Private consortia will be invited to bid to operate ten regional concessions. Any one group will be limited to a maximum of one concession in Brazil's developed south and south east and another in the underdeveloped north, northeast and centerwest.  </p>
<p>Would-be concession holders will be required to state the maximum value of their proposed tariffs when bidding although those tariffs may be renegotiated should the concessions turn economically unviable, the gazette said.</p>
<p>Winners of concessions must ensure their cellular networks are interconnectable with the existing public system.</p>
<p>The gazette also published rules outlining technical criteria bidders must meet and how the private and public networks will compensate one another for interconnected calls.  </p>
<p>Newspaper Gazeta Mercantil said public hearings on the bidding rules would be held over the next 15 days but no-one was available to confirm the report.</p>
<p>The opening up to the private sector of Brazil's so-called B Band of cellular services is the first big step in the privatization of the country's telecommunications industry.</p>
<p>The number of cellular customers in Brazil is expected to grow ten times to 15 million by the year 2000, according to government estimates.</p>
<p>Winners of the B Band concessions will compete against regional subsidiaries of state holding Telebras TEL.SAu which currently operate on an A Band.</p>
<p>Some of the world's biggest telecommunications firms, like AT&amp;T, BellSouth Corp, SBC Communications Corp. and GTE Corp, have linked up with Brazilian partners to jointly bid for the B Band contracts.</p>
<p>-- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
