<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166508" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's Sony Music suffers from profit fall.</title>
<headline>Japan's Sony Music suffers from profit fall.</headline>
<byline>Kayako Watanabe</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sony Music Entertainment (Japan) Inc had to face the music on Tuesday, announcing that its half-year profits fell more than 50 percent due to fewer album releases during the period.</p>
<p>The company, 71 percent owned by Sony Corp, said the fall in the number of releases was partly intentional as part of a restructuring.</p>
<p>But in addition, planned releases of some CDs during the six months to the end of September were put off, the entertainment software company said.</p>
<p>&quot;Planned releases of new albums by some of our main artists were delayed until the second half of the business year, and due to the overall fall in new releases, our interim sales fell 12.1 percent year-on-year to 46.62 billion yen ($408 million),&quot; Sony Music said.</p>
<p>The company also boosted its efforts to promote its artists and that pushed up advertising costs as well, it said.</p>
<p>A Sony Music spokesman declined to say which artists' CDs were delayed.</p>
<p>Sony Music announced that it posted parent current profit of 4.74 billion yen ($41.5 million) in the six months to September 30, down 53.1 percent from the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Current profit is pre-tax but includes gains and losses made on securities investments and other non-operating activities.</p>
<p>Sony Music said it expects parent current profit of 12.6 billion yen ($110 million) in the full year to March 31, 1997, against actual current profit of 20.96 billion yen ($183 million) last fiscal year.</p>
<p>Besides selling CDs of domestic singers, the company also sells CDs of such international artists as Mariah Carey, Michael Jackson and Celine Dion, who have recording contracts with the company's U.S. sister firm, Sony Music Entertainment Inc.</p>
<p>The U.S. company is 100 percent owned by Sony Corp. ($1=114 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
