<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166571" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stocks jump as traders hope for status-quo in Washington.</title>
<headline>Stocks jump as traders hope for status-quo in Washington.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks prices jumped Tuesday as Wall Street, hoping for the status-quo in Washington following the national elections, threw an early celebration.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 39.50 points at 6,081.18, while the Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 7.41 points to a new high close of 714.14, beating the old milestone of 710.82 set on Oct. 18.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks also set a record high, rising 3.36 to 378.43.</p>
<p>The blue-chip Dow index is drawing closer to its all-time closing high of 6,094.23 set on Oct. 18. In the broader market, advancing issues led declines 1,447 to 945 on active volume of 486 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has predicted the election,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, an analyst at Prudential Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;It's jumped ahead and made the bet Republicans will retain control of Congress and (President) Clinton will win re-election,&quot; he said. &quot;But if we're wrong dramatically, the Dow could fall 100-150 points&quot; Wednesday.</p>
<p>The stock market is favouring a split in government on the belief that Democrats unchecked would run deep spending-driven deficits while Republicans unchecked would run equally deep deficits by failing to find spending cuts to pay for their tax cuts.</p>
<p>Evidence of Wall Street's confidence came from the bond market.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond was up a full point, which lowered its yield to 6.59 percent -- the lowest since March 26 -- from 6.66 percent at Monday's close.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is celebrating a status quo election,&quot; said David Shulman, chief equity strategist at Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>He noted the Dow index has surged 60 percent since the Republican party won control of Congress two years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The market obviously likes the current combination. If it's not broken, why fix it?,&quot; Shulman said.</p>
<p>Wall Street had been on edge in recent weeks, fearing a Democratic sweep might spur greater social spending, a ballooning deficit and a spike in inflation.</p>
<p>Interest-rate sensitive stocks led the market higher. Chase Manhattan rose 1-7/8 to 88-3/8, Fannie Mae added 5/8 to 38-1/4, Wells Fargo was up 5-5/8 to 273-1/4 and Citicorp gained 1-3/4 to 101-1/4.</p>
<p>Drug stocks also rose. &quot;They've risen the past week or so with confidence there won't be a change in the composition of Congress,&quot; said Wachtel.</p>
<p>Worries that a Democratically controlled Congress would revisit health-care reform had pressured the group. Merck rose 1/2 to 75-3/4, Pfizer added 1-7/8 to 86 and Eli Lilly rose 2-1/8 to 73-3/4.</p>
<p>Technology stocks also were solidly higher as worries about Christmas sales of personal computers abated. U.S. Robotics reported quarterly results that were in line with expectations, and Bear Stearns made bullish comments on Compaq.</p>
<p>U.S. Robotics rose 1-1/2 to 61, Intel surged 3-5/8 to 114, Microsoft rose 3-1/2 to 141-1/2, Compaq rallied 4 to 70-3/8 and International Business Machines rose 1-1/2 to 130-1/4.</p>
<p>Ascend Communications, which is expected to introduce a device to allow Internet providers to accept calls from higher speed 56-kilobit modems, surged 5-33/64 to 73-17/64.</p>
<p>Texaco lost 3 to 94-5/8. A lawyer who represents black employees who sued Texaco in 1994 for alleged discrimination said Tuesday that Federal prosecutors launched a probe into whether Texaco tried to obstruct justice by destroying documents sought in a racial discrimination lawsuit.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index rose 8.59 to 1,229.07. The American Stock Exchange index was up 1.86 to 573.62. The average NYSE share was up 36 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 6,920.285 up 59.151 or 0.86 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
