<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166628" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ballot questions and bond referendums by state.</title>
<headline>Ballot questions and bond referendums by state.</headline>
<text>
<p>ALABAMA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Amendment No 4 - To allow for-profit bingo in Morgan County.</p>
<p>--Amendment No 5 - In Jefferson County, to provide that the monetary amount of prizes for playing of bingo shall be established by local law.</p>
<p>--$60 million of Mobile County, Ala., special tax bonds for bridges and drainage.</p>
<p>ALASKA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Ballot Measure No 1 to require popular approval or 2/3 vote of legislature to change Statehood Act.</p>
<p>ARIZONA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Proposition 101 - A property tax exemption for the first $50,000 of the value of personal property that is used for agriculture, trades and business. Would allow the legislature to increase the exempt amount on a national inflation index.</p>
<p>--Proposition 201 - Would provide that Arizona can enter into gaming compacts with Indian Tribes that request a compact and that have not previously entered into a compact.</p>
<p>--Proposition 203 - Allocate $17 million of lottery revenues annually to fund six specified health and nutrition programs.</p>
<p>--Proposition 300 - Raise annual salaries of state legislators to $24,000 from $15,000.</p>
<p>ARKANSAS</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Amendment 1 - Establish uniform property tax rate for maintenance and operation of schools.</p>
<p>--Amendment 2 - Establish a sales/use tax of 1/8 of one percent to support the Arkansas Game and Fish Commission, the Department of Parks and Tourism, the Arkansas Department of Heritage and Keep Arkansas Beautiful.</p>
<p>--Amendment 4 - Establish state lottery, bingo games and raffles by non-profit organizations and allow voters in Hot Springs to decide whether or not to authorize casino gambling at or adjacent to the Oaklawn racetrack and at two casino establishments in Hot Springs.</p>
<p>CALIFORNIA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5:</p>
<p>--$2 billion Los Angeles Unified School District, Calif., school bonds.</p>
<p>--$995 million, California Proposition 204 - Safe, Clean, Reliable Water Supply Act. Would authorize the issuance of general obligation bonds to finance water programs.</p>
<p>--$750 million Los Angeles, Calif., park bonds.</p>
<p>--$700 million, California Proposition 205 - Youthful and Adult Offender Local Facilities Bond Act of 1996. Would authorize the issuance of general obligation bonds to construct and renovate county juvenile and adult correctional facilities.</p>
<p>--$400 million, Proposition 206 - Veterans' Bond Act of 1996. Would authorize the issuance of general obligation bonds to fund a program of farm, home and mobile home loans.</p>
<p>--$319 million Los Angeles County, Calif., greenbelt, zoo improvement bonds.</p>
<p>--$225 million Sacramento Unified School District, Calif., school GO bonds.</p>
<p>--$100 million San Francisco, Calif., GOs.</p>
<p>--$45 million Sequoia Union High School District, Calif., school GOs.</p>
<p>--$6 Ravenswood City Elementary School District, in Palo Alto, Calif., school GOs.</p>
<p>--Proposition 210 - Minimum Wage Increase. Increases the current state minimum wage of $4.25 per hour to $5.00 per hour on March 1, 1997 and then to $5.75 per hour on March 1, 1998.</p>
<p>--Proposition 217 - Top Income Tax Brackets. Continues highest tax rates of 10 percent and 11 percent on residents with taxable income over $100,000 and $200,000 respectively.</p>
<p>--Proposition 218 - Voter Approval for Local Government Taxes. Limits authority of local governments to impose taxes and property-related assessments, fees and charges. Requires majority of voters approve increases in general taxes and reiterates that two-thirds must approve special taxes.</p>
<p>COLORADO</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$100 million Colorado Springs, Colo., school bonds.</p>
<p>--Amendment 11 - Eliminates property tax exemption of churches.</p>
<p>--Amendment 16 - Changes Colorado State Board of Land Commissioners' current constitutional duty of maximizing revenue from state trust lands to managing the land to produce reasonable and consistent income over time; permits the state legislature to enact laws that allow the public school fund to be used to invest in and guarantee school district bonds and to make loans to school districts.</p>
<p>--Amendment 18 - Permit certain gambling in Trinidad, Colo.</p>
<p>--Referendum A - Require 60 percent majority vote, instead of simple majority vote, of people to amend state constitution; provides that amendments to the constitution previously adopted with less than 60 percent of the votes may be amended or repealed until January 1, 2003, with simple majority of votes cast.</p>
<p>--Referendun D - Allow unemployment insurance taxes to be increased without voter approval.</p>
<p>CONNECTICUT</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Cheshire: $1 million for the acquisition of land for recreational, open space, conservation, educational and municipal purposes and the issuance of bonds and notes in the same amount to defray the expenses; $2.9 million be appropriated for building an indoor/outdoor swimming pool and bonds in the same amount.</p>
<p>--Danbury: appropriations aggregating $14.9 million for various public improvements and authorizing the issuance of $14.9 million of bonds to meet such appropriations, and pending issuance, the making of temporary borrowings.</p>
<p>--Derby: appropriate $4.7 million for road and pavement constructions, storm drainage, improvements and bonds and temporary notes.</p>
<p>--East Hartford: $6 million be appropriated and bonds authorized for implementing the Main Street Business District Redevelopment; $2.95 million be appropriated and bonds authorized for roof repairs and paving improvements at various town schools and for an addition to Silver Lane School; $1.8 million be appropriated and bonds authorized for the planning, design and reconstruction of Lord, Drennan Goldstar Town Pools.</p>
<p>--Glastonbury: $5.75 million be appropriated for the Wells-Turner Memorial Library renovations and expansion and authorizing the issuance of bonds and notes in same amount.</p>
<p>--Groton: an ordinance appropriating $10.388 million and authorizing bonds and notes in the same amount for additions and improvements to the Water Pollution Control Facility and a sewer system evaluation study.</p>
<p>--Hartford: an ordinance authorizing $20 million of bonds for improvements to certain schools be approved; 5 ordinances authorizing the issuance of a total of $13.7 million of city bonds for planning, acquisition, construction, reconstruction and renovation of 5 schools throughout the city; an ordinance authorizing $16 million of bonds for renovations and improvements to Hartford public libraries, central library and 3 branches.</p>
<p>--Middletown: bond ordinance and appropriations for $9.96 million for the acquisition of land and for the planning, acquisition and construction of a new police headquarters.</p>
<p>--Montvale: $2.5 million be appropriated and bonds authorized for the expansion and modification of the Montvale Sewage Treatment plant.</p>
<p>--Norwalk: Section 1-289 of the Norwalk charter be amended to provide for the common council to set a cap on the operating budget; Section 1-669 of City of Norwalk existing referendum procedure be amended to allow for a binding referendum on the city's operating budget.</p>
<p>--Norwich: $11.5 million be appropriated and bonds authorized for the expansion and renovation of Samuel Huntington and Bishop elementary schools; $11 million be appropriated and bonds authorized for the implementation of citywide schools system computer technology improvements.</p>
<p>--Plainville: appropriate $2.5 million for the athletic fields project and authorize the issuance of bonds and notes.</p>
<p>--Waterbury: Charter Section 1553 be amended to clarify that the auditing functions are performed by the Department of Audit; Charter Section 2010 be amended so that the investment powers of the board of agents of the Silas Bronson Library are governed by section 45a - 234 of the Connecticut general statutes and the prudent investor rule and to eliminate the mortgage powers of the library board.</p>
<p>--Watertown: appropriate $7.275 million for the Town Hall Campus Complex project and authorize the issuance of bonds or notes in the same amount to finance said appropriation.</p>
<p>--Windsor: $1.3 million appropriation and bond authorization for an addition and renovation to the Poquonock Fire House.</p>
<p>DELAWARE</p>
<p>FLORIDA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$200 million Dade County, Fla., GOs for parks.</p>
<p>--Dade County, Fla., votes on whether tax money can be used to build $165 million basketball arena for Miami Heat.</p>
<p>--Dade County straw ballot on municipal revenue sharing proposal that would levy an additional property tax in affluent areas to subsidize services in poor areas.</p>
<p>--$35 million Fort Lauderdale, Fla., GOs for parks.</p>
<p>--Question No. 1 - Proposal requiring two-thirds voter approval for statewide tax increases.</p>
<p>--Question No 2 -- Would convene the next Constitutional Revision Commission in 1997 instead of 1998 as previously planned, and would give the panel more leeway in recommending changes to the state constitution.</p>
<p>--Question 4 - Impose fee on sugar production in the Everglades.</p>
<p>--Question No. 5 - Provides that those in the Everglades Agricultural Area who cause water pollution within Everglades Protection Area or the Everglades Agricultural Area be primarily responsible for paying the cost of the abatement of that pollution.</p>
<p>--Question No. 6 - Establish an Evergaldes Trust Fund for the purposes of conservation and protection of natural resources and abatement of water pollution, funded through any sources, including gifts and state or federal funds.</p>
<p>--Escambia County, Fla., votes on property tax increase to fund land preservation.</p>
<p>MARCH 25</p>
<p>--Pinellas Cty, Fla., 10-year extension of one-cent sales tax increase for schools.</p>
<p>GEORGIA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$115 million of Richmond Cty, Ga, GOs for schools.</p>
<p>--$30 million Cobb County, Ga., GOs for recreation.</p>
<p>--Gwinnett County, Ga., votes on a one-cent sales tax increase to finance park, library and public safety projects.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment 1 - Referendum on proposal to end intangibles tax.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment 2 - Referendum on proposal allowing school systems to impose one percent sales tax for construction.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment 3 - Allow General Assembly to create &quot;enterprise zones&quot; exempt from taxes levied by state , county, city or any combination thereof to persons, firms or corporations which create job opportunities within designated enterprise zones to provide employment opportunities.</p>
<p>--Referendun A - Exempt from ad valorem taxes certain vans and buses owned by religous groups.</p>
<p>--Referendum B - Exempt from ad valorem taxes certain property owned by historical fraternal groups. </p>
<p>HAWAII</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>1 - Allow use of revenue bonds to finance a loan program to make loans to state property insurance programs that provide hurricane insurance coverage to the general public.</p>
<p>2 - Allow state to appropriate funds of the state educational facilities improvement special fund for periods beyond three years to allow for acquisition or construction of public school facilities.</p>
<p>3 - Prevents the lapsing of unencumbered general obligation bond funds which are deemed necessary by the legislature to qualify for federal aid and financing and reimbursement be removed from the provision that requires the lapsing of all unencumbered funds at the end of each fiscal year.</p>
<p>4 - Convene a state constitutional convention.</p>
<p>IDAHO</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>Proposition 1 - Limit property taxes to one percent of value subject to asssessment and providing exceptions.</p>
<p>Proposition 3 - Limit authority of state officials to enter into agreements for the receipt and storage of additional radioactive waste in Idaho. Would require any such agreement to be approved by state legislature and voters.</p>
<p>ILLINOIS</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Voters in 19 Illinois counties will be asked to approve a limit on local property tax increases. Under the measure, annual increases in local property tax collections would be 2capped at five percent or the rate of inflation, whichever is less. The restriction would also prohibit the issuance of general obligation debt without voter approval. Counties slated to hold tax cap elections are: Boone, Champaign, Christian, Franklin, Jackson, Kankakee, Lee, Logan, Macoupin, Massac, Menard, Monroe,Morgan, Randolph, Sangamon, Schuyler, 2Union, Williamson and Winnebago.</p>
<p>--$4.5 million Mokena, Ill., park GOs.</p>
<p>INDIANA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Public Question No. 2 - Allow the state retirement funds to be invested in stocks and other securities.</p>
<p>IOWA</p>
<p>KANSAS</p>
<p>KENTUCKY</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Prohibit poll taxes on each person reading within county or city and to remove language requiring separate schools for &quot;white&quot; and &quot;colored&quot; children.</p>
<p>LOUISIANA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment 3 - Authorize legislature to exempt goods or property from sales or use taxes.</p>
<p>--State parishes vote whether to keep gambling legal.</p>
<p>MAINE</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>Maine is planning to ask its voters to approve or reject a total of around $40 million of bond initiatives:</p>
<p>--$16.5 million to clean up public health, hazardous substance discharge sites, including tire stockpiles, with $9 million set aside for drinking water grants for cities and towns.</p>
<p>--$11 million to encourage job growth and economic vitality by helping agricultural enterprises and small businesses get capital.</p>
<p>--$10 million to clean up water pollution and drinking water problems.</p>
<p>--$3 million for capital improvements at state parks.</p>
<p>MARYLAND</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$89.6 million Baltimore County, Md., GOs for schools.</p>
<p>--Prince George's County, Md., vote on proposal to repeal property tax cap.</p>
<p>MASSACHUSETTS</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Shall Berkley issue bonds to pay for a new school that would be exempt from the proposition 2-1/2?</p>
<p>--Shall Berkley issue bonds for new police and fire department facilities that would be exempt?</p>
<p>--Shall Athol issue bonds for buying or leasing land for a middle school for Athol-Royalston Regionanal School District that would be exempt?</p>
<p>--Shall Athol issue bonds to for refurbishing a high scholl that would be exempt?</p>
<p>--Should a Cape Cod Land Bank be established to protect drinking water, buy open space and conservation land, provide bicycling and walking trails, enhance recreation, help first-time home buyers, and be funded by a one-percent fee on all land transfers at the Barnstable county registry of deeds, exempting the first $100,000 of the purchase price?</p>
<p>--Shall Dover issue bonds for a new town garage and site improvements at 2 Dedham Street that would be exempt?</p>
<p>--Shall Easthampton issue bonds to build a new facility for the fire and police department that would be exempt?</p>
<p>--Shall Millbury issue bonds to pay for building sewage system and appurtenant works in the Oak Pond area tha would be exempt?</p>
<p>--Shall Millis issue bonds for drawings, bid documents, project representations, construction contracts and furnishings for major renovations to the Millis Middle School/High School Building that would be exempt?</p>
<p>--Shall Needham issue bonds not to exceed $5.75 miln for extraordinary repairs and additions to the Newman School Building that would be exempt? </p>
<p>MICHIGAN</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Proposal E - to allow three casinos in Detroit, establish a Michigan Gaming Control Board, and impose an 18 percent state tax on gross gaming revenues, allocating 45 percent of the revenues to the state's school aid fund and 55 percent to Detroit.</p>
<p>--Wayne County, Mich. - Voter approval for one percent hotel/motel tax, two percent car rental tax. Revenues from tax would pay off $80 million of bonds that would be sold to help finance a new $225 million domed stadium for the Detroit Lions football team in downtown Detroit.</p>
<p>MINNESOTA</p>
<p>--Amendment 2 - Provide for recall of members of the state legislature, governor, lieutenant governor, secretary of state, state auditor, state treasurer, the attorney general and state judges through a three-step recall process.</p>
<p>MISSISSIPPI</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$23 million Harrison County, Miss., GOs for schools.</p>
<p>--$6.4 million west Jasper Cty, Miss., GOs for schools.</p>
<p>MISSOURI</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment No. 3 - Provide funding from the general revenue fund for the Facilities Maintenance Reserve Fund for the purpose of maintenance, repair and renovation of state facilities. The proposal would result in the transfer of $5.4 million from the general revenue fund.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment No. 6 - Allow municipalities to be authorized to issue bonds to build revenue producing sewer treatment plants and have water plants removed from regulation as a public utility.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment No. 7 - Create a rainy day fund for the state to provide an operating reserve in years where revenue projections are below expectations.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment No. 8 - Extend for ten years the sales and use tax of one-tenth of one percent for use by the Department of Natural Resources for soil and water conservation and for the acquisition, development, maintenance and operation of state parks and historic sites.</p>
<p>MONTANA</p>
<p>--Initiative 122 - Increase requirements for water teatment.</p>
<p>--Initiative 125 - Prohibit corporate spending on ballot initiatives.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment No. 32 - To allow legislature to meet every other year.</p>
<p>NEBRASKA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Initiative Petition Measure 412 - Limit property taxes for various governmental subdivisions which could be exceeded by a majority vote of the voters.</p>
<p>--Initiative Petition Measure 411 - To make quality education a fundamental constitutional right.</p>
<p>--Proposed Amendment No. 1 - Allow legislature to authorize off-track parimutuel betting on horseraces.</p>
<p>--Proposed Amednment No. 2 - Allow merger, consolidation of local governments with popular approval.</p>
<p>NEW HAMPSHIRE</p>
<p>NEW JERSEY</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Proposed constitutional amendment to dedicate four percent of corporate business taxes each year to environmental projects.</p>
<p>--$300 million New York/New Jersey port region dredging bonds.</p>
<p>NEW MEXICO</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$12 million Sante Fe, N.M., bond measure to fund public works projects.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment I - To protect the state's permanent funds against inflation by limiting distributions to a percentage of each fund's market value and by modifying certain investment restrictions to allow optimal diversification of investments.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment II - To enhance education by authorizing school districts to incur debt witout an election for the limited purpose of acquiring education technology equipment through lease-purchase agreements.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment IV - Allow additional methods for voters to amend the constitution and directing the Secretary of State to inform voters about constitutional amendments.</p>
<p>--Constitutional Amendment VII - Would authorize counties to borrow money to acquire real estate for open space and open-space related uses and to purchase capital equipment for road and bridge construction and repair.</p>
<p>NEW YORK</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$1.75 billion New York Clean Water, Clean Air Bond Act. Would fund a variety of environmental projects through-out the state.</p>
<p>--$1.5 million Albany, N.Y., issue.</p>
<p>--Westchester County, $500,000 bonds to fund design and other studies for the Hudson River esplanade park. </p>
<p>NEVADA</p>
<p>Question No. 12 - $20 million of general obligation bonds to provide grants to local governments and Nevada's Department of Transportation to carry out projects for the control of erosion and the restoration of natural watercources in the Lake Tahoe Basin.</p>
<p>Question No.1 - Prohibit the state from borrowing money from public employees retirement funds.</p>
<p>Question No. 6 - Exemption from debt limit applies to borrowing to retrofit state buidlings.</p>
<p>Question No. 7 - Allow state money to be invested in private compnaies.</p>
<p>Question No. 11 - Would require two-thirds vote of the legislature to increase taxes.</p>
<p>Question No. 16 - New taxes must pass state legislature twice. --$634 million Clark County Sch Dist,, Nev., school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>NORTH CAROLINA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$1.8 billion North Carolina, GOs for schools.</p>
<p>--$950 million North Carolina, GOs for highways.</p>
<p>--$98.4 million Charlotte, N.C., GOs for streets and drainage.</p>
<p>--$86.3 million Durham, N.C., GOs for streets, parks, housing and arts.</p>
<p>--$37 million Greensboro, N.C., GOs.</p>
<p>--$25 million Greensboro, N.C., GOs for public safety.</p>
<p>--$13.5 million Chapel Hill, N.C., GOs for parks, streets and sidewalks.</p>
<p>--$11.5 million Wilmington, N.C., GOs for stormwater drainage, parks and roads.</p>
<p>--$10 million Greensboro, N.C., GOs for housing.</p>
<p>--$6 million Apex, N.C., GOs.</p>
<p>--Constitutional amendment to give governor veto powers.</p>
<p>NORTH DAKOTA</p>
<p>--Measure No.2 - Would reinstate the doctrine of sovereign immunity.</p>
<p>--Measure No. 3 - Would change terms of state representatives from two to four years.</p>
<p>OHIO</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Issue 1 - Constitutional amendment allowing casino gambling to support education programs.</p>
<p>--13.5 mill property tax operating levy for Cleveland Public  Schools.</p>
<p>--$6.2 million Bluffton Ex. Vg. School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$200,000 Brady Twp., Ohio, fire truck G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$15.9 million Canfield Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$36.0 million Chardon Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$8.1 million Clearfork Valley Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$7.6 million Columbiana Ex. Vg. School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$9.4 million Crestwood Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$61.9 million Dublin City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$14.3 million Field Local Sch Dist, Ohio, school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>--$8.710 million Finneytown Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$26.1 million Forest Hills Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$26 million Gallia Cty Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$23.5 million Geneva Area School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$6.5 million Genora Area Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$2.63 million Gorham Fayette Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$7.75 million Graham Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$7.95 million Greenview Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$16.535 million Highland Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$13 million Hillsboro City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$18.6 million Independence Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$12.9 million Jackson Twp., Ohio, community center G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$8 million James A. Garfield Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$21.787 million Kent City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$18 million Lakewood Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$44 million Lebanon Cty School Dist, Ohio, school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>--$16.8 million Little Miami Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$5.95 million Madeira City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$9.5 million Madison Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$9.2 million Maple Heights City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$3.25 million McComb Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$6.537 million Miami East Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$15.425 million Miamisburg City, Ohio, construction G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$5.4 million Mt. Gilead Ex. Vg. School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.  </p>
<p>--$9 million New Bremen Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$2.65 million Newton Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$33.7 million Nordonia Hills City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$255,000 N. Baltimore Village, Ohio, fire truck G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$48.430 million Oak Hills Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$32.383 million Olentangy Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$3.1 million Pandora-Gilboa Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$410,000 Paulding Ex. Vg School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$310,000 Paulding Village, Ohio, swimming pool G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$22.450 million Pickerington Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$1.35 million Powell, Ohio, real estate bonds.</p>
<p>--$3.950 million Rocky River, Ohio, city hall equipment G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$12.7 million Shaker Heights City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$600,000 South-Western School Dist, Ohio, school g.o. bonds.</p>
<p>--$3.5 million Southwest Licking Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$17.295 million Teays Valley Schoo Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$12 million Wauseon Ex. Vg Schoo Dist., Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$16.150 million W. Holmes Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$26.95 million Westlake City School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>--$4.59 million Zane Trace Local School Dist, Ohio, school G.O. bonds.</p>
<p>OKLAHOMA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Question 675 -Constitutional amendment that would change the way property is assessed for tax purposes. The measure would limit the percentage of fair cash value at which property may be assessed. The percentage for land would be not more than 13.5 percent, nor less than 11 percent. The percentage for personal property would not be more than 15 percent nor less than 10 percent.</p>
<p>--Question 676 - Constitutional amendment that would limit the fair cash value of real property for property tax purposes. The fair cash value would not increase by more than five percent in any taxable year. The limit would apply only to real property assessed by a county assessor.</p>
<p>--Question 677 - Constitutional amendment that would limit the fair cash value on a homestead for property tax purposes. The homestead must be owned by a person age 65 or older, with a gross household income of $25,000 or less.</p>
<p>OREGON</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Measure 30 - Amend state constitution to require that the state pay local governments for costs of new unfunded mandates or increased levels of services for state-mandated programs.</p>
<p>--Measure 32 - Permits state to issue lottery revenue bonds to fund $375 million of state's share of cost to build Tri-Met Portland area South North light rail and to fund $115 million of $375 million Transportation Equity Account. Also establishes Transportation Equity Account payable to cities and counties for transportation projects outside Portland region, funded by lottery bonds, general funds and other sources.</p>
<p>--Measure 44 - Increase cigarette tax to 2.9 cents from 1.4 cents.</p>
<p>--Measure 46 - Require majority of registered voters to approve new taxes.</p>
<p>--Measure 47 - Limits 1997-98 property taxes to lesser of 1995-96 tax minus 10 percent, or 1995-95 tax. Limits future annual property tax increases to three percent, with exceptions. Limits revenue available to schools, other local services funded by property taxes. Restricts new bonds.</p>
<p>PENNSYLVANIA</p>
<p>RHODE ISLAND</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Question 1 - $80 million of general obligation bonds for transportation projects.</p>
<p>--Question 2 - $40 million of general obligation bonds for telecommujications at publci colleges.</p>
<p>--Question 3 - $33 million of general obligation bonds for higher education facilities.</p>
<p>--Question 4 - $72 million of general obligation bonds for Quonset Point/Davisville development.</p>
<p>--Question 5 - $4 million of general obligation bonds for purchase of land to protect natural resources.</p>
<p>--Question 6 - $5 million of general obligation bonds for environmental remediation revolving loans.</p>
<p>--Questions 7 - $18.5 million of general obligation bonds for the repair and renovation of state owned facilities to assure individuals with disabilities accessibility to services and employment opportunities.  </p>
<p>SOUTH CAROLINA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Constitutional amendment allowing state pension money to be invested in equities.</p>
<p>--Beaufort County, S.C., votes on one-cent sales tax hike for highway improvements.</p>
<p>--Lexington County, S.C., to decide whether county should have power to use general fund revenues and property taxes to operate water and sewer systems.</p>
<p>--Dorchester County, S.C., votes on local-option sales tax to offset property taxes.</p>
<p>--Berkeley County, S.C., votes on local-option sales tax to offset property taxes.</p>
<p>--Greenville County, S.C., votes on proposal to merge public Greenville Hospital System into new non-profit system with Spartanburg Regional Healthcare System and Anderson Area Medical Center.</p>
<p>SOUTH DAKOTA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Amendment A -- Empower state investment council to invest state educational funds.</p>
<p>--Amendment B - No new or increased taxes without voter approval or 2/3 vote of legislature.</p>
<p>TENNESSEE</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Knoxville and Knox County, Tenn., vote on proposal to consolidate government.</p>
<p>--Lenoir City, Tenn., votes on half-cent sales tax increase for schools.</p>
<p>--Loudon County, Tenn., one-cent sales tax increase for parks.</p>
<p>--$5.8 million of Morristown, Tenn., GO bonds for industrial park.</p>
<p>TEXAS</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 2</p>
<p>--$7.7 million Pilot Point Independent School District, Texas, GO school bonds.</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 9</p>
<p>--$9.1 million White Settlement Independent School District, Texas, GO school bonds.</p>
<p>NOV. 23</p>
<p>--$99.5 million Spring Independent School District, Texas, GO school bonds.</p>
<p>UTAH</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Proposition 1 - Modify qualifications for property tax exemption on property owned by veterans.</p>
<p>--Proposition 4 - Amend constitution to allow state state to guarantee general obligation debt of school districts.</p>
<p>--Proposition 5 - Amend constitution to allow state to expand the revenue sources to the state school fund to include bequests, donations and other revenues and assets provided by law.</p>
<p>--Proposition 6 - Amend constitution to specify revenues from income tax  or intangible property tax to be used for the support of the higher education system in addition to the public education system.</p>
<p>--$9.9 million Washington County, Utah, GO bonds for a jail.</p>
<p>VERMONT</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Chelsea, Vt., voters will be asked to approve a $500,000 bond issue to pay for an addition to the Orange County courthouse.</p>
<p>--Montpellier, Vt., voters will be asked to approve a $400,000 bond issue to pay for rennovations and additions to the Washington County courthouse.</p>
<p>VIRGINIA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--$29.12 million Arlington County, Va., GOs for schools</p>
<p>--$21.305 million Arlington County, Va., GOs for streets and conservation.</p>
<p>--$12.92 million Arlington County, Va, GOs for parks.</p>
<p>--$9.650 million Arlington County, Va., GOs for metrorail.</p>
<p>--$174.8 million Chesterfield County, Va., GOs for schools.</p>
<p>--$34 million Chesterfield County, Va., GOs for public safety.</p>
<p>--$10.3 million Chesterfield County, Va., GOs for libraries.</p>
<p>--$9.3 million Chesterfield County, Va., GOs for parks.</p>
<p>WASHINGTON</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Initiative No. 173 - Would require the state to provide primary and secondary students born after September 1989, with scholarship vouchers for use at any eligible public or private school of their choice.</p>
<p>--Initiative No. 671 - permi tlimited electronic gaming on Indian lands for tribal government purposes, with joint regulation and specific use revenues.</p>
<p>--Initiative Measure 51 - Allow tax payers to challenge assessments.</p>
<p>--$3.9 billion, 10-year plan to build a 25-mile &quot;starter&quot; light rail system, develop 81 miles of commuter rail lines and improve bus service and highway express lanes, in Seattle, Wash. About $1.05 billion would be raised by issuing bonds. WEST VIRGINIA</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Amednment No. 3 - Allow state to sell up to $550 million GOs for improvement and construction of state roads.</p>
<p>WISCONSIN</p>
<p>WYOMING</p>
<p>NOVEMBER 5</p>
<p>--Amendment C -- Permit state legislature to authorize the investment of state permanent funds in shares of capital stock of corporations under such conditions as the legislature prescribes.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
