<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166682" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Plains fed cattle market not well tested- feedlots.</title>
<headline>Plains fed cattle market not well tested- feedlots.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Plains feedlot cattle markets Tuesday were extremely slow, with too few slaughter steers or heifers trading to establish a market, feedlot sources said.</p>
<p>There was one load of 50 head of Holstein steers sold in Kansas, discounted to $61.00 per cwt, according to USDA.</p>
<p>Regular slaughter steers and heifers last traded Monday at $71.00, with packer bids at that level going against asking levels of $72.00 to $73.00.</p>
<p>Prices were expected to be supported by continued light supplies of finished cattle, the sources said.  </p>
<p>Feedlot cattle prices also were expected to be lifted by ongoing strength in boxed beef prices, especially in choice grade cuts, because of a shortage of high yielding cattle, the feedlot sources said.</p>
<p>Increased profitability due to lower feed costs and strong packer demand the last two weeks encouraged feedlots to sell cattle as much as 20 to 30 days ahead of schedule.</p>
<p>Beef prices at midday were quoted up $1.71 to $1.85 per cwt for choice grades and up $0.62 to $0.89 for selects, according to USDA. There were 106 fabricated loads sold.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk 312-408-8720--</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
