<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166957" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish Match sees flat coming year.</title>
<headline>Swedish Match sees flat coming year.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish Match on Tuesday said it expected flat results over the coming year.</p>
<p>&quot;Our activities are so stable that I don't believe it is likely we will see either a strong leap up or a leap down,&quot; Swedish Match managing director Goran Linden told Reuters.</p>
<p>On Monday, Swedish Match posted a 15 percent fall in profits for the first nine months of 1996 compared to a year ago to 1.04 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Sales slipped to 5.44 billion crowns from 5.54 billion and the the company said sales of smoke-free products were growing in importance.</p>
<p>Linden said the company was trying to restructure itself in 1996/97 in preparation for future geographic expansion. The new organisation will structured along the lines of the company's current sales regions.</p>
<p>Swedish Match made its debut on the Stockholm bourse and Nasdaq in New York in May this year after its former owner, Swedish vehicle group Volvo AB, paid Swedish Match shares to shareholders in the form of a dividend.</p>
<p>Swedish Match shares were 0.40 higher at 20.00 crowns at 1440 GMT Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Kristina Zetterlund, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1005</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
