<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166929" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France delays rail reform bill damned by unions.</title>
<headline>France delays rail reform bill damned by unions.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>French Transport Minister Bernard Pons, apparently set on calming trade union disquiet, said on Tuesday that he would open wider consultations on a bill to reform the SNCF state railway before it went to parliament.</p>
<p>The transport ministry said after talks at Prime Minister Alain Juppe's office on Monday that it was delaying a senate debate on the bill on the advice of a senator who said there were still &quot;misunderstandings&quot; on the rail reform plans.</p>
<p>The senate was originally supposed to kick off the bill's passage through parliament with a discussion in mid-November.</p>
<p>&quot;We will open the broadest, clearest and most detailed consultation possible with parliament and unions,&quot; Pons said.</p>
<p>The government is proposing to relieve SNCF of 175 billion francs out some 200 billion francs in debts.</p>
<p>But it has drawn union fire because the bill enshrining the debt relief plan also involves creating a separate state company which would take over the 125 billion francs of debt and become owner of the French rail infrastructure.</p>
<p>Unions have expressed fears about a fee-paying relationship which the bill envisages between the SNCF as rail operator and infrastructure manager and the new company that would become infrastructure owner.</p>
<p>There are also fears from some unions that the SNCF's public service mandate could be threatened and that the new structure could pave the way for prising the network open to competition even if the government has said this was not its intention.</p>
<p>Those worries have been fuelled by a European Commission &quot;White Paper&quot; proposing greater liberalisation of rail networks in the European Union.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
