<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="166997" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Nobel winner urges more discreet UN E.Timor talks.</title>
<headline>Nobel winner urges more discreet UN E.Timor talks.</headline>
<byline>John Acher</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jose Ramos-Horta, East Timorese activist and co-winner of the Nobel Peace Prize, said on Tuesday that U.N.-sponsored talks between Indonesia and Portugal on the troubled territory needed to be more discreet to succeed.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel there must be a new format for the talks,&quot; Ramos-Horta told reporters during a two-day visit to Finland to draw support for his proposals for a settlement for East Timor, a former Portuguese colony which Indonesia invaded in late 1975.</p>
<p>&quot;The current format... has led to nothing. Maybe...we need a parlour approach to the tripartite talks so that Indonesia does not feel pressured by the media to make concessions in a public way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta has long been critical of the largely unproductive talks between Indonesian and Portuguese foreign ministers and United Nations Secretary-General Boutros-Boutros Ghali. The next meeting is set for December 21 in New York.</p>
<p>The United Nations does not recognise Indonesian sovereignty over the territory -- the eastern half of Timor island, about 2,000 km (1,200 miles) east of Jakarta -- and considers Portugal the administering power.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta, awarded the Nobel prize jointly with East Timor Roman Catholic bishop Carlos Filipe Ximenes Belo last month for their efforts for peace, denied East Timorese guerrillas had ever targetted collaborators or Indonesian civilians in their fight for independence.</p>
<p>Indonesian military authorities said on Monday the most senior East Timorese serving in its army in the territory had been killed in the past two weeks, while four villagers had been shot dead in a separate incident.</p>
<p>&quot;Never in 21 years of our struggle has one single collaborator or Indonesian civilian been killed by guerrillas,&quot; Ramos-Horta said, blaming the army for all past deaths.</p>
<p>&quot;If it were to happen...I would denounce it most strongly because we have a code of conduct,&quot; he said. &quot;The collaborators (with Indonesia) are poor people who are forced to collaborate and who have no choice,&quot; said Ramos-Horta.</p>
<p>No one has claimed responsibility for the killings, which follow a number of other unconfirmed reports of disappearances and deaths in recent months.</p>
<p>Ramos-Horta outlined a three-point proposal for resolving the conflict, &quot;a set of ideas that we have put on the table and which we are willing to negotiate with Indonesia&quot;.</p>
<p>Although the activists would never accept that East Timor is a part of Indonesia, Ramos-Horta said his plan called for an end to human rights abuses, leading to a referendum on independence for East Timor.</p>
<p>&quot;If Indonesia were to accept this challenge and we were to ask the people in five or six years, they might choose to be in some kind of association with Indonesia,&quot; he said. &quot;That is the challenge of the...plan.&quot;</p>
<p>He said an independent East Timor could be a viable entity: &quot;We have lots and lots of oil and other natural resources... It would be like Brunei or Kuwait.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
