<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167050" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India's Chidambaram gives upbeat economic outlook.</title>
<headline>India's Chidambaram gives upbeat economic outlook.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram delivered an upbeat outlook for the economy on Tuesday, projecting a solid expansion in gross domestic product (GDP) and dismissing fears of a growth slowdown.</p>
<p>He forecast GDP growth of around 6.5 percent in 1996/97 (April-March), virtually unchanged from 6.6 percent in 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;By and large, there is an agreement among the Reserve Bank of India (the central bank), the Planning Commission and my chief economic adviser that the (GDP) growth will be in the region of 6.5 percent or so,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>The government had revised down 1995/96 growth from an earlier GDP estimate of 7.0 percent and some economic analysts have warned of a possible slowdown in the economy this year.</p>
<p>But Chidambaram, addressing an economic editors conference, predicted the economy would do well in the current year.</p>
<p>Chidambaram, a free-market advocate in Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's centre-left coalition, said the government would fulfil economic promises announced in June.</p>
<p>The finance minister said despite slowing industrial production, which he hoped would improve in the second half of the current year, the economy would perform well mainly due to strength in the agriculture and service industries.</p>
<p>&quot;Agriculture this year is expected to touch a new peak after last year's decline,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>A rise in foodgrain output to 197 million tonnes in 1996/97, against 185 million tonnes last year, is expected to help bolster agricultural production, the finance ministry said.</p>
<p>&quot;The services sector last year did very well and there is no reason to believe that it will not do just as well as last year,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>He said the manufacturing sector was doing extremely well.</p>
<p>In April-July 1996, the manufacturing sector grew by 11.7 percent compared to 11.9 percent growth in the previous corresponding period.</p>
<p>A slowdown in overall industrial production partly reflected a drop in petroleum production, Chidambaram said, adding the industrial performance would improve in coming months.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said inflation, as measured by the wholesale price index, would come down as the government was keen to hold the annual growth in money supply to a shade below 16 percent.</p>
<p>He reaffirmed the government's commitment to a strict fiscal regime by keeping a tight lid on expenditure, and expected revenue collections to improve.</p>
<p>Chidambaram also said the government had carried forward its economic reforms and taken measures to boost the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;But I have to submit, collectively, these decisions speak of a government, which has not been idle, which has been active, in fact, which has been proactive and which has been decisive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--New Delhi Newsroom +91-11-301-2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
