<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16703" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hopes high but reviews mixed for Dole's tax plan.</title>
<headline>Hopes high but reviews mixed for Dole's tax plan.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>SANTA BARBARA, Calif. 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>To voters who turn out to cheer Bob Dole on the campaign trail, the Republican presidential candidate's pledge to hand out billions of dollars in tax cuts while balancing the budget is a simple matter of common sense and discipline.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure he can do it, absolutely,&quot; said Annette, a mother of three college-age children in Tampa, Florida. &quot;All he has to do it get rid of that waste in Washington.&quot;</p>
<p>But hard-core loyalists who brave the summer sun at Dole rallies or squeal when they spot him on the streets as he vacations this week in Santa Barbara are not the ones who will ultimately decide who occupies the White House come January.</p>
<p>That decision will rest with swing voters, the undecideds like Phyllis Kindsvogel, an elderly woman from North Dakota, who fretted after Dole spoke to the Ladies Auxiliary of the Veterans of Foreign Wars in Kentucky last week. &quot;I don't know if he can follow through. They've been working on that for years now. It's awfully tough,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Dole's campaign promise, which contradicts much of what he argued as a deficit hawk during 35 years in Washington, is to slash personal income taxes by 15 percent, cut capital gains taxes in half, grant child tax credits and expand long-term savings incentives. That adds up to $548 billion in tax cuts by 2002 but Dole says cutting taxes will not prevent him from wiping out the budget deficit.</p>
<p>In a conversion to the supply-side economics embraced by his running mate Jack Kemp and tested by President Ronald Reagan with mixed results, Dole says tax cuts will stimulate faster growth that will help offset revenue losses. He says he can balance the budget while &quot;restraining the rate of growth&quot; but not cutting Medicare, defence, or Social Security.</p>
<p>Defending the soundness of his plan after a Tuesday morning session with top economic advisers, Dole said, &quot;There isn't an economist at this table who will stick their neck out for political reasons.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he &quot;obviously&quot; will release more details of his proposed spending cuts but he did not say when.</p>
<p>Tom Carsen, an engineer from an affluent Chicago suburb, likes what he heard at a recent Dole rally. &quot;Reagan cut taxes -- but the Democrats in Congress wouldn't let him cut spending. Dole will have a Republican Congress, he'll have the line item veto, he can do it all.&quot;</p>
<p>Liberal Democrats naturally scoff at the Dole plan, but even some conservative economists -- academics or Wall Streeters who may support Dole but are not in his inner circle -- have reservations.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a conditional supporter of the Dole plan. The condition is that he balances the budget,&quot; said Bill Niskanen of the libertarion Cato Institute in Washington &quot;If he cuts taxes and he balances the budget we're all better off.&quot;</p>
<p>But Niskanen doubts that Dole can meet those dual pledges without cutting defence, veterans' benefits and entitlement programme like Medicare , Social Security or other areas Dole's campaign says are &quot;off the table.&quot;</p>
<p>Ben Bernanke, chairman of Princeton's economics department, says there are good reasons for both tax and spending cuts, but he predicts Dole will face pressure to downsize military spending and entitlement programmes.</p>
<p>Dole's advisers include prominent and respected economists such as Nobel prize winner Gary Becker of the University of Chicago and John Taylor of Stanford.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the kind of tax reduction we should have, and the growth effect is very modest,&quot; Taylor told Reuters. Unlike the most ardent supply-siders, he said, the Dole team is adding spending cuts to the mix and not relying solely on growth.</p>
<p>But Alan Blinder, a Princeton economist who was vice chairman of the Federal Reserve for a time under Clinton, says the Dole plan &quot;has two distinct credibility problems.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see anything in this plan that could raise the long-term growth rate to 3.5 percent a year. And on the budget numbers, we've heard this before,&quot; Blinder said, recalling the &quot;record deficits&quot; of the Reagan years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA BARBARA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
