<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167388" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - UK manufacturing picks up, but sluggishly.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - UK manufacturing picks up, but sluggishly.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>British manufacturing output grew modestly in September, according to official figures published on Tuesday, but economists said the recovery was fragile and could yet be threatened by the strength of sterling.</p>
<p>Output rose 0.3 percent in September, reversing a decline in August, but the pick-up was slow enough to raise questions over the need for further interest rate rises in the near future.</p>
<p>The Office for National Statistics said its preferred measure of manufacturing output rose 0.7 percent over the three months to September, compared with the previous three.</p>
<p>That was the largest rise in more than a year.</p>
<p>Industrial production, which measures manufacturing and energy industry output, rose 0.5 percent in September as oil and gas output bounced.</p>
<p>The Conservative government, anxious to make its management of the economy a key issue in the coming general election campaign, hailed the figures as further evidence of economic recovery. &quot;The improvement in the economy has now spread to manufacturing as well,&quot; a Treasury official said.</p>
<p>But economists said the modest manufacturing pick-up in September, which only matched a 0.3 percent fall in August, was less than inspiring and manufacturing could face tougher times following last week's shock quarter-point rise in rates.</p>
<p>&quot;The data show tentative signs of recovery in manufacturing but the improvement is still fragile,&quot; said Jonathan Loynes, UK economist at HSBC Markets. &quot;A further rise in base rates, pushing the pound even higher, could threaten to derail the recovery before it really gets going.&quot;</p>
<p>The strength of the pound -- it has now gained about nine percent on a trade-weighted basis in the last three months -- is rapidly becoming a millstone for manufacturing exporters as it pushes up export prices and makes imports cheaper.</p>
<p>To make matters worse, economists expect last week's rise in base rates to six percent will give sterling another leg up.</p>
<p>That, coupled with possible tax cuts, is the wrong policy mix, they said. The result is that Britain's economic recovery is being driven by the free-spending British consumer.</p>
<p>Given that last week's rate rise was not matched by major mortgage lenders, the impact on high street spending could be minimal. But for manufacturers, the harm could be much greater.</p>
<p>But healthy high street demand for consumer goods is only now starting to trickle down to British manufacturers who are still burdened with weak export demand.</p>
<p>&quot;The classic policy prescription for this demand imbalance is a tightening of the fiscal belt and a cautious approach to monetary tightening,&quot; said Alex Garrard, UK economist at UBS.</p>
<p>But tax rises from Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke's November 26 budget are out of the question with elections due by May 1997. Most analysts expect modest tax cuts.</p>
<p>Michael Dicks, UK economist at Lehman Brothers, said British manufacturers should enjoy a stronger fourth quarter. &quot;But in Q4 we're going to see the impact of the recent currency strength, so just as you're beginning to get manufacturing joining in the recovery, it could be strangled at birth.&quot;</p>
<p>Looking at the detail in the ONS figures, Loynes said most of September's rise in output was due to a 1.3 percent jump in durable goods over the three months to September. Within that car output rose by 2.3 percent.</p>
<p>He said a broader recovery than that was needed before the manufacturing sector's worries can be consigned to history.</p>
<p>&quot;With consumer durables accounting for only about five percent of total industrial production goods, there is no guarantee that the strength of consumer spending at home will be enough to ensure a recovery in industry.&quot;</p>
<p>He said exports remained key and the pound was a problem.</p>
<p>Jeremy Hawkins, economist at BankAmerica, agreed. &quot;The trend in output is accelerating but not at a fast enough pace to warrant any additional near-term rate hikes. Indeed, some still probably question the wisdom of last week's move.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
