<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167357" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Speculation, not facts, drive emerging mkts - survey.</title>
<headline>Speculation, not facts, drive emerging mkts - survey.</headline>
<byline>Caroline Allen</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emerging market investments are driven by &quot;speculation&quot; instead of fundamentals because fund managers are not getting the quality company research they need from stock brokers, said a report released on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The emerging markets report, sponsored by Reuters and done over three months by Tempest Consultants, polled over 840 fund managers and 230 brokers and about 1,700 brokers' analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of reliable and meaningful information for financial audiences&quot; was most striking, the report said. &quot;There is a knowledge problem which causes many share prices to be driven by stories and speculation as opposed to fundamentals.&quot;</p>
<p>While established markets produce regular information for investors about companies, it is notoriously difficult and expensive to obtain accurate and timely information from new markets with fledgling stock exchanges and companies.</p>
<p>The survey polled companies based in emerging markets, fund groups likely to invest in emerging markets and brokers offering advice and research to both investors and companies, and then gave rankings of each group by the others.</p>
<p>Investment firms without research groups often depend on brokers to supply material, but the report said they were now developing direct contact with companies in emerging markets due to the &quot;perceived low quality of broker product and service.&quot;</p>
<p>The report said &quot;quality company contact is critical. Against a noisy background and massive choice, it is the only way to overcome the knowledge problem.&quot;</p>
<p>Some 44 percent of fund managers said they were now spending less time reading and listening to securities houses' research.</p>
<p>The survey also showed stock picking, where fund managers emphasise the individual value of companies instead of the overall view of the country, was the favoured investment method.</p>
<p>The gap between the information funds want and what they are receiving has created &quot;big commercial opportunities for the most client-focused brokers,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>But it said brokers need to seize the chance quickly as fund mangement groups were expanding into research to fill the gap.</p>
<p>When choosing a broker, fund groups said they attached most importance to ideas and research, trading capability and counter-party risk, in that order. For local brokers, the demand was for local contacts, trading ability and &quot;market feel.&quot;</p>
<p>Fund groups equally wanted immediate electronic on-line research via exisiting suppliers and the Internet, but 87.9 percent said they would not pay cash for such a service.</p>
<p>Though the survey said companies in emerging markets could easily identify fund managers and brokers who best understood them and the industries, fund managers could not do the same.</p>
<p>These companies are &quot;avid readers&quot; of broker research but believe it often does not adequately reflect their company strategy and prospects, the survey found.</p>
<p>According to the report, ING Barings provided the best broker product and service for global emerging market equities.</p>
<p>Merril Lynch was best overall broker and Fidelity Investments was the best fund management group for global emerging markets equities, finance directors said in the survey.</p>
<p>The breakdown by regions was as follows: Banco Santander was best equity broker product and service for Latin America and ING Barings was best for Asia, Europe, the Middle East and Africa.</p>
<p>Finance directors said best regional broker in Latin America was J.P. Morgan in Latin America, Ivor Jones Roy in Europe, Middle East and Africa and Jardine Fleming Securities in Asia.</p>
<p>Fidelity Investments was rated the best overall fund management group in Latin America and Asia, while Liberty Asset Management was rated best for Europe, Middle East and Africa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
