<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167380" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: West sees troubled Russia, even with Yeltsin back.</title>
<headline>West sees troubled Russia, even with Yeltsin back.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Nicholas Doughty, Diplomatic Correspondent</p>
<p>Even if Russian President Boris Yeltsin makes a full recovery from heart surgery, Western governments face tough times ahead with Moscow and seem far less confident now about the future of the world's biggest country.</p>
<p>Diplomats and analysts say critical decisions about NATO expansion and relations with Russia in the next few months are just part of the problem.</p>
<p>Beyond that are deeper uncertainties about Russia's view of its own place on the world stage, problems with economic reform, leadership and the balance of power in the federation.</p>
<p>Western governments still see Yeltsin, who underwent apparently successful heart bypass surgery on Tuesday, as the best hope for safeguarding Russian reforms and for pushing the country towards stable democracy.</p>
<p>But they are worried by the power struggles among those close to Yeltsin, which may continue in the months it could take him to recover, and by problems in foreign policy.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a sense of stagnation in things with Russia, which is risky,&quot; said one Western diplomat, who asked not to be identified. &quot;We still want to anchor Russia in stability, within Europe, but it is proving a tough nut to crack.&quot;</p>
<p>The West hailed Yeltsin's stunning comeback victory over the resurgent Communist Party in July's presidential elections, but has since realised it is dealing with a sick man whose time may be limited and whose influence may be on the wane.</p>
<p>&quot;We underestimated the problems and the time it will take to solve them. Western governments are more cautious now,&quot; said Alexander Rahr of the German Foreign Policy Association in Bonn.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a great deal of uncertainty about where Russia wants to see itself,&quot; said Rose Gottemoeller of the International Institute for Strategic Studies (IISS) in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Is it going to be a major player or turn in on itself and be a self-pitying power?&quot;</p>
<p>One of the problems, diplomats say, is that Russia's political system now depends almost exclusively on the president's health since the constitution gives him such power.</p>
<p>If that is lacking, as recent weeks have shown, internal squabbling within the Kremlin and among various ministries can all too easily cripple the government.</p>
<p>Such problems could prove critical for the West in the next few months, even if Yeltsin is on the road to full recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;People around him will still be jostling for position, even though they will know their time is limited if Yeltsin is coming back,&quot; said another Western diplomat.</p>
<p>A NATO summit, expected in May or June of next year, will name the first candidates from Central and Eastern Europe to join the Western alliance since the end of the Cold War.</p>
<p>Despite some hints of a possible compromise, Moscow still opposes the idea of its former satellites joining NATO and is expected to push that line at a European security summit in Lisbon next month.</p>
<p>To calm Russian fears, the alliance has been trying to put together an agreement that would effectively build a special NATO-Russian relationship. Progress so far has been slow.</p>
<p>There are other Western concerns over signs of unrest in the armed forces and economic troubles, including an increasingly fraught relationship between Moscow and some regions of the Russian Federation.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has not yet agreed to release the latest instalment of a $10-billion loan because of problems over low tax revenues. Trade unions have launched protests because millions of workers have not been paid.</p>
<p>Even the United States, which has remained resolutely upbeat over Russia's prospects, is starting to lose patience with anti-Western rhetoric from some in Moscow and is troubled by problems over key arms control issues.</p>
<p>Last week, the top U.S. policymaker on Russia openly voiced those concerns in a speech. &quot;If Russians overindulge their misplaced suspicions that we want to keep them down...the result could be that we will indeed cooperate less and compete more,&quot; said Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
