<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167488" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pop star Jackson - expected child is &quot;my dream&quot;.</title>
<headline>Pop star Jackson - expected child is &quot;my dream&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Mark Egan</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pop superstar Michael Jackson said on Monday that a longtime friend is pregnant with his child, declaring &quot;this is my dream come true.&quot;</p>
<p>The woman, identified as Debbie Rowe, has been a close friend of the singer for 15 years and will have the baby in early 1997, according to a statement from Jackson's publicists.</p>
<p>Publicists denied reports he had paid Rowe to carry his child and said rumours in a British tabloid that she was artificially inseminated were &quot;completely false and irresponsible.&quot; But they declined to comment when asked about the couple's sexual relationship.</p>
<p>&quot;I am thrilled that I will soon be a father and am looking forward with great anticipation to having this child,&quot; Jackson said in a written statement.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman said that Jackson was not ready to talk about how the child would be raised but added, &quot;I'm sure that Michael is going to be giving this child 100 percent support.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier news reports identified Rowe as a 37-year-old nurse who had been paid $500,000 to have Jackson's child by artificial insemination.</p>
<p>Lisa Marie Presley, daughter of the late rock 'n roll legend Elvis Presley, filed for divorce from Jackson in January, citing irreconcilable differences, about 20 months after they were married in a secret ceremony in the Dominican Republic.</p>
<p>Some Hollywood insiders had speculated that the marriage was little more that a publicity stunt to deflect media attention that had mushroomed around allegations that Jackson sexually molested a young boy.</p>
<p>Only months before the divorce filing, the couple, in a national television interview, said they married for love, and Presley said she and Jackson shared the same bed and had an active sex life.</p>
<p>Jackson vehemently denied the boy's claims of sexual molestation, and prosecutors announced in late 1994 that they had decided not to file criminal charges after the boy refused to cooperate in the investigation.</p>
<p>That came after Jackson agreed in January 1994 to pay the boy a multimillion-dollar settlement in return for dropping a civil lawsuit against the singer.</p>
<p>In Monday's announcement Jackson pleaded with the media: &quot;Please respect my privacy and that of Debbie and the child ... this is my dream come true.&quot;</p>
<p>Jackson has long been a favourite of the tabloid press and rumours of the pregnancy had already made front-page headlines.</p>
<p>&quot;Michael regrets that the news of Debbie's pregnancy was accompanied by several false and distorted reports and speculations and urges the media to respect his and Debbie's privacy. This is a very exciting time for both Michael and Debbie,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Jackson, one of the top-selling recording artists of all time, is viewed as an oddity for his penchant for plastic surgery, and other eccentricities.</p>
<p>Something of a Peter Pan figure in the music world, he was sheltered from the real world and denied a normal boyhood as he repeatedly topped the charts with his brothers in &quot;The Jackson 5.&quot;</p>
<p>The five older Jackson boys first performed together at a talent show in Gary, Indiana, in 1964, when Michael was just 6 years old. He has remained in the spotlight ever since.</p>
<p>Jackson regularly entertained children at his Neverland estate near Santa Barbara, California, where he assembled a small zoo of exotic animals and had a children's fantasy land built.</p>
<p>Jackson told talk show host Oprah Winfrey in a 1993 interview that as a boy he missed &quot;slumber parties.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
