<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167435" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Shell wins Egypt oil block.</title>
<headline>Shell wins Egypt oil block.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt has awarded Royal Dutch/Shell Group the Matruh oil concession block and has asked eight companies to resubmit offers for two other blocks, an Egyptian General Petroleum Corp official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Royal Dutch/Shell was the only bidder for the offshore block, which covers 13,622 square km (5,260 square miles) off the northwest coast. Wafik Meshref, EGPC vice president for agreements, declined to give details of the terms.</p>
<p>EGPC received eight offers for the onshore block of South Dabaa and five offers for the Northeastern Block, Meshref said.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision was that they (EGPC bid committee) considered this to be the first round of negotiations, and recommended we renegotiate five out of the eight and three out of the five,&quot; he told Reuters. He declined to give company names or details.</p>
<p>He said the offers were to be resubmitted by November 20 and the concessions committee would meet about a week later.</p>
<p>The blocks are among the 11 oil concessions Egypt offered oil exploration companies in its 1996 bidding. Meshref said EGPC received 23 bids for seven of them.</p>
<p>In October EGPC said it awarded the North July block in the Gulf of Suez to Pennzoil of the United States and the West Bahariya block in the Western desert to an Egyptian private company led by Egyptian businessman Hossam Abu El-Fouttouh.</p>
<p>-- Christine Hauser +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
