<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167548" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: Reuter EC Report Long-Term Diary for Nov 11 - Dec 31, 1997.</title>
<headline>Reuter EC Report Long-Term Diary for Nov 11 - Dec 31, 1997.</headline>
<text>
<p>(page 1/9 - Nov 11-Nov 14)</p>
<p>			     ****</p>
<p>			   HIGHLIGHTS</p>
<p>				****</p>
<p>LISBON - Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) holds annual summit (To December 3).</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Inaugural World Trade Organisation (WTO) ministerial conference (December 9-13).</p>
<p>DUBLIN - Irish Presidency European Council of heads of state and government (December 13-14).</p>
<p>December 31, 1996 - Irish EU presidency ends. The Netherlands takes over to June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>EARLY 1997 - NATO holds summit to formally decide new members and approve a charter defining the alliance relationship with Russia - date to be set later.</p>
<p>AMSTERDAM - Dutch presidency hosts European Council of heads of state and government (June 16-17).</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>NOVEMBER</p>
<p>- Irish presidency hosts conference on &quot;Local employment initiatives&quot;. Date and venue to be announced.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>MONDAY, NOVEMBER 11</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - ECOFIN Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>-- Preparation for December 13-14 Dublin European Council:</p>
<p>	 - EMU;</p>
<p>	 - Employment;</p>
<p>	 - Report on taxation;</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Banking and financial directives;</p>
<p>-- Taxation issues.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Parliament plenary session (To November 15).</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>TUESDAY, NOVEMBER 12</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Health Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes:</p>
<p>-- Proposal for an EP and Council decision adopting a programme of Community action on the prevention of drug dependence within the framework for action in the field of public health.</p>
<p>-- Proposal for a decision adopting a programme of Community action on health monitoring in the context of the action in the field of public health.</p>
<p>-- Proposal for a Council directive on the approximation of the laws, regulations and administrative provisions of the member states relating to the advertising of tobacco products.</p>
<p>-- Proposal for a decision of the European Parliament and of the Council creating a network for the epidemiological surveillance and control of communicable diseases in the European Community.</p>
<p>-- Setting-up of an EU-U.S. task force to develop and implement a global early warning system and response network for communicable diseases.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Transmissible Spongiform Encephalopathies (TSE).</p>
<p>-- Blood safety/self sufficiency.</p>
<p>-- State of health in the EU.</p>
<p>-- Health protection requirements in Community policies.</p>
<p>-- European health card.</p>
<p>-- Pollution-related diseases:</p>
<p>	 - Rare diseases;</p>
<p>	 - Accidents/injuries.</p>
<p>-- Statement by presidency on Alzheimers Disease conference (November 21-22, 1996).</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>WEDNESDAY, NOVEMBER 13</p>
<p>BRUSSELS (NEW ITEM) - ACP ministers hold council (To November 15). Venue: ACP house 451 avenue Georges Henri. Contact: ACP House (322) 743 0600.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Committee of the Regions holds plenary session (To November 14).</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EuroCommerce launches the business of adding value, an analysis of European retail and distribution based on a study by London economics, and the EuroCommerce recommendations for future policy in recognition of the vital importance of this sector to the European economy (1030/0930 GMT) (To November 14). Venue: International Press Centre (IPC). Contact: Catherine Piana (322) 230 5 874.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Agra Europe holds third annual European grain conference (To November 14). Contact: Agra Europe (44) 1892 511 807.</p>
<p>TILBURG, Netherlands - Former German President Richard von Weizsaecker gives address on Culture of European Union (2000/1900 GMT). Venue: Brabant Catholic University.</p>
<p>ROME - U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation holds world food summit (To November 17). European Commissioner Fischler meets U.S. Department of Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman.</p>
<p>GENEVA - WTO holds conference with 48 poorest countries (To November 15).</p>
<p>PARIS - European Radiocommunications Office holds conference on &quot;Regulation and legislation in a liberalised market&quot; (1000/0900 GMT) (To November 15). Venue: Hilton Hotel. Contact: European Radiocommunications Office (45) 35 25 0300.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>THURSDAY, NOVEMBER 14</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Industry Council.</p>
<p>Provisional agenda includes</p>
<p>-- Steel:</p>
<p>	 a) State aids code;</p>
<p>	 b) Sixth monitoring report on state aids in steel sector;</p>
<p>	 c) (possibly) Future of ECSC Treaty.</p>
<p>-- Competition:</p>
<p>	 a) State aids;</p>
<p>	 b) Merger regulation;</p>
<p>	 c) Agreement with Canada.</p>
<p>-- Shipbuilding:</p>
<p>	 - (possibly) State of ratification procedure - OECD</p>
<p>agreement.</p>
<p>-- SMEs:</p>
<p>	 a) Proposal for a Council decision on a third multiannual</p>
<p>programme for small and medium sized enterprises (SMEs) in the European Union (1997-2000);</p>
<p>	 b) Report on integrated programme.</p>
<p>-- Competitiveness policy:</p>
<p>	 a) Commission's first report on the competitiveness of</p>
<p>European industry;</p>
<p>	 b) A European policy for quality promotion;</p>
<p>	 c) Benchmarking;</p>
<p>	 d) Standards.</p>
<p>-- Merger regulation:</p>
<p>	 -  Review of regulation 4064/89 on the control of</p>
<p>concentrations between undertakings.</p>
<p>-- Automobile industry.</p>
<p>-- Chemicals industry.</p>
<p>-- Textiles:</p>
<p>	 - Communication from the Commission on the</p>
<p>competitiveness of subcontracting in the textile and clothing industry in the European Union.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Recycling industry and environmental technology.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Space industry.</p>
<p>-- (possibly) Cooperation with third countries.</p>
<p>STRASBOURG - European Commision and EP host &quot;European film forum&quot; (To November 20). Venue: EP. Contact: Daniele Blin, DCB Productions (33) 1 42 768 82 14.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - Europe's 500 - the association for dynamic entrepreneurs hold international think-tank (To November 16). Venue: Conrad Hotel. Contact: Europe's 500 (322) 716 4838.</p>
<p>BRUSSELS - EuroCommerce holds conference on &quot;The business of adding value - European retailing and distribution&quot;. Main discussions focus on commerce in the cashless society and the challenges of multimedia (second of two days). European Commission President Jacques Santer attends. Contact: Catherine Piana (322) 230 5874.</p>
<p>PARIS - Foreign ministers of countries involved in Bosnia discuss plans for two-year civilian peace consolidation programme in Bosnia; countries meeting include members of the contact group on former Yugoslavia of Western allies and Russia, and the Arab contact group.</p>
<p>LUXEMBOURG - The Edmond Israel Foundation and the Cedel Group hold &quot;Vision for Europe&quot; award ceremony (1800/1700 GMT). Participants include: Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene and European Commission President Santer. Venue: European Centre, rue du Fort Thungen.</p>
<p>NEHGELO, The Netherlands - European Ostrich Association (EOA) holds world congress (To November 15). Venue: Expo Centre. Contact: EOA (31) 546 81 3677.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
