<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16755" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. says still wants fugitive Vesco returned.</title>
<headline>U.S. says still wants fugitive Vesco returned.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States said on Tuesday that it would still like Cuba to return Robert Vesco, the fugitive financier sentenced to 13 years in jail for economic crimes against the government of Fidel Castro.</p>
<p>&quot;We remain interested in Vesco, in his return to face prosecution here. He is a fugitive from justice in the United States,&quot; State Department spokesman Glyn Davies said.</p>
<p>Vesco, 60, has been wanted by U.S. authorities for nearly 25 years on charges he allegedly stole $224 million from a mutual fund. He has also been indicted on cocaine trafficking and other charges.</p>
<p>On Monday, a Cuban court sentenced Vesco to 13 years in a Cuban prison for crimes against economic plans and labour regulations, fraud and illegal economic activity in the communist-ruled country.</p>
<p>The United States has requested Vesco's return in the past, but has no plans at this time to press the request with Havana on the assumption it would be rebuffed, Davies said.</p>
<p>He declined comment on Vesco's conviction in Cuba but said that as a general matter &quot;Cuban law and trial practices do not, by our lights, meet international standards for fair public trials.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
