<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167594" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Zaire Church leader urges world to act.</title>
<headline>Zaire Church leader urges world to act.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The leader of the Roman Catholic Church in Zaire called on Tuesday for urgent international humanitarian and political action in eastern Zaire where more than a million Hutu refugees are at risk from war.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem of Rwandan refugees in the Great Lakes region of Zaire has been known for years but the international community has remained indifferent, despite all the appeals made to it,&quot; Cardinal Frederic Etsou-Nzabi-Bamungwabi said.</p>
<p>&quot;For that reason, I am absolutely in favour of any attempt to open a humanitarian corridor and to bring back peace in the region. The more this intervention is delayed, the more inhuman will be the damage,&quot; he told reporters in Rome.</p>
<p>African leaders opened talks in the Kenyan capital Nairobi on Tuesday on the war in eastern Zaire where more than a million Hutu refugees from Rwanda and Burundi are at risk in the wake of a two-week-old Tutsi rebel offensive.</p>
<p>A lobby group for Rwandan Hutus in Nairobi said 500,000 refugees in the South Kivu region had received no food, water or medicine for 15 days and 700,000 in Goma faced the same plight.</p>
<p>Etsou-Nzabi-Bamungwabi, who is archbishop of Kinshasa, arrived in Rome from Brussels to attend a celebration of the 50th anniversary of Pope John Paul's ordination as a priest.</p>
<p>His colleague Christophe Munzihirwa Mwene Ngabo, the Roman Catholic archbishop of the eastern Zairean city of Bukavu, was killed in a military attack last week. The Pope has appealed for urgent action to help refugees and stop violence in the region.</p>
<p>Etsou-Nzabi-Bamungwabi said the absence of Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko had &quot;worsened the situation because it has not enabled mediation with the presidents of Rwanda and Burundi&quot;.</p>
<p>Mobutu flew to the French Riviera on Monday from Switzerland where he was operated on for cancer.</p>
<p>But Etsou-Nzabi-Bamungwabi added: &quot;The problem has been on the table for years. Now we need the international community to move urgently because humanitarian aid, important though it is, is not enough.&quot;</p>
<p>France and Spain on Monday called for a U.N.-sanctioned military force to go to Zaire to ensure refugees can get food.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
