<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167506" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton awaits election results in Arkansas.</title>
<headline>Clinton awaits election results in Arkansas.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>LITTLE ROCK, Ark. 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton completed his final election campaign early on Tuesday, returning to Arkansas to await his expected victory surrounded by family and friends.</p>
<p>Closing out a grueling campaign season that unofficially began more than a year ago, Clinton, his wife Hillary and 16-year-old daughter Chelsea flew into Little Rock aboard Air Force One for an emotional return to a state where for 12 years they had been its first family.</p>
<p>&quot;I am now speaking at the last rally of the last campaign I will ever run,&quot; Clinton told a raucus late-night rally in Souix City, South Dakota, his final stop before Election Day.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the greatest country in human history because we have created a system in which you are the boss,&quot; Clinton said in asking voters renew his contract for four more years.</p>
<p>Unlike the sense of grim determination that characterised the mood of the presidential party that accompanied George Bush into Houston four years ago to await the election results, Clinton and his clan reflected joyful anticipation.</p>
<p>Enroute to Little Rock from South Dakota, the president and first lady toasted their staff and the Secret Service agents who have been away from home so often because of the campaign.</p>
<p>Although public opinion polls reflected a narrowing in the race with Republican challenger Bob Dole and Reform Party candidate Ross Perot, there was no indication the last minute shift would deny the incumbent a second four year term in the White House.</p>
<p>&quot;This election is about more than personalities and more than parties,&quot; Clinton said during his final day of campaigning, &quot;it is about the future of America.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The responsibility now shifts to you, my fellow Americans,&quot; he said in appealing to voters. &quot;It is your country, your children, your future ... seize the day to keep your country moving in the right direction.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton closed out his final trek on the campaign trail with speeches before enthusiastic crowds in New Hampshire, Ohio, Kentucky, Iowa and South Dakota before arriving in Arkansas. The Iowa and New Hampshire stops were particularly sentimental for him because voters in those two states helped launch his successful bid for the White House in 1992.</p>
<p>Vice President Al Gore, his wife Tipper planned to vote in Tennessee and then fly with their children to Little Rock to join the Clintons in awaiting election results. The Democratic ticket has a substantial lead in enough states that Clinton and Gore are likely to be projected as winners by early evening.</p>
<p>The fate of the Republican-controlled Congress, however, was far from clear. Although much of Clinton's popularity can be traced to his opposition to the Republican agenda the past two years, it was unclear his coattails would benefit fellow Democrats.</p>
<p>City officials in Little Rock were busy preparing a huge election-night street party, closing off downtown streets around the Old State House -- a large white Greek Revival structure where as many as 80,000 people are expected to gather.</p>
<p>When Clinton was elected president in 1992, it was on the front steps of the historic building, which once served as the state capitol, where he claimed victory before 50,000 people. He plans to do the same again this year.</p>
<p>Virtually all 6,000 hotel rooms in metropolitan Little Rock have been reserved and utility workers have added electrical circuits and telephone lines to handle the expected surge in demand.</p>
<p>Rock stars Stephen Stills and Nicolette Larson and country singer Kathy Mattea are to play at the Riverfront Ampitheatre and TV images of the events and network election returns will be projected on huge screens throughout the downtown area.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LITTLE ROCK, Ark."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
