<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167637" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS - Airbus orders to triple in 96 - DASA chairman.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Airbus orders to triple in 96 - DASA chairman.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European consortium Airbus Industrie will win almost three times as many orders in 1996 than in the previous year, Daimler-Benz Aerospace (DASA) chairman Manfred Bischoff predicted on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Market growth is already under way and can now clearly be seen by the rate of rapidly growing Airbus orders,&quot; Bischoff told a conference on the future of Europe's aerospace industry, which faces stiff U.S. competition.</p>
<p>&quot;Whilst only 106 new orders were placed with Airbus in 1995, I expect more than 300 new Airbus orders by the end of 1996,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The civil aircraft market for the next 20 years was generally assessed to be in the order of one trillion U.S. dollars, Bischoff told the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;We can therefore expect a demand of 12,000 new jets within the next 20 years,&quot; he said, referring to planes with more than 70 seats.</p>
<p>Airbus is a consortium made up of French state-owned Ste Nationale Industrielle Aerospatiale, British Aerospace Plc, Germany's DASA -- part of Daimler Benz AG -- and Construcciones Aeronauticas SA (CASA) of Spain.</p>
<p>Bischoff spoke the day after state-owned airline Emirates and Airbus signed a $2 billion deal for 16 new A330-200 aircraft, making the airline Airbus's biggest customer for the widebody jet.</p>
<p>Emirates has an option for a further seven aircraft.</p>
<p>Eleven-year-old Emirates is the first airline in the Middle East to order the A330-200 and it is the largest airline customer for the new twin jet, Airbus said.</p>
<p>Airbus won the deal against competition from U.S. rival Boeing Co's 767.</p>
<p>Also at Tuesday's conference, CASA President Raul Herrzanz de Miguel painted a positive picture concerning Airbus.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering that the effort made by the European aerospace industry it is not by chance that we are leaders in the regional aircraft market and that Airbus has captured 30 percent of the world market and its outlook is seen by most specialised analysts as being extremely positive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>British Aerospace President Sir Richard Evans said Airbus was at a crossroads.</p>
<p>&quot;The choice is simple: to remain as we are which means stagnation; or to move forward and displace Boeing from the top slot,&quot; Evans said, according to a copy of his speech.</p>
<p>Airbus is in the midst of changing to a joint stock company from the four-strong partnership, the first multilateral European aerospace company.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the path we have to follow. leading to real company mergers on the European level,&quot; DASA's Bischoff said.</p>
<p>Airbus does not publish profit figures, but its sales in 1995 reached $9.6 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
