<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167655" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France, Britain to step up defence cooperation.</title>
<headline>France, Britain to step up defence cooperation.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>France and Britain will step up defence cooperation at a summit in France beginning on Thursday that may highlight British wariness of France's push for an international force to end a refugee crisis in Zaire.</p>
<p>French President Jacques Chirac and British Prime Minister John Major, meeting for two days in tight security in Bordeaux, will also seek to iron out differences over European integration and review likely U.S. policies after the presidential election.</p>
<p>The only concrete deal expected from the talks, in Bordeaux city hall which has been repaired after a bomb attack by Corsican separatist guerrillas last month, will be to increase naval cooperation.</p>
<p>Chirac and Major, attending his last annual Franco-British summit before British elections due by May next year, will sign a letter of intent on issues ranging from naval training to meteorological surveys.</p>
<p>The pact, however, will not stretch to nuclear submarines or joint patrols. The two last year set up a Franco-British air group in High Wycombe near London to cover air force cooperation.</p>
<p>The British destroyer HMS Liverpool will be docked in Bordeaux during the summit.</p>
<p>French officials said that Paris also wanted to discuss Paris and Madrid's suggestions on Monday to send an international force to Zaire to help more than a million refugees threatened by fighting in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>British ministers have made clear their determination not to be rushed into a badly thought-out operation in a part of Africa where Britain, like France a former major colonial power, hardly has any interests.</p>
<p>French Prime Minister Alain Juppe, who is also mayor of the south-western city of Bordeaux, will also attend the talks, along with ministers of foreign affairs, interior, finance, Europe and transport.</p>
<p>Both sides say that Chirac, who once said he wanted to act as a bridge between the Euro-enthusiasm of Bonn and the greater scepticism of London, is unlikely to twist Major's arm to try to get Britain to join a single European currency from 1999.</p>
<p>Chirac would instead reiterate France's position that Britain would be welcome and that &quot;the more who join the single currency the better&quot;, a French official said.</p>
<p>Both Major and opposition Labour leader Tony Blair, leading Major's Conservative party in the polls, have adopted a wait-and-see attitude towards economic and monetary union.</p>
<p>The two leaders will also debate the slow pace of an overhaul of EU institutions ahead of enlargement to include eastern European and Mediterranean states and seek to patch up Franco-British discord over extending majority voting.</p>
<p>British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind, jealously guarding Britain's right of veto, last month warned that French and German plans to integrate faster than others would have to be approved by all 15 member states.</p>
<p>Chirac and Major will also seek common ground on the Middle East peace process after Chirac made a high-profile visit to the region this month that irked some of his EU partners who saw him as too pro-Arab.</p>
<p>And the two will have a chance to sketch out possible plans to extend a current NATO-led peace mission in Bosnia next year as well as to review plans for reform and enlargement of NATO.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
