<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167736" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU's Santer concerned about U.S. aerospace support.</title>
<headline>EU's Santer concerned about U.S. aerospace support.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS, Belgium</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Commission President Jacques Santer said Tuesday that &quot;United States government interference&quot; in favour of civil and military export sales could severely distort the global aerospace market and was contrary to world trade rules.</p>
<p>While he did not elaborate on what he meant by &quot;United States government interference,&quot; Santer said that there had been repeated charges that the United States had resorted to this sort of practice.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to counteract this whenever the problem arises and, in the longer term, try to persuade the United States to forego such government pressures altogether,&quot; Santer said in a speech.</p>
<p>Santer also said the commission, the European Union's executive body, was increasingly concerned by the level of indirect subsidies to the U.S. aerospace industry through the space agency NASA and the country's huge military research programmes, funnelled towards the civil sector.</p>
<p>&quot;We are continuing to monitor this carefully,&quot; he told a conference on the future of the European aerospace industry, which is facing fierce U.S. competition.</p>
<p>&quot;We may have to consider re-orienting some of our own strategic approaches in the future if this trend continues,&quot; Santer said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS, Belgium"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
