<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167866" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - SFE wheat futures trading hits record.</title>
<headline>RTRS - SFE wheat futures trading hits record.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A record 261 wheat futures traded on the Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE) on Tuesday, including overnight trades on the SYCOM system, following the Australian Wheat Board's (AWB) pool price revision, SFE chief executive Les Hosking said in a statement.</p>
<p>The A$15.00 a tonne pool price reduction to A$175.00 a tonne for Australian Standard White brought the total reduction in the pool price to A$70.00 since June this year, he said.</p>
<p>Regular revisions of pool prices demonstrated the need for growers to use wheat futures and options for hedging their price risk, he said.  </p>
<p>The pool price reductions have followed the release of AWB figures indicating a record wheat crop of 21 million tonnes in 1996/97, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday's decision dispels the perception that the AWB price pool limits possible price risks for growers. Even with a statutory authority price pool, growers can face significant price risk and can pay dearly for not hedging their crop,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The downward movement in price for the 1997 crop provides an illustration of what can happen to the value of crops if they are not properly hedged,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
