<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167868" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks end firmer, eye rate cut.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks end firmer, eye rate cut.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian shares closed slightly firmer in lacklustre trade on Tuesday after spending the day rangebound with market participants watching the Melbourne Cup and awaiting the Reserve Bank's verdict on interest rates.</p>
<p>By the close, the All Ordinaries index added 4.1 points to 2,361.6.</p>
<p>With the nation watching the Cup and the market watching the Reserve Bank, brokers said it was unsurprising the benchmark All Ordinaries failed to escape a lightly traded eight point range.</p>
<p>&quot;It was nothing to write home about,&quot; said a Sydney broker.</p>
<p>&quot;Melbourne had the day off and the rest were watching the Cup or waiting for a rate cut.&quot;</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank is widely tipped to cut official interest rates on Wednesday after a series of weak economic data was considered at its board meeting earlier today.</p>
<p>The broker was confident of further gains if rates were cut as most players expected. &quot;We'll get a run from it if the Reserve acts Wednesday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Expectations now centre on a cut of at least 50 basis points.</p>
<p>Takeover target TNT saw plenty of trade with brokers saying the bidder, Dutch group KPN, was most likely soaking up more stock.</p>
<p>Rises outnumbered falls by a ratio of about seven to five, while about 38 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
