<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="167935" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber ends mixed on technicals, Tokyo.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber ends mixed on technicals, Tokyo.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices ended mixed again, with the market virtually untraded on weak consumer interest and a fall in Tokyo futures, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing has basically changed,&quot; said a weary-sounding dealer. &quot;The mixed prices are just an adjustment as there's no real buying.&quot;</p>
<p>The Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board qouted December RSS1 buyer at 321 cents ($1.27) a kg, up 1.50 cents from Monday. December SMR 20 was 1.50 cents lower at 308.50.</p>
<p>Trading houses quoted the SMR CV at 364, SMR L at 343, SMR 5 at 320, SMR10 at 308, SMR 20 at 307 and drum latex at 234.  </p>
<p>There were no inquiries reported for Tuesday and buyers did not show any immediate signs of returning to the market, said dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather has also started improving the last two days... so I guess there's no real reason for prices to go higher without buying,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day average rose to 243.98 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on Nov 4 from 243.09 on Nov 1. The daily indicator was higher at 245.08 against 244.76.</p>
<p>-- Barani Krishnaan (603-230-7509) ($1=2.5220 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
