<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16803" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Detroit feels sting of Republican-run Michigan.</title>
<headline>Detroit feels sting of Republican-run Michigan.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Detroit Mayor Dennis Archer said this week he is hopeful that Democrats can reclaim the Michigan House and stem state legislative moves directed at his city.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters, Archer, Detroit's mayor since 1994, acknowledged an anti-Detroit bias in Michigan.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there is any question there is an anti-bias of what has been seen in the past as being favorable to the city of Detroit,&quot; Archer said.</p>
<p>With a Republican controlled Michigan Legislature and a Republican governor, Detroit has increasingly seen an ebbing in its support from Lansing, the state capital.</p>
<p>Archer said he was hopeful that the November election would eliminate the Republicans' two-vote majority in the Michigan House.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can take back the House on the Democratic side, then I think there will be a more balanced discussion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>And that would mean &quot;less of a chance for a perception if not a reality of an anti one or another,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Archer traced the roots of the anti-Detroit bias to the western part of Michigan, where he said some people have been pushing for legislation that could land up costing the city financially.</p>
<p>For example, some lawmakers during the last legislative session cited Grand Rapids, the largest city in western Michigan, as being a loser compared to Detroit when it came to state revenue sharing.</p>
<p>They said Detroit, with 11 percent of the state's population got 26 percent of revenue sharing dollars because of its high taxes, while Grand Rapids, with 5 percent of the population got 1.7 percent of state dollars.</p>
<p>The result was a change in the revenue sharing formula that allocates any growth in state revenues to local governments on a per capita basis only, guarenteeing Detroit a smaller share of those funds.</p>
<p>Earlier this summer, Gov. John Engler signed into law a bill that phases out state support for local courts in Detroit and Pontiac. For Detroit, the loss of state funding could cost the city $11 million a year to maintain its Recorders Court.</p>
<p>The new law has led the American Civil Liberties Union of Michigan and  the Detroit chapter of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People to consider a lawsuit challenging the law.</p>
<p>Archer called the new law &quot;clearly wrong&quot; and &quot;off-base.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The legislature wiped out a court that has been in existence for over 150 years with absolutely no legitimate reason to do so,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Other measures are lurking as well. Lawmakers are expected to take up a bill this fall that would prohibit Detroit and 20 other cities from collecting income taxes from non-resident workers. For Detroit, the bill would cost the city $90 million a year.</p>
<p>Oakland County Executive L. Brooks Patterson has said he would push for the introduction of a bill this fall that would allow his county and two others to remove their revenue support from $167 million of bonds Detroit sold to expand its Cobo Hall convention center.</p>
<p>While revenues from a state-wide liquor tax would stay intact for the bonds, the move was seen as a retaliatory measure for the announced move by the Detroit Lions football team out of the Pontiac Silverdome in Oakland County for a new domed stadium in downtown Detroit.</p>
<p>Archer said he looks forward to the day he could thank the state for its support of Detroit and say &quot;now that our tax base is such we no longer have to ask for additional assistance and indeed what we're looking for is to reduce taxes.&quot;</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
