<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168076" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Key JGB futures jump to record high by Tokyo close.</title>
<headline>Key JGB futures jump to record high by Tokyo close.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key December Japanese government bond (JGB) futures contract ended Tuesday's Tokyo session sharply higher, boosted by strong buying interest from investors, traders said.</p>
<p>Sentiment was also boosted by a media report which quoted a senior official close to the Bank of Japan (BOJ) as saying that the central bank hoped the JGB market would remain bullish for as long as possible, traders said.</p>
<p>The December closed up 0.95 at 126.40 after rising to 126.46 shortly before the close, an all-time high for any benchmark futures contract.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've been seeing good buying interest from investors since last week. They were keen to buy on any weakness, though dealers were becoming more cautious,&quot; a trader at a long-term credit bank's securities unit said.</p>
<p>In the cash market, there was buying in cash JGBs between the 180th and 189th issues from some city banks, a trader at a securities company said.</p>
<p>The yield of the benchmark cash 182nd JGB fell as low as 2.415 percent in the afternoon, the lowest yield for any benchmark JGB. The previous record low was 2.485 percent set on July 7, 1995.  </p>
<p>&quot;As the benchmark JGB yield fell below the key 2.485 percent level, it has become even more difficult to determine the targets. No one can say for sure where they are now,&quot; a trader at a city bank said.</p>
<p>Traders said there was also some buying of the December futures contract by banks who were receivers of variable interest rates and payers of fixed interest rates in swap positions.</p>
<p>These banks were buying JGB futures to hedge against the risk of falling variable rates, traders said.</p>
<p>Volume of the December contract was 55,826 contracts.  </p>
<p>&quot;As the benchmark cash JGB yield hit a new record low, the December JGB futures' bull-run may not end here,&quot; the first trader said.</p>
<p>In the morning session, vague market talk that a small Japanese regional bank may be suffering financial difficulties also helped push the JGB futures higher. The rumour, however, could not be immediately confirmed.</p>
<p>Market players are focusing on the formation of Japan's new cabinet under Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, which is expected later this week, traders said.</p>
<p>-- Kanta Watanabe, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-9780</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
