<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16807" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends at highs on trade buying.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends at highs on trade buying.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar futures closed at the day's highs, buoyed by trade buying which emerged once selling dried up and the October contract failed to test support at 11.55, dealers said.</p>
<p>Speculatlive selling pressured prices below unchanged and to a low of 11.57 basis October in midsession dealings, while short-covering and fresh buying held prices at the lows.</p>
<p>&quot;When (the market) didn't collapse like people anticipated, they got nervous and raised their buying ideas and that chased the market up,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>Support remained between 11.55 and 11.53 basis the October contract, and at 11.30 in March.</p>
<p>The October contract closed 0.09 higher to 11.74, having ranged from 11.75 to 11.57. March settled 0.05 firmer at 11.40, while the back months finished 0.08 to 0.04 higher.</p>
<p>LCE white sugar futures trimmed losses in the wake of strength in the New York market, but prices still ended the day lower. October closed at $350.10, down $2.40 a tonne from last Friday. December finished down $1.40 to $344.60.</p>
<p>One physical broker noted Syrian buying overnight.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities, 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
