<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168097" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul shrs end at 3-yr low on supply, probe fears.</title>
<headline>Seoul shrs end at 3-yr low on supply, probe fears.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks tumbled throughout Tuesday's trading as investors hurriedly dumped shares on fears that a huge oversupply of new stocks this month would spell disaster for the rudderless market, brokers said.</p>
<p>The uncertain atmosphere was further dampened by the government's on-going anti-corruption campaign, which could further destabilise stock prices, they added.</p>
<p>The composite stock index fell 13.74 points, or 1.84 percent, to a provisional close of 733.68.  </p>
<p>This was the lowest close since October 12, 1993, when the market closed at 723.57.</p>
<p>Brokers and analysts said the market's collapse over the past two days were linked more to a shift in sentiment than a sudden change in fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone knew about the margin loans and the oversupply of shares. It's now a psychological issue. People are really afraid to hold shares,&quot; said Choi Tae-hwan, head of sales department at KLB Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The 750 line was seen as a strong support,&quot; market analyst Steven Lee of Shinyoung Securities earlier said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Once that line was broken (on Monday), people didn't know where it would stop,&quot; Lee said.</p>
<p>Loans for margin trading are at a record high of around three trillion won, while customer deposits have declined to around 2.5 trillion. Between 500-900 billion won worth of the loans will have to be repaid this month, brokers said.</p>
<p>New stock supply in November is estimated at more than 1.1 trillion won, they added.</p>
<p>The exchange later revised the index to 733.65, down 13.77 points or 1.84 percent on the day.  </p>
<p>Brokers said investors were worried that the corruption investigations would also look into illicit share trading and could cause big investors to pull money out of the market.</p>
<p>President Kim Young-sam has staked his political reputation on fighting corruption, but was recently embarrassed by the arrest of a former defence minister for accepting bribes.</p>
<p>Prosecution officials have said the current drive would cover all levels of civil servants and would last till 1998.</p>
<p>Small-cap and second-tier shares, which had led the market's gains this year, bore the brunt of the selling.  </p>
<p>Tae Heung Leather fell 500 won to 12,400. Sammi Steel lost 70 won to 4,160. Tongil Heavy Industry shed 140 won to 4,660.</p>
<p>Heavily weighted blue chips saw some buying late on bargain hunting. Samsung Electronics rose 1,500 won to 60,700. Korea Mobile Telecom gained 16,000 won to 450,000.</p>
<p>The December futures ended down 0.10 of a point to 78.50, while the KOSPI 200 index lost 1.02 points to 76.93.</p>
<p>-- KATHERINE BRUCE (822) 727 5644</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
