<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168209" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Late profit-taking ends brief Taiwan bull run.</title>
<headline>Late profit-taking ends brief Taiwan bull run.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's brief, reform-driven bull run charged into the final hour of trade before faltering at the close on Tuesday as profit-takers moved in to hand the index a loss, brokers said.</p>
<p>The weighted index ended 18.47 points or 0.28 percent lower at 6,604.14.</p>
<p>Turnover was a hectic T$62.27 billion.</p>
<p>The rejuvenated market had gained nearly 300 points in the three previous sessions after the government freed one major state fund to invest in stocks and relaxed an investment cap on another big state fund.  </p>
<p>But after pushing the index higher in early trade on Tuesday, investors began taking profits on recently red-hot electronic shares and the market failed to find another sector to take up the charge, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;After their enormous gains in the last few weeks, high-tech stocks are a bit overbought and investors were unwilling to buy high-priced shares,&quot; said Chen Han-chung oof Yungli Securities.</p>
<p>Electronics closed 0.59 percent higher, but failed to hold on to greater gains registered earlier in the session.</p>
<p>Blue-chip Taiwan Semiconductor finished even at T$57.50 despite sizzling trade volume of 35.91 million shares.  </p>
<p>The heavily weighted financial sector also suffered mild, but widespread losses. Hua Nan, one of Taiwan's &quot;big three&quot; state-run commercial banks, dropped T$1.50 to T$125 while Cathay Life Insurance fell T$2 to T$169.</p>
<p>Brokers expected the market to remain in a consolidation for several more sessions before challenging for a higher upside.</p>
<p>They said they did not expect the U.S. election results -- likely to become available soon after the Taiwan market's open on Wednesday -- to have a significant impact on local shares.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Chen (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
