<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16822" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD bars 12 for cheating on qualifying test.</title>
<headline>NASD bars 12 for cheating on qualifying test.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>NASD Regulation Inc said Tuesday it censored and barred 12 people suspected of paying an imposter to take a qualifying examination for them.</p>
<p>Each was also fined in amounts ranging up to $50,000, NASD Regulation said in a statement.</p>
<p>Industry rules require security professionals who deal with the public to pass tests showing their knowledge of securities markets and regulations.  </p>
<p>NASD Regulation said it was still investigating other people suspected of similar misconduct and expected to announce further disciplinary actions shortly.</p>
<p>NASD Regulation spokesman Reid Walker said he did not know the time period in which the cheating or the initial investigation had taken place.</p>
<p>After the initial investigation by NASD Regulation's New York district office, 12 people were called in to testify, but half of them did not show up for their hearings, NASD Regulation said.</p>
<p>All 12 were barred for life from working in the U.S. securities industry. They are: Burton Butler Brous, Stephen Douglas Carollo, Peter Michael DelSeni, David Mark Gold, Kevin Michael Kelly, Frank Michael Mancini, Yury Moroz, Joseph John Pellegrino, Brian Thomas Rice, Peter Scali, Robert James Thornton and Felix Tkachenko.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
