<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168389" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Alusuisse names new CEO per April 1997.</title>
<headline>Alusuisse names new CEO per April 1997.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alusuisse-Lonza Holding AG said current chief financial officer Sergio Marchionne would take over as chief executive when Theodor Tschopp moves to the post of chairman of the board next April 2.  </p>
<p>Marchionne, 44, will be succeeded as finance officer by Urs Fischer, 42, who is currently divisional controller for the aluminium division, an Alusuisse statement said.</p>
<p>Alusuisse also said it would create a new position at group level in charge of corporate development in order to better achieve the compnay's prime goal of qualitative growth.</p>
<p>The corporate development post will go to Peter Kalantzis, currently head of the chemicals division, one of Alusuisse's three core business areas alongside packaging and aluminium products.  </p>
<p>&quot;The prime goal of the group is qualitative growth,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Kalantzis will be followed as head of the Lonza chemicals division by Leander Tenud, the group said.</p>
<p>The Alusuisse announcement answered the question of Tschopp's succession that had been open since August 1995, when designated CEO Dominique Damon left the group over what were officially called &quot;different opinions about strategic issues&quot;.</p>
<p>Tschopp, 59, had been planning since 1994 to succeed outgoing chairman of the board Hans Jucker at the general shareholder meeting next April 2.</p>
<p>Tschopp had said earlier this year he might remain chief executive for one or two years past next April in order to maintain strategic continuity if no successor was found in time.</p>
<p>Tschopp's focus has been on turning Alusuisse from a cyclically troubled aluminium producer in the late 1980s into a consortium of roughly equal sized divisions in aluminium products, chemicals and packaging.</p>
<p>As recently as October, Tschopp confirmed in a newspaper interview that Alusuisse was not considering splitting off any of its three major operations.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Newsroom, +41-1-631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22450">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
