<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168320" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ABU DHABI: Britain's Rifkind says defence pact with UAE close.</title>
<headline>Britain's Rifkind says defence pact with UAE close.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>ABU DHABI 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said on Tuesday Britain and the United Arab Emirates were close to agreeing on a long-delayed defence pact, which could help British business in the Gulf Arab state.</p>
<p>Rifkind told a news conference in Abu Dhabi at the end of his two-day talks in the UAE that his discussions with senior officials included the pact, which has been delayed for years with both countries haggling over its wording.</p>
<p>&quot;The two sides are very close to final agreement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>British arms makers have been urging London to finalise the pact to improve their standing in several pending arms deals in the UAE afetr losing lucrative business in recent years to other Western firms.</p>
<p>The UAE has defence pacts with the United States and France and is using the latter as a model for what it considers a clear and firm commitment to its security if threatened.</p>
<p>Rifkind had arrived in Abu Dhabi a day after a hectic round of talks with Israeli and Palestinian leaders designed to give new impetus to the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>He has also launched a British initiative intended to try to prevent conflicts in the region escalating.</p>
<p>The body, which Rifkind suggested could be called the Organisation for Cooperation in the Middle East (OCME), would &quot;provide a framework for dialogue and active collaboration.&quot;</p>
<p>Rifkind told the news conference on Tuesday that initial reaction to his proposed body was encouraging, but that it was in its &quot;very early stages.&quot;</p>
<p>Based on the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) rather than a military alliance, the new group could include Turkey, and would eventually be open to countries like Iraq and Iran, said Rifkind. He said he had already floated the idea with countries in the region and other allies like the United States, with a favourable response.</p>
<p>Senior officials travelling with Rifkind said the idea was not designed to replace the Middle East peace process, but to prevent another such crisis erupting.</p>
<p>Rifkind is flying to Yemen on Tuesday for talks there and will head back home on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
