<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168330" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanon inches towards agreement on new cabinet.</title>
<headline>Lebanon inches towards agreement on new cabinet.</headline>
<byline>Rashid Sinno</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lebanese leaders have agreed on most of the members who will make up the new government but are still discussing the distribution of cabinet posts, political sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said a two-hour meeting at the presidential palace on Monday evening resolved differences over the composition of the new government between Prime Minister-elect Rafik al-Hariri and President Elias Hrawi.</p>
<p>The two leaders would hold another meeting on Tuesday and the new government could be completed within days, the sources said.</p>
<p>It would comprise 30 members, like Hariri's outgoing government, and would be a compromise between Hariri's stated wish for a &quot;homogeneous working team&quot; and Hrawi's demand for inclusion of representatives from a broad political spectrum.</p>
<p>The sources said Hariri agreed on Monday that Hrawi, a Maronite Christian, should choose some of the Christian members of the new government which must be made up of Christians and Moslems on a 50-50 basis.</p>
<p>Hariri was originally expected to form the new government -- his third since he took office in October 1992 -- before the end of last week but his efforts ran into difficulties.</p>
<p>Hrawi's bid to impose Christian politicians he considers more representative of the community ran counter to Hariri's aim of forming a government free of internal opposition to his policies which plagued his earlier cabinets.</p>
<p>Simultaneous attacks on Hariri by Druze leader Walid Jumblatt, his former ally and a permanent fixture in the government, indicated that Hariri may not be as politically powerful as his success in recent parliamentary elections had indicated, political sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot replace the absolute powers of the president with absolute powers of the prime minister,&quot; Jumblatt declared at the weekend in a sharp attack on Hariri.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot accept a person who tells us: either me or the (Lebanese) pound will collapse,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Political sources said Hariri's emergence from the elections at the head of one of the strongest parliamentary blocs and his attempt to rush through the appointment of a cabinet tailored to his tastes may have caused concern that he was growing too powerful.</p>
<p>The sources said Syrian leaders, whose 35,000 troops in Lebanon make them the country's main power broker, may prefer to keep a balance between Lebanon's ruling troika -- Hrawi, Hariri and parliament Speaker Nabih Berri -- rather than let Hariri become dominant.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
