<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168335" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Nov 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Nov 5.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AN-NAHAR</p>
<p>-The five-nation ceasefire deal monitoring group will meet today to discuss a Lebanese complaint about Israeli shelling of civilian areas in south Lebanon on Sunday.</p>
<p>-Economic activity grew in August, and the balance of payments surplus on a year-on-year basis was $286 million.</p>
<p>AS-SAFIR</p>
<p>-The new cabinet will be formed within two days; it will consist of 22 MPs and eight dignitaries.</p>
<p>-Security forces seized 130 kg of cocaine and arrested 14 dealers and addicts.</p>
<p>-Bank of Lebanon's latest monthly bulletin reported that net public debt rose to 14,392.7 billion Lebanese pounds in August.</p>
<p>AL-ANWAR</p>
<p>-Christian Maronite Patriarch Sfeir heads to Vatican tomorrow.</p>
<p>-The weekly treasury bills issue reached 1,057 billion pounds, the highest level attained in a year.</p>
<p>AD-DIYAR</p>
<p>-The trial of 25 people accused of working for the Israeli Mossad resumed yesterday and five suspects in custody deny the charges.</p>
<p>NIDA'A AL-WATAN</p>
<p>-Israeli forces strafe with machinegunfire areas north of the eastern sector of the Israeli-held zone in south Lebanon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
