<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168328" id="root" date="1996-11-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Nov 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Jordan - Nov 5.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Jordanian press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AD-DUSTOUR</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kabariti says &quot;no devaluation of the dinar under any circumstance and the private sector and the government are in one trench...and our ties with Iraq are balanced.&quot;</p>
<p>- King Hussein and Syrian President Hafez Assad review the developments in the peace process and Arab situation.</p>
<p>- Central Bank foreign currency deposits deregulation frees $700 million of deposits back to the banking system, says a Central Bank official.</p>
<p>- Brother kills sister in the city of Mafrak.</p>
<p>- Jordan's ambassador to Israel arrives on Tuesday.</p>
<p>AL-RAI</p>
<p>- Kabariti emphasises the importance of resuming the peace process, President Arafat's senior aide says &quot;we are keen to see a continuation of the Jordanian custodianship of the Moslem holy sites in Jerusalem.&quot;</p>
<p>- Information Minister says Israeli President Weizman's visit to Jordan ceremonial.</p>
<p>AL-ASWAQ</p>
<p>- Information Minister Muasher says the civilian infiltrator who was shot by Israel this week was heading to the Jordanian border.</p>
<p>JORDAN TIMES</p>
<p>- Palestinian Authority requests Jordan to continue its role in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>- Kabariti receives Greek transport minister.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
