<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168493" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: BC Tel seeks local phone service rate hike.</title>
<headline>BC Tel seeks local phone service rate hike.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>BC Telecom Inc said on Wednesday it asked the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission (CRTC) to approve an increase in the price it can charge for residential and some commercial local telephone service.</p>
<p>The increase for residential customers would range between C$0.15 and C$1.50 a month with an average increase of C$0.70. The basic single-line home service now costs C$16 a month.</p>
<p>Businesses with a single line would see changes in their local phone service cost ranging from a decrease of C$9.90 a month to an increase of C$4.25 a month.  </p>
<p>The decreases would be mostly in larger communities.</p>
<p>BC Tel said it was asking for the rate changes to take effect January 1 at the same time as a C$2 a month increase announced last year. That increase is the second of three annual increases announced by the CRTC for all Canadian telephone companies. BC Tel said it ran a deficit of C$450 million for basic residential phone service in 1995.</p>
<p>It costs the company about C$30 a month, or nearly twice the average price charged, to provide the service. The company said it expects the price of basic single-line residential service to rise to between C$25 and C$30 a month by 2000.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
