<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168622" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Eurogas discovers gas in Slovakia.</title>
<headline>Eurogas discovers gas in Slovakia.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eurogas Inc said on Wednesday it made a significant gas discovery at its well in Slovakia and that it planned to drill two additional wells in the area very soon.</p>
<p>It said it successfully completed its discovery well, the Trebisov 5R in the Trebisov area of Slovakia, and that the well encountered an unusually large gas column measuring 970 meters. The well's upper interval tested one million cubic feet of natural gas per day and the lower interval zone tested at 400,000 cubic feet of natural gas per day, Eurogas said.  </p>
<p>The well also produced 20 barrels of condensate per day, the company said, adding that it hoped to install temporary surface gas lines to begin production as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Eurogas said it would spud, or start drilling, its second development well there, the Trebisov 8, in mid-November. That well was 1.2 kilometers northwest of the discovery well.</p>
<p>The company would then drill another well and simultaneously conduct a 3-D seismic survey of the Trebisov area, it said. The purpose of the survey was to minimize drilling and completion risks, Eurogas said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
