<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168715" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US stocks snare records in post-election euphoria.</title>
<headline>US stocks snare records in post-election euphoria.</headline>
<byline>Betty Wong</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stocks thundered to record heights in a post-election euphoria, with frenetic buying seen in sectors deemed winners after news President Clinton won re-election and Republicans kept control of Congress.</p>
<p>The Dow industrials soared 97 points, or 1.59 percent, to about 6178, snaring its first ever close above 6100 and nearing the next century mark. It was the biggest single day point gain since March 18's 98.63 point surge and topped the previous all-time high finish of 6094.23 set October 18.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P 500 set a second straight record, up 10 to 725.  </p>
<p>Analysts noted that stocks thrived under the politically divided U.S. government after Republicans re-took control of Congress in November 1994. Wall Street had feared a Democratic sweep that might spur more social spending, a balloning deficit and greater inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is happy with the fact there are no big changes. It's status quo. The market often dislikes uncertainty,&quot; said Richard McCabe, chief technical analyst at Merrill Lynch. He noted the Dow soared 60 percent since the November 1994 elections. As for the near term, he said: &quot;We may get to 6200, or 6300 and then people will take a look.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;My concern is we may be in a later stage or mature stage of the bull market,&quot; McCabe said. &quot;If the market stalls at year end or early next year, there could be a sizeable 20 percent pullback in 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The long bond slipped 8/32 to yield 6.60 percent after recent strong gains.</p>
<p>&quot;We go back to last year's argument that there's no alternative (to stocks) with yields this low,&quot; said Richard Cripps, chief market strategist at Legg Mason Wood Walker.</p>
<p>He described Wednesday's action as &quot;so awesome. I'm awed by it.&quot;  </p>
<p>Drug, health care, and tobacco shares surged on investor perception that a Republican Congress will keep a second Clinton administration from launching any aggressive campaigns to regulate the industries.</p>
<p>Merck rose 3-1/4 to 79, Pfizer up 2-7/8 to 88-1/2 and Bristol-Myers Squibb advancing 2-1/2 to 111. United Healthcare jumped 2-3/4 to 40 while Oxford Health Plans, which also posted strong third quarter earnings on Wednesday, rose 4-5/8 to 51-1/2. Among biotech shares, Biogen rose 3-3/8 to 77-1/8 and Centocor, getting an added boost from a UBS Securities buy rating, climbed 2-5/8 to 29.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
