<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168934" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-HINGUS ADVANCES IN OAKLAND.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-HINGUS ADVANCES IN OAKLAND.</headline>
<dateline>OAKLAND, California 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sixteen-year-old Swiss phenom Martina Hingus, seeded third at the $450,000 Bank of the West Classic, posted a 6-4, 6-4 victory over Anne Miller in an opening-round match on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hingus, who has defeated eight top 10 players this year, had little trouble with the 66th-ranked Miller, but felt she won the match with her head and not her groundstrokes.</p>
<p>&quot;She gave me a hard time.&quot; said Hingus, ranked seventh in the world. &quot;The surface was slow and I found myself running over balls and overhitting. I won this match with the head and mental part. I didn't really feel very good about my groundstrokes.&quot;</p>
<p>Hingus was down a break at 3-1 in the first, but regained her momentum with consecutive love games to even the score before pulling out the first set with a drop volley, her shot du jour. In the second, she lost her serve twice, but broke Miller in the final game to advance to the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>&quot;It was close the whole time and I felt I was right in there,&quot; Miller said. &quot;When I got up I just started making more errors. And I had a few double faults that hurt me.&quot;</p>
<p>Miller had six double faults, one of which cost her the first set.</p>
<p>Thirty-four-year-old Pam Shriver, a late wildcard entry, pulled out a tough three-set win against Rennae Stubbs 6-2 6-7 (5) 6-3. Shriver, ranked 229th in the world and playing in only her 12th match of the year, conceded she is gradually closing out her career.</p>
<p>&quot;I've made a point to not say I'm retiring,&quot; Shriver said. &quot;I'm just making a transition. I can still have wins on this tour, just not successively.&quot;</p>
<p>Tuesday's only upset was Romanian Irina Spirlea's 6-4 6-2 first-round victory over eighth seed Karina Habsudova of Slovakia, who became the third seed to fall in two days.</p>
<p>After blowing a 3-0 lead in the third, Canadian Patricia Hy-Boulais had to battle back from 3-5 to beat American Zina Garrison Jackson, a two-time winner of this event, 6-4 6-7 (7-4) 6-4.</p>
<p>Top-seeded Monica Seles will make her first appearance in Oakland since 1992, facing Hy-Boulais on Wednesday. Seles, co-ranked second in the world, won here in 1990 and 1992, both times beating Martina Navratilova in the final.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAKLAND, California"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
