<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="168957" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER SHOWCASE-ATLETICO MADRID PENPIX.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-ATLETICO MADRID PENPIX.</headline>
<dateline>BARCELONA 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pen pictures of the Atletico Madrid players most likely to play in Saturday's match against Barcelona in the Camp Nou stadium:</p>
<p>Jose Molina, goalkeeper, age 26. Outstanding in last season's league and cup double after signing from Albacete, Molina's characteristic sorties from the area make the Atletico offside trap difficult to beat. Came on as a striker and nearly scored on his sole international appearance in a friendly last year.</p>
<p>Santi Denia, defender, 22. Tough central defender who joined Atletico with Molina from Albacete last season and quickly became a regular in the side.</p>
<p>Roberto Solozabal, defender, 27. Quiet but influential, Solozabal is the unofficial leader of the Atletico defence and an automatic first choice.</p>
<p>Toni Munoz, defender, 28. In last year's game Johan Cruyff, then coach of Barcelona, ordered extra watering in the Camp Nou to slow down Toni whose speed down the left is a crucial element in Atletico's counter-attacking strategy.</p>
<p>Juan Lopez, defender/midfielder, 27. Spanish international utility man who has hardly played this season but may be given the tough job of marking Barcelona striker Ronaldo. A reckless tackler, Lopez is prone to getting sent off.</p>
<p>Carlos Aguilera, defender/midfielder, 27. Struggling to hold a first-team place since rejoining Atletico from Tenerife this season, Aguilera's strength lies in his ability to join in attacks down the right. May fill the gap left by Delfi Geli who is suspended.</p>
<p>Juan Vizcaino, midfielder, 30. Solid midfielder who provides support for creative chiefs Caminero and Pantic.</p>
<p>Milinko Pantic, midfielder, 30. Serbian set-piece specialist who has blossomed since signing as an unknown from Greek side Panionios last season. Scored a superb goal from a free-kick in a recent European Champions' League victory at Borussia Dortmund. Can even score from corners. Recovering from injury but hopes to be fit for Saturday.</p>
<p>Diego Simeone, midfielder, 26. Argentine international midfield dynamo who has found his goal touch this season, especially in the Champions' League in which he has scored four times. Strong in the air and combines well with Pantic at set pieces.</p>
<p>Roberto Fresnedoso, midfielder, 23. Has improved dramatically this season while filling in for Caminero. Scored Atletico's first goal in the 3-1 win at Barcelona in April.</p>
<p>Jose Luis Caminero, midfielder, 29. Playmaker who came to prominence in the 1994 World Cup. Celebrated his return from a month's lay-off through injury with a goal last weekend. Turns 29 on Friday and will hope to top off the celebrations in the same way.</p>
<p>Kiko Narvaez, striker, 24. One of the most imaginative strikers in the country, Kiko led Spain to Olympic glory in the Camp Nou in 1992. Not a prolific marksman but tends to score crucial goals.</p>
<p>Juan Eduardo Esnaider, striker, 23. Argentine international who helped Zaragoza win the European Cup Winners' Cup in 1995 but failed to perform on his return to Real Madrid. Combines well with Kiko and Caminero but is dogged by a quick temper. </p>
<p>Leonardo Biagini, striker, 19. Promising Argentine who is likely to get his chance only if Esnaider and Kiko fail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BARCELONA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
