<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169173" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Efforts to help Zaire refugees reach stalemate.</title>
<headline>Efforts to help Zaire refugees reach stalemate.</headline>
<byline>Richard Meares</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Efforts to help 1.2 million refugees stranded in the war zone of eastern Zaire reached stalemate on Wednesday, with Zaire telling aid agencies to keep out and the U.N. saying many lives were at risk.</p>
<p>&quot;We are asking humanitarian organisations to stop distributing any aid to the refugees on Zairean soil. They must instead distribute aid in Rwanda and Burundi...&quot; government spokesman Boguo Makeli said in Kinshasa.</p>
<p>The U.N. says many lives will be lost unless they take food and medicine into Zaire fast.</p>
<p>&quot;You can't repatriate dead refugees. We need to get in there,&quot; U.N. refugee agency spokesman Peter Kessler told Reuters in Nairobi.</p>
<p>Kessler said of half-a-million refugees in South Kivu province: &quot;The vast majority of these people have been without food for nearly three weeks.&quot; Some 700,000 others further north have had some food more recently but are also at risk.</p>
<p>The last international aid workers fled the east Zaire city of Goma last Saturday after battles there killed more than 400 people. Their flight left the Rwandan and Burundian refugees without any U.N. protection and support.</p>
<p>An eight-nation African summit in Nairobi on Tuesday called for a &quot;neutral&quot; protection force to rescue the refugees, but volunteers appeared sparse on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The summit requested the U.N. Security Council to take urgent measures to ensure the establishment of the safe corridors and temporary sanctuaries by deploying a neutral force,&quot; the regional leaders' final communique said.</p>
<p>The Security Council met later behind closed doors at France's behest but Britain and the United States seemed hesitant to send an intervention force.</p>
<p>British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind, visiting Yemen, said on Wednesday it was &quot;far too early&quot; to say if Britain would join a force for east Zaire.</p>
<p>As the world warned of impending doom but failed to act, the refugees spent another day out of reach of outside help, their whereabouts unknown and their last food feared running out.</p>
<p>If Zaire's ragged army continued to fight local Tutsis, who rebelled two weeks ago, it was hidden from the eyes and ears of independent observers who are barred from the area.</p>
<p>The Organisation of African Unity (OAU), responding to the Nairobi summit, said its conflict prevention group would meet to discuss Zaire -- but not until Monday next week.</p>
<p>Aid agencies are exasperated, fearing that every day brings nearer a repeat of the 1994 catastrophe in which 50,000 Rwandan refugees died from disease in just two months.</p>
<p>&quot;We are doing our best to speed up the process,&quot; European Union special envoy Aldo Ajello told a Nairobi news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We should intervene immediately, or at least as soon as possible. The framework should be very short.&quot;</p>
<p>Rwanda, Kenya, Uganda, Tanzania, Zambia, Ethiopia, Eritrea, Cameroon and the OAU called on Tuesday for a ceasefire and said the &quot;sub-region&quot; would contribute to any aid mission.</p>
<p>Eritrean President Isayas Afewerki told Reuters on Wednesday: &quot;The first step is to identify sites for the temporary sanctuaries and again see details of the safe corridor concept put on paper.&quot;</p>
<p>Rwanda, accused by Zaire of sending troops over the border to help the fellow Tutsi rebels, signed the summit communique hours after saying it could not accept foreign intervention.</p>
<p>Analysts said the key summit word was &quot;neutral&quot; and that Rwanda's Tutsi army does not consider France neutral, accusing it of helping its Hutu foes flee after they committed genocide.</p>
<p>Yet it is Paris that has pushed hardest for intervention. Fearing more claims of bias, it does not want to act alone.</p>
<p>The Hutu soldiers in Zaire are well armed. A U.N. report obtained on Tuesday showed they had been amply supplied with arms from Europe and South Africa.</p>
<p>The snag for all who have dealt with the post-genocide crisis in central Africa is that the vast bulk of Hutu refugees refuse to go home.</p>
<p>Another diplomatic initiative was to take place on Wednesday on the French Riviera where U.N. special mediator Raymond Chretien will meet Zaire's convalescing President Mobutu Sese Seko, whose long absence after Swiss surgery has left his country divided.</p>
<p>The turmoil in eastern Zaire has left the Zairean capital Kinshasa tense. Defying a government ban, anti-Tutsi students in protested in Kinshasa on Wednesday, demanding money from passers-by to pay for the funeral of a colleague killed in clashes the day before.</p>
<p>An estimated 1,000 Tutsis have fled by boat across the Zaire River to Brazzaville, capital of neighbouring Congo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
