<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169172" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Rights groups warn Nigeria could be another Zaire.</title>
<headline>Rights groups warn Nigeria could be another Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Eniwoke Ibagere</byline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>A human rights group in Nigeria on Wednesday launched a campaign against alleged rights violations, saying the West African nation could slide into ethnic conflict like Zaire.</p>
<p>Tribal warfare betwen Hutus and Tutsis in east Africa has left the eastern flank of sprawling Zaire in chaos, stranding hundreds of thousands of refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;Rights abuses by the military government could turn Nigeria into another Zaire if local and international communities don't stem the tide,&quot; Clement Nwankwo, head of the Constitutional Rights Project (CRP), told a news conference in Lagos.</p>
<p>&quot;The crisis in Zaire started in the same manner as the way the Nigerian military has been unlawfully detaining, intimidating and eliminating imagined enemies,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier, London-based group Amnesty International released a report on Africa's most populous country that accused the state of being openly contemptuous of human rights.</p>
<p>It reported little improvement in Nigeria since the government drew worldwide condemnation last November 10 for hanging author Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight minority rights activists of the Ogoni tribe.</p>
<p>&quot;As the first anniversary of their execution draws near, little has changed,&quot; Amnesty International said. &quot;The present military government in Nigeria has a record of open contempt for human rights.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The government continues to violate the human rights of its critics, including opposition politicians, journalists, human rights activists and members of the Ogoni ethnic group.&quot;</p>
<p>Nwankwo said Nigerian rights groups planned a three-day ceremony starting on Saturday to mark the anniversary of the executions of the nine men. They had been convicted of the murder of four Ogoni chiefs in a trial critics termed flawed.</p>
<p>Prayers and peaceful processions will be held simultaneously in southeastern Port-Harcourt, where the nine were executed, and at the Lagos university campus, he said.</p>
<p>Nigeria's special duties minister Wada Nas on Monday accused Amnesty International of planning to foment trouble by staging demonstrations on the anniversary.</p>
<p>The Lagos chapter of Amnesty International in a statement on Wednesday denied the accusation.</p>
<p>Nigeria, under military rule for 25 years since its independence in 1960, plunged into turmoil in 1993 when a presidential vote presumed to have been won by millionaire businessman Moshood Abiola was annulled by the army.</p>
<p>Abiola has been detained since 1994 when he proclaimed himself president in defiance of military ruler General Sani Abacha, who seized power in the mayhem that followed the annulment.</p>
<p>Several opposition men are also in detention or have fled abroad since strikes and riots were organised in 1994 to force Abacha to cede power to Abiola.</p>
<p>About half a dozen detainees have been released since the United Nations sent a fact-finding mission to Nigeria. The U.N. report endorsed Abacha's transition to civil rule programme but called for detainees to be freed and draconian laws reformed.</p>
<p>Abacha is implementing a programme of phased elections that he says would usher in an elected civilian government by October 1998.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
