<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169256" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Determined Yeltsin bounces back from operation.</title>
<headline>Determined Yeltsin bounces back from operation.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Lannin</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boris Yeltsin's doctors said they were optimistic on Wednesday as the Russian president made a surprisingly rapid recovery from multiple heart bypass surgery to resume full powers less than 24 hours after the operation.</p>
<p>The 65-year-old Kremlin leader was already badgering the medics to let him out of hospital.</p>
<p>Pioneering U.S. heart surgeon Michael DeBakey, 88, who supervised Tuesday's seven-hour operation, said Yeltsin could be back on the tennis court in four months.</p>
<p>But he urged him to be patient and follow doctors' orders.</p>
<p>Doctors grafted in veins to divert blood around five blockages in Yeltsin's cardiac arteries.</p>
<p>The surgery aims to give Yeltsin a new lease of life, four months into a new four-year term. It may be some time, however, before it is clear that he has the strength to return to the Kremlin with a firm hand after months of policy drift.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who met Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin in the Cardiology Research Centre where the operation was conducted, asked for a transfer to the elite Central Clinical Hospital, where he was treated for previous heart trouble.</p>
<p>The president said he would feel more at home there. Doctors are to discuss the request on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Within three or four months he could do almost anything he wants,&quot; DeBakey told CNN television after meeting Yeltsin on Wednesday, once the patient had been taken off a respirator.</p>
<p>Leading Russian cardiologist Leo Bokeria, who was not part of the operating team, said that judging by the information that had been made public, Yeltsin would be able to return this week to &quot;quite an active state and will be able to walk&quot;.</p>
<p>Doctors have said Yeltsin could be back at his desk in six to eight weeks.</p>
<p>The president delegated power to Chernomyrdin during the surgery and for the first hours after it. Kremlin press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky said Yeltsin had signed a decree taking back control of the country at six a.m. (0300 GMT).</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin met Yeltsin for 15 minutes on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Boris Nikolayevich is active already,&quot; said the prime minister, who underwent similar surgery several years ago.</p>
<p>&quot;A decree was signed and is already in force. He has taken his powers back. This means that he is back at his job.&quot;</p>
<p>The once tight-lipped Kremlin has released a series of statements about Yeltsin's health since the operation started, in an unprecedented public relations exercise.</p>
<p>The latest bulletin, dealing with Yeltsin's health at four p.m. (1300 GMT) on Thursday, said there had been no complications.</p>
<p>&quot;The post-operative recovery process...is proceeding normally, in line with the doctors' expectations and without complications,&quot; the statement said. &quot;The next bulletin about the president's state of health will be on November 7.&quot;</p>
<p>The Kremlin later called a news conference for midday (0900 GMT) on Thursday, when Russians will be enjoyed a public holiday for the anniversary of the 1917 Bolshevik revolution.</p>
<p>Yeltsin has spent only a few days in the Kremlin since he won a second term in office on July 3 and his absence has paralysed Russia's post-communist reforms, damaging investor confidence and unleashing a new bout of political infighting.</p>
<p>The president's friends and foes have been waiting to see whether he will take full control or become a lame duck for his second term, due to end midway through 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;The first thing he will want to do after he has recovered is to show he is in complete control. This is vital in a system where the president has huge powers,&quot; said Irina Kobrinskaya, an analyst at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.</p>
<p>But a mood of reconciliation reigned on Wednesday. Communist leader Gennady Zyuganov, Yeltsin's rival in the July presidential runoff, wished the president a speedy recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;He must now care more about health,&quot; he told reporters. &quot;He must trust more of the people he is working with, otherwise there will be neither health nor government.&quot;</p>
<p>Russian financial markets were pleased with the news of Yeltsin's health. Debt prices soared toward record highs and shares rose.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia is again a buy. The best possible outcome -- of a technocratic administration under the nominal control of a convalescent Yeltsin -- is now the base case,&quot; Bank of America analyst Richard Gray said in London.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
