<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169347" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Another deputy prime minister sacked in Kazakhstan.</title>
<headline>Another deputy prime minister sacked in Kazakhstan.</headline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Nagashbai Shaikenov became the latest victim on Wednesday in a wide-ranging purge of senior government officials in Kazakhstan.</p>
<p>A decree signed by President Nursultan Nazarbayev and published in the former Soviet republic's official press on Wednesday said Shaikenov was moved to &quot;other work&quot; but gave no further details.</p>
<p>Shaikenov, who was in charge of legal reform in the vast, oil-rich Central Asian nation, is one of a string of senior officials to have lost their jobs in the last week.</p>
<p>Another deputy prime minister, Garri Shtoik, who had responsibility for economic reform and high profile foreign investment deals, was sacked on October 28.</p>
<p>The minister of defence and the minister of trade and industry have also been replaced.</p>
<p>Officials have refused to comment on the sackings.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Akezhan Kazhegeldin, widely seen by foreign investors as the main driving force behind market economic reform, has retained his post so far.</p>
<p>Nazarbayev, the country's former Communist Party boss and who has wide-ranging executive powers, restated his commitment to market economic reforms earlier this month.</p>
<p>But some observers say he has lost touch with the tough economic problems facing the government, including growing popular unrest over unpaid wages and pensions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
