<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169316" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: IMF urges Bulgaria to adopt currency board. [CORRECTED 20:00 GMT]</title>
<headline>IMF urges Bulgaria to adopt currency board. [CORRECTED 20:00 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Adoption of a currency board would stabilise Bulgaria's national currency, curb inflation and boost economic growth, the International Monetary Fund (IMF) said in a statement on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Undoubtedly the currency board can quickly reduce inflation in Bulgaria and the benefits will be worth the value of its introduction,&quot; said the IMF.</p>
<p>Under a currency board -- a system introduced by some countries to boost credibility in their currencies -- the amount of currency in circulation must be matched exactly by hard currency reserves.</p>
<p>Such systems deprive the central bank of the usual tools of monetary management, such as market intervention and interest rates. Critics of the idea have said that unless Bulgaria boosts exports, restricted hard currency flow would stifle the economy.</p>
<p>The IMF said in a statement that a currency board would only succeed in Bulgaria if it was supported by a sufficiently austere budget and broad social and political consunsus.</p>
<p>Senior IMF officials are discussing with the government and bankers the introduction of a board as a means to stabilise the crumbling economy and restore confidence in the lev.</p>
<p>Nikolai Koichev, head of parliament's economy commission, told reporters a board should be introduced through legislation. IMF officials say that if Bulgaria agrees, a board would take two to three months (Corrects to months from years) to be introduced.</p>
<p>The IMF has twice postponed a $115 million loan so far due to Bulgaria's failure to meet reform targets which include curbing inflation, stabilising the exchange rate, speeding up privatisation and closing loss-making enterprises.</p>
<p>Personal and company deposits worth up to $600 million have been withdrawn from banks this year and a quarter of the country's banks were placed in receivership in a bid to prevent their collapse.</p>
<p>The central bank has sought the bankruptcy of 13 banks through the courts, which have not yet ruled on the cases. Delayed structural reforms and a stagnant economy pressured the lev to 249 to the dollar on Wednesday, compared with around 70 in January.</p>
<p>Converting lev income into dollars has become the most widespread form of saving.</p>
<p>The IMF said economic growth would be achieved only if inflation was reduced to less than 50 percent a year. Bulgaria's nine-month cumulative inflation stood at 154 percent, topping its annual inflation target of 105 percent.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has forecast a 10 percent decline of gross domestic product (GDP) this year. GDP sank by 6.2 percent in the first six months. In a bid to stabilise the lev, the central bank raised the central interest rate to a record-high 300 percent in September. It is currently 180 percent.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
