<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169516" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Nov 7.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Nov 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Referring to the Treasury submission to the Wallis inquiry,</p>
<p>Insurance and Superannuation Commissioner George Pooley</p>
<p>yesterday defended the present approach to superannuation,</p>
<p>particularly the Superannuation Industry Supervision law, and</p>
<p>attacked the idea of moving away from prudential supervision as</p>
<p>&quot;fatally flawed&quot; and &quot;extreme or eccentric&quot;. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Retailers welcomed the Reserve Bank's decision to cut interest rates yesterday, but they called for banks to cut mortgage rates sooner than later to spark an improvement in sales in the lead-up to Christmas.  Retail Traders Association Victorian executive director, Ron Thomlinson, praised the cut for allowing customers to make a balanced decision on shopping activity over Christmas, but he criticised the Federal</p>
<p>Government for inactivity over its economic policy.  Page 5.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After Tabcorp Holdings Ltd's  TAB.AX computer system that links its betting agency network collapsed just three hours before the running of the Melbourne Cup on Tuesday, Tabcorp chief executive Ross Wilson announced yesterday a new A$10 million wagering computer system would be in place by mid-1998, with the first phase of the system - telephone betting - in place by early 1997.  Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Canadian media proprietor Conrad Black said yesterday after John Fairfax Holdings' annual meeting that if media ownership laws were relaxed he would like to buy up to 50 per cent of Fairfax and expand it beyond publishing into areas such as pay TV and free-to-air TV.  However, Black ruled out any offer from Kerry Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd</p>
<p>to merge with Fairfax.  Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>With submissions to the Federal Government's review of media ownership rules due by Monday, most of Australia's media owners are expected to join Conrad Black's push for changes to the rules.  However, Kerry Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd is expcted to move against any changes to foreign ownership rules which would allow foreigners to increase their presence in Australia and Black and News Corp's Rupert Murdoch</p>
<p>would object to a relaxation of cross-media rules if the limits on foreign ownership were maintained.   Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Contradicting the Australian Shareholders Association's claim that it has no plans to oppose the re-election of Coles Myer Ltd vice-chairman Solomon Lew as a director of the retailer's board, the Victorian branch of the ASA yesterday voted 60-40 to oppose Lew's re-election, following his involvement in the Yannon transaction and the resulting court battle. Page 26.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Woolworths Ltd managing director Reg Clairs said yesterday the effect of the latest rate cut on consumer confidence should be almost immediate, lifting sales of consumable goods in the crucial Christmas period.  Davids Ltd joint managing director John Patten agreed with Clairs, claiming the rate cut was not too late to boost Christmas turnover.  Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A report by consultants Allen Consulting and Arthur Andersen suggests Australia takes the competition in the Asia-Pacific region more seriously and commits to a more active marketing of its strengths, otherwise it risks becoming an &quot;also ran&quot; as a regiona financial centre.  The study, released by the Federal Government yesterday, claims Australia could generate wealth of about A$25 billion by taking the lead as a financial services market.  Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following in the footsteps of some European, US and Asian competitors, Air New Zealand warned yesterday that it may be forced to increase ticket prices early next year to combat rising jet-fuel prices.  Air New Zealand chairman Bob Matthew also told the anual meeting in Auckland that the airline's net profit for 1996-97 was unlikely to match last year's result of NZ$225 million.  Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Just days after Ampolex Ltd convertible noteholders rejected a scheme of arrangement by which Mobil Exploration &amp; Producing Australia Pty Ltd would have collected the outstanding 557,000 notes for A$7 each, US oil and gas giant Mobil Corp has raised its ofer to A$10 in a bid to finalise its A$1.8 billion takeover.  Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Responding to planned moves by Kerry Packer's Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd to launch a bid for John Fairfax Holdings Ltd if cross-media ownership rules are relaxed, Conrad Black said yesterday PBL would have to pay cash, not shares, to have any  </p>
<p>chance of acquiring Black's stake in Fairfax.   Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Without the one-off payments from the sale of its half-share in Ansett Airlines, TNT Ltd's consolidated profit sank from A$11.9 million to A$7.8 million.  Chairman of the transport group, Fred Millar, said the figures showed the company's turnaround plan as beginning to produce results and TNT would have continued its strategy if not for the KPN takeover bid. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Following the release of a report on Australia's financial market performance by Allen Consulting Group, which found that Australia is falling behind many Asian nations and will be overtaken by Malaysia, South Korea and Taiwan before 2000, Industry Minister John Moore has urged immediate action to keep Australia's standing in the international financial markets, claiming the nation could increase its wealth by A$25 billion if it took a leading role in becoming a regional financial centre. Page 25.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Despite warning he would quit his controlling stake in John Fairfax Holdings if he were banned from lifting the shareholding above 25 per cent, Canadian media proprietor Conrad Black says he is confident the Federal Government will consider raising the level of foreign ownership for the newspaper group, following a meeting with Prime Minister John Howard on Tuesday.  Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite slow economic conditions and a deep slump in the housing industry, Howard Smith chairman Frank Conroy told shareholders at yesterday's annual meeting that higher profits were expected this year.  Managing director Ken Moss  </p>
<p>said most divisions shoud produce profit growth this year, with the rail division set to produce a better result because of the National Rail Corp contract and BBC Hardware poised for increased profits on the back of the success of the superstores roll-out across the country.  Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>TNT chairman Fred Millar told shareholders at the group's annual general meeting yesterday the A$2 billion friendly takeover bid for TNT launched by Dutch post and telecommunications group KPN was likely to be successful.  In its last annual performance a a public company, TNT posted a 75  </p>
<p>per cent drop in net profit to A$9.8 million.  Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Property developer and hotel group Mirvac reported a 21 per cent rise in net profit to A$21.7 million for the year to June and told shareholders at yesterday's annual general meeting that it expected a rise in housing starts from 780 last year to 1,000 in1996-97.  Mirvac is also examining at least five joint projects with new major shareholder Lend Lease Corporation.   Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Insurance and superannuation commissioner George Pooley has attacked a Wallis inquiry submission by Treasury as being &quot;extreme&quot; and &quot;eccentric&quot;, claiming the proposal to remove the trustee system for supervising superannuation funds would lead to more, no less regulation in the form of tougher disclosure requirements, without the prudential safeguards which the current scheme offers.  Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank is unlikely to consider another interest rate cut this year, unless there is clear evidence that wage settlements have moderated and economic growth has gone well below the Government's 3.5 per cent forecast, according to Macquarie Bank eonomist Andrew Ticehurst. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Media proprietor Conrad Black conceded yesterday that he would sell his stake in John Fairfax Holdings if he was satisfied there was no chance of raising his shareholding above 25 per cent.  Next week, Fairfax is expected to report a first-quarter profit s much as 25 per cent below last year's  </p>
<p>A$33.77 million. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A majority of Victorian members who attended a regular meeting of the Australian Shareholders Association yesterday, voted against the Coles Myer boardroom deal that will see Solomon Lew re-elected as a director.  Despite the result of the informal vote, he ASA will not oppose Lew's re-election at Coles Myer's annual meeting in Sydney on 19 November. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A report by the Allen Consulting Group and Arthur Andersen reveals Australia has slipped to fourth behind Tokyo, Hong Kong and Singapore as a financial services centre and unless it moves quickly to create a more competitive tax environment and promote itelf as a leading regional centre for financial services, it will lose more ground.  Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Since subscribers paid A$1.90 a share for a piece of Australia's national airline, Qantas Airways shares have traded only marginally above their issue price and yesterday hit an all-time low of A$1.80.  The latest downturn comes despite the  </p>
<p>release of figres this week by the Government which show Qantas has increased its share of traffic into and out of Australia. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Marking a continuation of its overseas expansion, Lend Lease yesterday announced it was buying a 50 per cent interest in the King of Prussia shopping centre in Pennsylvania.  The &quot;supermall&quot; includes 450 specialty shops, 35 restaurants and nine departmentstores. Page C3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
