<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169551" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Costello says another rate cut possible.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Costello says another rate cut possible.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Treasurer Peter Costello said on Thursday there may be room for another interest rate cut if inflation and wages growth stayed low but he did not expect Wednesday's official interest rate cut to have an immediate effect on economic growth.</p>
<p>The growth rate of the Australian economy was extremely strong by world standards, he added.  </p>
<p>Costello said the Reserve Bank's decision to cut official rates to 6.5 percent from 7.0 percent was in response to low inflation and moderate wages growth.</p>
<p>&quot;And people know that if we can keep that inflation rate low and wages consistent with it, we've got room for further reductions,&quot; he said on Australian Broadcasting Corp radio.</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that will threaten this is inflation and wages,&quot; he said. However, he said he did not see an immediate impact on economic growth from the rate cut. &quot;I don't think it will make any immediate difference,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Over time, of course, you would expect that interest rate cuts would probably add to disposable income and therefore to demand,&quot; Costello said.</p>
<p>Asked if the rate cuts reflected a depressed economy, Costello said: &quot;Let me make the point, there's no depressed state of the economy. We're looking at growth rates which by world standards are extremely strong.&quot;</p>
<p>Wednesday's rate cut was the second since July, when the bank cut rates to 7.0 percent from 7.5 percent, the first reduction in three years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
