<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169643" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran, S.Korea to boost annual trade to $2 billion.</title>
<headline>Iran, S.Korea to boost annual trade to $2 billion.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran and South Korea agreed on Wednesday to boost their annual trade to $2 billion from $1.6 billion, the Iranian news agency IRNA said.</p>
<p>Under a letter of understanding signed in Tehran, Iran and South Korea agreed to raise bilateral trade to $2 billion by the end of the Iranian year ending on March 20, 1997 from $1.6 billion the previous year, it said.</p>
<p>Iranian Vice-President Hamid Mirzadeh said South Korea would boost oil imports from Iran and expand cooperation in energy, car-making, copper production, and shipbuilding, IRNA added.</p>
<p>South Korea's International Trade and Industry Minister Park Jae-yoon, quoted by the daily Tehran Times, said it was possible to reach a bilateral trade target of $4 billion by 2000.</p>
<p>He said trade was up 50.8 percent in the nine months to September over the same period last year, the paper added.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite American sanctions against Iran, South Korea is determined to expand relations with the Islamic Republic,&quot; Iranian television quoted Park as saying at the end of a meeting of the two countries' joint economic commission.</p>
<p>Total trade between South Korea and Iran, Seoul's third largest oil supplier, stood at $1.6 billion in 1995, of which nearly $1.3 billion were Iranian exports.</p>
<p>Park visited Iran to attend the first meeting of the economic commission held after a five-year lapse.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
