<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16968" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Tired Hindu pilgrims in Kashmir start heading home.</title>
<headline>Tired Hindu pilgrims in Kashmir start heading home.</headline>
<byline>Sheikh Mushtaq</byline>
<dateline>PAHALGAM, India 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Weary Hindus packed into hundreds of buses left a Himalayan town on Tuesday and headed home from a grim pilgrimage in which 128 people died.</p>
<p>But thousands lay exhausted in tents in meadows around Pahalgam, the base-camp for an arduous trek to a holy cave 3,880 metres (12,725 feet) high.</p>
<p>Authorities in India's Jammu and Kashmir state said 128 pilgrims making the trek to the Amarnath cave died in freezing cold that followed ferocious rains and snow last week.</p>
<p>Other sources including the Press Trust of India put the death toll at 160.</p>
<p>Some 112,000 Hindus came to Kashmir for this year's pilgrimage to the holy Amarnath cave, where devotees worship an ice stalagmite believed to be a manifestation of the &quot;lingam&quot;, or phallus, of the Hindu God Shiva.</p>
<p>Many naked &quot;sadhus&quot;, or Hindu holy men who smear their bodies with ash, were among the dead.</p>
<p>The federal government said on Tuesday it would order an inquiry into the deaths of the pilgrims after deputies belonging to the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party stormed out of parliament, accusing the government of incompetence, news agencies said.</p>
<p>Atal Bihari Vajpayee, the BJP leader, led the walkout after Home (Interior) Minister Indrajit Gupta told the lower house of parliament that arrangements for the annual Hindu pilgrimage had been largely adequate.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda said incessant rain on the pilgrims' route starting on August 21 made it humanly impossible to launch immediate relief and rescue operations.</p>
<p>Gupta said the government would launch an inquiry into the deaths.</p>
<p>&quot;It may not be a judicial inquiry,&quot; he said. &quot;The government will decide what kind of inquiry and its terms of reference.&quot;</p>
<p>About 65,000 pilgrims were marooned in Pahalgam for up to three days after heavy rains cut off roads. On Tuesday as the flood water receded, they started driving out.</p>
<p>&quot;About 700 buses filled with pilgrims have left Pahalgam for Jammu,&quot; K.B. Jandial, spokesman for Jammu and Kashmir state, told Reuters in the state's summer capital Srinagar.</p>
<p>The federal government has maintained direct rule over the state's affairs since a separatist rebellion in which hospital sources and police say more than 20,000 people have been killed erupted in 1990.</p>
<p>Military helicopters plucked more than 2,000 pilgrims from the mountainside on Sunday after the weather cleared for the first time in four days.</p>
<p>On Monday the helicopters dropped food, medicine and blankets to help some 300 people in a thickly forested part of the route near the frozen Sheshnag lake on the route.</p>
<p>&quot;Now there is no one left on the higher reaches of the trek,&quot; an official said.</p>
<p>The authorities cremated about 40 unclaimed bodies, officials said. Ninety were claimed by relatives.</p>
<p>Last year the pilgrims were threatened by Moslem separatist guerrillas, who staged two bomb attacks on the heavily guarded pilgrims. A state civil servant was killed in one of the blasts.</p>
<p>This year the guerrillas issued no ban on the pilgrimage. Instead, bad weather plagued the pilgrims.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PAHALGAM, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
