<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16966" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Deathtoll in Himalayan pilgrim tragedy hits 161.</title>
<headline>Deathtoll in Himalayan pilgrim tragedy hits 161.</headline>
<dateline>SRINAGAR 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian rescue teams on Tuesday found more bodies of Hindu pilgrims along the trail to a holy ice-cave in the Himalayas, raising the deathtoll from 128 to at least 161.</p>
<p>The government of Jammu and Kashmir state said in a statement: &quot;With the recovery of more dead bodies by the police patrol parties on the track, the death toll of the Amrnath tragedy has risen to 161.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;The patrol parties are searching the tracks to eliminate the chances of dead bodies of any pilgrims remaining there,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>Last week, bitter winds and heavy downpours lashed a 48-km (30-mile) Himalayan pilgrimage route, stranding almost 70,000 people on the mountainside for three days before help could be sent to them.</p>
<p>Some 112,000 Hindus came to Kashmir for this year's pilgrimage to the 3,880-metre-high (12,725 feet) Amarnath cave, where devotees worship an ice stalagmite believed to be a manifestation of the &quot;lingam&quot;, or phallus, of the Hindu God Shiva.</p>
<p>Soldiers and military helicopters were pressed into the rescue operation. Later, almost 60,000 people were stranded at Pahalgam, the base camp, after their ordeal because roads to the town were made impassable by floods. The floodwaters receded on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SRINAGAR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
