<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16963" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Bangladesh's Khaleda says Speaker is partisan.</title>
<headline>Bangladesh's Khaleda says Speaker is partisan.</headline>
<byline>Anis Ahmed</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladesh's main opposition leader Begum Khaleda Zia on Tuesday accused the Speaker of parliament of being partisan and the government of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina of plotting to eliminate opponents.</p>
<p>&quot;They are killing our people everywhere and forcing our supporters to run for life,&quot; Khaleda told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Such an administration and one-sided parliament cannot serve interest of the country and its people.&quot;</p>
<p>Khaleda threatened to boycott parliament unless the ruling Awami League stopped &quot;persecution&quot; of the members and supporters of her Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP).</p>
<p>Khaleda, who served as prime minister for five years until Hasina replaced her in a June general election, asked her followers to prepare for a &quot;movement&quot; against repression and misrule by Hasina's government.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not tolerate any injustice,&quot; said Khaleda, the current opposition leader in parliament.</p>
<p>Khaleda issued the first warning to boycott parliament on Monday, telling a public rally in the northern district of Bogra that her followers might boycott assembly sessions chaired by the &quot;partisan&quot; speaker.</p>
<p>&quot;The ruling Awami league is making parliament ineffective and the speaker is contributing to that by not allowing the opposition MPs enough time to speak,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She blamed the recent violence in Bogra, where four people have been killed by police, on the government, describing it as a &quot;pre-planned attack&quot;.</p>
<p>Hasina, speaking to a group of engineers in Dhaka on Monday, accused Khaleda's BNP of resorting to &quot;terrorism&quot; as part of its plan to create instability and chaos in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not desireable...and we will deal with such designs sternly,&quot; the prime minister said.</p>
<p>Speaker Humayun Rasheed Choudhury said he had received death threats from anonymous callers after opposition parties threatened to boycott proceedings chaired by him.</p>
<p>He told the Bengali newspaper Banglabazar Patrika that such threats were possibly coming from &quot;those who want to push the country into chaos and unrest&quot;.</p>
<p>The callers said his life could be cut short, the newspaper said. The speaker was not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Choudhury, a former foreign minister and veteran diplomat, was appointed speaker of the 330-member parliament on July 13, a month after general elections returned the Awami League of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina to power after 21 years.</p>
<p>Choudhury also was president of the 41st session of the U.N. General Assembly in 1986-87.</p>
<p>Awami legislators in parliament described the threat as a &quot;grave threat to democracy&quot; and urged all to remain alert against any move to thwart peace and stability.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
