<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169776" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: &quot;Medical Marijuana&quot; measure stirs heated reaction.</title>
<headline>&quot;Medical Marijuana&quot; measure stirs heated reaction.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Orr</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The passage of a California ballot measure legalising marijuana for medical purposes was hailed by supporters on Wednesday, but opponents were set for a court battle to block it.</p>
<p>Lawmakers preparing to challenge the measure in court said it could cause legal nightmares for doctors and those charged with upholding federal anti-drug laws that still ban marijuana for medical and recreational purposes.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to have a very confused legal situation here,&quot; California Attorney General Dan Lungren said. &quot;Now doctors are in a situation where if they recommend it they are going to be in violation of federal law. What if there is a 10- or 12-year-old who claims marijuana relieves stress? What if prisoners sue for their right to smoke it?&quot;</p>
<p>The controversial measure received 56 percent of the vote in California, a centre of the counter-culture revolution of the Sixties where many voters are middle-aged baby boomers who experimented with drugs in their youth.</p>
<p>Arizona voters approved a similar medical marijuana measure on Tuesday by nearly a two-to-one margin.</p>
<p>Under the California measure, doctors who recommend marijuana for a medical treatment and their patients who smoke as part of their treatment will be protected from prosecution.</p>
<p>But it does not say doctors may write prescriptions for marijuana since that would directly conflict with federal law. As a result, several legal questions remained over how it would be enforced.</p>
<p>&quot;We're calling it a medical necessity defence bill,&quot; explained Scott Imler, president of the Los Angeles Cannibas Buyers Club, which led the campaign to pass Proposition 215, &quot;The Medical Marijuana Initiative.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What it means is that if someone is arrested and their medicine seized and is taken to court, they can get the charges dropped as long as they can provide a written or oral recommendation from a doctor,&quot; Imler said.</p>
<p>He became involved in the movement after a ski accident left him with a seizure disorder and he found that marijuana alleviated his symptoms with fewer side effects than valium and other medication his doctors had prescribed.</p>
<p>He now admits to smoking pot in the morning, afternoon and before bedtime to ease his pain. But he played down suggestions from Lungren and some lawmakers that the measure would give rise to a host of abuses.</p>
<p>Most members of the Cannibas Buyers Club are AIDS sufferers, who have doctors notes suggesting they smoke pot for their pain. Other members suffer from illnesses such as multiple sclerosis, cancer, glaucoma and chronic migraine. The membership ranges in age from 21 to 87 years.</p>
<p>Despite some studies that show marijuana reduces pain and nausea, doctors were split on the California initiative and medical groups did not endorse it because of a lack of a conclusive study that it was safe and effective.</p>
<p>Some legal experts dismissed the problems with the new state law, noting that while technically it did conflict with federal law there was not likely to be a problem.</p>
<p>&quot;At the federal level, prosecutors are only interested in drugs if it's a planeload or a busload or some huge amount,&quot; law professor Peter Arenella said. &quot;Are they going to go after a little old lady who's using marijuana because she's suffering from cancer? I don't think so.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
