<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169883" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mo. voters say no to rainy day fund, sewer bonds.</title>
<headline>Mo. voters say no to rainy day fund, sewer bonds.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Missouri voters have apparently rejected proposed constitutional amendments to create a state rainy day fund and to allow municipalities to issue bonds to build sewer treatment plants.</p>
<p>According to preliminary results from Tuesday's election provided by the Missouri Secretary of State's office, the rainy day fund measure was losing 938,432 to 899,537.</p>
<p>The sewer bond amendment, which would have also removed water plants from regulation as public utilities, was losing 921,012 to 909,609, the office reported.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, two other proposed amendments appeared to be winning. One amendment to transfer $5.4 million from the general revenue fund to the Facilities Maintenance Reserve Fund for maintaining, repairing and renovating state facilities was ahead in the vote count 988,305 to 851,413, the office reported.</p>
<p>Another amendment apparently heading for a win called for the 10-year extension of a one-tenth of one percent sales and use tax for use by the Department of Natural Resources for soil and water conservation and for aquisition, development, maintenance and operation of state parks and historic sites. That measure was ahead 1,249,604 to 627,203, according to the office.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
