<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169870" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Midcontinent unleaded gasoline diffs firm.</title>
<headline>U.S. Midcontinent unleaded gasoline diffs firm.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Midcontinent spot unleaded gasoline differentials firmed in Chicago and Group Three Wednesday on strong demand, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's been unusually strong buying demand,&quot; one Group Three trader said, adding differentials in the Midwest were drawing support from rising prices on refined products being shipped to the East Coast.</p>
<p>Shell Oil Co said it expected today to restart a 20,000 barrel per day alkylation unit idled by a fire that cut feedstocks and steam to the unit at its 268,000 barrel per day Woods River, Ill., refinery.  </p>
<p>Shell said crude runs were trimmed &quot;minimally&quot; following the two-hour fire in a gas plant at the refinery, and the alkylation unit was undamaged.</p>
<p>The market received mixed signals from weekly stocks estimates, with gasoline and distillate inventories up compared to the prior week but still below last year's levels.</p>
<p>Chicago unleaded for prompt November deliveries firmed to 6.75/7.0 cents a gallon over NYMEX December unleaded, with later deliveries steady at 2.75/3.0 cents over the print and premium 3.50 cents higher, traders said.</p>
<p>Group Three unleaded made a similar upward move to bids 4.75 cents a gallon over the print for prompt deliveries and unchanged at 1.25 cent over for later deliveries. Premium was talked 3.0 cents higher.</p>
<p>High sulphur diesel for prompt deliveries was bid even with NYMEX December heating oil and 3.0 cents over the print in Group Three.</p>
<p>-- Houston Bureau 713 210-8508</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
