<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169843" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn ends firm on Sparks crop estimate.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn ends firm on Sparks crop estimate.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures closed firm on a bullish crop estimate by Memphis-based analytical firm Sparks Companies, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sparks was supportive and it's the first time in quite a while corn closed on the plus side,&quot; said Ron Kucha of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>Sparks Companies estimated the 1996 U.S. corn crop at 9.147 billion bushels and the market was expecting a figure closer to 9.3 billion, traders said.</p>
<p>USDA's October forecast was for 9.012 billion and Farmers Commodities Corp pegged the crop at 9.33 billion bushels.</p>
<p>The Leslie-ADM Elevator Survey is slated for release Friday morning and the government's November crop report is scheduled for release at 0730 CST Tuesday.</p>
<p>Support also came from signals the market was oversold for the near term. The daily nine day relative strength index (RSI) for December dropped to 10 points at Tuesday's close and Wednesday closed at 15. Traders view an RSI of 30 or less as an indication of an oversold market.</p>
<p>But long-term indicators remain bearish, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn closed unchanged to 1-1/2 cents per bushel higher, with December up 1-1/2 at $2.60.</p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated at 70,000 contracts, down from 89,736 Tuesday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In corn options, Smith Barney bought 650 December $3.20 puts at 59 to 59-1/4 cents, LIT America bought 800 December $2.50 puts at 1-1/2 cents and Term Commodities sold 500 December $2.60 puts at 4-3/4 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 26,000 contracts, down from 38,528 Tuesday.</p>
<p>Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
