<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169953" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Guerrillas slay 31 civilians in Algerian village.</title>
<headline>Guerrillas slay 31 civilians in Algerian village.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moslem fundamentalists slaughtered 31 people in an attack on an Algerian village between Tuesday night and Wednesday morning, Algerian security forces said.</p>
<p>A statement, carried by the official Algerian news agency APS, said the 31 had been &quot;assassinated in a cowardly way&quot; in what it described as &quot;this ignoble terrorist act&quot;.</p>
<p>The raid took place on Sid el Kebir, on the road to Chrea in Blida province, which lies some 50 km (30 miles) south of Algiers. The village is the site of a Zaouia -- a traditional religious centre of someone locally respected for piety or learning.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Mustapha Ben Mansour termed the attack, the second in three nights, one of &quot;ignoble savagery&quot;. In the last attack 13 people had their throats cut at the weekend.</p>
<p>Neither source gave details on the actual attack, but the phrase &quot;in a cowardly way&quot; has been used in Algeria to describe the cold-blooded killing of victims by cutting their throats.</p>
<p>Algeria uses the term &quot;terrorist&quot; to describe Moslem rebels who have been fighting since 1992 to topple the government.</p>
<p>Ben Mansour confirmed that the dead were civilians.</p>
<p>&quot;In targeting once again defenceless people, these criminals only confirm the baseness and unqualified cowardice which drives them in their determination to assassinate, without distinction and with ignoble savagery, peaceful citizens,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>He reiterated the government's determination, expressed frequently over the five years of violence in the North African country, to &quot;put an end to these criminals' activities with all the rigour of the law&quot;.</p>
<p>An estimated 50,000 people have been killed since violence erupted following the authorities' cancellation in January 1992 of a general election dominated by Islamic fundamentalists.</p>
<p>After a series of bloody bomb attacks in September and October, including bombs planted in local markets crowded just ahead of mass Friday prayers, the rebels appeared to have changed their tactics.</p>
<p>Last month the Islamists killed 34 people at a roadblock they mounted in the Sahara Desert province of Laghouat -- knifing them, cutting their throats or shooting them as they tried to flee.</p>
<p>Early on Sunday, 10 women and three children were killed, &quot;their throats cut, one by one&quot;, after they were herded into a bedroom in Douadoua village west of Algiers, according to the Algerian newspaper Liberte.</p>
<p>It was not known why the rebels chose a particular house or village, but they are known to target inviduals whom they suspect of links with the security authorities. And when the intended target was not available, relatives or neighbours have been killed apparently as warning.</p>
<p>In a chilling statement published last Sunday, Algeria's most ruthless Islamist movement, the Armed Islamic Group (GIA), dismissed Algerian outrage at the deaths of civilians, saying:</p>
<p>&quot;There are many religious proofs which make legitimate (our) bombing operations even when there are civilian victims.&quot;</p>
<p>The GIA leader Antar el Zouabri, quoted by the newspaper al Hayat, also said: &quot;The GIA forbids daughters and Moslem women to leave their homes uncovered (without Moslem dress). No work or studies for women; those who refuse to obey must be killed.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;Everyone must accomplish the prayer (duty) and those who refuse will be killed, murder being the punishment of apostates. All Algerians must pay zakat (tax, or alms) to the GIA and it is illegal to give it to apostates.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
