<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="169945" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Germany's Hoechst strategic overhaul plans lifts shares.</title>
<headline>Germany's Hoechst strategic overhaul plans lifts shares.</headline>
<byline>Svea Herbst-Bayliss</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Hoechst AG, Europe's largest chemicals and drugs company, on Wednesday announced plans for a big strategic overhaul and a U.S.share listing, a step which sent share prices to record highs.</p>
<p>The announcement helped offset reaction to weak nine-month earnings, which showed Hoechst, like its German rival Bayer AG on Tuesday, had largely fallen victim to sluggish economic conditions in Europe.</p>
<p>By turning itself into a strategic management holding group and splitting its operating business into legally independent units, Hoechst sought to magnify its growth potential.</p>
<p>&quot;We will become more transparent and increase the group's value,&quot; chief executive Juergen Dormann told a news conference, underlining the step's urgency by adding, &quot;Hoechst AG's operating business is doing poorly.&quot;</p>
<p>While Hoechst said its nine month operating profit surged 32 percent to 4.1 billion marks ($2.7 billion), the group explained the rise was largely due to lower restructuring costs and 750 million marks in extraordinary income from spin-offs. &quot;On a comparable basis, operating profit rose by four percent,&quot; Dormann said.</p>
<p>Similarly special factors also affected pre-tax profits, which surged 65 percent to 5.7 billion marks but climbed only one percent on a comparable basis.</p>
<p>Sales fell two percent to 38.4 billion marks in the first nine months, as weaker prices offset stronger volume sales. The weaker mark helped boost international sales.</p>
<p>&quot;Weak economic conditions, especially in Europe, really hurt us and it is hard to say when things will pick up again,&quot; board member Ernest Drew said.</p>
<p>For the full year Dormann said sales, forecast to be around 51 billion marks, will be two percent below 1995 levels while the underlying operating profit should be 10 percent higher.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Hoechst chief financial officer Klaus Schmieder said shareholders &quot;will not be disappointed by the 1996 dividend payout&quot; after the group paid 13 marks for 1995.</p>
<p>Delighted by the listing news, the market shrugged off the weak data and sent shares to an all time high of 60.25 marks during Frankfurt bourse dealings in high volume trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Strategically Hoechst is on the right track even though it still has lots of work to do on the operating side,&quot; said Ronald Koehler, analyst at BHF Bank in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>The pharmaceuticals and agriculture units performed well while inorganic chemicals performed unsatisfactorily.</p>
<p>The listing of Hoechst AG shares in  New York will not require a capital increase and the step will likely occur next autumn, Schmieder said, adding the shares will be turned into American Depository Receipts or ADRs.</p>
<p>The listing will leave Hoechst as one of very few German companies listed in the U.S. following Daimler-Benz AG, the group's former unit SGL Carbon AG and Deutsche Telekom AG.</p>
<p>Schmieder said decisions on the flotations of other Hoechst businesses, including the strongly rumoured listing of the drugs unit Hoechst Marion Roussel (HMR), have not been taken.</p>
<p>Dormann also said the group will likely not buy back its own shares once German laws allow such a step and instead use the funds for more innovative activities.</p>
<p>Meanwhile Hoechst is also considering forming additional joint ventures or selling off certain units which are currently not performing well.</p>
<p>Part of planned changes are beefing up Asian business where Hoechst hopes to generate 20 percent of its sales by the year 2000, investing 2.5 billion marks in China, India and Asia. ($1=1.5217 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
