<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="16999" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Delhi stocks bounce back in hectic trade.</title>
<headline>Delhi stocks bounce back in hectic trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Delhi stock prices, mainly in A-group shares, bounced back in hectic trading as domestic financial institutions made massive purchases followed by heavy short covering by bear operators, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Delhi Stock Exchange sensitive index recovered 1.94 points to close at 797.94 points.</p>
<p>Activity in the latter half of the session was driven by the market's anticipation that the finance ministry might announce concessions in the Minimum Alternate Tax proposal on zero-tax paying companies before the budget gets parliamentary approval, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said shares of the Oriental Bank of Commerce remained the centre of brisk activity mainly on increased buying by financial institutions in the counter for the second straight session, mostly on the company's strong fundamentals.</p>
<p>&quot;The recovery was mainly attributed to speculative buying by major players who re-entered the ring after remaining on the sidelines,&quot; said Harish Malhotra of brokers Malhotra Financial Investments.</p>
<p>Reliance Industries ended 0.35 rupees down at 209.10 while TISCO gained 1.30 rupees at 189.95 on alternate bouts of buying and selling.</p>
<p>Oriental Bank of Commerce rose 2.55 rupees to 89.75 on mutual funds buying. State Bank of India quoted 1.10 rupees higher at 267.70.</p>
<p>TELCO closed 6.50 rupees higher at 498. ACC ended 23 rupees higher at 2,125 on heavy buying by financial institutions.</p>
<p>ITC rose two rupees to 285.50 on buying support from foreign institutional investors. Larsen and Toubro closed 2.85 rupees up at 252.35.</p>
<p>-- New Delhi newsroom +91-11-301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
