<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170071" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>VATICAN: Vatican says new openness with Cuba must continue.</title>
<headline>Vatican says new openness with Cuba must continue.</headline>
<dateline>VATICAN CITY 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Vatican's foreign minister, Jean-Louis Tauran, said on Wednesday a new-found openness with Cuba should continue and the Pope may soon be able to consider visiting the Communist-ruled island.</p>
<p>Tauran, who travelled to Cuba last month, told Vatican Radio that meetings he held with President Fidel Castro and Church officials proved &quot;that a dialogue exists, that the authorities want to continue this dialogue&quot;.</p>
<p>Castro is widely expected to meet Pope John Paul when he visits Rome for next week's U.N.-sponsored World Food Summit but Tauran said Cuba had not yet officially requested an audience. The summit runs from November 13 to 17.</p>
<p>Tauran said during his visit that the &quot;so longed-for visit&quot; by the Pope to Cuba would be a new departure point on the road towards normalised relations between the Roman Catholic Church and the communist state.</p>
<p>Cuba is the only Spanish-speaking country in Latin America which the Pontiff has not visited, but Tauran told Vatican Radio he was reminded during his visit that an invitation from the government in 1989 was still valid &quot;and one could soon think of (making) the necessary preparations&quot;.</p>
<p>He said preparations were in the hands of other Church officials, who would &quot;continue the dialogue&quot;, but he had no further details.</p>
<p>Tauran said Cuba's Marxist ideology, which does not recognise Christmas as a religious festival, limited the Church's freedom and place in mass-media, role in education and materials to print and disseminate religious documents.</p>
<p>&quot;All these are problems to resolve but dialogue exists, it must continue, and I hope the climate of cordiality, I would say, of comprehension, which marked my visit, will encourage a positive development for the solution of problems which are still outstanding,&quot; Tauran said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VATICAN CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VATICAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
