<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170055" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French CDR representatives quit AOM board.</title>
<headline>French CDR representatives quit AOM board.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Representatives of the French state rescue vehicle disposing of assets belonging to troubled bank Credit Lyonnais have resigned from the board of French domestic airline AOM, a spokesman for AOM said.</p>
<p>The rescue vehicle, Consortium de Realisation (CDR), would not comment on the resignation.</p>
<p>AOM is one of the assets belonging to Credit Lyonnais that CDR is seeking to sell. AOM has announced a general meeting for November 25 to establish a new board of directors.</p>
<p>Christian Blanc, chairman of state-owned French flag carrier Air France, said last week his company would &quot;certainly look into the question&quot; of buying AOM to counter British Airway's ambitions in France.</p>
<p>AOM has some 12 percent of the French domestic market.</p>
<p>In an interview with the French newspaper Le Figaro on Wednesday, junior transport Anne-Marie Idrac said a takeover of AOM by Air France would be impossible until March 1997 in light of commitments by the state airline to secure its financial recovery. She was referring to conditions attached to an aid package for Air France.</p>
<p>Beyond that date, she said, &quot;the question has not been studied. It would require some reflection. But why not?&quot;</p>
<p>AOM had been expected to be sold before the spring when further liberalisation of air travel is due.</p>
<p>British Airways this week cleared an important hurdle in its bid to take over Air Liberte, the independent French carrier, in conjunction with the Rivaud banking group.</p>
<p>A French court ruled that Air Liberte need not be wound down, effectively clearing the way for British Airways to present its takeover offer to Air Liberte creditors, although court officials said other offers could in theory still be made.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
