<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170078" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: FEATURE-Spain enlists Chirac in EMU drive.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Spain enlists Chirac in EMU drive.</headline>
<byline>Sharman Esarey</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar appears to have won over French President Jacques Chirac as a powerful new ally in his bid to portray Spain as a more credible contender for a single currency then fellow southerner Italy.</p>
<p>Chirac capped a two-day Franco-Spanish summit on Tuesday with a ringing endorsement of Spain's chances to join the launch of Europeana Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) in 1999.</p>
<p>But he was far more circumspect on the outlook for Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no doubt as regards Spain. Italy has expressed the same desire. We can only rejoice at that,&quot; Chirac told an Italian reporter when asked about Rome's chances.</p>
<p>SPAIN TO BE JUDGED ON OWN MERIT</p>
<p>This terse distinction -- a bombshell in diplomatic wrapping -- revealed what looks like a new willingness within Europe's core to judge Spain on its own merits, rather than throwing it into the same pot with the other so-called &quot;Club-Med&quot; nations.</p>
<p>Up until now, analysts had been convinced that Spain's single-currency hopes hinged as much on the ability of the more economically powerful Italy to make the grade as they did on its own performance.</p>
<p>Politically, they argued, the cost would be too high to exclude the big power but let in the little one -- even though Spain had worked feverishly to clean up its economic house and many economists feel it has tidied it up sufficiently.</p>
<p>Chirac's comment signalled he at least was prepared to differentiate between the two and lend his support to Aznar's political emphasis on EU states' individual merits.</p>
<p>&quot;Every country needs to make the effort to ensure it reaches the goal at the assigned date,&quot; Aznar told reporters at a joint news conference. &quot;I've told President Chirac of Spain's absolute determination to participate in EMU from the first moment.&quot;</p>
<p>Spain's resolute pursuit of its European goal, and the apparently wide-reaching and largely unquestioning support from its population for the plan, has long bemused other EU politicians with more recalcitrant citizens.</p>
<p>EMU MEMBERSHIP WOULD RAISE SPANISH PROFILE</p>
<p>For Spain, the value of Europe's single-currency project clearly transcends any immediate benefits it could bring to a nation suffering from an unemployment rate of more than 20 percent -- the highest in Europe.</p>
<p>The main attraction appears to lie instead in confirming Spain's place in the mainstream of Europe after decades at its fringes under the rule of fascist dictator Francisco Franco.</p>
<p>It means the coming of age of the fragile democracy that was put in place at his death in 1975.</p>
<p>It also means pushing back the borders of Europe to the Mediterranean again, rewriting the embittered Spanish anecdote that &quot;Africa begins at the Pyrenees.&quot;</p>
<p>And it means laying to rest--once and for all--the demeaning tourist slogan from the Franco years: &quot;Spain is different.&quot;</p>
<p>As a result, Chirac's new welcoming tone worked like a tonic, lending Spanish financial markets support.</p>
<p>&quot;The summit seems to have been set to support Spain,&quot; said Alfredo Urrutia, chief economist at Societe Generale in Madrid. &quot;The comments are most welcome.&quot;</p>
<p>For years, the political question on Spain's EMU fitness had not arisen as the country struggled to make the required progress on the convergence criteria of inflation, interest rates, public deficit, debt and currency stability.</p>
<p>But as Aznar's minority conservative Popular Party government came into power this spring, ending 13 years of Socialist rule, the pieces of the economic puzzle started to fall into place.</p>
<p>FINANCIAL MARKETS RALLYING</p>
<p>Financial markets, convinced the fledgling government would stand by its promises to shape up Spain's flabby finances, began to rally.</p>
<p>The peseta, victim of a series of devaluations until March 1995, stabilised near 84.00 per mark at the end of last year as the Popular Party's electoral chances appeared to improve.</p>
<p>Spain's stock market Ibex index of 35 leading shares began to climb in late October 1995 and has shot up some 36 percent since.</p>
<p>Even more dramatic, the diffence in yield between Spanish bonds and their sturdier German counterparts narrowed sharply -- suggesting that the extra risk in holding Spanish debt no longer warranted such a premium.</p>
<p>The spread has shrunk to 164 basis points from 330 at the start of March or from 500 in the summer of 1995.</p>
<p>Inflation also has declined steadily.</p>
<p>Finally, at the end of September, the government delivered an austere 1997 budget draft that would cut the public-sector deficit to three percent of gross domestic product from the 4.4 percent projected for this year and 6.6 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>The Bank of Spain backed the draft for 1997 -- the year when Spain and all the other EU states will be examined for EMU participation -- with its sixth official interest rate reduction of the year.</p>
<p>Flush with confidence, Aznar then said: &quot;There is no-one who now doubts that we will be in.&quot;</p>
<p>But until now, the fight to win recognition for Spanish sweat and toil had proved tougher than that.</p>
<p>Just a day before Chirac's vote of confidence, Madrid's demand for recognition turned strident in frustration.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Abel Matutes warned Spain's European partners that should they overlook any French shortcomings to let Paris join a single currency, it would accept no less than the same treatment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
