<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170033" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FOCUS-Swedbank confirms sector strength.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Swedbank confirms sector strength.</headline>
<byline>Trevor Datson</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's Swedbank rounded off the nine-month reporting season for the country's big four commercial banks on Wednesday, posting a strong improvement in earnings as loan losses fell by almost a third.</p>
<p>Swedbank's operating profit for the first three quarters came in at 3.82 billion crowns ($576.5 million), a 23 percent rise over the same 1995 period.</p>
<p>Much of the improvement was the results of a sharp decline in credit losses, which fell to 1.31 billion crowns from 1.80 billion in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>Underlying earnings were weaker, however. Profit before credit losses improved just over four percent to 5.12 billion crowns, largely thanks to higher income from investment banking operations.</p>
<p>Costs net of commission income rose 35 percent to 1.93 billion crowns, and financial transactions contributed 889 million crowns to group income.</p>
<p>Total costs rose a modest three percent to 6.60 billion crowns, much of which was due to an 11 percent rise in administrative expenses to 2.52 billion.</p>
<p>The bank's board said it would pay a five crowns per share dividend for 1996, corresponding to a total dividend payment of 1.39 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Commenting on the result, group CEO Reinhold Geijer said he was pleased with the stability of Swedbank's recent performance.</p>
<p>&quot;I am especially happy about the increase in commission income, and that we as a savings bank are so successful in the area of savings, where (Swedbank's fund manager) Robur has increased its market share substantially this year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In fact, Swedbank's 23 percent profit rise was by no means the best of the bunch. S-E-Banken's earnings were more than doubled to 4.42 billion crowns from the 2.06 billion reported for the same period last year.</p>
<p>Topping the earnings league in absolute terms was Nordbanken, whose operating profit increased by 13 percent to 5.74 billion crowns from 5.09 billion in the 1995 period.</p>
<p>Nordbanken has had the considerable advantage of having most of its loan losses removed in a rescue package that brought the state-owned bank back from the brink of disaster after the finance crash of the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Handelsbanken, which did not have the benefit of state support, posted a 19 percent increase in profits to 4.52 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Common to the improved fortunes of the four this year has been a normalisation of loan losses, which have returned to levels of around 0.6 percent of total lending.</p>
<p>A change in the statute books last year gave the banks approval to spin off their property units, unwillingly inflated by real estate taken over as collateral during the finance crash, without any unpleasant tax consequences.</p>
<p>Income has improved too, with all the banks noting higher earnings from lending as market interest rates have fallen steadily through the year.</p>
<p>As short rates have fallen further than long rates, the banks have been able to finance long-term lending with cheaper borrowing at the short end of the market.</p>
<p>Firmly back on their feet, the Swedish banks have limited room for improvement.</p>
<p>Cost levels have always been low in an international perspective, and with competition from niche banks hotting up, the only fast track to higher profits would seem to be expansion by acquisition.</p>
<p>And with cash assets in the system running at an all-time high, a shake-out in the industry may not be long in coming. ($1=6.626 Swedish Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
