<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17006" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Swiss Holderbank finally wins Sri Lanka cement plant.</title>
<headline>Swiss Holderbank finally wins Sri Lanka cement plant.</headline>
<byline>Prithi Kodagoda</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss firm Holderbank Financiere Glarus Ltd has agreed to take over Puttalam Cement Co, Sri Lanka's only integrated cement manufacturer, Puttalam chairman Manilal Fernando said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Analysts said the takeover was expected to end a legal battle among major Puttalam shareholders selling their holdings to the Swiss firm.</p>
<p>Holderbank, one of the world's leading cement manufacturers, had agreed to buy shares totalling 87.5 percent of Puttalam Cement's issued capital, Fernando said.</p>
<p>&quot;Holderbank will buy all these shares for a realistic price based on their 1993 bid price,&quot; Fernando said in an interview. The purchase would be completed by the end of this week.</p>
<p>&quot;Holderbank will also spend about $25 million on expansions and improvements in the next 18 months,&quot; said Fernando.</p>
<p>Puttalam was privatised in December 1993 when the government sold a 90 percent stake to a consortium of investors led by the Tawakkal Group of Pakistan for 2.03 billion rupees. ($37 million).</p>
<p>The Tawakkal Group has agreed to sell all of its 34 percent stake in Puttalam to Holderbank, which is also buying 48.5 percent of Puttalam from a group of Hong Kong investors and five percent from Sri Lanka's investment bank Vanik Incorporation, Fernando said.</p>
<p>Tawakkal and the Hong Kong investors have been involved in a controversy after the securities watchdog said their consortium violated domestic law banning leveraged buyouts.</p>
<p>The consortium had paid only 1.13 billion rupees in cash when it took over 90 percent of Puttalam and the rest in debentures issued by using the company's assets as collateral.</p>
<p>The Hong Kong investors accused the Tawakkal Group of poor management, leading to court cases being filed in Colombo.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Hong Kong) investors have filed five cases against the Tawakkal Group. The Tawakkal Group has filed two in return,&quot; said Fernando.</p>
<p>But once Holderbank buys out from both factions and redeems debentures, the cases will be withdrawn, he added.</p>
<p>Holderbank, which has more than 70 integrated cement plants and about 20 grinding units worldwide, was unsuccessful in its takeover bid in 1993 when it wanted to buy at around 1.2 billion rupees.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite it being three years since they first showed interest, Holderbank still sees Sri Lanka as a good investment station,&quot; Fernando said.</p>
<p>Nandakumar Nair, director of research at brokerage John Keells, said the Swiss company's takeover would end the controversy that &quot;left a bad taste in the mouth of many foreign investors and cast a pall of gloom over the general climate&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is good to see it being resolved,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Puttalam, which has 1,400 employees, supplies about 40 percent of Sri Lanka's monthly requirement of cement of 150,000 tonnes. ($=55 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
