<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170025" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch closing share market report.</title>
<headline>Dutch closing share market report.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares finished firm, but off their early peaks, after a U.S. election result widely perceived as favourable for world bourses, dealers said.</p>
<p>The AEX index spiked higher at the open before retracing a little in lively trade as players digested President Clinton's win and the Republicans' maintenance of control in Congress and the Senate.</p>
<p>Retailer Ahold extended its good run since announcing a large Brazilian joint venture on Monday, breaking well above its year high of 105.00 guilders at one stage before settling to finish at 104.90, up 1.40 guilders on the day.  </p>
<p>Trading group Hagemeyer also rallied strongly on news it would buy the remaining 50 percent of its Hong Kong-based joint venture HCL. It will issue 3.38 million new shares and pay 70 million guilders to fund the takeover.</p>
<p>The company said the full impact of the move would be seen from 1997 and it would have a positive effect on the its future earnings per share.</p>
<p>The transaction is expected to boost Hagemeyer's turnover by about 650 million guilders.</p>
<p>Hagermeyer shares gained 4.20 guilders to 134.20 at the close.  </p>
<p>Chemicals firm Akzo-Nobel dropped 2.30 guilders to 215.30 after it reported flat third quarter net profits and said it expected full-year profits to be flat as well. Analysts' opinions on the results ranged from slightly disappointing to mildly positive.</p>
<p>Unilever also lost ground after some analysts trimmed their earnings estimates ahead of what is expected to be a weak set of third quarter results on Friday.</p>
<p>Unilever certificates fell 2.50 guilders to 258.70.</p>
<p>Dutch airline KLM suffered after a minor rally on Tuesday after its results, shedding 2.10 guilders to 41.70.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
