<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170193" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan purges bureaucrats, denies Bhutto arrest.</title>
<headline>Pakistan purges bureaucrats, denies Bhutto arrest.</headline>
<byline>Alistair Lyon</byline>
<dateline>ISLAMABAD 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's new caretaker government purged the bureaucracy of senior officials but its lawyers denied on Wednesday the administration had placed sacked prime minister Benazir Bhutto under house arrest.</p>
<p>Interim Prime Minister Meraj Khalid and his nine ministers were set to hold their first cabinet meeting on Wednesday, a day after the president abruptly dismissed his former ally, Bhutto, on charges of corruption and misrule.</p>
<p>Bhutto, sacked for the second time in her turbulent political career, remained a virtual prisoner in her official Islamabad residence, but had been allowed to meet colleagues and take telephone calls, a government official said.</p>
<p>Lawyers for the caretaker government told a court on Wednesday Bhutto was not under arrest, saying she was under police protection for her personal safety.</p>
<p>They asked the court in Rawalpindi, near Islamabad, to reject a habeas corpus petition filed on Tuesday by lawyers for former defence minister Aftab Shaaban Meerani, pleading that Bhutto had been &quot;held unlawfully incommunicado&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is vehemently denied that the former Prime Minister is under arrest,&quot; they said. &quot;(A) Police contingent is deployed for (the) personal safety of the former Prime Minister.&quot;</p>
<p>The court was then adjourned.</p>
<p>He said Bhutto's husband, Asif Ali Zardari, had been flown to Rawalpindi, near Islamabad, late on Tuesday from Lahore, where he had been detained soon after President Farooq Leghari dissmissed Bhutto's government in the early hours of Tuesday.</p>
<p>Officials said on Wednesday the caretaker government had sacked many senior bureaucrats linked to Bhutto, including top economic advisers V.A. Jafarey and Shahid Hasan Khan.</p>
<p>Three more ministers were due on Wednesday to join the interim administration, expected to rule until elections Leghari has ordered for February 3. They had failed to reach the capital Islamabad in time for the main oath-taking ceremony.</p>
<p>Opposition to Bhutto's downfall has been muted. Her Pakistan People's Party (PPP) said its leaders would meet on Wednesday to discuss what it called &quot;the unconstitutional dismissal of the elected government in the darkness of night&quot;.</p>
<p>Police detained 10 activists from a score of PPP supporters who protested on Wednesday along the main Jinnah Avenue in the capital against Bhutto's dismissal.</p>
<p>One protester waved a PPP flag and others carried placards saying Bhutto was still the country's prime minister.</p>
<p>Bhutto's dramatic sacking was greeted warmly by most Pakistanis and calmly overseas, but newspapers in neighbouring India raised the possibility of regional instabilty.</p>
<p>&quot;While there is no reason why India should not respond, it would be well advised not to automatically assume that a change of guard in Pakistan must necessarily improve bilateral relations,&quot; the Hindustan Times said in a Wednesday editorial.</p>
<p>The United States said on Tuesday the sacking appeared to be constitutional, and it joined most other countries in expressing hopes for continued good relations with Pakistan.</p>
<p>&quot;The dismissal of the government appears to be in accordance with the Pakistan constitution,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns told reporters in Washington.</p>
<p>The local stock market opened more than one percent higher, bolstered by bullish sentiment over the political situation.</p>
<p>&quot;Bhutto's government had an anti-business image. The change has therefore been considered positive,&quot; Khalid Hussain of National Investment and Finance Services said.</p>
<p>Leghari has sought to reassure foreign investors, saying in a televised speech on Tuesday the new government must honour a recent accord with the International Monetary Fund for the revival of a $600 million loan.</p>
<p>The loan aims to plug a financing gap and put Pakistan's wobbly economy back on course.</p>
<p>A visiting IMF team said it would carry on with talks to clinch the loan despite Bhutto's dismissal but cautioned the deal could be delayed by the change in government or any sign of failure to meet stringent economic targets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISLAMABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
