<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17023" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India Ambuja sees profits staying strong.</title>
<headline>India Ambuja sees profits staying strong.</headline>
<byline>Shyam Kumar</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian cement maker Gujarat Ambuja announced a strong annual profits performance on Tuesday and scoffed at suggestions that oversupply could slow growth in coming years.</p>
<p>The company said after-tax profits rose 47 percent to 1.48 billion rupees ($41.46 million) in the year which ended on June 30, and raised its dividend to 5.0 rupees per share from 4.0 rupees the previous year.</p>
<p>&quot;With increased production from its cement plants and firm cement prices, the company is expected to do well during the current year,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>But a cement analyst at the Bombay office of a foreign securities firm said he did not think Gujarat Ambuja could maintain its profit growth in 1996/97.</p>
<p>He said a cement surplus in northern India and large capacity additions by Larsen &amp; Toubro and others in western India, Ambuja's major markets, would lead to oversupply that would slow down its profit growth.</p>
<p>But Anil Singhvi, Gujarat Ambuja's treasurer, said he did not agree with those who forecast an oversupply in cement.</p>
<p>&quot;There won't be any surplus in 1996/97,&quot; Singhvi told Reuters. &quot;It would be an equally good year if not better.&quot;</p>
<p>Some analysts said the firm's profit outlook was somewhat exaggerated because it did not take account of a 15 percent corporate tax known as the minimum alternate tax (MAT) announced by the government in its July 1996 budget.</p>
<p>But Singhvi said MAT was yet to be approved by the parliament, which is debating the budget.</p>
<p>Gujarat Ambuja's fourth cement plant is expected to be commissioned in December 1996, taking its total capacity to 4.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The company sold 3.1 million tonnes of cement during the year ended June 30, 1996, compared to 2.0 million tonnes during the previous business year.</p>
<p>The high market capitalisation and liquidity of Gujarat Ambuja was recognised by the recent inclusion of its shares in the revamped benchmark 30-share sensitive (sensex) index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE).</p>
<p>It is the youngest of the 30 BSE Sensex firms.</p>
<p>The Indian cement industry has been enjoying strong demand, fuelled by robust growth in the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth momentum of 1995/96 continues during the current year also and the first quarter growth of 14 percent which is the highest ever growth achieved by the industry,&quot; the Gujarat Ambuja statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cement demand will continue to grow at more than 8.0 percent, aided by strong GDP growth,&quot; said B. Shashikanth, cement analyst at securities firm Peregrine Capital in Bombay.</p>
<p>He said Gujarat Ambuja was India's lowest-cost cement producer. &quot;This partly stems from its internal efficiencies, as well as quality limestone deposits, which provide cheaper conversion costs,&quot; he said in a June cement sector report.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
