<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170338" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Royal Oak revalues assets, sees charges.</title>
<headline>Royal Oak revalues assets, sees charges.</headline>
<dateline>KIRKLAND, WASHINGTON 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Royal Oak Mines Inc said Wednesday it will close down its gold mine in Hope Brook, Newfoundland, and decrease the carrying value of its Colomac gold mine in the Northwest Territories.</p>
<p>Royal Oak expects to take C$37.4 million in charges because of the Hope Brook and Colomac decisions. After tax, the charges will amount to a decrease in net income of about C$27 million or C$0.19 a share in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>The Hope Brook mine has provided positive cash flow to Royal Oak but it believes &quot;a positive contribution by itself does not justify continuing to operate a mine.&quot;  </p>
<p>The company will move most of the mining and milling assets from Hope Brook to its Matachewan project in Northern Ontario and discontinue production in the third quarter of 1997, Royal Oak said.</p>
<p>Matachewan is expected to begin production in the second half of 1998.</p>
<p>The company said it will save about C$23 million by using Hope Brook assets.</p>
<p>At the Colomac mine, the company said it has decreased its mineable ore reserves by 253,000 ounces.  </p>
<p>The company's readjusted proven and probable reserves at Colomac and the nearby Kim-Cass project were about 358,000 ounces as of end-September this year.</p>
<p>The mine has produced lower grade ore in 1996, leading to cash costs of US$369 an ounce. The company said it expects costs to continue at this level.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still on target to become a senior-tier gold producer at an average cash cost of under US$230 an ounce -- well below the industry average -- by the year 2000,&quot; Royal Oak president Peggy Witte said in a statement.</p>
<p>She said the company started out by building an asset base by acquiring under-performing and inactive mines and turning them into profitable projects.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been very successful, but are now entering a new phase of our growth, based on the development of large, long-life, low-cost gold mines,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIRKLAND, WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
