<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170350" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Grossman's sees more charges in Q4.</title>
<headline>Grossman's sees more charges in Q4.</headline>
<dateline>CANTON, Mass. 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grossman's Inc said Wednesday it will take additional charges in the fourth quarter due to the more aggressive approach to selling the remaining eastern properties, headquarters moving costs and further corporate staff reductions.</p>
<p>The company also said it hired TM Capital Corp, a New York City investment bankers and financial advisors, last week to assist in forming strategies and capital generation options.</p>
<p>&quot;By September 1997, we intend to relocate our headquarters to California or Ohio to allow us to manage more efficiently the company's growth,&quot; chief executive Robert Swanson said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We will also seek shareholder approval at our September Annual Meeting to change the company's name and trading symbol.&quot;</p>
<p>Noting the meeting was also held during the third quarter this year, Swanson said he hoped next year's would be at the company's new headquarters.</p>
<p>Grossman's said it also retained Joanne Ralston &amp; Associates Inc, a Scottsdale, Ariz., based investor and public relations firm. &quot;We intend to be more open in our communications with employees, lenders, vendors, shareholders and investors,&quot; Swanson explained.  </p>
<p>The company Wednesday reported its first profitable quarter in a year, saying it earned $0.05 per share in the third quarter on sales from continuing operations of $96.0 million, up 6.1 percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>This compares with net income of $0.59 per share, in last year's third quarter when there was an $18.1 million gain on the sale of the company's former headquarters and establishment of a $4.5 million reserve for store closing expenses.</p>
<p>&quot;To date, we have sold 26 of our 55 properties, generating net proceeds of about $22 million, which has been used to pay down the original $33 million mortgage debt,&quot; Swanson said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are aggressively marketing the remaining properties and hope to pay off our remaining mortgage debt during the first quarter of 1997,&quot; he said.  &quot;Once this debt is repaid, further proceeds will be retained by the company.&quot;</p>
<p>Grossman's operates 42 retail stores - 16 Contractors' Warehouse facilities in California, Indiana, Kentucky, Nevada and Ohio, and 26 Grossman's Mr. 2nd's Bargain Outlets in Massachusetts, New York and Rhode Island.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANTON, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
