<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170536" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Forex markets upbeat on U.S. elections.</title>
<headline>Forex markets upbeat on U.S. elections.</headline>
<byline>Julia Meehan</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign exchange markets on Wednesday cheered the return of President Bill Clinton to the White House but were clearly relieved his hands, to some extent, will be tied by a Republican Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets are breathing a whole sigh of relief...Clinton has retained the White House and the Republicans have retained their grip on the House (of Representatives),&quot; David Brown, chief economist at Bear Stearns said.</p>
<p>The dollar moved higher against the mark and yen in early Europe, but had lost some of its momentum by midday.  </p>
<p>At 1128 GMT dollar/yen was at 113.99/4.09 against 114.20/25 in late Europe and off a session high of 114.67 hit in early Europe, on some light profittaking.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark had lost some of its momentum by midday but still held above the 1.52 level. Dollar/mark stood at 1.5208/13 against 1.5195/05 but off a session high of 1.5267.</p>
<p>Analysts said the dollar should remain underpinned.</p>
<p>&quot;Markets believe Clinton will keep a tight rein on the Republican tax cutting agenda, while the Republican Congress will operate to keep his spending priorities in check,&quot; Tim Fox, treasury economist at Standard Chartered Bank said.  </p>
<p>While analysts are betting that Clinton's last term will hearald a continuation of growth with low inflation, some fear the post election cheer could be short-lived with a question mark hanging over the strength of the dollar.</p>
<p>Ahead of the election the U.S. had a clear interest in a firm dollar policy to keep asset markets underpinned.</p>
<p>But some analysts fear that could change.</p>
<p>&quot;(Treasury Secretary Robert) Rubin is the big architect of the strong dollar policy and if he were to leave that would leave a gap...And the markets would become nervous about that,&quot; said Fox.  </p>
<p>If the Democrats had won the House of Representatives there would have been increased pressure for a change of dollar policy, analysts said.</p>
<p>Bu already U.S. car makers have sought to address the problem of the firmer dollar with the government.</p>
<p>&quot;On the dollar side, you can be a bit nervous on the slant policy might take,&quot; Fox added.</p>
<p>&quot;If the U.S. economy slows down and the auto-makers start to hit difficulty they will start to demand a softer dollar,&quot; said Gerard Lyons, chief economist at DKB International.  </p>
<p>And the short-term dollar's performance very much depends on the U.S. bond market reaction and at present it looks like it will take the result well. Given recent firmness it may well yet</p>
<p>&quot;The result of the election has unleashed a big welter of buying. Not only on the forex side but also on the bond side,&quot; said Bear Stearn's Brown.</p>
<p>&quot;The markets are reassured that policy will remain unchanged. There should be no change in currency policy, no change in tight fiscal policy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>--London newsroom +4471 542 6701</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
