<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170547" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK car registrations rise, post best-ever October.</title>
<headline>UK car registrations rise, post best-ever October.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>New car registrations in Britain jumped to 154,733 cars in October, up 13.3 percent compared with the year-ago period, the Society of Motor Manufacturers and Traders (SMMT) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The SMMT said the result was the highest October total on record, and that private sales, during the month of the high-profile UK Motor Show, had been especially strong.</p>
<p>&quot;Particularly encouraging was a rise in private retail registrations of 21.02 percent (in October). This compared with a fleet and business sector rise of just 7.48 percent,&quot; the car retailers group said in a statement.</p>
<p>So far this year the trade has reported two contrary trends, with private registrations generally soft and the fleet market generally strong, which have kept overall sales fairly flat.</p>
<p>Including today's data, the cumulative registrations for the 10 months of the year so far show an increase on last year of 4.7 percent, at just over 1.81 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
