<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170601" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Solidere shares change little despite GDR news.</title>
<headline>Solidere shares change little despite GDR news.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Solidere shares and changed little on Wednesday despite news that the company began marketing Global Depository Receipts (GDRs) worth $115-$125 million for issue on November 26.</p>
<p>A shares closed unchanged at $114 on the Beirut Stock Exchange and B shares fell slightly to $117.625 from $117.750 on Tuesday. They had dropped briefly to $113.5 and $117 respectively on Wednesday's 0800 GMT fixing.</p>
<p>&quot;So far the GDR news have not affected the real market. We will be watching prices closely at the end of this week and the beginning of next week. By then people will be better informed on the issue,&quot; a BSE official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Market sources on Tuesday said that Solidere was making an international offering of 10 million GDRs for an issue size of $125 million.</p>
<p>&quot;News of the GDR issue have not spread yet. Dealers are still informing their clients. I think we should wait before making any statement on how the issue affected the shares prices,&quot; a dealer told Reuters.</p>
<p>Turnover in Solidere shares fell to 6,167 shares from 10,684 on Tuesday and value was $710,811.75 from $1,225,938.</p>
<p>The market sources said each GDR would be worth one tenth of one of Solidere's shares. The price range on the GDRs was $11.5 to $12.5 for an issue price of $115-$125 million, the added.</p>
<p>A Solidere executive questioned by Reuters on the report declined to comment.</p>
<p>The issue is lead managed by Merrill Lynch International, with a selling syndicate formed by ING Barings, Robert Fleming and Co, Paribas Capital Markets and UBS Ltd and roadshows will take place in the United States, Europe and elsewhere, a source said.</p>
<p>There was no trade in the four other companies listed on the BSE: Ciments Libanais, Ciments Blancs, Eternit and Uniceramic.</p>
<p>The LISPI stock index fell 0.02 percent to 84.57 and the BLOM stock index also fell 0.05 percent to 984.38.</p>
<p>-Beirut editorial (9611) 353078 645456 602057</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
