<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170625" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Medical marijuana measure passes in California.</title>
<headline>Medical marijuana measure passes in California.</headline>
<byline>Adam Entous</byline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A California ballot initiative to legalise the use of marijuana by the sick won the support of voters on Tuesday despite warnings from opponents that it could undermine the fight against drugs.</p>
<p>California's Proposition 215, &quot;The Medical Marijuana Initiative,&quot; was one of the most closely watched ballot measures in the nation, drawing support from George Soros, the billionaire financier, and fire from President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>The measure had the support of about 56 percent of voters versus 44 percent against, with nearly 60 percent of electoral precincts reporting, state election officials said.</p>
<p>The measure would allow sick people and their &quot;primary caregiver&quot; to legally possess and grow marijuana for medical use when recommended by a doctor.</p>
<p>Supporters said marijuana often eased nausea in cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy, reduced the pain of AIDS patients and lowered eye pressure in glaucoma sufferers.</p>
<p>Opponents, who included many state law enforcement officials, said the proposal was an attempt to legalise marijuana through the back door.</p>
<p>Clinton's drug policy chief, retired Gen. Barry McCaffrey, denounced the proposition as a &quot;hoax&quot; and said the federal government would prosecute doctors who prescribed marijuana.</p>
<p>Doctors were split on the issue due in part to a lack of conclusive studies to prove whether marijuana was safe and effective as a medicine.</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, supporters of Proposition 215 were so confident of victory that they started celebrating at a &quot;Pot Luck&quot; party even before the polls closed in California.</p>
<p>The &quot;Yes on 215&quot; group had advertised their gathering well in advance, and police were on hand. An officer wrote a citation for at least one partygoer and confiscated a small amount of marijuana, but no arrests were made.</p>
<p>Emboldened by their victory, supporters of the measure said they would pursue similar efforts in other states.</p>
<p>During the high-profile campaign, proponents of the measure argued that thousands of ill Californians already used marijuana despite the law and that the initiative would give them a legal defence if they were arrested. Non-medicinal use of marijuana would still be illegal, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;This bill was designed for people who use marijuana for legitimate medical purposes and we intend to see that it is implemented in that manner,&quot; said Scott Imler, one of the authors for the measure. He added that he expected the controversial initiative to survive any court challenge.</p>
<p>Opponents of the initiative had warned that it would create legal loopholes to protect drug dealers from prosecution. They said it was so loosely worded that headaches, an upset stomach or a stiff neck could be cited as reasons for its use.</p>
<p>Clinton and three former U.S. presidents took stands against the proposal, while California Gov. Pete Wilson warned it would send the wrong message in the fight against illegal drugs and could conflict with federal law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
