<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170640" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Perot vows to keep pressure on Clinton, Congress.</title>
<headline>Perot vows to keep pressure on Clinton, Congress.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reform Party candidate Ross Perot shrugged off his crushing defeat in the U.S. presidential race on Tuesday and vowed to &quot;climb back in the ring&quot; to force the main parties into balancing the budget and passing campaign finance reform.</p>
<p>As early results and television projections showed Perot with less than 10 percent support across the country, the feisty Texas billionaire urged his Reform Party supporters to keep the faith.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to keep the pressure on,&quot; Perot told hundreds of disappointed supporters in downtown Dallas on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>Democrat Bill Clinton swept to victory in the presidential race over Republican Bob Dole, riding an upbeat economy to win four more years in the White House.</p>
<p>Perot said the Reform Party had forced the issues of campaign finance reform and the need for a balanced budget onto the national agenda and would not allow the Democratic and Republican parties to sweep them under the carpet.</p>
<p>Both major parties have in recent weeks called for a sweeping review of campaign reform, including an end to political contributions from foreigners.</p>
<p>Perot said he would back President Clinton and Congress &quot;all the way&quot; if they push through the reforms he has campaigned for.</p>
<p>&quot;But it must be done right. No shams, no whitewash. Lets get it done right,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear what Perot planned to do with his fledgling Reform Party although senior aides said it would continue its work of building a viable third party alternative to the Democrats and Republicans.</p>
<p>&quot;Take a little break and then we'll climb back in the ring and keep the pressure on to see that everybody keeps their promises,&quot; Perot said to thunderous applause from his party faithful.</p>
<p>Perot won 19 percent of the popular vote in his independent bid for the White House in 1992 but he failed to inspire angry or independent voters this time around.</p>
<p>The Reform Party had hoped Perot would score at least 25 percent of the vote, qualifying it as a major party and guaranteeing it would receive federal funds equal to those given to the Republicans and Democrats in the next presidential election.</p>
<p>As it is, Perot succeeded only in scoring the five percent needed to guarantee the Reform Party federal funding at levels proportional to its share of the vote.</p>
<p>He appeared irrelevant for much of the presidential campaign but won some attention towards the end, when Clinton came under fire for allowing allegedly improper fundraising by the Democratic Party from Asian business interests.</p>
<p>Perot seized the opportunity and launched a series of blistering attacks on the president's integrity.</p>
<p>He said Clinton would, if re-elected, be hit by criminal charges that would push the country into a Watergate-like constitutional crisis.</p>
<p>But the allegations did not bring a surge in support and Perot failed to threaten Clinton or Republican challenger Dole in any U.S. state.</p>
<p>Perot spent about $70 million of his own money in his 1992 White House bid but this year opted to accept $29.2 million of federal funds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
