<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170791" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR - World market for November 5, 1996.</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London ended slightly easier but off their lows ahead of the December expiry. Most active December shed 70 cents to close at $307.00, while March was down 40 cents at $305.10.</p>
<p>End user demand remains slack in spite of the recent fall in world market prices. Big buyers like Russia and China remained absent.</p>
<p>In New York raw sugar futures ended nearly unchanged. Front month March shed 2 points to close at 10.33 cents while May added 2 points to close at 10.44 cents. The outer months ended flat to 1 point higher. There was no fresh news to give the market direction.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>UKRAINE - At the beginning of November sugar beet production in the Ukraine reached 21.81 million tonnes down from 30.65 million tonnes the same date last year. The area harvested was 1.0 million ha compared to 1.37 million ha 1995. Beet yields per ha declined to 19.7 tonnes down from 22.3 tonnes last year.</p>
<p>Sugar production at the beginning of October stood at 1.3 million tonnes, white value, down from 1.9 million tonnes in 1995. Beet sugar production in 1996/97 is officially estimated at 2.8 million tonnes compared to 3.49 million tonnes in 1995/96.</p>
<p>INDIA - According to the Centre for Monitoring the Indian Economy (CMIE) sugar production in 1996/97 could be around 15 million tonnes, white value, which compares to industry estimates of 16 million tonnes and last years production of 16.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>In its October review of the Indian economy released recently, the Bombay-based independent think-tank said the projected fall in sugar production in 1996/97 was mainly due to a 3.0 per cent decline in sugar cane output during the year. However, it was pointed out that estimated production this season will still be 1 million tonnes above consumption of around 14.0 million tonnes.</p>
<p>EUROPE - Rainfall remained near normal across northern Europe during the week ending November 5. Rain amounts were generally between 6-25 mm. Harvesting progress is a little slower than normal. The production outlook remains largely unchanged, although slight upward revisions cannot be excluded.</p>
<p>Sugar beet areas in the former Soviet Union received near normal rainfall with rain amounts between 6-25 mm. The harvest is nearly three quarters complete which is slightly behind normal. Normal progress is expected for next week as mild temperatures will favor harvesting operations.</p>
<p>GERMANY - Sugar production in the 1996 campaign is still racing ahead of last year due to an excellent sugar content. The amount of beet processed in the week ended November 1 amounted to 2.21 million tonnes down from last year's 2.34 million tonnes.</p>
<p>This brought the cumulative amount of beets processed up to 12.34 million tonnes against 12.02 million tonnes in the like period the previous year.</p>
<p>Sugar content rose to an excellent 18.02 per cent sharply up on the 16.69 per cent in the like period the previous year and the 16.93 per cent in 1994. This resulted in a sugar production of 359,263 tonnes, raw value, up on last year's 347,796 tonnes and the 1994 result of 357,109 tonnes.</p>
<p>Cumulative production so far in the 1996 campaign reached 2.06 million tonnes against 1.84 million tonnes in 1995 and 1.89 million tonnes in 1994. At 26.43 million tonnes the estimate for the overall beet harvest remained unchanged but is considerably up on the actual total of 1995/96 of 26.05 million tonnes.</p>
<p>FIJI - Sugar output in 1996/97 (May/April) will amount to 475,600 tonnes raw value, up from last year's 472,998 tonnes, industry sources recently said. Even though higher than 1995/96, the result will still be down on the record output of 1994/95 when production hit 537,676 tonnes.</p>
<p>Molasses output will be slightly lower than last year at 172,500 tonnes against 181,348 tonnes in 1995/96, but up on the 1994/95 result of 154,692 tonnes.</p>
<p>Sugar consumption will decrease slightly to 45,000 tonnes against 46,639 tonnes in 1995/96 and 43,111 tonnes in 1994/95.</p>
<p>TENDERS</p>
<p>Syria's General Foreign Trade Organization for Chemicals and Foodstuffs (GEZA) has issued a tender to buy 13,000 tonnes of white sugar and 13,000 tonnes of raws for shipment between December 20, 1996 and January 20, 1997. November 27 is the final date to receive price offers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
