<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="170924" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Greenpeace vows new action against US soy ships.</title>
<headline>Greenpeace vows new action against US soy ships.</headline>
<byline>Vera Eckert</byline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greenpeace environmentalists have threatened to mount new protests around Europe's ports in a campaign against imports of American soybeans that have been genetically altered.</p>
<p>Besides Hamburg where one ship docked on Tuesday, Rotterdam, Ghent and Antwerp expect cargoes of new crop US soybeans in coming days.</p>
<p>Greenpeace's barge Beluga and dingies late on Tuesday picketed the freighter Ideal Progress as it sailed up a stormswept River Elbe to Hamburg with 44,600 tonnes of US beans for German processor Oelmuehle Hamburg (Oelag) aboard.</p>
<p>Protestors used slide projectors to emblazon its hull with slogans such as &quot;We are not your guinea pigs&quot;.</p>
<p>But German police stopped them from trying to prevent the vessel from docking.</p>
<p>Soya is used in some form or another in about 30,000 foodstuffs including margarine, chocolate and mayonnaise.</p>
<p>Genetically-changed beans now make up one to two percent of the US crop and Greenpeace said it was likely that some were aboard Ideal Progress, which left New Orleans 20 days ago.</p>
<p>Its cargo will take two days to be sucked into silos. The processed soy oil and meal will leave Oelag from November 10.</p>
<p>Health anxieties about biotechnology are most acute in Germany, where Greenpeace has gathered 120,000 signatories on a consumer petition against modified soybeans.</p>
<p>Developed by U.S. chemicals giant Monsanto Co, the soybeans have been altered to resist widely-used Roundup weedkiller.</p>
<p>Campaigners want crushers to segregate these beans and the food industry either to boycott them or at least to label products that might be derived from them.</p>
<p>US consumer activist Jeremy Rifkin, who seeks a world boycott of genetically-altered grain, arrived in Germany on Tuesday to declare that &quot;this global boycott will not go away.&quot;</p>
<p>He said brokers in the U.S. Midwest were already negotiating contracts for a gene-free supply with European processors who did not want Monsanto soy and an initial cargo would sail from Duluth, Minn. in the United States on Tuesday or Wednesday.</p>
<p>Some leading firms, including the German unit of Anglo-Dutch Unilever, have said they will not sell products with oils from modified beans because of the consumer anxiety although they consider the beans safe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
