<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171068" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian markets lag HK, Singapore - report.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian markets lag HK, Singapore - report.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's financial markets have failed to challenge Hong Kong and Singapore for regional leadership and may fall further behind as those competitors gain strength, the Australian government was told on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are increasingly at risk of losing some of our present ground as our competitors extend their self-reinforcing lead in the critical area of financial market depth, liquidity and maturity, or indeed to new competitors,&quot; a government task force reported to Industry Minister John Moore.  </p>
<p>Australia's loss of market share was not simply a result of faster economic growth in the two Asian tiger economies.</p>
<p>&quot;It traces more fundamentally to a lack of competitiveness extending across a range of key areas,&quot; said the report, prepared by the private Allen Consultancy Group on behalf of the government task force, the Financial Services Steering Group.</p>
<p>&quot;Australia lags well behind both Hong Kong and Singapore in derivatives, foreign exchange, cash management, settlements (and) back office (work), and corporate banking.&quot;  </p>
<p>Hong Kong had a competitive advantage over both Australia and Singapore in portfolio management, retail funds management, equity issues, equities trading, advisory functions and research on listed companies.</p>
<p>Australia's financial markets, centred in Melbourne and especially Sydney, were more competitive than Hong Kong's and Singapore's only in the areas of debt issues and fixed-interest securities.</p>
<p>Moore, who created the task force after the Liberal-National government won office in March, said the report confirmed his fears.  </p>
<p>&quot;The key findings of the report reinforce the concerns about Australia which were expressed by this government before coming to office,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>But the markets themselves blamed government policies.</p>
<p>&quot;The successful growth of the Australian financial markets following deregulation in the 1980s is now jepardised by an outdated tax regime and government lethargy,&quot; said Robert Webster, executive director of the International Banks and Securities Association of Australia.</p>
<p>The report estimated that about 100,000 Australians worked in the country's international financial markets.  </p>
<p>Australia would lift its gross domestic product by A$4 billion to $5 billion (US$3.2 billion to $4.0 billion) if its financial sector could catch up with Hong Kong, it said.</p>
<p>But chasing the leaders was not a take-it-or-leave-it option -- Australia had to sink or swim.</p>
<p>&quot;The ground that we presently hold is itself at risk -- for example, because technology contineus to advance the internationalisation of financial markets even in areas regarded as essentially domestic,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Moore said the report would be an important input into the current inquiry into Australian financial market deregulation, the first to be conducted since an early 1980s inquiry that resulted in the sector being deregulated and opened to the world.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
