<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171037" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Welsh county votes on right to have &quot;wet&quot; Sundays.</title>
<headline>Welsh county votes on right to have &quot;wet&quot; Sundays.</headline>
<dateline>PORTHMADOG, Wales 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Voters in this closely knit Welsh village go to the polls on Wednesday to decide whether drinkers should be allowed to enjoy a pint of beer at their favourite pub on a Sunday.</p>
<p>Porthmadog and several other communities on the windswept LLeyn pennisula, a finger of land jutting out from western Wales, have been &quot;dry&quot; on Sundays since 1881 because of an act of the British parliament in London 250 miles (400 km) away.</p>
<p>The electorate is expected to overwhelmingly vote in favour of permitting pubs and hotels to serve alcohol on the Sabbath.</p>
<p>&quot;There is little doubt that the vote will be in favour of allowing people to enjoy a drink on a Sunday,&quot; David Baird-Murray, chairman of pressure group, the Seven Day Opening Council, said.&quot;This is about having a choice.&quot;</p>
<p>Since parliament passed the Sunday Closing Wales Act in 1881, it has been illegal to sell alcohol in around 70 &quot;licensed&quot; premises in the area on a Sunday. Supermarkets are also not allowed to sell alcohol and hotels cannot serve even a glass of wine with a meal.</p>
<p>For 80 years pubs in all of Wales were shut on Sunday but in 1961 the Welsh were given the opportunity to vote, county by county, on whether to repeal the law in their local communties.</p>
<p>There have been five such ballots since 1961, and one by one, Welsh counties voted to go wet -- with the exception of the Lleyn pennisula, which now is the only area in all of Europe where pubs must stay shut on Sundays.</p>
<p>Because of electoral boundary changes, the Llyen pennisula has been incorporated into a larger new county called Gwynedd. In past ballots, the majority of the Gwynedd electorate have voted in favour of Sunday drinking, Baird-Murray said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORTHMADOG, Wales"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
