<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171097" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Cavalier sees steady full year result.</title>
<headline>Cavalier sees steady full year result.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Textile group Cavalier Corporation Ltd said on Wednesday it expected its full-year result to be similar to the $10.3 million net profit it reported for the year to June 30, 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;All in all, I think a full year result similar to last year is the most likely outcome,&quot; Managing Director Alan James told the annual meeting. He said high interest rates and a slowdown in the New Zealand market were still hurting Cavalier's carpet business and it was feeling the pain from a strong New Zealand dollar, which was encouraging imports and offsetting its strong performance in Australia.  </p>
<p>High interest rates and the strong currency were also negatives in the wool business.</p>
<p>&quot;Given how negative these macro economic factors are for us at present, we should probably be forecasting a further profit downturn for this year,&quot; James said.</p>
<p>&quot;But on the positive side we have the first full year's contribution from our wool procurement business to look forward to. And our ongoing commitment to continous improvement will bring further gains.&quot;  </p>
<p>James said Cavalier was so far tracking about the same as last year &quot;and we are a little cautious about the rest of the year&quot;. He said the key issues were the fragile carpet market in New Zealand and the cross rate with the Australian dollar.</p>
<p>Cavalier earlier announced an unchanged interim dividend of six cents per share.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
