<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171073" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australia, NZ wool sales to China grow - IWS.</title>
<headline>Australia, NZ wool sales to China grow - IWS.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's imports of Australian and New Zealand wool rose by 12 percent and 13 percent respectively in the first eight months of 1996 compared with the same period of 1995, despite an overall 14 percent fall in wool imports, the International Wool Secretariat (IWS) said.</p>
<p>The import decline reflected slowing retail growth, declining export demand for Chinese textiles and clothing, very strong competition on the domestic market from synthetic fibre imports, a tight cash flow position in state-owned mills, as well as a drying up of raw wool supplies from the CIS (former Soviet Union), IWS said.  </p>
<p>It also appeared there were ample supplies of wool and textile products in China, it said in its monthly market briefing.</p>
<p>Possibly as much as 40 percent of China's current year domestic clip remained unsold, with this wool moving slowly at prices 30 percent-50 percent lower than a year ago, it said.</p>
<p>Recovery in the wool textile industries of Japan, South Korea and Taiwan was slower than expected but firm ordering was expected in the December quarter, it said.  </p>
<p>Signs of improving conditions were emerging in Western Europe but high levels of yarn stocks remained to be cleared and production levels were still subdued, it said.</p>
<p>Continued improvements in ordering should enable further reductions in stocks in Western Europe this quarter, although market activity was yet to respond, IWS said.</p>
<p>On Australian sales, IWS said excess supply and patchy demand dampened auction prices.</p>
<p>Greasy wool sale volume in September and early October was 34 percent up on a year ago with cash-strapped growers less prepared to hold wool from the market, it said.  </p>
<p>Raw wool demand would not respond decisively to improving orders until stocks, most notably yarn in western Europe, cleared, IWS said.</p>
<p>IWS also said CIS wool production in 1996 was now expected to be even lower than first thought, with sheep numbers continuing to fall in response to low wool prices.</p>
<p>Total CIS production was expected to fall by 22 percent to 100 million kg clean in 1996, almost 60 percent lower than in 1990.</p>
<p>The previous estimate for 1996 was 109 million kg.  </p>
<p>Total raw wool exports by the CIS in the six months to June fell by 82 percent to 13.5 million kg clean, with exports to China down 91 percent and exports to the European Union down by 75 percent, it said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
