<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171197" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai T-bill repo rates, spots end mixed.</title>
<headline>Shanghai T-bill repo rates, spots end mixed.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Contracts on the treasury bill repurchase market in Shanghai closed mixed on Wednesday, with falling domestic stock markets in Shanghai and Shenzhen dampening sentiment on the repo market, traders said.</p>
<p>The annual rate for the most active seven-day contracts closed down at 10.00 percent from 11.00 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Turnover fell to nearly 5.9 million lots from 6.34 million. One lot is 1,000 yuan face value of treasury bills.</p>
<p>&quot;The repo market has been less active since late last week when the A markets began to fall,&quot; said a trader. &quot;Its short-term trend will continue to be linked to the A market performance.&quot;  </p>
<p>Contracts on the T-bill spot market in Shanghai ended mixed in slow trading, with most investors taking a wait-and-see attitude, waiting for a new listing later this month, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active 10-year bond that matures in June 2006 fell slightly to 122.70 yuan from 122.76 yuan.</p>
<p>Combined volume of the eight-contract market rose slightly to 1.20 million lots from 919,228 lots.</p>
<p>China's first seven-year bond is now being issued and will be listed on the market on November 21. Traders said its movement after the listing would affect prices of existing contracts.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
