<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171306" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul shrs end sharply higher, index up 1.85 pct.</title>
<headline>Seoul shrs end sharply higher, index up 1.85 pct.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares rallied to a sharply higher close Wednesday on a mixture of bargain hunting and hopes that the government would support the bourse, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite stock index rose 13.59 points, or 1.85 percent, to a provisional close of 747.24. Volume was active, with 31.5 million shares changing hands.  </p>
<p>The market fell to three-year lows on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has fallen so much so quickly,&quot; said Rhee Joo-ik of Daewoo Securities. &quot;Another important factor is that the government is showing signs of boosting the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Advancing shares beat decliners 756 to 155, with 84 unchanged.</p>
<p>The market was boosted by news that the Korea Securities Financing Corp would give brokerages 200 billion won for additional margin loans. Also helpful were reports that the finance ministry was considering raising the Korea Fund's capital to $580 million in the first quarter in 1997.  </p>
<p>But fears about rising margin loans, oversupply of shares and anti-corruption probes continued to haunt the bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;We see more selling pressure emerging,&quot; said a Dongsuh Securities broker. &quot;The index is expected to decline and move between 680 and 720.&quot;</p>
<p>Rumours that domestic houses had informally agreed to maintain buying positions was another boosting factor. But the Korea Securities Dealers Association denied the rumours.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if that is true, I don't think the houses would keep the promise,&quot; said the Dongsuh broker. &quot;That's a gentlemen's agreement, and there are no gentlemen in this industry.&quot;  </p>
<p>Margin loans are at record levels, nearing three trillion won. Between 500-900 billion won worth of the loans will have to be repaid this month, brokers said.</p>
<p>Customer deposits, on the other hand, have declined to around 2.5 trillion, and new stock supply in November is estimated at more than 1.1 trillion won, they added.</p>
<p>Brokers said that there was no impact seen on the Seoul bourse from U.S. President Bill Clinton's reelection. &quot;This was as had been expected,&quot; the Dongsuh broker said.  </p>
<p>Construction shares attracted attention on expectations of large infrastructure projects next year. LG Construction gained 400 won to 16,200. Il Sung Construction rose 500 won to 9,890.</p>
<p>Blue chips also saw favour. Samsung Electronics rose 2,300 won to 63,000 and LG Electronics gained 400 won to 13,500.</p>
<p>The Korea Stock Exchange later revised the closing index to 747.29, up 13.64 points or 1.86 percent on the day.</p>
<p>The December futures contract closed up 2.15 points to 80.65, while the KOSPI 200 index gained 1.54 points to 78.47.</p>
<p>--KATHERINE BRUCE (822) 727 5644</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
