<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171408" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan traders may re-export Thai rubber to China.</title>
<headline>Japan traders may re-export Thai rubber to China.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some Japanese traders are considering re-exporting around 1,000 tonnes of Thai benchmark Ribbed Smoked Sheet (RSS3) to China in an attempt to reduce bumper rubber stocks here, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;One trade house in Japan, which took around 500 tonnes of rubber at the October spot expiry, was believed to have sold the rubber to China,&quot; one market source said.</p>
<p>The trade house is likely to sell an additional 500 tonnes to China after November's spot expiry later this month.</p>
<p>Japanese traders said re-exporting was profitable due to lower prices for rubber here relative to those in producing countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the fact domestic rubber prices are currently lower by about 17-18 yen per kg compared with those in Thailand, re-exporting can be profitable despite the high export costs,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said more Japanese traders may be trying to intentionally cut bumper rubber stocks in Japan in an attempt to prop up the market.  </p>
<p>Japanese rubber stocks at designated warehouses totalled 47,520 tonnes as of October 20, the highest level since September 1990, the Rubber Trade Association of Japan said.</p>
<p>The high rubber stocks have cast a shadow on domestic rubber futures markets in recent months.</p>
<p>Since the benchmark rubber contract on the Tokyo Commodity Exchange (TOCOM) hit 166.90 yen per kg at the end of last May, the market has been in a downward trend.</p>
<p>The benchmark hit this year's low of 131.10 yen on October 7. The current benchmark April contract on TOCOM ended the morning session at 142.7 yen on Wednesday. -- Tokyo Commodity Desk +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
