<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171486" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>YEMEN: Britain to boost trade links with Yemen-Rifkind.</title>
<headline>Britain to boost trade links with Yemen-Rifkind.</headline>
<dateline>SANAA 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain plans to boost its trade relations with Yemen whose economy is moving in the right direction, British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Rifkind said more British cabinet ministers will be visiting Yemen to look into ways to improving trade between the two countries.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential is quite substantial given that this is a country of 16 million people...It is a poor country but its economy is firmly moving in the market economy direction,&quot; Rifkind told reporters.</p>
<p>He was speaking after talks with President Ali Abdullah Saleh and before flying home at the end of a Middle East tour.</p>
<p>Yemen's economy, hit by a brief civil war in 1994, is slowly improving under IMF-agreed economic reforms.</p>
<p>British officials, who see Yemen as a potential future market for British firms, said Britain was Yemen's second largest trading partner in terms of imports after the United States.</p>
<p>Rifkind had arrived in Yemen on Tuesday on the last leg of his tour during which he launched the idea of a new Middle East body designed to encourage regional cooperation and prevent escalation of conflicts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANAA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YEMEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
