<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171573" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bankgesellschaft sees '96 trading profit.</title>
<headline>Bankgesellschaft sees '96 trading profit.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Bankgesellschaft Berlin AG said on Wednesday that it expected its earnings improvement to continue in the final months of 1996 after narrowing its own account trading loss by the nine month stage.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the improvements in income to continue their positive development in the remaining months of the fiscal year,&quot; Bankgesellschaft said in an interim report.</p>
<p>The bank forecast a return to an own account trading profit for the full year after posting a trading loss of 56 million marks in the first nine months. At the half year stage, the bank had a trading loss of 110 million marks.</p>
<p>The bank said the loss was linked to writedowns on equity derivatives in the first half, which had been offset by interest income.  </p>
<p>The bank reported a 35.3 percent drop in operating profit after risk provisions to 465 million marks in the first nine months.</p>
<p>Risk provisions rose to 612 million marks in the first nine months, up from 542 million marks in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Bankgesellschaft said earnings remained under pressure from the continued need for high risk provisions caused by the difficult economic situation in its home region of Berlin and Brandenburg.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate the need to maintain high risk provisions to remain high,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>Bankgesellschaft noted that the nine-month fall in operating earnings marked an improvement from the half-year stage when profit had fallen 39 percent.</p>
<p>Operating profit before risk provisions was down 14.6 percent at 1.08 billion marks at the nine-month stage, the bank said.</p>
<p>--David Crossland, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
