<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171604" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Rushdie row rocks Danish government.</title>
<headline>Rushdie row rocks Danish government.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Denmark's minority government faced threats of a vote of no confidence after it admitted bungling a decision to postpone a visit by British author Salman Rushdie on security grounds.</p>
<p>But it looked likely to survive after left-wing parties holding crucial seats in the 179-seat parliament said they were reluctant to bring down the centre-left coalition although they wanted more than its offer of a commission of enquiry.</p>
<p>&quot;The affair must not under any circumstances be swept under the carpet,&quot; Socialist People's Party leader Holger. K. Nielsen said after Prime Minister Poul Nyrup Rasmussen made a contrite appearance before parliament's foreign affairs committee.</p>
<p>Pressure has been mounting since the government last week barred Rushdie from coming to Copenhagen to collect a European literary prize, on security grounds.</p>
<p>Rushdie has lived in hiding and under guard since 1989 when Iranian revolutionary leader Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini issued a fatwa or death sentence against him for his novel &quot;The Satanic Verses&quot;, saying it blasphemed against Islam.</p>
<p>Denmark initially said that advance publication of plans for Rushdie to attend a November 14 awards ceremony in Copenhagen, and police resources already strained by a long-running war between rival motorcycle gangs, put the writer at serious risk.</p>
<p>The entry ban brought howls of outrage from intellectuals at home and abroad and angry denunciation by Rushdie himself of what he called the government's cowardice.</p>
<p>Speaking to parliament on Tuesday Rasmussen admitted that a letter to Rushdie conveying the ban was poorly drafted and should have been personally delivered with a verbal explanation.</p>
<p>The mechanism of government, he said, malfunctioned at several points in the affair. &quot;There were a number of situations where the chain fell off,&quot; Rasmussen said.</p>
<p>Last week's public apology from the prime minister and a hasty offer to set a new date for Rushdie to receive his award in Copenhagen -- this year's European Culture Capital -- appeared to mollify the Indian-born writer.</p>
<p>But the Danish media continue to pillory Rasmussen and senior ministers daily while political foes bay for his blood.</p>
<p>Weekend cartoons showed the premier, Foreign Minister Niels Helveg Petersen and Justice Minister Bjoern Westh shooting themselves in the foot and by Tuesday Rasmussen was caricatured as telling aides to find him a bulletproof sock.</p>
<p>The right-wing opposition seized the moment and on Tuesday evening were holding meetings to gauge support for a vote to topple him. &quot;I believe that a vote of no confidence can win a majority,&quot; Danish People's Party leader Pia Kjrsgaard said.</p>
<p>The main opposition Liberals and the somewhat smaller Conservative party said they would decide whether or not to launch an assault after further talks this week.</p>
<p>The coalition can count on 76 votes from its own party members while the right is reasonably sure of 83. That leaves the 20 votes of the Socialist People's Party, the Unity List and independent Jacob Haugaard controlling the government's fate.</p>
<p>Logically the leftist fringe appears unlikely to open the door to a right-wing takeover, but its leaders have voiced deep dissatisfaction with Rasmussen's explanations so far of how decisions on the Rushdie affair were reached.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
