<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171612" id="root" date="1996-11-06" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Frankfurt bourse jumps higher after Clinton win.</title>
<headline>Frankfurt bourse jumps higher after Clinton win.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Frankfurt bourse opened sharply higher on Wednesday after Bill Clinton held onto the U.S. Presidency and the Republicans maintained control of Congress, a combination markets saw as optimal.</p>
<p>Overnight gains on Wall Street, which ended up 39.50 points at 6,081 points, a firmer dollar above 1.52 marks and continuing German bond strength also helped market sentiment.</p>
<p>The DAX index of 30 leading shares, was up 32.19 points, or 1.20 percent, at 2,723.48 in early trade, but off day highs and below the all-time bourse high of 2,739.26 hit on October 18.</p>
<p>Although the U.S. election results provided the morning's main focus, the market was also kept busy digesting a barrage of company figures and news.</p>
<p>Chemical company Hoechst rose 1.75 pfennigs, or over three percent, to 59.58 points, after the company announced nine month results.</p>
<p>Preference shares in business software group SAP AG gained the most ground amongst the DAX stocks, continuing to recover from the blow of a profit warning two weeks ago. SAP preference shares were up over four percent, or eight marks, at 204 marks.</p>
<p>Industrial group Daimler Benz also climbed strongly, after a newsletter said the firm was due to report nine-month turnover growth of 10 percent on Thursday.</p>
<p>Truck manafacturing and engineering group MAN AG was down over two percent or eight marks at 366.00 marks after the firm announced a rise in July to September sales.</p>
<p>Electronics firm Siemens, due to issue provisional 1995/96 results later in the day, was up 64 pfennigs at 80.00 marks.</p>
<p>Continuing weaker against the market trend was Germany's largest bank Deutsche Bank, which traded up three pfennigs at 69.80 marks, but below the crucial 70 mark level.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-06"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
