<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171754" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: United Healthcare Q3 cost ratio at 84.4 pct.</title>
<headline>United Healthcare Q3 cost ratio at 84.4 pct.</headline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Healthcare Corp said its medical cost ratio in the third quarter was 84.4 percent, down slightly from 84.8 percent in the second quarter, but up sharply from 79.3 percent in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;Sequential improvement in the level of medical care costs relative to revenue reflects ... higher premium increases achieved since February; the absence of any further increase in medical inflation over the 3 percent to 4 percent reported in the second quarter; and ongoing effort to improve on medical care integration and services,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>United Healthcare shares were up 4-1/4 to 44-1/4.  </p>
<p>Selling, general and administrative spending was 21.2 percent of total revenues, down from the 21.7 percent reported last quarter, but up from the 14.4 percent year-ago figure.</p>
<p>&quot;On a dollar basis, while revenue grew a little over $100 million in the quarter, SG&amp;A expenses increased less than $6 million. The company remains focused on SG&amp;A expense control and overall operational efficiency and believes further improvement in this ratio is feasible,&quot; United said.</p>
<p>The company on Thursday reported total revenues for the third quarter ended September 30, 1996, of $2.59 billion, compared to $1.22 billion for the same period a year ago.  </p>
<p>Third quarter profits were $91.2 million, or $0.45 per share, down from to $93.6 million, or $0.53 per share, in the third quarter of 1995.</p>
<p>Total health plan enrollment in United's various health maintenance organizations and other programs reached 4.64 million in the third quarter, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are pleased with the progression of results we achieved this quarter, and recognize that much remains to be accomplished,&quot; said United HealthCare chief executive Dr. William McGuire.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
