<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171777" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Many U.S. stocks overvalued -- fund managers.</title>
<headline>Many U.S. stocks overvalued -- fund managers.</headline>
<dateline>ORLANDO, Fla. 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. stock market is full of equities that are too highly priced, several managers of value mutual funds said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The managers, speaking at a roundtable discussion at the Charles Schwab annual Institutional Conference, said they are waiting for the market to turn bearish, so they will have their pick of cheap stocks.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market is not just pretty fully valued, it is past fully valued,&quot; said Michael Price, chairman of Heine Securities Corp, the investment advisor to the Mutual Series funds. Price said some of the firm's funds have cash positions as high as 24 percent in expectation of a correction, to allow them to buy cheap stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;You don't have to always be swinging,&quot; Price said, referring to buying stocks.</p>
<p>Robert Marcin, a partner at Miller, Anderson &amp; Sherrerd, said a bear market is looming. If the current bull market continues for the next two quarters, he will increase the cash position of the investment management firm to 15-20 percent from the current cash stake that is well below 10 percent.</p>
<p>Another value-oriented manager, Mason Hawkins of Southeastern Asset Management Inc, said the firm currently has about 21 percent in cash.</p>
<p>None of the managers suggested any timing on when the market would begin to correct.</p>
<p>All of the managers agreed that they are happiest in a bear market. &quot;We like bear markets, we like volatility,&quot; said Hawkins. &quot;It's hard to (buy) things now. Prices are too damn high.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORLANDO, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
