<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="171892" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton seen sticking behind strong dlr - US experts.</title>
<headline>Clinton seen sticking behind strong dlr - US experts.</headline>
<byline>Roanne Daniels</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton will not alter his administration's longstanding strong-dollar policy despite new pressure from U.S. manufacturers and a Japanese official's statement that the dollar's recovery against the yen has peaked, currency market experts said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders want to see where the U.S. stands, but I'm not so sure the U.S. wants to send much of a (new) signal,&quot; said Mike Malpede, senior foreign exchange analyst at Refco Group Ltd.</p>
<p>Malpede added that a currency tug-of-war with Japan could result if the U.S. does not change its strong-dollar policy.  </p>
<p>The dollar slid further Thursday after the head of the largest U.S. manufacturing association said Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin is likely to de-emphasize the strong dollar. Just before noon in New York, dollar/yen hit 111.27, close to a one-month low.</p>
<p>U.S. manufacturers have warned recently that the dollar was approaching levels that made U.S. exports uncompetitive. National Association of Manufactuers President Jerry Jainowski told reporters Thursday he felt Rubin &quot;will be saying less about the value of a strong dollar&quot; but added he does not expect Rubin to start &quot;talking down the dollar.&quot;  </p>
<p>Analysts in the U.S. interpreted Sakakibara's remarks as an attempt to cap the dollar's rise, but not reverse the G3 strong dollar policy.</p>
<p>&quot;They are trying to temper the move up in dollar/yen and mark/yen. I think U.S. (policymakers) will stay away from it, but it will cause dollar/yen to come down because people were long the dollar,&quot; said Mark Gargano, managing director of currency derivatives at First Union Natinal Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;I think (dollar/yen) will range from 113 to 110, maybe 108, as people get out of dollars and out of mark, but I don't look for a fundamental change,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>&quot;I've heard rumblings that the U.S. may shift dollar policy after Clinton is reelected. There is some concern, with a 40 percent depreciation of the yen and improvement in the current account starting to stagnate, that U.S. officials may consider that,&quot; Malpede said.</p>
<p>Gargano said he thinks U.S. policymakers &quot;don't mind&quot; dollar/yen around 114 to 115, but does not believe they would be comfortable with an exchange rate around 125 yen.</p>
<p>Some analysts said if the Clinton administration stays quiet in response to Sakakibara, that will indirectly signal a wish for the dollar to soften.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
