<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17199" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Sweden's Riksbank sticks to slower rate cut pace.</title>
<headline>Sweden's Riksbank sticks to slower rate cut pace.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM, Sweden</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's Riksbank, in a widely expected move, cut its key repo rate by 15 basis points Tuesday, continuing a policy of gradually slowing rate cuts.</p>
<p>The Riksbank cut the repo rate to 5.25 percent, the 18th cut so far this year, from 5.40 percent.</p>
<p>The cut was consistent with heavy hints from the central bank that rate cuts would continue, but at a slower pace than the regular 20 or 25 basis point cuts seen earlier in the year.</p>
<p>Riksbank governor Urban Backstrom said two weeks ago -- when rates were last cut -- that there was still room for easing in monetary policy.</p>
<p>Most analysts agree the Riksbank will continue cutting the repo rate into the fall, bringing it down to between 4.00 and 5.00 percent.</p>
<p>The repo is the central rate in a three-tiered interest rate management system, with the deposit and lending rates as the floor and ceiling.</p>
<p>The deposit rate is 4.75 percent and the lending rate is 6.25 percent. Both were last cut two weeks ago by 50 basis points and market players said they do not expect another immediate cut in these two rates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM, Sweden"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
