<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172046" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: SOCCER-JAPAN AND SOUTH KOREA AGREE ON 2002 WORLD CUP SCHEDULE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JAPAN AND SOUTH KOREA AGREE ON 2002 WORLD CUP SCHEDULE.</headline>
<byline>Stuart Young</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan and South Korea have cleared the first and biggest hurdle of the 2002 World Cup by agreeing to play the opening match in Seoul and the final in Japan, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan will stage the final and the closing ceremony and South Korea the opening game and the opening ceremony,&quot; said an official in Seoul at the Office of Preparation for 2002 FIFA World Cup.</p>
<p>The deal was confirmed by Japanese officials and it now needs formal approval only by a FIFA Executive Committee meeting in Barcelona on December 7.</p>
<p>The Japanese officials said the final would be staged in Tokyo's neighbouring port city of Yokohama where a brand new stadium was being built for the event.</p>
<p>The agreements were reached at a meeting in Zurich that was arranged by World soccer's governing body, FIFA, the Seoul official said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is unbelieveable that it's been decided so quickly,&quot; one Japanese soccer official said. &quot;Not just for soccer but for relations between our two countries. We've showed we can work things out.&quot;</p>
<p>Ties between South Korea and Japan are often strained by a rivalry rooted in Tokyo's 35-year colonial occupation of Korea and the events of World War Two.</p>
<p>A Japan World Cup spokesman said recently: &quot;I don't think people in Europe realise just how different Japan and South Korea are.&quot;</p>
<p>The two hosts agreed to call the event the 2002 FIFA World Cup Korea-Japan, resolving a sensitive issue of who should be mentioned first.</p>
<p>The Zurich meeting officially brought together Japanese and South Korean delegates for the first time since the 2002 tournament was awarded to both countries on May 31.</p>
<p>FIFA said after a three-hour meeting of the 2002 Study Group on Wednesday that the co-hosts had agreed on the major issues concerning the Cup finals. It said the final would be one match, not two, that Japan and South Korea would qualify automatically for the finals and that 32 teams would take part in 64 matches.</p>
<p>The official said details on the financial arrangements remained unresolved and could be discussed at the Barcelona meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;Draws for the qualifying and final rounds would be held in Japan, according to the decision made in the study group,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
