<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172038" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: RUGBY-SPRINGBOKS NAME ONE NEW CAP.</title>
<headline>RUGBY-SPRINGBOKS NAME ONE NEW CAP.</headline>
<byline>Andy Capostagno</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Natal prop Adrian Garvey is the only new cap in the South African team to play the first test against Argentina here at the Ferro Carril Oeste Stadium on Saturday.</p>
<p>Garvey played for Zimbabwe 25 times including the 1991 World Cup, but qualified for the Springboks with a three-year residency earlier this year. Garvey takes over the tight head berth from Marius Hurter who is carrying several injuries.</p>
<p>Only three players remain from the team which started the first test at the same round in 1993, wings James Small and Jacques Olivier and flank Ruben Kruger.</p>
<p>Small returns to the team after serving a disciplinary sentence for most of the year in South Africa. Hennie le Roux has shaken off the effects of a bruised shin and takes his place in the midfield.</p>
<p>Springbok manager Andre Markgraaff has hinted that he will take full use of the new substitution laws which came into effect on November 2. He has opted for a 4-2 forward split on the bench.</p>
<p>South Africa are unbeaten against Argentina in four post isolation test and they will be favourites to continue their run against a Puma side lacking powerhouse props Patricio Noriega and Matias Corral.</p>
<p>Team: 15:Andre Joubert 14:James Small 13:Japie Mulder 12:Hennie le Roux 11:Jacques Olivier 10:Henry Honiball 9:Joost van der Westhuizen 8:Gary Teichmann (captain) 7:Andre Venter 6:Ruben Kruger 5:Mark Andrews 4:Kobus Wiese 3:Adrian Garvey 2:James Dalton 1:Dawie Theron.</p>
<p>Replacements: Andre Snyman, Kevin Putt, Fritz van Heerden, Wayne Fyvie, Toks van der Linde, Henry Tromp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
