<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172084" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.AFRICA TO PROBE FRUIT MARKETING MONOPOLY.</title>
<headline>S.AFRICA TO PROBE FRUIT MARKETING MONOPOLY.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African farm minister Derek Hanekom said on Thursday he planned a full probe of agricultural marketing monopolies such as the one held by deciduous fruit marketer Unifruco.</p>
<p>This follows the passing of the Marketing of Agricultural Products Act by parliament, which paves the way for abolishing marketing monopolies in agricultural products.</p>
<p>Unifruco and Outspan hold monopoly agency agreements to market deciduous fruit and citrus products and Hanekom said the question was whether they would retain them.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue is how fast and what replaces it. I do not think that it is in our country's interest, despite the many arguments presented, to limit our exports to a single agency,&quot; Hanekom told a media briefing.</p>
<p>The appointment of an investigator would ensure that whatever steps were taken were &quot;informed decisions taking into account some of the problems of the European market&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not suggesting that we should go wild and go for a completely fragmented marketing system,&quot; Hanekom said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a process of issuing licences but it certainly cannot be confined to one monopoly. You have got to give space to other people. </p>
<p>&quot;For example, there is a company that has set itself up with strong connections in the United States which is at least a 31 percent black company and they have not been granted licences.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment I would argue that we are losing opportunities while, of course, Unifruco would argue that we are capturing a premium by acting through a single agency. </p>
<p>&quot;I would question the validity of that argument. We are not going to unbundle Unifruco through any legislative measure, we are simply going to open up competition.&quot; </p>
<p>Unifruco had provided a good service, he said. &quot;If it continues to do so, most fruit producers will choose to use Unifruco but it will not be a statutory matter.&quot;</p>
<p>Hanekom also said he planned a major investigation into the availability and affordability of food to ordinary consumers next year.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom +27 21 403-2502</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100206">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
