<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172126" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: East Midlands rejects bid by Dominion Resources.</title>
<headline>East Midlands rejects bid by Dominion Resources.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Young</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>East Midlands Electricity Plc said Thursday that it would reject as too low a contemplated $1.9 billion takover attempt by Dominion Resources Inc. of Richmond, Va.</p>
<p>The bid would mark the latest in a series of bids by U.S. utilities seeking to buy into the privatised British power supply business.</p>
<p>Dominion said late Wednesday that it was mulling an offer for the British utility at a price that would not be &quot;much in excess&quot; of its Wednesday closing price of 6.08 pounds sterling ($9.97) a share, which would value the company at $1.9 billion.</p>
<p>East Midlands responded Thursday by saying that it would reject an offer at that level, which it said would undervalue East Midlands Electricity.</p>
<p>&quot;At this level, our clear advice to shareholders would be to reject such an offer,&quot; East Midlands Chairman Nigel Rudd said in a statement.</p>
<p>Investors in London, however, seemed to take Dominion at its word Thursday, and East Midlands' share price slipped 21 pence (35 cents) to 5.87 pounds ($9.63).</p>
<p>Dominion, which owns electric utility Virginia Power, is a medium-sized company with a market capitalisation of about $6.6 billion and annual sales of $4.7 billion.</p>
<p>In addition to Virginia Power, its main subsidiary, Dominion has a number of joint generation ventures in the United States and internationally, notably in South America. It also has an interest in gas and real estate.</p>
<p>If Dominion proceeds with the bid, it would be the latest U.S. company to enter the privatised British power supply business. Last week, a unit of U.S.-based CalEnergy launched a hostile 650 million pound ($1.07 billion) bid for Northern Electric Plc.</p>
<p>Out of Britain's 12 privatised regional electric companies, which are all cash rich, seven have already changed ownership.</p>
<p>CE Electric, the CalEnergy unit bidding for Northern Electric, raised its stake in Northern to 19.9 percent Thursday after buying 6.5 million shares in the market.</p>
<p>Broker Hoare Govett said CE bought the shares at its bid price of 6.30 pounds ($10.33) a share.</p>
<p>Consequently, analysts in Lindon said, Dominion's offer of 6.08 pounds for East Midlands would be far too low.</p>
<p>&quot;I'd say Dominion will be unsuccessful anywhere near six pounds. If you look at the precedent of other successful offers, you'd have to say that this one would have to come in north of 8 pounds ($13.13),&quot; said David Campbell, an analyst at Greig Middleton.</p>
<p>Dominion Resources' stock lost 37.5 cents to $39.375 on the New York Stock Exchange in afternoon trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
