<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172128" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Eurobourses end down on weak dlr,rate nerves.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Eurobourses end down on weak dlr,rate nerves.</headline>
<byline>Medora Lee</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses ended lower on Thursday, depressed by a steep decline in the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;Bonds and the dollar have led us down across the board,&quot; said one London share trader.</p>
<p>The dollar started its more than two yen slide in Tokyo overnight after a Japanese finance ministry official said the currency's recovery from last year's post-war low against the yen was nearly complete and that Japan's economy was stronger than the markets believed.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial signal did not come from the new U.S. administration as many expected but from Japan, where it appears the groundwork is being laid for a rate hike,&quot; said Klaus Baader, senior currency economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>After steadying for a few hours in afternoon European trade, the dollar came under renewed pressure when the head of the U.S. National Association of Manufacturers said president Bill Clinton's administration was likely to de-emphasize its strong dollar policy.</p>
<p>By 1720 GMT, the dollar was quoted at 1.5061 marks and 111.45 yen, compared with 1.5165 marks and 113.83 yen in late European trade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But U.S. analysts were not yet convinced the United States was ready to steer away from a strong dollar policy.</p>
<p>&quot;Traders want to see where the U.S. stands, but I'm not so sure the U.S. wants to send much of a (new) signal,&quot; said Mike Malpede, senior foreign exchange analyst at Refco Group Ltd.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, traders said the momentum behind the dollar's sell-off remained worrisome.</p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese are trying to put a 115 yen top in,&quot; said Stephen Flanagan, a vice president at Credit Agricole in the United States. &quot;You've probably got more downside as all these yen-financed bond trades around the world are put at risk.&quot;</p>
<p>The only respite for European markets came late in the afternoon when Wall Street opened trading and the Dow Jones Industrial Average immediately erased losses of about 30 points to edge into positive ground.</p>
<p>The Dow was boosted by the Nasdaq index, comprised mostly of small-capitalisation and technology stocks, after Intel Corp predicted strong fourth-quarter earnings.</p>
<p>New York's gains helped pull French shares off session lows to close just below Wednesday's closing high and maintain levels not seen since early 1994.</p>
<p>British shares fell to an eight-week low but held above the key 3,900 level, though just barely.</p>
<p>London's blue-chip FTSE-100 index remained unnerved by Wednesday's Bank of England forecast of an imminent rise in inflation and the probable need for higher interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;Shares don't look significantly overvalued but are reacting to being caught unaware of a policy change,&quot; said Charterhouse Tilney startegist Richard Jeffrey.</p>
<p>Some traders also noted pressure on the London's blue-chip FTSE-100 index coming from heavy derivatives-related selling.</p>
<p>Germany's DAX index ended floor dealings lower, dragged down by a sharp fall in the shares of German electronic firm Siemens, which had already tumbled in Wednesday's post-bourse electronic trade.</p>
<p>The dollar's weakness, bad for German exporters, also pressured the market and overshadowed an overnight record close on Wall Street.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1720 GMT</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT THE CLOSE</p>
<p>LONDON - The Financial Times-Stock Exchange index of 100 leading British shares was 35.3 points lower at 3,900.4.</p>
<p>PARIS - The CAC-40 share index was down 1.56 at 2,211.81</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - The 30-share DAX index fell 15.97 at 2,713.22.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS AT THE CLOSE</p>
<p>Gold closed at $379.50, up from $378.20 previously after rallying on the dollar's drop against the yen and a downturn in stock, bond markets. Silver closed two cents firmer at $4.80.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
