<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172113" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: MANY CZECHS IGNORE SENATE ELECTIONS - SURVEY.</title>
<headline>MANY CZECHS IGNORE SENATE ELECTIONS - SURVEY.</headline>
<byline>Klara Gajduskova</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czechs are uninspired by the prospect of electing their first Senators later this month, according to an opinion poll forecasting low voter turnout and showing an ignorance of pre-election campaigns.</p>
<p>A survey by the state-funded research agency IVVM showed 57 percent of potential voters expected to cast a ballot in the first round of the elections on November 15-16, and only 52 percent said they would vote in runoffs a week later.</p>
<p>The early-October survey of a scientific sample of 1,365 Czechs said 46 percent of citizens did not know whether there was an election campaign or not.</p>
<p>&quot;There is, in general, low interest in the elections and the willingness to vote is low,&quot; Eliska Rendlova, an analyst at IVVM told Reuters. &quot;A part of the public even rejects having the Senate.&quot;</p>
<p>A previous IVVM poll showed that 53 percent of Czechs have doubts about the necessity of a second house of parliament.</p>
<p>The elections will be the first for the newly-created upper house of parliament which will have limited legislative power but will primarily act as an advisory body to the lower house, the Chamber of Deputies.</p>
<p>Voter turnout in the lower house elections was 76.41 percent, although surveys had suggested more than 80 percent planned to vote.</p>
<p>Analysts still are watching the Senate elections, which are based on a first-past-the-post system in 81 constituencies, as the first political test since June elections to the lower house stripped the centre-right government of its majority.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus's Civic Democratic Party (ODS), and the leading opposition Social Democrats (CSSD) are seen sending the most candidates into the final round of the two-step Senate elections, another survey, by an independent agency Factum showed earlier this week.</p>
<p>If no candidate in a constituency gets over 50 percent of votes cast in the first round, there is a second round with the top two candidates from the first poll, and analysts widely beleive that most races will go to two rounds.</p>
<p>The new survey showed only 25 percent beleived there was an election campaign underway.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom 42-2-2423-0003 - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
