<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172181" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK grain futures close higher on sterling dip.</title>
<headline>UK grain futures close higher on sterling dip.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sterling's bounce around lower levels continued to attract support for UK wheat futures with prices closing just firmer after recent declines.</p>
<p>&quot;The futures market has finally steadied up&quot;, one trader said.</p>
<p>Wheat futures closed 0.50 to 0.75 stg up on a turnover of 459 with the exception of the November contract which lost 0.25 stg.</p>
<p>A quiet day for barley saw just 12 lots traded with a gain of 0.40 stg for January.</p>
<p>The afternoon session was comparatively quiet ahead of the EU tender results the effects of which &quot;remain to be seen&quot; as one source said.</p>
<p>The EU granted export licences for 350,000 tonnes free-market soft wheat at 22.35 ecus per tonne and 133,500 tonnes barley at 31.49 ecus.</p>
<p>The Amsterdam milling wheat futures market was neglected.</p>
<p>On the UK cash markets, December feedwheat fetched 98.00 stg per tonne FOB east coast ports and Jan/Mar 100.00 stg.</p>
<p>Trade on the delivered market was quiet ahead of the tender.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone's working off short books and finding it difficult to draw business,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Trade in milling wheat 11 percent protein was particularly thin. November business to Liverpool was completed at around 18.00 stg.</p>
<p>Feedwheat fetched 97.50-99.25 stg Norfolk/Suffolk November and Avon range saw April/June quoted marginally up at 102.25 from 100.00 stg  on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-London Newsroom, +44 171 542 8071</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
