<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172367" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Nov 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Nov 7.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- A new cabinet might be the only chance for the ruling Socialist party to stay in power, a senior party official said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet has to submit to parliament the country's budget draft for 1997 by the end of the year, the parliamentary budget committee decided. @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria will peg the lev to a major currency only if the International Monetary Fund extends some $800 million to increase the country's foreign exchange reserves, deputy prime minister Roumen Gechev said.</p>
<p>-- A Finance Ministry audit began at Bulgaria's largest oil refinery Neftochim after its overdue debts to the budget rose by some 10.8 billion levs in the first ten months to 15 billion levs.</p>
<p>24 CHASA @</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Industry minister Lyubomir Dachev proposed only 24 of the country's 86 military production companies to remain state owned. Six of the 38 companies slated for closure under a government's restructuring programme have been privatised, said Dachev.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Agriculture ministry plans to issue three-year licences to companies trading in pesticides, rose oil and lavender oil.</p>
<p>TRUD @</p>
<p>-- The Bulgarian State Railways (BSR) will raise the passenger fees by 30 percent from December 1 but cargo tariffs will remain unchanged until the end of the year, a senior BSR official said.</p>
<p>-- Some 40 million levs were provided by the cabinet to extinguish an outbreak of foot-and-mouth desease in Southeastern Bulgaria, a National Veterinary Service senior official said.</p>
<p>PARI @</p>
<p>-- The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) approved a two-year strategy for Bulgaria, placing a major emphasis on support for the private business. -- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
