<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172354" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: FORECAST-Zambia expects growth of five pct a year.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Zambia expects growth of five pct a year.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambia's economy was buoyant and annual growth of around five percent is expected over the next 10 years, Finance Minister Ronald Penza said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is much more resilient, the economy is much more buoyant,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident to have, until the year 2005, an average of five percent growth in the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Penza said the government had managed to curb month-on-month inflation to only one percent. Real inflation measured on a year-on-year basis was 45.6 percent in September.</p>
<p>He said government economic reforms since 1991, when President Frederick Chiluba came to power after the first democratic elections, had been successful and foreign investors viewed the country in a favourable light.</p>
<p>&quot;The confidence that we create for the private sector is so critical for the future development of Zambia,&quot; Penza said.</p>
<p>Foreign aid donors, including the U.S., Japan, Britain and Scandinavia, suspended aid to Zambia in June over changes to the constitution which excluded former president Kenneth Kaunda from contesting general elections due on November 18.</p>
<p>Penza said although aid had been suspended, Zambia continued to service its foreign debt which stands at $6.4 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996 we have had very little donor support but we have been current with our debt service repayments. And this has largely been due to policy reforms,&quot; Penza said.</p>
<p>-- Marius Bosch, Lusaka office +2601 22689</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
