<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172312" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: Wood shortage hits Ivorian timber industry.</title>
<headline>Wood shortage hits Ivorian timber industry.</headline>
<byline>Clare Black</byline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two months after Ivory Coast cracked down on illegal timber felling, many companies in the timber industry, both loggers and processors, are feeling the pinch, industry sources say.</p>
<p>Some sources even go so far as to suggest that the shortage of newly felled wood in the West African nation threatens to put some companies out of business.</p>
<p>&quot;Timber supply was cut dramatically and some 50 percent of timber companies are close to bankruptcy as they were earning money with logs coming from buffer zones and forest reserves, north of the eighth parallel&quot; said one industry source.</p>
<p>Intensive logging and slash-and-burn peasant farming have devastated Ivory Coast's ancient rain forest in the three decades since independence in 1960.</p>
<p>The government cracked down on all felling north of the eighth parallel, which was largely banned in theory, after critics denounced a range of abuses.</p>
<p>&quot;They even cut down teak in a cemetry in Katiola, and bulldozers were found in the Comoe natural forest reserve,&quot; said one timber industrialist.</p>
<p>Ben Soumahoro of the opposition Rally of the Republicans accused the government in August of doing nothing. President Henri Konan Bedie promptly called a meeting of timber and forestry operators to solve the problem.</p>
<p>On September 6, the government adopted a directive banning all logging above the eighth parallel, in forest reserves, in buffer zones separating protected forest from forestry concessions and all teak logging, except in limited cases.</p>
<p>The ban has led to a shortage of wood for the West African nation's sawmills, notably of the popular Iroko species.</p>
<p>Industry sources say over 60 percent of the Ivory Coast's timber supply came from logs felled north of the eighth parallel and in buffer zones.</p>
<p>Supply has slightly reajusted itself. Legal concessions now account for 50 percent of timber supply but problems remain.</p>
<p>&quot;There is still a critical shortage in the industry, especially for Iroko,&quot; said the industry source.</p>
<p>Iroko is a multi-use, light-coloured tropical wood, which is very popular in Europe.</p>
<p>Industry sources say over 90 percent of Iroko is found north of the eighth parallel and that so much of it came out of Ivory Coast in mid-1996 that prices crashed from 3200 FF a cubic metre to 1900 FF due to oversupply.</p>
<p>Since the ban in early September, the price has been rising by around 50 FF per week. Iroko currently fetches around 2400-2600 FF a cubic metre.</p>
<p>Timber union SYNGOPIB has accused the forestry ministry of aiding illegal loggers. Critics accuse state forest management company, SODEFOR, of turning a blind eye to illegal logging.</p>
<p>Ivory Coast, the world's top cocoa producer, once boasted its own large slice of West and Central Africa's rich tropical rain forest and is keen to protect the little that remains and replace some of the trees that have been lost.</p>
<p>The World Bank, which sent a team to view the state of the forests earlier this year, is preparing a project for a $40 million loan split between SODEFOR and the forestry ministry.</p>
<p>The loan, expected to be put to the Bank's Board of Directors for approval in mid-1997, has strict conditions attached to it -- in particular adherence by the timber industry to existing laws governing the sector.</p>
<p>($1=511 CFA francs)</p>
<p>-- Abidjan newsroom +225 21 90 90</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I46000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
