<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172433" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland's PZU insurer eyes $200-300 mln new issue.</title>
<headline>Poland's PZU insurer eyes $200-300 mln new issue.</headline>
<byline>Tomasz Janowski</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's largest insurer, the state-owned  Powszechny Zaklad Ubezpieczen SA (PZU) plans to raise $200-300 million through a private placement in the first quarter of 1997, PZU's president said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our first goal is to quickly increase the company's capital...through a private placement to institutional investors,&quot; Jan Monkiewicz told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for investors who will have sufficient funds because...according to estimates we will need $200-300 million to cover our near-term capital needs,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Monkiewicz said PZU sought long-term investors and was in talks with a group of mainly domestic financial institutions, to whom it wanted to offer the new shares.</p>
<p>He said PZU was also in talks with the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development (EBRD) and had initiated contacts with the International Finance Corporation.</p>
<p>Monkiewicz declined to give names of Polish institutions targeted for the investment but asked whether Pekao SA group was one of the candidates said: &quot;We are talking with this bank but we are also in talks with all prime Polish banks.&quot;</p>
<p>He said investors would be offered minority stakes but there was no set limit of how much of the capital would be in their hands after the capital increase.</p>
<p>&quot;The privatisation blueprint approved by the finance ministry sets no firm limits...our approach is different, we say how much capital we need and the size of the stake will be determined by how the company will be priced,&quot; Monkiewicz said.</p>
<p>Monkiewicz said the capital increase was the most pressing need in the company's drive to prepare itself for increased competition ahead of the liberalisation of cross-border financial services in 1999.</p>
<p>He said that after the private placement, in which investors would be offered minority stakes, PZU wanted to follow through with a flotation on the Warsaw Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Under an optimistic scenario we should be able to close the second privatisation stage by the end of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Monkiewicz said it would be up to new PZU shareholders to decide whether PZU would issue new stock or the company would be floated through a sale of the treasury's shares.</p>
<p>He also said that after the flotation, the new shareholders would decide how and when to privatise PZU's life subsidiary.</p>
<p>He said an earlier plan to start PZU's privatisation with a an offer of a minority stake in PZU Life failed because investors did not want to buy Life's shares without knowing who would control its parent company.</p>
<p>Monkiewicz said the capital increase was a part of broader efforts aimed at modernising the company and making it more efficient ahead of an unavoidable squeeze on profit margins.</p>
<p>He said PZU would strive to boost its technical reserves and would seek to diversify its insurance portfolio, now dominated by loss-making motor insurance.</p>
<p>PZU, which in the first three quarters of this year collected a total of 2.7 billion zlotys in gross premiums, has a 61 percent share of Poland's non-life market and together with PZU Zycie about 70 percent of the total insurance market.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
