<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172485" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania to offer 1.156 trillion lei in T-bills.</title>
<headline>Romania to offer 1.156 trillion lei in T-bills.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's Finance Ministry, struggling to cover a soaring state budget deficit, said on Thursday it would launch two issues of 91-day treasury bills totalling 1.156 trillion lei this month.</p>
<p>The new paper will be placed by the central bank in three public subscriptions scheduled for November 8, 14 and 22 and can be bought by commercial banks operating in Romania and their corporate clients.</p>
<p>According to latest statistics, the state budget showed a 1.9 trillion lei deficit over January-August. The gap is forecast to expand to 4.27 trillion by the end of 1996.</p>
<p>Traders said they expected banks to rush to buy the new T-bills as the money market continued to be cash-heavy, with prices for funds up to one-week plunging to some 34 percent from 40 percent a few days ago.</p>
<p>The annual yield for the new T-bills will be equal with the three-month Bucharest Interbank Bid Rate (BUBID) set five days ahead of the public subscriptions. Three-month BUBID rate was 49.35 percent on Thursday. ($=3,430 lei) -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
