<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172532" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>PANAMA: Former Panama strongman Noriega shows some heart.</title>
<headline>Former Panama strongman Noriega shows some heart.</headline>
<dateline>PANAMA CITY 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Panama's jailed former strongman Manuel Antonio Noriega has declined to collect a $1,500-a-month pension and asked that it be paid to a woman who helped raise him, government officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Noriega, who is serving a 40-year sentence in Florida for a 1992 conviction on drug and racketeering charges, asked social security officials to send the payments to a Panamanian caretaker who helped raise him when his mother died.</p>
<p>Her name was not disclosed.</p>
<p>Social security officials said Noriega, who was deposed in a December, 1989 U.S. invasion, was entitled to the money after 27 years of service with the National Guard and the notorious Panama Defence Forces, which acted as his henchmen.</p>
<p>Panama's largest human rights group said Noriega should get a pension despite his dismal human rights record.</p>
<p>&quot;Even though he has committed human rights violations, he is entitled to receive his pension,&quot; said Osvaldo Velasquez, president of Panama's Pro Human Rights Committee.</p>
<p>Noriega is alleged to have amassed millions of dollars in corruption and payoffs from drug dealers during his rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PANAMA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
