<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172548" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina impatient with WTO farm committee.</title>
<headline>Argentina impatient with WTO farm committee.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentina said Thursday the World Trade Organization (WTO) Agricultural Committee has not gone far enough in calling for preparations for further agricultural trade liberalization.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Guido Di Tella told a news conference that Argentina signed a WTO agricultural committee report Wednesday to be presented to a WTO meeting in Singapore in December, but only after serious misgivings.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot say we are completely satisfied,&quot; said Di Tella, describing the committee meeting as &quot;stormy&quot;. He added, &quot;There are many lobbies that want to water down what was achieved in the Uruguay Round (of GATT).&quot;</p>
<p>Under the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, agricultural trade liberalization is due to come up for further negotiations in 1999, but Argentina wants the Singapore meeting to start the process of preparation for the talks immediately.</p>
<p>&quot;If we start in 1999, we won't have any result until 2004,&quot; Agriculture Secretary Felipe Sola told the conference, &quot;but if we start right away then by 1999 we'll be prepared and know what to debate.&quot;</p>
<p>Sola said the committee resolution finally did call for the Singapore meeting to start preparations, but &quot;it says so in the most subtle and lightweight way you can imagine possible within diplomatic language in an attempt not to offend anyone.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Jason Webb, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
