<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172683" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>Malaysia: PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Nov 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Nov 8.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Friday's Malaysian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NEW STRAITS TIMES</p>
<p>- The country will eventually collapse if society begins to accept corruption as a normal components of business transactions, be it with the government or the private sector, Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said.</p>
<p>- In a move to further curb the smoking habit, the Cabinet has endorsed the extension of no-smoking zones to 11 more places effective next month, Health Minister Chua Jui Meng said.</p>
<p>BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>- Tenaga Nasional Bhd has recorded a 29 percent reduction in group pre-tax profit to 1.16 billion ringgit for the financial year ended August 31 1996 from 1.64 billion previously.</p>
<p>- The Malaysian presence in Guinea was greatly felt on Thursday when Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad opened a local bank which is managed mainly by Malaysians.</p>
<p>- Malayan Banking Bhd and Rating Agency Malaysia Bhd have jointly pioneered an index to track the performance of the property market which has posted tremendous growth and price increases in the past few years.</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- A massive 1 billion ringgit gap separates the respective positions between Malayan Banking Bhd and Rashid Hussain Bhd over the sale of Kwong Yik Bank Bhd with just 10 days to go before the two sides are due to report back to the authorities on their negotiations.</p>
<p>- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
