<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172706" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan economy better now than few months ago - EPA.</title>
<headline>Japan economy better now than few months ago - EPA.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's economy is better now than it was a few months ago, newly appointed Economic Planning Agency (EPA) minister Taro Aso told a news conference on Friday.  </p>
<p>Aso said that Japan may be able to achieve its official growth target of 2.5 percent set for the current fiscal year ending March 31.</p>
<p>&quot;There was feeling a few months ago that the economy was marking time, but the economy is definitely better now and continuing its gradual growth,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Deregulation will help the economy pick up its pace of recovery, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;However, we have to keep in mind the unemployment rate may go up because of deregulation,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Asked if a supplementary budget to stimulate the economy was needed, Aso said he doubts if an extra budget can be implemented within the current fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;Theoretically, a supplementary budget may have good effects on the economy, but we have to assess if we really need that now,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
