<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172727" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: New Japan finance minister vows reform of ministry.</title>
<headline>New Japan finance minister vows reform of ministry.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's newly appointed Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka vowed on Thursday to carry out swift and effective reform of his powerful ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;Administrative reform is the voice of the people and something which will shape Japan's future,&quot; Mitsuzuka said in his first news conference as finance minister.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka said Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto asked him to concentrate particularly on the reform of his ministry, the central bank and the country's entire financial system, on the basis of a policy agreement his Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) signed last week with the Social Democrats and Sakigake -- the two parties now in a loose alliance with the LDP.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka also pledged to carry out Hashimoto's request for fiscal reform and to promote Tokyo financial markets to make them equal to those of the United States and Europe.</p>
<p>Asked how he will trim the power of over-zealous bureaucrats in his ministry, Mitsuzuka said: &quot;Pure confrontation will be bad, but I will say what I must say. I will welcome what they have to say and that's the way to do it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
