<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17298" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: INTERVIEW - Kvaerner integration advances.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - Kvaerner integration advances.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Huddart</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Erik Toenseth, president of Norway's Kvaerner ASA, said on Tuesday the group had made major advances in integrating the main units of UK construction and engineering group Trafalgar House since acquiring it in April.</p>
<p>However, he said that Kvaerner would now take a more gradual approach to fine-tuning the shape of the group's newly-enlarged core units to form a more efficient structure.</p>
<p>&quot;The core business of Trafalgar House is the kind of business we are used to and therefore it's been fairly quick to get a feel for where we are,&quot; Toenseth told Reuters in London.  </p>
<p>The initial assessment of the three Trafalgar House core units acquired via the merger had revealed few surprises, and Toenseth said the challenges now were mainly organisational.</p>
<p>A lot had already happened to ensure their integration, he said, but he added that long-term success would need a more gradual approach. &quot;I think a lot will be achieved fairly soon, and then it will take longer to fine-tune it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think organisation is a continuous process, so there will not be any end. But it will probably take a couple of years before we can say that &quot;now we have basically sorted out all the historic challenges'.&quot;  </p>
<p>In the meantime, those three areas which Kvaerner regards as of central strategic importance -- grouped around John Brown Engineers, Davy International and Trafalgar House Construction -- are &quot;basically making money&quot;, Toenseth added.</p>
<p>Although they were not making much, their profitability was not a burning issue, he said. &quot;It's important to get them to more acceptable profitability. But there aren't any leakages of money, and they are making money in a sustainable way.&quot;</p>
<p>He said a more important change in terms of financial and business policy was to inspire more confidence within the units.  </p>
<p>&quot;We want to help make (people in these units) more outward, more ambitious, more fighting for new projects and knowing that they are long-term winners,&quot; Toenseth said, .</p>
<p>&quot;We try to give them that self-confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>He said it was apparent that, in the past, companies within the Trafalgar House conglomerate had suffered from its endemic financial insecurity and from intra-group strains.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as they were in the situation where they didn't really know what the future would involve, they wouldn't approach markets -- or technology, or partners -- in an aggressive and positive way. That has changed,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Going forward, Kvaerner has brought the three Trafalgar units into a structure with six business &quot;legs&quot;,  three of which are headed by vice presidents from the British companies.</p>
<p>From September Toenseth intends all six business unit managers, along with finance chief Jan Heggelund, to join him in a new corporate headquarters in central London's St James area, a stone's throw from the old Trafalgar House base in Piccadilly.</p>
<p>The eight men will share an office, he says, and so seek to maintain in a new location a closeness and open communication style that Toenseth says he established at Kvaerner in Norway. They will also seek to implement the group's strategic shift.  </p>
<p>Toenseth commented on two areas of strategy outside engineering and construction -- shipbuilding and divestments.</p>
<p>Shipbuilding would remain, he said, but needed long-term change to achieve the efficiencies of engineering contracting.</p>
<p>However, the group still wants to quit Trafalgar's famed Cunard cruise line and to avoid paying for the expensive renewal of its fleet, but Toenseth saw no rush to divest the brand yet.</p>
<p>&quot;Long-term, we are unlikely to be the sole shareholder in Cunard...We would be happy to be investors on a small or large scale,&quot; he said, declining to elaborate on any timeframe.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
