<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172930" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Immigrants total nearly 5 percent of US military.</title>
<headline>Immigrants total nearly 5 percent of US military.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Immigrants are a significant part of U.S. military forces, as they have been since the Civil War, a report released Thursday said.</p>
<p>The report said 62,560 naturalised citizens and permanent resident immigrants were serving on active duty in the U.S. armed forces, nearly five percent of all enlisted personnel and 3.4 percent of officers.</p>
<p>Gen. John Shalikashvili, a naturalised citizen from Poland, is chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the nation's highest military rank. His predecessor was Gen. Colin Powell, the son of Jamaican immigrants.</p>
<p>Immigrants who have permanent resident status in the United States can enlist in the military.</p>
<p>The study was issued in advance of Monday's Veterans Day holiday to recognise the military contributions of immigrants.</p>
<p>&quot;As was the case more than a century ago, the evidence shows that immigrants are as willing as natives to support the nation's defence needs and, if necessary, to give their lives for their country,&quot; the report concluded.</p>
<p>The study was written by Stuart Anderson of the private Cato Institute and released by Empower America and the American Immigration Law Foundation.</p>
<p>Congress passed a bill this year clamping down on illegal immigration which also put restrictions on benefits available to legal immigrants because of concerns that immigrants were costing the government too much money.</p>
<p>&quot;The brave men and women featured in this report are true American heroes. These immigrants loved America enough to fight above and beyond the call of duty to protect her from enemies,&quot; Sen. Spencer Abraham, a Michigan Republican, said at a news conference on the report.</p>
<p>&quot;We Americans owe much to the skill, spirit and allegiance of immigrants,&quot; added former Education Secretary William Bennett, the co-director of Empower America.</p>
<p>The report said approximately 500,000 immigrants fought in the Union Army during the Civil War, making up one-quarter of the troops, and 67,000 of them were killed. The immigrants were mainly from Ireland, Germany and other European nations.</p>
<p>No figure was given for immigrants in Confederate forces.</p>
<p>The report highlighted the combat record of highly decorated Japanese-American troops from Hawaii during the Second World War who fought in Europe while other Japanese-Americans were being held in internment camps.</p>
<p>The study said 715 immigrants have won the Medal of Honour, the nation's highest military award for outstanding bravery in combat, out of 3,405 recipients.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
