<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172948" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY physical coffee - spot supply crunch persists.</title>
<headline>NY physical coffee - spot supply crunch persists.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York physical coffee market was sluggish this week, with a few scattered sales, amid a continued shortage of prompt supplies, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Business is slow because the coffee does not exist,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Roasters are calling and saying, 'I need some coffee, what can you get me?' Normally they call and ask, 'what's the price?'&quot;</p>
<p>Differentials on spot beans held firm on the week in tandem with surging prices on the futures market. In November, the December contract has risen 10.15 cents, or nearly nine percent.  </p>
<p>Although roasters are generally covered through November, traders said there was still enough last-minute scrambling for coffee to keep spreads sky-high.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not enough coffee to knock differentials down,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;If roasters need coffee, they will pay up for anything you have.&quot;</p>
<p>Although Brazilian coffee exports reached 1,706,691 60-kg bags in October, the highest monthly total in three years, traders said U.S. roasters were regularly outbid by their European counterparts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
