<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="172987" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Southeast power climbs amid firm Fla. demand.</title>
<headline>U.S. Southeast power climbs amid firm Fla. demand.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A return of air-conditioning load in Florida and tight generation capacity in the region bolstered the spot bulk electricity market in the southeastern U.S., market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're running a little above yesterday's load,&quot; said one Florida trader.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the pennisula peaked in the mid- to high-80s Fahrenheit, but a weekend cool front was predicted to cause the thermometer to plummet at five to 14 degrees below seasonal norm.</p>
<p>The 825 megawatt (MW) Crystal River 3 nuclear power unit remained out of service as the operator Florida Power Corp (FPC) began investigating its design and equipment operations. FPC did not set a restart date for the plant.</p>
<p>Slight relief occurred today when a 350 MW coal-fired unit at the McIntosh generating station in the city of Lakeland resumed operation today. The unit was shut last Saturday to repair a boiler tube leak.</p>
<p>With hourly prices in Florida in $30.00 a megawatt hour, participants took advantage of freed capacity at the Georgia/Florida border interface, and scheduled power for Friday, market sources said.</p>
<p>At the Ga./Fla. border, firm, peak electricity for Friday was valued near $24.00, up from Wednesday's quote of $21.00-$22.50.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak at the Ga./Fla. border was notationally assessed at $16.00-$18.00, higher than Wednesday's range of $15.00-$17.00.</p>
<p>Power deliveries during peak hours on Friday into northwestern portion of Tennessee Valley Authority's (TVA) territory were valued at $19.00-$21.00, up from a quote of $18.00-$19.00 on Wednesday. A cold weather system was forecast to arrive in Tennessee Valley on Friday.</p>
<p>Firm, next-day power for delivery into northwestern TVA during light load hours was notationally pegged at $16.00-$18.00, up from Wednesday's $15.00-$17.00.</p>
<p>The 1,129 MW McGuire 1 nuclear power plant in Cornelius, N.C. was restarted, and expected to begin to contribute power to the regional grid this weekend. The unit was shut October 31 afte one of the facility's four backup battery banks failed to meet performance criteria during a recent test.</p>
<p>The adjoining 1,129 MW McGuire unit 1 would resume service a day after unit 1 was back on line.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
