<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173084" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Perot's defeat leaves independents in disarray.</title>
<headline>Perot's defeat leaves independents in disarray.</headline>
<byline>Kieran Murray</byline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ross Perot's weak showing in the presidential race has left the fledgling third party movement in disarray with its would-be architects wondering who will lead them and if voters are angry enough to follow.</p>
<p>Perot, candidate of the Reform Party he built with his own money, won just eight percent of the vote on Tuesday, a bitter disappointment four years after storming the political stage and scoring 19 percent in his first presidential bid.</p>
<p>His campaign was crippled by concerns about his autocratic style and a growing perception among voters that he was much better at describing national problems than offering proposals to solve them.</p>
<p>Shrugging off his defeat, Perot's aides said they would continue to build the Reform Party and the feisty Texan said he would stick around to force the Republican-controlled Congress and President Bill Clinton into balancing the budget and pushing through promised campaign finance reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Take a little break and then we'll climb back in the ring and keep the pressure on to see that everybody keeps their promises,&quot; Perot told his party faithful on election night.</p>
<p>But most analysts see him as a spent force and critics in the third party camp are already calling on him to step aside.</p>
<p>&quot;Ross Perot has outstayed his welcome,&quot; said Richard Lamm, the former Democratic governor of Colorado who was beaten by Perot this year in an ugly battle for the Reform Party's presidential nomination.</p>
<p>Lamm has stayed in the Reform Party and is touring the country in a bid to bring moderate Democrats and Republicans together on a platform of a balanced budget, reform of entitlement programmes such as Medicare and a radical overhaul of campaign finance laws. While he has close ties with several prominent figures, some of whom are retiring from Congress, his is a frustrating mission.</p>
<p>Polls show many Americans are disgusted with mainstream politics but Lamm concedes major party politicians are wary about jumping ship and, no matter how important they may be, campaign finance and entitlements reform do not qualify as the &quot;wildfire issues&quot; that inspire strong third party movements.</p>
<p>Instead, most pollsters said this year's election campaign showed that voters had lost some of the anger shown in 1992 and 1994 and, satisfied with the economy, were prepared to give Clinton and congressional Republicans another shot.</p>
<p>Worse still for third party organisers, there are no obvious candidates with the charisma to inspire a political revolution. Perot sought to take on that role in 1992 and retired Gen. Colin Powell last year raised the hopes of many independents before ruling out a run for the White House.</p>
<p>&quot;If there was a JFK around who could focus this discontent, it would be easier for us,&quot; Lamm said, referring to former Democratic President John F. Kennedy.</p>
<p>Perot presents a delicate problem for his opponents in the third party movement: they like his willingness to spend part of his fortune establishing the party but do not like his apparent insistence that he be the candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;We owe him a lot but you can't build an autocratic political party and he has got to understand that,&quot; Lamm said.</p>
<p>Curtis Gans, director of the non-partisan Committee for the Study of the American Electorate, said he believed there was fertile ground for the growth of a strong third party but that Perot needed to back away from centre stage.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a role for Perot if he is willing to take a back seat. If he wants to determine either the nomineee or the platform, then the answer is 'No,'&quot; Gans said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
