<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173162" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss shares close lower despite late recovery.</title>
<headline>Swiss shares close lower despite late recovery.</headline>
<text>
<p>1535 GMT - Swiss shares were pressured by profit taking and closed lower despite a late recovery due to a friendly opening on Wall Street.</p>
<p>&quot;The market seems stuck in a range between 3,780 and 3,820 SMI points and has a hard time getting out of it&quot;, one dealer said. Early losses in London weighed on the market. Future development depended on Wall Street and the U.S. dollar, a dealer added.</p>
<p>* Blue-chip Swiss Market Index (SMI) ended down 3.9 points, or 0.1 percent, to 3,811.5 points.</p>
<p>* Broad SPI down 3.98 points, or 0.16 percent, to 2,438.88.  </p>
<p>* The strong tendency in Nestle underpinned the market, a trader noted. The stocks rose seven francs to 1,403 in high volume.</p>
<p>* Nestle's strong bias was outweighed by the weakness in Ciba and Sandoz which gave up between 0.3 and 0.6 percent. The stocks had posted sizeable gains on Wednesday. Roche certificates dropped five francs to 9,755 francs.</p>
<p>* SBC fell 0.25 francs to 249.50 after today's nine-month figures. Dealers said a slow-down in third quarter profit growth was seen as disappointing by some investors, although analysts said it was expected.  </p>
<p>* Cyclicals ABB, Holderbank and SMH were among the day's winners. Watchmaker SMH was sought by foreign investors. The bearer shares rose 0.85 percent to 826 francs.</p>
<p>* Alusuisse was unchanged at 965 francs.</p>
<p>* Among major banks, CS Holding traded evenly at 129.25 francs.</p>
<p>* Insurers were mostly lower with the exception of Baloise, which added 30 francs to 2,685 francs.</p>
<p>* Adecco slipped 1.7 percent to 349 francs.</p>
<p>-- Martin Gelnar, Zurich Newsroom, +41 1 631 7342</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
