<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173178" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: No Cr Lyonnais privatisation for 2 years -paper.</title>
<headline>No Cr Lyonnais privatisation for 2 years -paper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Credit Lyonnais chairman Jean Peyrelevade reiterated in a newspaper interview to be published on Friday that it would be another two years before the French state-owned bank could be privatised.</p>
<p>&quot;In my opinion, it will need two years to put Credit Lyonnais in a state to be privatised, he told Les Echos.</p>
<p>He believed Credit Lyonnais, which reported a first-half profit of 12.9 million francs, &quot;had reached the end of the first volume of the history of the bank's recovery.&quot;</p>
<p>The bank would remain a &quot;universal bank&quot; in France, but in Europe &quot;it will be necessary to define more closely the frontier of our activities, country by country.&quot;</p>
<p>He also reiterated that the bank, which has already received two state bailouts, would have to be recapitalised before being privatised as its tier one ratio of 4.5 percent was inadequate.</p>
<p>He did not say by how much it would need to be recapitalised. The average tier one ratio of French banks is six percent. Credit Lyonnais has estimated it would cost eight billion francs to raise the ratio by one percentage point.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
