<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173186" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: More French drinking wine, reversing 15-year trend.</title>
<headline>More French drinking wine, reversing 15-year trend.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The number of wine drinkers is again on the rise in France, reversing a downward trend dating from 1980, a survey released on Thursday found.</p>
<p>The ranks of wine drinkers increased by two million people in the latest survey by the French national wine board ONIVINS and the INRA national agricultural research agency after tumbling in similar surveys conducted since 1980.</p>
<p>The two state agencies said the increase was primarily due to more young people drinking wine compared to earlier surveys, though they were still drinking less regularly than their elders.</p>
<p>Despite the stereotype of the French as big wine consumers, the percentage of tipplers bottomed out at 63.8 percent in 1990 from 76.4 percent in 1980 before climbing to 65.3 percent in the latest survey, conducted in 1995.</p>
<p>Is this merely a passing phase or the start of a new trend? That is the question of the day,&quot; ONIVINS and INRA said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Despite the increase in the number of wine drinkers, average consumption continues to plummet, however, the agencies said. It fell to 80 litres a year per capita in 1994 from 160 litres in 1965.</p>
<p>A typical bottle of wine is about three-quarters of a litre.</p>
<p>The survey, based on interviews conducted last year with 4,000 people over 14 years of age, found that only about 28 percent could be considered regular wine drinkers while about 11 percent never consumed it and another 19 percent rarely drank it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
