<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173635" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. jobless claims drop hint tight labor markets.</title>
<headline>U.S. jobless claims drop hint tight labor markets.</headline>
<byline>Jose Paulo Vicente</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A drop in jobless claims data for the week ended November 2 suggests the U.S. labor markets remain tight, bolstering the theory that consumption in the fourth quarter might be strong, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It indicates that we have a persistent tighteness in the labor market and that should continue indefinitely since we're likely to get a bit stronger consumer numbers in the fourth quarter,&quot; said Lee Youngdahl, vice president and an economist at Aubrey G. Lanston and Co Inc.  </p>
<p>Youngdahl said the fact that claims are still hovering around current levels means that &quot;there is still hiring going on in the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>The Labor Department said jobless claims fell to 331,000 in the week ended November 2 against 342,000 in the previous week. The four-week moving average rose to 333,500 in the week from 331,250 in the last seven-day period.</p>
<p>Analysts said the numbers were not likely to change anyone's ideas about the overall economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;That four week moving average has been holding right around 330,000 for a while now,&quot; said Greg Jones, economist at Briefing.com, in an interview with Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have to realize that small moves in claims in the range of 10,000 to 20,000 really are not very helpful in predicting job growth,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts said the drop in the figures suggest that some workers who were laid off as a result of a recent General Motors strike did not file for jobless claims.  </p>
<p>The GM strike in Canada forced some plants in the U.S. to shut down due to a lack of parts. Pundits did not discount the possibility of a rise in claims over the next few weeks due to the strike effects.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be that these numbers will show up in the next week or two. In any case I think we know that's going to be a short-lived situation anyway,&quot; Youngdahl said.</p>
<p>The U.S. money market practically shrugged off the release of the jobless claims data. Analysts said players were more focused on the upcoming auction of $10.0 billion in 30-year Treasury bonds later on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Jobless claims had almost no impact on trading today,&quot; said a trader at a U.S. investment bank.</p>
<p>The 6-3/4 percent benchmark 30-year U.S. Treasury bond was quoted down 13/32 at 101-10/32 to yield 6.65 percent.</p>
<p>The drop in bonds is mostly tied to an overnight slump in the dollar, trigerred by bearish comments by a Japanese Finance Minister official.</p>
<p>The official, Eisuke Sakakibara, was quoted overnight in a newspaper as saying that the dollar's recovery against the yen from its sharp slide last year was about to finish.</p>
<p>-- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1676</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
