<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173639" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Alliance Imaging sees Q4 gain $0.11/shr.</title>
<headline>Alliance Imaging sees Q4 gain $0.11/shr.</headline>
<dateline>ORANGE, Calif. 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alliance Imaging Inc on Thursday said it will report an extraordinary gain in the fourth quarter of approximately $1.24 million, or 11 cents per common share, from an early extinguishment of debt.</p>
<p>The provider of hospital-based fixed-site and mobile magnetic resonance imaging and computed tomography services said the gain results from its prepaying $5.3 million of the principal amount of notes at a substantial discount, leaving $20.1 million in principal amount of the notes outstanding.</p>
<p>It said all of its 7.5 percent senior secured notes due in 2003 have been sold by the existing holders to new owners.  </p>
<p>In connection with the sale, the new holders and the company agreed to the removal or modification of various restrictive covenants contained in the note purchase agreement governing the notes. Alliance initiated this transaction and structured its primary terms.</p>
<p>The company noted, however, that to realize the benefits of the covenant modifications, it will be necessary to obtain substantially similar modifications to the nearly identical provisions of its 7.5 percent senior subordinated debentures.</p>
<p>The company intends to initiate discussions with the holders of its senior subordinated debentures with the view toward obtaining modifications or elimination of these restrictive covenants. There can be no assurance that the company will be able to obtain any modifications, or do so on terms acceptable to the company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ORANGE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
