<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173759" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: STATE DEBT IN CHECK SOONER THAN EXPECTED - LIPPONEN.</title>
<headline>STATE DEBT IN CHECK SOONER THAN EXPECTED - LIPPONEN.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Paavo Lipponen said on Thursday that the Finnish state's indebtedness was being brought under control sooner than expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The indebtedness of the state finances is being brought under control sooner than expected. The public sector debt in relation to gross domestic product will turn into a fall according to a more favourable than expected timetable,&quot; Lipponen was quoted as saying in a trade union newsletter.</p>
<p>Copies of the interview in the newsletter of the Confederation of Salaried Employees (STTK) were made available to the media in advance of publication.</p>
<p>Lipponen gave no details of the trends in state indebtedness or public sector debt to GDP that he referred to.</p>
<p>He said Finland had &quot;no problems with inflation or interest rates.&quot; The quicker fall in public debt to GDP would be seen in market interest rates and state borrowing, he added.</p>
<p>Referring to the government's drive to put Finland in shape to join the third phase of Europe's planned Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), Lipponen said: &quot;EMU will be the community's inner circle, which will move forward. It is inevitably also a question of influence when the choice is made about who will remain outside.&quot;</p>
<p>Lipponen also said the government did not want to dictate any terms to trade unions or employers ahead of the next round of incomes settlement talks duer in the autumn of 1997.</p>
<p>But he said the outcome of the 1995 round of pay talks -- a two-year nationwide pay deal with low nominal pay rises spiced with income tax cuts -- was encouraging.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the interests (of various social parties) fit together quite well if disposable income increases. The more stable the (pay rise) trend, the better the possibilities to continue the policy of tax reductions,&quot; Lipponen said.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom  +358 - 9 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
