<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173704" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hospital meals: fat, cholesterol and salt - study.</title>
<headline>Hospital meals: fat, cholesterol and salt - study.</headline>
<byline>Gene Emery</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hospital meals may be loaded with fat, cholesterol and salt, according to a study to be published in Thursday's New England Journal of Medicine.</p>
<p>A survey of 57 teaching hospitals found only one in 14 routinely offers meals to patients that meet the latest guidelines for promoting health and reducing heart disease. The study's authors, in a letter to the Journal, said it was &quot;discouraging&quot; that hospitals offering state-of-the-art treatments did not necessarily offer state-of-the-art diets.</p>
<p>Led by Dr. Adam Singer of the State University of New York at Stony Brook, the team based its work on nutrition standards published in 1989 by the National Research Council's Committee on Diet and Health. Using those standards to assess three daily menus from each of the 57 hospitals they found that:</p>
<p>-- 39 percent had too much fat and 47 percent had too much saturated fat. According to the standard, only 30 percent of the calories in the diet are supposed to come from fat; the limit for saturated fat is 10 percent.</p>
<p>-- 81 percent had more than the recommended 300 milligrams per day of cholesterol.</p>
<p>-- 54 percent had too much salt. Six milligrams is supposed to be the daily limit.</p>
<p>Hospitals did a better job of giving fruits, vegetables and grains to patients, the team concluded. Only 12 percent of the hospitals failed to offer enough fruits and vegetables and only 7 percent failed to provide enough breads and cereals.</p>
<p>&quot;Hospitals should assume a greater role in promoting more healthful diets. We cannot think of a more appropriate place to encourage the nutritional health of Americans,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
