<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173763" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: IONIAN BANK LAUNCHES NEW HOUSING LOAN PRODUCTS.</title>
<headline>IONIAN BANK LAUNCHES NEW HOUSING LOAN PRODUCTS.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>State Ionian Bank is expanding its loan products with two new housing loans for households and business clients, it President Haris Stamatopoulos announced on Thursday.</p>
<p>The new Ionian housing loan offers households the choice of either a floating or a fixed rate and a maturity of 15 years.</p>
<p>&quot;The floating rate housing loan is set at 15.5 percent, currently the market's lowest, with associated expenses like title search also squeezed lower. The fixed-rate loan is set at 13.00 percent for the first five years,&quot; Ionian Bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>The loans also feature a grace period of 18 months and for young couples they may be extended to 20 years, it said. Up to 100 percent of the cost of building, renovating or purchasing a home or even land may be financed by the new loan product.</p>
<p>For business housing and equipment needs Ionian is introducing its new business housing and equipment loan product with the same terms except that the rates, both fixed or floating are 100 basis points higher.</p>
<p>&quot;Ionian's loans for business equipment are for seven years with a floating rate of 19.5 percent and a six-month grace period,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The rates on both loan types do not include the special 4.0 percent tax surcharge known as EFTE and a 1.0 percent add-on as per law 128/75.</p>
<p>--George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
