<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17376" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SYRIA: Syria says Palestinian leader to stay in country.</title>
<headline>Syria says Palestinian leader to stay in country.</headline>
<byline>Issam Hamza</byline>
<dateline>DAMASCUS 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign Minister Farouq al-Shara on Tuesday denied an Israeli newspaper report that Damascus wanted a radical Palestinian guerrilla leader to leave Syria.</p>
<p>Israel's English-language newspaper Jerusalem Post reported on Monday that Syrian President Hafez al-Assad had asked Ahmed Jibril of the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine General-Command (PFLP-GC) to leave Syria and go to Iran.</p>
<p>&quot;These are baseless and unrealistic reports. No Palestinian could be expelled from Syria. The presence of the Palestinians here in Syria among their brothers is caused by their expulsion from their main homeland in Palestine,&quot; Shara said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Palestinians in Syria leave only by their own well and to their homeland,&quot; Shara said.</p>
<p>&quot;If those Palestinians are expelled from Syria and Arab states where should they go?&quot; asked Shara.</p>
<p>The PFLP-GC had already denied the report in an official statement issued on Monday.</p>
<p>Syria hosts over 500,000 Palestinian refugees, including leaders of a 10-member radical Palestinian alliance which opposes peace with Israel and calls for military struggle against the Jewish state.</p>
<p>Syria had rejected demands by Israel and the United States to expel the Palestinian leaders whose groups claimed several attacks in which socres of Israelis were killed.</p>
<p>The United States keeps Syria on a list of countries which allegedly sponsor international terrorism.</p>
<p>Shara said the presence of Syria's name on the list was political and because of the Israeli pressure on Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;We challenged the United States to give us a single proof of any Syrian involvement in international terrorism and there was nothing. The only reason for the existence of Syria's name there is because we host the Palestinians,&quot; Shara said.</p>
<p>Shara also rejected Israeli displeasure over reports that Syria possessed long-range missles capable of bombing Israeli targets.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole world knows that Israel possesses the biggest military conventional and non-conventional arsenal in the region. Israel with this arsenal challenges the whole Arab military capabilities,&quot; shara said.</p>
<p>Israeli television reported that Damascus had recently test-fired a Scud C missile able to hit most cities in the Jewish state.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SYRIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAMASCUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SYRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
