<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173793" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bond markets take fright as yen stalks again.</title>
<headline>Bond markets take fright as yen stalks again.</headline>
<byline>Adam Cox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Government bond markets were rattled on Thursday by the prospect that a resurgent yen could wipe out months of hard-won gains by U.S. Treasuries.</p>
<p>Only a day after bond investors were celebrating the results of U.S. elections, an influential Japanese trade official sent shock waves through financial markets with comments suggesting the dollar's rally against the yen was near an end.</p>
<p>This currency move has been one of the driving forces behind a recovery in the Treasuries market. Now dealers said investors were starting to panic.</p>
<p>&quot;This could be critical,&quot; said Bill Westgate, senior vice president at HSBC in London. &quot;Maybe this is just a wobble in the bond market, but for those of us who have been long this is definitely a time to take the chips off the table.&quot;</p>
<p>A dealer at a U.S. bank in London said the predominant trade of late had been where investors borrowed in yen, bought dollars, and then invested those into Treasuries.</p>
<p>&quot;What is nerve-wracking is that whenever the dollar backs up, those people get worried. If those trades do get unwound, that means selling of Treasuries and more selling of dollar/yen,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Until recently this strategy seemed perfect.</p>
<p>Investors could borrow at rock-bottom interest rates in yen, invest in a currency whose prospects looked bright and, on top of that, get higher interest rates in U.S. Treasury bonds.</p>
<p>Short-term yen rates range from 0.38 percent at three months to 0.62 percent for one year. Meanwhile the dollar has rallied from 106.30 yen in July to nearly 115.00 yen in late October.</p>
<p>By the time investors got their money into the long end of the U.S., they were getting rates of more than 6.5 percent.</p>
<p>Westgate said there had been heavy net purchases of U.S. assets by overseas accounts in recent months.</p>
<p>But Japanese Ministry of Finance official Eisuke Sakakibara, known in financial markets as &quot;Mr Yen&quot;, was quoted in a newspaper as saying the dollar's recovery was about to end, and that the MOF was not trying to push the yen down further.</p>
<p>The dollar, which traded as high as 114.67 yen on Wednesday after the U.S. election, had sunk to 111.78/88 yen by 1130 GMT.</p>
<p>The 30-year U.S. long bond slumped to 101-04, yielding 6.66 percent, from 101-23 at the New York close on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We've just been wallopped in bonds all morning from speculative accounts,&quot; one dealer said. He said he had only seen one-way flows although he had heard that other houses were seeing some buying.</p>
<p>The MOF reports also knocked back Japanese government bonds (JGBs), although there was talk that Japanese investors were covering some short positions, at least in JGBs.</p>
<p>Michael Derks, a cross market fixed income strategist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell in London, said it was too early to take the view the dollar would succumb to the pressure and that bonds in turn would feel the pain.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a little bit too simple to say the only reason Treasuries have rallied is because dollar/yen's gone up,&quot; he said. He said that even with these comments, there was no guarantee the dollar would willingly step back.</p>
<p>One of the chief reasons Treasuries have done so well in recent months is that U.S. authorities have been right in expecting a second-half economic slowdown, analysts said.</p>
<p>December T-bond futures have climbed more than nine full points in just two months, reaching a 114-15 high on Wednesday from 105-09 in early September. But they slipped to 113-07 in automated trade in London on Thursday from a 113-20 Wednesday close in Chicago.</p>
<p>The U.S. election results were also seen as a winning formula for Treasuries, with President Clinton staying in the White House but Republicans retaining control of both Houses of Congress. The markets had been concerned Democrats -- perceived to be high-spending -- might recapture one or both Houses.</p>
<p>Now, analysts said, the markets are decidedly looking to Japan, not the White House, for direction.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
