<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17372" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish lira firmer at close, money rates ease.</title>
<headline>Turkish lira firmer at close, money rates ease.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Turkish lira firmed to 86,165 per dollar from 86,200 at Monday's close because the lower dollar/mark parity reduced demand for dollars.</p>
<p>Overnight money rates closed at 74.25 percent, down from Monday's 74.78 percent, and the central bank did not fund banks after lending 14.2 trillion lira through overnight dealings on Monday at 75 percent.</p>
<p>Some 51.5 trillion lira will be cashed in from the treasury's t-bill maturities on Wednesdsay, while a total of 40.6 trillion lira will leave the system due to t-bill auction payments and repo repayments to the central bank.</p>
<p>The treasury said it would give banks the option to buy today's March 3, 1997 t-bill auction paper at an average rate of 107.59 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The treasury auctioned 36.16 trillion lira worth of March 3, 1997 paper and raised the average yield by six points from the previous 211-day t-bill auction.</p>
<p>T-bill yields were mixed. In the most active December 4 paper, the yield fell to 118.10 percent from 118.25 on Monday, but yields on longer papers rose.</p>
<p>The yield on the second most active paper, the February 26 bills, firmed to 133.10 percent from 131.44 at Tuesday's close.</p>
<p>Yields of March 5, 1997 paper, sold at an average of 135 percent at today's auction, fell to 133.23 percent with Wednesday's value on profit taking. --Istanbul newsroom +90-212-275 08 75</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
