<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="173810" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: DTB-New Euromark futures to pull trade from LIFFE.</title>
<headline>DTB-New Euromark futures to pull trade from LIFFE.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Terminboerse (DTB) board member Joerg Franke said on Thursday the planned introduction of new one- and three-month Euromark futures would help the German exchange attract business away from London.</p>
<p>&quot;The new Euromark futures will enable DTB participants to trade the entire deutschemark yield curve from one month to 10 years,&quot; Franke told a news conference in London. &quot;We can offer a one stop shop.&quot;</p>
<p>DTB's new one-month future will be launched on November 12, while a new three-month Euromark contract is due for launch on January 14.</p>
<p>Citing a number of differences between the DTB and its rival, the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE), Franke said the DTB contracts would be competitive with LIFFE's existing three-month future and with a new one-month LIFFE product due for launch on November 21.</p>
<p>He said DTB's market-making structure, its electronic trading system and the existing over-the-counter (OTC) market in Germany would aid the success of the new contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;The OTC market needs a complementary market on the exchange,&quot; Franke said in a prepared speech. &quot;It has been suggested that up to 20 percent of LIFFE's trading volume in the three-month Euromark future is done by German players. Why shouldn't they trade though DTB?&quot;</p>
<p>Franke said the DTB expected to have more than 50 percent of the trading volume in the new one-month contract while also bringing &quot;at least the percentage of LIFFE's trading volume in the three-month Euromark future that is made by German members&quot; back to Germany.</p>
<p>-- Kate Kelland, International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 8682</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
