<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174034" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Senate charman vows industry-friendly mining bill.</title>
<headline>Senate charman vows industry-friendly mining bill.</headline>
<byline>Yereth Rosen</byline>
<dateline>ANCHORAGE, Alaska 1996-11-06</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of the Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee said Wednesday he will introduce an industry-friendly mining reform bill to help head off more pro-environmental legislation backed by Democrats.</p>
<p>Sen. Frank Murkowski, an Alaska Republican, said he hopes to submit a mining reform bill to compete with a proposal likely to come from Sen. Dale Bumpers, an Arkansas Democrat and ardent environmentalist.</p>
<p>Although he predicted Bumpers' bill will not pass, Murkowski said in a speech at the Alaska Miners Association annual convention &quot;we need to draft responsible legislation that takes an edge off their drastic and irresponsible legislation.&quot;</p>
<p>Murkowski said the retirement of Sen. Bennett Johnston, a Louisiana Democrat who was somewhat industry friendly, is likely to result in a more pro-environment policy among minority members of the Energy and Natural Resources Committee -- starting with Bumpers, who will become the ranking minority member.</p>
<p>Bumpers wants to impose an 8 percent royalty on hard-rock minerals taken from federal lands and to eliminate the patent provision that transfers ownership of federal lands to miners who have staked claims there, Murkowski said.</p>
<p>The target is the Mining Law of 1872, cherished by miners and attacked by environmentalists, U.S. Interior Secretary Bruce Babbitt and many economists as an anacronism.</p>
<p>Under the 124-year-old law, miners pay no royalties for hard-rock minerals taken from federal lands. Miners also get to keep the land where their operations are located by filing claims there.</p>
<p>Babbitt and other critics of the law say miners should pay royalties for gold and other metals taken from federal lands, as extractors of oil and coal already do.</p>
<p>Murkowski said development supporters will have to soften their stances somewhat to be successful in the new Congress, even though Republicans widened their majority in the Senate and pro-development Alaskans kept control of key Senate and House committees.</p>
<p>&quot;To some extent, we're going to have to take a defensive posture on some of our issues,&quot; he said at the miners' gathering.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-06"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANCHORAGE, Alaska"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
