<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174262" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SOCCER-JAPAN TO HOST WORLD CUP FINAL, OFFICIALS SAY.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JAPAN TO HOST WORLD CUP FINAL, OFFICIALS SAY.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan and South Korea have cleared the first and biggest hurdle of the 2002 World Cup by agreeing to play the opening match in Seoul and the final in Japan, officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan will stage the final and the closing ceremony and South Korea the opening game and the opening ceremony,&quot; said an official in Seoul at the Office of Preparation for 2002 FIFA World Cup.</p>
<p>The deal was confirmed by Japanese officials and it now needs formal approval only by a FIFA Executive Committee meeting in Barcelona on December 7.</p>
<p>The agreements were reached at a meeting in Zurich on Wednesday that was arranged by world soccer's governing body, FIFA, the Seoul official said.</p>
<p>In Zurich, however, president of the South Korean football association Dr Chung Moon-Jong refused to comment on the reports.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no comment to make on any of that,&quot; he said. &quot;I am not denying it, or confirming it. If that is what they are saying in Seoul, that is what they are saying, but I am not saying anything.&quot;</p>
<p>The official in Seoul said the two countries had agreed to call the event the 2002 FIFA World Cup Korea-Japan, resolving a sensitive issue of who should be mentioned first.</p>
<p>The final would be one match and not two, and, as in France in 1998, the tournament will comprise 32 teams and 64 matches.</p>
<p>The Seoul official said he had confirmed the details of the agreements with South Korean delegates in Zurich.</p>
<p>&quot;This is unbelieveable that it's been decided so quickly,&quot; one Japanese soccer official said. &quot;Not just for soccer but for relations between our two countries. We've showed we can work things out.&quot;</p>
<p>Ties between South Korea and Japan are often strained by rivalry as intense as an India-Pakistan or England-Germany sporting clash. The rivalry is rooted in Tokyo's 35-year colonial occupation of Korea and the events of World War Two.</p>
<p>The Seoul official said details on the financial arrangements remained unresolved and could be discussed in Barcelona.</p>
<p>&quot;Draws for the qualifying and final rounds would be held in Japan, according to the decision made in the study group,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>FIFA spokesman Marius Schneider maintained FIFA's vow of silence over the issues agreed on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot possibly make any statement on any reports of this nature,&quot; he said, referring to the leaked news from Seoul.</p>
<p>&quot;Lennart Johansson (who chaired Wednesday's World Cup 2002 Study Group), made FIFA's position quite clear on Wednesday and the situation has not changed. The decisions taken by the Study Group will be put before the next executive committee meeting which meets in Barcelona on December 7.&quot;</p>
<p>Japan and Korea sent six-man delegations to the meeting, led by Japan Football Association president Ken Naganuma and his Korean counterpart Chung Moon-Jong.</p>
<p>Besides agreeing on the final, and the name of the event, the study group also agreed on, among other things, the event logo and mascot, composition of organising committees and the competition format, venues and time schedules.</p>
<p>But after the meeting Johansson stunned more than 120 media representatives, many of whom had flown from Japan and Korea especially for the meeting, by saying that FIFA would release no details of what had been decided.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
