<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174220" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Iraq's Anbari sees no US change in oil deal til January 1997.</title>
<headline>Iraq's Anbari sees no US change in oil deal til January 1997.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq's chief oil negotiator Abdul Amir Al-Anbari said on Thursday he did not expect any change in the U.S. position on the oil-for-food deal until January 1997 at the earliest.  </p>
<p>Anbari, in an interview with Reuters in Geneva, also said the U.S. was the only country in the U.N. Security Council to object to Baghdad's proposed pricing formula under the pact agreed earlier this year.</p>
<p>Anbari, asked whether he expected any change in the U.S. policy on the oil-for-food deal in light of President Bill Clinton's re-election, said he hoped the U.S. leader would take into account the humanitarian aspects of sanctions.</p>
<p>Asked whether he expected any changes ahead of an OPEC ministerial meeting later this month, he replied: &quot;I hope so, but I doubt it. I believe the U.S. will be holding their position until January 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The deal allows Iraqi partial oil sales worth $2 billion over six months to raise money for food and medical supplies to alleviate the effects of U.N. sanctions imposed after its 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
