<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174244" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RAINBOW CHICKEN SAYS CAN'T PREDICT 2ND HALF.</title>
<headline>RAINBOW CHICKEN SAYS CAN'T PREDICT 2ND HALF.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Struggling broiler producer Rainbow Chicken Ltd said on Thursday it was impossible to give an indication of second half prospects.</p>
<p>The company said it had made some headway with an action programme announced earlier this year involving substantial investment which would not be completed before December 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Some progress has already been made in this direction but much still has to be achieved,&quot; the companmy said in a statement with half year results.</p>
<p>&quot;A meaningful indication of the expected results for the second half of the year cannot be given at this time.&quot;</p>
<p>The attributable loss in the six months to end-September increased to 164.4 million rand from 57.2 million a year ago. The company had warned in August that it faced a 165 million rand loss in the period.</p>
<p>Rainbow said it had been hit by low prices and rising feed costs, a situation aggravated by the fall in the rand. However, the group's previously excessive stock levels returned to normal in September and chicken prices have since firmed.</p>
<p>Rainbow received a 550.3 million rand cash injection following a rights issue on September 30 and a final 118.0 million on October 3.</p>
<p>Earlier this week Jorge Antonio Del Corral Ibarrondo was appointed as the new managing director, effective from mid-November. Del Corral was formerly chief executive of Mexico's Bachoco SA, one of the largest producers of broilers, eggs and pork in Latin America.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41230">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
