<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174457" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian Stocks to Watch Today - Nov 7.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian Stocks to Watch Today - Nov 7.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Some Australian stocks to watch this morning:</p>
<p>* News Corp Ltd A$7.22 (-0.01)</p>
<p>Time Warner Inc won a major court battle Wednesday when a federal judge issued a preliminary injunction that stops New York City from airing Rupert Murdoch's Fox News on a city-run cable television channel. Also Moody's Investors Service assigned a &quot;Ba2&quot; rating to News Corporation Exchange Trust's exchangeable trust originated preferred securities (TOPrs). News was also given an initial neutral rating by Lehman brothers.</p>
<p>* RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd A$19.64 (-0.19)</p>
<p>Aber Resources Ltd said in Vancouver overnight diamonds from the A-154 South Pipe at the Diavik property in Canada's Northwest Territories were valued at an average US$56.10 a carat based on a sample of about 7,210 carats. The valuation was done by CRA Diamonds, a unit of RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd which holds a 60 percent stake in the property through RTZ's Kennecott unit.</p>
<p>* Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd A$16.71 (-0.13)</p>
<p>Allegheny Teledyne Inc said in a letter to customers it will increase prices on stainless steel sheet, strip and plate products, reducing discounts by three percentage points from March 3.</p>
<p>* National Australia Bank Ltd A$13.85 (-0.04) Thailand has granted an offshore banking licence to National Australia Bank Ltd, The Australian newspaper reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>* Foodland Associated Ltd A$5.60 (+0.04)</p>
<p>Progressive Enterprises Ltd said on Thursday total group sales for the 13 weeks ended October 27 were NZ$517.98 million. This was 0.5 percent below the first quarter of the previous year. Foodland owns 58 percent of progressive.</p>
<p>* Freedom Furniture A$1.16 (+0.02)</p>
<p>Freedom Furniture Ltd said on Thursday it had made earnings before interest, tax and abnormals (EBIT) of A$10.2 million for the 12 months to September 30, 1996 and would post a final dividend of 1.5 cents per share.</p>
<p>* Devex Ltd A$0.44 (+0.005)</p>
<p>Devex Ltd said on Thursday its previously announced share buyback would proceed on a 1-for-11 basis, with each share to be priced at 55 cents. It said this payment represented a 28 percent premium over the average share market price over the last 30 days.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
