<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174411" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Gulf and Hardy examine Command.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Gulf and Hardy examine Command.</headline>
<byline>Ian Pemberton</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two international oil firms with operations in the Asia/Pacific region, Gulf Canada Resources Ltd and Hardy Oil and Gas Plc, had conducted due diligence on Command Petroleum Holdings NL to see if they could better the A$354.5 million bid by Cairn Energy Plc, market sources told Reuters.</p>
<p>Invited by the Command board of directors, Gulf and Hardy examined the predominantly Indian-based assets of the company over the last few weeks but were unable to increase the cash offer of A$1.10 per share.  </p>
<p>Snyder Oil Corp, Command's largest shareholder with a 32.6 percent stake, agreed to the Cairn bid when a higher offer did not emerge, the sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Two other parties were invited by the Command board to go into a data room and do due diligence to see if could come up with a higher bid which would have been a nuisance for Cairn,&quot; one source said. &quot;Each of those parties could get to A$1.10 which is the Cairn offer price but neither of them could get much beyond that.&quot;</p>
<p>Cairn announced the agreed takeover of Command on October 2, offering either cash or a two-for-13 share swap.  </p>
<p>Command shares soared to a year's high of A$1.24 soon after the bid was announced due to speculation that the oil producer and explorer was likely to receive a higher bid.</p>
<p>The Australian petroleum exploration industry has seen a number of takeovers this year, with local companies viewed as undervalued and therefore attractive to foreign firms seeking to expand their production and exploration acreage.</p>
<p>Hardy Petroleum Ltd, the local unit of Hardy oil and Gas, said it could not comment on the Command talks. Hardy Petroleum chief executive Chas Greenway said the company often examined the data of other firms, subject to confidentiality clauses.  </p>
<p>Command's major asset is a 22.5 percent interest in the big Ravva oil and gas field off the Indian coast in the Bay of Bengal. It also has gas producing assets in Papua New Guinea and exploration acreage in Yemen and Russia.</p>
<p>Cairn also has significant gas exploration activities in the Bay of Bengal, and cited the complimentary nature of the two companies work in India and Bangladesh as one reason for the agreed bid.</p>
<p>Command shares ended one cent higher at A$1.13 on solid turnover of 4.36 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
