<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174441" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's CHH seen emerging from commodities gloom.</title>
<headline>NZ's CHH seen emerging from commodities gloom.</headline>
<byline>James Gray</byline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Forest products group Carter Holt Harvey Ltd on Thursday showed tentative signs that it was slowly emerging from the depths of a commodities slump with a slight improvement in second quarter earnings.</p>
<p>First half earnings for the International Paper-controlled CHH slumped to NZ$118 million (US$83.8 million) in the six months to September from $271 million a year earlier, but second quarter earnings were up at $62 million from $56 million in the first quarter.</p>
<p>Analysts said the first quarter probably reflected the worst of the pulp and paper cycle but they did not rule out the possibility further price falls, despite recent improvements.</p>
<p>Chief Executive John Faraci told analysts and journalists the company had already realised NZ$8.0 million in cost savings, was on target for $25 million in the current year and for savings of $50 million in 1997/8.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say I'm cautiously optimistic, but clearly our second quarter was an improvement over the first quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There had been price improvements in paper businesses but most of the quarter-to-quarter gain came from better margins and efficiency gains.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see a good snap back in either log markets or in the wood markets although I think the correction from here is up, it will be up at a fairly modest pace,&quot; Faraci said.</p>
<p>He saw little likelihood of &quot;price spikes&quot; on the horizon, so earnings improvements would therefore come from within the company as opposed to market-led factors.</p>
<p>Faraci said he saw continued growth of the company in a planned and managed way and its recent acquisition for A$125 million of Australia's Forward Products was an example of that.</p>
<p>The Forward purchase made CHH the second largest marketer of wood products in the Australian market, he said.</p>
<p>David Stanley at Doyle Paterson Brown said he was confident the company's second half would be better than the first and analysts generally expect a full year result in the high NZ$200 millions against the previous year's record of NZ$453 million.</p>
<p>The first half result was in line with expectations, but the company's operating performance was a little better than anticipated.</p>
<p>Since the start of the financial year, the price of softwood pulp and risen to US$550 from $500 per tonne.</p>
<p>But there was still uncertainty in the industry and a risk that pulp and paper prices could still drop.</p>
<p>&quot;It's really in the hands of the northern hemisphere pulp producers as to what happens there,&quot; Doyle Paterson's Stanley said. &quot;If they restrain production then the market should tighten going into 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite that, the second half -- under most scenarios -- is going to be better because wood products are looking better.&quot;</p>
<p>Francis Loo at SBC Warburg said opinions varied on the commodities outlook, but that SBC belonged to the &quot;slow recovery scenario&quot;. However, the overall picture of the company was one where its three main businesses were at the bottom of their cycles rather than the top.</p>
<p>&quot;The only question will be the quantum of pickup and I guess that's the question that is on everybody's mind at the moment,&quot; Loo said.</p>
<p>US$1 = NZ$1.41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
