<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174525" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sony earnings jump sharply thanks to good sales.</title>
<headline>Sony earnings jump sharply thanks to good sales.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Consumer electronics giant Sony Corp said on Thursday its half-year net profit more than tripled thanks to robust sales in its electronics and entertainment businesses.</p>
<p>Sony said it expects the upward trend to continue and forecast its group operating profit would reach a record 305 billion yen ($2.72 billion) for the full business year ending March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>Sony's group net income, which includes that of Sony and its units worldwide, shot up to 51.74 billion yen ($461 million) in the six months ended September from 16.09 billion yen ($144 million) a year earlier.</p>
<p>Its group sales in the same half-year period were up 23 percent at 2.53 trillion yen ($22.5 billion).</p>
<p>Sales in the group's electronics business and the entertainment business grew sharply, but revenues from its insurance and financing business fell.</p>
<p>The rise in sales in the electronics division was due to the company's cost-cutting and strong sales overseas which were helped by the yen's fall, Sony said.</p>
<p>A weaker yen makes Japanese companies' products more competitive abroad because it makes them cheaper in terms of foreign currency.</p>
<p>In the entertainment business, sales grew due to the weak yen as well as strong sales, it said.</p>
<p>Sony's entertainment group includes Sony Pictures Entertainment, the umbrella company for Columbia and Tri-Star Pictures and Sony Music Entertainment.</p>
<p>Industry analysts say Sony Pictures has struggled to achieve the same performance as its peers, with a big part of its profits coming from television operations rather than the film unit.</p>
<p>The performance of its films &quot;The Cable Guy&quot;, &quot;The Fan&quot; and &quot;Multiplicity&quot; this summer was disappointing, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
