<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174791" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: KL interbank rates fall on decline in overnight.</title>
<headline>KL interbank rates fall on decline in overnight.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Interbank rates dropped across the board in a reaction to the sharp fall in the overnight rate on Wednesday, dealers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>They said one-week money dropped to 7.10/15 percent against 7.50/70 previously, two-week was at 7.15/20 against 7.50/80 and one-month at 7.20/23 against 7.30.</p>
<p>Three-month money was quoted at 7.23/25 percent against 7.26/32 and six-month was at 7.25/30 against 7.28/35.  </p>
<p>The dealers said the overnight rate fell to around 6.0 percent from 8.6 in the last few minutes before trading ended on Wednesday. They said aggressive lending, particularly by foreign banks, caused the drop in the overnight rate.</p>
<p>They said liquidity had improved quite suddenly, though the reasons were not immediately clear.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be that the dollar/ringgit's decline in the last two days has put some money back in the hands of foreign banks,&quot; a dealer with a foreign bank said.</p>
<p>The ringgit has recovered by over 100 points after declining by over 250 points last week.  </p>
<p>&quot;It could also be that some Bank Negara fund that the market does not know about has matured,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Bank Negara regularly intervenes in the interbank market to keep a check on liquidity and set interest rates. It usually borrows through an open tender, but sometimes approaches select banks directly.</p>
<p>Bank Negara could not be contacted for a comment.</p>
<p>Dealers said the fall was expected to be limited to around the current levels as Bank Negara has made clear it will maintain its tight monetary policy for the rest of the year.  </p>
<p>The falling interbank rates accelerated buying in interest rate futures on the Malaysia Monetary Exchange, dealers said.</p>
<p>Volume rose sharply to 318 lots by 0245 GMT for all contracts based on the Kuala Lumpur Interbank Offered Rate.</p>
<p>Spot month December contract was up one point at 92.83, or an implied yield of 7.17 percent.</p>
<p>Next year's contracts were all sharply higher. March was up six points to 93.01, June up seven at 93.14, September rose seven to 93.19 and December gained six to 93.18.</p>
<p>- Madhav Reddy (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
