<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="174974" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Nov 7.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Nov 7.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Thursday morning's Austrian newspapers:</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- Chamber of Economy is planning to reform Austria's professional licensing system, as it has been heavily criticised in the past for being too complicated.</p>
<p>- Introduction of the European Union's single currency Euro will cost Austria's banks up to eight billion schillings.</p>
<p>- Car engineer Steyr-Daimler-Puch plans to enlarge the firm's R&amp;D units.</p>
<p>- Even though the Austrian electricity industry posted pre-tax profits up 1.4 billion schillings to 4.5 billion schillings last year, liberalisation of the industry in the near future may bring about a rash of insolvencies.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- Conservative People's party is against the Social Democrats' proposition of imposing taxes on national health contributions.</p>
<p>- Austria will have to work hard to reduce the country's deficit in order to make it into the European Monetary Union, the EU Commission said.</p>
<p>- Austria to target Japan with a huge advertising campaign in a bid to gain more tourists.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Bank Austria will take over German bank WestLB's Austrian subsidiary WestLB Austria through a share swap.</p>
<p>O NACHRICHTEN</p>
<p>- Upper Austria's Hypo Landesbank will most probably be sold to Raiffeisen bank. The sale is expected to be announced today.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
