<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17499" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gingrich public enemy number one for Democrats.</title>
<headline>Gingrich public enemy number one for Democrats.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican House Speaker Newt Ginrich and not presidential nominee Bob Dole emerged on Monday as chief bogeyman on the first night of the Democratic convention.</p>
<p>Several speakers virtually ignored Dole and his running mate Jack Kemp in their remarks and took dead aim at Gingrich. Some sought to link the three.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, we are ready to defeat the Dole-Kemp-Gingrich ticket,&quot; said Democratic chairman Don Fowler, conveniently ignoring the fact that Gingrich is not on the ticket.</p>
<p>Polls have consistently identified Gingrich as the most unpopular leading Republican. For that reason, he adopted an uncharacteristically low profile at the Republican convention in San Diego earlier this month.</p>
<p>He made one brief appearance on the podium in which he avoided harsh jabs at the opposition and puzzled many by praising the growth of the sport of beach volleyball as the embodiment of American free enterprise.</p>
<p>For the same reason that Republicans kept Gingrich in the background, Democrats are pushing him into the limelight.</p>
<p>&quot;To do what's right, Bill Clinton faced down the Gingrich-Dole Congress to stop the Medicare cuts, the student loan cuts, the cuts in school lunches and the environment,&quot; said House Minority Leader Dick Gephardt.</p>
<p>Gephardt recalled the January day in 1995 that Gingrich took over control of the House of Representatives for the Republicans as the worst in his life.</p>
<p>The very first speaker on the podium lost no time in linking Dole with Gingrich.</p>
<p>&quot;The Republican Party's leaders have been re-inventing the truth. They want to force the Gingrich-Dole agenda on our parents, our children, our families,&quot; said Bill Purcell, a Democratic state representative from Tennessee.</p>
<p>Anne Mackenzie, co-chair of the Democratic Rules Committee, made the message even plainer. &quot;Yo Newt, get a heart, get a soul, get another job in Georgia,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Texas Representative Martin Frost also joined the assault, accusing Gingrich of trying to take school lunches out of the mouths of American children.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
