<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175080" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X jumps on rumors.</title>
<headline>Bre-X jumps on rumors.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Bre-X Minerals Ltd spiked up more than two points over a half-hour period on Friday amid a wave of market rumors swirling around the company, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a rumor a COW is imminent,&quot; said one trader. Bre-X rose 2.60 to 23.80 on more than 1.8 million shares in Friday morning trading.</p>
<p>Bre-X, which controls the spectacular Busang gold discovery in Indonesia, has been awaiting crucial contracts of work for months. The Indonesian government has delayed the contracts due to an ownership dispute.  </p>
<p>One of Bre-X's Indonesian partners has claimed up to 40 percent of the discovery. The Indonesian government has said it will not issue permits until Bre-X settles the claim.</p>
<p>Bre-X stock has been volatile because of uncertainty over the ownership. Recently Bre-X announced it had formed an alliance with the son of Indonesia's President Suharto to help the company win the permits quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is up because there's a rumor that they will soon have a contract of work,&quot; confirmed gold analyst Michael Fowler of Levesque Beaubien Geoffrion. &quot;But those are just rumors.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bre-X would not comment, maintaining the silence it has held since it announced its alliance with Suharto's son on October 28.</p>
<p>The company is searching for a major mining company to act as an operator and part or full owner of the deposit, but analysts said a  deal will likely need to wait until Bre-X won its permits.</p>
<p>&quot;The street is torn. They want to see if Suharto is sitting on all the COWs because he's been told that payoffs will happen,&quot; said gold analyst Catherine Gignac with Deacon Capital Corp. &quot;The indications from people close to Bre-X are that it will be resolved quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Heather Scoffield, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8104</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
