<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175044" id="root" date="1996-11-07" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Gates fortune tops $20 billion as Microsoft rises.</title>
<headline>Gates fortune tops $20 billion as Microsoft rises.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-11-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Say hello to the $20 billion man.</p>
<p>When Microsoft Corp. stock rose Wednesday, Chairman Bill Gates' stake in the giant software company grew in value to more than $20 billion, according to recent disclosure statements.</p>
<p>Gates, America's wealthiest individual, owned slightly more than 141 million shares, or about 24 percent of the Redmond, Wash.-based company, as of Sept. 9, according to a proxy statement.</p>
<p>Microsoft rose $3 to $144.50, giving Gates a stake valued at about $20.37 billion.</p>
<p>That's up from about $13.13 billion a year ago, reflecting a 55 percent increase in Microsoft stock price -- and Gates' sale of nearly 52,000 shares for living expenses.</p>
<p>Gates earned only $563,000 in salary and bonus in the latest fiscal year and is the only one of Microsoft's 20,000 employees not eligible for stock options.</p>
<p>Gates, 41, was ranked the richest man in America by Forbes magazine last month, when his fortune was valued at a mere $18.5 billion.</p>
<p>Nebraska investor Warren Buffett was second with a stock-based fortune of $15 billion.</p>
<p>Third on the list was Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen, whose Microsoft stake was worth $7.7 billion at Wednesday's prices. Allen, who sits on Microsoft's board but no longer manages the company, also owns sports, entertainment and technology properties including Ticketmaster.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-07"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
