<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175191" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NAM's Jasinowski -- dlr too high for some firms - RFTV.</title>
<headline>NAM's Jasinowski -- dlr too high for some firms - RFTV.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>National Association of Manufacturers President Jerry Jasinowski said Friday that the dollar was still too strong for some manufacturing firms attempting to be competitive overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes, I think it is from the point of view of a number of manufacturing firms,&quot; he said in an interview on Reuters Financial Television, noting that the dollar has been run up about 40 percent against the yen in the past 18 months.</p>
<p>He said that the firms that have been affected represent a major part of the American economy, including autos, aircraft equipment, computers and informational processing equipment and other big capital items that are engaged in international trade.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Jasinowski told a post-election briefing for reporters that he doubted the administration would be trying to jawbone the dollar stronger with the economy appearing to weaken, although it was also unlikely to seek to talk it down.</p>
<p>He repeated this on Friday, saying that &quot;I think that is about over, and neither the Japanese nor the U.S. are going to be talking about that as much.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said that the trade association has not approached the administration directly about the strong dollar, preferring to make its feelings known through public statements, but will pursue it further with them now.</p>
<p>But he said the administration had responded to industries that have complained about the dollar strength by saying that it reflected efforts by the Japanese to weaken their own currency to buoy exports.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the response is ...that to some extent this is occurring on the other side of the water, which I think is of course true,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Jasinowski said that he saw the U.S. economy in a stable but slow growth path with little wage inflation.</p>
<p>He said that the restocking of inventories had largely been completed and that firms had them about where they wanted them to be, adding &quot;that we're going to have a decent Christmas season.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
