<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175237" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Japan not readying to hike rates soon - U.S. experts.</title>
<headline>Japan not readying to hike rates soon - U.S. experts.</headline>
<byline>Roanne Daniels</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. experts dismissed market and foreign press speculation that Japanese officials were trying to lay the groundwork for a near-term official discount rate hike with recent remarks that helped strengthen the yen.</p>
<p>While Japan's economy has improved in recent months, it is far from needing to be constrained by higher rates, which could damage Japan's fragile banking sector, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is way too premature to expect an official discount rate hike,&quot; said Marc Chandler, senior foreign exchange analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the flood of commentary from Japanese officials over the past two days had so far met its intended objective -- a rise in the yen versus the dollar and the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Controlling the yen is the alternative to an interest rate hike,&quot; said Lars Pedersen, international economist at CS First Boston Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not whether they are going to raise rates, that's a confusion; it's whether they are going to intervene because they cannot raise rates,&quot; Pedersen said, adding that he expects the Bank of Japan to sell dollars for yen if the exchange rate rises to between 115 and 120 yen.  </p>
<p>Pedersen said Japan's interest rates are virtually locked down due to its troubled banking system, so the BOJ was forced to start moving exchange rates much earlier than ever before.</p>
<p>&quot;That is why they are so far ahead of the curve in starting to talk about no further decline of the yen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Over the past three weeks, over 1.6 trillion yen worth of Japanese bank loans have been written off, according to data from High Frequency Economics Ltd, pointing to continued trouble in that sector.  </p>
<p>DMG's Chandler doubted that Japanese monetary policy would change before the November 27 release of the Bank of Japan's Tankan report on corporate sector expectations for future business, capital spending, profits and other data.</p>
<p>A near-term rate hike also seems unlikely, he added, because the overnight unsecured call rate has not yet been allowed to regularly trade above the official discount rate.</p>
<p>&quot;When overnight rates are below the discount rate, it is as if the monetary spigot is open fully,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The dollar, which hit a 42-month high of 114.92 yen on October 29 slid to its lowest level in almost a month at 111.27 on Thursday following remarks from a senior Japanese official.</p>
<p>The Nikkei Financial Daily Newspaper quoted finance minister Eisuke Sakakibara as saying the dollar's correction from last year's sharp slide against the yen was about finished and the Ministry of Finance was not trying to weaken the yen further. Sakakibara, known in the markets as &quot;Mr. Yen,&quot; also said financial markets were too pessimistic about Japan's economy, which was stronger than the markets expected.  </p>
<p>On the heels of Sakakibara's remarks, traders focused on talk of an editorial in the Asian Wall Street Journal on Friday that called for tighter Japanese monetary policy.</p>
<p>But Japan's newly appointed Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka helped quell speculation on Friday. He said the current policy of keeping interest rates low will continue and is needed to help the economy &quot;at the moment&quot;.</p>
<p>Japan's discount rate has fallen from 6.0 percent in early 1991 to a record low 0.50 percent, where it has stood for more than a year. Mitsuzuka said primary and secondary industries as well as small firms were happy with this situation.  </p>
<p>Gary Evans, senior emerging markets strategist at Lehman Brothers, warned that a Japanese rate hike might reduce capital flows from Japan into emerging countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Because Japan provides more than 50 percent of the world's savings, we view a change in the direction of BOJ monetary policy as a greater risk to the emerging markets than a 25-50 basis point increase by the Federal Reserve.&quot;</p>
<p>A stronger yen would aid the Japanese economy mainly because it would cheapen the price of crude oil, which has risen 18 to 19 percent, including yen depreciation, over the last three months. Japan imports 100 percent of its oil, which has to be bought in dollars, said Christopher Low, senior economist at HSBC Markets Inc.</p>
<p>A stronger yen would help Japan keep its commitment make its economy less dependent on exports. It would also aid Japanese firms running operations overseas, and appease a U.S. government nervous about its bilateral trade deficit with Japan, said Chris Widness, economist at Chase Securities Inc.  </p>
<p>-- Roanne Daniels, 212-859-1677</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
