<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175363" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Casino America expects Q2 loss.</title>
<headline>Casino America expects Q2 loss.</headline>
<dateline>BILOXI, Miss. 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Casino America Inc said Friday it expects to report a loss before extraordinary item for the second quarter ending October 31 in the range of $3.5 million to $5 million, or between $0.15 per share and $0.21 per share.  </p>
<p>The company said it will record an extraordinary after tax charge of $12.2 million or $0.52 per share as a result of the refinancing of its 11-1/2 percent First Mortgage Notes and other debt in August of this year.  </p>
<p>The company attributed the projected loss primarily to &quot;adverse performance&quot; of its Louisiana casinos as well as weakness in the Vicksburg, Miss., market.  </p>
<p>The company said performance at its Lake Charles, La., casinos was hurt by lower than anticipated revenues at that location and substantially higher marketing and labor costs primarily associated with opening the company's second riverboat casino.</p>
<p>Casino America said it is taking steps to reduce expenses.</p>
<p>Casino America said performance at its Bossier City casino was hurt by increased competition. A fourth casino opened in that market in October, the company said.</p>
<p>These competitive conditions are expected to continue, Casino America said, and the company is taking steps to improve operating margins in Bossier City.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BILOXI, Miss."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
