<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175564" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dlr ends choppy session near lows in Europe.</title>
<headline>Dlr ends choppy session near lows in Europe.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar failed to gain the upper hand against the yen and mark in late Europe and ended a choppy session near lows on rumours, swiftly denied by the White House, that President Clinton had been shot.</p>
<p>Traders said rumours Clinton had been shot hit the dollar amid thin turnover as the market geared-up for a quiet start to the week with U.S. markets on holidays for Veteran's Day on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I know of no incident at all,&quot; said White House deputy press secretary Barry Toiv. He said Clinton was fine and at work in the Oval office.  </p>
<p>Dollar/mark took a hit from 1.5100 at 1458 GMT to 1.5060 marks following market rumours that Clinton had been shot, but recovered some ground to end the European session at 1.5075/80.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen slid from around 111.90 to 111.50 yen following the rumours but recovered some steam to end the European session at 111.59/1.69 in late Europe.</p>
<p>U.S. September wholesale inventories, down 1.3 percent in September from a revised 0.1 percent drop in August, were said to have posted the biggest drop since February 1982 but failed to impress the market. A forecast by analysts had pointed to an average 0.3 percent gain.  </p>
<p>&quot;It (the wholesale number) implies a much stronger economy than one would suspect,&quot; said Adrian Schmidt, international economist at Chase Investment Bank.</p>
<p>Overall, however, traders said the dollar was relatively quiet on Friday and struggling to keep in ranges after its steep slide on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The next focus for the market is going to be Tuesday when the U.S. market re-opens...We are in a bit of a lull,&quot; said a trader at a US bank. Failing news out of the U.S. or Japan on the strength of the yen against the dollar, the focus will shift to U.S. retail and inflation data out next week.  </p>
<p>&quot;As far as U.S. numbers are concerned there will be some focus on the inflation numbers...But really the main focus will be on the retail sales and the industrial production numbers,&quot; said Chris Turner, currency strategist at  BZW in London.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a very strong sense that the U.S. economy has slowed in recent months and our own view is that it may be overdone and that the economy may be stronger than people suspect,&quot; said Turner.</p>
<p>U.S. October producer prices are due out on Wednesday, retail sales and consumer prices are expected Thursday and industrial production figures are due on Friday.  </p>
<p>He said a sense the US economy has slowed was partly to blame for the dollar/mark softness this week.</p>
<p>And comments from Japan's finance ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara on Thursday ignited market concerns that Japan wanted an end to yen weakness and the G3 strong-dollar policy was unwinding. Later, damage-limitation from Japan's prime minister and economic planning agency helped calm fears of an imminent Japanese rate hike, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;That's tempered some of the enthusiasm to pile back into yen,&quot; said Mark Cliffe, chief international economist at HSBC Markets. --Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 6701</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
