<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175550" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE sugar extends gains but pressure cited.</title>
<headline>LIFFE sugar extends gains but pressure cited.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>LIFFE white sugar futures mustered further gains on nearby short-covering on Friday afternoon but no news was cited.</p>
<p>Traders said the volume on nearbys was encouraging and buyers, although now apparently backing off, could to be tempted again.</p>
<p>But the outlook depended on the level of physical offtake which is nothing more than a just routine schedule of purchases at present.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps for the time being the market may be near the lows but I would imagine over the course of next week if there is no further offtake the market would start its way back down again,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>At 1630 GMT, the spot December contract stood just off the day's high at $307.10 a tonne, up $1.40, while the second-month March traded $1.00 higher at $306.20 after a peak of $306.90.</p>
<p>The day's turnover reached 1,962 lots.</p>
<p>Chart resistance is expected to show up around $308.00-309.00, according to analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;The RSI is currently attempting to break out of oversold levels and this could help push prices higher,&quot; said trade house Sucden in a comment on March sugar. On December, it saw resistance at $307.50.</p>
<p>Traders said good crop reports from Europe added to overall jitters.</p>
<p>&quot;Eventually the market will return and start easing back off again,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Paris March sugar traded $1.20 up on the day at $306.20 a tonne.</p>
<p>-- Clelia Oziel, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
