<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175741" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Rwanda rejects French role in Zaire force.</title>
<headline>Rwanda rejects French role in Zaire force.</headline>
<byline>Buchizya Mseteka</byline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwanda said on Friday it opposed French participation in a U.N. intervention force to open aid corridors for over a million refugees trapped in fighting in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;France and even Rwanda should abstain from contributing troops. The force must be neutral and countries with interests must not participate in the operation,&quot; Rwandan President Pasteur Bizimungu told a news conference in his capital Kigali after talks with U.N. special envoy Raymond Chretien.</p>
<p>&quot;A French presence would complicate matters rather than solve the problem we are facing.&quot;</p>
<p>Rwanda, through which key supply routes to eastern Zaire pass and which supports rebels whose advances in Zaire have sent the refugees fleeing, is crucial to any rescue operation.</p>
<p>But Kigali, now controlled by Tutsis, considers France as an ally of the former Hutu-led government whose army and militias committed the genocide of up to a million Tutsis and moderate Hutus in 1994, lost the civil war and fled to Zaire.</p>
<p>The Hutu gunmen are still armed and stop anyone returning to Rwanda. It is uncertain how many refugees would choose to go home if they could. Rwanda says the innocent have nothing to fear.</p>
<p>Zairean rebels who have seized much of east Zaire along the border with Rwanda -- where the Hutu camps had been until the refugees fled the fighting late last month -- are blessed by Rwanda and also opposed French involvement this week.</p>
<p>Unfortunately for the refugees, France is about the only major nation promoting the idea of intervention. Britain, the United States and other African countries appear lukewarm.</p>
<p>Earlier Rwandan Foreign Minister Anastase Gasana said any force would have to be mixed and include African troops.</p>
<p>Gasana said he wanted to rule out the risk of a repeat of &quot;Operation Turquoise&quot; -- the French military intervention in Rwanda following the 1994 genocide when Gasana said the French deported thousands of Rwandans to Zaire.</p>
<p>An eight-nation African summit this week in which Rwanda took part called for a &quot;neutral&quot; protection force to feed the refugees and then escort them home, but no names were named.</p>
<p>Bizimungu, sitting beside Defence Minister Paul Kagame who is believed to hold the real power in Rwanda, said Rwanda still backed an international force to help bring its people home.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea of a military presence to secure (repatriation) corridors is accepted by us and everybody else, what we must decide is the composition,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chretien said his talks with Bizimungu and Kagame were &quot;fruitful, candid and positive&quot; and flew off to Zairea's capital Kinshasa, some 2,000 km (1,200 miles) to the west, to explain Rwanda's position.</p>
<p>Zaire, growing more chaotic by the day and bereft of its President Mobutu Sese Seko, convalescing from cancer in France, accuses Rwanda of waging undeclared war on its territory.</p>
<p>Chretien said no timetable for intervention was agreed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
