<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175811" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Fighting inflation prime goal - S.Africa's Stals.</title>
<headline>Fighting inflation prime goal - S.Africa's Stals.</headline>
<dateline>BELLVILLE, South Africa 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fighting inflation had to be the prime goal of South African monetary policy as the authorities prepared for the gradual easing of exchange controls on residents, Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals said on Friday.</p>
<p>As a result, interest rates would have to stay high, he told a conference near Cape Town.  </p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates which reflect the underlying monetary policy will have to be maintained at a level high enough to force the necessary disciplines needed to restore stability, also to the external value of the rand,&quot; he told the meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;More so than at any other time in the past eight years, the monetary authorities will now have to use all the powers at their disposal to fight inflation in South Africa.&quot;  </p>
<p>This had become even more critical as South Africa moved forward with plans for the gradual easing for foreign exchange controls, Stals said.</p>
<p>&quot;It becomes of even greater importance to bring inflation in line with the average rate of inflation in the economies of our major trading partners as we proceed on the road of the gradual removal of exchange controls.</p>
<p>&quot;Without exchange controls, the external value of the rand will be exposed to even more pressures and to greater volatility, unless this prime goal of lower inflation will also be achieved.&quot;  </p>
<p>Stals reiterated his view that calls for the immediate abolition of all remaining exchange controls were &quot;unrealistic&quot;.  </p>
<p>Referring to the sharp fall in the rand this year, Stals said the risk was that depreciation could stoke a vicious circle of inflation.</p>
<p>Between 1988 and 1995, average changes in the exchange rate more or less corresponded with the inflation differential between South Africa and its trading partners. This pattern has, however, now been broken.</p>
<p>&quot;The daunting question for monetary policy is whether the internal value of the rand will now, perhaps with some time lag, follow the external value, or whether we can on this occasion break this sequence and avoid inflation in 1997/98 following the depreciation of 1996,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If not, there is a real danger that a new cycle of more inflation/more depreciation/more inflation could be reintroduced into South Africa which will defeat the defined objectives of monetary policy.&quot;  </p>
<p>Many economists have been pleasantly surprised by the relatively low rate of inflation in South Africa to date, despite the sharp fall in the rand since mid-February.</p>
<p>South Africa's annual consumer inflation rate stood at 8.4 percent in September while producer inflation was 7.6 percent that month. The central bank last raised its key Bank rate to 16.00 percent from 15.00 percent in April.</p>
<p>Stals said 1996 would be the fourth year in succession that CPI was held below 10 percent.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELLVILLE, South Africa"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
