<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="175853" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo c.banker says dinar rate under control - agency.</title>
<headline>Yugo c.banker says dinar rate under control - agency.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Bank of Yugoslavia (NBY) is holding the dinar rate firmly under control solely with economic measures, the Tanjug news agency quoted central bank deputy governor Bozidar Gazivoda as saying on Friday.</p>
<p>The measures included tight monetary policy, interventions in the local interbank foreign exchange market, and control of money supply growth through the recently reintroduced reserve requirement for commercial banks.</p>
<p>&quot;The exchange rate, which has been stable for months even though it is not fixed administratively, contributes to the International Monetary Fund's requirement that a currency exchange rate policy excludes administration,&quot; Gazivoda said.</p>
<p>He said that since the official rate has a firm backing in stable hard currency reserves and prices, continued production and export growth, the recent slight divergence on the unofficial black market mostly resulted from speculation the dinar would be devalued.</p>
<p>According to Gazivoda, debtors hoped for a devaluation and inflation in order to reduce, and even erase their debts.</p>
<p>&quot;Officially everybody advocates a stable exchange rate policy founded on economic measures, but it is evident the bulk of credits is not being paid back,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Inflationary expectations have recently also appeared in banks where dinar liquidity is being sacrificed to raise foreign currency liquidity in an effort to obtain NBY funds at interest rates on the level of the central bank discount rate.</p>
<p>The NBY discount rate has been stable at 4.5 percent per month since June, while commercial bank lending rates ranged from 10-12 percent or even higher per month.</p>
<p>Gazivoda said one of the reasons the NBY decided to raise the reserve requirement from 10 to 15 percent, was to prevent the &quot;multiplication&quot; of credits or uncontrolled money supply growth.</p>
<p>High commercial bank lending rates were partly the result of a reduced circulation of money and capital with the international economy, which gave the local banking sector a monopoly due to a lack of external competition, Gazivoda said. -- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
