<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176033" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico '97 budget seeks $5 bln net borrowing limit.</title>
<headline>Mexico '97 budget seeks $5 bln net borrowing limit.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Mexican government will seek a $5.0 billion limit on net foreign borrowing in 1997, according to its budget proposal delivered to Congress on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;With relation to external debt, the initiative proposes a limit to net external public sector debt in the national currency equal to $5.0 billion (U.S.),&quot; the budget said.</p>
<p>The increase in public debt will allow Mexican development banks to give a boost to exporters and allow investment spending by the National Electricity Commission and Petroleos Mexicanos to increase, the budget said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The federal government resorts to external debt mainly with the object of refinancing existing debts in better conditions,&quot; the budget said. &quot;As a consequence the external debt of the federal government will not vary significantly with respect to the end of 1996.&quot;</p>
<p>With respect to the internal debt, the public sector deficit will rise to 15.89 billion pesos or 0.5 percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>The deficit will reflect a surplus of 18.348 billion pesos and a federal government deficit of 34.238 billion pesos, the government said.</p>
<p>&quot;With these numbers, we are looking for ... a federal government net internal debt of 34.0 billion pesos,&quot; the budget proposal said.</p>
<p>-- Robert Kozak, Mexico City newsroom (525) 728 9559</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
