<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176112" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FOCUS-NZ jobs data mask real story, say analysts.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-NZ jobs data mask real story, say analysts.</headline>
<byline>Simon Louisson</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Apparently much stronger than predicted jobs data mask a weakening employment picture and leave New Zealand on track for a monetary policy easing next month, economics and traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>Statistics New Zealand figures showed New Zealand's unemployment rate rose to 6.3 percent at September 30 from 6.1 percent in the previous quarter, but employment grew 0.8 percent in the September quarter against economists' forecasts of 0.2 percent.  </p>
<p>The central Reserve Bank has been concerned about the surprisingly robust job growth in the past few quarters but today's figures disguised the real picture -- part time employment accounted for all 0.8 percent of the growth and full-time employment actually fell 0.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise in part-time jobs has masked the real picture,&quot; said Garlick &amp; Co economist Matthew Goodson. &quot;It's certainly news consistent with what the Reserve Bank requires.&quot;</p>
<p>Debt markets initially sold on the news but when it became apparent the jobs growth was all in part-time employment the market bought back.  </p>
<p>&quot;People were shocked initially at the employment growth being so large but then they saw it was all part-timers and there was a sense of relief. The market rallied back,&quot; said a Wellington bank chief dealer.</p>
<p>He said that the Reserve Bank would await confirmation of a weaker labour market in wages data due later this month but should be on track for easing monetary policy in its December 17 Monetary Policy Statement.</p>
<p>Some observors believe the bank may hold off again with its long-awaited easing until a government has been formed following the inconconclusive election a month ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think as long as the wages data is fine, they will ease regardless of whether a government is formed, given that the currency is up where it is,&quot; the chief dealer said.</p>
<p>Goodson though, suggested such a move could be premature.</p>
<p>&quot;A further easing now really depends on the Reserve Bank knowing the rules of the game under a future government.</p>
<p>&quot;It is going to be pretty hard to ease a tremendous amount more in the very near term because it doesn't know if it will have a 0-2 percent inflation target, a one billion (dollars) or two of extra fiscal spending to contend with.&quot;  </p>
<p>The nationalist New Zealand First Party holds the balance of power and has been negotiating with the ruling conservative National Party and the centre-left Labour Party.</p>
<p>Bank of New Zealand Treasury Economist Peter Jolly said today's data would do nothing to deter the Reserve Bank from any easing in monetary policy it may be considering.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it adds anything extra, and it wouldn't have surprised the Reserve Bank. If they are going to ease in December, this won't deter them from doing that,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Reserve Bank has been especially cautious about easing because inflation has been at the top limit, or above, the bank's 0-2 percent inflation band for six quarters, and it is forecast to stay above for another two quarters.</p>
<p>Last month markets rallied when September year inflation came out at 2.34 percent percent against the bank's forecast of 2.7 percent, but the bank warned markets after that data that it wanted further evidence of falling inflation pressures before it could ease.  </p>
<p>So attention will now turn to see how much wage pressure there is in the economy. Economists forecast average hourly easings rose 3.5 percent in the August year and the labour cost index rose 1.92 percent in the September year.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
