<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176144" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Shell aims to complete term Oman talks next week.</title>
<headline>Shell aims to complete term Oman talks next week.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shell International Trading and Shipping Co (Stasco) plans to complete term negotiations for the sale of 1997 Oman crude towards the end of next week, industry sources said on Friday.</p>
<p>Stasco officials have been holding talks with customers through this week, including those in South Korea and Japan, to assess views of the Oman market.</p>
<p>The major hopes to issue a term price before Friday, the sources said.</p>
<p>Price indications have ranged 10 to 15 cents per barrel over the official Ministry of Petroleum and Minerals (MPM) price. In 1996, Stasco term Oman was set at MPM plus eight cents.</p>
<p>In recent years the Stasco premium, which is used as a benchmark price for other term talks concerning Oman sales, has been set around two cents above the average traded spot premium.</p>
<p>Traders said the average trade spot premium for Oman in 1996 has been 10 to 11 cents, leading some sources to assess the likely outcome of the price negotiations at MPM plus 12 cents.</p>
<p>Industry sources said Stasco's bullish sentiment for the price talks has not been dampened by the market presence of Alaskan North Slope (ANS) in Asia, which is often seen as a direct competitor of Oman.</p>
<p>Several million barrels of ANS has been sold on both a spot basis and on term, with South Korea's LG Caltex becoming the latest term buyer.</p>
<p>LG Caltex confirmed earlier Friday that it had agreed to buy 30,000 barrels of ANS in a term deal with British Petroleum &amp; Co Plc.</p>
<p>The sources said Stasco has pointed to recent and rare arbitrage trades of Oman into South Africa and the Meditarranean as indications of a broadening market for Oman.</p>
<p>In addition, growing refining capacity and more stringent product specifications were likely to be supportive.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65 870 3081)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
