<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176158" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Wrong rate rise rumours rout SIMEX JGBs, Euroyen.</title>
<headline>Wrong rate rise rumours rout SIMEX JGBs, Euroyen.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rumours of an imminent rise in Japanese interest rates, knocked down later by the country's Economic Planning Agency (EPA) Minister, kicked Japanese government bond (JGB) and Euroyen futures to new lows on Friday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rumours stemmed from the absence of the Bank of Japan in the money market on Friday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Which was ridiculous,&quot; said one Singapore dealer. &quot;The bank didn't make its usual adjustment (to liquidity) because it wasn't needed.&quot;</p>
<p>The December JGB futures contract ended 0.85 down at 123.83 after hitting an early low of 123.55. Volume was 1,268 lots.  </p>
<p>Euroyen futures were was also weaker. By 1115 GMT, the June 1997 Euroyen contract was down five ticks at 99.10 against its IMM close at 99.16 on active volume of 32,535 lots.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rumours of a rate rise had been believed by some people because of comments on Thursday by Ministry of Finance official Eisuke Sakakibara suggesting the Japanese economy was gaining strength.</p>
<p>But the rumours were promptly contradicted by EPA Minister Taro Aso who told foreign news agencies in an interview Japan's policy of low interest rates must be maintained.  </p>
<p>One dealer said he thought the JGBs and Euroyen contracts were now approaching their floor.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have now almost seen the bottom,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Today the June Euroyen hit 99.05. While it could go a bit lower, even through the figure maybe, that will be the low...Intrinsically, there's good value there now.&quot;</p>
<p>He said economic fundamentals also meant JGBs had probably little room left on the downside.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is in the same state now as it was when the December JGBs were at 126.50,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Eurodollar futures were slightly stronger on the back of fresh highs on Wall Street overnight.</p>
<p>The most active March 1997 Eurodollar contract closed at 94.46, unchanged from its previous IMM close.</p>
<p>But dealers said that contract may have peaked.</p>
<p>&quot;The 94.45/50 area looks like a logical top...unless we get a rate cut, which I think is unlikely,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>-- Chris Johnson, Singapore newsroom (65 8703199)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
