<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176137" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan minister says no to currency intervention.</title>
<headline>Japan minister says no to currency intervention.</headline>
<byline>Yoko Kobayashi</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Japanese government should not intervene in the currency market as it naturally moves along with trends in global trade and market economies, newly appointed Finance Minister Hiroshi Mitsuzuka said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Markets are by nature things that move, and all I can say is that we will keep careful watch. It's not something that we should intervene in,&quot; Mitsuzuka told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will naturally reflect the strength of Japan's economy, and I am not very worried (about the current state of the foreign exchange market),&quot; said Mitsuzuka, who was named finance minister on Thursday after the re-election of Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is moving in a way that reflects (Japan's) overall economic conditions,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka is a veteran conservative politician who heads one of the biggest factions in the ruling Liberal Democratic Party.</p>
<p>When Mitsuzuka was trade minister in the early 1990s, he took a realistic line, promising only what he thought he could deliver in trade talks with the United States and other countries.</p>
<p>The newly appointed finance minister explained that the Japan's overall economic recovery was still gradual as not all industries were showing signs of strong growth.</p>
<p>He prescribed steady implementation of fiscal and monetary policies such as reforms of state finances and flexibility in formulating a state budget as ways to put the economy on a stable growth trend.</p>
<p>Japan plunged into years of recession after the &quot;bubble&quot; economic era of inflated land and stock prices burst in the late 1980s. It is now slowly recovering from that shock with the help of huge economic stimulus measures featuring public works spendings and easier monetary policy.</p>
<p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ), which decides on the country's monetary policy, has kept the official discount rate at a record low of 0.5 percent since September 1995.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka said the record low official discount rate had kept primary and secondary industries along with small firms happy.</p>
<p>Asked whether the BOJ was likely to maintain the current policy of keeping interest rates low, Mitsuzuka said: &quot;Yes, I think this will continue.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked whether such a policy was needed to help the economy, he said: &quot;I think we do need it, at the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>As a way to further strengthen Japan's economic recovery, politicians have called for the government to form a supplementary budget this fiscal year ending March 31, 1996, with hefty public works spendings.</p>
<p>Mitsuzuka said the government would draft a budget to cover necessary costs for areas such as those to reconstruct the port city of Kobe that was devastated by an earthquake in January 1995, and for funds to help nurture new technologies.</p>
<p>But it could not follow the precedent of heaping money on public works, Mitsuzuka said when asked whether stimulative measures should be included in the extra budget.</p>
<p>Japan enjoyed general government surpluses until 1992 because its gigantic social insurance fund more than offset big deficits at central and regional governments.</p>
<p>But economic stimulus packages coupled with dwindling tax revenues from the recessions has tilted the balance into the red in recent years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
