<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176673" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: LG-Caltex to import 30,000 bpd of ANS from BP.</title>
<headline>LG-Caltex to import 30,000 bpd of ANS from BP.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's LG-Caltex Oil Corp, a unit of LG Group, said on Friday it has agreed to import 30,000 barrels per day of Alaskan North Slope (ANS) crude from British Petroleum Co Plc (BP) effective December 20.  </p>
<p>LG-Caltex said in a statement the purchase agreement would be extended annually unless either side objects to it.</p>
<p>LG-Caltex, the nation's first refiner to import ANS on a long-term basis, said the deal was in line with the South Korean government's efforts to diversify its crude supply lines.</p>
<p>Wholly dependent on imports, South Korea has relied heavily on the Middle East countries for a majority of its crude demand.</p>
<p>The refiner's crude oil demands are increasing as it plans to start running a new 220,000-bpd crude distillation unit this month.  </p>
<p>The new unit will boost LG-Caltex's licensed crude processing capacity to 600,000 bpd from the current 380,000 bpd.</p>
<p>South Korea currently has a refining capability of 2.22 million bpd.</p>
<p>LG-Caltex is a joint venture between LG Group  LUGG.CN and Caltex Petroleum Corp, itself a joint venture between U.S. oil giants Texaco Inc and Chevron Corp.</p>
<p>BP became a large equity holder in the Alaskan oil fields, following the lifting of ANS crude exports ban in May.</p>
<p>-- Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5643</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
