<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176760" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PHILIPPINE STOCKS - factors to watch - Nov 8.</title>
<headline>PHILIPPINE STOCKS - factors to watch - Nov 8.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Philippine stocks on Friday:</p>
<p>* On Thursday, the Dow Jones rose by 28.33 points to 6,206.04. PLDT's ADR rose by $0 1/4 to $60.</p>
<p>* The peso closed on Thursday at 26.244 to a U.S. dollar from 26.249</p>
<p>* The Philippine Stock Exchange index closed at 3,063.06, up 64.63.</p>
<p>* The Philippine interbank call loan rate was up at 14.53125 pct from 14 pct.  </p>
<p>* Brokerage firm Sun Hung Kai Securities (Phil) Inc says the market will likely experience a technical correction today as third quarter earnings results have already been released while euphoria over the U.S. presidential elections have waned providing no added incentive to buy into the market.</p>
<p>* The Manila Bulletin says the Senate unanimously passed on third and final reading on Thursday its version of the specific tax bill on beer and cigarettes that is expected to bring in 14 billion pesos in additional revenues in the first two years.</p>
<p>* The Business Daily says the country's three oil refiners are asking government to settle 1.9 billion pesos in duty drawback in addition to the 2.3 billion pesos claims of the oil firms from the Oil Price Stabilisation Fund.</p>
<p>* The Inquirer says First Philippine Holdings Corp has tied up with Sumito Corp of Japan to develop a 2.6 billion peso industrial estate in Batangas.</p>
<p>* The Manila Times says former Budget Minister Benjamin Diokno has advised legislators to exercise caution in finalizing the bill implementing the comprehensive tax reform program, particularly the provision on the corporate income tax, lest it would reduce the Philippines' competitive edge in luring foreign direct investments.</p>
<p>					 -----------</p>
<p>To contribute to this page, please fax your comments on the stock market to Reuters newsroom on fax (632) 817 6267. For details, please phone the newsroom on (632) 841 8934.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632)841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
