<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176890" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton hails Christopher as job turnover starts.</title>
<headline>Clinton hails Christopher as job turnover starts.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moving swiftly to put some fresh faces in his Cabinet after his re-election, President Bill Clinton accepted the resignation of Secretary of State Warren Christopher on Thursday as a major reshuffle began.</p>
<p>&quot;The cause of peace and freedom and decency have never had a more tireless or tenacious advocate,&quot; Clinton said at a White House ceremony where he called Christopher &quot;America's elder statesman&quot; and gave the dapper secretary a hug.</p>
<p>Saying he accepted the resignation &quot;with great regret ... but deep gratitude for his service,&quot; Clinton gave Christopher high marks for working for peace in the Middle East, Bosnia and Haiti, among other places.</p>
<p>&quot;Being secretary of state is to take part in history's relay race,&quot; Christopher replied in a brief farewell speech. &quot;It's been a great privilege for me to have the opportunity to run this challenging leg over the last four years.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton said he had made no decision on a successor for the 71-year-old Christopher, who was the most travelled secretary of state in U.S. history, logging more than 700,000 miles, and who is planning more globe-trotting before stepping down Jan. 20 when Clinton is inaugurated for his second term.</p>
<p>Clinton's next move may be naming of a new White House chief of staff to replace Leon Panetta, who is eyeing a possible 1998 campaign for California governor.</p>
<p>Clinton is to hold a 3 p.m. EST (2000 GMT) news conference on Friday and aides said he could announce his choice then. A leading contender is a former deputy White House chief of staff, Erskine Bowles, a North Carolina venture capitalist who has maintained close ties to Clinton.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said other people were also being considered but &quot;at this point, I don't think the president knows&quot; who he will pick.</p>
<p>Clinton said at the Christopher ceremony that in keeping with his view that Tuesday's re-election victory was a win for &quot;the vital centre,&quot; he will look at Americans across the broad spectrum of politics, not just at Democrats, to fill high-profile jobs.</p>
<p>But that promise may not extend to secretary of state.</p>
<p>The top names in contention are U.S. ambassador to the United Nations Madeleine Albright, who attended the Christopher event, and former Senate Majority Leader George Mitchell, a Maine Democrat currently getting high marks as special U.S. envoy to peace efforts in Northern Ireland.</p>
<p>Albright would be the first woman secretary of state, while Mitchell has a good relationship with the president and would breeze through confirmation by the Republican-run Senate. The successor may be announced next week.</p>
<p>Apparently fading as a possibility is retired Gen. Colin Powell, a Republican. Many aides doubt Clinton would put a possible presidential contender in such a high-profile post to compete against Vice President Al Gore, who is expected to run for president in 2000.</p>
<p>Transportation Secretary Federico Pena emerged Thursday as the latest Cabinet officer expected to depart. Department sources said Pena had given Clinton his resignation.</p>
<p>The Washington Post reported in Friday's editions that Labour Secretary Robert Reich had confirmed in an interview his widely anticipated departure.</p>
<p>Other big names expected to leave as Clinton's prepares for a second term include Defence Secretary William Perry, Commerce Secretary Mickey Kantor and Energy Secretary Hazel O'Leary.</p>
<p>&quot;I plan to meet with the president tomorrow to discuss the transition,&quot; Perry told reporters on a speaking trip in Denver. He said he had recently reaffirmed to Clinton his intention to serve for just one presidential term.</p>
<p>Contenders for Perry's job could include CIA Director John Deutch, Deputy Defence Secretary John White and retiring Sen. Sam Nunn, a Georgia Democrat and military expert.</p>
<p>Some mention Indiana Republican Sen. Richard Lugar.</p>
<p>One aide said: &quot;This is a department you could go bipartisan.&quot; The allure of putting a Republican in a big job would be to blunt Republican congressional criticism of Clinton policies on Bosnia or NATO expansion, for example.</p>
<p>Aides said Clinton wants to get as much transition work done as possible quickly so he is delaying his departure for a vacation in Hawaii from next Tuesday until Thursday or Friday.</p>
<p>He is to hold a Cabinet meeting Friday before his news conference to discuss the transition to a second term. McCurry said Clinton has not asked for a blanket resignation from his Cabinet, instead wanting to handle job changes &quot;in a more sensitive way.&quot;</p>
<p>While the period between two terms is often a good chance to bring in new blood, a number of top-level officials are either planning to stay or fighting to keep their jobs.</p>
<p>Attorney General Janet Reno told reporters on Thursday she wants to remain in her job if asked by Clinton. She has often been cited as likely to go because of concerns she is too independent-minded and not a &quot;team player.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;As far as I am concerned, nobody has been critical to my face or critical as a source that I can trace,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
