<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176865" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Royal Dutch/Shell sued in human rights case.</title>
<headline>Royal Dutch/Shell sued in human rights case.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Gail Appleson, Law Correspondent</p>
<p>Royal Dutch Petroleum Co. and Shell Transport and Trading Co. Plc. were sued on Friday by relatives of two Nigerian human rights activitists who allege the companies played a role in the 1995 hanging of the men.</p>
<p>The suit, filed in federal court on the first anniversary of the men's deaths, was brought by the familes of Ken Saro-Wiwa, who was the leader of the Movement for Survival of Ogoni People, and John Kpuinen, deputy president of the group's youth wing.</p>
<p>The families allege the two men were killed because of their challenges to the military dictatorship of Sani Abacha in Nigeria and to Shell's role in alleged human rights violations, including environmental destruction.</p>
<p>The two men and seven other activists were hanged on Nov. 10, 1995, in Port Harcourt, Nigeria, after a sham trial based on fabricated charges, the lawsuit alleges.</p>
<p>The suit alleges that Saro-Wiwa and Kpuinen were accused of murders they did not commit and tried before a special tribunal that violated international standards of due process.</p>
<p>The plaintiffs allege that the executions by the Nigerian military junta were carried out with the &quot;knowledge, consent and/or support&quot; of Royal Dutch Petroleum and Shell Transport.</p>
<p>A spokesman in London said the companies had not had a chance to study the suit but said the company had previously denied allegations that they played a role in the deaths.</p>
<p>&quot;Those (allegations) have been refuted previously and they are further refuted now,&quot; a Shell spokesman said.</p>
<p>The suit alleges that the hangings were part of a conspiracy &quot;to violently and ruthlessly suppress any opposition to Royal Dutch/Shell's conduct in its exploitation of oil and natural gas resources in Ogoni and in the Niger Delta.&quot;</p>
<p>The case was filed by the Centre for Constitutional Rights under the Alien Tort Claims Act, which provides federal jurisdiction for alleged civil wrongs committed by aliens in violation of a nation's laws or a U.S. treaty.</p>
<p>The claims were also brought under the Torture Victim Protection Act, which provides for federal jurisdiction for acts of torture and extrajudicial execution.</p>
<p>The suit alleges that Royal Dutch/Shell's operations have caused oil-related pollution that has contaminated the local water supply and agricultural land.</p>
<p>More than half the population of Ogoni in 1993 was organised under the Movement for Survival of Ogoni People, a human rights organisation that protested the effects of oil exploitation.</p>
<p>In April 1993, Willbros, a U.S. pipeline contractor for Royal Dutch/Shell, began bulldozing crops on Ogoni farmland.</p>
<p>The suit alleged that the contractor, acting at the direction of or on behalf of the defendants, called in government troops who fired on villagers peacefully protesting the destruction of their farms.</p>
<p>A Royal Dutch/Shell official then asked a Nigerian official for &quot;the usual assistance&quot; so that work on the pipeline could continue, the lawsuit alleged.</p>
<p>Saro-Wiwa and other activists who supported the demonstration were then arrested on fabricated charges, the suit alleged.</p>
<p>The suit alleged that the defendants continued to enlist the Nigerian military to quash peaceful demonstrations by residents of Ogoni villages who complained about pollution.</p>
<p>The resulting attacks included the 1993 killing of 35 residents of one Ogoni village; the May 1994 killing of four Ogoni tribal leaders and the summer 1994 raids on 60 towns and villages in which at least 50 Ogonis were killed, it said.</p>
<p>Saro-Wiwa, who had been released, and Kpuinen were arrested in May 1994 because of their opposition to Royal Dutch/Shell's activities, the suit alleges.</p>
<p>They were charged with murder and tried by a special tribunal, which was appointed by the Nigerian military regime. The men were found guilty and hanged.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
