<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176871" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. again denies TWA &quot;friendly fire&quot; charge.</title>
<headline>U.S. again denies TWA &quot;friendly fire&quot; charge.</headline>
<byline>Grant McCool</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nearly four months after a TWA jumbo jet blew up without warning near New York, killing 230 people, the U.S. government was on Friday again forced to deny charges that a Navy missile accidentally shot down the plane.</p>
<p>The latest version of the persistent conspiracy theory that has circulated on the Internet and in other media for months, erupted again at a time when some investigators were leaning toward ruling out sabotage and declaring the July 17 disaster an accident.</p>
<p>A report in Friday's Washington Post quoted a senior National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) official as saying that if no evidence of a bomb or missile is found in the remaining scraps of the Boeing 747 on the ocean floor, the agency will declare the crash an accident.</p>
<p>Former White House press secretary Pierre Salinger said on Thursday night in France that he had been given a government document that he believed proved a U.S. missile destroyed TWA Flight 800 off New York's Long Island.</p>
<p>But on Friday, Salinger said he was told it had been on the Internet for two months and acknowledged his information was at least second-hand.</p>
<p>The head of the FBI in New York, James Kallstrom, said on Friday investigators had studied the possibility of &quot;friendly fire&quot; but there &quot;was not one scintilla of evidence that proves this out.&quot; He said it was &quot;highly, highly, highly unlikely.&quot;</p>
<p>A U.S. Navy spokeswoman referred inquiries to the FBI but said the Navy's investigation had found nothing in the area that could have downed the aircraft.</p>
<p>&quot;The FBI and the NTSB has found that allegation to be without merit and they have moved on,&quot; Lt. Cmdr Susan Haeg said. &quot;We've tracked any Navy assets in the area and there's nothing different. There was nothing in the area that could have done that. There's nothing more to add.&quot;</p>
<p>The FBI and NTSB have identified three possible causes of the disaster -- a bomb, a missile or catastrophic mechanical failure -- but have not reached any definitive conclusion.</p>
<p>The Washington Post quoted the NTSB's director of aviation safety Bernard Loeb as saying: &quot;If we find no evidence of criminal activity in anything else we retrieve, as far as I am concerned this will be an airplane accident and we will treat it as such.&quot;</p>
<p>Investigators believe the centre fuel tank exploded but do not know what caused the blast.</p>
<p>Salinger, 71, press spokesman for President John F. Kennedy and later Paris bureau chief for ABC, told French television TF1 on Friday that the document blaming a missile for the crash had been on the Internet for two months.</p>
<p>He also acknowledged that he had received the document, which he initially said came from a U.S. Secret Service agent, second-hand from an unidentified Frenchman &quot;involved in various government things&quot; who had met a U.S. agent.</p>
<p>The U.S. Secret Service, responding to Salinger's remarks, said in a statement on Friday that it had &quot;absolutely no information that one of our agents, or a person with official ties to the Secret Service, has known of, received or produced a document of the type alleged by Salinger.&quot;</p>
<p>Kallstrom, lead investigator of the TWA probe, said he was baffled that Salinger had not contacted the agency first with his information if he believed it was authentic.</p>
<p>&quot;I can assure the American people that we are not in the business of covering things up, we would never, ever, ever do that. It didn't happen, we've looked at it from every angle,&quot; the FBI's Kallstrom said on CBS News radio on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;There have been a lot of conspiracy theories all over the Internet and this may be what he (Salinger) has. They are all nonsense,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The FBI said it would hold a joint news conference at 2 p.m. EST (1900 GMT) in New York with the NTSB and the Navy.</p>
<p>Salinger, despite the denials by the U.S. government and his realisation that the charges had been circulating for months, said he stood by the document's allegations. He left his hotel in the Mediterranean resort of Cannes for an undisclosed destination.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
