<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176984" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Grand jury charges 19 in Teletek case.</title>
<headline>US Grand jury charges 19 in Teletek case.</headline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal grand jury in Las Vegas indicted 19 people with securities fraud and money laundering involving long-distance provider Teletek Inc., authorities said Thursday.</p>
<p>In a pair of indictments, the U.S. Attorney for the District of Nevada charged four former Teletek executives and a stock broker with racketeering, securities fraud, money laundering and bribes paid to stock promoters across the country to sell Teletek stock.</p>
<p>The first indictment, brought under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organisations Act, better known as RICO, alleges that bribes were paid in the form of cash and Teletek stock by Michael Swan, Teletek president until April 1995, his wife Claudia Higgins, Keith Shwayder, Teletek president in 1992 and Kevin Orton, a Teletek accountant.</p>
<p>Higgins was an officer and director of United Payphone Services Inc a unit of Teletek.</p>
<p>Also named in the 52-count indictment was Steven Wertman, a New York stock promoter.</p>
<p>The U.S. Attorney's Office said the activity continued from November 1991 to December 1995 and occurred in at least 10 states: Nevada, California, Utah, Colorado, Texas, New York, New Jersey, Florida, Illinois and Oklahoma.</p>
<p>One legal expert said if convicted, some of the defendants being charged under the RICO Act, could potentially face up to 20 years in prison.</p>
<p>A second indictment charges 14 people outside the company with conspiracy, securities fraud and in some instances, money laundering.</p>
<p>Teletek declined comment, but a representative said the company planned to issue a statement through its attorneys on Friday.</p>
<p>The Las Vegas company which provides long-distance telecommunications services, is also being investigated by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) for alleged securities law violations.</p>
<p>According to the Justice Department, the cash payments included thousands of dollars sometimes hidden inside Federal Express packages which were allegedly sent to the homes of various stockbrokers.</p>
<p>In one case, Swan allegedly directed his then secretary to deliver $15,000 in cash to the husband of a stockbroker at the airport in Las Vegas.</p>
<p>Swan's attorney, Frank Razzano of the Washington, D.C. law firm of Dickstein, Shapiro, Morin and Oshinsky, said he had not yet seen the papers but was told Swan had received a summons to appear for an arraigment on November 27.</p>
<p>He said he was told that Swan would be permitted to remain free until the arraignment.</p>
<p>A special assistant to the U.S. Attorney District of Nevada said that federal agents were in the process of arresting some of the defendants nationwide.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr. Swan proclaims his innocence and intends to controvert the charges against him. He's very proud of what he's accomplished with Teletek, which employs 34 people and turned a profit last year,&quot; Razzano said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
