<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176955" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Navy says it could not have shot down airliner.</title>
<headline>Navy says it could not have shot down airliner.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Navy said on Friday it could not have shot down a TWA airliner that crashed over the Atlantic in July, saying it had no weapons in the area to do so and federal investigators had already found that possibility &quot;without merit.&quot;</p>
<p>Lt. Cmdr. Susan Haeg, a Navy spokeswoman, said the FBI would have to comment directly on allegations by former White House Press Secretary Pierre Salinger that a Navy missile might have downed the jet. But she added: &quot;We've tracked any Navy assets in the area and there's nothing different. There was nothing in the area that could have done that. There's nothing more to add.&quot;  </p>
<p>Salinger, who was press spokesman for the late president John F. Kennedy and later Paris bureau chief for ABC television, said in France he had obtained a document alleging that the crash of the Boeing 747 near New York on July 17, in which 230 people died, was caused by a missile test.</p>
<p>&quot;The FBI and the National Transportation Safety Board have found the allegation to be without merit and they have moved on,&quot; Haeg said in response to questions. &quot;We refer you to the FBI.&quot;</p>
<p>Another U.S. official following the investigation heaped scorn on Salinger's account.</p>
<p>&quot;I would find that unbelievable,&quot; the official said, asking not to be identified. The official said this was because Navy logs could account for the positions of its ships and any firings of its weapons systems. &quot;This is the first I've heard of the theory that a Navy ship was involved in the incident.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
