<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17696" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ shares claw back initial weakness, end level.</title>
<headline>NZ shares claw back initial weakness, end level.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>* NZ share prices claw back from initial weakness</p>
<p>* Ports re-rated after Port of Tauranga result</p>
<p>* Market withstands weakness abroad, but on light volume.</p>
<p>---------------------------(Aug 27)-----------------------------</p>
<p>Price movements at close</p>
<p>	    LAST CHG</p>
<p>144  nil  * NZSE-40 cap index -0.90 at 2,219.97</p>
<p>328  nil  * NZSC cap index +33.61 at 4,474.01</p>
<p>286  - 2  * NZSE-10 cap index -1.45 at 1,121.61</p>
<p>382  + 2  * Volume NZ$28 million. Futures -1 at 1,122</p>
<p>685  nil  * Other movers - +12 +13</p>
<p>New Zealand share prices clawed their way back from initial weakness to end square on Tuesday but on very light volume.</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 Capital Index was down just 0.90 of a point to 2,219.97 on light volume but Charles Batchelor at First NZ Capital said it was a reasonable peformance given weakness in overseas markets and rising domestic bond yields.</p>
<p>&quot;It started off on the back foot then got back to being virtually zero change. It really was quite well supported,&quot; Batchelor said.</p>
<p>The index had gone through a 2,209.99 to 2,219.97 range.  </p>
<p>Ports continued to be the highlight after Port of Tauranga's stronger-than-expected result on Monday, which today meant the stock was re-rated up by 6.3 percent or 12 cents to NZ$2.04.</p>
<p>Fellow provincial port operator Northland appeared to coat-tail Tauranga, also gaining 6.3 percent and ending 13 cents higher at NZ$2.20.</p>
<p>Brokers said Northland appeared to have missed out in the recent re-rating of the sector.</p>
<p>Ports of Auckland also gained, by 10 cents to NZ$5.35, while in the South Island, Lyttleton Port firmed two to NZ$1.46.  </p>
<p>Not so lucky was Designer Textiles, which was again singled out for selling. Designer ended five cents or 4.8 percent down to close at NZ$1.00 after revising down its 1996/7 profit forecasts. - James Gray (64 9 302 1253)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
