<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176951" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Muni board warns dealers of post-election payments.</title>
<headline>Muni board warns dealers of post-election payments.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The MSRB on Friday warned municipal bond dealers that contributions they give to help state and local officials with transition and inaugural expenses following Tuesday's elections could trigger the board's &quot;pay-to-play&quot; ban.</p>
<p>&quot;The Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board is deeply concerned that a number of dealers are going to be caught by helping with those inauguration and transition expenses,&quot; MSRB Chairman Roger Hayes said in a telephone press conference following a quarterly meeting of the panel on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;Everbody be sure and do it in accordance with the rule so that nobody is banned&quot; from doing business for the next two years, said Hayes, managing director of municipal finance for NationsBank Corp.</p>
<p>Enacted in April 1994, rule G-37 bars muni dealers that make contributions to issuer clients from doing business for two years with those governments.</p>
<p>In a one-page &quot;election season reminder&quot; in September, the MSRB noteds that the term &quot;contributions&quot; includes &quot;monies given for transition or inaugural expenses and the payment of debt for an election.&quot;  </p>
<p>In other announcements, Hayes said the 15-member board will focus soon on &quot;concerns about practices in the formation of syndicates and selling groups and the pricing and allocation of bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be absolutely sure that's done in a way that's understandable to issuers and to other firms in the underwriting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;And we want to make sure (there is) the broadest and most efficient distribution of bonds to investors throughout the country,&quot; he said, noting the board is following up on a survey it did of bond dealers last summer on the issue.  </p>
<p>Hayes said the board also will more carefully examine &quot;the whole process of obtaining financing for an issuer client.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We want to be absolutely sure that the interest of the issuer is paramount,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the board will look at the need for &quot;shedding more light on the role of financial advisers&quot; in bond deals, and the &quot;potential for conflicts among the parties.&quot;</p>
<p>The board will look at &quot;the compensation arrangements between the various parties and how that might, in effect, create a conflict of interest,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hayes said the board will look at &quot;how collateral or related transactions to an issuer might need additional light shed on (them), like swaps, derivatives and guaranteed investment contracts (GICs).&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
