<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="176903" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sinatra's health worsens, TV reports.</title>
<headline>Sinatra's health worsens, TV reports.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frank Sinatra remained in a Los Angeles hospital on Friday amid reports that his health problems may be more serious than originally announced.</p>
<p>When the 80-year-old singer entered Cedars-Sinai Medical Centre a week ago, his publicist Susan Reynolds said it was for treatment of a &quot;pinched nerve.&quot;</p>
<p>But Army Archerd, a leading Hollywood columnist who writes for Daily Variety, said on Tuesday that Sinatra's daughter, Nancy Sinatra, told him her father had a slight case of pneumonia.</p>
<p>Citing an unnamed source, Los Angeles television station KCBS reported on Friday that Sinatra's condition had worsened and that he was being treated for &quot;heart failure&quot; as well as pneumonia.</p>
<p>The TV station said Sinatra's hospital room at Cedars-Sinai Medical Centre resembled an intensive care unit but that he wanted to go home against his doctor's orders.</p>
<p>The report could not be independently confirmed.</p>
<p>Sinatra's publicist and a hospital spokesman had earlier denied reports that he was seriously ill when he entered the hospital on Nov. 1.</p>
<p>Reynolds has since refused to answer questions about his health, saying he &quot;personally requested there be no comment on his condition until he is released.&quot; Hospital officials have also remained silent.</p>
<p>Sinatra was originally expected to return home last weekend, but doctors extended his hospital stay without explanation.</p>
<p>In Tuesday's column, Archerd said Nancy Sinatra told him her father was feeling better after a minor bout of pneumonia.</p>
<p>Sinatra's other daughter, Tina, said the singer had been suffering from the pinched nerve &quot;for several weeks&quot; before being admitted, Archerd wrote.</p>
<p>The hospital has received dozens of flower displays and hundreds of letters from Sinatra's fans and well-wishers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
