<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17693" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian bonds knocked back again.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian bonds knocked back again.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian bonds were beaten down for the second day in a row as a combination of hedge fund selling, stop-loss orders and profit-taking continued to correct the recent massive rally, traders said.</p>
<p>The September 10-year bond futures contract dived to 91.770 at one stage in the wake of today's A$700 million Treasury bond tender having touched 92.210 just under a week ago in the midst of a post-budget buying frenzy.</p>
<p>&quot;We're hearing from the futures floor that offshore hedge funds have been fairly aggressive again, and obviously the tender didn't help,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>A weakening U.S. bond market has also dampened the post-budget after glow which took the 10-year bond yield down to its lowest in nearly 2-1/2 years at 7.80 percent, but it still remains well above the 9.0 percent-plus level seen in mid-June.</p>
<p>U.S. bonds slid on Monday as the fear of a tightening in monetary policy after a string of stronger than expected data continued to grip the market, as did forthcoming fresh supply in the shape of two- and five-year note auctions this week.</p>
<p>The key 30-year long bond yield hit 7.0 percent for the first time in four week's, but eased back to 6.97 percent in Tokyo trading amid Japanese bargain hunting.  </p>
<p>-----------------------(SPREADS)----------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 97 (+ 08)   142 (+ 10) * FUTURES   72   (+ 01)</p>
<p> CAD	135 (+ 09)    88 (+ 14) * CASH	88   (+ 03)</p>
<p> NZD	-79 (+ 10)   -03 (+ 05) *</p>
<p>------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The local market is also correcting the sharp tightening in yield spreads to other dollar bloc bonds which had taken the 10-year margin to the U.S. down to 120 basis points on Monday. Canada continued to strongly outperform Australia and the U.S., benefitting from its current bullish fundamentals.  </p>
<p>--------------------(TECHNICALS)-----------------------------</p>
<p>FUTURES	*DAY'S HILO  *SUP/RES     *RSI    *MA-10 *MA-20</p>
<p>10-YEAR (SEP)*91.89-91.77 *91.75-91.83 *51 PCT *92.00 *91.93</p>
<p>3-YEAR  (SEP)*92.63-92.51 *92.53-92.59 *54 PCT *92.73 *92.67</p>
<p>90-DAY  (DEC)*93.24-93.16 *93.16-93.20 *58 PCT *93.31 *93.29</p>
<p>-------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>The 10-year bond contract ended testing resistance at 91.830 after filling a chart gap down to 91.785 left in early August. Support is seen at the pyschological 91.750.</p>
<p>-- Colin Brinsden 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
