<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17700" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Rugby union-Hawkins quits as New South Wales coach.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Rugby union-Hawkins quits as New South Wales coach.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>New South Wales rugby union coach Chris Hawkins has resigned at the end of his first season because of business commitments, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hawkins, whose side failed to reach the semifinals in the inaugural Super 12 competition, left on amicable terms, New South Wales Rugby Union chairman Ian Ferrier said.</p>
<p>&quot;Chris' business commitments make it difficult for him to embrace the coaching job on a full-time basis which is an essential element of the position given the year-round nature of preparing a team for professional provincial rugby,&quot; Ferrier said in a statement.</p>
<p>Ferrier said the union would begin the search for Hawkins' replacement in the near future.</p>
<p>New South Wales were rated among the favourites for the southern hemisphere Super 12 competition involving provincial sides from Australia, New Zealand and South Africa.</p>
<p>Auckland defeated Natal in the Super 12 final in May.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
