<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177060" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Bid to solve German metal pay row collapses.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Bid to solve German metal pay row collapses.</headline>
<byline>Mark John</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's metal and engineering industry on Friday moved one step closer to possible all-out strikes after an attempt by regional negotiators to solve a bitter dispute over proposed cuts to labour costs collapsed.</p>
<p>There had been hopes that union leaders and employers in the state of Baden-Wuerttemberg, home to Daimler-Benz AG's Mercedes car-making unit, might come to a deal that could then be used as a &quot;pilot&quot; agreement for other regions.</p>
<p>But leaders of the IG Metall trade union said after the 19-hour talks broke down early on Friday that employers had continued to demand cuts to sick pay entitlements, an issue on which they were not ready to negotiate.</p>
<p>&quot;The employers must finally realise that no deal can be struck with IG Metall that is to the detriment of those workers who fall ill,&quot; IG Metall deputy chairman Walter Riester told journalists.</p>
<p>Dieter Hundt, chief negotiator for the Gesamtmetall metal and engineering employers federation, attacked IG Metall for showing &quot;no willingness for agreement&quot;. Employers are seeking an overall freeze in labour costs in 1997.</p>
<p>The talks followed the failure last month of attempts to find a national agreement over planned cuts to sick pay and other worker benefits such as holiday and Christmas bonuses.</p>
<p>A union spokeswoman confirmed the two sides had now agreed to hold further talks this month in the state of North-Rhine Westphalia in what is likely to be the last chance to solve the row on labour costs before the main 1997 wage round in January.</p>
<p>If no overall agreement is reached in Germany's major steel-producing region, union leaders could decide to follow a decision made by Bavarian worker representatives in September to cancel existing wage contracts.</p>
<p>Regional union chiefs there gave notice of their intention to cancel existing wage contracts from January 31, allowing the 650,000 engineering workers in the southern state to stage all-out strikes from March onwards.</p>
<p>Such a development could be disastrous for employers, which have already suffered wild-cat protests involving hundreds of thousands of workers against earlier attempts by firms including Daimler to impose a new law cutting sick pay from the current 100 percent of salary to 80 percent.</p>
<p>Gesamtmetall's Hundt said employers had in the latest talks offered to continue paying full sick entitlements in return for employees losing 1.7 days of holiday for each three weeks of absence -- something that was also rejected by the union.</p>
<p>The only area of agreement reached in the talks was in job protection measures that form part of IG Metall's 1997 wage demand.</p>
<p>The union agreed that in future companies suffering from a business downturn would be able to cut working hours with a proportional reduction in wages.</p>
<p>In return workers councils would seek a commitment from employers to prevent redundancies.</p>
<p>-- Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
