<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177202" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: UN agencies powerless to help in combat-hit Zaire.</title>
<headline>UN agencies powerless to help in combat-hit Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>United Nations agencies on Friday said it was too dangerous for them to do anything to help hundreds of thousands of refugees in eastern Zaire and expressed bitterness at their impotence.</p>
<p>With stocks of aid piling up around east Africa to feed and shelter the refugees when it is once more safe to do so, the agencies said they were powerless.</p>
<p>Ruth Marshall, spokeswoman for the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), also regretted the international community had failed to come forward earlier to help separate extremists from bonafide Rwandan Hutu refugees in camps in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>A complex multi-sided war in eastern Zaire has cut off more than a million Rwandan refugees from the outside world and also driven more and more Zaireans to hunger. Goma's foreign aid workers fled to Rwanda last Saturday after fierce battles.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the U.N. Children's Fund (UNICEF) cited refugee women arriving at the Rwandan border as having left their dead or dying children behind.</p>
<p>&quot;Our impotence to react to this catastrophic situation must be recognised,&quot; UNICEF spokeswoman Marie Heuze told a briefing.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all in the same boat. It is the last 10 or 15 kilometers which prevents us from getting aid to these people,&quot; Heuze added.</p>
<p>Marshall told the same news briefing in Geneva: &quot;It is a very bitter thing for this agency to look at the same scenario happening again.&quot;</p>
<p>Sadako Ogata, U.N. High Commissioner, on Thursday said a &quot;neutral force&quot; should be sent by the international community to set up safe routes to deliver aid through fighting and empowered to arrest and disarm militias in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;We want a ceasefire, we would like corridors,&quot; Marshall said. &quot;The corridors, if they were set up with security guarantees of the parties to the conflict, could conceivably be staffed with civilians to reassure the refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;They could be UNHCR staff or civil defence staff. It doesn't have to be military,&quot; the spokeswoman added.</p>
<p>Asked whether Western states had responded to UNHCR's appeal on October 29 for satellite pictures to trace hundreds of thousands of refugees fleeing ethnic conflict, she replied:</p>
<p>&quot;To my knowledge, we do not have sat photos.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
