<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177282" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Union plans industrial action at Lufthansa.</title>
<headline>Union plans industrial action at Lufthansa.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>German white-collar workers union DAG on Friday said it planned &quot;limited industrial action&quot; against Deutsche Lufthansa AG despite the German airline's offer of new wage talks announced on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The warning strike is to take place at several airports at the same time and involve sections of both the ground and air personnel,&quot; DAG said in a statement.</p>
<p>DAG said the protest would take place &quot;in the next few days&quot;. A spokesman said the union was not giving further details so as not to help the airline plan its response.</p>
<p>Talks between the two broke down last month after Lufthansa refused to meet DAG's demand for a four percent increase in wages.</p>
<p>DAG, which said Lufthansa's offer would give its workers a pay rise below inflation, also objected to the 27-month contract period it said Lufthansa was demanding.</p>
<p>Lufthansa earlier on Friday took out a full-page newspaper advertisement to reassure passengers that it would be doing &quot;everything to maintain a normal flight service&quot;.</p>
<p>The advert, in the form of a letter to customers from chairman Juergen Weber, said that the airline was seeking to be &quot;an attractive partner in terms of price and quality offering a worldwide network&quot;.</p>
<p>Lufthansa said last month it was trying to rein in its unit costs by as much as 20 percent to meet growing competition in the airline business.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Lufthansa said that it had received very little information over DAG's planned industrial action but was not expecting any major disruption to flight service.</p>
<p>Lufthansa had on Thursday said it was ready to hold further wage talks with the DAG white collar workers trade union, with a new focus on possible job protection measures for employees.</p>
<p>A spokesman for DAG said it had not replied to Lufthansa's call for it to suggest new dates when negotiations could start.</p>
<p>Lufthansa last month struck a two-year pay deal with 50,000 workers represented by the OeTV public sector and transport union. In an unusual move for a German company, the deal gave employees the option of being offered Lufthansa stock.</p>
<p>--Mark John, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 7567525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
