<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17744" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-BHP Minerals says eyes larger projects.</title>
<headline>RTRS-BHP Minerals says eyes larger projects.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd said on Tuesday its minerals division would look beyond traditional businesses to a new range of large scale projects in order to build on its strong performance in fiscal 1995/96.</p>
<p>In the year to May 31, BHP Minerals achieved an 11.9 percent rise in profit to A$1.078 billion, on the back of higher price and shipments for most of its commodities, plus an abnormal profit of A$65 million.</p>
<p>The division planned to target a range of commodities for future growth including diamonds, platinum, titanium, silver, lead and zinc, BHP said in its 1995/96 annual report.  </p>
<p>BHP Minerals' current product portfolio is centred around steelmaking raw materials and gold.</p>
<p>The group's growth strategy would focus on exploration, strategic business alliances and development of technical expertise, BHP said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is invigorating its world class steelmaking raw materials operations and expanding through increased downstream processing and a worldwide marketing network,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>At 1.23 p.m. (0323 GMT) BHP shares were down 12 cents to A$17.46.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne bureau 61-3 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
