<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177465" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-IRWIN HOLDS ONE-SHOT LEAD IN SENIOR CHAMPIONSHIP.</title>
<headline>GOLF-IRWIN HOLDS ONE-SHOT LEAD IN SENIOR CHAMPIONSHIP.</headline>
<dateline>MYRTLE BEACH, South Carolina 1996-11-07</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senior PGA Tour money leader Hale Irwin shot a five-under-par 67 Thursday to hold a one-stroke lead after the first round of the $1.6 million Senior Tour Championship.</p>
<p>The top 31 players on the Tour money list are playing in the season-ending event, which could determine the Arnold Palmer Award given to the season's money-winner. Irwin has earned $1,572,894, appproximately $66,000 more than defending champion Jim Colbert, who stood three shots back after a 70.</p>
<p>Irwin, a two-time winner in his second year on the Senior Tour, had a bogey-free round and was one shot in front of Bob Charles and Vicente Fernandez. Jay Sigel and Mike Hill were another stroke back at 3-under 69.</p>
<p>Irwin had three birdies on the front nine and added birdies at 14th and par-four 18th holes. The final birdie proved to be the difference, as Charles, who overcame an early bogey, missed a four-foot par putt at the final hole.</p>
<p>&quot;I putted well,&quot; said Irwin, who finished first once and second three times in the Senior Tour's four majors. &quot;There were a couple of shaky ones but again, these greens are not the easiest to putt. They do have some breaks that are hard to pick up.&quot;</p>
<p>Charles, a 60-year-old and one of the shortest hitters on Tour, bogeyed the par-three fifth hole when his tee shot came up on the front edge of the green before a 10-foot chip and two putts. He had six birdies before the final hole.</p>
<p>&quot;I am in as better shape at 60 as I have ever been in my life,&quot; Charles said. &quot;I feel just as strong, just as much energy. I have never felt better in my life at 60 years of age.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;Other than a lack of distance off the tee, I feel like I am still very competitive.&quot;</p>
<p>Colbert, who leads the Tour with five wins this year, was among a group of four with John Bland, Lee Trevino and Larry Gilbert. Bland has won four times this season and Trevino won last week for the first time in more than a year to move past Charles as the all-time Senior Tour money leader with $6,689,649.</p>
<p>Bob Murphy had a hole-in-one at the par-three 12th hole en route to a 72. It was Murphy's second ace on the Senior Tour and the first in tournament history. It also was the 16th on the Senior Tour this year, breaking the record of 15 set in 1995.</p>
<p>The par-72 Dunes Golf &amp; Beach Club course measures 6,815 yards. First prize for the 72-hole tournament is $280,000, by far the largest on the Tour.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-07"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MYRTLE BEACH, South Carolina"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
