<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177451" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Hundreds dead in Indian cyclone.</title>
<headline>Hundreds dead in Indian cyclone.</headline>
<dateline>HYDERABAD 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Relief work was under way on Friday after a cyclone called the worst in 10 years hit the southeast Indian state of Andhra Pradesh, killing hundreds of people and leaving thousands homeless, officials said.</p>
<p>There was no official word on casualties from the cyclone, which ravaged the state on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>A police official late on Thursday said more than 460 people had died, while state television Doordashan put the figure at 230 in its Friday morning newscast.</p>
<p>Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister V. Chandrababu Naidu said on Thursday that the death toll might rise to 1,000. &quot;The rice bowl of the state looks like a burial ground,&quot; he said after flying over the flood-hit areas.</p>
<p>H.S. Bramha, the official in charge of relief operations in the state capital Hyderabad, said he hoped to receive details by late morning from the hardest hit areas around the Godavari River delta, south of the port city of Kakinada.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the worst cyclone in 10 years,&quot; Brahma told Reuters.</p>
<p>The cyclone crossed the coast 50 km (30 miles) south of Kakinada, tore down power and telephone lines and wreaked havoc in the rice-growing Godavari districts, officials said.</p>
<p>Local tax collector Reddy Subramaniam told Reuters that at least 309 people had died in East Godavari, where 100,000 homes were destroyed or damaged. About 42 of the deaths occurred when a boat capsized in the Godavari River.</p>
<p>There was a shortage of drinking water in the villages along the coast in East Godavari distict, the official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Water is being transported (to the villages) from towns as far as 200 km (125 miles)&quot; away, Subramaniam said. &quot;Food packets and kerosene are being distributed freely.&quot;</p>
<p>The official said nearly 250,000 hectares of rice paddy was inundated and 450,000 acres of other crops including chillies, banana plantations and coconut grooves were badly damaged.</p>
<p>Several thousand head of cattle died in the storm, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a problem on our hands with the dead animals -- whether to burn them or bury them,&quot; Subramaniam said.</p>
<p>Medical teams would be on hand to prevent the spread of disease when the dead cattle begin to decompose, he added.</p>
<p>Some areas of Kakinada were submerged after a tidal wave from the sea hit the town.</p>
<p>&quot;The water receded after an hour but stayed on in the low-lying areas,&quot; Subramaniam said.</p>
<p>Port authorities had moved 12 ships anchored at Kakinada out to sea to escape the cyclone, and residents of the town were still recovering from its fury, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HYDERABAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
