<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177420" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian investors must be lured back - Chidambaram.</title>
<headline>Indian investors must be lured back - Chidambaram.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said on Friday he hoped the launch of country's first share depository will lure retail investors back to sluggish capital markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important element missing is the confidence of the retail investor,&quot; Chidambaram said about the gloom surrounding Indian capital markets.</p>
<p>The benchmark stocks index of the Bombay bourse has fallen 25 percent since its 1996 peak of 4067.29 hit in June. The index closed the week at 3066.66 on Thursday ahead of a long weekend.</p>
<p>Chidambaram was speaking at the launch of the National Securities Depository Ltd (NSDL) which will introduce paperless trade in the country.</p>
<p>The NSDL -- promoted by Unit Trust of India, the National Stock Exchange and the Industrial Development Bank of India -- is expected to eliminate lengthy share transfer rules, cut transaction costs and boost foreign inflows.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said the confidence of the retail investor must be boosted and he must be convinced he will get adequate returns on his investments.</p>
<p>More than 20 million retail investors trade on the country's 23 turbulent exchanges. Analysts say investors have increasingly lost faith in firms which raise money through high premium issues and are then listed below their issue price.</p>
<p>Some 50 percent of the nearly 7,000 scrips listed on the Bombay Stock Exchange are trading below par, they say.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said lengthy share trasfer procedures also deterred retail investments.</p>
<p>&quot;The settlement system is so tardy...that many of them shudder at the thought of buying shares,&quot; Chidambaram said.</p>
<p>Currently, transfer procedures for physical shares take more than three months in India. Shares often go missing in the mail or are returned undelivered if signatures fail to tally.</p>
<p>&quot;A 1,000 complaints pour into the Department of Company Affairs every month,&quot; the finance minister said.</p>
<p>He said India must move from this inefficient and lengthy settlement system to a system of &quot;painless trade.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The depository is a beginning...but there's a long way to go,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chidambaram said investors must be persuaded to demateralise their holdings. Dematerialisation is the process by which the physical certificates of an investor are taken back by the company or registrar and destroyed. An equal number of shares are credited to the electronic holdings of the investor.</p>
<p>&quot;What you're telling the investor is that your scrips will be taken away from you, given back to the company where it will be dematerialised -- a euphimism for shredding,&quot; he joked.</p>
<p>He said the NSDL and participating companies and members must educate investors about the advantages of the depository.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
