<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17749" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Compulsory NZ super would drain economy - Gresham.</title>
<headline>Compulsory NZ super would drain economy - Gresham.</headline>
<byline>Mark Trevelyan</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Social Welfare Minister Peter Gresham said on Tuesday that New Zealand could afford to sustain its current pensions regime if it repaid public debt, and a switch to compulsory super would act as a drag on the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Compulsory superannuation has its problems of being a very significant drain on the economy for quite a long time while the fund is being set up, regardless of how the fund is invested and where it's held, the security and the safety of it, all of those things,&quot; Gresham said in an interview.  </p>
<p>&quot;In the first 20 or so years which the fund takes to build up, all your taxpayers in that time pay double. They pay for current retirees and they pay for their own retirement and it will be 20 or 30 years before they'll start to produce a significant return.&quot;</p>
<p>Gresham noted that compulsory superannuation would be one of the areas examined in a 1997 review of the multi-party accord on retirement income.</p>
<p>He declined to speculate on whether National would be prepared to negotiate on compulsory superannuation after the October 12 election.  </p>
<p>The New Zealand First Party proposes to go ahead with a second round of tax cuts on July 1, 1997 and introduce compulsory superannuation at three percent of income, rising to eight percent over time.</p>
<p>The Labour Party wants to create a national superannuation fund, financed through a tax at eight cents in the dollar, to be paid instead of the same amount of personal income tax. It proposes an initial cash injection of NZ$150 million.</p>
<p>Gresham said studies indicated that the current superannuation regime could be sustained, given prudent fiscal management. This would mean repayment of public debt.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the country shifts its public debt, has no debt servicing burden, possibly gets to a credit position...coming to 2015 and beyond, yes it's reasonable to say we're in a position to sustain it. But if we still have a public debt and it's 20 to 30 percent of GDP at that stage, it would be highly unlikely that we would sustain it.&quot;</p>
<p>Gresham said the government was confident of passing a bill to raise the threshold for the superannuation surtax -- the last piece of legislation it aims to push through in the current term -- despite possible blocking tactics by New Zealand First.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think the surcharge thresholds will be changed next April...We'll get the legislation through,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bill increases the thresholds for the surcharge from April 1, 1997 so the cut-in point occurs when a couple's gross income is about 10 percent above the average ordinary time wage.</p>
<p>The new thresholds will be $15,444 a year of other income for couples ($6,825 previously) and $10,296 a year for single superannuitants ($4,550 previously).</p>
<p>The government estimates the change will reduce the number paying the surcharge by more than 100,000 or from 25 percent to 14 percent of all superannuitants.  </p>
<p>New Zealand First argues the surcharge should be scrapped altogether. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
