<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177588" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: DUTCH ABN AMRO SPREADS EAST WITH HUNGARY MHB BUY.</title>
<headline>DUTCH ABN AMRO SPREADS EAST WITH HUNGARY MHB BUY.</headline>
<byline>Ian Geoghegan</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>ABN AMRO NV, Europe's fifth largest banking group, on Friday beat off an Austrian rival to capture a majority stake in Hungary's Magyar Hitel Bank (MHB).</p>
<p>The biggest Dutch bank said it was paying $89.23 million for the near 90 percent stake in MHB, Hungary's fifth largest bank.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO, which expects the deal to be finalised before the year-end, said it would substantially increase MHB's capital.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition to the purchase price ABN AMRO will invest another $100 million in MHB over the next year,&quot; Michael Drabbe, head of ABN AMRO International, told reporters in Budapest.</p>
<p>&quot;We aim to become one of the top three banks in the central and east European region (and) our new acquisition will enhance this position enormously.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The total transaction is one of the largest foreign investments in a commercial bank in central and eastern Europe to date,&quot; ABN AMRO said in a statement released in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>MHB, with its network of 70 branches across Hungary, is a leading bank for major domestic companies and is active in the capital markets, leasing and factoring. It has also developed plans to set up electronic consumer banking and life insurance operations.</p>
<p>Analysts welcomed the move, saying that ABN AMRO had to have a local presence in eastern Europe as many of its global corporate clients were expanding there.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good move,&quot; said Rutger Terluin at Amstgeld.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a growth market and ABN AMRO has to be there. It is very good to have the local expertise -- knowledge of local rules and legislation.&quot;</p>
<p>In a one-round tender, ABN AMRO beat off a rival bid from Austria's Creditanstalt-Bankverein to win the go-ahead from Hungary's state privatisation agency APV.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO started business in Hungary in 1990 and opened an outlet in Budapest three years later. It currently employs 80 staff in Hungary.</p>
<p>The MHB buy will give ABN AMRO an immediate network of branch offices throughout Hungary. MHB has plans to regroup 40 branches in retail banking under the MHB Nepbank banner and to have 30 branches specialising in corporate clients.</p>
<p>&quot;ABN AMRO fully underwrites the MHB board's development plans,&quot; Drabbe said.</p>
<p>The Dutch financial services group, with business in 70 countries and with over 64,000 staff, has total assets of $384.3 billion.</p>
<p>MHB made post-tax profits of 3.44 billion forints in the first eight months of 1996, versus 1.4 billion forints for the whole of 1995.</p>
<p>Under chief executive officer Zsigmond Jarai, who took over in 1995, MHB has written off millions of dollars of bad debt, cut staff by 40 percent to 2,500 and reduced operating costs.</p>
<p>The privatisation of MHB was briefly threatened last month after a scandal over irregular payments which resulted in the dismissal of the privatisation minister and APV's board.</p>
<p>In early Amsterdam trading ABN AMRO stock added 1.20 guilders to 100 guilders. 081036 GMT nov 96</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
