<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177545" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - SLOVENIA  - NOV 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SLOVENIA  - NOV 8.</headline>
<text>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- Slovenian Foreign Minister Davorin Kracun attended a meeting of the Council of Europe in Strasbourg on Thursday.</p>
<p>- The hearing at a Nicosia court on whether the assets of the former Yugoslavia in the offshore Beogradska Banka will remain frozen continues on Friday.</p>
<p>- Slovenian election campaign will end at midnight on Friday, a day before the country's second general election on Sunday.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Mitja Gaspari said public spending increased this year mainly due to the rise in salaries in the public sector.</p>
<p>- Ski firm Elan expects to sell 40 percent of its ski production in the United States this year.</p>
<p>- The price of shares of Port Luka Koper is rising on the unlisted market ahead of an expected listing on the Ljubljana bourse at the end of November.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- Employers said on Thursday that the general collective agreement determining salaries and work benefits should be changed from next April.</p>
<p>- President Milan Kucan on Thursday presented research awards to five Slovenian experts, mainly in connection with scientific and engineering projects.</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- Ljubljana city council is expected to decide whether the city's heating system should continue to use Slovenian coal, considered ecologically unsuitable for the capital.</p>
<p>- The government office of macroeconomic analysis said Slovenian GDP growth could be below three percent in 1996.</p>
<p>- Slovenian state prosecutor Anton Drobnic said on Thursday he was not aware that a computer diskette containing details of up to 150 prominent Slovenians had got into unauthorised hands.</p>
<p>FINANCE</p>
<p>- Slovenian state institutions said they would not be badly hurt by the possible bankruptcy of Komercialna Banka Triglav.</p>
<p>- From January, individuals will have to pay tax on profits made in the securities market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
