<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177696" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Roche wins Europe patent for PCR enzymes.</title>
<headline>Roche wins Europe patent for PCR enzymes.</headline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switzerland 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pharmaceutical group Roche Holding AG said the European Patent Agency would grant it a patent covering key enzymes used in polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technology.</p>
<p>A Roche statement said the patent would cover &quot;thermostable enzymes having DNA polymerase activity from any species of bacteria such as Tag DNA polymerase from Thermus aquaticus&quot;.</p>
<p>Roche said these enzymes were important in PCR technology, which helps in testing of blood products for diseases such as AIDS or cancer by amplifying very minute amounts of genetic material into billions of copies.</p>
<p>Roche said the imminent patent strengthened its large patent portfolio in nucleic acid amplification technology.</p>
<p>It was also important in regard to patent litigation against Promega Corporation in the United States, Roche said.</p>
<p>&quot;Roche is now in a position to actively protect its own interests in the area of nucleic acid amplification technology as well as those of licensees,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Roche originally sued Promega in October 1992 for breach of a licensing agreement to make and sell Taq DNA polymerase and infringement of the Taq patent. Promega counter-claimed in December 1994, alleging the Taq patent was invalid.</p>
<p>&quot;The European patent is expected to be issued within the next six months,&quot; Roche said.</p>
<p>It said the European agency's examining division, at a hearing on November 6, accepted the claims submitted by Roche &quot;covering native and recombinant thermostable DNA polymerases, without limitation to a particular species or genus&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Newsroom, +41-1-631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switzerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
