<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177621" id="root" date="1996-11-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - NOV 8.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS - NOV 8.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--The government presents civil servants with a proposal calculated to stick to the convergence programme and to keep reactions to the minimum. The unified wage scale the government is proposing offers few to no increases and, in some cases, may lead to a reduction in take-home pay. </p>
<p>-- The Athens Stock Exchange faces a credibility crisis as bourse authorities find themselves incapable of controlling procedures.</p>
<p>--The ban on departing the country for those with debts to the state and to the Social Security Foundation (IKA) will be lifted, following a higher court ruling. The ruling, however, runs contrary to the Maastrict treaty.</p>
<p>--New taxation measures and additional favourable lending conditions are two of the incentives offered to farmers in the agriculture ministry's new bill.</p>
<p>--The Halkidiki casino faces closure, as competition from the new Thessaloniki casino halves its monthly profits. </p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--National Bank Governor Theodoros Karatzas says that there's a serious crisis at the Athens Stock Exchange, with the first indication being Delta Securities inability to comply with the clearing house on settlement regulations. Capital market sources dub yesterday's events at the ASE &quot;Black Thursday&quot;.</p>
<p>--The Bank of Greece is proceeding with the full deregulation of foreign exchange deposit accounts for permanent residents.</p>
<p>--Civil servants on low pay will receive higher increases under the new wage scale to come into effect on January 1. The new scale sees a gradual increase in basic wages in the order of 8-9 percent for 1997.</p>
<p>KERDOS</p>
<p>--The ASE received a blow to its credibility yesterday as a major brokerage firm failed to comply with the clearing houses's settlement regulations.</p>
<p>--Development Minister Vasso Papandreou announces a series of measures for Greek tourism. Papandreou says the success of the tourist product is dependent on the professionalism of sector employees.</p>
<p>--The housing loan market is seeing more activity as the Ionian and EuroInvestment Banks offer a range of new products. Sources say the market will develop further as interest rates fall.</p>
<p>--The central bank orders increased capital for banks to safeguard against new credit risks.</p>
<p>EXPRESS --Economic circles say the European Commission's recent warning that Greece had to make the grade for convergence by mid-1997 or foot the bill has had a positive effect on developments. The government's response to Brussels will be in the new budget to be tabled this month, they say.</p>
<p>--The finance ministry is faced with making final decisions on improving the objective tax criteria and taxing derivatives, state titles and real estate within the next few days.</p>
<p>NAFTEMBORIKI</p>
<p>--The civil servants union, ADEDY, appears determined to fight the government's new wage scale for the public service. ADEDY will make its decisions today.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
