<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177773" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada beauty queen pleads not guilty to assault.</title>
<headline>Canada beauty queen pleads not guilty to assault.</headline>
<dateline>ST. JOHN'S, Newfoundland 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The woman known as Canada's brawling beauty queen pleaded not guilty on Friday to assault charges and said she planned to continue her public engagements.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been the worst experience of my life -- a nightmare,&quot; Danielle House, 20, told reporters after a brief court appearance, saying she was shocked by media interest in the case.</p>
<p>Her trial was scheduled for next March.</p>
<p>House, who holds the Miss Canada International title, said she would keep up her engagements, including an appearance in this month's parade for the Canadian Football League's Grey Cup championship game in Hamilton, Ontario.</p>
<p>She declined to discuss the charge against her, that she allegedly punched a woman in the face in a university pub. Police have said the fight started after House saw the woman with House's former boyfriend.</p>
<p>House called the incident a hazard of being a beauty queen.</p>
<p>&quot;I always knew there was cattiness involved in pageants, but nothing like this,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>House has been barred from the Miss World International pageant this month, but not all the news is bad.</p>
<p>Her agent, Isabelle Fry, said media interest in House had prompted a barrage of inquiries from modelling agencies.</p>
<p>&quot;This kind of exposure is something money can't buy,&quot; Fry said. &quot;I believe she's got a great career ahead of her.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. JOHN'S, Newfoundland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
