<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177870" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia detains activists, youths disrupt meeting.</title>
<headline>Malaysia detains activists, youths disrupt meeting.</headline>
<byline>Syed Azman</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-11-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian police detained dozens of activists, including two Roman Catholic bishops, on Saturday after a youth group allied to the government broke up a controversial conference on East Timor.</p>
<p>Almost 40 foreign participants at the second Asia Pacific Conference on East Timor (APCET) were taken by police truck to the Immigration Department. Conference organisers said they were likely to be deported.</p>
<p>A Malaysian minister said earlier this week that the government did not want the conference to take place because it could harm bilateral ties with Indonesia.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded East Timor in 1975 and now rules the territory in defiance of the United Nations.</p>
<p>Among those taken away by police were the two bishops, the Rev. Aloisuis Nobulo Somo of Japan and the Rev. Hilton Deakin of Melbourne, Australia.</p>
<p>Also detained were dozens of Malaysian human rights group activists. Police would not immediately say how many activists were being detained or why.</p>
<p>Two foreign journalists, Asiaweek correspondent Roger Mitton and Australia Broadcasting Corporation correspondent Catherine McGrath were also detained.</p>
<p>A youth group, calling itself the Malaysian Action Front, drew riot police to a hotel in central Kuala Lumpur after they stormed into the East Timor meeting, shouting slogans and singing patriotic songs.</p>
<p>Shoving activists aside, the youths broke down a collapsible door into a fourth-floor conference hall.</p>
<p>Malaysian Action Front Secretary-General Saifudin Nasution said the group comprised youth groups allied to the three main political parties in Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad's coalition -- the United Malays National Organisation, the Malaysian Chinese Association and the Malaysian Indian Congress.</p>
<p>Using a loudspeaker, Nasution accused the activists -- who sat quietly on the floor looking glum -- of trying to damage ties between Indonesia and Malaysia.</p>
<p>Malaysia's Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim said earlier this week the government strongly objected to the meeting and would seek legal ways of stopping it.</p>
<p>Witnesses said police made no effort to stop the youths from charging up the stairs of the hotel, carrying banners and signs and singing at the top of their voices.</p>
<p>Police later arrested about a dozen of the youths when they refused police demands to leave the hotel.</p>
<p>&quot;It has all the hallmarks of an orchestrated act,&quot; Fan Yew Ting, a Malaysian human rights activist who was to have spoken at the conference, said amid the shouting. &quot;What we have here is definitely uncivilised and illegal.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It's very strange,&quot; Fan said. &quot;The police were not here (to stop the youths). Security people were missing.&quot;</p>
<p>Said conference spokesperson Debbie Stothard: &quot;This is a day of shame for me as a Malaysian.</p>
<p>&quot;They have trespassed on private premises. They have been so violent and yelling at us. They have pushed us around. And they put fear in our visitors,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>About 150 foreign delegates from 20 countries had been expected to attend the three-day meeting ahead of Tuesday's anniversary of the 1991 killing by Indonesian troops of at least 50 demonstrators in East Timor's capital of Dili.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, immigration authorities refused to allow Renato Constantino of the Philippines into the country to attend the conference. He organised the first APCET in Manila in 1994.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded East Timor in December 1975 and annexed it the following year. The United Nations still recognises Lisbon as the administering authority in the territory, located in the far east of the Indonesian archipelago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
