<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177875" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: North Korea criticises U.S.-Japan wargames.</title>
<headline>North Korea criticises U.S.-Japan wargames.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korea's state press on Saturday condemned the U.S.-Japanese war games under way in the Sea of Japan, saying they were part of military provocations by South Korea, Japan and the United States.</p>
<p>The Rodong Simun newspaper called the exercises &quot;a grave provocation and a grave threat to peace and security in Asia.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Rodong Sinmun today brands the U.S.-Japan Keen Sword military exercise as an aggressive war drill against the DPRK (North Korea), a grave provocation against the DPRK and a grave threat to peace and security in Asia,&quot; the North's Korean Central News Agency (KCNA) said in a report seen in Tokyo.</p>
<p>U.S. and Japanese forces are conducting the &quot;Keen Sword '97&quot; war games in the Sea of Japan from November 4-17. The exercises involve 26,000 personnel, half from each country.</p>
<p>Keen Sword '97 also involves one of the largest displays of airpower by U.S. forces this year, with more than 300 sorties flown from the carrier USS Independence over four days, according to the authoritative Jane's Defence Weekly.</p>
<p>Rodon Sinmun, organ of North Korea's ruling Communist Party, said the manoeuvers coincided with U.S.-South Korea war games.</p>
<p>&quot;The exercise is timed to coincide with the U.S.-South Korea joint military manoeuvres codenamed Foal Eagle '96, which are rendering the situation on the Korean Peninsula to the extreme pitch of strain. This is a very grave development,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Foal Eagle is schedued to end on Sunday.</p>
<p>Rodon Sinmun said most of the U.S. forces involved in Foal Eagle '96 would also take part in Keen Sword '97.</p>
<p>&quot;This is patent proof that the Keen Sword 97 is a reckless provocation to round off the combat preparedness of the U.S.-Japan-South Korea tripartite military alliance and stifle the DPRK by force of arms,&quot; the North Korean daily said.</p>
<p>The Keen Sword games are normally held in the Pacific Ocean. A Japanese Defence Ministry spokesman has said the shift this year to the Sea of Japan was to provide training in different weather and environmental conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no connection with any international situation, such as the Korean Peninsula,&quot; the ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>Tension in the region has been high since a North Korean submarine ran aground in South Korean waters on September 18. All but one of the 26 of the North Koreans who evacuated the submarine on the East Coast beach has been killed or captured.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
