<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177898" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore clean, green, but not so gracious.</title>
<headline>Singapore clean, green, but not so gracious.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore has a well-deserved reputation for being clean, green and relatively crime-free, but lags in graciousness, the Minister of State for Trade and Industry and Communications said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Goh Chee Wee said in a speech at the launch of a Mass Rapid Transit Corp courtesy campaign that &quot;there is one element that lagged behind our economic and material achievements. That one element is the graciousness among our population.&quot;</p>
<p>As an example, Goh noted the reluctance of some passengers on trains to give up seats for pregant women or the elderly.</p>
<p>&quot;It is common to see such passengers sitting snugly in their seats and pretending to be asleep or engrossed with their books, ignoring the person standing right in front of them who is in greater need of the seat,&quot; Goh said.</p>
<p>&quot;Another annoying behaviour which one often encounters during peak hours are people who rush their way into the train without letting others alight first.&quot;</p>
<p>Goh also cited young teenagers who sit and play on the floor in front of train doors and obstruct the passageway.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to discourage such behaviour. It will take time to change people's attitude and behaviour but we must try. A gracious Singapore is not an impossible dream,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
