<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177948" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. thrown off U.N. money panel, France, N.Z. join.</title>
<headline>U.S. thrown off U.N. money panel, France, N.Z. join.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States was voted off a key U.N. financial committee for the first time on Friday, a reflection of countries' anger at Washington's $1.4 billion debt to the world body, U.S. officials said.</p>
<p>Instead, France and New Zealand were given spots on the prestigious 16-member Advisory Committee on Administrative and Budgetary Questions (ACABQ), the first legislative step in formulating the U.N.'s $1.3 billion annual budget.</p>
<p>Diplomats said it was the first time the United States, which is supposed to pay 25 percent of the U.N. budget, was not given a seat on the panel of financial experts.</p>
<p>France received 117 votes followed by New Zealand with 116 and the United States with 103. French envoys said they did not campaign against Washington, assuming it would get one of the two vacant seats for which it was eligible automatically.</p>
<p>Asked why the U.S. lost, a U.S. official said, &quot;Three things: money, money and money. The resentment of U.S. arrears to the United Nations was clearly the decisive factor.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of our participation will inevitably diminish the committee,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The vote by secret ballot was in the General Assembly's administrative and budgetary committee, which includes all 185 countries with U.N. membership. It makes the final decision on the budget, which the Assembly then usually rubber stamps.</p>
<p>Some Western diplomats who supported the United States said the arrears were one factor but that the unpopularity of the current U.S. member of the panel, Minister Counsellor Linda Shenwick, contributed to the defeat. She was to be replaced by Melinda Kimble, who diplomats said was not yet well known and was facing two strong candidates, Gerard Biraud of France and Denise Almao of New Zealand.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. is very, very upset and so are some of the rest of us. It (the committee) is a very bid deal,&quot; said one envoy.</p>
<p>But the U.S. official noted that final decisions would be made by the full committee and that U.S. Ambassador Madeleine Albright would continue to battle for fiscal restraint and a continuation of the United Nations' no-growth budget.</p>
<p>Other U.S. envoys admitted that the lack of a seat on the committee would make it more difficult than ever to get funds from the Republican-dominated Congress.</p>
<p>Many Republicans have been severely critical of the United Nations, regardless of reforms it has initiated. U.S. envoys had hoped budget cuts, which have been ongoing for two years, as well as a new secretary-general, would convince Congress to abide by U.S. international commitments.</p>
<p>The United States owes the world body about $1.4 billion for dues and peacekeeping, more than half of the U.N.'s entire debt. Japanese and Western Europeans, who pay the bulk of U.N. costs, have been openly criticial of U.S. demands for reforms when it failed to pay its debts. In addition, U.S. influence has waned because of severe cuts in international non-military aid programmes around the world.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
