<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177904" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALGERIA: Algeria inaugurates Maghreb-Europe gas pipeline.</title>
<headline>Algeria inaugurates Maghreb-Europe gas pipeline.</headline>
<byline>Lamine Ghanmi</byline>
<dateline>HASSI-R'MEL, Algeria 1996-11-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algeria on Saturday inaugurated the Maghreb-Europe gas pipeline built at an estimated cost of $2.3 billion over 30 months.</p>
<p>Energy ministers of Morocco, Spain, Portugal and Algeria attended the inauguration at desert gas fields of Hassi-R'Mel, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a dream which became true...Three years ago, few believed in achieving this great project,&quot; Ammar Makhloufi, the Algerian energy and mines minister, told reporters.</p>
<p>In the huge gas dispatching centre of Hassi R'mel, the four ministers pushed buttons corresponding to four gates through which the natural gas flows to neighbouring Morocco and on to southern Spain.</p>
<p>Spanish Industry and Energy Minister Joseph Pique said the &quot;Maghreb-Europe pipeline is one of the most ambitious and historical projects in the region.&quot;</p>
<p>More than 100 reporters and senior officials from Spain, Portugal and Morocco were invited to the inauguration ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;This new type of cooperation will be followed soon by other bilateral and multilateral projects,&quot; Moroccan Energy Minister Abdellatif Guerraoui said.</p>
<p>A similar ceremony will take place on December 2 to inaugurate the pumping station in Morocco's northern city of Tangier, which will be followed by another ceremony at the final pipeline section in the southern Spanish city of Cordoba a week later, Guerraoui said.</p>
<p>The pipeline, on which a first agreement was signed in 1991, runs from the gas fields for 1,385 km (865 miles), across Morocco, under the Strait of Gibraltar, to the Spanish city of Cordoba, and is to link up with a gas distribution network for Portugal. The section in Portugal is expected to be operational in January 1997, officials said.</p>
<p>More than 2,000 people from nearby villages celebrated by the traditional firing of shotguns as official delegations enjoyed whey milk and couscous meals.</p>
<p>The inauguration set the seal on an investment of some $2.3 billion for the line capable of carrying 9.5 billion cubic metres of gas from Algeria's Sahara Desert field of Hassi R'mel to Spain and Portugal.</p>
<p>Officials said that by the year 2,000, Algerian gas would cover 12 percent of Spain's energy consumption.</p>
<p>Algeria hopes to double its annual gas exports to 60 billion cubic metres by the year 2,000, when one Algerian official said its annual oil and gas exports should earn $16 billion.</p>
<p>Morocco will use gas from Hassi R'mel, including for electricity generation, when it has set up the infrastructure. Until then it will take a share of the income generated.</p>
<p>If successful, another pipeline -- of around 500 km (300 miles) -- may be needed to carry more gas to Hassi R'mel and then onto Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HASSI-R'MEL, Algeria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
