<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="177992" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE world sugar ends firmer, battles resistance.</title>
<headline>CSCE world sugar ends firmer, battles resistance.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE world sugar prices posted modest gains again on Friday, managing to finish in firmer territory despite having failed several bids to punch through key resistance, dealers said.</p>
<p>Short covering by commodity funds fueled the bulk of the day's gains, but each charge to the upside was met with steady producer pricing. Key March delivery crossed the previous day's peak of 10.51, but a late-session rally stalled at the 10.54 cent mark.</p>
<p>Benchmark March delivery rose 0.05 cent a lb on the day, to 10.53, having ranged narrowly from 10.45 to 10.54. Second-position May climbed 0.04 cent, to 10.58, while the outer months finished 0.05 to 0.06 higher.</p>
<p>After sagging to six-months lows at the start of the week, New York raws put in a fairly strong performance in the past few sessions, dealers said. But continued heavy industry selling overhead would make the upside difficult.</p>
<p>&quot;Coming into this week, everybody was bearish,&quot; said one. &quot;It's a good close, but 10.60 cents in March would have been a great close.&quot;</p>
<p>To confirm the uptrend, March would need to clear 10.63 cents, representing a 50 percent retracement from the recent lows. To the downside, support was seen at 10.46, with major objectives noted at 10.29 and 10.21.</p>
<p>Volume on the day was moderate, at 9,829 lots.</p>
<p>-- Wendy Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
