<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178013" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fla. inmate pleads guilty to &quot;talk radio&quot; killing.</title>
<headline>Fla. inmate pleads guilty to &quot;talk radio&quot; killing.</headline>
<dateline>AVON PARK, Fla. 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Florida inmate charged in a prison-yard slaying that may have been inspired by a challenge issued on a radio programme has pleaded guilty to second-degree murder, court officials said Friday.</p>
<p>Under a plea agreement reached Wednesday, Arba Barr, 33, will serve a life sentence concurrently with the 114 years he was serving for other crimes.</p>
<p>Barr was sentenced for the brutal slaying of Donald McDougall, one of Florida's most notorious child killers, who was serving a 34-year sentence for the sadistic 1982 slaying of five-year-old Ursula Sunshine but was up for early release.</p>
<p>McDougall was beaten to death with an iron horseshoe stake on Oct. 1 as hundreds of inmates watched, only hours after being released from protective custody at his own request. He had been placed in solidary confinement after the Sept. 25 broadcast dedicated to Ursula's memory on the &quot;Russ and Bo Show&quot; on WTKS-FM, an Orlando radio station.</p>
<p>Ursula died in 1982 after McDougall and her mother starved and tortured her, including 55 hours of torture that led to her death when her heart gave out, police said. The case attracted national attention after investigators said at least 89 people knew Ursula was being abused and did not report it.</p>
<p>During the show, the hosts joked about lynching him, encouraged inmates to beat him and pretended McDougall was already dead with a mock announcement of his demise. A caller who identified himself as a prison inmate let the hosts know their words were being taken seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;The name's gotten out. The word's gotten out,&quot; he said of McDougall. &quot;We've got a lot of guys listening to you tonight. This kind of thing makes us sick to our stomachs.&quot;</p>
<p>Most of the inmates questioned by Polk County Sheriff's deputies cited the radio broadcast as the reason McDougall died. A false rumour that the show had actually offered a $1,000 bounty on McDougall had spread through the prison.</p>
<p>McDougall's family has hired an attorney and said they were considering a lawsuit over the broadcast.</p>
<p>Susan Assaid, Ursula's mother, pleaded guilty to manslaughter and testified against McDougall.</p>
<p>McDougall, convicted of second-degree murder, had been scheduled to be freed in April under an early release programme. He was originally due to leave prison in 1993 because of overcrowding, a decision stopped by public protests.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AVON PARK, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
