<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178018" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Seven militia members charged in West Virginia plot.</title>
<headline>Seven militia members charged in West Virginia plot.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven West Virginia militia members or associates were indicted on Friday on charges of plotting to plant bombs at the FBI's national fingerprint centre in the state, the U.S. Justice Department said.</p>
<p>A federal grand jury in Wheeling, West Virginia, handed up four indictments against the seven defendants, who were arrested a month ago after an FBI undercover investigation.</p>
<p>The indictment, made available by the Justice Department in Washington, essentially repeated the charges initially made when the seven were taken into custody on charges of scheming to damage and blow up the facility.</p>
<p>Among the key figures indicted in the scheme were Floyd Raymond Looker, the &quot;commanding general&quot; of the Mountaineer Militia, and James Rogers, another militia leader and fire department lieutenant in Clarksburg, West Virginia.</p>
<p>The indictment said Looker, at a militia training session in 1995, had identified the FBI facility as a primary target in the event of confrontation with the federal government.</p>
<p>It charged that Rogers agreed to provide the militia with blueprints, maps and general intelligence information about the FBI fingerprint facility, which is located in Clarksburg.</p>
<p>The indictment alleged Looker on October 11 sold the materials for $50,000 to an FBI agent. The agent was posing as a broker who would sell the information to an unnamed Middle Eastern terrorist group.</p>
<p>William Wilmoth, a U.S. attorney in West Virginia, said the federal government &quot;is committed to prosecute individuals or groups seeking to further political or social goals through violence and force. This includes conduct calculated to injure government officials or property.&quot;</p>
<p>All seven defendants remain in custody without bond.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
