<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178140" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Ailing Mobutu says will go home in &quot;several weeks&quot;.</title>
<headline>Ailing Mobutu says will go home in &quot;several weeks&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, convalescing in France after surgery, said on Saturday he will go home &quot;in several weeks&quot; to tackle a revolt in east Zaire that threatens the lives of more than a million refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;Zaire needs me,&quot; he said as one of Africa's worst humanitarian disasters unfolded in his chaotic Central African nation.</p>
<p>Mobutu, in his first newspaper interview since prostate surgery in Switzerland in August, also said he was willing to allow an international force to protect refugees from warfare.</p>
<p>He said he accepted a de facto truce by Tutsi rebels.</p>
<p>Asked when he would return home, he said: &quot;In several weeks, at the end of my convalescence&quot;.</p>
<p>French officials had been expecting Mobutu to stay only a few days after his arrival from Lausanne on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The current situation demands my return to Kinshasa. I will return and take things in hand,&quot; Mobutu told the French daily Liberation at his luxury villa at Roquebrune-Cap-Martin on the French Riviera. &quot;Today Zaire needs me.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the crisis was &quot;an aggression by Rwanda with the complicity of the Banyamulenge (Tutsi rebels), who have in some respects played the role of a fifth column.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They've taken advantage of my illness while I was abroad to stab us in the back,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He repeated he would accept a multinational force to help protect 1.2 million Hutu refugees from Rwanda and Burundi left without food and water by the Tutsi uprising. France and Spain have suggested a 5,000-strong force.</p>
<p>&quot;The Secretary General of the United Nations and (French) President (Jacques) Chirac have spoken to me about it, and I told them yes. I accept a de facto truce. From what I understood before giving my accord, that's essential,&quot; Mobutu said.</p>
<p>He said that any U.N. force would have to be in well-defined corridors. And he said the refugees &quot;must go home. It's time for them to return.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council on Saturday called on U.N. members to lay the groundwork for a multinational force for Zaire but stopped short of immediately creating a force.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Bourtos Ghali has warned there could be &quot;genocide by starvation&quot; in eastern Zaire. The Tutsis blame some of the Hutu refugees for the slaughter Tutsis and moderate Hutus in Rwanda in 1994.</p>
<p>Liberation said Mobutu looked as if he had lost weight and was obviously convalescent but his voice was strong and he walked without problems.</p>
<p>It said he drank a glass of port during the 30-minute interview and had Belgian chocolates at hand.</p>
<p>&quot;Mobutu is far from looking moribund,&quot; it commented.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66 and in power in Africa's largest country since 1965, denied a report in the French daily Le Monde that he was suffering from a cancer that had spread into his bones.</p>
<p>&quot;I deny in the most categorical manner that I'm suffering a generalised cancer. I have been operated on, I've been -- thank God -- in expert hands and I'm now starting my convalescence.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he would stand again for re-election, due in 1997. &quot;I'm in good health. Follow me until the elections!&quot;</p>
<p>Mobutu said he did not believe Zaire could implode because of uprisings and dissent but avoided saying how he would tackle the Tutsi rebellion. He refused to say if he would use his special presidential division to back up the ragged army.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not take the situation lightly. With perked up Zairean armed forces, I repeat, perked up, there will be ways of...But let's not talk of war. We can't play Napoleon here. Let's talk of peace,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
