<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178286" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain to probe Eurotunnel stock allegations.</title>
<headline>Britain to probe Eurotunnel stock allegations.</headline>
<byline>Astrid Zweynert</byline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Serious Fraud Office said Sunday it would investigate allegations of market manipulation in the stock of Eurotunnel Plc.</p>
<p>But the SFO, which investigates and prosecutes major financial crimes, said it was doing so on behalf of French police and there were no grounds for a domestic inquiry.</p>
<p>The announcement followed a report in the Sunday Times that French police wanted to raid the head offices of up to nine of Britain's leading banks and financial institutions over allegations of insider dealing in the shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The SFO has agreed to investigate on behalf of the French authorities allegations of market manipulation in Eurotunnel shares,&quot; SFO spokesman James O'Donoghue told Reuters.</p>
<p>The information gathered by the SFO will be for the French authorities. &quot;We don't have grounds to investigate allegations of market manipulation on a domestic level,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Asked why the SFO was only assisting in an overseas investigation, and not conducting a domestic one, he said, &quot;The bulk of shareholders in Eurotunnel are French, and most dealings in Eurotunnel have taken place in Paris, rather than in London, so it's not surprising that the focus should be over there.&quot;</p>
<p>The Sunday Times reported that a team of French fraud squad detectives visited the SFO last week.</p>
<p>The French concerns are centred on allegations sensitive commercial information about the financial restructuring of Eurotunnel have been leaked to speculators, it reported.</p>
<p>The deals under investigation date back to 1994, the year the Channel tunnel was opened, the paper said.</p>
<p>It said they were understood to have taken place shortly before the Anglo-French consortium made announcements about efforts to reschedule its  debt burden, now totalling 9.1 billion pounds ($15 billion).</p>
<p>The newspaper said the surveillance unit of the London Stock Exchange had already carried out an inquiry into the allegations but had not uncovered any evidence.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the exchange declined comment, saying it was its policy not to comment on confidential matters.</p>
<p>A source close to the investigation said the SFO agreed to take on the case earlier this month after representations from French police. British Home Secretary Michael Howard also approved the investigation, the source said.</p>
<p>The SFO can conduct the investigation under the Criminal Justice Act, which compels production of verbal or documentary information on request to assist overseas investigations.</p>
<p>There does not have to be evidence of fraud committed in Britain to enable the SFO to investigate.</p>
<p>French police said they were unable to comment on the report. Eurotunnel was unavailable for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
