<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178245" id="root" date="1996-11-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: SOCCER-AUSTRIA'S HERZOG SINKS 10-MAN LATVIA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-AUSTRIA'S HERZOG SINKS 10-MAN LATVIA.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-11-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>A classy 74th minute goal by Andreas Herzog gave Austria a 2-1 victory over 10-man Latvia in a World Cup qualifier on Saturday.</p>
<p>Herzog, easily the best player on view, thundered a shot past goalkeeper Olegs Karavajevs from the left side of the box to send his team top of European group four.</p>
<p>They are one point clear of Sweden, who play away to Scotland on Sunday. Austria surprised Sweden 1-0 last month in Stockholm.</p>
<p>Anton Polster put Austria ahead on Saturday with a record 35th goal for his national side, tapping home a 43rd minute corner.</p>
<p>But the home fans' joy was short-lived with Vits Rimkus making the most of a goalkeeping mistake to grab an equaliser on the stroke of halftime.</p>
<p>Seventeen minutes into the second half Latvia lost defender Igors Stepanovs after a second yellow card offence. Werder Bremen's Herzog sealed the issue just 12 minutes later.</p>
<p>&quot;We should have decided the match a lot earlier because we were the stronger side,&quot; said Herzog. &quot;But we relaxed too much after scoring the first goal.&quot;</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Austria: Michael Konsel, Goran Kartalija, Peter Schoettel, Anton Pfeffer, Markus Schopp, Peter Stoeger (Dieter Ramusch 60th), Adi Huetter (Dietmar Kuehbauer 60th), Andres Heraf, Arnold Wetl, Andreas Herzog, Anton Polster.</p>
<p>Latvia: Olegs Karavajevs, Igors Stepanovs (red card 62nd), Igors Troickis, Jurijs Sevjakovs, Imants Bleidelis, Mihails Zemlinskis, Andrejs Stolcers, Vitalijs Astafjevs, Valerijs Ivanovs, Vits Rimkus, Vladimirs Babicevs (Marians Pahars 65th).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
