<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178404" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Castro attacks U.S. in Latin American summit speech.</title>
<headline>Castro attacks U.S. in Latin American summit speech.</headline>
<byline>Roger Atwood</byline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuban President Fidel Castro attacked the United States for interfering in Latin America and &quot;dismembering our culture&quot; at the opening of a summit of 19 regional nations plus Spain and Portugal on Sunday.</p>
<p>Conflicting stances on Cuba's communist regime boiled just below the surface at the summit, which is aimed at strengthening democracy in the region.</p>
<p>Castro, the only non-elected head of state at the meeting apart from Spanish King Juan Carlos, lashed out at the United States which he said had &quot;repeatedly invaded countries in the region.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Our culture is dismembered by the mass media monopoly from the hegemonic power, while that same power ... applies criminal blockades and constantly intervenes in our states' purely internal affairs,&quot; Castro said in a speech.</p>
<p>Castro's words were by far the toughest among the string of speeches by Latin American presidents, who arrived on Friday and Saturday for the sixth Ibero-American Summit in Santiago ending on Monday in the coastal city of Vina del Mar.</p>
<p>With the summit's official theme as &quot;Governability in an Efficient and Participative Democracy,&quot; there were clear differences on the exact nature of democracy, as well as on how to approach Cuba.</p>
<p>&quot;Mexico firmly sustains that democracy cannot be transplanted from one place to another, from one society to another, nor through pressures, interference or foreign pressures,&quot; said Mexican President Ernesto Zedillo.</p>
<p>But other leaders including Chilean host and President Eduardo Frei made what appeared to be veiled references to Cuba's lack of political freedoms.</p>
<p>&quot;One cannot speak of two democracies. There is only one legitimate one, that which respects human rights and makes decisions through majority rule in sincere elections,&quot; said Frei.</p>
<p>&quot;No one defends any more a democracy ... that expects a paradise that is always to come, but never arrives.&quot;</p>
<p>Portuguese President Jorge Fernando Branco de Sampaio urged states to recognise &quot;the international trends that stimulated the political change&quot; to democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The authoritarian models have become exhausted, drained by the lack of legitimacy, the inability to respond to economic and social crises, by external isolation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the summit's final statement, to be issued on Monday after approval by the president, would make no call for democratic reforms in Cuba.</p>
<p>Spain and Argentina had supported some kind of indirect call for reform in Cuba in the statement, but Mexico and other states rebuffed them in drafting meetings, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The final statement will include, however, a clear criticism of the Helms-Burton Act signed into law by U.S. President Bill Clinton early this year which tightened the U.S. embargo on Cuba, diplomats said.</p>
<p>The Helms-Burton law, named after its U.S. congressional sponsors, punishes foreign investors for doing business with Cuba.</p>
<p>Castro earlier visited the tomb of Chile's late socialist president Salvador Allende, who died in a 1973 military coup.</p>
<p>Visiting Chile for the first time since Allende's presidency in 1971, Castro stood in front of the tomb for a few moments in a quiet, emotional homage in Santiago's General Cemetery. He said nothing.</p>
<p>Castro's visit revived memories of the Allende years and brought controversy in Chile, though street rallies called by Cuban exiles and local rightists against his regime flopped. One demonstration on Saturday drew no more than 150 people.</p>
<p>Former dictator Augusto Pinochet, who led the 1973 coup against Allende and is still army commander-in-chief, said that if he were in Santiago for the summit, he would greet Castro if ordered to by Frei, who has the title of armed forces chief.</p>
<p>Pinochet, known for his blistering anti-communism, appeared to compare Castro to the devil.</p>
<p>&quot;If tomorrow the government wants to invite Lucifer and Lucifer comes here, what am I going to do if my orders come from the government?&quot; said Pinochet in a television interview on Saturday night from the northern city of Iquique.</p>
<p>&quot;I consider (Castro's visit) just another visit, nothing more,&quot; said Pinochet. &quot;I have no interest in confronting Fidel Castro.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
