<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178460" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Brash says rapid rise in NZ dlr would harm exports.</title>
<headline>Brash says rapid rise in NZ dlr would harm exports.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reserve Bank Governor Don Brash said on Monday the continued rapid rise in the New Zealand dollar would weaken export growth.</p>
<p>&quot;While our current projections see an increase in export growth over the next few years there are risks.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular, continued rapid strengthening in the exchange rate would considerably weaken export growth,&quot; Brash said in a speech to Federated Farmers in Invercargill.  </p>
<p>&quot;In view of this risk, it is worth considering whether we have policy measures available that might help reduce the scale of the problem and reduce the risk,&quot; Brash said.</p>
<p>Brash said that while many would advocate temporary relaxation of monetary policy it would mean higher short term inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;Tolerating more inflation might result in a lower exchange rate but of course, as all our history proves, that provides only very temporary relief for exporters.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;It is not too long before the higher domestic inflation catches with the temporary benefits conferred by the lower exchange rate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In current circumstances, where the domestic economy is already pushing close to its capacity limits, that loss of the temporary benefit arising from a lower exchange rate might happen very quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;And perhaps more importantly over the longer haul allowing a temporary relaxation of the inflation target now would only increase pressure to do the same thing again in the future, something that would get built into inflation expection to the  </p>
<p>detriment of all.</p>
<p>&quot;Fiddling with medium-term policy in response to temporary problems is almost always unwise.&quot;</p>
<p>Brash talked of an ideal scenario where inflation pressures weakened and interest rates, assisted by a supportive fiscal stance, came back more into line with world interest rates.  </p>
<p>Brash said a return to price stability associated with a &quot;considerable and unhealthy crunch&quot; to the export sector would be a bad scenario.</p>
<p>&quot;To be sure, the exchange rate would eventually drop sharply -- perhaps in response to a sharp rise in the current account deficit -- but by then serious damage might have been done and the suddeness of the adjustment would itself create further damage,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
