<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17848" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia to deport four-year-old Japanese child.</title>
<headline>Indonesia to deport four-year-old Japanese child.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia plans to deport a four-year-old Japanese boy for overstaying but would allow him to re-enter the country and apply for a residential permit, an immigration official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>M.A. Gani, spokesman for the directorate-general of immigration, told Reuters that Andreya Masaru Miyakoshi, who is of Japanese and Indonesian parentage, would shortly be deported to Singapore but could re-enter Indonesia and apply for a permit to stay in the country.</p>
<p>The boy has a Japanese father, Mitsuo Miyakoshi, and an Indonesian mother, Atik Kristia Mulyani. They divorced last year and failed to have the child's Indonesian residence visa renewed. Under Indonesian law, a child's citizenship always follows that of the father.</p>
<p>&quot;He (the child) will be deported to Singapore in the near future. His father has agreed to provide round-trip tickets for the child and his mother to go Singapore, which is the nearest place (to get a visa),&quot; Gani said by telephone.</p>
<p>The boy can get a social visit visa for Indonesia and later obtain an extendable residence visa, Gani said. &quot;At the age of 18, he can apply to become an Indonesian citizen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gani said the boy was currently with his mother, who is living on the island resort of Bali.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Post newspaper reported on Tuesday that the district court in the east Java town of Surabaya, where Mitsuo Miyakoshi now lives, had ruled that he had to give his former wife 250,000 rupiah ($107) a month.</p>
<p>Atik said last week she had never received any money. ($1=2,341 rupiah)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
