<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178663" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl threatened to resign over German budget row.</title>
<headline>Kohl threatened to resign over German budget row.</headline>
<byline>Erik Kirschbaum</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl threatened to resign and bring down his 14-year-old government last week because of a row over the 1997 budget, German government sources said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Confirming reports in news weeklies Focus and Der Spiegel, the sources said Kohl had warned squabbling ministers on Tuesday that unless they came to an agreement on tax policies he would tell President Roman Herzog the government had failed.</p>
<p>&quot;If this...keeps on like this, then I will go to Roman Herzog,&quot; Kohl told the cabinet, according to Focus.</p>
<p>The sources described Kohl's remarks as &quot;more an outburst of anger than an ultimatum.&quot;</p>
<p>Such threats have been extremely rare during Kohl's 14-year-long rule. Focus said it was the first time Kohl had used such a warning since a similar row over taxes in 1988.</p>
<p>It underscored how badly relations have deteriorated between Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) and the junior coalition partners, the Free Democrats (FDP).</p>
<p>It also turned the tables on the small FDP, which had itself threatened to leave the coalition recently over the dispute.</p>
<p>Although the FDP have been kingmakers in Bonn for the last three decades -- leaving a coalition with the Social Democrats in 1982 to join the CDU -- the FDP would almost certainly end up on opposition benches in the event of a government collapse now.</p>
<p>&quot;No one in Europe would have understood it if the government had collapsed over this,&quot; said Wolfgang Gerhardt, FDP chairman.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Theo Waigel, who has faced blistering criticism from the FDP, said on Sunday he was confident the coalition would survive because the &quot;FDP hasn't shown any desire of ending up on the opposition benches.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl, who recently became Germany's longest-serving chancellor this century, issued stern warnings to the FDP last week to stop criticising Waigel.</p>
<p>But in public he insisted the internal cabinet talks on the budget had been going smoothly, even telling journalists after the critical Tuesday meeting: &quot;Everything is fine.&quot;</p>
<p>The shaky FDP, which has gambled its political survival on its image as a tax-cutting party, staunchly refuses to let Waigel increase taxes to fill the budget gaps.</p>
<p>They have rebelled against Waigel's budget policies after they were forced to accept a delay in cutting the loathed solidarity tax surcharge last month.</p>
<p>But Kohl's CDU and their Bavarian sister party the CSU have been in no mood to let the FDP score points with voters as the tax-cutting party at their expense.</p>
<p>The solidarity tax was to have been cut by one point from 7.5 percent in 1997 and another point in 1998. The FDP gave up on the one point cut in 1997 but wants a law guaranteeing the tax will be cut by two points to 5.5 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>The CDU has refused and the two sides squabbled for weeks while Kohl was traveling around the Far East.</p>
<p>In a face-saving gesture, the two sides agreed to put off a decision on solidarity tax until next month.</p>
<p>But Gerhardt told FDP leaders at a rally in Duesseldorf on Sunday: &quot;We will have a good result for the party at Christmas.&quot;</p>
<p>Juergen Moellemann, the leader of the FDP in Germany's most populous state of North Rhine-Westphalia, said the party would keep up its &quot;healthy pressure&quot; on Waigel and criticised Kohl for trying to cause divisions in the FDP.</p>
<p>&quot;Kohl is being cheeky, unfair and deliberately not telling the truth,&quot; Moellemann said. &quot;Kohl should keep his paws off the FDP. We don't need any advice from the chairman of the CDU.&quot;</p>
<p>Kohl ran into criticism on Sunday from an unlikely source -- his former finance and defence minister Gerhard Stoltenberg. In an interview with Welt am Sonntag, he said that the CDU lacked a broad leadership the public could identify with.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
