<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178673" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish FinMin denies Nordbanken sale speculation.</title>
<headline>Swedish FinMin denies Nordbanken sale speculation.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's Finance Minister Erik Asbrink on Sunday denied reports that discussions were going on over the sale of the state's holding in Nordbanken to one of Sweden's other four big banks, S-E-Banken.</p>
<p>The denial followed newspaper reports in Sweden on Friday and Saturday quoting Bertil Aberg, managing director of the smaller Swedish bank Stadshypotek, as saying the state was thinking of selling its stake to S-E-Banken.</p>
<p>&quot;There are not any discussions nor negotiations with S-E-Banken or any other bank on the state's shares in Nordbanken,&quot; Asbrink told Swedish newspaper Dagens Nyheter on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bertil Aberg is off line and should refrain from this type of loose speculation, instead concentrating on taking care of Stadshypotek.&quot;</p>
<p>The state currently holds 58 percent of Nordbanken shares worth a market value of about 18.5 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Asbrink said the action plan was for the state to first sell its holding in Stadshypotek.</p>
<p>&quot;Before this can be done we must have support of the parliament (the question will be dealt with in a few weeks time),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The future of the state's share in Nordbanken will be discussed shortly after that happens.&quot;</p>
<p>Aberg told Dagens Nyheter that he had been voicing his personal views when he was commenting at a business lunch in Stockholm on Friday.</p>
<p>Stadshypotek's chairman Gosta Rennell declined to say anything about Aberg's comments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
