<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178643" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/CPI, PPI, the rally continues?.</title>
<headline>WALL ST WEEK AHEAD/CPI, PPI, the rally continues?.</headline>
<byline>Andrej Gustincic</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>As the economic and political scenes bask in the glow of Bill Clinton's second electoral honeymoon, the Dow Jones Industrials could reach the 6400 level between this week and year-end.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a short honeymoon period without much sniping at the president. It would look pretty tacky for the Republicans if they said their first order of business was to get Clinton, especially before he is sworn in,&quot; said Joseph Barthel, chief investment officer at Fahnestock &amp; Co.  </p>
<p>A busy calendar of economic data arrives this week against the backdrop of a highly valued stock market and a long bond yield down at the 6.50 percent level.</p>
<p>&quot;This week is packed full of important releases that will determine whether the long bond yield goes below 6.50 percent,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany Corp. &quot;If it does, it will set off another strong move on the stock market.&quot;  </p>
<p>Data include the October producer and consumer price indices, due on Wednesday and Thursday, respectively, October retail sales on Thursday and October industrial production and capacity utilization due on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers are likely to send a mixed signal. The core consumer inflation number could come in stronger than expected. Industrial production and capacity utilization may not be as weak as expected.&quot;</p>
<p>Still, many analysts expect the market to put in a solid performance for the remainder of the year with nothing short of a major event stopping its upward momentum.  </p>
<p>&quot;My suspicion is that the rally phase is not complete and that there will be an extension of the current rally before a more significant time-out,&quot; said Barthel.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a short pause, but not before we get closer to the 6400 level on the Dow. If the data this week are favorable, you will see stocks rally to 6400 by the end of the year,&quot; Barthel said. &quot;If not, we may take a pause and rally later. The trend is up.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that the various legal woes still ahead for President Clinton are not likely to kick in and start making trouble until after he is sworn in next January.  </p>
<p>Not all forecasts are rosy, however. Michael Metz, chief investment strategist at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said that 1997 could see deterioration in earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we are facing something of a margin squeeze,&quot; Metz said. &quot;The bull story has been the expansion of profit margins, which resulted in earnings growth, which was much more rapid than the overall economy over the next few years.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that the factors behind expanding profit margins such as downsizing, improving productivity and a weak dollar, were no longer in place.  </p>
<p>&quot;Any industry competing with imported products will be hit by a stronger dollar,&quot; he said. &quot;The market will suffer from anemic money flows, disappointments in profit margins and a little fear of inflation because of rising commodity prices and wage costs at a time when valuations are absolutely obscenely high,&quot; Metz said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
