<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178619" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Bahrain to allow Red Cross visit to prisoners.</title>
<headline>Bahrain to allow Red Cross visit to prisoners.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bahrain has agreed to allow the International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) to visit prisoners held in the Gulf Arab state in connection with political unrest, government officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement was reached last month...It is something all civilised countries usually do,&quot; one official told Reuters by telephone. &quot;We welcome the Red Cross to come any time.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We always welcome any cooperation with human rights organisations like the Red Cross. We don't mind if it is in the benefit of the people,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The official did not say when the ICRC would visit Bahrain or how many prisoners its representatives would meet.</p>
<p>Another official said the ICRC visit would include prisoners held in connection with unrest in the Gulf's financial and banking centre.</p>
<p>Members of Bahrain's majority Shi'ite Moslems have waged a two-year violent campaign to demand political and economic reforms -- including job opportunities and the restoration of an elected parliament dissolved by the government in 1975.</p>
<p>Diplomats estimate the government has rounded up 1,000 political prisoners. Opposition circles give a far higher figure of around 2,500 in jail but a government official told Reuters they numbered just a few hundred.</p>
<p>The detainees include some of the leaders of the unrest, in which at least 27 people have died.</p>
<p>The Sunni-led government says the protesters are out to destabilise Bahrain and blames Iran for much of the unrest, a charge denied by Tehran.</p>
<p>A widespread security crackdown by the government has disheartened the Shi'ite opposition, according to members of the Shi'ite community and Western diplomats.</p>
<p>It has also succeeded in containing the unrest, they said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
