<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178732" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Dostum jets bomb Kabul airport amid artillery duel.</title>
<headline>Dostum jets bomb Kabul airport amid artillery duel.</headline>
<byline>Sayed Salahuddin</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jets from northern General Abdul Rashid Dostum's air force bombed Kabul airport on Sunday as Taleban forces exchanged artillery fire with their opponents north of the city, witnesses said.</p>
<p>They said the planes made two bombing runs, dropping four high-explosive bombs within the perimeter of the airport, on the northeast edge of Kabul. Taleban soldiers guarding the airport gate said the raids had caused no casualties or damage.</p>
<p>Shortly after the bombing, a Taleban jet fighter scrambled in pursuit of the attackers, but it was not immediately clear if it had caught Dostum's planes as they headed back to base.</p>
<p>The boom of artillery could be heard in parts of the Afghan capital as Taleban forces fought those of ousted government commander Ahmad Shah Masood in the Shamali Valley to the north.</p>
<p>The artillery exchanges followed fighting on Saturday night in which the Taleban-controlled Voice of Shariat radio said the Taleban had captured several positions from Masood's troops.</p>
<p>The Pakistan-based Afghan Islamic Press agency said the Taleban had thrown back an offensive by Masood's forces on Saturday, killing at least nine of his soldiers.</p>
<p>Dostum, now allied to Masood against the radical Islamic Taleban militia, has launched several air raids on Kabul in the past few weeks, most of them targeting the airport.</p>
<p>His alliance planes bombed Kabul twice on Saturday, aiming for the airport but causing little damage and no casualties.</p>
<p>Three children were killed and seven people wounded in an air raid 11 days ago. A girl was wounded and two houses destroyed in the city centre in a raid on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The fundamentalist Taleban seized Kabul on September 27 and now control nearly 75 percent of the country. They are fighting opposition forces 20 to 25 km (15 to 19 miles) north of Kabul and also in the northwestern province of Badghis.</p>
<p>The fighting near Kabul has stagnated though the two sides exchange rocket and artillery fire daily. Anti-Taleban forces have failed to take strategic hills that protect the city.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
