<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178729" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India cyclone victims grieve over Diwali festival.</title>
<headline>India cyclone victims grieve over Diwali festival.</headline>
<byline>Dev Varam</byline>
<dateline>EAST GODAVARI, India 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most Indians on Sunday celebrated Diwali, the joyous Hindu festival of lights, but for villagers in the cyclone-devastated Godavari delta it remained a time of darkness and mourning.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda flew over the flooded paddy fields and coconut groves during the day to assess damage to the region, known as the rice bowl of southeastern Andhra Pradesh state.</p>
<p>Officials fear more than 1,000 people died in the winds, rain and tidal waves that lashed the Andhra Pradesh coastline for five hours on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>&quot;How can we think of celebrating Diwali,&quot; Purasala Siva, a 27-year old man in the tiny village of Annatavaram, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Four people died in Annatavaram, but the number of dead in many of the 800 battered villages in the area was still unknown.</p>
<p>Makeshift camps were sheltering thousands of families whose houses were destroyed or badly damaged by the storm.</p>
<p>Relief workers were struggling to reach outlying fishing villages, marooned by flood waters, while aerial surveys showed some communities were completely submerged.</p>
<p>A sea search was on for about 1,000 fishermen who sailed just before the cyclone struck. Officials said the bodies of 50 men had washed ashore at the mouth of the Godavari, but hopes remained that others reached land before the tidal wave struck.</p>
<p>About 10,000 people died when a cyclone hit the area in 1977. In 1990, 967 people died and in June this year, a cyclone killed 120.</p>
<p>Communications remained difficult and power lines were down, leaving cities like Rajahmundry, with a population of 200,000, and the port of Kakinada in darkness at night.</p>
<p>In Kakinada, some normalcy had returned as the clean-up operations continued. Loading and unloading of 12 ships that had been moved to safe anchorage had begun, and roads were clear.</p>
<p>The farming and fishing villages were expected to take longer to recover.</p>
<p>Preliminary reports estimate the damage to paddy fields and coconut groves at about 20 billion rupees ($559 million).</p>
<p>&quot;Forty-two villages in Amalapuram division are inaccessible. So far 350 bodies have been recovered,&quot; an official in East Godavari district told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said Amalapuram, which has about 100,000 residents, had been hit by three cyclones in the past month.</p>
<p>&quot;The region depends mainly on coconut, paddy and cattle. They suffered losses on all three counts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Annatavaram, villagers had held funeral rites for their dead, and burnt and buried fifty buffaloes and cows.</p>
<p>&quot;It is only God who saved us,&quot; Siva said as he recounted the terrifying night. &quot;We were all in our own homes when the winds started shaking the walls. But before the storm reached full strength we ran into a nearby building and locked ourselves in. The building really shook as wind and rain assaulted it.</p>
<p>&quot;We lost hope and all of us started chanting bhajans (Hindu prayers), but luckily the wind died out. We were all saved.&quot;</p>
<p>But while the rest of India reverberated on Sunday to the sound of firecrackers and the celebrations of Diwali, the people of the Godavari delta were observing the 13-day Hindu mourning period.</p>
<p>On the final day, if possible, the bereaved families will immerse the ashes in the Godavari river.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EAST GODAVARI, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
