<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178824" id="root" date="1996-11-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-HOLYFIELD STOPS TYSON TO WIN WBA TITLE IN SHOCK UPSET.</title>
<headline>BOXING-HOLYFIELD STOPS TYSON TO WIN WBA TITLE IN SHOCK UPSET.</headline>
<byline>John Phillips</byline>
<dateline>LAS VEGAS 1996-11-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>No one ever doubted Evander Holyfield's strong faith in God, but it was his belief in his right hand that so many people scoffed at.</p>
<p>After beating Mike Tyson Saturday in one of the biggest upsets in boxing history, Holyfield has certainly convinced everyone that his right hand is as solid as his faith in God.</p>
<p>And he may have made some people, as he said he hoped he could do, believe in more than his right hand with his victory over one of the most feared fighters ever to win the World Boxing Association's heavyweight championship.</p>
<p>Holyfield was supposed to be a washed up fighter who was in danger of permanently injuring himself.</p>
<p>But the 34-year-old former two-time world heavyweight champion became only the second three-time champion, after Muhammad Ali, by raining nine unaswered punches to the head of a helpless Tyson to bring in referee Mitch Halpern to stop the fight at 37 seconds of the 11th round.</p>
<p>Over and over again Holyfield landed right hands to Tyson's head that seemed to confuse him, throwing his timing, and ultimately his senses, way off.</p>
<p>Holyfield charged right at Tyson from the opening bell, swarming over the 30-year-old Tyson to trade punches toe-to- toe.</p>
<p>It was a message Tyson, now 45-2, had been sent in only one other fight -- against James &quot;Buster&quot; Douglas in Tokyo in 1990 when Douglas staged the biggest upset in boxing history by knocking out the seemingly invincible Tyson in the 10th round.</p>
<p>It was the strategy that Holyfield insisted he would follow for months, and so many people considered to be suicide against the power-punching Tyson.</p>
<p>Tyson seemed surprised by the tactic, and in the early going in the first round was missing with his hard overhand rights, while Holyfield countered with combinations.</p>
<p>Holyfield kept landing his punches first, and toward the end of the second round the 30-year-old Tyson was slowing down and holding, reminiscent of hapless Briton Frank Bruno, whom Tyson easily defeated last March.</p>
<p>Just before the bell ended the second round, Holyfield landed a right-left-right combination that staggered Tyson up against the ropes in a precursor of what was to happen often in the fight and at the end.</p>
<p>Holyfield caught Tyson with a short left to the head in the sixth round, sending Tyson down onto the seat of his black trunks to a tremendous roar from the capacity crowd of 16,325, which at the end of the round was chanting and stomping feet for Holyfield.</p>
<p>Tyson got up quickly and the two traded hard punches. But at the end of the round it was Holyfield again with a left- right-left-right combination that sent Tyson into the ropes.</p>
<p>Holyfield was warned for holding in the seventh round and later in the round Tyson complained to the referee that Holyfield had worked his glove into a cut that had opened up under Tyson's left eye. Then Tyson ran into Holyfield's head with his own, and again Tyson looked imploringly at the ref.</p>
<p>Tyson appeared ready to be knocked out in the 10th round after Holyfield stopped a Tyson charge with a very hard jab and soon afterward landed a hard right-left-right-right that pounded him into the ropes.</p>
<p>When the bell rang for the 11th round, Tyson seemed dazed, standing in front of his corner with his hands down at his sides.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't know where I was at,&quot; Tyson said after the fight. &quot;I didn't know anything.&quot;</p>
<p>Tyson added, &quot;I don't even remember going down. I don't even remember the fight.&quot;</p>
<p>Holyfield, now 33-3, waded in again and Tyson's legs appeared wobbly. Holyfield landed nine unanswered punches to Tyson's head, finishing the execution with a huge overhand right that knocked Tyson into the ropes senseless.</p>
<p>&quot;God is good. God is good,&quot; said Holyfield, wearing a cap inscribed, &quot;Jesus is Lord.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I give all my glory to God. With God on your side you can do the things you choose to do,&quot; said Holyfield.</p>
<p>Holyfield, who was paid $11 million, said he would go home to Atlanta and rest, and think about whether he wants to fight again.</p>
<p>For Tyson, who received $30 million for the bout, fighting again is a no-brainer: &quot;I get so much money to fight, man, how can I not continue to fight.&quot;</p>
<p>From an acrimonious and very distasteful promotion with Tyson promising to hurt Holyfield and Tyson's camp constantly belittling the challenger, the post-fight news conference was all sweetness and light.</p>
<p>Everyone praised everyone.</p>
<p>Holyfield thanked Tyson for the opportunity to fight him and, of course, thanked God many times more.</p>
<p>Tyson was particularly gracious, saying to Holyfield, &quot;Man, I just want to shake your hand. It's been so long. I just want to touch you.</p>
<p>&quot;He fought a tremendous fight. Thank you. I have the greatest respect for you. By the will of God, I hope we can do it again.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAS VEGAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
