<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178882" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian shares ease as investors mull election.</title>
<headline>Slovenian shares ease as investors mull election.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian shares inched lower on Monday as investors stuck to the sidelines after Sunday's general election, waiting for hints on the composition of the country's next government.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will stagnate until the next coalition is known,&quot; said Karmen Cerar, a trader at brokerage Poteza.</p>
<p>The ruling Liberal Democrats of Prime Minister Janez Drnovsek won 27.1 percent of the vote, but analysts expect he will have to form a coalition to remain in power. His most likely coalition partner, the rightist People's Party, came second with 19.6 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If Drnovsek remains in power, shares are expected to go up immediately, but if the rightist parties take over, shares may well go down,&quot; Cerar added.</p>
<p>The SBI index fell 0.46 percent or 5.61 points to 1,218.9. Overall 10 shares fell, eight rose and one was unchanged, while five were untraded. Turnover fell to 205.4 million tolars from 392.7 million.</p>
<p>Bank SKB, which last week said it planned a global depository receipts issue in the near future, was the day's most heavily traded share, falling 0.24 percent to 45,000 tolars on volume of 2,711 shares.</p>
<p>The bank's shareholders are expected to vote on the proposal later this week. SKB's stock has gained more than 50 percent since the end of September as investors anticipated plans for a foreign listing.</p>
<p>Food producer Kolinska led the day's decliners, shedding 3.7 percent to close at 2,020 tolars on volume of 3,784 shares.</p>
<p>Brokerage Finmedia was the biggest gainer, firming 4.45 percent to 16,190 tolars on volume of just 30 shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
