<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="178914" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Munich Re- no plans to cut Allianz stake. [Corrected 14:45 gmt]</title>
<headline>Munich Re- no plans to cut Allianz stake. [Corrected 14:45 gmt]</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>German reinsurance group Muenchener Rueckversicherungs AG, or Munich Re, said on Monday it had no plans to reduce its 25 percent stake in fellow insurance giant Allianz AG Holding.</p>
<p>Management board chairman Hans-Juergen Schinzler told a news conference that the sale of the Allianz stake would yield around 15 billion (corrects from &quot;50 billion&quot;) marks ($9.97 billion),  but that this would be cut by more than half by tax charges.</p>
<p>&quot;Then we would have to invest that money somewhere that would give us a better yield than Allianz, and we haven't found that,&quot; Schinzler said.</p>
<p>Moreover, Munich Re had no wish to make any changes in its long-standing relationship with Allianz, of which shareholdings formed a crucial part, he added.</p>
<p>However Schinzler said Munich Re and Allianz might get involved in a share swap in the U.S. as a result of Munich Re's decision this year to take over American Re.</p>
<p>Allianz owns 40 percent of Munich American Reinsurance Company, which is to be merged with American Re and may decide not to transfer this holding into a significantly smaller stake in American Re, Schinzler said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing has been decided but if Allianz does decide to do this (pull out), then it is possible that we might swap that stake for shares in Allianz North America,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.504 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
