<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179038" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vanguard Air eliminating some routes.</title>
<headline>Vanguard Air eliminating some routes.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-11-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vanguard Airlines said Friday it is discontinuing several of its airline routes to eliminate unprofitable and non-strategic flying.</p>
<p>It will discontinue service to four destinations: Cincinnati, effective November 17, Seattle on November 19, Salt Lake City on December 2 and Phoenix on December 20.  </p>
<p>Vanguard said it will continue to offer service between Wichita and Denver, Wichita and Chicago and Wichita and Kansas City.</p>
<p>Chairman John Tague said, &quot;These difficult decisions are critical to our plan to strengthen the company. The routes Vanguard is eliminating today simply didn't produce acceptable results and did not hold sufficient promise for the future.&quot;</p>
<p>He added in a statement, &quot;Today's announcement is the first step in a process to build a more focused route strategy at Vanguard Airlines.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Within two weeks we will announce a substantial expansion that will allow us to better serve our core customers and build a sustainable niche for Vanguard,&quot; said Tague, continuing, &quot;The elimination of unprofitable flying will also allow us to accelerate routine scheduled maintenance on several aircraft, enabling Vanguard to significantly increase flying in the first quarter of 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>Customers who hold reservations on affected flights will be re-accommodated on other Vanguard flights or given refunds as appropriate.</p>
<p>Vanguard, which began service in December 1994 and is based in Kansas City, is a low-price, short- to medium-haul passenger airline providing scheduled jet service to cities in the West, Rocky Mountains and Midwest.</p>
<p>	   -- Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
