<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179192" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ethics questions dog Gingrich in new Congress.</title>
<headline>Ethics questions dog Gingrich in new Congress.</headline>
<byline>David Lawsky</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two years after Newt Gingrich led the Republican takeover of the House of Representatives, his leadership is being questioned by some fellow Republicans as he seeks to continue as speaker in the new Congress.</p>
<p>Some House members and conservative commentators are suggesting that the portly Georgia politician should step aside pending an investigation of ethics charges against him.</p>
<p>For the time being no one doubts Gingrich will win when House Republicans, returned with a reduced majority in last week's election, meet on Wednesday to choose a speaker. But that vote becomes official only when the House as a whole votes after Congress reconvenes early next year, and several members have made clear their concern about the ethics violations charges, which Gingrich has denied.</p>
<p>Rep. Chris Shays of Connecticut said he could not vote for Gingrich then unless the issue is settled. &quot;I am fully prepared to vote for him in our conference next week,&quot; Shays said in a telephone interview on Monday. &quot;But I will abstain from voting on the floor until this issue is resolved.&quot;</p>
<p>Rep. Steve Largent of Oklahoma said in a weekend television interview that he would favor veteran Republican Rep. Henry Hyde of Illinois taking over as Speaker of the House while Gingrich dealt with the charges.</p>
<p>Largent said he thought there would be some support among other House Republicans for such a move. &quot;I think that behind closed doors there would be, but publicly people would be fearful to say that on national TV,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The House Ethics Committee is investigating Democrats' charges that Gingrich's tax-exempt foundation funneled money illegally to Republican candidates in the 1994 Congressional elections. In September, the committee dismissed three charges against Gingrich but at least four more remained unresolved.</p>
<p>Bill Kristol, editor of the conservative Weekly Standard, said: &quot;If the ethics thing is unresolved, he's got problems.&quot; Republicans hold only a thin margin in the newly elected 435-member House and during the election campaign most members distanced themselves from the pugnacious and increasingly unpopular Gingrich, branded an &quot;extremist&quot; by Democrats.</p>
<p>Republicans, who held a 235-198 margin near the end of the last session, lost at least five seats, with others still undecided due to run-offs and late mail ballots.</p>
<p>The Ethics Committee has said it expects matters to be wrapped up before the House reconvenes and Shays said he had told Gingrich that if Democrats deliberately delayed a conclusion to the ethics investigation he would vote for him as speaker anyway in January.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there are an awful lot of Republicans who recognize that their agenda and Newt's longterm political prospects might best be served by a temporary absence of Newt as speaker,&quot; said Kate O'Beirne, who wrote a commentary in the conservative National Review putting forward Hyde's name.</p>
<p>Some advocates of Gingrich taking a temporary back seat argue that this would make it easier for Republicans to pursue allegations against President Bill Clinton.</p>
<p>A special prosecutor and several congressional committees have been examining allegations of financial impropriety and influence peddling involving Clinton generally referred to as Whitewater, the name of a failed land deal he and his wife engaged in when he was governor of Arkansas.</p>
<p>If Gingrich did step aside for Hyde, O'Beirne wrote, &quot;Democrats would no longer be able to shield the president by making Newt Gingrich the issue. Indeed, Mr. Clinton would be doubly on the defensive.&quot;</p>
<p>A spokesman for Hyde said on Monday, &quot;While Mr. Hyde is flattered by the suggestion he run for speaker he has no plans to do so.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
