<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179252" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. West spot power lackluster due to holiday.</title>
<headline>U.S. West spot power lackluster due to holiday.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The spot power market in the western U.S. saw little activity Monday with next-day business completed Friday ahead of the Veterans Day holiday, market sources said.</p>
<p>In addition, mild weather conditions in much of the region may keep prices flat for the rest of the week, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all scheduled up through Tuesday,&quot; said one Northwest utility trader.</p>
<p>He added that &quot;things are looking pretty steady&quot; in the Northwest, which continues to see warmer-than-normal temperatures and normal precipitation.</p>
<p>Another trader said, &quot;I don't expect a whole lot this week. Prices are already above normal and I don't see them rising, but I don't expect them to fall off either.&quot;</p>
<p>Market sources said the Bonneville Power Administration (BPA) is likely to post prices near those it announced Friday for Sunday through Tuesday schedulings.</p>
<p>BPA had offered firm power during heavy load hours in the Northwest at $24.25 per megawatt hour (MWh) and $25.00 at the California-Oregon border (COB). Firm power during light load hours was offered at $19.00.</p>
<p>Cash Palo Verde for December was last quoted $21.40-22.20, compared with $21.50-22.25 on Friday. COB for December was quoted $23.20-23.75, up from $22.75-23.25.</p>
<p>--Los Angeles bureau + 1 213 955 6761</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
