<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="17933" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia posts second consecutive trade surplus.</title>
<headline>Malaysia posts second consecutive trade surplus.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia has posted a trade surplus for a second consecutive month, with a gain of 574.1 million ringgit ($230.56 million) in June, figures released on Tuesday by the Statistics Department showed.</p>
<p>The June figure followed a 238.5 million ringgit surplus in May and was a vast improvement from the 2.1 billion ringgit deficit in June 1995.</p>
<p>June's trade improvements were led by exports of 16.3 billion ringgit against imports of 15.7 billion ringgit.</p>
<p>Malaysian officials have predicted a strengthening of its balance of payments this year amid prudent budgetary and tight monetary policies, the encouragement of savings and improvements in the export sector.</p>
<p>The central bank, Bank Negara Malaysia, has forecast the current account deficit will fall to 17 billion ringgit in 1996 from 17.82 billion ringgit last year. Malaysia's deficits have caused concern among international investors.</p>
<p>Malaysia posted a 9.2 billion ringgit trade deficit for all of 1995.</p>
<p>In the first six months of 1996, Malaysia registered a trade deficit of 798.4 million ringgit, a sharp improvement over the 5.6 billion ringgit deficit in the same period in 1995.  </p>
<p>Faster growth in exports of 12.6 percent over the six months versus a 6.6 percent increase in imports accounted for the improvement, the department said.</p>
<p>Export values in the first half of 1996 climbed to 96.5 billion ringgit from 85.7 billion ringgit in the 1995 comparable period.</p>
<p>Electronic valves and tubes and other related parts remained Malaysia's largest export earner in the first half of the year, netting receipts of 18.2 billion, or 18.8 percent of total export earnings.</p>
<p>Palm oil was the second biggest revenue earner, accounting for 4.5 percent of total exports, or 4.4 billion ringgit.</p>
<p>The major destinations for Malaysia's exports in the first half of 1996 were Singapore at 19.3 billion ringgit, the United States at 18.5 billion ringgit and Japan at 13.2 billion ringgit. The three countries accounted for 52.9 percent of total exports in the first six months of the year.</p>
<p>Imports totalling 97.3 billion ringgit in the first half of 1996 compared with 91.3 billion in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Machinery and transport equipment accounted for the biggest proportion of the imports, at 59 billion ringgit or 60.7 percent of the spending.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
