<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179524" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-NEW SOUTH WALES WIN DESPITE RECORD PARTNERSHIP.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-NEW SOUTH WALES WIN DESPITE RECORD PARTNERSHIP.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A record breaking sixth wicket partnership of 290 between Matthew Elliott and Darren Berry was not enough to save Victoria from a 58-run defeat to New South Wales in their Sheffield Shield match on Monday.</p>
<p>Opener Elliott and wicketkeeper Berry took Victoria within sight of an improbable victory only to see the last five wickets fall for 19 runs in the final session of play.</p>
<p>Victoria had been set a winning target of 457 and collapsed badly on Sunday to be 89 for five when Berry joined Elliott atthe crease.</p>
<p>Elliott played an imperious innings, reaching 187 before the tall left-hander was bowled by leg-spinner Stuart MacGill, who took three second innings wickets in his first match for New South Wales.</p>
<p>Berry made 148, his highest score for Victoria, before falling in the next over to wrist-spinner David Freedman. Freedman cleaned up the Victorian tail to finish with four for 92 from 27 overs.</p>
<p>Elliott and Berry had taken Victoria to 349 for five at tea,raising hopes of a first win for new captain Shane Warne. Their partnership was a record for the sixth wicket in first-class matches between the two states.</p>
<p>Elliott led the Australian domestic averages last season with 1,233 runs at an average of 63.50, including five centuries from 11 first-class matches.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
