<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179508" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GEORGIA: SOCCER-BROOKING NEEDS STITCHES AFTER MEDIA MATCH BRAWL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BROOKING NEEDS STITCHES AFTER MEDIA MATCH BRAWL.</headline>
<dateline>TBILISI 1996-11-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former England international Trevor Brooking, now a television commentator, needed four stitches after being involved in a fight with a Georgian journalist during a media match ahead of England's World Cup qualifier on Saturday.</p>
<p>The former West Ham player, who now works for the British Broadcasting Corportation (BBC) was on the receiving end of several crude tackles by Georgian players.</p>
<p>&quot;One of them clouted me from behind,&quot; Brooking said. &quot;There was what you might call a verbal exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;Then, apparently, while this was going on, another fellow ran 20 yards. I just saw him at the last minute from the side. He thumped me with a real right hook and he must have caught me with a ring or something because he cut me wide open just above the right eye.</p>
<p>&quot;I just walked away. I only ever had three bookings in my career and I have never been involved in anything like this. But I knew if I stayed around, it could have got nasty.&quot;</p>
<p>Brooking, who was substituted by English Football Association (F.A.) chief executive Graham Kelly, was treated by the England team doctor. The match referee sent off two Georgians and the game ended 1-1.</p>
<p>Brooking was expected to be fit to take his place in the BBC commentary box at the European group two qualifer between Georgia and England later on Saturday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GRGIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TBILISI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GEORGIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
