<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179542" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-BRAVES' JOHN SMOLTZ WINS N.L. CY YOUNG AWARD.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-BRAVES' JOHN SMOLTZ WINS N.L. CY YOUNG AWARD.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Right-hander John Smoltz became the third Cy Young Award winner on the Atlanta Braves' staff on Monday, joining teammates Greg Maddux and Tom Glavine as the only pitchers to win the National League award in the past six years.</p>
<p>Smoltz won his first Cy Young Award with 26 first-place votes and 136 points from the Baseball Writers Association of America voters, two from each N.L. city.</p>
<p>The Florida Marlins' Kevin Brown received the other two first-place votes and 26 votes for second place, finishing with 88 points. The Marlins' right-hander and Smoltz were the only pitchers named on all 28 ballots.</p>
<p>Smoltz stopped the string of four Cy Young Awards captured by Maddux, who was tied for fifth with three points. Glavine won in 1991 and Maddux captured the 1992 award with the Chicago Cubs before winning three in a row with the Braves, the last two by unanimous votes.</p>
<p>Smoltz led the major leagues with 24 wins and 276 strikeouts and had a 2.94 earned run average. His career-high win total was six more than any other N.L. pitcher and he led the league in winning percentage and innings pitched (253 2/3).</p>
<p>The 29-year-old has long been said to have the &quot;best stuff&quot; of any N.L. pitcher but began his eighth full major-league season never having won more than 15 games. He was third in the rotation behind Maddux and Glavine.</p>
<p>Smoltz lost his first start, but by June 19 he was 14-1.</p>
<p>His wins were the most by a Braves pitcher since the franchise moved to Atlanta in 1966.</p>
<p>Although it didn't factor into the voting, he continued his dominance in the post-season, going 4-1 with an 0.95 ERA in five starts as the defending champion Braves got to the World Series before falling in six games to the New York Yankees.</p>
<p>The breakthrough year could not have come at a better time for Smoltz, who already has filed for free agency and could command up to $8 million per season.</p>
<p>Brown, signed as a free agent by the Marlins, went 17-11 with a league-leading 1.89 ERA. He was the victim of a lack of support as Florida was shut out in five of his starts and managed just one run in two others.</p>
<p>St. Louis Cardinals right-hander Andy Benes won 18 games and was third with nine points, four more than right-hander Hideo Nomo of the Los Angeles Dodgers. Nomo, the 1995 Rookie of the Year, won 16 games and pitched a remarkable no-hitter at hitter-friendly Coors Field in Denver.</p>
<p>Maddux was 15-11 with a 2.72 ERA and finished tied with closers Trevor Hoffman of San Diego and Todd Worrell of Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Left-hander Denny Neagle, who was dealt to Atlanta by Pittsburgh in August and won 16 games, received two points.</p>
<p>Left-handers Jeff Fassero of Montreal and Al Leiter of Florida and Houston right-hander Shane Reynolds received one point. Fassero was traded to the Seattle Mariners last week. Leiter pitched the first no-hitter in the Marlins' history.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
