<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179672" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK, Norway to meet next week on Frigg gas dispute.</title>
<headline>UK, Norway to meet next week on Frigg gas dispute.</headline>
<byline>Sebastian Alison</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norwegian and U.K. energy officials are to meet on November 19 and 20 to try to revive negotiations on a long-running dispute over gas pipelines from the North Sea Frigg field, a DTI spokesman said on Monday.</p>
<p>Until now, Britain has blocked Norway from using a pipeline from the field to bring gas from other fields to sell into the U.K.</p>
<p>But industry sources said recent changes in the energy portfolios of both countries may give new impetus to talks held on and off for several years between Norwegian Energy and Industry minister Jens Stoltenberg and U.K. Energy Minister Tim Eggar.</p>
<p>Stoltenberg became finance minister in a recent cabinet reshuffle and was replaced by Grete Faremo, while Eggar was replaced in July by Lord Fraser of Carmyllie, the Department of Trade and Industry's spokesman in the House Of Lords.</p>
<p>The Frigg field straddles the boundary between the U.K. and Norwegian sectors of the North Sea, and there are two parallel gas pipelines both running to the Scottish gas terminal of St Fergus.</p>
<p>Under an inter-governmental treaty signed in 1976, Norway is only allowed to deliver gas produced from Frigg or from one of its satellites down the Norwegian pipeline, and this treaty remains in force until Frigg is fully depleted.</p>
<p>But Frigg output has been falling since 1992, so the Norwegian pipeline is greatly underused. Norway wants to renegotiate the treaty to use the spare capacity to deliver gas from other fields, but Britain has so far said no.</p>
<p>The DTI's spokesman told Reuters: &quot;Our understanding is that the treaty expires with the conclusion of production from Frigg.&quot;</p>
<p>He declined to speculate on what the two sides would discuss in their meeting next week.</p>
<p>Julian Kennedy, gas analyst with consultants Wood Mackenzie, said one reason for reopening negotiations was that Britain fears it may go short of gas at times of peak demand.</p>
<p>&quot;If exports through the Interconnector (a 20 billion cubic metres a year link from Bacton in Norfolk to Zeebrugge in Belgium, due for completion in late 1998) are greater than expected, it could remove enough gas to create a shortage and Britain would need extra sources of supply.&quot;</p>
<p>He said renegotiating the Frigg treaty could be a quick and easy way to secure extra gas at times of peak demand.</p>
<p>But an industry source who did not want to be named said Britain's current willingness to talk may be related to its own ambitions to compete in continental Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;Norway feels that the Interconnector is a potential lever. They can say to Britain, 'You want competition elsewhere in Europe, and we'll try to make it difficult for you if you don't allow us competition in Britain.'&quot;</p>
<p>Kennedy agreed that competition is a central issue. &quot;If Norway had joined the European Union, it would be inevitable that there would be contract renegotiation.</p>
<p>&quot;The main market for Norwegian gas is Europe, so when the Interconnector starts to flow, U.K. gas will compete with Norwegian gas&quot;. He added that Norway could be persuading Britain to accept that, as a quid pro quo for the market opening up on one side, Britain should open it up on the other side.</p>
<p>&quot;Ten years ago it might have been possible to renegotiate the treaty for peak periods only,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But the ability to police this in future will be limited now that all participants will have third party access.&quot;</p>
<p>There are other potential ways to deliver Norwegian gas to Britain. There is already a gas pipeline from Statfjord, another field which straddles Britain and Norway, which ties into the FLAGS pipeline system, also landing at St Fergus, and Norway could step up deliveries from its own part of Statfjord if necessary.</p>
<p>It also may be possible to build a spur from the existing Frigg pipeline to the Oseberg field, about 80 km away.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom, +44 171 542 6412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
