<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179691" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Election could baulk N.Irish peace search - sources.</title>
<headline>Election could baulk N.Irish peace search - sources.</headline>
<byline>Robert Woodward</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Progress must be made by the end of 1996 in the search for peace in Northern Ireland before the approaching election in Britain puts the province's problems on ice for several months, political sources in the province say.</p>
<p>Conflicting claims about a possible IRA ceasefire and the future of former U.S. senator George Mitchell, chairman of multi-party talks on Northern Ireland's future, have added to an atmosphere of gloomy uncertainty in the province, they added.</p>
<p>But the sources, speaking on the basis of anonymity, said they believed a breakthrough in the Belfast talks on the key issue of scrapping arms was possible in the next two weeks.</p>
<p>And they said they expected an intervention soon by British Prime Minister John Major aimed at easing the impasse that threatens to plunge Northern Ireland back into virtual war.</p>
<p>The date of the election is not yet set but it must held by May 22 and campaigning is likely to start early in 1997.</p>
<p>Major is unlikely to launch a major initiative in the election run-up in case he is accused of making political capital out of the province's problems and because his attention will be on retaining power, the sources said.</p>
<p>If Labour wins power after 18 years in opposition, as opinion polls strongly suggest, Northern Ireland is unlikely to be top of their list of priorities in the early months, the sources said. Labour has fully supported Major's peace efforts.</p>
<p>Progress towards peace could also be delayed by the departure of Mitchell, who is rumoured to be in line for a top post in U.S. President Bill Clinton's second-term cabinet.</p>
<p>Major laid the ground for ceasefires by the Irish Republican Army and rival Protestant guerrillas in mid-1994 with a joint Anglo-Irish peace plan in December 1993.</p>
<p>But republicans accuse the British government of bad faith that caused the IRA to break their ceasefire in February with a series of bombs on the British mainland. The IRA, which wants a united Ireland, also bombed Britain's main army base in Northern Ireland in October, killing one soldier.</p>
<p>Senior republican sources, speaking in the province late last week, said there was no peace process any more and they had no information to substantiate rumours that the IRA planned to stop its armed struggle.</p>
<p>They were speaking before a weekend newspaper report that the IRA planned a month-long Christmas truce. Major has said the IRA must restore its ceasefire before its political wing, Sinn Fein, can join the multi-party talks.</p>
<p>Major's possible intervention may concern the terms of any ceasefire declaration that might allow Sinn Fein quick admission to peace talks, political sources said.</p>
<p>They said the chances of a ceasefire may be improved by a possible &quot;deal&quot; at the multi-party talks in Belfast over arms held by guerrillas, the so-called decommissioning issue.</p>
<p>The British and Irish governments say decommissioning should be examined by a committee in parallel with the negotiations. But pro-British Unionists are demanding the IRA hand in guns before Sinn Fein can enter substantive talks after any truce.</p>
<p>A deal could involve flexibility on the timing of any future arms handover, thus allowing the talks to move on to substantive political issues and finally make progress, the sources said.</p>
<p>Republicans want Major to signal that in the event of an IRA ceasefire Sinn Fein would get an immediate seat at talks that would have their goal of an all-Ireland state on the agenda.</p>
<p>With Major having a majority of just one in parliament -- a position likely to worsen following by-elections in early 1997 -- the support of the 13 Unionist MPs is vital to the Conservative government's survival.</p>
<p>Any perceived weakening of the government's position over the terms of any IRA ceasefire would anger Protestants deeply and could cause a parliamentary &quot;revolt&quot; by Unionists.</p>
<p>But the sources said some Unionists believed their representatives should try to accelerate negotiations rather than hobble them. This would allow them to lock away agreement on some key issues before the arrival of Sinn Fein at the talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
