<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179697" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE white sugar steady, gears up for Dec expiry.</title>
<headline>LIFFE white sugar steady, gears up for Dec expiry.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>White sugar futures bounced slightly higher on Monday, following a steady New York raws performance, but activity was routine as traders started preparing for the December expiry at the end of the week.</p>
<p>Volume was dominated by trades in the two nearby contracts as spot positions were rolled forward and trade houses posted &quot;against actuals' trades against December.</p>
<p>The nearby spread was also a focus of interest.</p>
<p>&quot;Dec/Mar spreads are reasonably active prior to the expiry on Friday so people are tidying their book up,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Some white premium business was also reported but although the London market was firmer following the open of the New York market, the steady raws performance was not enough to spur more bullish sentiment, traders said.</p>
<p>At 1628 GMT December was 60 cents higher at $307.40 and March up $1.10 at $306.80.Volume totalled 2,407 lots.</p>
<p>Open interest in the spot December contract has fallen sharply since the start of the month, while that in March has soared and gently climbed in May.</p>
<p>The Paris market is closed on Monday due to a public holiday on account of Armistice Day.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Smith, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8064</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
