<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179755" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mandela says willing to commit troops to Zaire.</title>
<headline>Mandela says willing to commit troops to Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Nelson Mandela said on Monday he was prepared to send South African troops to troubled Central Africa as part of an international force to bring peace to eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;In principle, I am prepared to contribute troops,&quot; Mandela said in a joint television interview with South Africa's state broadcaster and CNN, but added that he had not decided how big a unit to commit.  </p>
<p>Mandela says willing to commit troops to Zaire</p>
<p>Mandela, who had resisted military intervention in any African crises, said he had given the commitment to former Tanzanian president Julius Nyerere, who visted South Africa at the weekend to discuss the ongoing crisis in Central Africa's Great Lakes region.</p>
<p>Mandela said he would send a delegation to the region to gather information that would allow him to decide how big a unit to commit.</p>
<p>Nyerere briefed Mandela on a summit of East and Central African leaders in Kenya last Tuesday where the crisis in Zaire was discussed.</p>
<p>One of the key decisions was that a neutral force be created to provide safe corridors for aid to more than a million refugees from ethnic violence in Rwanda and Burundi. It would be intended to help Rwandan refugees now in eastern Zaire to return to their home country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
