<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179772" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.Africa rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African bonds tumbled in late trade, spooked by Monday's surge in money market rates and fears of an interest rate hike, dealers said.</p>
<p>But the rand ended steady, supported by a large exporter order in the afternoon and earlier Reserve Bank action, as earlier political fears about the Mandela succession subsided.</p>
<p>The sharp fall in bonds left the yield on the benchmark R150 up 35 basis points on the day at 16.18 percent at the local 1400 GMT close.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a bit surprised at the fall, but we've just got a complete sell-off here -- it's mainly because of the money market,&quot; one bond dealer said.</p>
<p>Three-month NCD rates jumped to between 16.90 to 17.10 from 16.75 to 16.90 percent on Friday, while the 90-day BA rate was at 16.25 to 16.45 from 16.10 to 16.25 percent as the daily shortage remained above nine billion rand.</p>
<p>Economists said Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals was likely to let banks sweat it out for the time being, but dealers said a hike in Bank rate, currently 16.00 percent, and prime, currently 19.25, appeared inevitable sooner or later.</p>
<p>&quot;It will have to happen at some stage,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Bond traders said institutions had failed to come into the bond market above 16.00 percent as expected, causing the market to break through various stops.</p>
<p>The rand, however, ended well off its day's worst of 4.7180 bid hit in pre-market dealings, buoyed by one large exporter order in the afternoon.</p>
<p>The market also took some comfort from the African National Congress' firm denial of press reports that President Nelson Mandela had disavowed his deputy Thabo Mbeki as successor.</p>
<p>Friday's anxieties about an inquiry into the Reserve Bank's role in the forward cover market also subsided as the Bank explained that the move did not affect short-term cover of up to 12 months, but only long-term deals.</p>
<p>There had been fears that since the Bank had protected the rand to a large extent via intervention in the forward market, the inquiry might result in curbs on its future capacity to intervene in this way. But an official said intervention was not relevant in the long-term area.</p>
<p>Dealers added investors in all South African markets remained disappointed by Stals' remarks on Friday that scrapping controls would be a gradual process that was likely to take four or five years.</p>
<p>His comments dashed any lingering hopes of a &quot;big bang&quot;  -- or one-off -- end to rand restrictions.</p>
<p>The rand was last trading at 4.7020/70 unchanged from Friday. Against the crosses, the rand was at 7.7350/7494 against sterling from 7.7390/7520 and at 0.3195/99 marks against 0.3206/3210.</p>
<p>The Bond Exchange said foreigners sold a net 4.66 million rand worth of South African bonds on Friday after buying a net 180.39 million on Thursday. Nominal cumulative volumes stood at 2.92 billion rand on Friday from 48.25 billion rand on Thursday, a settlement day.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank indicated the daily shortage above nine billion again on Saturday at 9.191 billion rand from 9.189 billion on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Ben Hirschler, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
