<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179747" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Some aid reaches eastern Zairean town of Goma.</title>
<headline>Some aid reaches eastern Zairean town of Goma.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign aid workers took some aid into the eastern Zairean city of Goma on Monday, but more than a million refugees remained beyond reach and were reported to be dying in their thousands.</p>
<p>Vehicles and workers from the U.N. Children's Fund, Concern, Save the Children, Medecins sans Frontieres (MSF-Doctors without Frontiers), CARE and the British agency Merlin drove into Goma from Rwanda.</p>
<p>&quot;They got thoroughly searched (by rebel forces) at the border and they only took in emergency food supplies for patients in hospitals and enough drugs to treat them,&quot; said MSF spokeswoman Samantha Bolton.</p>
<p>&quot;Full-scale operations will only go ahead after they have made their security assessments, in a day or two,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>The aid vehicles and about 70 foreign journalists were taken to a sports stadium, from where distribution to hospitals short of supplies for many wounded from fighting would take place.</p>
<p>The U.N. World Food Programme said a U.N. assessment team followed by two eight-tonne trucks carrying maize meal and pulses also crossed to Goma by road and headed for the stadium.</p>
<p>&quot;We are simply demanding access with good security to the camps so we can carry out an assessment mission impartially,&quot; said Marc Gastelleu-Etchegorry of MSF before reaching Goma.</p>
<p>But most camps for more than a million refugees in eastern Zaire have been emptied by a three-week-old rebellion and by former Rwandan Hutu troops and militiamen herding them deeper into Zaire, on the opposite side of the frontline to Goma.</p>
<p>Rebel forces who seized Goma a week ago have been unable to push west because of firing, including shells slamming into the city, from exiled Rwandan Hutu forces around Mugunga, which was the largest refugee camp in the world with 400,000 inmates.</p>
<p>The Rwandan government, which supports the Tutsi revolt in Zaire, agreed on Sunday to allow food and medicine into Goma.</p>
<p>Standing on the Rwandan side of the border, Rwandan Health Minister Joseph Kalemera, who mediated the entry of aid, said Kigali had given permission for the aid vehicles to cross but most aid should be delivered into Rwanda and not into Zaire.</p>
<p>Citing security concerns, rebels ordered 30 journalists out of Goma on Sunday but they were allowed to return on Monday.</p>
<p>In Addis Ababa, Ethiopian Prime Minister Meles Zenawi hit out at the United Nations for calling on African nations to pay for their participation in any peace force for eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.N. Security Council decision that the cost of the operation (of any Zaire force) should be borne by the participating countries...would naturally make it difficult for African countries to take part in this effort,&quot; Meles said.</p>
<p>He was addressing the opening session of the Conflict Prevention Committee of the Organisation of African Unity (OAU), itself criticised for failing to come up with any meaningful response to the humanitarian disaster in Central Africa.</p>
<p>Last week, a summit of regional leaders in Nairobi called for a &quot;neutral force&quot; to be set up and funded by the Security Council, effectively handing the problem back to New York.</p>
<p>In a new setback for supporters of military intervention, British Defence minister Michael Portillo said Britain was unlikely to send troops to Zaire to help relief operations.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is to be a military operation it must be carefully planned, it must have clear objectives and there must be an exit strategy,&quot; Portillo told the British Broadcasting Corporation.</p>
<p>&quot;In other words we must know how forces would withdraw whether those forces are African or non-African,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The United States denied on Monday it was blocking creation of the force but said it had seen no coherent plan for one.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said Washington recognised a force was needed, as demanded by the U.N. Security Council, which has urged member states to prepare.</p>
<p>Burns said U.S. planners still sought answers. &quot;You can't go rushing in with troops without knowing what the mission is, the scope of responsibility and who's going to pay for it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He refused to say whether American troops would take part.</p>
<p>The U.N. Security Council gave Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali, a strong supporter of a multinational force, until November 20 to report on its framework and operations.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali said on Sunday thousands were dying each hour.</p>
<p>&quot;Two years ago the international community was confronted by a genocide of the Tutsis by arms. Today we are confronted by a genocide of the Hutus by famine,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Rwandan refugees are Hutus who fled in 1994 and have resisted pressure to return home, saying they feared reprisals for the genocide of up to one million Tutsis and Hutu moderates.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
