<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="179804" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: No change on S.African succession - spokesmen.</title>
<headline>No change on S.African succession - spokesmen.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spokesmen for President Nelson Mandela and his ruling African National Congress (ANC) on Monday poured cold water on media reports that Mandela had disavowed Thabo Mbeki as his successor.  </p>
<p>&quot;What he said is nothing new. He repeated what he has been saying all along, namely that he does not have the right to annoint a successor,&quot; Mandela's spokesman Joel Netshitenzhe told Reuters.</p>
<p>The ANC said that, if anything, Mandela had reiterated his &quot;vote of confidence&quot; in Mbeki.</p>
<p>ANC spokesman Ronnie Mamoepa said: &quot;If anything, President Mandela reiterated his vote of confidence in deputy president Thabo Mbeki in particular.&quot;</p>
<p>In a wide-ranging interview with The New York Times, The Times and Sowetan, Mandela stressed that it was not up to him alone to choose the country's next leader.</p>
<p>He said it was a &quot;misconception&quot; that he had tapped Mbeki for the job, since that was the prerogative of the national executive committee of his party.</p>
<p>&quot;The president has no right to chose a successor and I never did so. When the president of the ANC steps down, the National Executive Committee or congress will elect a successor,&quot; Mandela said.</p>
<p>&quot;If (they) elect Mbeki, I will support that because he is a competent man who deserves that position.&quot;</p>
<p>Mandela, 78, again repeated his determination to step down as president in 1999 when general elections are due and make way for younger blood.</p>
<p>Last July he gave a clear signal he believed Mbeki was the best person to fill his shoes, saying in a television interview: &quot;He is very talented and very popular and if the organisation elected him I would feel they had made the right decision.&quot;</p>
<p>Johannesburg's daily The Star newspaper on Monday carried a banner headline saying &quot;Mandela drops Mbeki bombshell&quot;, reporting that a weekend meeting of the ANC's executive was &quot;stunned&quot; when Mandela told them what he had said in his newspaper interview.</p>
<p>Mbeki, the most prominent South African leader on the international stage after Mandela, is currently on a mission to Europe to drum up trade and investment -- his latest sortie in what is widely assumed to be a process for grooming for the presidency.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
