<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="180144" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ job ads trend rises slightly in October - ANZ.</title>
<headline>NZ job ads trend rises slightly in October - ANZ.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The trend number of job ads rose 0.5 percent in October following a 2.3 percent fall in September, ANZ Bank said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In annual terms, the trend number of job ads continued to fall, with October's number 5.4 percent below October 1995.</p>
<p>ANZ said job advertisements had risen slightly in Auckland during October. Wellington and Christchurch continued to experience a decline in monthly job ad figures, although of a smaller magnitude than previous months.</p>
<p>In annual terms the number of job advertisements continued to decline in all of the main centres.  </p>
<p>The monthly trend in job ads in Auckland rose 1.1 percent in October, following a 0.3 percent rise in August. In annual terms, the trend number of job ads was three percent lower than a year ago.</p>
<p>Job ads in Wellington fell 0.5 percent on the previous month, and 17.9 percent on a year ago.</p>
<p>Christchurch also recorded a decline in October, falling 1.8 percent, with the trend number of job ads 8.2 percent below October 1995.  </p>
<p>ANZ said the slowdown in job ads growth over the past year was consistent with the September quarter Household Labour Force Survey last week, which showed a continued decrease in the annual rate of employment growth, to 3.7 percent from 3.9 percent in the year to June.</p>
<p>&quot;This slowdown in employment growth is expected to prevail over the remainder of 1996,&quot; ANZ said.</p>
<p>--Wellington Newsroom (64 4) 4734746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
