<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="180217" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Iran slams U.N. human rights report as &quot;baseless&quot;.</title>
<headline>Iran slams U.N. human rights report as &quot;baseless&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran on Monday rejected a United Nations report criticising the state of human rights in the Islamic republic, saying such documents would hurt the esteem of the world body.</p>
<p>Iranian Foreign Ministry spokesman Mahmoud Mohammadi, quoted by Tehran radio, called the report &quot;baseless and affected by ulterior political motives&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran believes that using human rights as a political tool...is detrimental to the esteem of the United Nations,&quot; Mohammadi said.</p>
<p>He was referring to a report by U.N. Human Rights Commission envoy Maurice Copithorne that said the rights situation in Iran &quot;may well have deteriorated&quot; this year.</p>
<p>Iran's Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati, quoted by the radio, said on Sunday: &quot;Unfortunately, human rights has become a tool of the world powers in international bodies.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of countries which do not believe in the principles of democracy and human rights, but there is no talk of them (by human rights bodies) because of their close ties with the West,&quot; Velayati added.</p>
<p>Copithorne, a Canadian, cited a reported rise in executions, the closing of newspapers and disruptions of meetings while government forces allegedly refused to intervene.</p>
<p>The U.N. envoy also referred to reports of harassment or intimidation of relatives in Iran of political dissidents living abroad, breaches of human rights and discrimination against Iran's Baha'i religious minority.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
