<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="180567" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-UK's Labour rejects wider EU majority vote.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-UK's Labour rejects wider EU majority vote.</headline>
<byline>Michael Peacock</byline>
<dateline>HARROGATE, England 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's opposition Labour Party said on Monday that it would veto any extension of majority voting in the European Union's social chapter on workers' rights.</p>
<p>Finance spokesman Gordon Brown said Labour was committed to signing up to the social chapter, but would adopt &quot;a balanced and moderate approach&quot; to its implementation.</p>
<p>&quot;It is absolutely right to sign the social chapter,&quot; Brown said in an interview on BBC radio, several hours before he was due to address the Confederation of British Industry (CBI) annual conference in Harrogate.</p>
<p>&quot;It is wrong for people to say that a Labour government would remove the requirement of unanimity for changes in social security or for changes in co-determination in the boardroom.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I'm going to make it absolutely clear today, as has always been clear to the Labour Party, we will veto any attempt to do that,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>Both Labour and the Conservative government have sent party heavyweights to the annual conference of the employers' group in a bid to win support ahead of a general election due by May 1997. Europe is likely to be a major issue in the campaign.</p>
<p>Government ministers criticised Brown's comments, saying the social chapter would destroy jobs in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;I regard the Social Chapter as a catalogue of job-destroying measures,&quot; defence minister Michael Portillo told the CBI conference. The European Union takes most of its important decisions by a consensus of all 15 members.</p>
<p>Any move towards extending areas decided by majority-voting is seen by Britain's vociferous &quot;Euro-sceptics&quot; as an unacceptable erosion of national sovereignty.</p>
<p>British business leaders are divided about closer European integration, with some welcoming the possible benefits of a single European currency while others are worried that the social chapter would increase their costs.</p>
<p>A survey of nearly 1,700 companies released by the CBI and the British Chambers of Commerce on the eve of the CBI conference showed 73 percent thought Britain should retain the opt-out it negotiated from the social chapter.</p>
<p>Andrew Buxton, chairman of Barclays Bank and the CBI's economic affairs committee, said the opt-out should be retained although at present the chapter contained nothing too harmful.</p>
<p>Once in, Britain could become loaded with further legislation voted through by a majority of EU members against its will. &quot;At the moment, the social chapter does not bring in too many problems, it's more what the future holds,&quot; Buxton told reporters. &quot;Majority voting opens the door to quite a lot.&quot;</p>
<p>The other workplace issue to loom large on the first day of the conference was a national minimum wage.</p>
<p>Labour plans to introduce one at a so far unspecified level, but deputy prime minister Michael Heseltine said the Conservatives were opposed.</p>
<p>&quot;We will resist a minimum wage which would accelerate wage push, which would destroy jobs,&quot; Heseltine said.</p>
<p>Buxton said the CBI disagreed with the idea of a minimum wage in principle but if one were introduced, the level would be more crucial than the principle.</p>
<p>&quot;There is absolutely no doubt that at 4.26 pounds, jobs would be lost. But at 3.50, fewer jobs would go,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Trade unions have called for a minimum wage to be set at 4.26 pounds ($7.02) an hour. ($1=.6069 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARROGATE, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
