<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="180547" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Bangladesh clears way for trial of Mujib killers.</title>
<headline>Bangladesh clears way for trial of Mujib killers.</headline>
<byline>Anis Ahmed</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladesh's government has moved to quash a law preventing the trial of the killers of Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's father, independence leader Sheikh Mujibur Rahman, who died in a military coup 21 years ago.</p>
<p>State Minister for Law, Justice and Parliamentary Affairs, Abdul Matin Khasru, tabled a bill in parliament on Sunday night describing the September 1975 law as &quot;repugnant to fundamental rights and rule of law as enshrined in the constitution&quot;.</p>
<p>Mujib, who led Bangladesh to independence from Pakistan in 1971, was gunned down with most of his family on August 15, 1975, in the country's first military coup.</p>
<p>Mujib's successors protected themselves from prosecution with an indemnity ordinance.</p>
<p>&quot;Repeal of the indemnity law will remove all barriers to the trial of the killers of Mujib,&quot; one Awami League leader said on Monday.</p>
<p>Six army officers, suspected masterminds of the 1975 coup, were assigned to diplomatic jobs abroad. They went into hiding after Hasina's Awami League toppled Begum Khaleda Zia's Bangladesh Nationalist Party (BNP) in general elections in June this year.</p>
<p>Bangladeshi police have arrested three former army officers as well as Mujib's information minister Taheruddin Thakur as part of the murder investigation.</p>
<p>Khasru tabled the repeal bill while the BNP began an indefinite boycott of parliament.</p>
<p>The BNP said on Sunday &quot;it was not possible for us to be in the House or participate in its proceedings because they are meaningless&quot;.</p>
<p>A committee will now scrutinise the repeal bill, which is expected to be adopted in a week. The Awami League has a majority in the 330-member legislature.</p>
<p>The 1975 coup, which brought Khaleda's husband then army Major Ziaur Rahman to power, was followed by 15 years of direct or indirect military rule.</p>
<p>Zia was killed in a 1981 army mutiny, 10 years before Khaleda became Bangladesh's first woman prime minister in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
