<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="180701" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: UAE banks to apply Internat'l Accounting Standards.</title>
<headline>UAE banks to apply Internat'l Accounting Standards.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Central Bank governor said on Monday banks in the United Arab Emirates (UAE) will soon have to base their accounts on International Accounting Standards.</p>
<p>Sultan bin Nasser al-Suweidi told an Islamic banking forum this was needed to give investors a chance to chose where to put surplus funds by comparing risk levels based on the same disclosure requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;Disclosure based on similar foundations is paramount to comparing these risk levels,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, all UAE financial institutions will, in the near future, be required to base their accounting systems and disclosure statements on the basis of International Accounting Standards,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier, Suweidi told a news conference on the sidelines of the meeting the central bank had received several licensing requests from a host of banks, including conventional and Islamic institutions. But he said no decision had been made yet on granting licences.</p>
<p>Suweidi said he did not believe there was congestion in the UAE banking sector that could prompt the country to take action, such as preventing new banks from opening.</p>
<p>&quot;In a free system, there is nothing called a banking glut,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There are 27 foreign banks, 15 representative offices and 19 local banks operating in the UAE.</p>
<p>Some analysts have suggested that the UAE, like its Gulf Arab neighbours, is over-banked and some banks should merge.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
