<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18073" id="root" date="1996-08-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Denmark - Aug 27.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights of stories in the Danish press on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>BERLINGSKE TIDENDE</p>
<p>--- The social democrats are to propose a new drug policy which will give drug addicts free access to treatment and suggests distribution of heroin to the most dependent addicts.</p>
<p>--- The Danish army still has not found the reason for the plane crash on the Faroe Islands in the North Atlantic on August 3 which killed the Danish defence chief. However the investigation team cannot exclude that the crash was caused by bad weather.</p>
<p>POLITIKEN</p>
<p>--- Experts from the brewing sector now warn that the new cooperation between Danish brewery group Carlsberg and the British brewery Bass could cause conflicts because of the difference in management within the two groups.</p>
<p>JYLLANDS-POSTEN</p>
<p>--- One of the world's largest department stores the Japanese Itochu has invested 120 million crowns in an eel breeding project in western Denmark. It hopes to breed about 1200 tons of eel within the next three to four years.</p>
<p>BORSEN</p>
<p>--- Danish industrial group Danfoss says it will move part of its production in Germany to Slovenia and Mexico as production prices in Germany have shown to be higher than expected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
