<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="180747" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bergen, IVAX to merge in stock deal.</title>
<headline>Bergen, IVAX to merge in stock deal.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bergen Brunswig Corp., a drug wholesaler, and IVAX Corp., a generic drug maker, said Monday they were combining to form a new company in a tax-free stock deal valued at $1.65 billion.</p>
<p>The two companies said in a statement they were forming BBI Healthcare Corp., which will acquire California-based Bergen and Florida-based IVAX through an exchange of common stock.</p>
<p>The merger will combine the marketing strength of Bergen's chain of 16,000 managed care, retail chain and independent pharmacy customers with IVAX's strength in developing and manufacturing generic and proprietary pharmaceuticals.</p>
<p>The announcement said IVAX holders will receive 0.42 share of stock in the new company for each IVAX share, and Bergen Brunswig holders will receive one share of BBI for each share of Bergen.</p>
<p>Bergen's stock closed Friday at $32.75 on the New York Stock Exchange while Ivax ended at $15.75 on the American Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>IVAX holders will own about 56 percent of the new company's 91 million shares, while Bergen holders will own about 44 percent. Shares in BBI are expected to be traded on the New York Stock Exchange after the deal closes early next year.</p>
<p>The announcement said the new company was being formed at a time when some $48 billion in annual sales of branded pharmaceuticals will become available in the next five years for generic substitution.</p>
<p>Bergen Brunswig Chairman and Chief Executive Robert Martini and IVAX Chairman and CEO Phillip Frost will serve as co-chairmen of the new company, which will be based in Miami and have about 12,000 employees.</p>
<p>Bergen Brunswig President Donald R. Roden will become chief executive of BBI.</p>
<p>&quot;This combination will enhance revenues, take advantage of synergies by streamlining the supply chain, improve margins, and create shareholder value that exceeds the value of Bergen and IVAX as stand-alone businesses,&quot; Martini said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;BBI Healthcare will manage the supply chain together with our customers throughout the distribution process -- from the laboratory right to the patient,&quot; Roden said. &quot;With the full integration of manufacturing and distribution, we can cut costs in the supply chain and help make healthcare more affordable.&quot;</p>
<p>The merger also expands Bergen's business outside the United States for the first time. IVAX's Norton Healthcare subsidiary is the largest generic pharmaceutical company in Britain and serves as the hub of operations in Ireland, Poland, Germany, the Czech and Slovak Republics, and China.</p>
<p>&quot;We are combining our efficient organisation and consistent financial performance with IVAX's innovation and higher margins,&quot; Martini said. &quot;Together, we will deliver earnings growth and the broadest, most technically advanced generic drug product line in the world.&quot;</p>
<p>BBI Healthcare's board will have seven members designated by Miami-based IVAX and seven members designated by Bergen Brunswig, which is based in Orange, Calif.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
