<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="180823" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: G10 hopes for global banking guidelines.</title>
<headline>G10 hopes for global banking guidelines.</headline>
<byline>Peter Nielsen</byline>
<dateline>BASLE, Switerland 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>There is a need to establish prudential banking standards for emerging countries and guidelines should be developed that covered industrial and emerging countries, Hans Tietmeyer, chairman of the Group of 10 (G10) central bank governors' committee, said</p>
<p>Tietmeyer, who is also president of the Bundesbank, said G10 governors at their regular monthly meeting at the Bank for International Settlements (BIS) also had debated the scope of supervision as part of their discussions on how to improve cooperation between G10 and non-G10 central bank governors.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer noted the International Monetary Fund (IMF) was very interested in cooperation between the Basle Committee on Banking Supervision and representatives from emerging countries.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope in the end they will elaborate some guidelines for supervision. On one hand for the industrial countries and also for emerging countries,&quot; Tietmeyer told reporters.</p>
<p>International policy makers have been discussing global banking guidelines for several months as a way to strengthen banking systems in emerging countries following Mexico's financial crisis in late 1994.</p>
<p>IMF officials have described fragile banking systems in emerging countries as the Achilles Heel of the global economy and fear the next major international crises will begin as a crisis in a local banking system.</p>
<p>Several working groups in G10 countries are currently considering how to reform banking systems in emerging countries. The Group of Seven (G7) leading nations have also asked the G10 to report back on the progress in improving supervision in emerging countries at their summit in Denver in June 1997.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer said he had been asked by the G10 governors to inform G10 ministers about the work by the Basle Committee.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to cooperate with with G10 deputies, especially deputies from the finance ministries, and hope a dublication of work can be avoided,&quot; Tietmeyer said.</p>
<p>Tommaso Padoa-Schioppa, head of the Basle Committee, briefed G10 central bank governors on its current working programme and how cooperation with emerging countries could be developed.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer characterised the G10's discussion of the work of the Basle Committee as &quot;a real in-depth discussion&quot; and &quot;a useful debate.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We especially discussed cooperation with emerging countries because it seems to be necessary to develop prudential standards also for emerging countries,&quot; Tietmeyer said.</p>
<p>In addition to the growing cooperation between G10 and non- G10 supervisors, the central bankers also discussed the work of the Joint Forum, which comprises supervisors from the banking, insurance and securities sector.</p>
<p>&quot;This cooperation is improving and we encourage the Basle Committee to continue to do so,&quot; Tietmeyer said.</p>
<p>The Basle Committee is comprised of supervisors from the G10 and Luxembourg, but its recommendations of banking practices are widely followed.</p>
<p>The G10 actually comprises 11 countries: The United States, Japan, Germany, Canada, Britain, France, Italy, the Netherlands, Belgium, Sweden and Switzerland.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEVGCO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BASLE, Switerland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
