<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181053" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CSR sees lower second half profit.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CSR sees lower second half profit.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building products, sugar and aluminium group CSR Ltd said on Monday it expected second half earnings in the 1996/97 year (July-June) to be considerably below the 1995/96 second half result.</p>
<p>CSR said also that the final dividend for 1996/97 could be below the 12 cents per share dividend declared for the first half.  </p>
<p>CSR said trading conditions in Australia for all of CSR's building and construction products remained difficult.</p>
<p>It said continued low prices for refined sugar and the return to more normal sugar milling season, almost all of the profit from sugar in the year ending March 1997 will fall in the first half year.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result second half profits are expected to be considerably lower than the second half profits last year. The final dividend for the year to March 1997 could be lower than the 12 cents per share interim dividend,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>CSR earlier reported a 24 percent fall in net profit to A$154.7 million for the six months ended September 30, 1996.</p>
<p>It said the cut in interest rates by the Reserve Bank last week confirmed the current soft conditions of the domestic Australian market.</p>
<p>The group said in the longer term, lower interest rates should assist recovery of the housing industry.</p>
<p>At 1.25 p.m. (0225 GMT), CSR shares were three cents lower at A$4.25.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
