<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181046" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia's Alston wants formal SBS response.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia's Alston wants formal SBS response.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Communications Minister Richard Alston said on Monday he expected a detailed from the Special Broadcasting Service (SBS) on allegations that it had breached its ethnically-aimed charter.</p>
<p>&quot;They (the allegations) need to be treated seriously and I therefore expect a detailed response,&quot; Alston told reporters in Sydney.</p>
<p>SBS has been accused of moving away from its brief as a multi-cultural broadcaster to chase trendy middle-class viewers.</p>
<p>Channel Nine's Sunday television programme renewed that allegation and aired others on Sunday.</p>
<p>Although he was generally pleased with the broadcaster's performance, Alston said the allegations were substantial and needed further discussion.</p>
<p>&quot;There can always be problems at the margin, but I think in general terms it (SBS) is continuing to provide a multicultural alternative,&quot; Alston said.</p>
<p>&quot;It does cater for all Australians and I think they've been taking their responsibilities pretty seriously,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But this is the first occasion on which there's been any substantial complaints or criticism and obviously we'll be wanting to discuss them further.&quot;</p>
<p>Alston said he had asked for a formal response from SBS chairman Nicholas Shehadie.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
