<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181103" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysian NGOs see chilling effect from crackdown.</title>
<headline>Malaysian NGOs see chilling effect from crackdown.</headline>
<byline>Christina Pantin</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's crackdown on a conference about East Timor over the weekend could stifle dissent in the country, human rights activists said on Monday.</p>
<p>Police detained 112 people at the start of the Asia Pacific conference on East Timor II (APCET II) in Kuala Lumpur on Saturday after the meeting was noisily disrupted by a Malaysian youth group protesting the event.</p>
<p>Included among the detainees were seven members of the youth group, which is allied to Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad's ruling coalition, and five journalists.</p>
<p>&quot;This may make it more difficult for NGOs to work,&quot; said Stephanie Bastian, who works with an non-governmental organisation (NGO) representing plantation workers and one of the 19 local women detained for a day on Saturday by police.</p>
<p>She was speaking to Reuters while holding a vigil outside the police station for the release of her husband, who is also an activist.</p>
<p>Bastian, 38, said she and other Malaysian activists were stunned by the protest and arrests. &quot;Everyone is shocked. We've never had a mob that was so violent and abusive.&quot;</p>
<p>The youth group members were released on Saturday night. Government officials said they endorsed what the youths did and the chairman of the youth wing of Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad's political party said he ordered the disruption.</p>
<p>The APCET II organisers, in a statement on Monday, called on the government &quot;not to incite further violence by praising the actions of the rioters&quot;.</p>
<p>Sanusi Osman, one of the conference organisers, said APCET II was not an attempt to embarrass the government.</p>
<p>&quot;It is part of our responsibility as Asians to discuss this issue, otherwise we, by default, let the West dominate the discussion on human rights..,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>About 100 NGOs are estimated to be active in multi-ethnic Malaysia, which has a population of 21 million. The activists have taken on issues ranging from the proposed massive Bakun hydro-electric dam to the rights of foreign workers.</p>
<p>Government officials, including Deputy Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim, had warned the NGOs last week not to proceed with the conference over concerns it could harm ties with Indonesia.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded East Timor in 1975 and annexed the former Portuguese colony the following year in a move never recognised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Lim Guan Eng, an opposition party Member of Parliament, said: &quot;I think this will affect them (NGOs),&quot; when asked about the impact on NGOs in Malaysia.</p>
<p>&quot;The government should realise Malaysia's image is tarnished ... The climate of fear now pervading Malaysia is very real,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Conference organisers said they were within their legal rights to host the private meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;The authorities themselves recognise that the conference was organised within the constraints of Malaysian law,&quot; Debbie Stothard, a spokeswoman for the organisers said on Monday.</p>
<p>Sanusi said attendance at the conference, which had been expected to draw 150 attendees from 20 countries, was by invitation only.</p>
<p>Asked if the organisers regret pushing ahead with the conference in hindsight, Sanusi said: &quot;We believe what we are doing is right. We believe the only solution is through discussion...having conferences and seminars.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
