<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181166" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai B share index closes at record low.</title>
<headline>Shanghai B share index closes at record low.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai's B share index on Monday ended at a record closing low for the fourth successive day, with long-term investors liquidating their positions due to very weak market sentiment, brokers said.</p>
<p>The index fell 0.809 points or 1.77 percent to 44.867, on volume of 5.8 million shares worth $2.1 million. In intra-day trading on Monday, the index hit an all-time low of 44.803 points, surpassing the record of 45.585 points last Friday.</p>
<p>Brokers said that successive record lows over the past two weeks had badly hit sentiment. There was little buying on the market and light selling easily pushed down the index.  </p>
<p>&quot;Overseas investors were seen selling their shares more actively given the lack of signs of recovery in the short-term after a long bearish run,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;The index is likely to continue to move down if there is no positive news,&quot; a second broker said. &quot;We may see it go as low as 42 points this week.&quot;</p>
<p>Shanghai Rubber Belt was the biggest loser on speculative selling, plunging $0.036 or 23.37 percent to $0.118 on volume of 50,600 shares.  </p>
<p>Shanghai Shangling Electric Appliance followed on institutional selling with concerns about its results amid competition in the domestic refrigerator market, brokers said.</p>
<p>It fell $0.040 or 13.33 percent to $0.260 on volume of 153,000 shares.</p>
<p>Shanghai New Asia saw heavy liquidation selling and failed to hold to the high price levels reached recently, brokers said. It was the most heavily-traded stock, ending down $0.026 or 5.46 percent to $0.450, on volume of 1.5 million shares.</p>
<p>The Shanghai A share index rose on a technical rebound, but trading remained slow, brokers said.  </p>
<p>The A index rose 15.769 points or 1.63 percent to 983.659 points, on volume of 332.4 million shares worth 3.1 billion yuan. The SSE 30 blue-chip index gained 32.799 points or 1.37 percent to 2431.227 points.</p>
<p>Shanxi Xinghuacon Fenjiu Distillery was the star on speculative buying, jumping 0.91 yuan or 13.20 percent to 7.80 yuan on volume of 15.9 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
