<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181118" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Globalstar in China mobile telecom pact.</title>
<headline>Globalstar in China mobile telecom pact.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Globalstar Telecommunications Ltd said on Monday it had reached an accord with a unit of China's Ministry of Posts and Telecommunications to extend its planned global mobile satellite system to customers in China.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, the China Telecommunications Broadcast Satellite Corp (Chinasat) would act as sole distributor for the Globalstar services in China once it is operational in 1998.</p>
<p>Chinasat would also own and operate four planned ground stations and be responsible for interconnections with the Globalstar system.</p>
<p>Globalstar will provide the gateway links with international fiber-optic and wireline telecommunications switching centres.</p>
<p>&quot;We will provide the initial ground station in Beijing at a cost of about $10 million,&quot; Globalstar chairman Bernard Schwartz told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect another three to be deployed around the country,&quot; he said, adding that they would cost $5-6 million each.</p>
<p>Globalstar, based in San Jose, California, was founded by Loral Corp and QAULCOMM Inc. It also includes France Telecom, Hyundai, Alcatel Alsthom, and Daimler-Benz Aerospace among others.  </p>
<p>It plans to have a system of 48 low-earth-orbit satellites launched to provide service by 1998 in a project that is expected to cost $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>The system is designed to give customers in over 100 countries voice communications as well as data transmission, paging and facsimile services. Customers would use hand-held, vehicle mounted or fixed site terminals.</p>
<p>Schwartz said satellite communications were expected to play a significant role in a country of China's size. He estimated Globalstar would have 200,000 customers in China by the year 2002, representing about eight percent of the company's global market.</p>
<p>China does not allow foreign companies to operate telecommunications networks domestically but Schwartz said the structure would meet Beijing's requirements.</p>
<p>&quot;The arrangement was specifically designed for countries like China,&quot; he said,</p>
<p>Globalstar was discussing a possible equity stake by China, Schwartz said, although he added that this was not a pre-condition for China's role in the venture.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
