<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181101" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Some Asian buyers agree on 1997 Murban term price.</title>
<headline>Some Asian buyers agree on 1997 Murban term price.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Equity holders of Abu Dhabi crudes said on Monday that they have concluded negotiations with some Asian customers for 1997 term cargoes of Murban crude.</p>
<p>A dealer with one European major said it has concluded negotiations for term cargoes of Murban crude with a leading Japanese trading company.</p>
<p>Under the deal, the trading company will lift Murban crude at a premium of 25 cents above ADNOC, he said.</p>
<p>Other negotiations have also been concluded at similar levels, traders said.  </p>
<p>Other term contracts were likely to be agreed upon at levels slightly below or above that level, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders in Asia said the premium of the Gulf crude has averaged about 26 to 27 cents this year. The average of the premium on the spot market is used as a guideline in setting the premium for the next term.</p>
<p>Murban, which is richer in kerosene compared with heavy grades, has attracted brisk demand this year from Japanese refiners who need to replenish their stock of the oil product.</p>
<p>Murban's premium under the 1996 term contract was about 22 cents above ADNOC, compared with 24 cents in 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
