<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181390" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Nomura Sec to invest in new domestic airline-paper.</title>
<headline>Nomura Sec to invest in new domestic airline-paper.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nomura Securities Co Ltd and 10 others, including Hikari Tsushin, will invest in a new domestic airline company being planned by Tokyo discount ticket agency H.I.S. Co Ltd, a Japanese business daily said on Monday.</p>
<p>An H.I.S. official declined to comment on the report, but said the company plans to announce details on the new company around November 18.</p>
<p>The Nihon Keizai Shimbun financial daily reported that seven firms and four individuals would provide the new company's starting capital of 150 million yen.</p>
<p>H.I.S. will hold 60 percent in the new firm, while Nomura Securities and Hikari Tsushin, a provider of telecommunications services, are expected to own 3.3 to 6.7 percent, the paper said. The new firm is expected to boost its capital to three billion yen when it becomes certain that the firm will obtain government approval for domestic flights, the paper said.</p>
<p>H.I.S. announced last month that it plans to launch internal flights in the next few years, which would make it the first new challenger in Japan's domestic air travel market in more than four decades.</p>
<p>There was no immediate comment from Nomura Securities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
