<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181438" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: FEATURE - Woo abandons business to bid for top HK post.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Woo abandons business to bid for top HK post.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Lau</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Still in his prime, Peter Woo has turned his back on business, given up stewardship of two blue-chip companies and entered politics with a bid to lead Hong Kong as chief executive after the handover to China.</p>
<p>Woo is one of four contenders jostling to succeed Governor Chris Patten when the British hand back their colony of six million people to China at midnight on June 30 next year.</p>
<p>The chief executive will be chosen by a China-controlled 400-member electoral college by mid-December and Woo, like his rivals, is waging a campaign on the streets of Hong Kong while keeping one eye firmly fixed on Beijing.</p>
<p>Political analysts credit Woo for turning what would have been a low-key, influence-gathering effort into a presidential-style election campaign, even though the people of Hong Kong do not get to vote for their next leader.</p>
<p>The electoral college assembled by a China-appointed Preparatory Committee is responsible for the choice, but the panel is unlikely to plump for a candidate who cannot demonstrate public support.</p>
<p>At 50 Woo is the youngest of the four front-runners, and during his years living in the United States he picked up some lessons in the arcane art of spin-doctoring.</p>
<p>His media conferences have been slick affairs. He was the first to announce a platform, forcing the others to follow suit.</p>
<p>Woo graduated in physics and mathematics at the University of Cincinnati and holds an MBA from the Columbia Business School. He worked for three years at Chase Manhattan Bank in New York before returning to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Woo joined the business empire founded by his late father-in-law, Sir Yue-kong Pao, the shipping magnate who was then Hong Kong's most prominent tycoon.</p>
<p>Woo quickly rose to the top and in 1986 took over as chairman of two publicly-listed companies in the Pao group, Wheelock and Wharf.</p>
<p>But by 1993 he severed his active business ties in order to concentrate on public service as head of Hong Kong's hospital authority.</p>
<p>That raised speculation in Hong Kong that Woo was preparing himself for a top political job in Hong Kong once the British furled their flag and departed in 1997.</p>
<p>Woo, who married Bessie Pao in Hong Kong in 1973 in a glittering ceremony and is a much-photographed member of Hong Kong's high society, has his roots in the middle-class.</p>
<p>He was born in Shanghai in 1946 and arrived in Hong Kong in 1950 with his parents after the communists took over China.</p>
<p>His father, John Woo, was an architect who left home at an early age, qualified as an architect in Germany, and established a respectable practice in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;Like many others, we came from China. When we arrived, we lived in 'Little Shanghai,' in North Point. Then I grew up in Mid-levels. There were just three of us. We were a simple family,&quot; Peter Woo said in a recent interview.</p>
<p>In the eyes of Hong Kong's democracy movement, Woo is no different from the three other front-runners.</p>
<p>All are wealthy conservatives who favour turning back the clock on the democratic advancements of recent years.</p>
<p>Woo favours reinstating a system of appointed seats in district representative bodies after the handover, a retreat from the expansion of democracy made by Patten since 1992.</p>
<p>Woo says the pace of democratisation should be gradual to ensure stability.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
