<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181552" id="root" date="1996-11-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Commodity markets stay aloof from Rome food summit.</title>
<headline>Commodity markets stay aloof from Rome food summit.</headline>
<byline>Tim Hepher</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A World Food Summit will prick the world's conscience over the problem of hunger this week, but for the middlemen in global commodity markets the $2 million dollar event may be little more than a side-show.</p>
<p>World leaders meeting in Rome from November 13 to 17 have agreed in advance to try to reduce the number of people who go hungry from 840 million to half that figure by the year 2015.</p>
<p>But with grain prices tumbling after soaring to records early this year, warnings of crisis have given way to mutterings about complacency as the U.N.'s Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO) prepares for its five-day summit.</p>
<p>&quot;Frankly this summit couldn't happen at a worse time for the FAO,&quot; a senior international food official who monitors aid to developing nations told Reuters, asking not to be identified.</p>
<p>&quot;If they had met in April when we had record grain prices it would have been easier to mobilise everyone. But the market fall has been very bad timing for them,&quot; the official said on Monday.</p>
<p>While the threat of starvation in eastern Zaire provides a grim backdrop to the summit, leaders will struggle to find ways of ensuring market price swings do not cause less visible damage in the long run, officials said.</p>
<p>Grain markets panicked in April, driving wheat to nearly $300 a tonne, when stocks seemed close to running out. But bumper harvests have halved prices since then and traders say the risk of shortage is no longer a market factor.</p>
<p>Falling prices have reversed increases in Third World import bills -- pegged by the FAO at $3 billion for the poorest nations at the market's peak. But officials fear they will also encourage farmers to sow less grain, creating the potential for serious price volatility again next year if the weather is bad.</p>
<p>Commodity traders said they were sceptical the World Food Summit -- the largest gathering aimed solely at tackling hunger -- would offer much of practical interest to a market accustomed to operating with less and less political intervention.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it will be all platitudes and communiques and nothing will happen,&quot; a veteran European grain trader said.</p>
<p>He recalled that a similar World Food Conference in 1974 had vowed to wipe out hunger in 10 years. Two decades on, the number of malnourished people had hardly been dented, while the role of governments in agriculture had declined.</p>
<p>Europe and the United States, the world's food superpowers, have slashed farm spending to help clean up budget deficits and do away with unpopular grain mountains of the 1980s.</p>
<p>That means less dumping of spare grain, blamed in the past for driving Third World farmers out of business. But it leaves politicians less say in where the food goes except in emergency.</p>
<p>Future action to fight hunger is likely to put financial assistance before expensive schemes to boost production in the West and other forms of control over the commodity markets, a senior World Bank official said before the Rome summit.</p>
<p>Defending the summit's aims, organisers say they are more practical than the failed 1974 mission to abolish hunger. And despite less market pressure now, long-term food risks remain.</p>
<p>&quot;People have a tendency to be reassured very quickly. We say the situation has certainly become easier, but the future does contain significant risks,&quot; FAO assistant director general Henri Carsalade told Reuters during a visit to Paris last week.</p>
<p>He said that despite increased supplies this year, the cushion of spare grain in the world had barely recovered from a level representing 14.5 percent of one year's needs -- well below the FAO's &quot;danger&quot; threshold of 17 to 18 percent.</p>
<p>The London-based International Grains Council, a forum of some 50 nations, has warned a bad crop in just one or two key places next year will put importers at the market's mercy again.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THDWLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
