<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181725" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-ADAMS AND BROWNE SPARE WEST INDIES' BLUSHES.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-ADAMS AND BROWNE SPARE WEST INDIES' BLUSHES.</headline>
<dateline>ALICE SPRINGS, Australia 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Middle-order</p>
<p>batsman Jimmy Adams and wicketkeeper Courtney Browne spared West</p>
<p>Indies' blushes as they beat an invitational side by 48 runs in</p>
<p>a limited overs tour match on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The sixth-wicket pair rescued West Indies from a perilous</p>
<p>66 for five after 19 overs by adding 98 to help lift the final</p>
<p>score to a comparatively respectable 218 for eight in their 50</p>
<p>overs.</p>
<p>In reply, the Northern Territory Invitation XI, a side</p>
<p>containing seven Sheffield Shield players, struggled to 170 all</p>
<p>out in 42.5 overs in a carnival atmosphere for this rare visit</p>
<p>by a touring side to Australia's arid interior.</p>
<p>Adams contributed a valuable 67 while Browne scored exactly</p>
<p>50 after West Indies captain Courtney Walsh won the toss and</p>
<p>elected to bat.</p>
<p>Earlier, West Indies delighted the crowd of more than 4,000</p>
<p>by inviting local chidren to join them on the ground for their</p>
<p>pre-match practice drills.</p>
<p>Several hundred children from isolated Aboriginal</p>
<p>settlements in the Territory attended the match after travelling</p>
<p>hundreds of kilometres by bus to Alice Springs.</p>
<p>The Invitation XI side contained four players based in the</p>
<p>Northern Territory, a vast, sparsely populated area stretching</p>
<p>from the central desert to Australia's northern coast.</p>
<p>Western Australia captain and wicketkeeper Adam Gilchrist,</p>
<p>who led the Invitation XI, compiled an impressive, unbeaten 64</p>
<p>to further his claim for a test call-up.</p>
<p>Gilchrist, who scored an unbeaten century for his state</p>
<p>side when they were beaten by West Indies in a three-day match</p>
<p>last weekend, is pushing for a place in Australia's team for the</p>
<p>first test, starting in Brisbane on November 22.</p>
<p>Widely regarded as a likely successor to Ian Healy, for</p>
<p>whom he deputised when Australia's wicketkeeper was injured on</p>
<p>the recent tour of India, Gilchrist is also being touted by</p>
<p>local media as a potential specialist batsman for the current</p>
<p>test side.</p>
<p>Fast bowler Kenneth Benjamin was the pick of the West</p>
<p>Indies bowlers here, taking three for 25 in eight overs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WEIND">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALICE SPRINGS, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
