<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181721" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: CRICKET-DONALD, KLUSENER SHAPE SOUTH AFRICAN WIN.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-DONALD, KLUSENER SHAPE SOUTH AFRICAN WIN.</headline>
<dateline>COCHIN, India 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African pace bowlers Allan Donald and Lance Klusener demolished Karnataka for the second time to inflict a 244-run defeat on the Ranji Trophy champions on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Karnataka, set an improbable victory target of 362 on the third and final day, were bundled out for 117 in 205 minutes.</p>
<p>The South African victory was delayed by a two-hour interruption due to afternoon showers, but their bowlers completed the task quickly once play had resumed.</p>
<p>Opener Jagdish Arun Kumar and Fazal Khaleel offered the only resistance to the touring team's pace attack.</p>
<p>Kumar struck three boundaries in his 33 before being caught behind by Dave Richardson off captain Hansie Cronje's medium pacers.</p>
<p>Cronje was adjudged man of the match for his brilliant knock in South Africa's second innings and positive captaincy.</p>
<p>Khaleel, the top scorer in Karnataka's first innings, hit two boundaries in his second effort of 26.</p>
<p>Donald rattled the Karnataka second innings early on by dismissing opener Sujith Somasundar and Khaleel, finishing with three for 29 to give him a seven-wicket match haul.</p>
<p>Klusener's second innings haul of three for 32 took his match tally to eight wickets.</p>
<p>He helped to polish off the middle and lower orders after Donald had removed Pram Bathe Shashikanth in his second spell.</p>
<p>The last six Karnataka wickets tumbled for 32 as the touring team completed a crushing victory in the first of two three-day matches ahead of the opening test against India starting in Ahmedabad on November 20.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COCHIN, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
