<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181867" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek bourse to resume trade Wed, crisis averted.</title>
<headline>Greek bourse to resume trade Wed, crisis averted.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Weeks</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Athens bourse was expected to reopen on Wednesday for the first time in three days after angry stockbrokers accepted government proposals to overcome a fraud scandal involving at least one brokerage.</p>
<p>National Economy Minister Yannos Papandoniou intervened on Tuesday with a series of measures to placate the brokers after they accused the government of a cover-up in the brokerage fraud scandal.</p>
<p>They had refused to resume trading until action was taken to prevent a similar fraud in the future.</p>
<p>Panayotis Kondalexis, president of the 65-member Association of Athens Stock Exchange Members (SMEHA), told reporters after a brokers' meeting that Papandoniou's proposals were accepted and the decision to resume trading was unanimous.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the conditions for resuming operations at the Athens stock exchange are satisfied,&quot; he said. Brokerages may resume trading as soon as they settle their accounts at the clearing house. They should all be back trading by Thursday.</p>
<p>The sudden turnaround in the crisis came hours after the row blew up with SMEHA publicly denouncing the government's handling of the scandal and a state prosecutor laying negligence charges against unnamed stock exchange officials.</p>
<p>&quot;We didn't get everything we wanted but it is a good step towards a more open market and putting an end to bad elements who have damaged the exchange,&quot; said Constantine Panagides, general director of Axon Securities.</p>
<p>He said Papandoniou's measures signalled the beginning of a rapid, thorough and unimpeachable examination of all brokerage transactions by independent international auditors.</p>
<p>&quot;That it will not apply to clearing, as we had wanted, is unfortunate but the new measures are a big step in the right direction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bourse crisis erupted last week when a state prosecutor brought fraud charges against one brokerage, Delta Securities. Delta's assets and accounts were frozen and offices sealed.</p>
<p>Delta's three top officials were charged with fraud after the firm tried to settle a 2.6 billion drachma ($11 million) account with the bourse clearing house with bad cheques. Delta has made no comment since the charges were brought.</p>
<p>Brokers seized on the Delta scandal to demand that the settlement system be investigated, with a look at brokerages on the other side of the Delta deals, to ensure the system was not abused to manipulate prices.</p>
<p>The government, smarting from the SMEHA charge of cover-up, ordered inspectors on Tuesday to audit 10 Athens brokerages.</p>
<p>Some SMEHA members have expressed suspicion about trades in the shares in textile firms Magrizos, Mills St. George and Parnassos.</p>
<p>Magrizos, whose shares have been linked to the Delta scandal, said its dramatic share rise and fall over the past year may have been part of a &quot;trading game&quot; but denied any involvement.</p>
<p>&quot;It could be a trading game took place,&quot; David Magrizos, deputy managing director of Magrizos, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Magrizos shares rose from 201 drachmas to 1,365 over the past year before falling sharply since September and closing at 911 drachmas on November 7 when the bourse crisis struck.</p>
<p>The crisis intensified on Tuesday when the state tried to force a resumption of trading by ordering several state bank- owned brokerages to go back to work and trade.</p>
<p>With colleagues booing and shouting insults, the brokerages began executing a handful of trades just before the close. The general share index closed up 0.09 percent at 918.91 on turnover of 1.71 million drachmas.</p>
<p>The Delta scandal looks likely to continue for a while after a state prosecutor laid charges against unnamed bourse officials for negligence in connection with the Delta fraud scandal.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Anastassios Kanellopoulos, who laid fraud charges against Delta last week, laid the charges against unnamed bourse officials, empowering him to summon bourse officials to testify under oath.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
