<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181927" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Second &quot;whip&quot; named in alleged UK sleaze cover-up.</title>
<headline>Second &quot;whip&quot; named in alleged UK sleaze cover-up.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government's difficulties over allegations that it tried to stifle an investigation of sleaze claims involving a former minister deepened on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A member of parliament of the opposition Labour Party produced a letter that he said showed a deliberate attempt by the government in 1994 to influence the probe into allegations of influence-peddling against ex-trade minister Neil Hamilton.</p>
<p>The MP, Dale Campbell-Savours, distributed the letter during the second day of questioning by parliament's powerful Standards and Privileges Committee of junior minister David Willetts, a high-flyer who is a close adviser to Prime Minister John Major.</p>
<p>Stripped of the minutiae of parliament's murky working methods, the central question of whether there was a cover-up of sleaze claims has considerable potential to embarrass Major in the run-up to a general election he must call by next May.</p>
<p>The Privileges Committee is investigating whether Willetts, when he was a &quot;whip&quot; or government business manager, improperly tried to influence a panel of MPs probing Hamilton.</p>
<p>The former minister was alleged to have accepted cash and favours for asking parliamentary questions on behalf of Mohammed al Fayed, owner of London's up-market Harrods department store.</p>
<p>With no warning to fellow members of the committee, Campbell-Savours handed around a letter that he said was written by another former whip who is now a minister, Andrew Mitchell.</p>
<p>In the purported letter, Mitchell reported to the Chief Whip on a conversation he had about Hamilton with a senior parliamentary official.</p>
<p>&quot;I put it to you that there was a deliberate, very effective effort made by the Whips' Office... to try to influence this inquiry,&quot; Campbell-Savours told Willetts.</p>
<p>Willetts refused to comment on the document and insisted he had not tried to influence the committee investigating Hamilton.</p>
<p>The hearings, which are being televised, made front-page news in Britain on Tuesday after Willetts was accused by fellow Conservative Quentin Davies of deceiving the committee.</p>
<p>Davies returned to the attack on Tuesday, suggesting to Willetts that he had changed his account of a meeting in 1994 with the chairman of the Hamilton committee to protect the latter from embarrassment.</p>
<p>Willetts, whose career could be ruined if he is judged to have deliberately misled MPs, replied firmly: &quot;There is no truth in the suggestion that I lied to this committee.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
