<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181920" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Economist highlights confusion over 1997 oil price.</title>
<headline>Economist highlights confusion over 1997 oil price.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A leading oil economist on Tuesday highlighted the confusion in world markets as to where currently high prices will move next, predicting an oil price anywhere between $12 and $24 a barrel by the end of next year.</p>
<p>&quot;I am ashamed to show you this graph...The gap between the lowest and highest is $12 a barrel,&quot; said Leo Drollas, chief economist at the Centre for Global Energy Studies (CGES) in London. &quot;Next year is a very, very difficult year to predict.&quot;</p>
<p>Uncertainty over whether Iraq, currently under a U.N. oil embargo, will resume exports, and over how severe the coming winter will be, were among the key factors clouding the outlook for oil prices.</p>
<p>Exports from the chaotic former Soviet Union form a big question mark too, as do world economic growth levels and the politics of the Organisation for Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC).</p>
<p>Drollas, speaking at an oil and gas conference in London, forecast one scenario where the OPEC basket price would be $16-$18 a barrel by the end of next year. This was based on many assumptions -- that limited Iraqi exports resume in mid-1997, that OPEC moves to accommodate Iraqi on its return, that world economic growth outside the former centrally planned economies remains around 2.8 percent annually.</p>
<p>Using OPEC and CGES data, he saw a scenario without a return of Iraqi oil where the price was between $20 and $22 by the end of next year.</p>
<p>Given a mild winter this year he saw prices as low as $12, and over $24 if the winter is a cold one.</p>
<p>He said he thought it unlikely that prices would fall as low as $12, however. &quot;OPEC will get together and act...way before this incredible fall happens.&quot;</p>
<p>In all scenarios he saw prices rising to a peak in early 1997, then falling from then. &quot;There is going to be a substantial correction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Events in the former Soviet Union (FSU) add to the uncertainty.</p>
<p>&quot;The industry in the FSU is in complete chaos now...A lot of (the assumed increase in production will come) from Kazakhstan and Azerbaijan, without pipelines having been built, and consortia arguing where funding will come from and even where the pipelines will end.&quot;</p>
<p>But world oil inventories, whose currently low levels have contributed to this year's higher prices, also remain a key to the equation. Drollas thought it unlikely that oil companies would decide to run stocks below the current level of 60 days' of supply.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the desired stock level has reached a minimum,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But he said he was clearer about forecasting output from Saudi Arabia, the world's biggest oil producer and the cornerstone of OPEC which has boosted the world price of oil by restraining its production.</p>
<p>He said the increase in Saudi Arabia's revenue in 1996 that was purely due to the higher oil price was around $9 billion, almost twice the fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>The Saudi government's increased confidence due to this extra revenue made it less likely to boost production. &quot;They are sitting pretty - they are helped in not doing anything by the 17 percent gain in their revenues.&quot;</p>
<p>But Venezuela, which has consistently flouted its OPEC output quota, would continue to raise production, he said. &quot;There is more oil to come from Venezuela.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Nicholas Shaxson, London newsroom +44 171 542 8167</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OPEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
