<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="181973" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: EMS/Late mark report.</title>
<headline>EMS/Late mark report.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The mark steadied off early highs on its European cross rates here in late trading, after two Bundesbank council members helped buoy the dollar/mark rate from two-month lows set below 1.50 overnight.</p>
<p>The dollar's unexpected slide below the psychologically important 1.50-mark level in thin, late trading on Monday boosted the mark across the board in early trade today.</p>
<p>Jitters about internal European Union disagreements over the details of a post-monetary union budget stability pact, during Monday's EU finance ministers meeting, helped keep the mark firm, traders said.  </p>
<p>The verbal Bundesbank intervention came on cue, however, with a slew of council members scheduled to speak today and during the remainder of the week.</p>
<p>First up was Hans-Juergen Krupp who said it would be appropriate for the dollar to be at higher levels. Later Edgar Meister said that the current dollar exchange rate below 1.50 marks was &quot;not appropriate.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a lot of confusion in the market lately about the Bundesbank view of the world and today it looked like they were finally reading from the same scriptwriter,&quot; said Peter Wood, trader at Bank of Boston.  </p>
<p>The mark's retreat was restrained, however, as traders waited to see if Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer would reinforce the view of his two council members in a speech due for release at 1700 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank, in an ideal world would like to see it (the mark) at 1.50/60 against the dollar,&quot; said Julian Jessop, European economist at Nikko Europe. &quot;They have an informal target range of 1.50/60 marks and this is a warning signal that it does not want damage to the export recovery.&quot;</p>
<p>Tomorrow council member Franz-Christoph Zeitler takes centre stage while chief economist Otmar Issing speaks on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Bundesbank and the German government are unlikely to want the mark to rally further from here, especially against a very fragile looking dollar,&quot; said Henry Wilkes, senior trader at Bank Julius Baer.</p>
<p>Not all believe the Bundesbank will be ultimately successful in stemming mark strength, however, and see EMU jitters rallying the mark further.</p>
<p>Jessop at Nikko said ultimately an extension of mark strength from here will force the Bundesbank to ease interest rates again, possibly early next year. Others believe the mark rise is simply year-end position adjustment and temporary.  </p>
<p>An ongoing drift back to marks ahead of the year-end, largely from unwinding European convergence trades, was the backdrop to current sentiment, analysts said. Faded hopes of a U.S. interest rate rise by year-end has also weighed on the dollar as has the absence of any dollar-supportive statement from U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin since the election.</p>
<p>Meantime, traders said early demand for marks was helped by a story in today's Financial Times which said Germany threatened on Monday to stall agreement on the introduction of the single currency if its demands on the stability pact were not met.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the focus was on Italy.  </p>
<p>Analysts are watching the 1997 Italian budget's passage through parliament this week.</p>
<p>Despite public and opposition-party protests over the higher taxes, aimed at tailoring Italy's public finances in line with EMU entry criteria, the majority centre-left coalition is expected to push the budget through in the lower house by the Thursday deadline.</p>
<p>At 1610 GMT, mark/French franc was trading at 3.3820/23 compared with 3.3825/30 late Monday. Against the lira, it was at 1008.35/70 lire compared with 1010.00/85 late yesterday.</p>
<p>--Mike Dolan, London newsroom +44 171 542 6762</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
