<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18201" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH GOVT LIMITS DUTY-FREE IMPORTS OF CAR PARTS.</title>
<headline>POLISH GOVT LIMITS DUTY-FREE IMPORTS OF CAR PARTS.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish government has passed a regulation curbing the duty-free import of parts for car assembly, the industry ministry said on Wednesday, confirming earlier newspaper reports.</p>
<p>Under the regulation, adopted by the government eight days ago, but not made immediately available to the media, auto firms must secure a permit from the foreign trade ministry to import parts for assembly duty-free as of August 24.</p>
<p>&quot;The regulation obliges firms importing duty-free parts for car assembly to obtain a permit from the foreign trade ministry,&quot; industry ministry spokeswoman Beata Nawracka told Reuters.</p>
<p>Before then any company was automatically exempted from car parts duty if it assembled more than 1,000 units annually.</p>
<p>Nawracka said the new rules were meant to limit small assembly plants run by companies, which want to profit on Poland's booming car market without investing much.</p>
<p>The government's decision gave car producers little time to obtain the permit and some of them said the short notice would force them to temoporarily pay duty, which they so far did not have to do.</p>
<p>The Polish unit of Italy's Fiat Spa will probably have to pay the duty, ranging from 6.6 percent to 35 percent depanding on a part involved, if it does not get the permit soon, company's spokesman Giovanni Prati said.</p>
<p>&quot;(Without the permit) we will probably have to pay (the duty) so as not to stop production,&quot; Prati told Reuters, adding his firm has applied for the permission.</p>
<p>The regulation has blocked the launch of the assembly of Hyunai cars by a recently created joint venture between Universal SA and South Korea's Hyundai , Universal spokesman Roman Janczewski said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said trucks carrying parts for assembly of Hyundai's Accent model were being held up at the border. Univeral and Hyundai plan to assemble 15,000 units annually.</p>
<p>The foreign trade ministry said it would issue permits to eligible companies as soon as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be a matter of days,&quot; said the ministry spokesman Zbigniew Ostrowski.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
