<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182055" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Cholera breaks out among refugees in Zaire -doctor.</title>
<headline>Cholera breaks out among refugees in Zaire -doctor.</headline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cholera has broken out at a hillside settlement of about 250,000 Rwanda Hutu refugees outside the Zairean town of Bukavu and could wipe out the entire population within days, a U.N. doctor said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Walter Bonifazio, a medical doctor with the U.N.-funded agency Doctors in Catastrophic Situations, told Reuters that the refugees were trapped at the village of Mwenga, 200 kms (120 miles) west of Bukavu.  </p>
<p>&quot;Cholera broke out at Mwenga on Saturday night, but there is also dysentery and malnutrition. This, put together with the conditions of the 250,000 people, is like putting fuel on fire,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bonifazio was evacuated from Bukavu at the end of October and said his information was based on radio reports reaching his expatriate colleagues who are still working at Bukavu hospital.</p>
<p>He said he believed several people had already died, but he had no exact figures. The Hutu refugees fled camps in eastern Zaire after fighting erupted earlier this month between Tutsi rebels and the government army.</p>
<p>&quot;The human loss will be impossible to calculate, it is a bomb, and the people will die like flies unless help reaches them soon,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
