<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182004" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada wants at least 10,000 troops for Zaire.</title>
<headline>Canada wants at least 10,000 troops for Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Malina Poshtova Zang</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada said on Tuesday it has offered to lead a multinational military force to provide food, water and other aid to Rwandan Hutu refugees in Zaire but that details of the operation were still being worked out.</p>
<p>At the United Nations, Canada has told officials it needed more than 10,000 troops for the operation that it expects to last four to six months, U.N. spokeswoman Sylvana Foa said in answer to queries. After that time any mission, if needed, would be under a U.N. flag.</p>
<p>Among the countries that have expressed a willingness to join the force are France, Spain, Italy, South Africa, Ethiopia and Mali. Still key to the operation are anticipated responses from the United States and Britain before the U.N. Security Council formally approves the operation.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros Ghali said in Rome that he expected more than 12 countries to participate.</p>
<p>In Ottawa, Foreign Ministry spokeswoman Catherine Lappe told Reuters: &quot;What we can tell you at this point is that Canada has offered to take the lead in a humanitarian relief mission that would be a multinational force.</p>
<p>&quot;Beyond that, we are in a process where both the prime minister and the foreign minister are calling a number of their counterparts to get a better sense of where different countries are at in terms of the mandate, the funding issues and the troop contribution commitment.&quot;</p>
<p>More than a million Hutu refugees in central Africa face starvation and disease after being displaced by four weeks of savage fighting between the Zairian army and Tutsi-led rebels.</p>
<p>Asked about the mandate of the multinational force, Lappe said it would help maintain safe operation of local airports, shipments of relief supplies and relocation of refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;There would have to be airlift capacity and freeing the airports. There would have to be help with the distribution networks. There would have to be assistance in getting aid to the (refugee) camps. And there would have to be allowing for the voluntary repatriation of refugees,&quot; Lappe said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a very fluid situation right now; we are trying to work out the details.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada has at its disposal a special Disaster Assistance Response Team (DART) formed by the military to provide disaster relief at home and abroad. The rapid response team, comprised of about 180 people drawn mainly from the military on a rotating basis, can be deployed to provide relief for up to 40 days until long-term international relief is provided.</p>
<p>But a Defence Department spokesman said no decision had been made yet as to whether the team would be part of the Zaire operation.</p>
<p>Canada has a long history of peacekeeping at the United Nations, having participated in about 30 operations since 1949. At present, Canada has fielded 1,058 military and civilian police to eight U.N. peacekeeping missions, including those in the former Yugoslavia, in the Middle East and in Cyprus as well as Haiti where it leads the operation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
