<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182049" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African stock market closing report.</title>
<headline>S.African stock market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African shares bounced to firmer levels on Tuesday afternoon, finishing in positive territory for the first time in nine sessions.</p>
<p>Dealers said industrial stocks whipped around from early morning weaker levels after lunch when futures traders began to aggressively cover positions in the spot market.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a very volatile day, primarily driven by baskets running through the market,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of stock was absorbed this morning...and when the futures began to trade at a premium to fair value, baskets were turned around and players covered their short positions, buying shares in the spot market.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said Standard Bank's raising of its lending rate on scrip also saw players rush to cover their short positions.</p>
<p>Trading was choppy throughout the day with shares initially opening firmer, only to slide soon after on futures-driven trade before the same futures players changed direction pushing stocks higher once again.</p>
<p>Dealers said a stronger rand -- which put on 2-1/2 cents to finish at 4.6785/6835 on the dollar -- also gave shares a welcome boost.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength in the rand helped, but it was mainly futures driven,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The industrial index ended 38.3 points firmer at 7,930.2, with the near-month industrial futures contract last at 7,575/90 from 7,506 before. The all-share index put on 29.4 pts to 6,762.1 with the near-month futures contract unchanged at 6,095.</p>
<p>Foreigners remained largely aloof again on Tuesday, scared off by delays in the abolition of exchange controls, although they were seen buyers of Sasol shares which were part of an asset swap, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We did an asset swap of 3.5 million Sasol shares, which was taken up by some overseas players,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;Overall volumes were moderate but they were boosted by the asset swap.&quot;</p>
<p>Amongst other shares De Beers rose 300 cents to 137 rand, Remgro lifted 110 cents to 38.60 rand and Standard rose 200 cents to 171 rand.</p>
<p>Traders said the market, which has lost over three percent of its value since the end of October, remained edgy, weary of the sudden share gains. They said it was difficult to predict a direction for Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It very much depends on futures and what the rand does. And if the foreigners can be lured back,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Gold shares took heart from an improved bullion price, which clung to the $382 level, helping to inject better sentiment into the whole of the market. The index added 22.4 points or 1.3 percent to 1,701.6.</p>
<p>Amongst gold shares, Vaal Reefs upped 800 cents to 348 rand and Dries lifted 100 cents to 60.25 rand.</p>
<p>-- Nicole Mordant, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
