<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182178" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: Lithuanian shares rise, further gains seen.</title>
<headline>Lithuanian shares rise, further gains seen.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lithuanian shares rose on Tuesday after a two-week slide and dealers said they expected to see further gains.</p>
<p>The young bourse's main index rose to 1,443.02, a gain of 26.13 points, amid central market turnover of 341,500 litas.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks used to dominate, but investors are showing more interest in industrial companies and other enterprises,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of these companies are beginning to show good profit figures and that is stimulating interest,&quot; he said, adding that further gains were expected, at least in the short-term.</p>
<p>The Birzhiu dairy was the leading blue chip, rising to five litas from 4.81 litas in trade of over 70,000 litas.</p>
<p>Nomura is currently managing a $6 million international equity listing for the dairy.</p>
<p>There was also almost 3.8 million litas worth of bloc trades on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Klaipedos Nafta, an oil terminal partly owned by U.S.-based Lancaster Steel Co, saw over 3.1 million litas worth of its shares traded.</p>
<p>Dealers were tight-lipped about the deal but the Lithuanian daily, Lietuvos rytas, said on Monday that Lancaster Steel was preparing to reduce its stake in the terminal.</p>
<p>The terminal has plans for a new 20 million litas share capital issue in which Russian oil concerns LUKoil and Yukos are expected to buy stakes.</p>
<p>That issue will not be a public offering distributed on the bourse.</p>
<p>-- Ed Stoddard, Riga newsroom +371 721 52 40</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
