<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182105" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenia's right bids for power after close race.</title>
<headline>Slovenia's right bids for power after close race.</headline>
<byline>Marja Novak</byline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marjan Podobnik, leader of Slovenia's main right-wing party who is heading an alliance to form a new coalition, held out a conditional olive branch on Tuesday to centre-left Prime Minister Janez Drnovsek.</p>
<p>The People's Party chief said that, if his alliance failed to secure a parliamentary majority as a result of last Sunday's general election, it would be prepared to negotiate with Drnovsek's Liberal Democrats. The final official count in the prosperous former Yugoslav republic was expected on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The result is very tight and (the alliance) has agreed it could possibly cooperate with the Liberal Democrats with the aim of establishing as stable a government as possible,&quot; Podobnik, 36, a prime ministerial hopeful, told a news conference.</p>
<p>But he made clear Drnovsek would have to give up his post as prime minister and his party relinquish the top positions of state it currently holds.</p>
<p>However, Liberal Democrat general secretary Gregor Gulobic told Reuters: &quot;Under no condition will we participate in a coalition in which Drnovsek is not prime minister.&quot;</p>
<p>Unofficial results of Sunday's vote showed the so-called &quot;Slovenian Spring&quot; alliance, consisting of the People's Party, centre-right Social Democrats and Christian Democrats, winning 45 seats in the 90-seat parliament.</p>
<p>Drnovsek's Liberal Democrats won most votes with 27.04 percent and 25 parliamentary seats.</p>
<p>There was a slim chance that calculations of the complex voting system might produce an extra seat for the right-wing alliance, giving them a parliamentary majority.</p>
<p>Slovenia has made strides to establish a thriving economy. International credit agencies now rate the country on a par with the Czech Republic and ahead of Poland.</p>
<p>It has applied to join the European Union and stands a good chance of being included in NATO's first expansion eastwards.</p>
<p>Economic analysts have expressed concern over the prospect of a right-wing alliance taking power, saying privatisation could be stalled and foreign investment could slow to a trickle.</p>
<p>Political commentators said Drnovsek might still outmanoeuvre the alliance and persuade one of the rightist parties to join his Liberal Democrats in a new government.</p>
<p>Podobnik, whose party is backed by farmers hostile to EU membership, tried to allay fears that his party would push for slower integration into European institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;Fear that our government would slow Slovenia's international integration is unfounded,&quot; he said. &quot;We have a clear stand...in favour of (membership) of the EU and NATO&quot;.</p>
<p>Social Democrat leader Janez Jansa said EU membership was still on course, but a new government would have to ensure Slovenian interests were protected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
