<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182268" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia eases terms for foreign T-bill purchase.</title>
<headline>Russia eases terms for foreign T-bill purchase.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian central bank is easing one of the conditions under which Russian commercial banks handle foreign transactions on the government securities market, a senior central bank official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This change will affect only Russian banks, not non-residents,&quot; first deputy chairman Sergei Aleksashenko told Reuters. &quot;The other parameters for non-resident participation remain unchanged.&quot;</p>
<p>Since mid-August non-residents have been allowed to open special rouble &quot;S&quot; accounts at designated Russian banks, and to use funds in these accounts to buy T-bills and government bonds at auctions, and trade in the secondary market.</p>
<p>Non-residents can repatriate funds from these accounts through forward and option deals with a minimum term of three months.</p>
<p>The Russian banks must offset part of these transactions with the central bank, at special rates which allow the central bank to cap the effective guaranteed dollar yield to foreigners.</p>
<p>Aleksashenko said the central bank is cutting the proportion of such offsetting deals on spot purchases of roubles to 75 percent from 90 percent.</p>
<p>In mid-October the central bank had already cut the proportion of offsetting deals on forward sales of roubles to 75 percent from 90 percent, at the same time as it cut the guaranteed dollar yield to 16 from 19 percent.</p>
<p>The authorities have said they will gradually liberalise the non-resident scheme, but are proceeding cautiously to avoid the possibility of a sudden outflow of hot money, which could destabilise both the T-bill market and the rouble.</p>
<p>A mission from the International Monetary Fund, which left Moscow last month without recommending whether Russia should receive the next tranche of its $10 billion Extended Fund Facility, said the non-resident scheme was not in line with Russia's commitments to the IMF on currency convertibility.</p>
<p>The main concern of the mission, which returns to Moscow later this week, was Russia's poor tax revenue performance.</p>
<p>Alekashenko said non-residents had invested more than half a billion dollars through the scheme so far this month.</p>
<p>The guideline for total investment in November is $1 billion, but the authorities have emphasised that they may raise it during the month if demand is strong, as they did in October.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
