<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182228" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo Hemofarm expands its Montenegrin business.</title>
<headline>Yugo Hemofarm expands its Montenegrin business.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslav drug maker Hemofarm, expanding its operations in Montenegro, has started work on a 14.5 million dinar ($2.9 million) medical solution plant in Podgorica, Hemofarm press officer Gordana Velovan said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the second stage in our planned expansion in Montenegro,&quot; Velovan said.</p>
<p>Out of the total investment of 14.5 million dinars, Hemofarm of Vrsac in north-eastern Serbia provided 69.85 percent, Velovan said.</p>
<p>The Montenegrin mortgage bank Hipotekarna banka invested three million dinars, while the rest was provided by the Montenegrin Health Fund and the Montenegro Bank, she added.</p>
<p>According to Velovan, the company will first build a new boiler plant. Hemofarm will also remodel and equip production and storage areas.</p>
<p>Two years ago, Hemofarm launched its Montenegrin operations entering a joint venture with the Montenegrin Health Fund and the Montenegro Bank to create the first plant producing simple medical solutions in Podgorica.</p>
<p>Hemofarm appeared as a majority shareholder, owning 76 percent of the stake in the venture called Hemomont.</p>
<p>Hemomont began to produce eight varieties of eye drops, deficient in the Yugoslav market.</p>
<p>&quot;Over last two years, the plant expanded its production to reach a three percent share in the total Hemofarm turnover,&quot; Velovan said.</p>
<p>Hemofarm is the second largest Yugoslav drug producer. Its nine month turnover exceeded 460 million dinars.</p>
<p>The Hemofarm concern comprises seven domestic and seven foreign companies. Foreign operations are based in Germany, Romania, China and the Bosnian Serb Republic.</p>
<p>($1 = 4.9625 dinars)</p>
<p>-- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
