<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182287" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: Guatemala sets final peace accord for December 29.</title>
<headline>Guatemala sets final peace accord for December 29.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-11-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guatemala and leftist rebels said on Monday they would sign a peace treaty next month formally ending a 36-year war that has killed more than 100,000 people.</p>
<p>&quot;We have just set the date for putting an end to 36 years of confrontation and that will be the signing of a peace agreement on Dec. 29,&quot; President Alvaro Arzu told an Ibero-American summit meeting in Vina Del Mar, Chile, drawing loud applause from leaders of 20 other countries.</p>
<p>In Mexico City, the guerrilla leader who heads the peace negotiating team for the Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unit (URNG), Pablo Monsanto, confirmed the signing &quot;will be on that date and in Guatemala City.&quot;</p>
<p>Officials are already planning a ceremony on Dec. 29 to celebrate the culmination of five years of negotiations to end Central America's last and longest civil war in which 100,000 people have died and an estimated 40,000 disappeared.</p>
<p>Deputy Foreign Relations Minister Gabriel Aguilera Peralta told reporters the ministry was making formal invitations to heads of state from around the world to attend the ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the best gift the president can give the people for the year-end holidays,&quot; Carlos Garcia Regas, the president of Congress, told Reuters in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>Following the presidential announcement in Chile, the United Nations released a statement saying the government and the URNG concluded talks on a bilateral ceasefire on Monday. The ceasefire, to be signed in Norway in early December, is one of 11 separate accords comprising the final peace treaty.</p>
<p>The two sides will also sign an accord on constitutional and election reforms in Sweden and an agreement on the political future of the URNG in Spain, both in mid-December, according to the U.N. statement.</p>
<p>Until last week, Arzu had planned on Dec. 15 to sign the final peace treaty, but the date was moved after a recent crisis in the U.N.-brokered talks, which have dragged on since 1991.</p>
<p>The government abruptly suspended negotiations in October after rebel commander Rafael Valdizon was arrested on suspicion of kidnapping an elderly member of an influential family. Police briefly jailed him but let him go in return for freeing 86-year-old Olga Alvarado de Novella, matriarch of the family that owns Guatemala's only cement company.</p>
<p>After 12 tense days of silence from the government and a series of concessions from guerrilla leaders, talks resumed last weekend.</p>
<p>The guerrilla high command says Valdizon acted on his own and denies prior knowledge of the kidnapping. But before the talks could get back on track, one of the top four guerrilla leaders, Valdizon's direct commander, agreed to withdraw from the negotiating table.</p>
<p>Congressional leader Garcia said he was optimistic peace negotiations would not suffer any further breakdowns.</p>
<p>Many Guatemalans hope peace will attract foreign investment and mark the beginning of an economic revival in this country where more than 80 percent of the population lives in poverty.</p>
<p>But Garcia said peace would mean a lot of work for Congress and the nation.</p>
<p>&quot;The peace signing means that from that moment on we must resolve the country's most difficult problems such as security, education, health, communications and housing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>According to Garcia, the 1997 government budget, passed by Congress last week, contains a high content of social spending in order to implement agreements contained in the accords.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
