<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18239" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Directionless German equities end trade lower.</title>
<headline>Directionless German equities end trade lower.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A lack of direction on the German share market combined with a weak dollar and neutral German Bunds to drag the electronically-traded IBIS DAX index lower at the end of trade on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The IBIS DAX index ended the day down 6.95 points, or 0.27 percent, at 2.556.64 points, having traded in a range of between 2,553.69 and 2,574.60 over the day.</p>
<p>Earlier, the 30-share DAX index closed trading up 4.32 points at 2,563.16, having traded in a range between 2,571.69 and 2,563.01.</p>
<p>While some individual stocks performed well, dealers said the market lacked the necessary impetus to forge significant overall gains.</p>
<p>Dealers had expected range-bound trading for both the floor session and the afternoon session, saying the market needed something more significant to ferry it back towards the 2,600 level.</p>
<p>Biggest trading volumes over the day were in chemical companies, with foreign investors seeking to line their portfolios with German chemical stocks.</p>
<p>But at the end of the day Hoechst AG was the only one of the three big chemical groups to hold onto gains, closing up 13 pfennigs at 52.70 marks.</p>
<p>Meanwhile profit-taking sent BASF AG shares down 21 pfennigs to 44.18 and Bayer AG shares down 61 pfennigs to 53.55 at the end of the day.</p>
<p>Carmaker Volkswagen ended the day up 1.52 percent at 549.10 marks, off earlier highs, after it said its car deliveries in western Europe were up 11.3 percent to 1.451 million vehicles.</p>
<p>There was strong interest in industrial giant Daimler Benz which ended up 1.06 marks at 81.26 marks at the end of the session in advance of half-year figures, due Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
