<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18237" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London precious metals quiet after options expiry.</title>
<headline>London precious metals quiet after options expiry.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The precious metals markets were quiet and prices mildly mixed on Wednesday after off-market options expired quietly.</p>
<p>Gold closed unchanged from Tuesday at $388.55 per ounce.</p>
<p>&quot;As far as we can see there was very little going on at the expiry. It's been very quiet,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Options give their owner, often a speculator, the right but not the obligation to buy gold at a fixed price, called the strike price, at a given time, known as the expiry date.</p>
<p>Often they can influence the direction of physical gold prices as the option sellers buy gold to cover their likely liabilities when the options expire.</p>
<p>If they are not called upon to deliver that metal to the option holders, the consequent selling can drive prices lower.</p>
<p>When the option's strike price is higher than the market price, as was the case with the most popular options on Wednesday, the holders of these options simply let them expire without exercising their right to buy gold.</p>
<p>&quot;We would expect prices to drift a little lower now the expiry is out of the way,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>There was little in overnight business to give Europe direction. The New York markets were mainly slightly softer ahead of the expiry and an upcoming three-day weekend.</p>
<p>Tokyo gold futures were marked up in response to a slightly weaker yen following a below-forecast Bank of Japan (BOJ) business confidence report.</p>
<p>The BOJ's quarterly survey showed the index of business conditions for major manufacturers was much lower than in the previous quarter and well below forecasts.</p>
<p>The report coincided with the release of statistics showing Japan's gold imports for the first seven months of 1996 at 95.55 tonnes versus 178.73 in the like 1995 period as the weaker yen pushed up retail gold prices and crushed investment and jewellery demand.</p>
<p>But dealers said gold generally was receiving some support from physical buying although interest was still low-key.</p>
<p>Silver opened slightly firmer but lost ground later to end three cents lower at $5.21.</p>
<p>&quot;Silver has had a nice bounce (from under $5.00 late July), but it's a flip of a coin whether it goes up or down,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>Platinum edged easier to close at $400.00, down $1.10 but its sister metal palladium finished firmer at $127.00, up $1.75.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
