<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182462" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China Light to submit Black Point report.</title>
<headline>China Light to submit Black Point report.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hong Kong government has asked China Light &amp; Power Co Ltd (CLP) to submit a report on deferring the second phase of its Black Point power station in three months' time, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think our consultants have given us the recommendation that it would be in the best interest of the consumers for China Light to defer units five to eight of Black Point for five years,&quot; Hong Kong's Secretary for Economic Services Stephen Ip said.</p>
<p>&quot;I have written to China Light asking them to let us have a detailed plan for the deferral of the unit in three months time.&quot;</p>
<p>China Light will present its economic analysis of the cost of a deferral to the Economic Services Panel of Hong Kong's Legislative Council, said Katherine Ma, the company's assistant public affairs manager.</p>
<p>&quot;CLP has promised to submit a detailed study on the deferral of (the later phases of) Black Point to the government and the first meeting will be on December 9,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>An independent consultant's report issued on Monday recommended a halt or delay in the commissioning of four units of the plant's eight units due to slowing growth in electricity demand.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were undecided on whether it would be more costly to cancel work on the second half of Black Point or to continue it.</p>
<p>China Light said earlier 84 percent of the estimated HK$24 billion in capital cost of the plant has already been committed.</p>
<p>The government had formally approved -- both in 1992 and then again in a 1994 -- the need for and construction of the 2,496-megawatt gas-fired power plant at Black Point, and construction and capital commitments related to the plant are at advanced stages, China Light officials have said.</p>
<p>Black Point consists of eight 312 MW units, two of which were commissioned in mid-1996 and two are to be switched on in mid-1997.</p>
<p>The remaining four were due to be turned on at a rate of one a year until the year 2001.</p>
<p>The growth in demand for power in Hong Kong has slowed following the shift of much of the territory's manufacturing base across the border to China. China, which used to rely heavily on Hong Kong power generators, is building its own power plants.</p>
<p>China Light said last week that four units of the Black Point power station have already been deferred and rescheduled for 1998-2001, and planned capital expenditure had been reduced by HK$10 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;Any further deferral would require negotiations with equipment suppliers, export credit agencies and some 60 banks involved in the loan syndications financing the project,&quot; said Ross Sayers, chief executive and managing director of China Light, speaking after the release of the 1996 full year results last week. -- Kathleen Kearney +852 2843 6933</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
