<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182498" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Saudi sends technical team to India air crash site.</title>
<headline>Saudi sends technical team to India air crash site.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saudi Arabia's state airline and civil aviation authority dispatched a technical team to New Delhi to investigate the world's worst mid-air collision on Tuesday, Saudi state television said.</p>
<p>King Fahd, Crown Prince Abdullah and Defence Minister Prince Sultan offered condolences to families of the estimated 350 people killed in the crash of a Saudi Boeing 747 and a Kazakh Airlines cargo plane over India, the television said.</p>
<p>Most of the passengers aboard the Saudi airliner were from India and Nepal, Saudi-owned Middle East Broadcasting Corp (MBC) television said.</p>
<p>The London-based satellite channel, quoting a Saudi Arabian Airlines Corp official in New Delhi, said Europeans were also among the passengers. It did not give their nationalities.</p>
<p>Eight children were among the 312 passengers and crew aboard flight SV 763 bound for the Saudi cities of Dhahran and Jeddah from New Delhi, MBC said. Only one Saudi passenger was on board, it said.</p>
<p>MBC said the crew comprised 11 Saudis and eight others from India, the Philippines and Morocco.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of people, mostly men, from the Indian subcontinent work in Saudi Arabia and remit much of their earnings to their families at home.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabian Airlines is the largest airline in the Middle East. It flies 12.5 million passengers a year.</p>
<p>The airline's last major disaster was in August 1980 when a Lockheed TriStar aircraft caught fire at Riyadh airport shortly before takeoff. All 301 people aboard were killed.</p>
<p>The state carrier has suffered operating losses for more than a decade mainly due to heavy government subsidies, particularly on fares on domestic routes, on which it has a monopoly.</p>
<p>Founded 51 years ago, the airline changed its name from Saudia in July and adopted a new livery for its fleet of 109 aircraft.</p>
<p>The airline is a leading candidate for privatisation when Saudi Arabia begins selling off state assets. It is spending $6 billion on 61 new Boeing and McDonnell Douglas airliners, the first of which are due to enter service next year.</p>
<p>Industry executives say up to 70 percent of its operations are domestic and 30 percent international. But almost 75 percent of its income is generated on international routes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
