<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182450" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's palladium use to rebound next year.</title>
<headline>Japan's palladium use to rebound next year.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's palladium demand for calendar 1996 is expected to fall sharply due to a slump in demand from the electronics sector, but growth in that sector should resume in 1997, platinum group metals refiner Johnson Matthey PLC said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Japan is the world's largest palladium consumer.</p>
<p>Johnson Matthey's interim 1996 platinum review estimated Japan's total palladium demand in 1996 at 2.115 million ounces this year against 2.505 million ounces last year.</p>
<p>Of this, demand from the electronics sector is expected to slip to 1.25 million ounces this year from 1.65 million ounces last year, pressured by a drop in output of multi-layer ceramic capacitors (MLCC) and substitution in MLCCs of nickel for palladium.</p>
<p>MLCCs are used in a variety of electronic and telecommunications equipment, especially cellular phones.</p>
<p>&quot;In Japan, nickel is increasingly substituting for palladium in lower-end products, lower price capacitors used in basic consumer electronics,&quot; said Alison Cowley, Publications Executive at Johnson Matthey's Precious Metals Marketing Division.</p>
<p>&quot;But I don't expect Japan's palladium demand from the electronics sector to continue falling in 1997 as we see a recovery in MLCC output in Japan, and the fact that the application of nickel substitutes for middle and higher end products has been very small,&quot; she said in an interview.</p>
<p>The platinum group refiner also said palladium demand from the autocatalyst sector in 1996 will grow modestly to 165,000 ounces from 145,000 ounces last year.</p>
<p>&quot;With no changes in gasoline emissions legislation on the horizon in Japan, there have been few technical incentives for manufacturers to alter their catalyst fitment programmes, and therefore, palladium consumption from the sector will grow only moderately,&quot; the Johnson Matthey report said.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Commodity Desk +81-3-3432-7431</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
