<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182618" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Utah's Jordan School District mulling bond issue.</title>
<headline>Utah's Jordan School District mulling bond issue.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite a 1992 bond issue that enabled it to build six schools, Utah's Jordan School District is running out of room again, and may put a new bond act before voters in May, a district spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are getting in about 1,000 students a year, so that means that if we don't build an elementary school every year or so, we rapidly fall behind, and we are in the fall behind category right now,&quot; Patty Dahl, director of public information for the district, said. Jordan covers the area around the southern third of Salt Lake Valley.</p>
<p>Dahl said it is too early to estimate how many bonds the district might sell or how many schools might be built.</p>
<p>Jordan has sought help from various city planners, an outside consulting firm, and representatives of the University of Utah, she said. Five study committees have been formed, and are expected to present a report to the school board on January 28.</p>
<p>One such committee is looking at the district's current buildings to determine how much money each needs for upkeep. Another is studying how the district would accomodate students if it doesn't sell bonds.</p>
<p>A third is mulling the financial implications of various sizes of bond issues, and how a longer, bigger bond issue would affect taxpayers versus a  shorter-term, smaller issue.</p>
<p>&quot;If we go bigger, we have fewer bond elections to face,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Once the committees present their findings, the school board is expected to conduct public opinion polls to determine what level of support exists for the proposed initiatives. Once the polls are back, the board will make its decision as to whether to sell debt, and, if so, in what amount and duration, she said.</p>
<p>The level of public support will be key to whether the district adopts a short-term solution or a longer term one, she said.</p>
<p>The $115 million issue the district sold in 1992 built two high schools, two middle schools, and two elmentary schools, Dahl said. It also paid for 25 to 30 major revovations. Of the six schools, two are already overcrowded, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;And we have probably 20 schools west of the Jordan River that have no room at all for growth, and growth is still continuing of course, and we expect it to continue,&quot; Dahl said.</p>
<p>A short-term solution, going out three to six years, would probably mean eight to 10 schools, she said.</p>
<p>New High schools currently cost roughly $40 million; new middle schools, $18 million to $20 million; and new elementary schools usually run $8 million to $10 million, Dahl said.</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
