<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182633" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Vitamins could soften blow of junk-food binge.</title>
<headline>Vitamins could soften blow of junk-food binge.</headline>
<dateline>NEW ORLEANS 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A mega-dose of vitamins taken before a junk-food binge could soften the meal's blow on the body, researchers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cardiologists at the University of Maryland Medical Centre in Baltimore found that blood vessels do not dilate normally after a person takes in a high-fat meal.</p>
<p>But they also learned that taking high doses of vitamins C and E shortly before a double-cheeseburger could prevent the vessels' impairment.</p>
<p>A big fast-food meal &quot;may be affecting our blood vessels even as we eat it,&quot; Mary Corretti, an assistant professor of medicine at the university and co-author of the study, said in an interview during the American Heart Association's annual scientific sessions in New Orleans.</p>
<p>The researchers tested 20 healthy adult volunteers who ate a 900-calorie meal of fast-food eggs, sausage and hash browns that was 50 percent saturated fat.</p>
<p>The average blood vessel dilation before the meal was 21 percent.</p>
<p>Two hours after the meal, the volunteers' blood vessels could only dilate an average of 12 percent. &quot;If we repeatedly eat this way I can see we can injure the lining of the blood vessel,&quot; Corretti said.</p>
<p>But when the same volunteers took one gram of vitamin C and 800 international units of vitamin E before eating the meal on a different day, the average dilation two hours later was 17 percent.</p>
<p>Corretti was quick to add, however, that she was not recommending that people chew vitamins before an order of large fries, saying the research was still preliminary.</p>
<p>She said the immediate message from the study was the value of a balanced diet, including fruits and vegetables. &quot;It's another argument for eating sensibly,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW ORLEANS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
