<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182765" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Md. county exec terminates $585 mln mall project.</title>
<headline>Md. county exec terminates $585 mln mall project.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Montgomery County, Md., executive said he terminated a pact with Canadian supermall builder Triple Five Group for the construction of a $585 million entertainment center in downtown Silver Spring, Md.</p>
<p>County Executive Douglas Duncan said at a press briefing he reviewed a financing plan submitted last week by Triple Five and concluded that the private capital pledged by the group, which built the popular Mall of America near Minneapolis 10 years ago, is inadequate.</p>
<p>&quot;Regretfully, it appears today that the challenges outweigh the promise and that it is time for us to move in a new direction,&quot; Duncan said.</p>
<p>Duncan said revitalization of economically troubled Silver Spring, which borders the District of Columbia, continues to be a top priority for upscale Montgomery County.</p>
<p>He added that the campaign to revitalize Silver Spring will never again hinge &quot;on the sucess of just one project.&quot;</p>
<p>Triple Five said in its financing plan that only 15 percent to 25 percent of the center's cost would come from taxpayers. The rest would be financed through private capital and revenue bonds, the plan says.</p>
<p>But Duncan said, &quot;The report does not provide concrete evidence that private sector support is available.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They (said) they were going to have Morgan Stanley &amp; Co. come up with $350 million in private capital,&quot; Stephen Simon, press spokesman for the county, said. &quot;They were showing us a shell of a plan, but there was no evidence that any element of that had materialized,&quot; Simon said.</p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is a unit of Morgan Stanley Group Inc.</p>
<p>Duncan said the level of private capital assumed by Triple Five would force county taxpayers and the state to &quot;foot entirely too much of the bill.&quot;</p>
<p>Duncan told Reuters last week that both his county and the state of Maryland would be very reluctant to issue the necessary revenue bonds for the projects.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
