<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182756" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYCE cotton ends lower, Dec holds major support.</title>
<headline>NYCE cotton ends lower, Dec holds major support.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYCE cotton fell to a fresh contract low for the second consecutive session but managed to recoup some losses and close above the key 70.00 cents a lb level basis December.</p>
<p>Analysts viewed the move as positive and said prices could climb higher Wednesday.</p>
<p>The day's major sellers were the funds, who pressured the market early and then covered short positions amid thin volume late in the session.</p>
<p>One dealer estimated the funds will reveal a 20 percent net short position in Wednesday's speculative/hedge report. &quot;If it's more we could get some bulls back in here,&quot; he said, pegging resistance at 71.00 in December.</p>
<p>December cotton settled down 0.42 at 70.30 cents per pound, traded 70.75 to 69.90, a life-of-contract low. The back months finished 0.30 lower to 0.17 firmer.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 14,500 lots.</p>
<p>Prices slid early on the U.S. Department of Agriculture's November supply and demand data. The USDA pegged the 1996/97 crop at 18.594 million 480-lb bales, up 2 percent from October's estimate of 18.189 million bales. Domestic use was flat at 11.0 million bales.</p>
<p>The USDA also raised ending stocks to 4.9 million bales from 4.5 million bales in October.</p>
<p>Internationally, lower estimates in Pakistan, Brazil and Uzbekistan were offset by increases in India, Australia, West Africa and the U.S.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1646 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
