<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182734" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Impairment issue left in Ill. park district suit.</title>
<headline>Impairment issue left in Ill. park district suit.</headline>
<dateline>WHEATON, Ill. 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A DuPage County, Ill., Circuit Court judge on Tuesday gave a park district one last chance to prove that his ruling in a tax case would impair its contract with bondholders.</p>
<p>Judge John Darrah rejected a motion to rehear the entire case brought against the county tax collector by a group of business owners.</p>
<p>However, the judge gave attorneys representing the tax collector a few weeks to present briefs on their contention that his April ruling would unconstitutionally impair contracts with holders of Lisle Park District's debt.</p>
<p>The Lisle Park District is being used as a test case in the lawsuit, which has the potential to affect several other park districts in the county.</p>
<p>Lawyers representing the tax collector had filed a motion for a rehearing in the wake of Judge Darrah's ruling last April that property taxes used by the Lisle Park District to pay off general obligation debt issued for the retirement of approximately $6 million of installment contracts and alternate bonds were subject to limitations under a 1991 state tax cap law.</p>
<p>That law subjected park districts and other local governments in five suburban Chicago counties to an annual limit in property tax collection increases of five percent or the rate of inflation, whichever is less. Any increase in taxes over that limit require voter approval, under the law.</p>
<p>Darrah ruled that all taxes levied in excess of the limit were illegal and void and that the plaintiffs were entitled to a refund.</p>
<p>One attorney familiar with the case said that if the ruling is ultimately upheld, it would impact almost all park districts in the county that pledged to issue GO bonds to retire installment contracts or alternate bonds. Those districts would be forced to use operating revenues to pay debt service on their bonds, according to the attorney.</p>
<p>Tuesday's hearing before Judge Darrah was attended by several representatives of park districts in DuPage County, who said after the proceedings that the judge's ruling would be devastating.</p>
<p>Larry Wheeler, director of the Hanover Park Park District said that if upheld, the ruling would lead to cuts in services and layoffs as park districts would be forced to use operating revenues to pay off debt obligations.</p>
<p>Court filings for the motion for Judge Darrah to rehear the case claimed his ruling would unconstitutionally impair Lisle Park District's contract with holders of its installment contracts whether or not there is a default by impairing the district's pledge to issue GO debt to pay them off. The filings also claimed that GO debt sold to pay off alternate bonds was statutorily authorized and exempted from the tax cap law.</p>
<p>Darrah is scheduled to rule on rehearing the impairment issue on Dec. 4. In the meantime, he allowed the Wood Dale Park District and the Illinois Association of Park Districts to intervene in the lawsuit on the side of the county tax collector.</p>
<p>Attorneys said the case is expected to be appealed to the Illinois Appellate Court no matter which side ultimately wins.</p>
<p>-- Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WHEATON, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
