<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182919" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Industry Council set to clash on cash to SMEs.</title>
<headline>Industry Council set to clash on cash to SMEs.</headline>
<byline>Fredrik Dahl</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union industry ministers are set for difficult negotiations in Council on Thursday to find a compromise on how much money to spend on an action plan to help small firms grow and create needed jobs.</p>
<p>The Third Multiannual Programme for small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs), COM(96)98, is part of the Commission's campaign to cut a jobless rate of nearly 11 percent in the EU.</p>
<p>But the Commission, already smarting from earlier setbacks in its efforts to create jobs, will most likely see its original budget proposal scaled down by ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a good time to be coming with a four-year, multiannual programme when people have their minds so fully focused on Maastricht (EMU) criteria,&quot; one diplomat said.</p>
<p>At the Council in May, ministers agreed on the bulk of the text but they failed to agree on how much the SME programme, to run from 1997 to 2000, would cost.</p>
<p>The Commission has proposed a budget of 180 million Ecus, of which 40 million Ecus would come from re-allocating funds within the EU budget.</p>
<p>This represents an increase of some 60 percent compared with the 112 million Ecus for the previous four years.</p>
<p>However, countries including Germany, Sweden, Britain and the Netherlands object to the proposed increase.</p>
<p>Britain wants to see an unchanged budget while Germany can accept 120 million Ecus.</p>
<p>EU diplomats say a compromise may be possible at around 120-140 million Ecus but agreement, which requires unanimity, is not guaranteed.</p>
<p>&quot;If we get a decision, it will be a decision with a lot of disappointed people,&quot; said one diplomat.</p>
<p>Ministers, however, will be under pressure to reach a deal as the Florence EU summit in June requested that the Council adopt the new action plan before the end of 1996 &quot;to reinforce the potential for their further development so that they can benefit fully from the internal market and thus make a more effective contribution to the creation of jobs&quot;.</p>
<p>The proposed programme includes a series of measures aimed at boosting the development and competitiveness of SMEs, which account for 99.8 percent of all companies and 66 percent of employment in the EU.</p>
<p>It proposes steps to reduce the administrative burden on firms, give them better access to loans and other financing, improve the flow of information, encourage the training of managers and support women and young entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>The plan was part of Commission President Jacques Santer's confidence pact for employment which has run into much opposition from EU finance mininisters reluctant to spend money while they desperately try to meet criteria for monetary union.</p>
<p>The Commission had proposed to revise the EU budget's financial perspectives so that money from the farm budget could be used on employment policies, mainly on trans-European networks but also on SMEs and research.</p>
<p>But in Luxembourg last month, EU finance ministers once again rejected the Commission's proposal to spend one billion Ecus on rail and road networks to boost jobs, the most important element of Santer's plan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
