<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182932" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German beer consumption continues long slide.</title>
<headline>German beer consumption continues long slide.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>German beer consumption, which has been declining steadily in recent years due to health concerns, continued to slump in the first three quarters of 1996, the association of German brewers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Germans remain among the world's leaders in beer drinking, however, with a per capita consumption of just under 140 litres (30.8 Imperial gallons) per year, leaving them trailing only the Czechs.</p>
<p>Rainer Pott, the president of the brewers' association, said beer sales fell 2.8 percent over the first nine months of 1996 to 78.8 million hectolitres.</p>
<p>A relatively cool summer hurt beer sales this year. Steadily rising unemployment in Germany, currently around 10 percent, has also had a negative impact, as have increases in beverage taxes in many municipalities.</p>
<p>German workers have also seen their real incomes stagnate or even decline in recent years as wage increases have generally failed to keep pace with inflation.</p>
<p>Pott said there has nevertheless been a marked increase in beer mixed with other beverages such as lemonade.</p>
<p>The most fiercely competitive and impregnable beer markets in the world, Germany is the home to three-quarters of all breweries in Europe, although most are small operations.</p>
<p>The number of breweries in Germany declined by 35 in 1996 to 1,243.</p>
<p>The German beer industry has an annual turnover of 20 billion marks ($13 billion) and employs nearly 50,000 people. ($1=1.4945 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
