<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="182935" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German stock watchdog bites harder in 1996.</title>
<headline>German stock watchdog bites harder in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's fledgling securities watchdog, the BAWe, said on Tuesday it had stepped up its clampdown against irregularities such as insider trading in the first half of 1996 and had gained a higher profile.</p>
<p>In an adjunct to its 1995 annual report, the BAWe said mounting awareness of its role as the stock market &quot;police force&quot; had sparked 64 customers to register official complaints over brokers' behaviour in the six-month period, compared with 61 in the whole of 1995.</p>
<p>Investigations of suspected insider trading, the BAWe's main brief, were also stepped up this year.</p>
<p>A total of 38 possible insider-trading cases were probed in the first six months, 13 of which had been dropped as they failed to yield evidence of wrongdoing, while eight had been passed on to public prosecutors and two had ended in court.</p>
<p>BAWe chief Georg Wittich described the operations so far as a success.</p>
<p>&quot;The first year was mostly concerned with personnel and organisational build-up, which is now mostly finished,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The BAWe is a key part of Germany's wide-ranging plans to transform Frankfurt into a financial centre with structures and regulations to match its international rivals.</p>
<p>Its chief task is to clamp down on insider trading, which was made illegal in this country for the first time by a law passed in mid-1994, as well as ensuring that companies become more transparent.</p>
<p>The BAWe also stepped up its efforts to ensure that companies comply with Germany's new reporting laws, which demand that companies report market-moving information in the form of an &quot;ad-hoc&quot; communication, usually electronically.</p>
<p>Ten firms had been fined in the period for failing to comply with the law, more than a fifth of the 46 companies investigated for suspected irregularities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
