<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183360" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USAir plans internal growth, not mergers.</title>
<headline>USAir plans internal growth, not mergers.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>USAir Group Inc said it plans to expand internally by increasing its international operations, not through mergers or acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;Our preference has been for internally-generated growth and that remains our preferred course of action,&quot; said USAir Chairman Stephen Wolf.</p>
<p>&quot;We're in no (merger discussion) and we don't see any on the horizon,&quot; Wolf said.  </p>
<p>USAir, which recently said it will end its code-sharing relationship with British Airways Plc in March 1997, said it expects to eventually pursue other international alliances.</p>
<p>&quot;Long-term we want to participate with somebody, but it's not real high on our radar scope at this time,&quot; Wolf said.</p>
<p>USAir, instead, sees &quot;fast, big growth&quot; in its international operations.</p>
<p>The Arlington, Va.-based carrier said it expects to add service to up to 23 international markets from Philadelphia and other key cities within the &quot;next few years.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;We have inherent, fundamental strength to Europe that needs to be exploited,&quot; USAir president Rakesh Gangwal said.</p>
<p>In 1997, USAir said it expects domestic growth of about 0.7 percent and total system growth of about 2.0 percent.</p>
<p>USAir said its international expansion is not dependent on the development of a new Anglo-U.S. air treaty.</p>
<p>&quot;Having no 'open skies' deal would not be a big blow; we have a number of other opportunities,&quot; said Wolf.</p>
<p>Talks for a new &quot;open skies&quot; agreement between the U.S. and Britain are expected to resume in December.  </p>
<p>USAir has filed for access to London Heathrow airport, which could become available if a new U.S.-U.K. air treaty were reached.</p>
<p>Without access to Heathrow, USAir said it could not effectively compete against a proposed pact between British Airways and AMR Corp's American Airlines.</p>
<p>USAir sued British Airways and American over the proposed alliance, saying the deal would lead to a monopoly of air travel between the United States and Britain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
