<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18337" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Competition cuts Indonesia Matahari target - analysts.</title>
<headline>Competition cuts Indonesia Matahari target - analysts.</headline>
<byline>Helen Lumban Gaol</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fierce retailing rivalry and over-expansion have cut profits of Indonesia's largest department store operator PT Matahari Putra Prima and forced it to cut its 1996 net profit forecast, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The company said on Tuesday it was forced to lower its target in the wake of a sales drop following riots last month seen by many as the worst disturbances in more than 20 years.</p>
<p>Matahari lowered its 1996 net profit to 46 billion rupiah ($19.6 million) from a target of 50 billion rupiah.</p>
<p>Company finance director Hanifah Komala said the drop was partly due to riots in Jakarta on July 27. &quot;After the riots, many people in Jakarta prefered to stay at home and it affected our sales which were already weak,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Analysts said they were was not really surprised that Matahari had revised down its target as they had concerns about the pace of the company's expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;What's more surprising is the company gave the reason that riots in Jakarta affected their sales. We have checked with other department stores, it hasn't affected their sales,&quot; said an analyst at a foreign brokerage, who asked not be named.</p>
<p>The analyst also doubted the firm could reach its 1997 net profit target of 83 billion rupiah as first-half 1996 sales grew at only 2.3 percent. Matahari had forecast 10 percent growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Current market concensus for 1997 net profit is 65 billion rupiah,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But Wilianto Ie, analyst of Schroeders Indonesia, believed the company could reach its target.</p>
<p>&quot;If management slows down their expansion of new outlets and assuming their first quarter result meets the expectation, I think the figures are still realistic,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said it was more likely Matahari's department store sales were depressed by fiercer competition among department stores, especially in Jakarta.</p>
<p>Ironically, Matahari had suffered from competition from its own outlets after aggressive expansion, Wilianto said.</p>
<p>Competition among department stores in Jakarta was getting fiercer, especially in up-market department stores, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;But if we take out Galeria and Mega M (both up-market Matahari-owned stores), most Matahari outlets are aimed at middle class consumers where it still leads the market,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Wilianto was recommending a &quot;hold&quot; position for Matahari.</p>
<p>Komala said aggressive expansion had caused difficulties as 54 percent of Matahari's stores were less than three years old.</p>
<p>&quot;On average, each new outlet will only make profit after three years of operation. So, in general, only 46 percent of present outlets generate a profit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>To avoid further losses, Matahari had committed itself to slowing its expansion. By December, it planned to have total outlets covering 667,000 sq metres (7.1 million sq ft), and by 1997 the firm planned only to open seven new outlets with a total of 83,000 sq metres (893,400 sq ft).</p>
<p>&quot;Now we are more focusing to get more profit, stronger financial position rather than expand aggresively,&quot; Komala added.</p>
<p>Matahari expects a net profit of 83 billion rupiah in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;With conservative sales growth target of nine percent, I believe we can reach the target,&quot; said Komala.</p>
<p>($1=2,341 rupiah)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
