<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18350" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia Powertek at premium ahead of listing.</title>
<headline>Malaysia Powertek at premium ahead of listing.</headline>
<byline>Reme Ahmad</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia's first infrastructure project listing has made an auspicious start with Powertek Bhd shares already trading at a sharp premium on the grey market, analysts and dealers said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The power firm will be listed on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange on Thursday. But market players said some of the shares placed earlier had traded at up to 7.50 ringgit ($3.01) each in the unofficial market.</p>
<p>This is an 18 percent premium over the 6.38 ringgit price of the placement shares and nearly double that of the public tranche at 3.90 ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;The grey market price is around 7.00, and I heard up to 7.50,&quot; said an institutional dealer at a local brokerage.</p>
<p>Powertek, one of Malaysia's five pioneer independent power producers (IPPs), offered 43.131 million shares at 3.90 ringgit each to the public for its listing on the main board of the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>The company had earlier placed out 16.293 million shares to international institutions at 6.38 ringgit each after open bidding which was oversubscribed by 4.7 times.</p>
<p>Institutions had bid up to 8.15 ringgit to get the shares, said joint managers for the placement, TA Securities Bhd and Yamaichi Merchant Bank (Singapore) Ltd.</p>
<p>Powertek, whose 440 megawatt plant achieved full commercial operations in June 1995, is the first infrastructure project company to list on the exchange.</p>
<p>To ease fund-raising for big infrastructure projects, Malaysia has relaxed listing requirements for infrastructure project firms, including waiving the five-year earnings track record requirement.</p>
<p>Some analysts said that like almost all local initial public offerings (IPOs), Powertek should have a rousing debut, possibly rising as high as 8.00 ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;You know how IPOs go in Malaysia. The first week they go over the moon ... before falling back to fundamentals,&quot; said Adin Jarjis, an analyst at Pesaka Jardine Fleming.</p>
<p>Analysts cautioned that based on the company's earnings outlook, the stock is worth buying up to 7.00 ringgit.</p>
<p>&quot;Powertek appears a pretty good alternative play in the IPP sector on existing measurements ... buy up to seven ringgit,&quot; a Mohaiyani Research analyst said in a research note.</p>
<p>Fans of Powertek say it has safe, stable earnings with a 21-year agreement from 1993 to sell electricity to state power firm Tenaga Nasional Bhd.</p>
<p>Its open cycle-plant is expected to be converted to a combined-cycle plant with a 680 MW capacity by the turn of the century.</p>
<p>However, the company's main strength was also its major weakness, some analysts said.</p>
<p>Powertek's predictable growth from being a one-product, one-client firm was attractive for those wanting steady earnings but may turn off others seeking companies with explosive earnings potential.</p>
<p>There were also reservations on whether Powertek could negotiate the same margins from Tenaga when it has installed its new plant capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;The additional capacity increase would entail a new power purchase agreement and is not likely to be as lucrative,&quot; said an analyst at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>($1 = 2.49 ringgit)</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
