<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183580" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: M-Wave sees lower sales, loss in Q4.</title>
<headline>M-Wave sees lower sales, loss in Q4.</headline>
<dateline>BENSENVILLE, Ill. 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>M-Wave Inc said Tuesday it expects lower sales and a loss in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;During the third quarter, we were able to fill orders that had been on hold while we were reorganizing manufacturing operations and improving quality control,&quot; Joe Turek, chairman, said in a statement.  &quot;We anticipate lower sales and a loss in the fourth quarter while we complete the strategic repositioning of the company.&quot;  </p>
<p>It reported a third quarter net loss of $0.07 a share, compared with a loss of $0.16 a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;Going forward, we are focusing our business on producing Teflon-laminated microwave circuit boards for industrial applications such as cellular telephone and personal communication systems (PCS) infrastructure and base stations, as well as military applications such as satellite tracking systems,&quot; Turek said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We analyzed our markets with a view to their future potential and feel that our best opportunity for sustainable growth and profitability is in those areas where we provide engineered solutions in developing complex circuit boards for high frequency applications,&quot; Turek said.</p>
<p>He added that M-Wave has decided not to compete in the consumer products market, which has become a &quot;mass production, low margin business.&quot;  M-Wave said it will place less emphasis on consumer applications such as telephone handsets and direct broadcast satellite (DBS) systems.</p>
<p>&quot;We concluded that while there is rapid growth in these markets, the profit margins are well below our targets,&quot; Turek said.</p>
<p>He added the company's new 45,000 square foot P C Dynamics manufacturing facility became fully operational during the third quarter.  But it is not expected to make a significant sales contribution to the company until 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The facility is currently running well below capacity; however, we anticipate that more aggressive sales efforts should result in new business,&quot; Turek said.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk - 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34440">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BENSENVILLE, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
