<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183659" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LME copper rallies in AM kerb trading, others slow.</title>
<headline>LME copper rallies in AM kerb trading, others slow.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper prices pushed higher following a drawdown in London Metal Exchange (LME) stocks on Tuesday, with an eye towards resistance at $2,050, traders said.</p>
<p>The other metals were mostly lacklustre and quiet.</p>
<p>Benchmark three-months copper ended the morning kerb at $2,045 a tonne, up from Monday's LME kerb close of $2,012.</p>
<p>Traders said the move above recent resistance at $2,040 could see prices push higher towards $2,050/60 against the backdrop of option related covering and renewed speculative short-covering.</p>
<p>Activity turned brisk during the kerb after sluggish ring sessions, after New York markets posted a higher than expected opening, traders said.</p>
<p>LME stocks declined 4,225 tonnes, in line with expectations, bringing inventories to six-year lows of 109,175 tonnes.</p>
<p>Opinions remained divided as to whether stocks were being used by end consumers or simply being removed off LME warrant to bonded warehouses.</p>
<p>Nearby spreads tightened, cash to three months was at a $90 backwardation and now looks to have the potential to claw towards $100 and possibly higher by the close of the week.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall there is a lot of bullish sentiment creeping in,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Another noted that the break higher reflected a lack of Chinese selling which has helped to cap any significant rallies.</p>
<p>&quot;The sellers have backed off which has given the market a chart boost,&quot; one LME floor trader commented.</p>
<p>Traders said they were closely watching a severe drought in central Chile, site of state copper company Codelco's El Teniente mine, the country's third largest.</p>
<p>Officials said it was probable the drought would have an impact on production on El Teniente and Exxon Mineral's Los Bronces pit. s 7</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
