<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183647" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BA says may appeal on French hostages ruling.</title>
<headline>BA says may appeal on French hostages ruling.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc said it may make an appeal to the French supreme court against a ruling on Tuesday that it must pay 61 passengers who became Gulf War hostages 400,000 to 600,000 francs each in compensation.</p>
<p>A Paris appeals court today upheld last year's lower court order that BA should pay the French hostages for landing them in Kuwait City at the start of the Iraqi invasion.</p>
<p>&quot;We are disappointed with today's decision...and we are considering a further appeal,&quot; a company spokesman said. &quot;If we appeal it will go to the Court of Cassation (supreme court).  </p>
<p>BA says it did not know about the invasion before the aircraft landed and therefore it could not be held responsible for what happened next.</p>
<p>The 61 French nationals and foreign residents of France were among the 364 people on board a BA flight from London which landed at Kuwait airport on August 2, 1990 -- four hours after Iraqi invaders entered the emirate.</p>
<p>&quot;We have said throughout that while we have every sympathy with those taken hostage what happened to them was the result of an act of war by Iraq which took the whole world by surprise,&quot; the BA spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;We could not have foreseen it and cannot have be held responsible for its consequences,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the British supreme court, the House of Lords, is due to give its verdict later this month on appeals brought by other passengers in two similar actions in England and Scotland after their cases were dismissed by lower courts.</p>
<p>BA said it had settled out of court on two other actions brought by hostages in the United States &quot;to avoid the high costs of litigation in the U.S.&quot; It said a third action in the U.S. was dismissed in a summary judgement.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
