<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183678" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Palladium demand seen steady in 1996 - JM.</title>
<headline>Palladium demand seen steady in 1996 - JM.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A strong rise in palladium use in autocatalysts should counter lower demand for the metal from the electronics industry, refiner Johnson Matthey (JM) said in its Platinum 1996 Interim Review published on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Supply of the metal was forecast to decline this year to 5.98 million ounces down from 6.34 million ounces last year.</p>
<p>Slightly higher exports were forecast from South Africa but lower shipments were saeen from supplier Russia and from North America.</p>
<p>With demand expected to be virtually unchanged at 6.11 million ounces, JM forecast the palladium price to range between $105 and $135 per ounce during the coming six months.</p>
<p>On Tuesday palladium was fixed at $117.75 per ounce.</p>
<p>The report's author, Alison Cowley, said that the market had built a surplus of 650,000 ounces in 1994 and 1995 but the small deficit this year would reduce stocks by 135,000 ounces.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand for palladium is down largely because of the electronics industry,&quot; Cowley said. &quot;Underlying demand for electronic goods is still quite strong but towards the end of last year the rate of growth slowed.&quot;</p>
<p>That caught producers of both electronic components and finished goods with a stock build this year and producers of palladium-rich components like multi-later ceramic capacitors pulled back production.</p>
<p>Consumption of palladium in electronics was forecast to fall by 20 percent this year to 2.123 million ounces. &quot;We would expect to see production picking up again in 1997. Certainly 1997 should be a better year for palladium demand than this year,&quot; said Cowley.</p>
<p>Japan, the largest palladium user, is expected to import 2.115 million ounces this year compared to 2.505 ounces in 1995.</p>
<p>Palladium use in autocatalysts could rise by 31 percent this year to 2.27 million ounces due to the increased use of palladium-rich catalysts with 88 percent of the total being used by automakers in Europe and North America.</p>
<p>Russia is the largest supplier of palladium to the world market but was forecast to cut shipments to about 3.8 million ounces this year from 4.2 million ounces in 1995.</p>
<p>That level of export still required Russia to dip into its palladium stockpile, the size of which is a close secret.</p>
<p>&quot;We estimate that Russian sales will be almost double the current level of production at Norilsk (its major mining centre),&quot; said the JM report.</p>
<p>JM precious metal marketing division marketing director Keith Green said, &quot;Russia can now supply sponge grade material as well as ingot although it is not clear what percentage of production now in sponge.&quot;</p>
<p>South African output was expected to be up 70,000 ounces at 1.67 million ounces this tear of a total world supply of 5.98 million ounces, down from 6.34 million ounces last year.</p>
<p>Cowley said there were few signs to suggest that following the decline in Japanese imports, Russia had sold additional metal on to the dealer market.</p>
<p>&quot;They have got the palladium. The reason they have not sold as much is that the Japanese market was down because of the electronic sector and palladium was in over supply in 1994 and 1995,&quot; Cowley said.</p>
<p>&quot;They were put in a position where prices have come back and there wasn't a price rise for them to sell into,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She added that the Russians could also be selling less than in previous years to keep the yen price stable.</p>
<p>&quot;The market will continue to rely on Russian sales from stock,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>-- Brian Spoors London newsdesk +44 171 542 8058</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22472">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
