<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183687" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British cancer patients sue tobacco firms.</title>
<headline>British cancer patients sue tobacco firms.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Reaney</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twelve British cancer patients launched a legal case on Tuesday against two tobacco firms for failing to change their products to limit the damage of smoking.</p>
<p>The case, Europe's largest ever legal battle against the tobacco industry, could open a floodgate of similar law suits.</p>
<p>Martyn Day, who is representing the 12 in the group action, issued formal writs against Imperial Tobacco Group Plc and Gallaher, a subsidiary of American Brands Inc, and applied for a judge to be appointed in London to determine a timetable for the case.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a historic day. It is the first time the tobacco companies in this country have been challenged for the actions they took and the decisions they made once it became clear that tobacco was killing a large number of its consumers,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>The case is also the first in Britain where lawyers for the plaintiffs, who have been denied legal aid, are working on a no win, no fee basis, a common practice in the United States.</p>
<p>Under the English legal system a single judge is likely to be appointed to deal with the claim. The plaintiffs have asked for the case to be heard in October 1998.</p>
<p>The group action is based on the alleged failure of the two companies, which control 80 percent of the British cigarette market and produce such brands as Benson &amp; Hedges, Silk Cut, Players and Embassy, to reduce the level of tar in their cigarettes after doctors in the 1950s began saying tar could lead to the onset of cancer.</p>
<p>Imperial Tobacco, recently demerged from conglomerate Hanson Plc and Gallaher, a unit of American Brands in the United States, say there is no proof that by reducing the tar levels in cigarettes these people would not have suffered from cancer.</p>
<p>Under the no win, no fee agreement, Day and the other lawyers in the group action will receive nothing if they lose the case but could reap huge benefits if they win.</p>
<p>&quot;The action holds serious risks to both our firm and to the clients,&quot; said Day. &quot;For us the risk is of a massive loss if the claims are unsuccessful of around 3 million pounds ($4.96 million) in costs and lost fees.&quot;</p>
<p>Day said that when the trial begins in 1998, more than 100 plantiffs could be included in the group action which carries tremendous legal implications.</p>
<p>In the United States, where hundreds of suits against the tobacco industry have been filed, Liggett Group became the first tobacco company to agree to settle a class action case in New Orleans and to negotiate with states in their litigation to recoup the health costs of smokers.</p>
<p>($1=.6050 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
