<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183739" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: King Hussein frees Jordan bread riot detainees.</title>
<headline>King Hussein frees Jordan bread riot detainees.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan's King Hussein has declared a general amnesty for all detainees arrested in connection with widespread bread riots in August, the state news agency Petra reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It said the king's amnesty also extended to any prisoners not considered a threat to public security or whose term behind bars was considered sufficient punishment.</p>
<p>&quot;We request you to take measures to halt prosecution of those who deviated from the right way and harmed their country...in the events connected with the change in the wheat subsidies,&quot; Petra quoted the king as instructing Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti in a letter.</p>
<p>The king's letter gave no indication of how many people would be covered by the amnesty.</p>
<p>Government officials said hundreds of people were arrested after the rioting, the worst civil unrest in Jordan for seven years. But they said most had subsequently been released.</p>
<p>The king also instructed Kabariti to &quot;look again at the sale price of bread&quot; in light of the fall in world grain prices from their record levels earlier this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
