<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183880" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Frankfurt bourse closes firmer as dollar stablises.</title>
<headline>Frankfurt bourse closes firmer as dollar stablises.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Frankfurt bourse ended slightly firmer on Tuesday as the dollar stemmed its fall, and the market was supported by a record close on Wall Street and strength in German government bonds.</p>
<p>But dealers said a weaker dollar, at its lowest level for two months, had weighed on German exporters, most notably in the chemicals and auto sectors.</p>
<p>The DAX index of 30 leading shares, closed up 5.98 points, or 0.22 percent, at 2,734.30 points.</p>
<p>But after the bourse close, the IBIS DAX, measuring all-day electronic dealings in the DAX index, bounded ahead to a new record high of 2,752.75 points as the dollar recovered some ground.</p>
<p>The dollar rose to trade just under the psychologically important level of 1.50 marks after Bundesbank directorate member Edgar Meister said the current dollar exchange rate was &quot;not appropriate.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said although the market had been suffering from dollar weakness, the longer term outlook was still positive. &quot;The market is very robust at the moment,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>The banking sector led the market. Commerzbank ended bourse dealings up 32 pfennigs at 34.65 marks, while Germany's biggest bank Deutsche Bank gained over one percent, or 1.45 marks to 69.70 marks.</p>
<p>Dealers said Deutsche Bank was boosted after the Oslo Stock Exchange said its investment arm Deutsche Morgan Grenfell was not obliged to bid for the Norwegian software company Sysdeco Group.</p>
<p>Consumer products group Henkel KGAA was up 20 pfennigs at 72.00 marks, after it announced nine month figures in line with expectations.</p>
<p>Sportware manufacturer Adidas jumped in pre-bourse dealings to a high of 137 marks after it published its nine month results, but reaction to the figures then calmed down and the stock ended floor trade up two marks at 134.50 marks.</p>
<p>Meanwhile the world's largest reinsurer Munich Re continued to fall on the back of a statement made on Monday that the company could see a fall in profits for the 1996/97 financial year. The stock was down 42 marks at 3,688 marks.</p>
<p>Munich Re shares were also under pressure from a downgrade by Deutsche Morgan Grenfell to &quot;neutral&quot; from &quot;overweight&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
