<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="183934" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Greens flourishing in Germany's urban landscape.</title>
<headline>Greens flourishing in Germany's urban landscape.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU) may have scraped home in elections for a new Stuttgart mayor but most commentators have little doubt about the real winners of the poll -- the environmentalist Greens.</p>
<p>The party's candidate, Rezzo Schlauch, took 39.3 percent of the vote in Sunday's election -- less than four points behind winner Wolfgang Schuster and more than 20 points ahead of the Social Democrats (SPD), Germany's main opposition party.</p>
<p>&quot;Never before has a Green received almost 40 percent of the vote in a city with more than half a million residents,&quot; noted the conservative daily Die Welt in an editorial on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The result was indeed little short of sensational for a party born only two decades ago from the peace movement and radical anti-capitalist student protests of the 1960s.</p>
<p>But it was also confirmation of a growing trend in favour of the Greens, now closer to the social democrat mainstream, in big cities across Germany.</p>
<p>&quot;The Greens have always been a stong local party... and we've probably acted much more pragmatically at that level,&quot; Schlauch said at a triumphal news conference in Bonn on Tuesday. &quot;Now we can harvest the fruits fo that labour.&quot;</p>
<p>This year alone, the party has also captured the mayor's office in the southern city of Konstanz and taken second place among first preference votes in local elections in Hanover.</p>
<p>&quot;Such results are about much more than local events or personalities,&quot; the liberal Frankfurter Rundschau commented. &quot;They show how far social changes in the big cities have gone already.&quot;</p>
<p>Underscoring the party's confidence in metropolitan areas, the Greens' co-leader Krista Sager is giving up her post to campaign as local party boss for elections in Hamburg, Germany's second biggest city, next year.</p>
<p>&quot;We see ourselves in Hamburg, as in Stuttgart and other cities, not as supporters but as competitors of the big parties,&quot; Sager told German Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;There's an increasing awareness that we're an independent force and that we can act as an independent power with increasing confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>Opinion polls may give the SPD, Germany's oldest party, nationwide support of 35 percent to the Greens' 10 but it is the upstarts who look capable of pulling in the ballot papers in many urban areas, particularly among younger voters.</p>
<p>Polls showed Schlauch attracted more votes in all age groups under 50 than any of his rivals.</p>
<p>Daniel Cohn-Bendit, the leader of France's May 1968 student revolt who is now a Green city councillor in Frankfurt, said the SPD would not even be in the running for mayor in Germany's financial capital at the next election.</p>
<p>&quot;The next election for mayor in Frankfurt will be a fight between the CDU and the Greens,&quot; he predicted.</p>
<p>Die Welt said it was not just the SPD who should worry about the Stuttgart result.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that the Greens conquered the Konstanz town hall and just missed in Stuttgart by a hair's breadth must give not just the SPD but also the CDU pause for thought,&quot; it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
