<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184062" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK union leader welcomes working hour ruling.</title>
<headline>UK union leader welcomes working hour ruling.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>John Monks, general secretary of Britain's Trades Union Congress (TUC), on Tuesday welcomed the decision of the European Court of Justice to reject Britain's challenge to a European Union law on working hours.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this is very good news for British workers... This is a major contribution by the European Union,&quot; Monks told the BBC.  </p>
<p>In a separate statement issued by the TUC, Monks accused Prime Minister John Major of blackmailing the European Union over the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;By threating to interrupt the IGC (the running EU inter-governmental conference), Mr Major is blackmailing the rest of Europe because his government cannot accept defeat graciously,&quot; Monks said.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously, the TUC welcomes the government's announcement that it will consult on how best to implement the directive, but we doubt their sincerity and will keep a close eye on their progress,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>A spokesman for the TUC, the main UK union confederation, said three affiliated unions were preparing test cases in the event of the government refusing to implement the directive.</p>
<p>The country's biggest union, UNISON, which organises workers in public services, will lead the way. General union GMB and MSF, which organises amongst professional and managerial staff, are also planning court action, if necessary.</p>
<p>Monks said the directive was flexible and would, in fact, boost productivity. &quot;As good employers already know, a workforce that is treated well is more productive that an exploited and exhausted one.&quot;  </p>
<p>Britain is the only EU country where workers have no legal right to paid annual leave. According to TUC data, 2.5 million British workers -- 12 percent of the workforce -- have no paid holidays. These people will, from November 23, be entitled to three weeks paid leave, rising to four weeks in 1999.</p>
<p>The directive limits the working week to an average of 48 hours over any four-month period, although many exemptions are allowed.</p>
<p>Some 31 percent of full-time employees in Britain work 46 hours per week or more, against nine percent in France and six percent in Germany, again according to the TUC.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
