<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184027" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Adidas CEO says erred on U.S. basketball campaign.</title>
<headline>Adidas CEO says erred on U.S. basketball campaign.</headline>
<byline>John Gilardi</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief executive of Germany's Adidas AG, seeking to break into the U.S. basketball market, said on Tuesday he believed the sports brand had erred in its marketing strategy for the lucrative sport.</p>
<p>&quot;If I had to do it again, maybe I would have approached the stars and then developed the product,&quot; Adidas Chief Executive Robert Louis-Dreyfus told Reuters in an interview. &quot;We made a mistake with hindsight&quot; in doing the reverse.</p>
<p>Louis-Dreyfus inherited the strategy -- which was to create products and then seek sports endorsements -- when he took control of the then-troubled sports brand in December 1991.</p>
<p>Adidas announced in August that it was again seeking to make inroads into the massive U.S. basketball shoe market against rivals Nike and Reebok with the launch of a new high-tech shoe.</p>
<p>The shoe, called the Equipment Top Ten 2000, was launched with a $20 million campaign developed by Leagas Delaney.</p>
<p>The shoe is endorsed by Kobe Bryant, a first-round draft pick last year in the National Basketball Association who opted to head straight to the NBA from high school.</p>
<p>&quot;It was absolutely the right thing to do but maybe we should have signed a Kobe Bryant two years ago,&quot; Louis-Dreyfus said about signing Bryant to an endorsement contract.</p>
<p>Although sales of the new shoe -- linked to Adidas' &quot;Feet You Wear&quot; shoes designed to mirror the foot -- were very strong, he said overall basketball shoe sales were weak.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had some bad categories in the states and basketball is not doing well,&quot; he said. &quot;With basketball, we will be down against last year's levels.&quot;</p>
<p>Adidas is predicting growth in the number of shoes sold and sees 20 percent growth in the number of textile pieces sold in North America.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not as quick as I would like but it is still doing well,&quot; he said about North American sales, while also repeating his goal for $1.5 billion in sales by 2000.</p>
<p>The sports brand, well known for its three-stripe logo, has seen its overall U.S. market sales surge in recent years, moving up to No. 3 last year behind Nike and Reebok with its sales of $680 million from No. 8 three years ago.</p>
<p>Louis-Dreyfus also said Adidas would still follow its &quot;guerrilla campaign&quot; strategy of targeting specific areas of North America with specialised advertising to attract customers instead of broad-market campaigns used by its rivals.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we are a year-and-a-half away from dropping the guerrilla tactics,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the states where you have big stores, we are only in 50 percent of their stores. To go with a full blown attack, we need to be in 70 to 80 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
