<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184248" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China Nationalist Party replaces murdered chairman.</title>
<headline>China Nationalist Party replaces murdered chairman.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has replaced the murdered leader of a political party whose death in February shocked the nation and led to the fall of a protege of President Jiang Zemin, the Xinhua news agency said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It said the Revolutionary Committee of the Chinese Kuomintang elected on Monday parliamentary adviser He Luli as its new chairwoman, filling the post left empty by the murder of Li Peiyao on February 2.</p>
<p>Remnants of the Nationalist Party, or Kuomintang, stayed behind in China and formed the Chinese Kuomintang at the end of the Chinese civil war in 1949 which saw Chiang Kai-shek's defeated Nationalists flee into exile in Taiwan.</p>
<p>The Chinese Kuomintang is funded by the Communist Party and its members are viewed as turncoats by Taiwan's Nationalists.</p>
<p>China gives a handful of minor parties, such as the Chinese Kuomintang, a nominal role in advising on policy matters to back its claim that it tolerates multi-party democracy.</p>
<p>China in May executed an 18-year-old paramilitary policeman for murdering Li, who was also one of 19 vice-chairmen of the standing committee of the National People's Congress, or parliament.</p>
<p>Zhang Jinlong of the People's Armed Police (PAP) was executed for stabbing Li to death after the 63-year-old Li caught him burglarising his home in Beijing.</p>
<p>Xinhua referred to the murder only as &quot;Li's unfortunate death&quot;.</p>
<p>Li's murder led to the removal of Major General Ba Zhongtan as head of the 800,000-strong PAP, whose tasks include guarding dignitaries and quelling riots.</p>
<p>Ba's fall was seen as a political blow to his sponsor, state president and Communist Party chief Jiang.</p>
<p>Li's replacement, 62-year old He Luli, is the daughter of He Siyuan, Beijing's last mayor before the fall of the Nationalists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
