<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184334" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul shrs end sharply higher on boosting talks.</title>
<headline>Seoul shrs end sharply higher on boosting talks.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks closed sharply higher on Tuesday on the strength of lingering market talk on government boosting steps, brokers said.</p>
<p>The composite stock index ended 3.15 percent, or 23.01 points, higher at a provisional 752.54.</p>
<p>The rumoured steps include cutting a tax on securities transactions, providing tax incentives to long-term stockholders and increasing the return on customer deposits at brokerage houses, brokers said.</p>
<p>Samsung Electronics gained 2,900 won to 66,900 on news that the U.S. semiconductor book-to-bill ratios rose in October.  </p>
<p>Volume totalled 28.09 million shares, compared with 21.8 million on Monday.</p>
<p>Gainers outpaced losers 858 to 90 with 62 unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's rise is the highest this year. It showed sentiment has firmed,&quot; said Choo Hee-yup of Dongwon Securities.</p>
<p>The previous highest rise was 2.84 pecent or 22.64 points on September 4. Brokers said rumours of boosting measures and the belief that the market has bottomed boosted sentiment dramatically today.</p>
<p>Finance ministry officials refused to confirm whether the ministry was working on such measures.  </p>
<p>But the finance ministry has said it would be difficult to announce boosting measures because Seoul is committed to joining the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development.</p>
<p>Shares of Samsung Electronics were also boosted by the announcement that the company had begun test production of its version of Digital Equipment Corp's Alpha microprocessor.</p>
<p>The Korea Stock Exchange said the market would open 30 minutes later than usual on Wednesday due to expected traffic congestion as a result of the first round of university entrance exams.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the market would maintain much of the upbeat mood in Wednesday's morning trading.</p>
<p>&quot;But profit-taking is likely to emerge at any noticeable rises as market fundamentals still remain weak,&quot; said Kim Heung-shik, a broker at Hyundai Securities.</p>
<p>Brokers cited an oversupply of stocks, an overhang of loans for margin trading and a gloomy economic outlook as market dampening factors.</p>
<p>--KIM MYONG-HWAN (822) 727 5645</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
