<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18458" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-SERIOUS MEDVEDEV IS HAVING FUN AGAIN.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-SERIOUS MEDVEDEV IS HAVING FUN AGAIN.</headline>
<byline>Richard Finn</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Outspoken Andrei Medvedev exchanged his reputation as the clown prince of tennis on Wednesday for a new no-nonsense attitude that has made life on the courts fun again.</p>
<p>&quot;I think I'm much more focused on what I have to do, and that's playing tennis,&quot; Medvedev said after routing Frenchman Jean-Philippe Fleurian 6-2 6-0 6-1 in the opening round of the U.S. Open.</p>
<p>It was Medvedev's sixth victory in a row after winning his first tournament of the year last week at the Hamlet Cup.</p>
<p>&quot;I realised this year, that without putting 99.9 percent of your mind into tennis, I don't think you can successful,&quot; said the 22-year-old Medvedev.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole day I'm thinking abnout tennis. I felt that all the other things I was doing the years before, they were distracting me, they were not helping me at all.&quot;</p>
<p>For Medvedev that meant confining his post-match comments to tennis and not going off on tirades about about peripheral issues such as the poor quality of food in the players lounge, an entertaining rant that took his mind off the task at hand.</p>
<p>&quot;I know what I'm here for,&quot; said Medvedev, who lost in the second round of the Open the last two years after reaching the quarters in 1993, the same year he tried his hand as a restaurant critic.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not here to fight the press or talk about the food or entertain the people off the court. I'm here to play tennis and to win. I have much less fun off the court. I have much more fun on the court,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Just three years ago Medvedev was one of the world's best, with a ranking of six after reaching the French Open semifinal and winning three tournaments.</p>
<p>But Medvedev's ranking slowly began to drop last year as he struggled with a wrist injury. The Ukrainian finally hit a low of 44th two months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It's somewhere where I wouldn't like to stay very long,&quot; Medvedev said of his current ranking of 36. &quot;It's a part of the penalty that I have to accept.&quot;</p>
<p>As part of his new businesslike approach, Medvedev hired Australian coach Bob Brett at the start of this year and the partnership is beginning to pay off.</p>
<p>&quot;At the beginning of the year we started from zero,&quot; said Medvedev. &quot;Winning in Long Island (last week) was like winning for the first time.&quot;</p>
<p>While Medvedev's 77-minute romp past Fleurian was rather ordinary, the fact that the two were playing each other was rather remarkable. In the original draw, Medvedev and Fleurian were slotted to play each other. When controversy forced the draw to be done over -- against odds of 151-to-1 -- Medvedev and Fleurian drew each other a second time.</p>
<p>&quot;When I saw the new draw I didn't have to change my preparation,&quot; Medvedev said. &quot;I think it's destined that it turned out for me.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
