<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184677" id="root" date="1996-11-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Nov 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Nov 12.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- Egypt said to hold missing Israeli Azam Azam for spying.</p>
<p>- Hebron deal possible in days, says Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai.</p>
<p>- Mordechai: Army considers missing soldier Sharon Edri as being held hostage.</p>
<p>- Cairo economic parley opens today.</p>
<p>- Trade deficit breaks $9 billion barrier in first 10 months.</p>
<p>- Africa-Israel's new owner Lev Leviev sees active role at company.</p>
<p>- Teva Pharmaceutical Industries profits up 21.5 percent in third quarter.</p>
<p>- Rafael workers angry at decision to make it a state company.</p>
<p>- Knesset approves 9.7 percent water price hike for farmers.</p>
<p>- Bezeq launches universal Internet access.</p>
<p>- Insurers appoint complaints officers.</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Treasury Director-General David Brodett says he hopes that by the year 2000 the banking establishment in Israel will be privately owned.</p>
<p>- Yuli Ofer in negotiations to participate in establishing power stations in India with investment of billions of dollars.</p>
<p>- Vote on raising the minimum wage won't be brought to a vote in the Knesset during the next two weeks.</p>
<p>- In letter to IMF, industrialists head Dan Propper attacks report on Israel.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- Economic conference opens today in Cairo; Egypt will focus on cooperation among Arabs. Americans hope to clinch agreement on Hebron redeployment before Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu leaves for U.S. on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>- Lebanese newspaper claims: missing Israeli airman will be freed soon in return for Moslem clergymen Dirani and Obeid held by Israel.</p>
<p>- &quot;Israel 2000&quot; programme of the prime minister's office will be presented to local council heads; director-general Avigdor Lieberman initiates transfer of two million dunams of land from regional councils to development towns.</p>
<p>- Ultra-Orthodox neighbourhood in Bet Shemesh heights to be built on dozens of burial caves which were destroyed.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak: Complete the Hebron agreement immediately. Israeli intention to renew talks at a high level -- and reach an agreement quickly.</p>
<p>- Major-General Oren Shahor to be released soon from army duty.</p>
<p>- Cairo: The Israeli who was arrested &quot;a Mossad agent&quot;.</p>
<p>- Proposal being discussed: Giving the &quot;Little Triangle&quot; to the Palestinians -- for settlements.</p>
<p>- Yehoshua Matza to be appointed health minister and Tsachi Hanegbi to be made justice minister.</p>
<p>- New Tel Aviv municipality sticker: Here we don't speak on cell phones.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Egypt: We arrested &quot;a spy for the Mossad&quot;. Israel: A libel.</p>
<p>- Netanyahu ready to promise Palestinian President Yasser Arafat in writing a continuation of Oslo agreement.</p>
<p>- Commentator Nahum Barnea writes that in five months Netanyahu has accomplished almost nothing. Instead of making the tough decisions, he travels to the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
