<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18461" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-EDBERG NOT READY TO GO JUST YET.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-EDBERG NOT READY TO GO JUST YET.</headline>
<byline>Bill Berkrot</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tennis star Stefan Edberg may be playing his last Grand Slam at the U.S. Open, but he's not quite ready to say farewell just yet.</p>
<p>&quot;What I'm really aiming to do here this week is hopefully get into the second week and be around,&quot; said the Swedish fan favourite after a swift 6-3 6-3 6-3 first-round upset of fifth-seeded Wimbledon champion Richard Krajicek.</p>
<p>&quot;On paper it's a little upset, I would say, not a huge one,&quot; the former world number one, who is now ranked 28th, said with a sly grin and a shake of his blond head.</p>
<p>The low-key 30-year-old is remarkably relaxed and feeling right at home on the U.S. Open's stadium court these days as his glorious Grand Slam career winds down.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment I'm actually feeling very, very calm about the whole thing,&quot; said Edberg, who early in his career was not a big fan of New York's Grand Slam.</p>
<p>&quot;I found this place very, very tricky to come to,&quot; he said of his early U.S. Open campaigns.</p>
<p>That changed forever in 1991 when the smooth Swede put together the first of his back-to-back title runs.</p>
<p>&quot;Always when you've won at the place, the whole place just changes, no question about it,&quot; said Edberg, who considers his straight sets win over Jim Courier in the '91 final to be the best tennis he ever played.</p>
<p>&quot;Since then, I've enjoyed every year coming here. It's been one of the very special places to come to,&quot; added Edberg, who also has two Wimbledon and two Australian Open titles.</p>
<p>But Edberg has no regrets about his decision to make this U.S. Open the 54th and last Grand Slam of his career.</p>
<p>&quot;Knowing when you're going to retire, I think that makes it easier,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't really want to hang around playing tennis out there if I can't perform the way I want to perform,&quot; he continued.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to be in the top 10 and really have a chance to win a Grand Slam. Those years are pretty much over.</p>
<p>&quot;I've been on the tour for many, many years. It's time for me to go now before it's too late.&quot;</p>
<p>And if he should surprise himself and delight the fans by winning the U.S. Open one more time, might he change his mind about retiring?</p>
<p>&quot;No I will not,&quot; he said, smiling at the idea. &quot;I'm so sorry.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Being realistic, there is a very little chance, but as long as I see that chance, I will go out there and do what I can.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
