<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184770" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Group tries diamond sellers' strategy with gems.</title>
<headline>Group tries diamond sellers' strategy with gems.</headline>
<byline>Candace Talmadge</byline>
<dateline>DALLAS</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taking a page from successful consumer promotions for diamonds, gold and platinum, the International Coloured Gemstone Association has launched the coloured gemstone industry's first consumer marketing effort.</p>
<p>Four-page, full-colour inserts kicked off a tony advertising and special events campaign to promote rubies to upscale U.S. jewelry buyers.</p>
<p>The ICA's 1996 budget, earmarked solely for the United States, is $500,000. By comparison, DeBeers spends $400 million annually on diamond promotion worldwide.</p>
<p>The ICA ads are running in November and December issues of Town &amp; Country and Departure magazines. They were designed and produced by Brown Productions, a Dallas-based direct marketing agency that specialises in fine jewelry.</p>
<p>Television advertising &quot;is not out of the question&quot;in the future, said Cheryl Kremkow, ICA gem bureau director.</p>
<p>The current magazine-based effort also includes a travelling exhibit of unique ruby jewelry for joint local promotions with high-end retailers in six U.S. markets, including Ben Bridge Jeweller in Seattle; Fortunoff, The Source, New York; Hyde Park of Aspen, Aspen, Colo.; Lee Michaels, Metairie, La.; Neiman Marcus, Dallas; and Schwarzschild Jewellers, Richmond, Va.</p>
<p>The marketing problem for the New York-based ICA is the wide variety of coloured gemstones, which range from rubies, emeralds and sapphires to stones such as jade, amethyst and turquoise.</p>
<p>Unlike diamonds or gold, there is no standard grading system for coloured gemstones. As a result, it won't be possible to build brand image or equity for coloured gemstones in the same way DeBeers has done for diamonds, said Stephen Magner, vice president for precious jewels at Dallas-based Neiman Marcus.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Magner praised the ICA effort. He said the advertising will provide exposure for coloured stones and help build consumer awareness of coloured gemstones as a jewelry alternative. According to a recent survey of U.S. consumers by the Jewellers of America, 61 percent of respondents chose diamonds as their favourite gemstone, while just 10 percent cited emeralds, 9 percent chose sapphires and 7 percent picked rubies.</p>
<p>Kremkow said the ICA decided to promote only one coloured stone per year in order to focus the consumer message and track the results of what she called a pilot marketing effort.</p>
<p>Although she would not say which coloured gemstone the ICA plans to promote in 1997, she did say that ICA members ranked emeralds along with rubies as the two most important coloured gemstones in a survey conducted prior to the development of the initial campaign.</p>
<p>She also said consumer marketing for a costly coloured gemstone such as the ruby has become feasible due to the opening five years ago of a ruby mine in the Mong Hsu region of Myanmar, known formerly as Burma.</p>
<p>Kremkow said the Mong Hsu mine has transformed the world ruby market by producing lots of quality rubies of smaller size and thus greater affordability.</p>
<p>Unlike DeBeers, the ICA does not own any gem mines directly. It relies instead on pooled funding from producer countries such as Thailand for rubies and Colombia for emeralds, as well as its members: miners, cutters and wholesalers in 38 countries.</p>
<p>Kremkow said the ICA will track the results of the 1996 campaign by using U.S. Commerce Department reports on the amount of loose rubies imported into the United States during 1996 compared with the previous year. She also said the ICA will ask members and retailers about their sales of rubies to assess the effectiveness of the campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;It's our job to show that this can work,&quot; she said, predicting that there will be an increase in loose ruby imports to the United States and in ruby jewelry sales due to the effort.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
