<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="184882" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAB SAYS MAY MULL INVESTMENT CHANGES.</title>
<headline>SAB SAYS MAY MULL INVESTMENT CHANGES.</headline>
<byline>Paul Harris</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Breweries Ltd (SAB), the world's fourth biggest brewer, said on Wednesday it may consider reshuffling its portfolio of diversified interests.</p>
<p>Earlier the firm posted half year results that just pipped analysts' expectations. But the market had been nervous about the results as some of SAB's investments outside its beer businesses had been showing signs of faltering.</p>
<p>Retailer Edgars Stores , Coca-Cola bottler ABI and glass-maker Plate Glass and Shatterprufe Industries Ltd all posted lower-than-expected interim earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;In any portfolio, especially one as big as ours, there are always ones (investments) that come in and go out,&quot; deputy chairman Selwyn MacFarlane told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>MacFarlane said there was no reshuffle currently planned, but all busineses would be judged on their ability to compete on international terms.</p>
<p>MacFarlane said that the investments had performed no worse than other firms in their sectors and added the results were due to a fall in consumer confidence and a slowdown in the South African economy at large.</p>
<p>The period saw group earnings per share of 185.2 cents, up from 162.5, and a dividend hiked to 65 cents a share from 57 cents.</p>
<p>The growth was mainly due to another good performance from the firm's core beer operations, especially its international businesses.</p>
<p>MacFarlane said the beer market was proving robust in the face of the harder economic times, but was not escaping unscathed, especially among lower income groups.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no doubt that lower income consumers have been pressurised. That is a big sector of our consumers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Outside South Africa SAB has interests in southern Africa, central and eastern Europe and China and recently launched a $413 million international share issue to raise funds for its overseas expansion.</p>
<p>It is also expanding its exporting operations into places like Russia and Latin America, which is now its biggest export market outside Africa.</p>
<p>SAB is also the largest brewer in Poland, Hungary and Romania and is seeking out further buying opportunities in other privatising economies in the area such as Bulgaria.</p>
<p>&quot;We constantly look at these places,&quot; MacFarlane said, but added no specific talks were being held at the moment.</p>
<p>The group is also looking to spread into more African countries outside its current interests of Zambia, Zimbabwe, Tanzania and Mozambique.</p>
<p>The focus of the hunt is on East Africa, as the West African market is seen as already well served by French-dominated brewing concerns. &quot;We are exploring other countries on the east coast (of Africa),&quot; MacFarlane said. </p>
<p>SAB controls a massive 97 percent of its home market through brands such as Castle. MacFarlane said the firm would grow organically and that sales volumes were expected to show a yearly jump of 3-4 percent in the medium term.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
