<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18489" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: ATHLETICS-CHRISTIE AND JOHNSON ASKED TO JOIN OWENS' TRIBUTE.</title>
<headline>ATHLETICS-CHRISTIE AND JOHNSON ASKED TO JOIN OWENS' TRIBUTE.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Organisers hope to persuade Britain's former Olympic 100 metres champion Linford Christie to join a &quot;Dream Team&quot; sprint relay in a special tribute to Jesse Owens at Friday's Berlin grand prix.</p>
<p>Christie, who is retiring from international competition at the end of the season, was not due to compete in the German capital but Berlin promoter Rudi Thiel said: &quot;We are still hopeful of getting him to come.&quot;</p>
<p>Thiel has managed to get most of the Olympic 100 metres champions since 1948 to attend the meeting, which is being held in the stadium where Owens won four gold medals 60 years ago at the Berlin Olympics.</p>
<p>Canada's Donovan Bailey, the Olympic 100 metres champion and world record holder, and Namibian Frankie Fredericks, the silver medallist at the recent Atlanta Games, have already agreed to run in the 4X100 metres team.</p>
<p>Thiel said on Wednesday that he had also asked Olympic 200 and 400 champion Michael Johnson to run as well as Christie.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of the Olympic champions of the past are coming including Britain's (1980 champion) Allan Wells. Christie belongs to them. It would be great to have him here.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a good offer....My minimum would be that he just ran the relay,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 36-year-old Briton is still considering the offer and is expected to announce his decision later on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Owens's widow Ruth is not well enough to attend but a message from her will be read out during the meeting and one of the sprinter's relatives is expected to attend.</p>
<p>The relay race, which will include squads from Africa, the United States and Europe as well as the Owens' quartet, will be held at the end of the meeting.</p>
<p>Organisers had hoped to include 1984 and 1988 champion Carl Lewis in the squad but he injured himself in Brussels last Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
