<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185253" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electric futures seen opening flat to lower.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electric futures seen opening flat to lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures were called to open flat to lower Wednesday, continuing recent weakness in power and natural gas prices in the western U.S. due to persistent mild weather.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see how it's going to stay up,&quot; said a Houston trader.</p>
<p>In early over-the-counter (OTC), December Palo Verde (PV) futures were talked at $20.60-$21.00 a megawatt hour (MWh) against a Tuesday settlement of $21.05. December OTC California-Oregon Border (COB) futures were discussed at $22.25-$23.50 versus a close of $23.05.</p>
<p>December natgas delivered to the San Juan/Blanco Hub was last quoted near $2.35 per million British thermal units, flat from late Tuesday's quote.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather forecast is bearish for the next two weeks,&quot; said a New York-based broker.</p>
<p>For Thursday, the Pacific Northwest was forecast to experience temperatures peaking in 40s-50s Fahrenheit range and bottoming in the 20s-40s, while the Southwest peaking in 60s-80s and bottoming in 30s-50s.</p>
<p>Extended outlook indicated Northwest's temperatures would stay near seasonal norms through Friday with clouds and showers moving into the region. Southwest's weather would be normal to above-normal through Friday.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk 212-859-1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
