<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185332" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Oct PPI shows wholesale prices in check.</title>
<headline>U.S. Oct PPI shows wholesale prices in check.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The October U.S. Producer Price Index, whose overall gain exceeded economists' forecasts but whose core dropped unexpectedly, showed wholesale prices were moderate in the first month of the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>The headline 0.4 percent rise in the total PPI startled the bond market, which had anticipated a gain of 0.2 percent or at most, 0.3 percent.</p>
<p>The second headline on the wholesale price data, reporting that the core PPI had fallen 0.3 percent when many economists had expected a rise of 0.1 percent, briefly buoyed prices.  </p>
<p>A couple of minutes after the data were released, the 6-1/2 percent 30-year bond was up 8/32 of a point.</p>
<p>That gain proved momentary, however.</p>
<p>A 1.6 percent drop in passenger car prices, the biggest decline in two years, contributed to the decline in the core PPI. Economists note that car prices at this time of year, when new models are introduced, tend to be volatile.</p>
<p>Other elements of the report favorable for the credit markets were an unchanged reading in the overall price index and a 0.1 percent decline in the core index at the intermediate stage of production.  </p>
<p>At the early, crude stage of production, the October PPI fell 0.6 percent, reflecting a recent fall in energy prices.</p>
<p>The core PPI, the index without its food and energy components, rose a more robust 0.3 percent at the crude stage of production.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very favorable report,&quot; said Marilyn Schaja, economist at Donaldson, Lufkin &amp; Jenrette. &quot;We know energy prices have already come down from highs reached in October. And food prices, if anything, are coming down. So it's even more important this month to disregard the rise in the total PPI and to focus on the core which is down 0.3 percent.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
