<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185443" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Execs may seek proxies for Universal slate.</title>
<headline>Execs may seek proxies for Universal slate.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Texas-based executives said they holds a 5.17 percent stake in Universal Seismic Associates Inc and may seek shareholder proxies to elect its own slate of directors of the company.</p>
<p>Michael Kanarellis, president of Technoflex Inc, a Houston-based marketing services firm and Robert Kecseg, an analyst at Irving, Texas,-based First Research Financial Inc, said they have agreed to act as a group in light of Universal's deteriorating financial and stock performance.</p>
<p>The executives hold 263,000 common shares in Universal, a Houston-based oil exploration services company.  </p>
<p>The executives said they are &quot;dissatisfied&quot; with the company for its apparent failure to carry out a complete review of a letter of intent for the company to merge with Suelopetrol C.A., of Venezuela.</p>
<p>Such a failure, they said, has &quot;seriously jeopardized&quot; the likelihood the merger would go through. The merger, they said, &quot;is essential for the company's future viability.&quot;</p>
<p>The executives said they are considering seeking a court order to compel the Universal board to call an annual meeting of shareholders. It said it may also seek a call for a special meeting to remove at least a majority of the current board members.</p>
<p>If they succeed in replacing the board, they would recommend that the company resume negotiations with Suelopetrol and seek to complete a deal with the Venezuelan company on favorable terms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
