<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185486" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-PADRES' CAMINITI UNANIMOUS NATIONAL LEAGUE MVP.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-PADRES' CAMINITI UNANIMOUS NATIONAL LEAGUE MVP.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>San Diego Padres third baseman Ken Caminiti, who helped lead his team to its first division title in 12 years, became the fourth unanimous choice as National League Most Valuable Player on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Caminiti was voted first on all 28 ballots from a panel of members of the Baseball Writers Association of America.</p>
<p>Caminiti, who led the charge that put the Padres over the top in the National League West, hit .326 and posted club records with 40 homers and 130 runs batted in. He was third in the National League in RBI, tied for fifth in homers and sixth in batting.</p>
<p>The 33-year-old Caminiti is the eighth third baseman to win the award and the first-ever Padre. San Diego's Bruce Bochy won the National League Manager of the Year award last week.</p>
<p>Los Angeles Dodgers catcher Mike Piazza (237 points) and Colorado Rockies outfielder Ellis Burks (186) were second and third, and were the only others named on all 28 ballots. Fourteen points are given for first place, nine for second, eight for third and down to one for 10th.</p>
<p>Piazza was the Dodgers' offensive focal point, batting .336 with 36 homers and 105 RBI. He was third in the league in hitting, tied for ninth in homers and 16th in RBI for a team that hit just .252, but still made the post-season.</p>
<p>Burks, who stayed healthy for the first time since joining Colorado in 1994, exploded for 40 homers and 128 RBI with a .344 batting average. He also topped the league with 142 runs scored and a .639 slugging percentage, finished in the top five in batting average (second), doubles (second), RBI (fifth), homers (tied for fifth) and triples (tied for fifth).</p>
<p>Atlanta Braves third baseman Chipper Jones was fourth with 158 points, outfielder Barry Bonds of the San Francisco Giants was fifth (132), while Rockies first baseman Andres Galarraga and Florida Marlins outfielder Gary Sheffield tied for sixth (112).</p>
<p>Jones hit .309 with 30 homers and 110 RBI. Bonds, a three-time N.L. MVP, hit .308 with 42 homers, 40 steals and 129 RBI. Galarraga batted .304 and led the league with 47 homers and 150 RBI, both career highs. Sheffield hit .314 with a career-high 42 homers and 120 RBI.</p>
<p>Caminiti joined Jeff Bagwell of the Houston Astros (1994), Mike Schmidt of the Philadelphia Phillies (1980) and Orlando Cepeda of the St. Louis Cardinals (1967) as the only unanimous National League MVPs.</p>
<p>The American League MVP will be named Thursday. Cleveland Indians outfielder Albert Belle, Seattle Mariners shortstop Alex Rodriguez and Texas Rangers outfielder Juan Gonzalez are the leading contenders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
