<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185491" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BOXING-TOP TRAINER IS CLOTHING COMPANY SPOKESMAN.</title>
<headline>BOXING-TOP TRAINER IS CLOTHING COMPANY SPOKESMAN.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boxing in recent years has not been a favourite of many corporate sponsors, but just days after one of the biggest nights of the sport when Evander Holyfield upset Mike Tyson a clothing manufacturer introduced one of the sport's top trainers as its spokesman on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Teddy Atlas, who very early in his career trained a young Tyson and last Saturday guided Michael Moorer on the Holyfield-Tyson card to successfully retain his International Boxing Federation title against South African Francois Botha, now is a spokesman for a new line of Everlast clothing.</p>
<p>The new line of gym clothes is dubbed &quot;The Power of One&quot;, and for once it seems a corporation actually may have accurately fit the advertising pitch with the spokesman.</p>
<p>Atlas is known as probably the best motivator in boxing and strongly believes in his fighters finding the power within themselves to win, often with more than a little prodding from him.</p>
<p>Atlas has a one-year contract with Garen Incorporated, which bought the license to use the Everlast name -- long associated with boxing -- and introduced its new line with a fashion show, using a variety of boxers and kickboxers as models for a variety of sweatpants, sweatshirts and T-shirts.</p>
<p>Many people give Atlas a large degree of the credit for taking Moorer to a decision over Holyfield two years ago after gambling that Moorer would respond positively to Atlas grabbing his fighter's stool between rounds and threatening to fight Holyfield himself. Moorer reacted by upsetting Holyfield to win two of the main heavyweight titles, which he subsequently lost.</p>
<p>Again on Saturday, Moorer was less than a tiger in defending his new title. In another gambit, Atlas brought the referee over, threatening to stop the fight if Moorer would not fight better. Again Moorer responded and stopped Botha in the 12th round.</p>
<p>And typical of Atlas, who administers his own private tests for loyalty and honesty, he said of his corporate venture: &quot;This is as much a test for them as it is for me. We both want to see how it goes.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
