<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185593" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: EMU IMPACT ON CORPORATE FINANCING POSITIVE -STUDY.</title>
<headline>EMU IMPACT ON CORPORATE FINANCING POSITIVE -STUDY.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The impact on the corporate sector's financing possibilities of the planned third stage of Europe's Economic and Monetary Union is expected to be good, a Finnish employer lobby said in a statement on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The third stage of EMU is expected to affect financing possibilities favourably,&quot; the Confederation of Finnish Industry and Employers (TT) said.</p>
<p>A study among finance directors at major Finnish companies of the effects of EMU on big firms' financing and exchange rate risks commissioned by TT and the Finnish Bankers' Association found that half of respondents saw improving possibilities to issue corporate bonds, TT said.</p>
<p>A vast majority said the availability of equity financing for Finnish companies would improve once the exchange rate risk linked to the markka disappeared.</p>
<p>Nearly half of respondents expected lower margins on short-term financing.</p>
<p>Exchange rate risk management systems would be required also if Finland joined EMU and the block started using the new Euro currency, TT said.</p>
<p>&quot;Of currencies outside the EU, especially the U.S. dollar is central for corporate currency positions. The growth of (Finnish companies') sales in Asian markets will increase the importance of the U.S. dollar because in most cases products are priced in dollars on Asian markets,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;Taking the Euro into use would simplify exchange rate risk management, but would not eliminate (it),&quot; TT said.</p>
<p>Finnish companies will continue to compete with firms from other EMU countries and in this respect the level at which exchange rates will be irrevocably locked in EMU is important.</p>
<p>&quot;If the central parity exchange rates are at such levels that the production costs of a certain sector measured in the same currency are of the same size in different EU countries the move to the third stage of EMU will reduce exchange rate risk relating to most companies' competitiveness,&quot; TT said.</p>
<p>--Helsinki Newsroom +358 - 9 - 680 50 245</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
