<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185553" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: CZECHS MULL RENTING ADVANCED WESTERN FIGHTERS.</title>
<headline>CZECHS MULL RENTING ADVANCED WESTERN FIGHTERS.</headline>
<byline>Klara Gajduskova</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech Republic, strapped for cash as it prepares for NATO membership, is looking closely at renting advance western fighter aircraft or buying used units, the head of parliament's defense committee said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;In my opinion, buying new modern (fighters) by the end of the century is not a realistic plan, nor is it necessary,&quot; Petr Necas, the chairman of the Czech parliament's Defence and Security Committee told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Used ones or rented ones, that would be a different idea. I take it for a realistic plan - to rent fighters and train staff by the year 2000,&quot; Necas said.</p>
<p>The Czechs have said they would need about 24 fighters to replace their ageing Soviet made MiG-21s to be more compatible with NATO, but at more than $20 million per fighter, new western planes are too pricey.</p>
<p>The Czechs, along with the Poles and the Hungarians, are widely seen as top candidates for NATO's planned expansion to former Soviet bloc members, expected by the end of the century.</p>
<p>Necas named as companies which could rent the fighters as:</p>
<p>- U.S. McDonnell Douglas Corp which makes the F-18A &quot;Hornet&quot;, and - U.S. Lockheed Martin maker of the F-16</p>
<p>- French-based Dassault Aviation which makes the &quot;Mirage&quot;</p>
<p>- Swedish-British consortium led by Saab which makes the &quot;Gripen&quot;.</p>
<p>All of these companies have been strongly lobbying the government to buy their planes.</p>
<p>But there probably would not be a public tender for the deal as has been the Czech defense procurement procedure in the post-Communist era, Necas said.</p>
<p>&quot;I can imagine rather talks government-to-government than a pure business tender.&quot; He declined to give more details.</p>
<p>Necas said Prague will launch a &quot;parliamentary-diplomatic offensive&quot; which would establish contacts with parliaments of all NATO countries.</p>
<p>He said he expected a broad debate about NATO within the Czech political scene next year.</p>
<p>Necas said consultations with Poland and Hungary will be frequent too, but he said he did not expect a joint initiative or coordination on NATO accession plans.</p>
<p>He added that Slovakia should be in NATO so as not to leave the Czechs' former federation partner as a &quot;border country&quot; left outside the alliance.</p>
<p>Slovakia, which split with the Czech Republic in 1993, has been strongly criticised especially by the United States for dragging its feets on democratic reforms.</p>
<p>The U.S. has suggested on several occassions that the lack of full reform in Slovakia could threaten NATO membership.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our interest to have Slovakia in the same political and military structures as the Czech Republic ... it is our national interest,&quot; Necas said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640047">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
