<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185604" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices soar before U.S. stocks figures, on Iraqi news.</title>
<headline>Oil prices soar before U.S. stocks figures, on Iraqi news.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices soared on Wednesday led by U.S. heating oil demand and fuelled by comments from Iraq's ambassador to the United Nations.</p>
<p>With weekly U.S. stock figures from the American Petroleum Institute due to be released later on Wednesday and following remarks by the Iraqi ambassador to the United Nations, benchmark Brent crude gained over $1 a barrel on the day.</p>
<p>At 2052 GMT benchmark December Brent crude oil futures on London's International Petroleum Exchange (IPE) were $1.06 higher at $23.85 a barrel.</p>
<p>On Wednesday Iraq's ambassador to the United Nations in Geneva said that Iraq hoped to &quot;clear the air&quot; with the United States now that President Bill Clinton was re-elected.</p>
<p>He went on to say that Iraqi President Saddam Hussein would not sit by if he became sure there was no hope of the Gulf War sanctions being lifted.</p>
<p>&quot;I would say that President Saddam Hussein knows the details of the daily suffering of his people and that's why he will not stand by before the sanctions are lifted.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That's fighting talk,&quot; one trader of Brent crude said.</p>
<p>On the refined product markets the main focus was again the level of heating oil stocks in Europe and the United States.</p>
<p>On Tuesday IPE crude and gas oil (heating oil) prices fell after heating oil stocks in Europe showed a healthy build in October.</p>
<p>The prospect of extra supplies arriving on the Rotterdam market following the expiration of the November IPE gas oil futures contract further weighed on the oil complex.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the perception among some brokers was that most of the record 865,100 tonnes of gas oil due to be delivered into the expiring contract would be shipped out of the region.</p>
<p>December IPE gas oil responded by gaining $5.50 a tonne to $216.25.</p>
<p>But on the late gains on crude oil the December gas oil contract on the IPE was expected to open on Thursday up a further $3 a tonne.</p>
<p>Supply of crude and products was enough to meet demand in the short term, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an appreciable overhang of North Sea crude,&quot; Harris said. &quot;Apparently there is also sufficient gas oil in Europe to meet current demand,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Crude prices rocketed to near six-year highs in October, boosted by fears that low heating oil stocks on both sides of the Atlantic would fail to cover peak winter demand.</p>
<p>But refineries in the United States and Europe responded by working flat out to replenish low inventories.</p>
<p>U.S. output of distillates, which include heating oil, rose to near-20-year highs of 3.65 million barrels per day in October, the American Petroleum Institute said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Their efforts helped drag Brent back from a $25.06-a-barrel peak last month and gas oil from as high as $250.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>While the short term supply/demand balance worldwide looked more comfortable than it did a few weeks ago, traders warned against selling into the market prematurely.</p>
<p>&quot;Stocks look adequate at the moment,&quot; Mees Pierson's Harris said. &quot;But of course the market remains susceptible to cold weather.&quot;</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					   Nov 13	Nov 12</p>
<p>					   (close)    (close)</p>
<p> Dated Brent			   $23.39	$22.37</p>
<p> IPE London Brent futures (Dec)  $23.85	$22.83</p>
<p> NYMEX light crude futures (Dec) $24.05	$23.35</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
