<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185722" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Toronto stocks close softer, pulled down by golds.</title>
<headline>Toronto stocks close softer, pulled down by golds.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Toronto stocks ended easier on Wednesday, dragged lower by a sell-off in financial service issues, while the value of trading was the third-highest ever.</p>
<p>The Toronto Stock Exchange key 300 Composite Index fell 7.96 points to close at 5799.01 points, before setting a new intra-day high of 5816.40 points.</p>
<p>Trading volume was 133.2 million shares worth C$2.29 billion. The TSE's highest trading value was C$2.53 billion (US$1.9 billion), set in April 1986.</p>
<p>RBC Dominion Securities analyst Dunnery Best noted that bank stocks were retreating from their recent rally.  </p>
<p>&quot;Weaker bond markets are fueling the shift away from the interest sensitives into the more glorious investing terrain of golds and the cyclicals,&quot; Best said in a market report.</p>
<p>Ron Meisels, president of P and C Holdings Ltd, added that a pause was warranted after the TSE 300 Index added about 200 points since November 5. &quot;It would be quite normal and understandable for it to have a correction after such a robust move,&quot; Meisels said.</p>
<p>Toronto's 14 sub-indices were evenly split between rising and falling groups. Pipelines lost the most ground, followed by banks, utilities, and conglomerates.</p>
<p>Golds, base metals and communications led the gaining side.</p>
<p>Advancing issues edged out declining ones 492 to 473 while 315 traded flat.</p>
<p>--- HOT STOCKS ---</p>
<p>* Nickel giant Inco Ltd rose 1.80 to 45.95 in heavy trading while gold firm Euro-Nevada Mining Corp Ltd topped net gainers, adding 2.55 to reach 42.80.</p>
<p>* Toronto-Dominion Bank fell 0.75 to 32.65.</p>
<p>-- Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
