<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18572" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Industrial oilseeds losing importance - German firm.</title>
<headline>Industrial oilseeds losing importance - German firm.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marketing problems and declining land-set aside have lessened the role of oilseeds crops grown for industrial purposes, German crusher Oelmuehle Hamburg AG said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Farmers are losing interest in growing industrial crops and sales of oils for non-food uses are developing more slowly than hoped,&quot; Oelmuehle chairman Arnd von Wissel told a shareholders meeting.</p>
<p>The EU Farm Council in July reduced the land set-aside rate for the 1997 harvest to five percent from 10, 12 and 15 percent respectively in the most recent campaigns.</p>
<p>This will release an estimated seven to eight million tonnes of grain on to the market.</p>
<p>But under U.S./EU agreements, the oilseeds area for food and animal feed purposes is permanently fixed at 5.48 million hectares, from which 10 percent set-aside is deducted.</p>
<p>The agreements also allow production of one million ha worth of seeds where the oils are restricted to industrial applications.</p>
<p>Von Wissel said the EU had nearly reached that limit in 1995, with Germany alone accounting for 330,000 ha.</p>
<p>But farmers were now likely to focus on additional arable areas to grow lucrative grain and traditional oilseeds crops.</p>
<p>Rapeseed oil used in alternative car fuels was uncompetitive versus oil from fossil fuels, farmers were receiving less compensation for idling land and the bureaucracey surrounding biodiesel was too costly.</p>
<p>The oilseeds lobby UFOP, which promotes rape oil in fuel, oleochemical and hydraulics industry uses, has estimated the industrial rapeseed area this year will be down by 16 percent.</p>
<p>Von Wissel said biofuel sales volumes were not strong enough to support a number of specialised crushing plants.</p>
<p>Only one out of three planned biofuel projects -- Oelmuehle Leer Connemann GmbH near the Dutch/German border with an annual capacity of 80,000 tonnes -- had come on stream, in April 1996.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
