<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185793" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe stocks trade weaker in unsettled market.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe stocks trade weaker in unsettled market.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean shares were generally weaker in thin volumes on Wednesday with brokers saying the market seemed unsettled as the rainy season, which normally starts around mid-November, approaches.</p>
<p>Brokers also said continuing profit-taking mainly by foreigners had also contributed to the market's weaker trend.</p>
<p>&quot;The market looks unsettled although this may be temporary with a host of companies expected to report in the next few weeks and the commencement of the wet season (if on time) likely to ease tension,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;People are watching the sky now and we might see the market continuing to slow down, even easing, until we see rain,&quot; another one said.</p>
<p>Brokers said the current strike by state nurses and doctors which has paralysed two of the country's largest hospitals had had no impact on trade.</p>
<p>The 57-counter industrial index lost 32.04 points to close at 7,917.41, dragged down mainly by construction and plastics investor IHL's 100-cent drop to 1,800, horticulture firm Ariston's 50-cent loss to 1,450 and tobacco group TSL's 30-cent climb down to 560.</p>
<p>Also among the losers, cable manufacturer BICAF shed 30 cents to 350, pork processor Colcom was 10 cents off at 350 while discount house DCZ, tea and coffee growers EHPL and conglomerate TA eased five cents each to 180, 135 and 150 respectively.</p>
<p>Against the trend, clothing retailer Truworths rose 40 cents to 740, cement producer Circle gained 20 cents to 670, transport group Clan put on 10 cents to 270 while five-cent additions were recorded in winery Afdis to 455, pharmaceutical group Caps to 350, builders Mash to 175 and engineers Radar to 210.</p>
<p>Minings continued dull with gold producers Ashanti, Falgold and Rio Tinto trading at previous levels while copper miners Mhangura added five cents to 20.</p>
<p>Nickel company Bindura shed 10 cents to 365 and Wankie Colliery lost 20 cents to 1,030, leaving the seven-counter mining index 14.08 points down at 1,211.36.</p>
<p>-- Emelia Sithole, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
