<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185875" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: FOCUS - Czech PM won't hurry big bank privatisation.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Czech PM won't hurry big bank privatisation.</headline>
<byline>Jan Lopatka</byline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Czech Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus said on Wednesday that there was no reason to hurry the privatisation of the country's four largest banks.</p>
<p>&quot;(The privatisation) does not have any exceptional level of urgency,&quot; Klaus told a news conference after a cabinet meeting.</p>
<p>He said the cabinet would wait until the central bank submitted a more complete plan to the cabinet for the privatisation of the remaining state shares in the large banks.</p>
<p>&quot;It is irrelevant if it is two or three weeks later or two or three weeks sooner,&quot; Klaus said.</p>
<p>The central bank and the finance ministry have both called for the rapid privatisation of the state's roughly one-third stake in Investicni a Postovni Banka a.s. to a strategic foreign partner.</p>
<p>Japan-based investment bank Nomura and Dutch ING Bank NV are both said to have a strong interest in the IPB stake.</p>
<p>The Czech National Bank, the central bank, also has called for the merger of the largest savings bank Ceska Sporitelna a.s., with the foreign trade bank Ceskovslovenska Obchodni Banka a.s..</p>
<p>If the merger goes ahead, forming a bank with 540 billion crowns ($20.16 billion) in assets based on end-1995 results, the plan would be to privatise the new megabank several years later.</p>
<p>Klaus has balked at the merger plan, saying that it was akin to merging Prague's two top soccer clubs, Sparta and Slavia, which would be hard for Czechs to imagine.</p>
<p>The prime minister has reacted favourably in recent weeks to news that Nomura was keen to buy the state's stake in IPB.</p>
<p>At the news conference Klaus bristled at a series of questions on the subject by foreign news agencies. When asked specifically about the timing of IPB's privatisation Klaus said: &quot;I don't know if this is the question of some lobbyist who wants to buy some bank fast, or really the general interest of a journalist.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;From the point of view of the first (case),&quot; he continued, &quot;then I think that a party interested in buying or who instigates you into this question is probably in a hurry.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003 ($1=26.78 Czech Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
