<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185801" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire offers &quot;flexibility&quot; on refugee aid.</title>
<headline>Zaire offers &quot;flexibility&quot; on refugee aid.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire's Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo said on Wednesday his country was prepared to show &quot;flexibility&quot; to ensure that emergency food aid reached civilians and refugees fleeing a Tutsi revolt in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Kengo, speaking after talks with U.N. special envoy Raymond Chretien, said Zaire accepted the idea of a multinational force under Canadian command but stressed that protected aid corridors should be designed to ensure a return home of all refugees.  </p>
<p>&quot;In order to bring food supplies to the displaced and refugees, Zaire must be prepared to be flexible if necessary,&quot; Kengo told reporters after the 90-minute meeting.</p>
<p>Chretien paid tribute to Kengo's commitment, which followed earlier Zairean statements that any shipment of aid through rebel-held territory would violate its sovereignty.</p>
<p>&quot;It's extremely important that the Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo has expressed his willingness not to use international principles as a barrier to aiding the refugees very, very quickly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Aid efforts in the east, where Tutsi rebels control a string of Zairean towns, have been complicated by Zairean accusations of territorial violations by Tutsi-led Rwanda. The U.N. and other relief agencies transported supplies into the eastern town of Goma on Monday after negotiations with the rebels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
