<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185816" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Nov 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Nov 13.</headline>
<dateline>BLANTYRE 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Malawi press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- A Committee set up by the University of Malawi to document atrocities committed in the 30-year-old single party rule of former President Kamuzu Banda has began interviewing Jehovah's Witnesses, a religious sect whose members were persecuted in 1970s.</p>
<p>- The main opposition Malawi Congress Party (MCP) said on Tuesday the Electoral Commission has not acted on complaints of &quot;serious irregularities&quot; brought to its attention.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- The main opposition Malawi Congress Party (MCP) has threatened to take legal action against the Electoral Commission if it does not address the irregularities in campaigning at Ndirande township of Blantyre.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Aleke Banda has shown willingness to testify in court as defence witness in a defamation suit against The Democrat newspaper currently sued by former Education Minister, Sam Mpasu.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Press Corporation, the country's biggest conglomerate, has sacked the general manager for its bakery subsidiary following alleged racist remarks.</p>
<p>- A newly baby-born survived 29-hour-ordeal in a pit latrine which his 17-year-old mother tossed him in.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLANTYRE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
