<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185847" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish senator sees 1997 tax vote on Thursday.</title>
<headline>Polish senator sees 1997 tax vote on Thursday.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's upper house, the Senate, will probably vote on whether to accept the lower house's 1997 income tax bill on Thursday, a senator from the leftist ruling coalition said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Senate will most likely vote on taxes tomorrow,&quot;  the head of the Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) party in the Senate, Ryszard Jarzembowski, told Reuters late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Last month the lower house of parliament, the Sejm, unexpectedly passed a bill which envisaged the creation of a fourth income tax bracket for the lowest-paid, a scheme strongly opposed by the government.  </p>
<p>The government, which has submitted a three-tax level plan of its own involving less radical tax cuts, says the Sejm bill is unacceptable because it would increase the budget deficit and lead to higher inflation.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, Finance Minister Grzegorz Kolodko hinted the government might accept one of two alternative three-bracket income tax proposals submitted to the Senate, although it still upheld its own plan.</p>
<p>After the vote, the Senate's decision on next year's tax bill is likely to return to the Sejm for a second reading before it is sent for signature by President Aleksander Kwasniewski, who has indicated he would veto a four-level tax bill should it again be passed by the lower house.</p>
<p>The tax levels have a crucial bearing on the main proportions of next year's budget, which the Sejm starts debating on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
