<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185807" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: WFP slams proposed Zaire aid route via Kisangani.</title>
<headline>WFP slams proposed Zaire aid route via Kisangani.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. World Food Programme (WFP) on Wednesday slammed plans for a huge aid airlift through the Zairean outpost of Kisangani, saying it would be a logistical nightmare.</p>
<p>A U.N. official meanwhile said the United Nations was now playing down plans to make the route through Kisangani its main aid artery because it would be &quot;astronomically expensive&quot; even if it was approved by Kinshasa authorities.</p>
<p>Kisangani is the last outpost of tenuous Zairean authority before tens of thousands of square kilometres (miles) of forest and hills where Hutu Rwandan and Burundian refugees are hiding.</p>
<p>An alternative is to send aid in from Rwanda into rebel-held east Zaire, but Kinshasa objects and shelling in Goma on Wednesday stopped small-scale aid deliveries there.</p>
<p>&quot;We have everything set up on eastern side of Zaire. The roads in the area are in good condition. We could move in there within 72 hours with large quantities of food,&quot; said Michelle Quintaglie, a WFP spokeswoman.</p>
<p>&quot;Kisangani on the other hand is about 500 km (310 miles) from where the action is. We would have to move in a total of about 500 tonnes of food per day through Kisangani to supply refugees in those areas, let alone Zairean displaced,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>That amount of food would be enough for the 1.2 million refugees, but not the hungry local Zaireans in the area.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be a logistical nightmare. It would require a fleet of C-130s (transport planes) flying 32 rotations per day carrying 16 tonnes of food each to bring it up to 500 tonnes per day,&quot; Quintaglie added.</p>
<p>&quot;Even an airport in New York would have difficulty coping with that many daily aid flights. Plus you need the trucks to move the food and we suspect there is no large trucking concern in Kisangani,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said WFP estimated a total of 60 trucks would have to be airlifted in on a total of 60 flights and they would need petrol, spare parts, communications and support staff to keep the fleet running.</p>
<p>&quot;An old assessment indicates the roads from Kisangani are in very bad condition. It could take a week to reach Walikale, where we have heard reports there are large numbers of people,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is unfeasible for us to consider mounting a huge U.N. operation from Kisangani to feed these people. Plus Kisangani is currently considered insecure so it is hardly ideal for such a large operation,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>U.N. officials in Geneva who outlined the plans for an aid hub at Kisangani on Tuesday admitted it would cost a fortune to fly in thousands of tonnes of fuel, food, blankets and supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;Kisangani will be the main centre for distribution of aid. It will be a huge operation,&quot; said a U.N. official in Geneva.</p>
<p>&quot;Bringing food and supplies to Kisangani will create a lot of problems. That's why we are considering using military helicopters and planes,&quot; he added but gave no details.</p>
<p>U.N. refugee agency officials said emergency food and relief supplies would be airlifted to Kisangani from airports in Kenya and Uganda and then helicopters would drop food for refugees who were inaccessible by road.</p>
<p>The army commander in Kisangani told soldiers on Sunday they would be shot if they carried weapons in the streets after two nights of shooting and looting by drunk and ill-disciplined troops.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
