<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185907" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish zloty rise sparked by foreign bond buying.</title>
<headline>Polish zloty rise sparked by foreign bond buying.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty firmed against the basket of currencies in live trade on the back of a strong speculative currency-selling trend sparked by an early foreign purchase of Polish two-year bonds, dealers said.</p>
<p>They estimated the total foreign interest in Polish fixed income bonds over the last four days at around $60 million.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been growing interest in fixed Polish T-bonds on the secondary market since last Thursday ... foreigners bought roughly $60 million of the paper,&quot; said Pawel Dudzinski from PKO SA.  </p>
<p>The zloty closed at 2.29/2.26 percent from the trading band centre, stronger than yesterday's close at 2.16/2.09 percent.</p>
<p>It was at 2.8038/50 to the dollar, down from 2.7970/90 on Tuesday and at 1.8620/25 to the mark, up from 1.8690/00.</p>
<p>Dealers were mixed about a short-term outlook for the zloty with some saying it would now drop anchor between 2.2 to 2.3 percent from the parity rate.</p>
<p>&quot;The zloty is likely to trade at 2.2 to 2.3 percent from parity tomorrow,&quot; said Tomasz Nowakowski from Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>But others said it might fall back to 1.9 or 2.0 percent from parity after hitting 2.35 percent in midday today.  </p>
<p>&quot;The 2.3 percent from parity level seems unusual for the zloty. It may go back to 1.9 to 2.0 percent in the near future,&quot; said Konrad Kolasinski from Amerbank in Warsaw.</p>
<p>The central bank fixed the zloty at 2.8050 against dollar and at 1.8625 per mark, lower than the average session's rates, which could signal the zloty's weakening on Thursday.</p>
<p>Yields on the secondary T-bill market remained flat with the benchmark quoted 19.52/47 percent in a sign the firmer zloty did not spark any foreign profit-taking on T-bills.  </p>
<p>&quot;The situation on the spot forex market did not influence the T-bill market, foreigners were absent,&quot; said Krzysztof Kozuchowski from ING Bank in Warsaw.</p>
<p>Some foreign players said, however, any further investment in Polish paper was unlikely because of the zlotys' relative strength.</p>
<p>&quot;The current zloty exchange rate is strong which may put people off from buying Polish paper,&quot; a dealer at London bank said.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
