<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="185994" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Nov 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania - Nov 13.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- Romanians pay high taxes and the services they get in return are very poor.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- Romania's five regional private ownership funds are to turn into investment companies under a law recently approved by parliament, but the process is expected to take some time.</p>
<p>- Energy prices should go up in November to avoid inflationary blips, said Victor Romert, president of the electricity authority  Renel RA.</p>
<p>TINERETUL LIBER</p>
<p>- The leu currency's rate against the dollar at retail currency shops has dropped to 4,800.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- Romania has yet to announce the successful bidder for the GSM licence.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- New companies have applied for a Bucharest bourse quotation.  Electroceramica SA engineering company is expected to join in trading on November 20.</p>
<p>JURNALUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- The bourse announced mass privatisation shares in Artrom SA  could trade on its floor starting on Thursday.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- A judge in a polling station in Valcea, north-west of Bucharest, said President Ion Iliescu's Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) had already marked 200,000 ballot papers for Iliescu to be stuffed into the voting boxes on Sunday evening shortly before the downclosing of the polling stations.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- The newspaper publishes opinions by leaders of major parties after on the first face-to-face life televised debate between Iliescu and his rival Emil Constantinescu.</p>
<p>- Bucharest has turned ugly because of the illegal construction, says the city's chief architect Peter Derer in a full-page interview.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- President Ion Iliescu's latest nationalist-extremist statements against the ethnic Hungarians are an extremely serious signal for all western countries says an editorial.</p>
<p>- &quot;President Ion Iliescu is more and more alone on the political scene&quot; reads a headline listing the parties which declared their support for the opposition candidate in Sunday's presidential run-off.</p>
<p>- The newspaper publishes leaflets allegedly drafted by the PDSR warning that opposition parties which won parliamentary polls would jail all former communist party members.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- The upper house, the Senate, debates the reports drawn by a parliament commission on the December 1989 revolution.</p>
<p>- President Iliescu asks the voters to ponder two issues -- the restitution of houses and the alleged split of Romania.</p>
<p>($=3,451 lei)</p>
<p>-- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
