<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186186" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>MONGOLIA: Russia's Primakov looking to boost Mongolian ties.</title>
<headline>Russia's Primakov looking to boost Mongolian ties.</headline>
<byline>Irja Halasz</byline>
<dateline>ULAN BATOR 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov, said on Wednesday that Moscow supported Mongolia's foreign policy and pledged to improve ties between the two Soviet-era allies.</p>
<p>Russia and Mongolia, both in the throes of painful economic transitions, shared many of the same foreign policy goals and views, Primakov told reporters in Mongolia's capital Ulan Bator.</p>
<p>Both countries had enjoyed stable ties for decades and now maintained relations on a basis of equality, Primakov said.</p>
<p>Landlocked Mongolia relied on aid from Moscow for nearly 70 years until a peaceful revolution in 1990 and the collapse of the Soviet Union a year later prompted the remote nation to emerge from isolation.</p>
<p>In Mongolia's parliamentary elections in June, a democratic coalition scored an upset victory over the ruling ex-communist party and embarked on ambitious market-oriented reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;We also see that Mongolia's task in Asia is increasing,&quot; Primakov said, adding that Russia supported Mongolia's relations with China, the United States and European countries.</p>
<p>Primakov and Mongolia's Foreign Minister Altangerel signed an agreement aimed at boosting cooperation between the two foreign ministries, the two sides said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Russia and Mongolia would hold talks on the possibility of setting up free trade zones in border areas and bolstering trade ties, the statement said.</p>
<p>Mongolian-Russian trade totals about $300 million a year and is likely to increase, Primakov said.</p>
<p>Mongolia's major export item to Russia is copper concentrate while its main import is petroleum.</p>
<p>Moscow and Ulan Bator also hoped to establish relations in areas such as information, human rights, education and science, the statement said.</p>
<p>Primakov said his trip would pave the way for a visit to Mongolia by Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, possibly in January. He also invited Altangerel to visit Russia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MONGLA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ULAN BATOR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MONGOLIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
