<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186154" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Affco yr profit strong despite hard times.</title>
<headline>Affco yr profit strong despite hard times.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>AFFCO Holdings Ltd Chairman Peter Jackson said on Thursday the international market place would generate increased returns in the future and continued growth for the New Zealand meat processor.</p>
<p>AFFCO earlier reported an annual operating profit of NZ$26.5 million, 9.5 percent ahead of last year's result and 19.2 percent higher than prospectus forecasts.</p>
<p>The bottom line profit of NZ$31.9 million included a total net gain from non-operating items of NZ$5.47 million.  </p>
<p>Over the year to Septebmer, AFFCO bought Mathias International, increased its holding in the New Zealand Lamb Company (North America) and formed a joint venture in South Korea through its 50 percent associate, New Zealand Beef Japan.</p>
<p>Chief Executive Don Manson said trading conditions were difficult during the year.</p>
<p>Revenue was affected by continued low prices for beef and the high New Zealand dollar.</p>
<p>Balancing this were significant improvements in world prices for sheep meats, which were most noticeable in the second half.  </p>
<p>Looking ahead, Manson said it was clear that some early forecasts had been too conservative in their estimates of the numbers of livestock to be processed in 1996/7.</p>
<p>&quot;We also believe that there will be significant numbers of cattle carried over from the 1996 season into 1997 in the expectation that beef prices will improve over this time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Increased processing would improve the prospects for the coming year and prospects in the medium term were positive.  </p>
<p>New Zealand had a reputation as a cost-effective producer of red meats. &quot;The fact that we can produce this protein from environmentally friendly, sustainable production systems will be increasingly important to the more affluent markets,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
