<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186273" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Focus - The Future of Your Company Depends on it.</title>
<headline>Focus - The Future of Your Company Depends on it.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Fromartz</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Focus. It's something that people think about but can find hard to do, and so end up doing a little of everything but nothing exceptionally well.</p>
<p>Finding a way out of this morass isn't impossible, as long as you recognise the problem. But many businesses fail to get to this crucial first step, says a man who has made a career out of helping others focus.</p>
<p>Al Ries, a marketing consultant in Great Neck, N.Y., says he is often hired by companies who want to hear his ideas but then finds that some incessantly try to convince him that their do-everything-to-achieve-growth approach is right. It's the equivalent of flailing, he says.</p>
<p>&quot;When things are going badly, we always want to go into something that we don't know about because we always think somebody else's business is easier than ours,&quot; Ries said. &quot;I have to try and convince people that's not a good strategy.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You can get more attention if you specialise,&quot; Ries said.</p>
<p>The author of &quot;Focus: The Future of Your Company Depends on It&quot; (HarperCollins), Ries said he went through a similar exercise when he ran an advertising firm. With 70 employees and millions in bookings, Ries's turning point came when he wrote an article with a parter on &quot;positioning.&quot;</p>
<p>The thesis was that you first need to find a strategic focus and a business identity before you can construct a coherent marketing and advertising campaign. The result was that more people started calling his company for advice on positioning than for advertising.</p>
<p>With the writing on the wall, he eventually closed the advertising business and focused on his new business.</p>
<p>&quot;Sure it was scary; we didn't do it overnight either. We made a commitment two years in advance, told our employees and made the move,&quot; he said. &quot;The funny thing was that we should have done it a lot earlier.&quot;</p>
<p>He said one benefit of focusing is that you become known as the expert in a field -- you have an identity and customers know what you do.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing in advertising is that you own a word in people's mind,&quot; he said. Take Volvo, he said, which is equated with car safety, or McDonalds, which has defined fast food, or Coca-Cola, which has grown largely by emphasising one product the world over.</p>
<p>In a time when growth is paramount, the goal, he said, is not to do anything to achieve growth, but rather to hone what you do best and expand from there -- either by tweaking your basic product or service or expanding geographically.</p>
<p>Take Starbucks, with one of the most mundane products around -- coffee. It built a marketing machine around that one commodity drink and in the process transformed it into a specialised good.</p>
<p>When Starbucks expanded, it did so geographically and into goods that enhanced the underlying product: like flasks that keep coffee hot, upscale pastries and music that is soothing while taking a coffee break.</p>
<p>&quot;Entrepreneurs almost invariably have a narrow focus to start with,&quot; Ries said. But the danger they face with success is expanding beyond their basic business, looking for new and far-flung markets to conquer.</p>
<p>&quot;The process that should take place all of the time is that you should always be asking: 'Should we really do this? Should we launch this new product? What should we do to make our basic business more powerful?'</p>
<p>&quot;You think you may be better off with more varieties and doing more things. But then people get confused about what you stand for,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>(Questions or comments on the Newbiz column can be sent via E-mail to Sam.Fromartz(at)Reuters.com)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
