<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186356" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC sees Pataki workfare saving another $100 mln.</title>
<headline>NYC sees Pataki workfare saving another $100 mln.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City, which is studying Gov. George Pataki's new welfare plan, said on Wednesday that it expects to save another $100 million from its &quot;aggressive&quot; effort to put welfare recipients to work.</p>
<p>Pataki on Wednesday released his new program, needed to comply with the new federal welfare reforms that were signed into law in August, but it is not yet clear how the Assembly, which last spring thwarted the governor's reforms, will react.</p>
<p>The Assembly is controlled by Democrats and its Speaker, Sheldon Silver, D-Manhattan, is not expected to return from a vacation to China until early next week.</p>
<p>Noting that workfare gives the state gets an equal amount of savings, Richard Schwartz, a senior advisor to Republican Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, said, &quot;We must be assured that any state plan gives New York City full credit for the savings generated by the historic reforms we already implemented.&quot;</p>
<p>In his prepared statement, the city official added that New York City already had saved more than $150 million from workfare, and that the extra $100 million of savings would be achieved by June 1997. The city's iscal year ends on June 30.</p>
<p>New York City is expected to issue its first quarter modification to the budget as soon as Thursday, and there is speculation that due to a surprising surge in tax revenues, which ran around $289 million above projections, the Giuliani Administration might scale back on planned reductions.</p>
<p>While Mayor Rudolph Giuliani this summer directed city agencies to find $500 million of savings, city sources, who declined to be named, speculated that the November budget modification might include less than half that sum.</p>
<p>&quot;Less than $200 million is the gossip. The Office of Management and Budget was very disappointed by the $500 million (in cuts) they got back from the agencies,&quot; said a city source, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>He explained that the city's budget office felt a number of the cuts that were proposed were unrealistic or politically impossible to achieve. A spokeswoman for Giuliani was not immediately available to comment.</p>
<p>New York City's fiscal vulnerability under the governor's new welfare program was highlighted by the Democrat-led City Council, as well as by the City of New York Independent Budget Office, which is similar to the Congressional Budget Office.</p>
<p>The Democrat-led Council, which has estimated that as many as 245,000 people could lose their benefits in 1998 under the new federal plan, blasted aspects of Pataki's new program.</p>
<p>Council Speaker Peter Vallone, in a prepared statement, said, &quot;It appears that the governor's welfare plan is asking us to make soup out of snow.&quot; Some of the Speaker's criticisms revolved what he said was a lack of sufficient funding for day care, job skills training and job development that is needed to make welfare reforms succeed.</p>
<p>And despite Pataki's pledges to plow the state's $450 million windfall from the federal government back into public aid, the Speaker remained skeptical, fearing that the city will have to pick up the tab.</p>
<p>&quot;As we had warned, a large portion of the federal surplus New York could expect from welfare reform is being used to plug the state budget gap,&quot; Vallone wrote.</p>
<p>This concern about whether the city would get enough of the state's block grant from the federal government, estimated at $2.36 billion, was echoed by the Independent Budget Office.</p>
<p>Douglas Criscitello, director of the office, said there was real uncertainity about the share of the block grant the city would get and noted the risks the city faces if the economy does not produce enough new jobs for welfare recipients.</p>
<p>&quot;The question is can New York State generate the level of private sector jobs needed to accomplish that goal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Criscitello faulted the governor for focusing his program on the years 1997 to 1998 because most of the impact of the new federal reforms will not be felt until 1999 and beyond.</p>
<p>And the director argued that Pataki did not have to adopt the same tack as the federal law and require welfare recipients to work after collecting benefits for two years as Washington set no penalties for not meeting this standard.</p>
<p>Some parts of Pataki's reforms were praised by the City Council Speaker, like giving Medicaid benefits for one year to people who exit welfare and asking Washington to waive Food Stamp workfare requirements for the Bronx and Brooklyn.</p>
<p>Vallone, who had asked that the Food Stamp waiver apply for all of the city, reiterated this request.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
