<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186369" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Trucker who took ValuJet crash parts sentenced.</title>
<headline>Trucker who took ValuJet crash parts sentenced.</headline>
<dateline>MIAMI 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A truck driver who took parts from a crashed ValuJet airplane for souvenirs was sentenced Wednesday to six months in a halfway house, a U.S. Attorney's Office official said.</p>
<p>Michael Gadsden, of Fort Lauderdale, was arrested June 3 after an FBI investigation into reports that pieces of the DC-9 jetliner had disappeared. The plane crashed May 11 in Florida's Everglades northwest of Miami, killing all 110 people on board.</p>
<p>The FBI said a search of Gadsden's apartment turned up two aircraft parts hidden in a closet. He pleaded guilty to interfering with an accident investigation.</p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Stanley Marcus sentenced Gadsden to three years probation with a special condition that he spend six months in a community correctional centre, essentially a halfway house, the official said.</p>
<p>He also was ordered to pay a $2,000 fine and told not to work on any aircraft accident reconstruction site as a term of his probation.</p>
<p>One of the stolen parts was a piece of a circuit breaker panel from the aircraft's cockpit, considered a key to discovering the cause of the crash. But investigators said at the time of the theft that the disappearance of the parts had not slowed their investigation.</p>
<p>Gadsden was a trucker driver for Resolve Salvage &amp; Towing, which was aiding in the recovery of the airplane. In the arrest warrant, the U.S. Attorney's Office said Gadsden had confessed that he had found the parts about 12 days after the crash, and had kept them as souvenirs.</p>
<p>Gadsden had faced a 10-year prison term and a $250,000 fine. Removing parts of an aircraft involved in an accident is a federal crime.</p>
<p>ValuJet Flight 592 plunged into the Everglades shortly after takeoff on a flight to Atlanta. The plane disappeared beneath the shallow water of the mucky crash site and the ensuing recovery effort was considered one of the longest and most difficult in U.S. aviation history.</p>
<p>The official cause of the crash has not been determined, but speculation has centred on boxes of oxygen-generating canisters that were carried in the plane's cargo hold and may have sparked or fuelled a fierce fire on board.</p>
<p>The National Transportation Safety Board has scheduled hearings on the crash in Miami beginning Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MIAMI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
