<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186327" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bronco fiber in knit cap, Simpson jury told.</title>
<headline>Bronco fiber in knit cap, Simpson jury told.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>SANTA MONICA, Calif 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rare carpet fibers like those in O.J. Simpson's Ford Bronco were found on a bloody glove at his estate and inside a woollen cap left at the scene of his ex-wife's murder, an FBI expert testified on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Douglas Deedrick, an FBI hair and fiber specialist on the witness stand for a second day in Simpson's civil trial, also said cashmere fibers from the glove were found on the bloody shirt worn by Ronald Goldman, who was stabbed to death along with Nicole Brown Simpson.</p>
<p>Deedrick had testified on Tuesday that hairs matching Simpson's were found inside the knit cap at the crime scene and on Goldman's shirt.</p>
<p>The prosecution in Simpson's criminal trial was not allowed to present much of its key fiber evidence to the jury that acquitted him Oct. 3, 1995, in the murders of his ex-wife and Goldman.</p>
<p>But in the civil trial, in which Simpson faces a wrongful death suit brought by the victims' families, Judge Hiroshi Fujisaki allowed Deedrick to present his findings linking the hat and glove to Simpson's white Bronco. Legal analysts consider it to be some of the most damaging evidence against the former football star.</p>
<p>Questioned by Edward Medvene, an attorney for the plaintiffs, Deedrick was asked about fibers he found and examined from the knit cap left at the scene of the June 1994 murders at Nicole Brown Simpson's home.</p>
<p>He said they were unusual man-made fibers of a type he later established were from a type of nylon, &quot;medium mocca&quot;-coloured carpeting manufactured exclusively for Ford and used in 1992-94 model Broncos and only two other types of Ford vehicles.</p>
<p>&quot;Fiber from the Bundy hat and the Rockingham (Simpson's estate) glove matched each other,&quot; Deedrick said.</p>
<p>He said the fibers also matched fibers from three items taken from the back of Simpson's Bronco -- a shovel, a sheet of plastic and a towel. &quot;All the fibers could have originated from the same source, from the same carpet,&quot; the FBI expert said.</p>
<p>Talked through his microscopic investigation by Medvene, Deedrick said his lab later received a sample of carpet fiber from Simpson's Bronco. &quot;They all matched the known sample of carpet from Mr. Simpson's car,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under questioning, Deedrick filled in a chart for the jury showing the hairs and fibers found on each piece of evidence and how they matched.</p>
<p>He testified that the cashmere fibers and blue-black fibers were found on Goldman's shirt and also on the hat and both the gloves, one of which was dropped at the crime scene and the other found by a detective at Simpson's home.</p>
<p>&quot;They all had fibers that matched up with Ron Goldman's clothing,&quot; he said. &quot;It shows a link, it shows an association between these items and the victim.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The presence of fibers represents recent physical contact and is highly suggestive of recent contact,&quot; Deedrick said, explaining that such microscopic fibers tend not to remain in one place for long.</p>
<p>The blue-black fibers matched a sample taken from Simpson's socks, Deedrick said.</p>
<p>Simpson was not in the Santa Monica court on Wednesday. He was in a suburban Orange County courthouse fighting a custody battle with his former in-laws for the two children he had with Nicole Brown Simpson.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA MONICA, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
