<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186405" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fergie blames herself and Palace bureaucrats.</title>
<headline>Fergie blames herself and Palace bureaucrats.</headline>
<byline>Arthur Spiegelman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The disgraced Duchess of York, in her much-hyped autobiography, blames Buckingham Palace bureaucrats and even the British secret service for sabotaging her -- as a warning to Princess Diana that the same could happen to her if she does not behave.</p>
<p>But in the 306-page book published on Wednesday, called &quot;My Story,&quot; the flame-haired former Sarah Ferguson also blames herself, loneliness, a history of self-hatred, betrayals by friends and the British press for her estrangement from the Royal Family.</p>
<p>If a book can be judged by its cover, then &quot;My Story&quot; tells a tale without ever having to open a page. The cover shows a photo of a now slimmed-down duchess -- a lady once derided as the &quot;Duchess of Pork&quot; -- dressed in black, sitting on a red velvet chair without shoes.</p>
<p>Her naked right foot almost dominates the picture -- a reminder to one and all of the &quot;toe-sucking&quot; scandal that destroyed any affection the British public might have had for her, rocked the House of Windsor and won her a furious dressing down from Queen Elizabeth.</p>
<p>Shortly after the duchess announced in 1992 that she had separated from Prince Andrew, the London Daily Mirror published photos of a topless &quot;Fergie&quot; in the south of France with her bald &quot;financial adviser&quot; Texan John Bryan in a bathing suit appearing to suck her toes.</p>
<p>In the book, the duchess says the scene was a lot less &quot;intense&quot; than it looked -- Bryan was not sucking her toes but playing a game of Cinderella. While she admits an affair with him, she thinks the photographs were a set-up probably arranged by her enemies at Buckingham Palace, whom she calls the &quot;Grey Men of the Firm.&quot;</p>
<p>She said she believes the bureaucrats set her up by tipping off photographers about where she would be on holiday with Bryan. &quot;As I saw it, 'The Firm&quot; had done a job on me and done it well. I was routed and disgraced; I'd been flung into exile. The irony is I would have gone anyway. They expelled me with a pipe bomb when a small shove would have done.&quot;</p>
<p>The duchess said that betrayal was just one of several by &quot;the Firm&quot; and the MI5 secret service to disgrace and publicly humiliate her.</p>
<p>After one humiliation, she writes, &quot;The Firm's best interests could not be served if I went gently into the night. They needed to cut me off at the knees, abort my future options, destroy my standing with the queen. They also needed to send a message, a warning to Diana, to keep her in the fold and shore up the monarchy.</p>
<p>&quot;My public vivisection would be a pointed reminder: This is what happens if you cross us. (They did indeed scare the daylights out of my sister-in-law, who was now afraid to be seen with me and I could not blame her.)&quot;</p>
<p>The duchess said she feared that her rooms were bugged and says she even found a &quot;worm-like&quot; camera hidden on the grounds of her home. &quot;I know MI5 (the British secret Service) tapped my phones and analysed the recordings at their 'listening center' ... When their taps came up empty, they had to trap me by some other means fair or foul,&quot; she wrote.</p>
<p>Her book is replete with references to how much the duchess hated herself, from the way she looked to the way she acted. Even the index is not spared her self-doubts and deprecations with sections on &quot;breeches of decorum and self-sabotage,&quot; &quot;depressions,&quot; &quot;loneliness&quot; and a section devoted to being &quot;unsuitable and opportunistic.&quot;</p>
<p>There is also a section on betrayals which includes her father for writing a book about her and Bryan for doing the same. She is especially angry over a News of the World headline in which Bryan is quoted as saying, &quot;I had sex with Fergie as she spoke to Andy on phone.&quot;</p>
<p>It never happened she said, adding, &quot;When you lie down with dogs, you can't be shocked to get fleas.&quot;</p>
<p>She wrote that only one person stood by her -- Prince Andrew, the man she divorced six months ago and whom she says she still loves deeply.</p>
<p>But what she could not deal with was being a member of the Royal Family, being criticised right, left and centre. Even Prince Phillip attacked her once for looking like a bag lady while taking her children to school. &quot;Could you take your children to school looking a little smarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Never was a fish more out of water,&quot; she says of herself.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
