<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186467" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INTERVIEW - CoCensys sees lower 1996 sales.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW - CoCensys sees lower 1996 sales.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>CoCensys Inc expects full year 1996 sales to be lower than last year, even though they more than doubled in the nine month year-to-date period, Chief Financial Officer Peter Jansen told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the drop will come mainly from its co-promotion venture for Ciba-Geigy AG's drugs to treat obsessive-compulsive disorder and depression. Those drugs are losing market share to new competing generic drugs.</p>
<p>CoCensys' co-promotion deal with Ciba ends at the end of this year, and it is actively looking to enter a new deal to co-promote another company's drugs, Jansen said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are most definitely working on it, and hope to have a new deal as soon as possible,&quot; Jansen said. &quot;We think we can offer some very viable and interesting sales capabilities.&quot;</p>
<p>CoCensys, whose main focus is its own development-stage drugs for various neurological disorders such as stroke and epilepsy, also has a specialty sales force that markets other company's drugs and generates funding for in-house projects.</p>
<p>Jansen said a recent reorganization of its sales force will shift its focus more toward &quot;deals that are focused on sales and the bottom line.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Before there was much more of a focus on making sure each product and arrangement was part of a long term strategic effort,&quot; he explained. &quot;We believe that is good, but there are products out there we can sell while continuing to develop our own market, but at the same time bring in a little mroe cash.&quot;</p>
<p>However, since the revenues from the co-promotion deals can &quot;not support but only complement&quot; its other fundraising, Jansen said the comapny would be looking at additional sources of finacing such as a share offering &quot;in the next year or so.&quot;  </p>
<p>Jansen said research and development spending will total about $18 million for 1996, and will increase from that level next year, with most spending going toward its CCD drug candidate for epilipsy and ACEA 1021, designed to prevent brain damage following strokes.</p>
<p>Jansen said the second part of a Phase 1 safety study of ACEA 1021 should be completed early next year, and it is looking at a February 1997 start date for Phase Two trials.</p>
<p>A full Phase II pilot stoduy of CCD 1042 is also expected to begin sometime next year. --Andrea Orr 213 380-2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
