<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186493" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Northeast spot power extends gain on cold spell.</title>
<headline>US Northeast spot power extends gain on cold spell.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot wholesale electricity prices in the northeastern U.S. extended their recent gains Wednesday amid the ongoing cold spell overhanging most the region.</p>
<p>Higher space-heating demand offset increased generating capacity from startup of two nuclear generating units in western New York.</p>
<p>The 470 megawatt (MW) Ginna nuclear plant in Ontario, N.Y., was last reportedly running at 30 percent power, and the 610 MW Nine Mile Point unit nuclear power unit in Scriba, N.Y., was approaching full output late Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still tight,&quot; said a Northeast trader, referring to overall generating capacity in the Northeast due to seasonal maintenance shutdowns.</p>
<p>In the western part of the New York Power Pool (NYPP) district, peak, non-firm electricity for Thursday delivery was quoted near $25.00 a megawatt hour (MWh), up from Tuesday's range of $22.00-$23.00.</p>
<p>Western NYPP power for non-firm delivery during light load hours on Thursday was assessed near $15.00, up from Tuesday's quote of $13.50-$14.50 for Wednesday delivery.</p>
<p>In the eastern part of NYPP, peak, non-firm electricity for Thursday was still valued at $30.00-$32.00.</p>
<p>Off-peak, non-firm Thursday electricity in eastern NYPP rose to $18.00-$20.00, up from Tuesday's $16.00-$18.00.</p>
<p>In the New England Power Pool (NEPOOL), peak, non-firm electricity for Thursday at the Northeast Utilities border climbed to $38.00-$29.00, compared with Tuesday's range of $33.00-$37.00.</p>
<p>Non-firm, off-peak NEPOOL power for next-day delivery to the NU border held steady at $20.00-$21.00.</p>
<p>Next-day electricity for non-firm, peak delivery at the U.S.-Quebec border was offered near $21.00-$23.00 and for non-firm, off-peak delivery $18.00-$19.00.</p>
<p>Most traders and marketers anticipate the uptrend in Northeast spot prices to continue until weather starts to moderate next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Our load is way up. I don't think it's going to drop off that much,&quot; a New York trader said.</p>
<p>For Thursday, temperatures in the Northeast were predicted to peak in 20s-30s Fahrenheit and to bottom in teens to 20s. Two to four inches of snow was forecast to fall in parts western New York and New York-Pennsylvania border.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
