<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186509" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Midco products jump with NYMEX, firmer diffs.</title>
<headline>U.S. Midco products jump with NYMEX, firmer diffs.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Midcontinent spot products jumped sharply Wednesday afternoon, with tight Gulf Coast gasoline helping squeeze Midwest gasoline prices higher, traders said.</p>
<p>Differentials firmed one cent on conventional unleaded gasoline in Group Three and 1.5 cents in the Chicago market, helped by stronger Gulf prices and increased liquidity as traders returned from an American Petroleum Institute get-together in Washington, D.C.</p>
<p>Chicago unleaded was bid at about 8.75 cents above the print, while Group Three material commanded 5.25 to 5.50 cents over.</p>
<p>&quot;The Colonial Pipeline has been favoring shipments of distillates from the Gulf&quot; to New York Harbor, lessening the number of barrels available for the Midwest, one trader said.</p>
<p>And refineries are still down in the Gulf Coast, the East Coast and the Midwest, other traders said, noting Gulf Coast &quot;M4&quot;-grade conventional unleaded was sold Wednesday for 4.0 cents over the print, 1.50 cents firmer than Wednesday diffs.  </p>
<p>Group Three low sulfur diesel firmed a half cent differentially to 4.0 cents over December heating oil, players said, whith prompt spot Chicago material stable at 3.50 cents over.</p>
<p>&quot;We're stable even though agricultural demand has begun to slip in the group,,&quot; one trader said, noting that absolute prices had risen through the day as December heat raced 2.70 cents high 1701978210</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk, 212 859-1632</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
