<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186751" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Christopher urges Bosnia to build unity government.</title>
<headline>Christopher urges Bosnia to build unity government.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Worsnip</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher met the three members of Bosnia's joint presidency on Wednesday to persuade them to bring to life the government of their divided state.</p>
<p>They met a day before an international conference in Paris is due to adopt a two-year plan to consolidate peace in the former Yugoslav republic, where the Dayton accords ended an ethnic war a year.</p>
<p>Despite elections in September, rivalry among the Moslems, Serbs and Croats has hindered the creation of a functioning government for the two-part Bosnian state foreseen by Dayton.</p>
<p>The co-presidents -- Moslem Alija Izetbegovic, Serb Momcilo Krajisnik and Croat Kresimir Zubak -- earlier had lunch with French Foreign Minister Herve de Charette and told reporters they had agreed Thursday's conference should give a boost to slow-moving civilian reconstruction.</p>
<p>&quot;What Christopher will do in this meeting is he will stress to (the Bosnian leaders) the need to complete work on building the institutions of the new state,&quot; including the cabinet and parliament, State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said.</p>
<p>There has been no agreement so far on a cabinet line-up and the Serbs have been reluctant to attend the parliament.</p>
<p>It was the first time the three co-presidents have appeared together on the international stage. But their collegiality does not yet stretch to sharing an aircraft.</p>
<p>Western officials said Krajisnik refused to fly to Paris in the same aircraft as the two others and flew from Belgrade, capital of rump Yugoslavia, instead.</p>
<p>Burns said Christopher also planned to stress a need to respect human rights provisions of the Dayton pact, a problem highlighted by fighting sparked Tuesday by an attempt by Moslem refugees to return to their former homes in Serb territory.</p>
<p>&quot;The Serbs have been the most recalcitrant of the parties on this issue,&quot; Burns told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;People have a right to return to their homes...Here you have Bosnian Serbs firing, it's a very, very bad, negative incident,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bosnia's U.N. ambassador Muhamed Sacirbey, a Moslem, said that despite paper guarantees of a right to return, the NATO-led peace force in Bosnia IFOR was failing to protect Moslems who wished to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no one giving us any protection -- IFOR or anyone else -- and (the refugees) feel naked in the face of Serb antagonism,&quot; Sacirbey told journalists.</p>
<p>Burns said Christopher would also be raising a need for the factions to hand over to an international tribunal in The Hague people accused of atrocities during the Bosnian war. Very few of the more than 70 indicted so far have been arrested.</p>
<p>Christopher also planned to press Izetbegovic again to fire Deputy Defence Minister Hasan Cengic, who Washington says is obstructing a U.S. plan to equip and train the forces of Bosnia's Moslem-Croat Federation, Burns said.</p>
<p>The United States has made delivery of $100 million of arms contingent on the dismissal of Cengic. Izetbegovic has several times promised to comply but Cengic is still at his post.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
