<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186745" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: Helsinki eases in wait-and-see ahead of Nokia result.</title>
<headline>Helsinki eases in wait-and-see ahead of Nokia result.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares ended slightly lower on Wednesday as investors squared positions ahead of bourse-engine Nokia's January-September report, brokers said.</p>
<p>The HEX index edged down 0.1 percent to 2,263.32. Volume rose to 622 million markka, with trade boosted by lively Nokia and by a few massive inhouse deals in energy sector shares.</p>
<p>Nokia -- expected to show a 2.2 billion markka profit for the nine months -- slipped from its upward track and lost 3.00 markka to end at 227.00.</p>
<p>Nokia's profit announcement, due at about 1200 Finnish time/1000 GMT on Thursday, has been in focus most of the week and brokers expect it to set the near-term trend.</p>
<p>&quot;If Nokia's figures are in line with expectations, it could resume its upward trend,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>General prospects for stock markets remained favourable since the U.S. Federal Reserve was not expected to raise key rates in its policy meeting, due to announce decisions after the market closed here, brokers said.</p>
<p>Forestries continued their upward correction which started on Tuesday as selling pressure eased. The minor recovery was also underpinned by Swedish paper maker MoDo's higher than expected January-September earnings.</p>
<p>UPM-Kymmene added 1.00 markka to end at 89.00. Enso also rose 1.00 markka to 35.00, and Metsa-Serla gained 0.50 markka to close at 29.80.</p>
<p>Bourse volume was generally moderate, but the total was boosted by massive deals in regional power company Lansivoima as state-owned energy group Imatran Voima upped its stake in the firm to 44 percent from 31.5 percent.</p>
<p>Lansivoima closed up 5.00 markka at 220.00.</p>
<p>Big in-house deals were also registered in steel group Rautaruukki, in plastic and cleaning equipment maker Lassila &amp; Tikanoja and in cargo shippping group Finnlines.</p>
<p>Rautaruukki advanced 0.50 markka to 42.30, Lassila added 4.00 markka to 265.00, but Finnlines lost 0.70 markka at 109.30.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
