<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186854" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Recessionary trends in Indian economy - ING Barings.</title>
<headline>Recessionary trends in Indian economy - ING Barings.</headline>
<byline>Priya Ramani</byline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian stocks have yet to discount grim news on political, economic and corporate fronts, broking firm ING Barings warned on Wednesday.</p>
<p>In a report titled &quot;The Purge is on But Incomplete&quot;, the European firm said it disagreed with the common perception that the Indian economy was going through a minor slowdown that would be set right by an infusion of liquidity.</p>
<p>ING Barings said investors should watch out for recessionary trends and inflationary tendencies, and advised them to underweight private sector businesses and sell cement, auto and steel stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;We are noting early signals of the exhaustion of demand for consumer as well as industrial goods on the back of robust consumption in the last three-four years,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>India began its gradual conversion to a free-market economy in 1991 under the former ruling Congress government.</p>
<p>ING Barings said early recessionary signals were falling import/export growth, poor excise/customs collections, rising inventories and growing deposits/falling advances by banks.</p>
<p>Other warning signs included the growth rate of industrial production, which has been in decline since the second quarter of 1996, impending production cuts and idling freight capacity.</p>
<p>Most analysts welcomed the central bank's monetary policy last month which released funds by cutting the cash reserve requirements of Indian banks. They forecast the policy would spur growth in the second half of fiscal ended March 31, 1997.</p>
<p>But ING Barings said it expected a &quot;U-turn in corporate profitability&quot; and forecast second half results of Indian companies would be lower than the first half with improvement in 1997/98 over 1996/97 &quot;suspect&quot;.</p>
<p>The report advised investors to restructure their portfolios to overweight shares of state-run firms and underweight private sector businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;On the sectoral front we recommend investors to BUY oil, refineries, telecom, banks, utilities and petrochemicals and SELL automobiles, cement and steel companies,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>ING Barings said that it expected the country's shaky United Front ruling coalition was likely to lose office in 1997 and the new government would include the Congress.</p>
<p>The Congress currently supports but is not part of Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's government.</p>
<p>The securities firm said another factor not discounted by the capital market was the pain of liberalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the change in the business environment and the emergence of recessionary trends will hasten the shake-out of Indian businesses in the next two years,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the market is going to form a long-term bottom as it recognises recessionary trends and evaporating corporate growth. After this period, we see a good upside for the Indian stock market later in 1997,&quot; the report said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
