<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18684" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK--Firm anchor at 7.0 percent.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK--Firm anchor at 7.0 percent.</headline>
<byline>Isabelle Clary</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. 30-year Treasury bond will likely trade sideways on Thursday as the 7.0 percent yield continues to prove a firm anchor until the August employment report, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not going to see big market moves until Friday next week,&quot; said Daniel Friel, director of financial and economic research at NationsBank Corp.</p>
<p>Payroll creation and its potential implications for inflation and monetary policy have been the market's focus since March.  </p>
<p>&quot;I'll be focusing on the claims numbers on Thursday because the market is already beginning to think about what the payroll number might be,&quot; Friel said.</p>
<p>A Reuter survey puts the jobless claims for the week ended August 24 at 330,000 versus 327,000 in the prior week.</p>
<p>&quot;If the claims remain in the 320-330,000 range after averaging 365,000 in the first half of the year, this means the labor market has improved,&quot; Friel said. &quot;This means a payroll gain in excess of 200,000 for August.&quot;</p>
<p>A Reuter preliminary survey estimates August payroll creation, to be released September 6, at 238,000.  </p>
<p>Friel said payroll creation in excess of 250,000 would unnerve a market wary of possible rate rises in an &quot;economy doing better than what (Federal Reserve Chairman Alan) Greenspan was saying about the second half.&quot;</p>
<p>The NationsBank director noted that Greenspan's second- half slowdown scenario was based on lower consumer spending, mainly for big-ticket items.</p>
<p>&quot;Consumer demand is not likely to slow that much. The inventory-to-sale ratio is near a cyclical low, which means you see businesses rebuilding inventories,&quot; said Frield who added the second half may still record above-trend growth.  </p>
<p>With the jury still out regarding the pace of the July- December expansion and future inflation, the market is eager to hold on to price concessions.</p>
<p>&quot;The long bond is trading at roughly 400 basis points above inflation, which is an attractive level if you assume inflation is 3.0 percent and will remain there,&quot; said one trader who remarked the U.S. long-term benchmark historically yields 300 basis points above inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;You are going to see buyers for as long as we stay in the 7.0 percent area, at least until we see the August payrolls,&quot; the trader added.  </p>
<p>Micheal Casey, economist at MFR Inc, said it would take major news to force the long bond yield outside ot its 6.75- to 7.25 percent range and the revision of the second-quarter gross domestic product won't be it.</p>
<p>&quot;It's deadly boring news,&quot; Casey said of the GDP revision, scheduled for release on Thursday at 1230 GMT.</p>
<p>The market consensus is not looking for much change either in the growth rate that was first reported at 4.2 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The long bond is firmly in a range between 6-3/4 percent and 7-1/4 percent. The real money does not want to buy these bonds under 6 3/4 percent,&quot; Casey said.  </p>
<p>In late Wednesday trade, the 6-3/4-percent 30-year bond was quoted off 3/32 to yield 6.98 percent.</p>
<p>Earlier, the Federal Reserve Bank of New York temporarily added reserves via overnight system repurchase agreements to supplement outstanding three-day and seven-day fixed system repos. Federal funds are expected to open on the firm side on Thursday when the three operations expire.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1666</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
