<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186991" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Martha Stewart may spin off retail stores.</title>
<headline>Martha Stewart may spin off retail stores.</headline>
<byline>Jackie Frank</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Martha Stewart, the stockbroker turned empress of entertaining, said Tuesday her $200 million gardening, food and decorating empire may start a chain of retail stores and hinted a stock offering may be coming.</p>
<p>With public appetite for her lifestyle of studied elegance growing, her company is developing a long-term strategy to meet the demand, she told the National Press Club.</p>
<p>A line of paints based on the colors of eggs produced by her chickens is now available. Articles on how to make wreaths of freeze-dried Black-Eyed Susans and hand-paint gift wrap have led to soaring sales for her Martha Stewart Living magazine. &quot;Martha By Mail&quot; sells her project kits.</p>
<p>Stewart, the woman other women either admire or disdain, told the audience she vacuums to relax and finds her career, being Martha Stewart, is her life. Fulfilling public desire for the &quot;Martha Stewart&quot; product now requires a staff of 140 in her New York offices and on her Westport, Conn. mini-farm.</p>
<p>While she approves projects, the staff started work on ideas for this year's Christmas photo settings and projects five days after last Christmas. She will have &quot;celebrated&quot; Christmas six times before she gets to the real one with her family in December.</p>
<p>Retail stores are one of the options being considered as the company maps its future, she said. &quot;Those kinds of things will be forthcoming,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Asked whether her entertaining, cooking and decorating enterprise would issue stock, the former stockbroker replied with a smile, &quot;We love the stock market.&quot;</p>
<p>Stewart's long-term goal is to turn her company, which started with one book on entertaining in 1982, into a full-fledged information company with an interactive site on the Internet and expanded versions of her television series produced by Martha Stewart Living Television.</p>
<p>But ideas, not product evaluation, will be the focus. &quot;I am not so much interested in telling people what to buy, as how to live,&quot; Stewart said.</p>
<p>She acknowledged that the projects she suggests require more time than most people have, but whether or not people actually make her cranberry wreaths, it is the idea that sells.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of us are dreamers and not doers. If you can find time to do both, it is nice,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
