<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186901" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Major nations ponder military force for Zaire.</title>
<headline>Major nations ponder military force for Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.N. Secretary General Boutros Boutros Ghali has said he expects more than 12 countries to provide troops and equipment for a Canadian-led force to open up aid routes to starving Rwandan and Burundian refugees in Zaire.</p>
<p>The following are the views of major nations on whether to contribute to such a force, which has yet to be approved by the United Nations.</p>
<p>CANADA - said the first Canadian troops could be deployed within 48 hours of a U.N. resolution to send a multinational force. The first deployment would be a special 350-member Disaster Assistance Response Team, formed by the Canadian military to provide disaster relief at home and abroad.</p>
<p>FRANCE - has spearheaded efforts to create the proposed Zaire force and says it is ready to contribute about 1,500 troops, 600 of them within 24 hours of receiving an international mandate to do so and a further 600 to follow 24 hours later. Paris, however, says it will not move alone.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - White House officials hinted that President Bill Clinton will back Canadian leadership of an international force, but said he has still made no decision on whether Washington would play any role, such as contributing troops.</p>
<p>The U.S. is under growing pressure to take action, but remembering a U.N. mission to Somalia in 1993 which led to heavy casualties among U.S. and other troops, has insisted on seeing full details of the force's mandate and funding. A military-led U.S. assessment team has been sent to the region.</p>
<p>BELGIUM - Zaire's former colonial ruler, has ruled out sending any troops to the region but has offered to help with logistics and money. The country has already promised $10 million towards funding any force and sent four C-130 heavy lift cargo planes to Entebbe to transport supplies.</p>
<p>BRITAIN - is expected to make a preliminary decision later on Wednesday on whether to contribute to the proposed force.</p>
<p>GERMANY - Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel has ruled out sending German troops to Zaire, but the government has discussed contributing financial aid. So far nothing concrete has come out of the talks and in light of a tight budget squeeze, Germany is unlikely to make any substantial contribution.</p>
<p>SOUTH AFRICA - President Nelson Mandela said he is prepared in principle to contribute troops to an international force, but that he wanted more specific information before deciding on what size military unit to send.</p>
<p>THE NETHERLANDS - is expected to discuss sending troops in a parliamentary debate on Wednesday or Thursday about foreign and military spending. The Defence Ministry says it has begun vaccinating a company of 270 military personnel, mainly combat troops, from its Air Mobile Brigade. The vaccinations take three weeks to become effective and the ministry said it did not envisage vaccinating any more people. Any company sent to Zaire would be equipped with personal weapons plus 10-15 armoured personnel carriers armed with light canons.</p>
<p>IRELAND - has said it will provide troops for the proposed force if asked. Army chief of staff Lieutenant-General Gerry McMahon said Ireland's contribution would probably be a specialist unit of soldiers such as engineers, military police or logisticians. Officials said Ireland's contribution would be unlikely to exceed 100 troops.</p>
<p>FINLAND - said it will not send troops but is studying other ways it can help.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
