<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186926" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Threat or boon? Europeans resist engineered soybeans.</title>
<headline>Threat or boon? Europeans resist engineered soybeans.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>They are small, pale and inoffensive-looking, but genetically engineered soyabeans have excited a unique opposition alliance of environmentalists and supermarkets who fear consumers being used as human guinea pigs.</p>
<p>Protesters trying to keep the beans out of Europe this week chained themselves to gates in Germany, occupied the office of the Austrian health minister and climbed onto the roof of food giant Nestle's headquarters.</p>
<p>They are worried that Monsanto Co's Round Up Ready soyabean, modified to resist the company's Round Up herbicide, could pose a significant threat to human health. But are the beans really a threat ? Or are the protests just a reactionary, and unjustified, rebellion against progress?</p>
<p>&quot;Genetically modified soyabeans and derivative products are as safe as conventional soyabeans,&quot; said a spokeswoman for Britain's Agriculture Ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;All soya foods are processed and in the processing, the actual genetically altered bit has been taken out.&quot;</p>
<p>Andrew Dickson of the European Association for BioIndustry in Brussels agreed. &quot;In the processing of them, any organism that would have been live in there is killed off. The material is completely dead in terms of any live genetic organisms.&quot; Dozens of genetically modified products are on the market already, many of them launched with a minimum of protest. One is Calgene's Flavr-Savr tomato, genetically changed to slow the action of an enzyme that starts the rotting process.</p>
<p>But opponents point out that deleting a gene and adding one to a plant are two different things. Monsanto's bean has a gene inserted that confers resistance to herbicide.</p>
<p>Also, the tomatoes and products made from them are clearly labelled so consumers can avoid them if they wish.</p>
<p>They say no one knows what the beans could do to people. They have not been tested on humans, except in simulations, and nothing is known about long-term effects of genetic engineering because it is such a new technology.</p>
<p>Environmentalists and some scientists say the pieces of genetic material that make the bean resistant to herbicide could interact in unpredictable ways with bacteria in the gut.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the creation, potentially, of new proteins that have potentially new toxic and allergenic effects,&quot; said Julie Sheppard, spokeswoman for the Genetics Forum, a private research and lobbying group funded in part by charities.</p>
<p>&quot;There are fears some genetic modifications could be dangerous for people with allergies and strengthen their immunity to antibiotics,&quot; said Hiltrud Breyer, a German Green Party member of the European Parliament. But U.S. Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman called such worries &quot;unsound science&quot;.</p>
<p>Soya is one of the most versatile and widely used foods in the world. Between one and two percent of U.S. soyabean exports are now expected to contain the modified beans, mixed in with unmodified varieties.</p>
<p>The American Soyabean Association says it would be too expensive to separate out the genetically engineered crop.</p>
<p>The beans will be used in up to 60 percent of all products sold in supermarkets, from bread to noodles. Anything containing soya flour, oil or the beans themselves could be affected.</p>
<p>British supermarkets have called for more information and greater choice on the products. A spokesman for J. Sainsbury Plc said the retail community was &quot;disappointed&quot; that modified soya would come to Britain next year.</p>
<p>The European Consumers' Organisation, BEUC, wants food containing genetically modified soya bean protein to be labelled so that consumers can choose whether to eat them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
