<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="186986" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FEATURE - For Eartha Kitt, life really is a cabaret.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - For Eartha Kitt, life really is a cabaret.</headline>
<byline>Steve James</byline>
<dateline>HOLLYWOOD 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eartha Kitt is purring.</p>
<p>As she approaches 70, that voice can still slink across the stage, snake through the smoke and slide right down on a man's lap.</p>
<p>The legendary entertainer recently finished an engagement at the Hollywood Roosevelt Hotel's Cinegrill, the kind of intimate room her inimitable style of singing was made for. But Kitt fears her smooth kind of personal act is threatened by the cacophony of modern technology and an entertainment industry driven only by profits.</p>
<p>&quot;I like a closed environment where you can meet the people and people can feel you, but these great big arenas, you're singing AT the people not TO them,&quot; she said. &quot;It's important for entertainers to get a response ... (but) not all the screaming and yelling and ranting and raving. ... With all these amplifiers, I don't think you really hear the artist,&quot; she told Reuters between shows at the Cinegrill.</p>
<p>&quot;They ask me what I think about Michael Jackson -- he's a product of technology. All the lighting and the blowing up, what the hell is that? You don't know how talented these people are because there's so much technology.&quot;</p>
<p>On the subject of another modern-day pop icon, Kitt was equally outspoken, pointing out that she was playing the sexy, I-Don't-Give-A-Damn woman looking for &quot;an old-fashioned millionaire&quot; long before Madonna was even born.</p>
<p>&quot;Now I'm being compared to Madonna,&quot; she said with a wry smile. &quot;But actually Madonna should be compared to Eartha Kitt. Whatever she does seems to be packaging Eartha Kitt. But she's doing it very well, you can't blame her either. Packaging, that's the name of the game today.&quot;</p>
<p>Perhaps flattered by the imitation, Kitt is more concerned by the decline of cabaret rooms, like New York's Cafe Carlyle. &quot;There used to be the Persian Room (in New York's Plaza Hotel), the Empire Room, Chez Paris in London and Talk of the Town. I always went to work in England once a year. But you don't have any places for me to work there anymore. There's no cabaret,&quot; mused Kitt, who started her career as a dancer.</p>
<p>&quot;I did the Hollywood Bowl one year. But it's this outdoor situation where you have amplifiers coming back at you, it's like singing in a football field. So the true sound of your voice, I believe, is never truly enriched by this technology.&quot;</p>
<p>Kitt, whose versatility has seen her nominated for Broadway Tony awards, Grammys for recordings and Emmys for her television work, explained what audience response meant.</p>
<p>&quot;It's communication that helps you connect with people. The El Rancho (in Las Vegas) was like that -- about 750 people and I could reach every one of them. But when it got so big and broad ... these people on a recording tour can reach hundreds of thousands of people at a time. I don't see where that's ... real.&quot;</p>
<p>What is real for Eartha Kitt is her well-documented tough childhood in the impoverished South and what happened to her when she typically spoke her mind about the Vietnam War (she was against it) at a White House luncheon hosted by President Lyndon Johnson's wife Lady Bird. She says she was blackballed by the entertainment establishment and ended up living in exile abroad for several years until President Jimmy Carter invited her back to the White House 10 years later.</p>
<p>She still owns a house in London, a fact that elicited a typical Kitt one-liner: &quot;Diamonds and furs are wonderful to have, but I prefer a piece of land.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Well, Americans in general thought I was out of sight out of mind,&quot; she said. But all the time she was performing in cabaret, musicals and films and recording. &quot;Back in Business,&quot; her latest album, nominated for a Grammy this year, was her first recorded in the United States in 30 years.</p>
<p>For a woman who will be 69 in January, Kitt keeps up a grueling schedule. This year, she appeared at the Carlyle and the Cinegrill and in a one-woman show in Chicago -- &quot;Lady Day at Emerson's Bar and Grill,&quot; about jazz singer Billie Holiday.</p>
<p>In addition, she appeared with Rosie O'Donnell in the children's movie &quot;Harriet the Spy&quot; and her distinctive throaty vowels have been wrapped around several products in TV ads. And this month she will be seen in a special celebrity version of the popular game-show &quot;Jeopardy!&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I feel I'm a very lucky person because I'm still working at the age of nearly 70. As long as I can feel I gave a damn good show, I can feel good about that,&quot; Kitt said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOLLYWOOD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
