<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187062" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: FOCUS - Erste rejoins Creditanstalt race.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Erste rejoins Creditanstalt race.</headline>
<byline>Knut Engelmann</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian savings bank Die Erste said on Wednesday it would rejoin an Austro-Italian-German consortium poised to make a bid for privatisation candidate Creditanstalt, Austria's flagship bank.</p>
<p>&quot;The board of governors voted unanimously to make a joint offer with the consortium around EA-Generali,&quot; Die Erste said in a statement.</p>
<p>Sources close to the talks had said as early as two weeks ago the savings bank's return to the group was a done deal.</p>
<p>Die Erste stormed out of the consortium, led by insurer EA-Generali and including Germany's Commerzbank and Banca Commerciale Italiana, on September 6 following disagreement on a joint bid.</p>
<p>Days later, Finance Minister Viktor Klima rejected a bid by the remaining members of the group because it was not for all of the government's 70 percent of voting shares in the bank. He has indicated he may be more flexible in the latest tender, which closes on Friday.</p>
<p>EA-Generali, majority-owned by Italy's Assicurazioni Generali, said it welcomed Die Erste's return into the group, which also includes various industrial interests ranging from electronics to fruit juices. &quot;I'm happy that (Die Erste) has made this decision,&quot; a spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>After the savings bank's initial departure, the consortium in September bid around 6.7 billion schillings ($632.7 million) for roughly half the state's 19.9 million shares. The whole stake was valued at about 18 billion schillings by J.P. Morgan, the government's advisors, last year.</p>
<p>Austrian media said this week the consortium was likely to stick to Die Erste's original proposal to form a joint holding that would control up to 74.9 percent of the savings bank's shares and all of Creditanstalt's.</p>
<p>This time, the group was expected to bid about 10 billion schillings for the government's stake, with Die Erste contributing about a third of the total.</p>
<p>Die Erste is barely a third the size of Creditanstalt, which has total assets of about 700 billion schillings. Senior executives at Creditanstalt privately have balked at the prospect of relinquishing control of their bank, Austria's most traditional finance house, to the much smaller savings bank.</p>
<p>But with international interest in the seemingly endless privatisation saga fading fast, banking sources said Klima may have little choice but to give the consortium, the only known bidder left in the race, the green light.</p>
<p>&quot;There obviously aren't so many who're really interested (in Creditanstalt),&quot; said one earlier this week.</p>
<p>According to unconfirmed media reports, only nine parties have asked for a copy of Klima's information memorandum on the bank on which they could base a potential bid.</p>
<p>Klima has repeatedly said he was confident Austria's longest-running privatisation project since the end of World War Two could be wrapped up before year-end. ($1=10.59 Schilling)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
