<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187121" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss Re sees organic growth in U.S..</title>
<headline>Swiss Re sees organic growth in U.S..</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lukas Muehlemann, chief executive of Swiss Reinsurance Co. said Swiss Re would focus on organic growth in the United States, rather than acquisitions after rival Munich Re bought up American Re.</p>
<p>Muehlemann's designated successor Walter Kielholz also told a business luncheon that Swiss Re expected to be able to close its acquisition of British group Mercantile &amp; General Re by the end of November.  </p>
<p>Muehlemann was speaking to reporters after a speech by Kielholz to the Swiss-American Chamber of Commerce.</p>
<p>Asked whether Swiss Re was interested in other acquisitions in the United States after Munich Re snapped up American Re, he said:</p>
<p>&quot;In the United States for us it is back to organic growth,&quot; Muehlemann said.</p>
<p>He declined to answer questions about other potential acquisition plans, saying it was company policy not to comment on possible purchases.</p>
<p>Kielholz, who will become chief executive of Swiss Re when Muehlemann moves to Credit Suisse Group on January 1, 1997, said regulatory approval for the purchase of Mercantile &amp; General (M&amp;G) was progressing smoothly.</p>
<p>&quot;We are currently in the process of acquiring M&amp;G, a transaction that we hope to close by the end of this month,&quot; he said, adding:</p>
<p>&quot;The only thing that is holding us up is government and regulatory agency approval, but this is going along smoothly,&quot; Kielholz said.  </p>
<p>Muehlemann told reporters that the M&amp;G acquisition required approval from about 20 or 30 government and industry regulatory agencies.</p>
<p>&quot;There is nothing to indicate that we would have any trouble closing,&quot; Muehlemann said about regulatory approval for M&amp;G.</p>
<p>On November 4 the European Commission approved Swiss Re's takeover of M&amp;G from the Prudential Group.</p>
<p>Muehlemann declined to comment further on the timing or expected results of talks on acquiring Italy's Unione Italiana de Riassicurazione Spa from Istituto Nazionale delle Assicurazioni (INA).</p>
<p>Swiss Re announced on Monday that it was in talks with INA that could lead to it buying Unione Italiana de Riassicurazione.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
