<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187160" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Time running out for Zaire refugees-EU's Bonino.</title>
<headline>Time running out for Zaire refugees-EU's Bonino.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Humanitarian Aid Commissioner Emma Bonino urged the world on Wednesday not to delay a second further in setting up a force to enable aid workers to help refugees in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;Every second counts. It's no longer a question of whether to have a force but when,&quot; she told the European Parliament. &quot;If it arrives in three weeks time it will have a lot of work burying corpses but not much else.&quot;</p>
<p>Bonino, who has just returned from Africa's troubled Great Lakes region, has been the most vocal critic of the United Nations Security Council for its slowness in reacting to the crisis.</p>
<p>&quot;This military action is a prerequisite if we are to try to save lives,&quot; she said. &quot;I'm frustrated because so far I've not been able to get across the message of how urgent this is.&quot;</p>
<p>More than a million long-term Rwandan and Burundian Hutu refugees are cut off from all aid in eastern Zaire by the conflict between Zairean troops and Tutsi rebels, who hold much of the region.</p>
<p>Thousands are feared to be dying on mountains and in the jungle.</p>
<p>The question of U.S. approval stood in the way on Wednesday of a Canadian-led relief force and Bonino said European people should look across the Atlantic for the reason for the inaction.</p>
<p>She said humanitarian aid corridors should be two-way, that refugees should not be forced to return to Rwanda and that they should be disarmed to prevent an explosive situation developing in the camps.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise we will have the refugee camps with thousands of armed refugees and we will go back to the situation that humanitarian aid people have had to work with for the last two years,&quot; she said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
