<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187255" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-'Annus horribilus' over-Mt Edon Gold.</title>
<headline>RTRS-'Annus horribilus' over-Mt Edon Gold.</headline>
<dateline>PERTH 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mount Edon Gold Mines (Australia) Ltd said on Wednesday it believed it was heading for a successful year after a difficult 1995/96.</p>
<p>&quot;It has probably been the most difficult year in the company's history,&quot; chairman Trevor Kennedy told shareholders at the annual meeting, adding that he believed the company's problems were largely behind it.</p>
<p>&quot;It was our 'annus horribilus'. However, unlike the British Royal Family, we believe we have put our problems behind us,&quot; Kennedy said.  </p>
<p>Recent problems for the company included delays and increased costs involved in doubling the Tarmoola mine's production which coincided with the changing nature of the orebody at depth.</p>
<p>The company said this coincided with pit wall failure at the Nevoria mine and an elongated period of wet weather which severely hampered operations.</p>
<p>Both Tarmoola and Nevoria are located in Western Australia. Kennedy said the company had impemented a turnaround strategy with the September quarterly report providing evidence of progress.  </p>
<p>&quot;By September quarter it became apparent that the strategy we had adopted was putting the operation back on track. The September quarterly report provided evidence for our confidence,&quot; he told shareholders.</p>
<p>Mt Edon's September quarterly reported record gold output of 35,848 ounces with the company saying it had achieved substantial improvements and better performance from both mines.</p>
<p>Kennedy said the company's reserves inventory had increased to 1.118 million ounces of gold while the resource inventory had risen to 2.974 million ounces.  </p>
<p>Mt Edon shares closed two cents higher oon Wednesday at A$1.66 on turnover of 1.17 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PERTH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
