<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187219" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hambros sees gradual banking revenue lift.</title>
<headline>Hambros sees gradual banking revenue lift.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>British investment banking group Hambros Plc said on Wednesday that the profitability of its banking business would grow through a gradual increase in revenues and continuing strong demand for independent advice.</p>
<p>Hambros, which announced pretax profits of 35.0 million pounds ($57.85 million) for the first half compared with a 7.7 million pound loss for the same period in 1995, said second half profits from its investment group would not match the first, but it expected &quot;considerable improvement&quot; in its subsidiaries.  </p>
<p>Hambros sees gradual banking revenue lift</p>
<p>Lord Hambro, the group's chairman, said he would retire from his post in July 1997 and be succeeded by Sir Chips Keswick, currently group chief executive.</p>
<p>Bad debt provisions for the period were 5.9 million pounds compared with 23.5 million in the same period in 1995. Hambro said the full effect of a drive to reduce the banking group's cost base &quot;should steadily become evident during the course of the next two years&quot; and the benefits were already showing.</p>
<p>Hambro said the banking group had recruited well-qualified individuals to fill key posts and is &quot;actively pursuing a number of initiatives which would strengthen our core businesses both in the UK and abroad&quot;.</p>
<p>Hambro said the Hambro Countrywide estate agency subsidiary and the Hambro Insurance Services arm should both produce considerable improvements in their contributions, in particular Hambro Countrywide. Despite a challenging environment for the group as a whole, prospects were good, he added. ($1=.6050 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
