<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187246" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ debt rallies at close but underperforms U.S.</title>
<headline>NZ debt rallies at close but underperforms U.S.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>* NZ debt markets finish bid after good session</p>
<p>* Some dealers disappointed, say mkt could have gone further  </p>
<p>* October FPI has limited market impact</p>
<p>New Zealand bonds enjoyed a good rally at Wednesday's close but its limited extent disappointed some.</p>
<p>The three year maturity shed five basis points in yield, while the 10-years shed six. In the money market, 90 day bank bills rallied five basis points to 9.13 percent and their corresponding futures contract reversed its recent bearish trend, climbing four points to 91.24.  </p>
<p>One dealer said given the strength of the U.S. Treasuries performance in Tokyo he would have expected New Zealand debt to rally further.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a little disappointing really. It's lagging the other dollar bloc markets and I'm not sure why. We've seen local buying, but it doesn't seem enough to be generating any great rally,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said Tuesday's session had seen stop-loss selling from traders who had accumulated longs in the hope of a rally but then grew impatient and dished their positions out.  </p>
<p>&quot;We probably need a bit of offshore buying to support the market, to get it going again. It's just stagnating at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Political risk was weighing reasonably heavily on the minds of domestic traders. On Monday, Reserve Bank Governor Don Brash warned about the dangers of increased government spending.</p>
<p>And on Tuesday, nationalist New Zealand First leader Winston Peters said there was a &quot;certain inevitability&quot; the RBNZ's current 0-2 inflation target would be widened.  </p>
<p>New Zealand First holds the balance of power after October's inconclusive general election and is negotiating with both Labour and National over coalition possibilities.</p>
<p>However, one dealer said international investors did not seem at all perturbed by the statements.</p>
<p>&quot;Once again, the long-term fundamentals should remain in this economy. They know there may be some tinkering but Winston is never going to get the Labour party or the National party to change the Reserve Bank Act, even though he may get them to change the Policy Targets Agreement,&quot; a dealer said.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, October Food Price Index data had very little impact on the market. Bankers Trust economists said the 0.4 percent monthly rise was marginally positive for the currency and marginally negative for interest rates, but it had only slight implications given the volatility of the series. ---------------------------(SPREADS)----------------------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close NZD VS	    3 YR	 10 YR     * NZD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p>USD	   129 (+1)     108 (+2)    * FUTURES    -18 (nil)</p>
<p>CAD	   262 (-5)     113 (-2)    * PHYSICALS   13 (-3)</p>
<p>AUD	    64 (+2)	15 (+2)</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Catherine McCaw (64 4) 471 4275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
