<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187244" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian bond yield curve flattens on rally.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian bond yield curve flattens on rally.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australia bond yield curve flattened on Wednesday as the long end rallied on a vibrant U.S. market, while the short end was pegged at the 6.50 percent official cash rate.  </p>
<p>Local bonds also broke out of their recent tight trading range, which saw long-dated yields drop to their lowest level since late February 1994, and saw spread margins tighten against other dollar bloc bonds, continuing this week's trend.</p>
<p>The Australian/U.S. 10-year bond yield spread now stands at its lowest level since late October.</p>
<p>However, some traders were concerned that the market could be due for a correction on a spread basis given the recent tightening trend.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're the only market that has kept pace with the U.S. in recent weeks. We've seen both gilts and JGBs blow out, so it makes you think that someone else could be due for a tumble,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The local market also continued to outpace the short-end of the Canadian market as investors there continue to switch longer as the Bank of Canada is now seen on hold after its recent vigorous policy easing.</p>
<p>The three-year Australian/Canadian spread now stands nearly 20 points down since Friday.</p>
<p>-- Colin Brinsden 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
