<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187297" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAPUA NEW GUINEA: Papua New Guinea police fire tear gas into crowd.</title>
<headline>Papua New Guinea police fire tear gas into crowd.</headline>
<dateline>PORT MORESBY 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Papua New Guinea police on Wednesday fired tear gas into a crowd of more than 500 people planning to march on the South Pacific nation's parliament in protest at the recent pay-back killing of four school boys.</p>
<p>Several people at the planned march in the capital Port Moresby told reporters police fired tear gas after youths waving placards became restless, wanting to start the march early.</p>
<p>Police fired several tear gas canisters into the crowd which consisted of unemployed youths, schoolboys and women, including the mothers of the murdered boys, local reporters said.</p>
<p>&quot;People ran in all directions,&quot; said a woman at the sports oval where the crowd had gathered around 6.00 a.m. (1900 GMT).</p>
<p>&quot;The women, including the mothers of the four students, were caught by the tear gas,&quot; a local newspaper photographer at the scene told Reuters. No injuries were reported.</p>
<p>Many schools had been closed to allow students to join the protest march which planned to deliver a petition to parliament calling for an end to the crime wave sweeping the country and for the early arrest of the schoolboys' murder or murderers.</p>
<p>Police told the crowd they would not be allowed to march on the parliament, but the country's police commissioner would meet them to hear their grievances</p>
<p>The four schoolboys were found hacked to death on a beach on the outskirts of Port Moresby last month in what is believed to be a pay-back killing after a man was stabbed to death at a dance in the capital the night before.</p>
<p>Pay-back killings -- often disproportionate to the original crime -- are part of Papua New Guinea tradition.</p>
<p>But the schoolboy killings have shocked the residents of Port Moresby, one of the world's most dangerous cities where wealthier residents live behind high walls, razor-wire and electronic surveillance.</p>
<p>Rising unemployment and urban drift has led to the growth of urban gangs called &quot;rascals&quot; and a spiralling crime rate which has seen numerous shoot-outs in Port Moresby between rascals and police in the past month.</p>
<p>Last Friday a two-month dusk-to-dawn curfew was imposed across this mountainous, resource-rich country in an attempt to curb crime. Police can also impose special daylight curfews.</p>
<p>Police last month gave permission for the protest march, but said on Wednesday they had stopped it under the new curfew laws.</p>
<p>Assistant Police Commissioner Philip Taku said on Wednesday he was considering a gun amnesty to coincide with the curfew.</p>
<p>Taku also said police were checking whether guns used by rascals were of army issue, after claims that some defence force members might be selling arms to the gangs.</p>
<p>He also said police were checking whether marijuana drug runners were bringing arms into the country from Australia, Indonesia and the nearby Solomon Islands.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAPNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT MORESBY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAPUA NEW GUINEA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
