<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187335" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper headlines - Nov 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper headlines - Nov 13.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- WEN WEI PO -- Chinese President Jiang Zemin said the Communist Party was the determined successor of the Kuomingtang revolutionary leader Sun Yat-sen.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG DAILY NEWS -- Chinese Vice-Premier and Foreign Minister Qian Qichen will come to Hong Kong on Friday to host a conference of the Selection Committee, which will pick the Chief Executive who will succeed colonial Governor Chris Patten.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO DAILY -- A Chinese official admitted recently that in the first nine months of the year, the financial income of the central government was 18.4 percent less than that of provisional governments.</p>
<p>-- The third most serious mid-air crash in history took place near New Delhi on Tuesday night, killing all 351 people aboard the two planes.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES -- Transitional policies had been made to guide the New China News Agency and the Hong Kong and Macau Affairs Office after the handover. The agency will concentrate on managing Communist Party members in Hong Kong and developing a united front.</p>
<p>-- Research by Hong Kong University showed that Chief Executive contender Ti Liang Yang had more public support than Tung Chee-hwa.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC JOURNAL -- Henderson Land said the group had used $10 billion to buy land reserves over the past nine months and was preparing to get involved in two construction projects in China.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- Lee Shau-kee, chairman of Henderson Land and the most influential name in Hong Kong property, said growth in residential prices would slow next year.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong's Dragon Airlines was set to reveal within days that chief operating officer Philip Chan would take up a senior role at Cathay Pacific Airways, the latest step in the localisation of the carrier.</p>
<p>-- Controversy over indirect mainland involvement in a telecoms joint venture involving Hongkong Telecom hints at the pitfalls in triangular business.</p>
<p>-- HONGKONG STANDARD -- The Hong Kong Monetary Authority has drafted guidelines for the Mortgage Corp and expects it to be launched early next year.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441 (c) Reuters Limited 1996</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
