<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187312" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-FAI says 1st 4 months 96/97 profitable.</title>
<headline>RTRS-FAI says 1st 4 months 96/97 profitable.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>FAI Insurances Ltd said on Wednesday the first four months of the 1996/97 (July-June) financial year had been profitable.</p>
<p>&quot;The first four months have beeen profitable. You will appreciate that these figures are only early indicators and developments during the year may have a material effect,&quot; FAI chairman John Landerer told the company's annual general meeting.  </p>
<p>FAI reported a A$10.04 million net profit in the year to June 30, 1996 from a loss of A$89.84 million the previous year.</p>
<p>On October 25, FAI managing director Rodney Adler told Reuters FAI was ahead of budget in the quarter to September 30.</p>
<p>Landerer said today FAI was anticipating further reductions in the compulsory third party (CPT) underwriting losses in the current year.</p>
<p>&quot;A number of initiatives were introduced into our CTP division to improve profitabiltity which included changing the mix of business both at the new business and renewal stages,&quot; Landerer said.  </p>
<p>FAI had noticed a substantial softening in the commercial insurance market during the past year, Landerer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Most rates have fallen, with some companies being particularly aggressive in chasing new business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>FAI had chosen to place greater emphasis on the control and underwriting of quality business, rather than reducing prices, Landerer said.</p>
<p>FAI's home insurance business had continued to improve.</p>
<p>&quot;A new range of products has recently been released which seeks to appeal to a much wider cross section of the community,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Landerer said FAI's wholly-owned St Moritz hotel in New York had its strongest year since its acquisition in early 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;Indications are that the current level of demand should be sustained throughout 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>FAI shares were one cent lower at 69 cents at 11.20 a.m. (0020 GMT).</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
