<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187475" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan bank lending falls in October -- BOJ.</title>
<headline>Japan bank lending falls in October -- BOJ.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Aggregate outstanding lending by Japan's 149 banks dipped 0.5 percent in October from a year earlier to 525.51 trillion yen, the first year-on-year decline since April 1995, the Bank of Japan (BOJ) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A BOJ official said the decline in lending reflected action taken by major banks at the end of the first half of the current fiscal year to forgive massive loans to failed mortgage firms. The first half ended on September 30.</p>
<p>Excluding the loans forgiven, loans outstanding were believed to have increased compared with a year earlier, he said.  </p>
<p>The average total lending balance of Japan's 10 big commercial banks was 242.03 trillion yen in October, unchanged from a year earlier, the BOJ said in a statement.</p>
<p>The average total of three long-term credit banks fell 4.8 percent to 44.67 trillion yen and that of seven major trust banks was down 4.1 percent at 53.73 trillion yen.</p>
<p>The average total of 64 regional banks, meanwhile, grew 2.2 percent to 133.13 trillion yen, while that at 65 second-tier regional banks fell 1.5 percent to 51.95 trillion yen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
