<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187779" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egypt, Eni plan to export gas to Turkey.</title>
<headline>Egypt, Eni plan to export gas to Turkey.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egypt said on Wednesday the Italian energy company ENI had agreed to take part in a project to export Egyptian gas to Turkey.</p>
<p>The Egyptian oil ministry said in the same statement that Egypt also wanted the U.S. company Amoco Corp to participate in the project. ENI and Amoco have been working closely in natural gas fields in and off the Nile Delta.</p>
<p>The statement did not say if the exports would be by pipeline or by tanker.</p>
<p>The Egyptian government newspaper al-Ahram said a pipeline would run to Gaza and then under water to the southeastern Turkish town of Iskanderun, skirting around the coast of Israel.</p>
<p>The organisers of a Middle East economic conference in Cairo said on Wednesday that Amoco, the Turkish company Botas and the state Egyptian General Petroleum Corp (EGPC) would announce a joint venture at 4.30 p.m. (1430 GMT).</p>
<p>Oil industry sources said ENI was not part of the joint venture and that Amoco executives were taken by surprise to hear of the Egyptian oil ministry statement on ENI.</p>
<p>The oil ministry statement said Egyptian Oil Minister Hamdi el-Banbi had met ENI Chairman Gulgielmo Moscato and ENI chief executive Franco Beranbe in Cairo.</p>
<p>&quot;The minister submitted the option inviting ENI participation in the gas exportation project to Turkey... ENI has declared its acceptance of this offer,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>&quot;The parties will finalise the necessary ad hoc agreement with the full participation of Amoco in view of its implementation in the shortest possible time.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The minister expressed his wish that ENI and Amoco should participate in this project on an equal basis and invited ENI management to conclude an agreement with Amoco and EGPC to this effect,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>ENI and Amoco executives will meet after the Cairo conference and the two companies will submit a joint proposal for developing newly found gas fields in Egypt, it said.</p>
<p>Egypt has originally planned to export gas first to Israel, through a pipeline crossing the Gaza Strip.</p>
<p>But in an interview published in al-Ahram on Sunday, Banbi said gas export negotiations with Turkey were more advanced than those with Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;We have negotiated and have almost reached an understood framework with Turkey,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Turkish Energy Minister Recai Kutan will be at the joint venture announcement in Cairo on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Before he left, Turkish officials said he would discuss buying gas from Egypt through either a pipeline under the Mediterranean or by tanker in the form of liquefied natural gas (LNG).</p>
<p>&quot;The deals with Turkey went through really fast,&quot; said one oil industry source at the Cairo conference.</p>
<p>-- Jonathan Wright +20 2 489 0154/5</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
