<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187801" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Nov 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Nov 13.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AN-NAHAR</p>
<p>-Ten MPs handed an urgent draft law to speaker of the parliament Berri demanding a five-month grace period for the mass of private television and radio stations ordered to shut down by the end of this month.</p>
<p>-Israeli shelling wounded two civilians in south Lebanon.</p>
<p>AS-SAFIR</p>
<p>-Lebanon's total public debt reaches 17,983 billion pounds.</p>
<p>-Lebanese businessmen take part in the Cairo economic summit despite Beirut's boycott of the meeting.</p>
<p>-Workers of Lebanon's cargo carrier Trans Mediterranean Airlines (TMA) returned to work following a four month stoppage.</p>
<p>-Despite the negotiations with the Minister of Education, the teachers' unions reiterated that school teachers will go on the one-day strike tomorrow on pay scale demands.</p>
<p>AL-ANWAR</p>
<p>-The new cabinet postponed its first meeting because of differences on the ministerial statement among the members of the statement's members.</p>
<p>-Two new containers of plastic toxic wastes were found in Beirut port and police is searching for their owners.</p>
<p>AD-DIYAR</p>
<p>-A Palestinean delegation will arrive in Lebanon today.</p>
<p>NIDA'A AL-WATAN</p>
<p>-Iran denies that it has any information on the fate of Israeli pilot Arad who went missing in Lebanon in 1986.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
