<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187810" id="root" date="1996-11-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: FEATURE - Business study unites Israelis and Palestinians.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Business study unites Israelis and Palestinians.</headline>
<byline>Tova Cohen</byline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli and Palestinian business students, brought together by a fragile peace, avoid at least one tough subject as they pursue an advanced degree -- politics.</p>
<p>&quot;I really believe that economic ties are a common groundwork for producing long-term peace, and real peace. I think Palestinians in the class see that in the same way,&quot; said Israeli student Jeff Anker.</p>
<p>He is one of 40 students, including five Palestinians from the West Bank and two Jordanians, in an executive Master of Business Administration (MBA) programme offered by Northwestern University's School of Management and the Recanati School of Business at Tel Aviv University.</p>
<p>In the classroom, Anker said, students discuss the fact that politics affects business -- &quot;but we don't get into the politics itself.&quot;</p>
<p>When Tel Aviv and Northwestern decided to create a joint two-year MBA programme for American, Israeli and Arab students, they focused on the Middle East in the belief that business ties can make a significant contribution to the peace process.</p>
<p>What they did not count on was that the programme would be launched at a time when Palestinian and Israeli relations would sink to their lowest level in years.</p>
<p>&quot;We have really hoped this would be a regional programme. We were well on the way to attracting a number of students in the region and were very concerned the recent developments might harm that,&quot; said Donald Jacobs, dean of the Kellogg School.</p>
<p>The school year opened at a time of great tension in the Middle East. In late September bloody clashes between Israeli soldiers and Palestinian police killed 75 people and raised fears for the future of the peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;We feared political tension would influence the programme, we thought some Arab students would cancel. Fortunately, this didn't happen. It is easier to get peace among nationals than among politicians,&quot; said Recanati Dean Israel Zang.</p>
<p>The programme, most of which is held at Tel Aviv, is geared towards executives who continue to work as they study.</p>
<p>The political situation has had repercussions for the programme. One of the biggest headaches for the academic coordinators has been securing entry permits into Israel for the Palestinians.</p>
<p>The Israeli government provides only a limited number of day permits, mainly for Palestinians working in construction and agriculture.</p>
<p>Anker said students have been split into work groups, with one Palestinian, Sa'id Abu Hijleh, in his.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first week we were already faced with the logistical fact that Sa'id had to cross the border every day and because of curfew had to be back every day by a certain time,&quot; Anker said.</p>
<p>&quot;We feel the rules of what's happening around us yet we are trying to work towards the ideal of what will be in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Anker, who is director of product sales for Europe, the Middle East and North Africa at Madge Networks, a multinational maker of computer networking equipment, already has extensive dealings with Middle Eastern businesses.</p>
<p>While employers of the Israeli and American students foot the $16,000 a year tuition bill for their workers, most of the Palestinian and Jordanian students receive scholarships from Israeli organisations and companies, such as Koor Industries, the country's largest industrial concern.</p>
<p>Palestinian students also expresseed a belief that this type of programme could go a long way towards strengthening ties between nations.</p>
<p>&quot;Actually, this is building peace. I know more people, I know how they live. Even though we can't speak in Hebrew, we can communicate in English,&quot; said Abu Hijleh, a consultant for a fund that aids small Palestinian businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope in the near future I will see some (Israeli) students in Al-Najah University (in the West Bank city of Nablus).&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
