<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="187981" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France calls off CIC bank privatization.</title>
<headline>France calls off CIC bank privatization.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS</dateline>
<text>
<p>France called off the $1.9 billion privatisation sale of regional banking group CIC Thursday and accused the management of the bank and its state-owned parent of failing to help with the sale.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Jean Arthuis announced the cancellation of a sell-off tender launched in August, but said that he was determined that the bank would be sold eventually.</p>
<p>CIC, or Credit Industriel et Commercial, is a profitable chain of 11 regional banks whose main customers are medium and large companies and whose sell-off was seen as a prerequisite for the eventual sale of its parent, insurer GAN, to the private sector.</p>
<p>&quot;After serious reflection, the government has decided to call off the privatisation process for CIC,&quot; Arthuis told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;It seemed important that everyone had the necessary time for reflection,&quot; he said, referring to the sale of 67 percent of CIC shares with a book value of about 9.4 billion francs ($1.85 billion).</p>
<p>&quot;The managers of GAN and CIC did not behave in a way to encourage progress in this process,&quot; Arthuis said.</p>
<p>He said he had decided to abandon the privatisation in view of public and staff reactions to the sale but that the government remained determined to sell CIC in the future.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no question of not privatising CIC,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
