<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188006" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: FOCUS - HK's Hang Seng hits 13,000, more records seen.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - HK's Hang Seng hits 13,000, more records seen.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index achieved its first ever close above 13,000 points on Thursday, and analysts said the index may drive deeper into uncharted territory.</p>
<p>&quot;Thirteen-thousand was sort of a target for many short-term people,&quot; said Ted Chen, technical analyst at Technical Data Inc. &quot;It is a good sign.&quot;</p>
<p>The blue-chip index rose 61.11 points on Thursday to set the record close of 13,004.80. It hit an all-time intraday high of 13,009.74 in mid-afternoon.</p>
<p>The index is up 29.1 percent this year as of Thursday's close.</p>
<p>&quot;The benign interest rate environment and the property market really have been driving this market,&quot; said Richard Verin, head of equity trading at CS First Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;The third thing that has contributed to that is the fact that the Chinese economy is looking healthier than it has for a number of years.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said investors were re-rating the Hong Kong market, with the political discount at which local stocks trade in comparison to other Asian markets shrinking as investors anticipate a smooth transition to Chinese rule.</p>
<p>Hong Kong reverts to Chinese sovereignty at midnight on June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;People are more comfortable with China and China risk,&quot; said Verin.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything, people are saying that they should be in Hong Kong because of the exposure to China. People are willing to pay a premium for well-connected, China-related stocks.&quot;</p>
<p>Jake van der Kamp, investment strategist at HG Asia, agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;You are getting a re-rating of the entire market because political fears are dissipating rapidly, the economy is growing quite nicely on all fronts and we are being led by a rise in property prices,&quot; he said. &quot;The trend, I think, is up.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the rise in confidence in Hong Kong had manifested itself in higher property prices. Residential property prices have risen about 20 percent so far this year and are expected to continue moving higher.</p>
<p>&quot;Many analysts predict that in 1997, residential prices may continue to go higher,&quot; said Alex Tang, head of research at Yamaichi International. &quot;This kind of assumption will invite some aggressive buying on property counters.&quot;</p>
<p>Property stocks have a weighting of about 30 percent in the Hang Seng Index.</p>
<p>Verin said there was nothing on the immediate horizon that would change the course of the market and he expected the rally to spread from the property sector into other areas of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;An enormous part of the move is concentrated on a few large stocks,&quot; Verin said. &quot;This move should spread.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said there may be some consolidation at current levels.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly at some point you are going to see the market take a breather,&quot; said van der Kamp. But he said he expected &quot;steady growth up&quot; between now and the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;I have said that I think the Hang Seng will reach 15,000 in the second half of 1997, and the way it is going it will reach that long before the second half of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Chen also said it was possible that investors would take profits at this level.</p>
<p>&quot;But in terms of support, we should expect very good support around 12,200 (corrects level of support),&quot; he said. &quot;At the moment there is no sign that the market has topped out.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
