<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188152" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Potent NYH gasoline takes flight, bypasses US Gulf.</title>
<headline>Potent NYH gasoline takes flight, bypasses US Gulf.</headline>
<byline>Ransdell Pierson</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York Harbor gasoline came alive Thursday afternoon, with conventional unleaded jumping as much as two cents a gallon as differentials swelled on tightness and bullish new inventory data, players said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's wild. The market is crazy,&quot; one New York Harbor trader said, adding brokers were hard-pressed to keep up with firming differentials on most other grades as well.</p>
<p>NYH &quot;M5&quot; winter-grade regular conventional unleaded was traded several times for 4.50 cents over December futures, players said, 1.5 cents firmer than Wednesday values.</p>
<p>Offers on NYH &quot;A5&quot; winter-grade regular reformulated meanwhile vaulted 1.25 cents higher to 5.0 cents over the print, with deals done at four cents over, traders said.</p>
<p>Premium grades shot up even faster as turnarounds left the market short of high-octane blendstocks used to turn regular unleaded into premium, traders said.</p>
<p>Prompt NYH &quot;V5&quot; 93-octane premium was offered as high as 12 cents over the print, compared with differentials of only 8.75 cents late Wedensday, traders said.</p>
<p>Diffs on NYH reformulated &quot;D5&quot; 93-octane premium firmed 2.0 cents to 11 cents over, players said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's just not a lot of barrels,&quot; the trader said, saying that East Coast prices have finally leapfrogged above U.S. Gulf Coast values after two weeks of trailing behind values on Houston's &quot;Refinery Row.&quot;</p>
<p>East Coast differentials tend to be one to three cents firmer than the Gulf Coast because it costs about 2.5 cents to transport barrels north on the Colonial Pipeline from Houston to New York Harbor.</p>
<p>But Gulf Coast diffs have been unusually potent for two weeks, as much as five cents higher than New York, because of tight supply attributed to sundry refinery outages and to lower gasoline production as refineries began maximizing heating oil output in early autumn.</p>
<p>With U.S. Gulf values higher, traders said few barrels have been shipped north to New York in recent weeks because it would have been a losing proposition. That trend, combined with reduced imports to the East Coast, has cut into East Coast supply.</p>
<p>Also not to be overlooked, traders said, were bullish new inventory data. Wednesday's weekly report from the American Petroleum Institute showed a 2.9 million barrel drop in total U.S. gasoline stocks for the week ending Nov 8, and today's EIA report showed a 1.8 million drawdown.</p>
<p>Prices have gone up, traders said, despite the fact that nominations for gasoline shipments are full for most of November on the Buckeye Pipeline BPL.N, parts of which runs from New York Harbor to Pennsylvania and upstate New York.</p>
<p>Gulf Coast &quot;M4&quot; conventional unleaded meanwhile took a breather, with diffs a half cent softer than on Wednesday at about 3.50 cents over December futures as avid buying seen earlier this week by traders and refiners came to a halt.</p>
<p>Distillate differentials were little changed on Thursday, players said, following inventory data showing drawdowns of between 400,000 and 850,000 barrels for the prior week.</p>
<p>December heating oil futures were about 1.25 cents stronger at 1400 EST Thursday, helped by the distillate draw during a time of year when significant builds are the norm.</p>
<p>New York heating oil stocks remain over 30 percent below the comparable period last year.</p>
<p>-- New York Energy Desk, 212 859-1632</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
