<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188285" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Indiana Federal, Pinnacle Financial approve merger.</title>
<headline>Indiana Federal, Pinnacle Financial approve merger.</headline>
<dateline>VALPARAISO, Ind. 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indiana Federal Corp and Pinnacle Financial Services Inc said Thursday their boards of directors have approved plans to merge the two companies.</p>
<p>Under the plan, each Indiana Federal share of common stock will be exchanged for one share of Pinnacle. The companies said the merged financial institution will have nearly $2 billion in assets.  </p>
<p>The &quot;merger-of-equals&quot; will create a company to provide financial services and manage a network of banking centers extending from southwestern Michigan to the Illinois state line, the companies said.</p>
<p>The company will consolidate under the name of Pinnacle Financial Services Inc,  with the holding company headquartered in Valparaiso, Indiana.  The largest subsidiary of the corporation, the merged Pinnacle Bank and Indiana Federal Bank, will continue as Pinnacle Bank and will be headquartered in St. Joseph, Michigan.  </p>
<p>The new corporation will be governed by a 10-member board of directors, five each from Indiana Federal and Pinnacle. Richard Schanze, currently chairman of Pinnacle, will serve as chairman and chief executive of the new company, and Donald Lesch, chairman of Indiana Federal, will be vice chairman, president and chief operating officer, the companies said.</p>
<p>The merger is subject to shareholder and regulatory approvals and will take four to six months to complete, the companies said.</p>
<p>At September 30, 1996, Pinnacle reported assets of $1.018 billion while Indiana Federal reported assets of $809 million.</p>
<p>&quot;With this merger, we will create a financial institution with nearly $2 billion in assets,&quot; Schanze said.</p>
<p>Indiana Federal operates 16 full-service banking centers in Northwest Indiana, and Pinnacle has 17 branches in Southwest Michigan and 14 branches in Lake and Porter Counties in Indiana.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue to aggressively expand our product base and market penetration in our respective Indiana and Michigan markets, along with looking at selective deals in the Chicago suburban area,&quot; Lesch said, adding the new company will expand either through new branches or acquisitions.</p>
<p>--Chicago newsdesk, 312-408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VALPARAISO, Ind."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
