<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188320" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-CAMPESE OFFERED ROUTE BACK TO TEST SIDE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-CAMPESE OFFERED ROUTE BACK TO TEST SIDE.</headline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>David Campese is in line for a test recall after being selected in Australia's team to face Ulster this weekend.</p>
<p>The Wallabies have made three changes to the side who defeated Scotland last weekend, with Campese drafted into the back division in place of Pat Howard.</p>
<p>Tim Horan moves to centre, George Gregan takes over from Sam Payne at scrum-half and Michael Brial replaces Owen Finegan in the back-row.</p>
<p>Campese, axed for the Murrayfield game after making his 100th test appearance in Italy, is desperate to regain his place for the remaining tests against Ireland and Wales on his farewell tour of Europe.</p>
<p>Ulster will be without their two London Irish internationals, fly-half David Humphreys and lock Jeremy Davidson, required for an English league match.</p>
<p>Team - Matthew Burke; David Campese, Daniel Herbert, Tim Horan, Joe Roff; David Knox, George Gregan; Daniel Manu, David Wilson, Michael Brial, John Eales (captain), Warwick Waugh, Andrew Blades, Michael Foley, Richard Harry</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
