<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188339" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: OLYMPICS-ATLANTA GAMES BROKE EVEN, SAY ORGANISERS.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-ATLANTA GAMES BROKE EVEN, SAY ORGANISERS.</headline>
<byline>Martin Langfield</byline>
<dateline>CANCUN, Mexico 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The controversial Atlanta Olympic Games, which cost $1.7 billion to stage, broke even and will probably end up showing a small surplus, organisers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We reported that we have met our goal, which was to break even, and that we will probably have a very small amount of money remaining after we actually close the books sometime this summer,&quot; Games organising committee president Bill Payne told reporters.</p>
<p>He was speaking after delivering a financial report to the International Olympic Committee (IOC), which is holding a four-day meeting at this Mexican Caribbean resort.</p>
<p>Asked whether the surplus would be more than $10 million, Payne replied: &quot;I don't think so.&quot;</p>
<p>He did not give an exact figure. Payne said that outstanding costs, consisting mainly of partial demolition of a stadium and some pending debts, were already covered by money in the bank and were firmly under control.</p>
<p>&quot;These Games cost the taxpayers of Atlanta virtually nothing,&quot; he said, adding that the city would benefit from new paid-for facilities worth about $500 million.</p>
<p>The IOC had expressed concern that the privately-funded Games lacked the usual safety net of state financial support.</p>
<p>IOC director general Francois Carrard welcomed the Atlanta report, saying it was &quot;highly applauded&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The first objective is not to make money, neither to lose money...money should go directly to staging the best possible Games,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>IOC officials have also criticised what some saw as excessive commercialisation of the Atlanta Games, where street vendors hawked all manner of Olympic memorabilia in an atmosphere derided by critics as sadly akin to a flea market.</p>
<p>Payne shrugged off such charges.</p>
<p>&quot;Only in America does the private sector support the Games to this overwhelming extent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier, IOC president Juan Antonio Samaranch stressed the need for continued government involvement in Olympic events, however.</p>
<p>In his opening address, Samaranch said he was glad to see that an Australian government official was heading the organising committee for the 2000 Sydney Olympics.</p>
<p>The presence of Michael Knight, New South Wales Olympics minister, at the helm would be &quot;a useful bridge, a necessary bridge, so that relations between the government and the organising committee are as fluid as possible&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This has been a lesson of the past which we must learn from in the present and in the future,&quot; Samaranch said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANCUN, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
