<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188312" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GOLF-LEHMAN TAKES LEAD IN GRAND SLAM OF GOLF.</title>
<headline>GOLF-LEHMAN TAKES LEAD IN GRAND SLAM OF GOLF.</headline>
<dateline>POIPU, Hawaii 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Open champion Tom Lehman took a one-shot lead over Masters winner Nick Faldo and U.S. Open champion Steve Jones on Wednesday in the rain-delayed MasterCard PGA Grand Slam of Golf.</p>
<p>The four champions of golf's major tournaments completed a round and a half of the scheduled 36-hole tournament at the 6,957-yard, par-72 Poipu Bay Resort golf course with nine holes still to be played on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>Faldo, owner of three Masters and three British Open titles, had completed the first 18 holes Wednesday morning one stroke ahead of Lehman.</p>
<p>Lehman, 37, birdied four of the first six holes of the day's last nine holes en route to a four-under-par 32 for an even 100 total, eight under par.</p>
<p>Faldo shot 34 on the nine for a seven-under 101, while Jones produced the best nine-hole stretch of the day with a six-birdie, one-bogey, five-under 31 that also put him on 101.</p>
<p>The fourth member of the elite group, PGA champion Mark Brooks, stood at one-over-par 109 for the 27 holes.</p>
<p>&quot;I couldn't get zeroed in this morning,&quot; Jones said of his putting. &quot;This afternoon it seemed like everything I looked at went in. It should be a real shootout tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>Lehman agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Nick gave us a little break after running away with it after 12 holes in the morning,&quot; said Lehman, who also won the PGA Tour Championship this season and finished atop the money list with $1,780,159. &quot;It's going to be pretty exciting out there tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>While the rain that wiped out Tuesday's scheduled opening round stayed away Wednesday, the course remained wet and soggy and players were allowed to lift, clean and place their golf balls in the fairway.</p>
<p>&quot;If it's a decent day (Thursday), I think you're going to see a lot of birdies and a lot of low scores,&quot; Lehman said. &quot;I played well and putted well today. I like my chances tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>The winner will pick up $400,000 from the $1 million purse. Second place is worth $250,000, third is $200,000 and last is $150,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="POIPU, Hawaii"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
