<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188355" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: TENNIS-FIVE SEEDS FALL AT ADVANTA CHAMPIONSHIP.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-FIVE SEEDS FALL AT ADVANTA CHAMPIONSHIP.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Five seeded players saw action at the WTA Advanta Championships on Wednesday, and all five lost in the final event on the Tour before next week's Corel WTA Championships.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone's tired,&quot; said Olympic champion Lindsay Davenport, the fifth seed, after losing to fellow American Anne Miller 6-4 7-6 (7-3) in the second round.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the end of the year and all the top players have played a lot of matches. I don't think I played very well and didn't serve well. She played well, but I think it might've been more me than her.&quot;</p>
<p>Second seed Conchita Martinez of Spain was upset 6-2 6-3 by hometown favourite Lisa Raymond. It was the first victory over a top ten player of her career.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't feel too good today,&quot; said Martinez. &quot;I've been sick for about a week and can't seem to recover. I don't know what it is.</p>
<p>&quot;But she played great today and I couldn't get to balls.&quot;</p>
<p>Only three seeds are among the 12 players remaining in the tournament, including top seed Steffi Graf of Germany, who will play American Amy Frazier Thursday. Third seed Jana Novotna of the Czech Republic and eighth seed Barbara Paulus of Austria are the others.</p>
<p>The day of frustration for the seeded players began with fourth seed Anke Huber of Germany, the 1994 winner of this event, wasting a commanding lead in a 3-6 7-6 (7-1) 6-1 loss to American Marianne Werdel-Witmeyer.</p>
<p>Then sixth seed Iva Majoli of Croatia lost to American Chanda Rubin 5-6 6-2 6-1 and seventh seed Mary Joe Fernandez was forced to default to fellow American Kimberly Po because of a sprained right wrist.</p>
<p>The 21-year-old Huber allowed a second-set lapse to revive Werdel-Witmeyer, squandering a 5-3 lead to lose in a tiebreak.</p>
<p>Werdel-Witmeyer, who had never beaten Huber in three previous meetings, took full advantage.</p>
<p>&quot;I played well until the second set at 5-3,&quot; said Huber, &quot;but I just wasn't concentrating enough to finish.</p>
<p>&quot;Then she played better when she saw she had some chances.&quot;</p>
<p>Werdel-Witmeyer, who was sidelined more than four months this year with a wrist injury, agreed.</p>
<p>&quot;I've played very streakily,&quot; said the 29-year-old, who lost in the opening round of 11 successive tournaments earlier this year.</p>
<p>&quot;That's been caused by my wrist. For me my forehand is my best shot and I haven't been able to hit it as well as I can. But for me this is the best way to end the year. Now I'll go home, practice and look forward to next year.&quot;</p>
<p>She added: &quot;When I broke her to get to 5-4 she kind of threw her racket to the chair. It was good to know she was a bit upset.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
