<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188441" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products end mostly up, helped by futures.</title>
<headline>Med oil products end mostly up, helped by futures.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were mostly higher on Thursday tracking recent gains in crude and products futures, traders said.</p>
<p>Gasoline edged higher tracking NWE prices and a firm crude market, but traders said premium unleaded was balanced while lower octane grades were well supplies.</p>
<p>&quot;Essentially there is no buying for November,&quot; said one trader. &quot;There is more supply of lower octane and no buyers.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the arbitrage to the U.S. looked shut but sellers may be forced to look there for buyers.</p>
<p>Naphtha also rose, catching up recent gains in crude. The Med was also seen balanced and traders were awaiting results of the Egyptian tender for 1997, where bids were re-submitted.</p>
<p>Gas oil gained on firmer futures but business was inactive. Discussion was dominated by the announcement of a Turkish tender for 100,000 tonnes of 0.5 percent sulphur for December which traders said would provide direction in an inactive market.</p>
<p>&quot;Sellers are at really high numbers and buyers are saying 'no'. This market is probably overdone but I don't see the sellers coming off until something proves it and their backs are against the wall,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Cargoes were offered at cif high quotes +$3/+$2 into Greece with Italians, Romanians and Bulgarians offered variously at cif high quotes +$1/$2.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cracked fuel was firmer with a deal in the north at $128.50 fob NWE while Dec and Nov swaps sold at $129.50 fob. Paper numbers eased $1-2 but the physical remained strong. High freight rates of up to $11 a tonne result from scarce tonnage.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil was steady with a lack of activity.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
