<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188458" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE gas oil ends up $3 despite drag from Dec Brent.</title>
<headline>IPE gas oil ends up $3 despite drag from Dec Brent.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE gas oil ended up $3.00 a tonne at $219.25 on December but well below the day's high of $223.00 as the expiring Brent contract dragged at it's heels.</p>
<p>Weakness on the expiring Dec Brent crude contract and an unimpressive performance by NYMEX futures took the shine off the market during the afternoon, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Gas oil shot its bolt first thing this morning,&quot; said Alastair Harris of brokers MeesPierson Derivatives in London.</p>
<p>Despite the lacklustre afternoon he added &quot;we are still open to the vagary of the weather and it held well above $217.00 support&quot;.  </p>
<p>Many dealers remain bullish on the physical market where Turkey announced a tender to buy 100,000 tonnes for December. In November it bought 225,000 tonnes. Premiums for physical gas oil held reasonably steady over the day and the some dealers said the large volume of oil delivered against the expired November contract was unlikely to reappear on the market.</p>
<p>Dec Brent, which expires at the close, was down eight cents at $23.81 at 1743 GMT just above the days low of $23.77.</p>
<p>But further forward months were all positive with Jan up nine cents at $23.43 and the next three month 9-12 cents higher.</p>
<p>Dealers said the physical market remains sluggish as dealers await further North Sea loading programmes due on Friday.</p>
<p>Some dealers saw the physical market staying under pressure for a few more days but noted that demand for most oil products remains good. Gasoline snapped $5 a tonne higher during the morning and both gas oil and fuel gained against Brent.</p>
<p>Swaps brokers said the first quarter crack spread between gas oil and Brent has gained 10 cents a barrel over the past couple of days but that the next three quarters were holding steady. &quot;We had good bids all day and the only selling was on physical,&quot; said a broker.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
