<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188571" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Flawed Zambia poll to proceed despite opposition.</title>
<headline>Flawed Zambia poll to proceed despite opposition.</headline>
<byline>Jowie Mwiinga</byline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Zambian court threw out a challenge to President Frederick Chiluba's candidacy on Thursday, clearing the way for disputed elections which seven opposition parties have pledged to boycott.</p>
<p>The November 18 poll has already been dismissed by critics who say a government ban on opposition figures, the rival parties' boycott and the fact that no more than half the eligible voters are registered will make it invalid.</p>
<p>The European Union said last month it would only recognise an election in which all political parties were satisfied.</p>
<p>But despite appeals for a delay, the government appears bent on conducting the presidential and parliamentary elections, Zambia's first in five years.</p>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela on Thursday urged Chiluba to postpone the ballot, and Zimbabwe's President Robert Mugabe voiced his concern over the recent law banning Chiluba's main opponent from taking part.</p>
<p>The opposition's legal challenge to the candidacy of Zambia's president, mounted by four parties, was quickly rejected.</p>
<p>&quot;The law is clear. A petition against the election of a president can only be made after the winning candidate is sworn into office,&quot; Supreme Court Chief Justice Mathew Ngulube said.</p>
<p>Mandela told reporters in Durban he had sent a fax to Chiluba asking him to &quot;postpone the elections in the interests of peace in the country&quot;.</p>
<p>Speaking in Rome, Mugabe said: &quot;Although Chiluba assured us that things are not getting out of hand, it is a matter of concern in the region that...there could be violence which could spill to other countries.&quot;</p>
<p>A law passed by Chiluba's government bans some opposition leaders, particularly former President Kenneth Kaunda, from contesting the presidential elections, on the grounds that they are not native Zambians.</p>
<p>The opposition challenged Chiluba with his own legislation, asserting that he lied about his nationality and parentage on his electoral nomination papers.</p>
<p>The new law, widely seen as aimed squarely at Kaunda whose parents were Malawian, has been severely criticised by political observers and Western donor countries, which have cut or frozen aid to Zambia in protest.</p>
<p>The freeze has already had a telling effect on the country's economy -- one of the world's poorest -- with donor money all but dried up since May. With a foreign debt of $6.4 billion and a per capita GDP of $350, Zambia is now dependent on its much-reduced copper earnings.</p>
<p>Analysts say the combination of the lower copper earnings and the donor freeze on balance-of-payment support implies a larger current-account payment gap than last year's $300 million. Exports are likely to fall and, with weak import demand, the current account deficit will increase.</p>
<p>But Chiluba, who visited Mandela on Tuesday, has vowed to ignore outside pressure.</p>
<p>Ironically the polls will, in a sense, be the most successful in Zambian history, with a record five presidential candidates and eight political parties.</p>
<p>But of the 4.6 million elligible voters, only 2.3 million are registered, and of those only about a million have collected their cards. Analysts say at best 23 percent of the voting population will cast their ballots -- and many could be deterred by heavy rains predicted for Monday in several parts of Zambia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
