<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188526" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada to send team to Zaire ahead of rescue.</title>
<headline>Canada to send team to Zaire ahead of rescue.</headline>
<byline>Malina Poshtova Zang</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada was sending an advance team to Zaire on Thursday to assess the dire situation in Central Africa and it announced that Lt. Gen. Maurice Baril will command a multinational humanitarian relief force.</p>
<p>Defence Department spokesman Capt. Ian Stock said the advance team would have between 24 and 30 members, some of whom would come from the special Disaster Assistance Response Team (DART) formed by the Canadian military to provide humanitarian relief at home and abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;They basically have to assess the situation and come back and make recommendations,&quot; Stock said. He said he did not know how long they would stay in Zaire but the main multinational force would not leave for Africa until the team was back.</p>
<p>Canada last weekend offered to lead a multinational relief force to help more than a million mainly Hutu refugees in Zaire who face hunger and disease after being displaced by weeks of fighting between Tutsi rebels and the Zairean army.</p>
<p>The United States agreed in principle on Wednesday to participate in the force, which will number around 10,000 troops, of which 1,500 will be Canadian. The mission was expected to last four to six months but the U.N. special envoy to the region, Canadian Ambassador Raymond Chretien, said on Wednesday he expected troops will have to remain in Central Africa longer than that.</p>
<p>Baril, the commander of Canada's land forces, will lead the operation, Defence Minister Doug Young said on Thursday. He has served as the military adviser to United Nations Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali and is considered Canada's top soldier.</p>
<p>He has been widely tipped to succeed Gen. Jean Boyle, Canada's former chief of defence staff who resigned last month over an investigation into atrocities committed by Canadian peacekeepers during a 1993 mission in Somalia.</p>
<p>The choice of Baril, who has experience serving with a U.N. peacekeeping mission in Cyprus, to lead the relief force demonstrates Canada's desire to restore its image as one of the world's leading peacekeeping nations -- an image that was tarnished by the Somalia mission.</p>
<p>Baril, 52, has served in the military for 35 years, some of which he spent in the elite Canadian Airborne Regiment, which was disbanded in disgrace following the Somalia mission and several other incidents.</p>
<p>The international community, under enormous pressure to help alleviate the crisis, is at a loss over how to avoid a re-run of 1994 problems when it effectively fed and gave sanctuary to many of those, primarily Hutus, responsible for the slaughter of an estimated 800,000 people, mainly Tutsis, in Rwanda. That mission was also under Canadian command.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
