<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188527" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Saskatchewan Wheat Pool plans hog deals.</title>
<headline>Saskatchewan Wheat Pool plans hog deals.</headline>
<byline>Gilbert Le Gras</byline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Saskatchewan Wheat Pool plans to diversify into hog production by courting pork producers into tapping their expertise ahead of a &quot;dramatic&quot; rise in output, a SWP director told Manitoba Pool Elevators delegates.</p>
<p>&quot;A number of communities are meeting with management. We hope to be a catalyst to dramatically increase the amount of pork that's produced in Saskatchewan. We would provide some of the expertise to producers,&quot; SWP director Marvin Wiens said.</p>
<p>Canada's largest grain handler said in August it planned to expand into the pork industry.  </p>
<p>Canada exported 341.05 million tonnes of pork in calendar 1995, valued at C$967.55 million, Agriculture Canada statistics show.</p>
<p>&quot;We will do it either through community groups and there has been discussion of doing it through something like the closed cooperative systems they have in North and South Dakota,&quot; Wiens told the MPE delegates.</p>
<p>MPE delegates presented a motion at their annual meeting that MPE consider diversifying into the hog industry.</p>
<p>Manitoba was the first Canadian province to end its hog export monopoly July 1, 1996.  </p>
<p>Saskatchewan is investigating whether it should end its marketing monopoly.</p>
<p>World pork consumption was forecast to increase by 750,000 tonnes a year while Saskatchewan's annual output is 100,000 tonnes, Wiens said.</p>
<p>&quot;Saskatchewan is one of the lowest cost areas to raise pork. We envision this (production) growing dramatically in the next couple of years,&quot; Wiens said.</p>
<p>Manitoba produced 2.5 million hogs, Saskatchewan produced 1.0 million and Alberta produced 3.0 million hogs last year, the respective hog marketing groups said.</p>
<p>Alberta will be the second Canadian province to do so when it ends its hog export monopoly December 2, 1996, Alberta's Agriculture Minister Walter Paszkowski said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Strategic planning is part of the role that I play at Alberta Wheat Pool and whether that's an issue we should be involving ourselves in is a decision we'll be making a little further down the road,&quot; AWP first vice-president John Pearson told Reuters.</p>
<p>-- Winnipeg bureau 204 947 3548</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100119">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
