<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188692" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine coal output seen sharply down on forecasts.</title>
<headline>Ukraine coal output seen sharply down on forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Output at Ukraine's coal mines, which churned out hundreds of millions of tonnes every year in Soviet days, was forecast on Thursday to fall sharply this year to 71 million tonnes from a planned 90 million tonnes.</p>
<p>First Deputy Coal Minister Dmytro Herasymchuk told Reuters ageing equipment, lack of funds and a wages crisis had caused the drop, but the government would press on with plans to develop the industry in the eastern Donbass region.</p>
<p>&quot;The plan was 90 million tonnes for this year but real output will be 71 million tonnes,&quot; he said. &quot;The financial situation in the industry is extremely difficult. Miners are being paid irregularly. The industry has been hit by strikes.&quot;</p>
<p>About 200,000 miners went on strike in July over four months' unpaid wages, and the govenment has promised to solve the salaries' problem by September.</p>
<p>According to trade union estimates about one million miners are owed up to $600 million in wages.</p>
<p>Output, once up to 200 million tonnes a year, has fallen gradually every since the Soviet Union fell apart, reaching 95 million tonnes two years ago and 84 million tonnes last year.</p>
<p>Herasymchuk said 25 pits would be closed by the end of 1997 as part of plans to close a total of 60 pits by 2000 and modernise more profitable mines -- with the help of part of a $300 million World Bank credit.</p>
<p>Many mines in Donbass were developed at the turn of the century and under Soviet industrialisation before World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;We are already in the process of closing unprofitable pits. They are very old and mostly have no coal left,&quot; Herasymchuk said. &quot;But at the same time seven new mines will be opened next year. Three of them will be extremely profitable.&quot;</p>
<p>Experts say only 76 of Ukraine's 270 pits are profitable and able to operate without subsidies. The government currently pays $34 in subsidies for every tonne of coal produced.</p>
<p>Herasymchuk also said exports had fallen sharply.</p>
<p>&quot;We sold some coal to Belarus and Moldova -- just several hundred thousand tonnes to each country per year. But it's almost nothing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last month Bulgaria signed a contract to import 1.5 million tonnes of coal from Ukraine in 1997.</p>
<p>Ukraine imports up to 20 million tonnes of cheap coal from Poland and Russia mostly for its coal-fired electricity plants.</p>
<p>-- Rostislav Khotin, Kiev newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
