<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188784" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo sugar output seen at 270,000 tonnes.</title>
<headline>Yugo sugar output seen at 270,000 tonnes.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia expects its sugar output to reach 270,000 tonnes this year, which would be enough to meet domestic demand and secure even some surplus, the federal ministry for agriculture said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to harvest 2.35 million tonnes of sugar beet which would enable us to produce enough sugar to satisfy domestic demand,&quot; Milan Prostran of the ministry for agriculture told Reuters.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia's annual sugar consumption stands at 250,000 tonnes, well below the pre-war level of 460,000 tonnes in 1991.</p>
<p>By mid-November, Yugoslav sugar refineries had processed almost 1.73 million tonnes of sugar beet, producing about 200,000 tonnes of sugar.</p>
<p>He said 15 sugar refineries with an annual capacity of 900,000 tonnes of sugar were exceeding the country's needs.</p>
<p>But Prostran said the government would have to reduce their production because the former Yugoslavia's markets had disappeared.</p>
<p>But its policy was not to sell the refineries as Hungary and Poland did but to use them for processing sugar and re-exporting it, he said.</p>
<p>According to Prostran's figures, this year's sugar beet harvest is well above the 1.69 million tonnes reaped in 1995 when the average yield was 27.45 tonnes over 62,000 hectares.</p>
<p>-- Gordana Kukic, Belgrade Newsroom, 381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100128">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
