<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="188992" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Chase Manhattan takes HK$.</title>
<headline>ASIAN DEBT MARKETS - Chase Manhattan takes HK$.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian debt markets offered a few new issues on Thursday.</p>
<p>Chase Manhattan Asia said it had chosen lead managers and market makers for the HK$1.5 billion three-year floating rate certificates of deposit issue for Chase Manhattan Bank Hong Kong Branch.</p>
<p>Chase Manhattan Asia is the sole arranger and bookrunner of the transaction.</p>
<p>Lead managers and bookrunners are Chase Manhattan Asia, HSBC Markets, Sakura Finance Asia, Schroders Asia and Union Bank of Switzerland.</p>
<p>The FRCDs will carry a coupon of 27.5 basis points over the one-month Hong Kong Interbank Offered Rate.</p>
<p>Application will be made to the Hong Kong Monetary Authority to accept the certificates as eligible for its Liquidity Adjustment Facility, or discount window.</p>
<p>Chase didn't reveal fees, but bankers said the issue is expected to pay an all-in return &quot;in the low 30s.&quot;</p>
<p>Bankers said that spread would be a bit narrower than those offered by outstanding LAF paper.</p>
<p>Still, some syndicate managers said they expected the deal to go well, given the good name of the issuer and the popularity of LAF paper.</p>
<p>International Bank of Asia launched its HK$500 million FRCD, seemingly timing the launch to coincide with the announcement that the bank had received a first-time rating from Standard and Poor's Corp.</p>
<p>S&amp;P assigned the FRCDs a rating of BBB. It also gave the bank a long-term counterparty rating of BBB and a short-term counterparty rating of A3.</p>
<p>The FRCDs pay an all-in return of 79 basis points, a level bankers thought was reasonable for a BBB-rated bank.</p>
<p>International Bank of Asia last week said it would raise HK$495 million via a share issue.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, Indonesia's Bank Danamon launched a US$100 million floating rate note issue via Merrill Lynch International. The notes have a final maturity of five years but can be put on the third anniversary.</p>
<p>The notes were launched and re-offered at par to float at 90 basis points over the London Interbank Offered Rate.</p>
<p>With fees, the all-in return to the put is 100 basis points.</p>
<p>Some bankers said the issue compared favorably with the three-year FRCD for Bank Bali, another Indonesian private bank. That deal paid an all-in of 92.5 basis points.</p>
<p>Bank Danamon is rated Ba2 by Moody's Investors Services. Bank Bali is unrated.</p>
<p>In other news, Philippine Central Bank governor Gabriel Singson said he was considering a proposal to issue a 30-year bond in the international market.</p>
<p>The Philippines in September launched a 20-year bond in exchange for Brady bonds.</p>
<p>-- Andrea Ricci (852) 2843-6371 fax (852) 2845-0636</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
