<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189065" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Cairo conference says carry out peace agreements.</title>
<headline>Cairo conference says carry out peace agreements.</headline>
<byline>Jonathan Wright</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Middle East economic conference ending in Cairo on Thursday called for quick implementation of Israeli-Palestinian agreements and an end to Israel's closure of the Palestinian territories.</p>
<p>But a three-page declaration in the name of the governments and businessmen who attended did not specifically blame Israel for the economic hardships of Palestinians or say explicitly that a Middle East settlement should be based on land for peace.</p>
<p>It said the participants were committed to peace on the terms of reference of the Madrid peace conference in 1991 and U.N. resolutions 242 and 338, which Arabs understand to mean land for peace. The Israeli government does not agree.</p>
<p>More than 2,500 delegates from 92 countries took part in the three-day conference, which discussed regional economic cooperation and economic reform in individual countries.</p>
<p>It was the third conference of its kind since Israel and the Palestinians made their first agreement in 1993. The first was in Casablanca in 1994, the second in Amman in 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Participants in the Cairo Economic Conference expressed their unwavering commitment to the achievement of a just, lasting and comprehensive peace in the Middle East, on the basis of the terms of reference of the Madrid Peace Conference, established by U.N. Security Council resolutions 242 and 338.</p>
<p>&quot;They reaffirmed their determination to build upon the agreements reached among the parties and underlined the utmost importance of the faithful and expeditious implementation of the those agreements by all parties in particular on the Israeli-Palestinian track,&quot; the declaration said.</p>
<p>&quot;They noted with concern that the already weak Palestinian economy is suffering from restrictions and closures which hinder the daily movement of Palestinian labour and trade.</p>
<p>&quot;They reiterated that removing restrictive measures and closures will prevent the decline of, and contribute positively to the performance of the Palestinian economy,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa and Klaus Schwab, president of the World Economic Forum, said that during the conference businessmen and governments reached deals worth a total of $10 billion but did not give details of them.</p>
<p>The biggest one publicised was a memorandum of understanding on exports of Egyptian liquefied natural gas to Turkey. The project will cost between $2 billion and $4 billion.</p>
<p>Moussa told a joint news conference with Schwab that the Cairo conference had succeeded in putting regional cooperation into perspective, shifting the focus away from integrating Israel into the Middle East economy.</p>
<p>&quot;Arab-Arab cooperation is the backbone. That doesn't exclude cooperation with others under the right conditions but we don't want any one country to be the centre,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Peace has conditions, fulfil them. Otherwise there will not be peace, however many deals are signed,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
