<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18904" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Copper ends sleepy LME steady, still ranging.</title>
<headline>Copper ends sleepy LME steady, still ranging.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper prices traded in a narrow $10 range on Wednesday on the LME, closing another subdued session little changed and still trapped in a wider technical band, traders said.</p>
<p>News that workers at Codelco's Salvador mine in Chile voted to go on strike from Saturday to demand wage rises did little to excite as output is just 85,000 tonnes a year. More impact is likely if there were to be a stoppage at Chino in the U.S.</p>
<p>Spreads softened for most of the day before ending at $32/42 backwardation, basis cash/threes, against $29/34 at one stage.</p>
<p>However, there is always the possibility of a flare up in nearby premiums, with September options declared next Wednesday and some crunch prompts falling due after that.</p>
<p>Generally, prices are seen in a broad range between $1,900 and $1,970 in the medium term with banks capping both ends of the band. A tighter $1,915/50 collar will serve as a jobbing range, traders added.</p>
<p>Last kerb business was at $1,943 a tonne, down just $1 from Tuesday's kerb close.</p>
<p>Aluminium activity was low-key, although the market's stability back above the $1,480 level was encouraging. The last trade was at $1,486.50, a $4.50 gain.</p>
<p>Nickel business was confined to a narrow range as well, with prices edging towards the highs to close at $7,350, a $10 gain from Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lead retained earlier gains above $800, which were notched up by Far Eastern buying and short-covering, closing at $805, a $10 advance.</p>
<p>Analysts were also watching developments at Gold Fields Namibia operations at Tsumeb which have been hit by strike action. The lead and copper smelters have been shut down.</p>
<p>Zinc trade was slow, both in futures and in the physical sector, and last LME business was at $1,024, down just $1.</p>
<p>Tin market conditions were equally slow, but prices held steady on the kerb, closing at an unchanged $6,175. Alloy was $7 higher at $1,285.</p>
<p>--Martin Hayes, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
