<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189093" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. readying for new Bosnia force - NATO chief.</title>
<headline>U.S. readying for new Bosnia force - NATO chief.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States is preparing to take part with as many as 8,000 troops in a new international force of up to 30,000 in Bosnia next year, NATO Secretary General Javier Solana said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Yes. Leave it at that,&quot; Solana told reporters when asked if he had been given a positive signal by U.S. Vice President Al Gore in a White House meeting on Bosnia on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Spokesmen at the Defence and State Departments said, however, that Gore had made clear to Solana that no final decision had been made. &quot;The Vice President does not believe he signalled a decision to the secretary general,&quot; Pentagon spokesman Ken Bacon told reporters.</p>
<p>Solana said that U.S. participation was essential and he now expected Washington to send &quot;7,000 to 8,000 troops&quot; to a new NATO-led force until the end of 1997, replacing 50,000 in the international peace implementation force (IFOR) now being removed from Bosnia.</p>
<p>He predicted the force would be out of Bosnia by the end of next year and said it would include 5,000 German troops and also Russians and forces from at least a dozen NATO countries.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton, who this week tentatively agreed to send 1,000 U.S. troops to Zaire in an international refugee rescue mission, was to discuss Bosnia with his top security advisers at the White House on Thursday night.</p>
<p>White House spokesman Mike McCurry said he expected Clinton to raise some questions about the new force at that meeting. But he said, &quot;We've said all along that we would be looking at ways of preserving the gains in Bosnia.&quot;</p>
<p>McCurry said he expected Clinton to address both the Bosnia and Zaire troop issues publicly before leaving on Friday on a Hawaiian vacation.</p>
<p>Defence Secretary William Perry told reporters at the Pentagon that he expected a quick decision by Clinton but declined to predict what that decision would be.</p>
<p>&quot;I am optimistic,&quot; Solana said. &quot;I have the impression that the final (U.S.) position will be taken in the coming hours, and the position to my mind will be a positive response to continue.&quot;</p>
<p>The United States is beginning to pull its 15,000-member IFOR contingent out of Bosnia and is sending in about 7,500 troops from Germany to cover the withdrawal. Many of those protective troops are currently scheduled to remain in Bosnia until mid-March and are now expected to be the vanguard of U.S. participation in the new force.</p>
<p>Solana said he expected formal approval for the new force by NATO political leaders in Brussels next Monday and expected the replacement force for the current IFOR would total &quot;about 25,000 on the ground -- between 20,000 and 30,000.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If things evolve in the appropriate manner, I don't think we should stay there longer than another year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But many members of Congress and private defence analysts note Clinton and other Western leaders promised when NATO sent troops to war-torn Bosnia last year that only a year would be required for peace and IFOR would be gone by this December.</p>
<p>Clinton, elected to a new four-year term, has in recent months declined to commit U.S. troops to a new force, saying he wanted to first examine the mission of the force.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
