<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189026" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore oil products rise, China seeks gas oil.</title>
<headline>Singapore oil products rise, China seeks gas oil.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore oil products prices rose across the barrel on Thursday along with firmer crudes, with gas oil leading the pack as China and Indonesia hungry for the product, traders said.</p>
<p>They said physical gas oil sellers were sidelined despite a high bid from a Singapore trader at $31.00 a barrel for 240,000 barrels lifting early December. Sellers expect prices to rise higher as China was seen seeking more gas oil for December arrival. The market was also firm on talk that Indonesia's December demand has not been satiated. Swaps December gas oil traded higher at $30.30 and $30.40, up from $29.83 Wednesday.  </p>
<p>Taiwan was heard to have sold 0.3 percent sulphur diesel for December lifting around $29.92 per barrel fob Kaohsiung.</p>
<p>Jet fuel also rallied with 130,000 barrels traded between a Singapore trader and a Dutch trader at $30.95 per barrel for December 10-14 lifting fob. Traders said the jet fuel market continued to get support from North Asia and Indonesia, but supplies in Singapore were also healthy.</p>
<p>Singapore naphtha rose sharply on the back of the five-year high in the open-specification forward contract in Japan. November swaps leaped to $30.80/$31.10 from Wednesday's $30.20/$30.35.  </p>
<p>Strong demand from North Asia provided the momentum with a Sri Lankan cargo of 125,000 barrels of naphtha lifting November 28-29 heard likely to head to Japan after being awarded at 62 cents a barrel below Singapore quotes. The last Sri Lanka cargo, lifting October 19-20, was sold at at much larger discount of $1.18. Gasoline cargoes lifting end November-early December were bid/offered at higher levels -- 92-octane bid at $25.30 a tonne up from $24.75 Wednesday and 95-octane at $25.50/$25.70 and 97-octane bid at $26.60. Fuel oil firmed in line with crudes and enquiries from Chinese buyers. A fall in stocks also boosted sentiment, traders said. -- Singapore Newsroom (+65-870-3084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
