<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189174" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electric futures rally on natgas, firm cash.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electric futures rally on natgas, firm cash.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity futures settled sharply higher Thursday on surging natural gas prices and firm cash values in the western U.S.</p>
<p>Despite outlook of weather being mild in most of the West next week, the electricity complex leaped toward the upper end of its recent trading range.</p>
<p>In late over-the-counter (OTC) activity, December California-Oregon Border (COB) futures were discussed at $24.50-$24.75 a megawatt hour (MWh), compared with a settlement of $24.83.</p>
<p>January COB finished at $22.25, up $1.25. Deferred COB contracts ended 25 cents to $1.13 higher.</p>
<p>December OTC Palo Verde (PV) futures were talked at $21.80-$22.00, versus a close of $23.00.</p>
<p>January PV finished at $20.25, up 75 cents. Outer PV months ended 65 cents to $1.00 higher.</p>
<p>Daily, peak power prices at COB was assessed late Thursday at $22.50-$22.30, and at PV $20.00-20.50.</p>
<p>The next-day market was bolstered by stronger natgas prices and Bonneville Power Administration withholding offers for Friday.</p>
<p>December gas delivered at the San Juan/Blanco Hub finished the day at $2.49-$2.53 per million British thermal units, compared with Wednesday's range in the $2.36-$2.37.</p>
<p>Natgas prices around the U.S. jumped today on bullish storage data, cold weather in the eastern U.S. and rumor of a problem at the Gulf Coast pipeline.</p>
<p>Most brokers and marketers expected the electricity complex would take cue from gas prices.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
