<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189239" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Southeast spot power pressured by warmer temp.</title>
<headline>U.S. Southeast spot power pressured by warmer temp.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wholesale electricity prices in the southeastern U.S. were pressured Thursday by forecasts of temperatues in the winter moderating from recent winter-like lows.</p>
<p>&quot;The milder temperature is the main driving force,&quot; said a Southeast power marketer, adding that some regional utilities planned to restore operation by this weekend to some generating units that were idled for seasonal maintenance.</p>
<p>For Friday, the Southeast excluding Florida was predicted to receive peak temperatures in 40s-60s Fahrenheit and off-peak temperatures in 20s-40s. The Florida pennisula was expected to enjoy mild temperatures in the 70s-80s during the day and 50s-60s in the evening.</p>
<p>&quot;We had pretty flat loads today. This weekend, there's a very likelihood we'll have rain and clouds,&quot; said a Florida trader.</p>
<p>Among Florida utilities, peak, firm electricity scheduled for Friday was valued near $24.00 a megawatt hour (MWh) and for Saturday near $22.00-$23.00, compared with Wednesday's $23.50 quote for Thursday.</p>
<p>Peak, firm power for Friday delivery into northwestern portion of Tennessee Valley Authority's (TVA) territory were pegged near $23.00, down from Wednesday's $25.00-$28.00.</p>
<p>Firm, next-day power for delivery into northwestern TVA during Friday's light load hours was discussed near $15.00, compared with a range of $14.50-$15.00 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>TVA was reportedly offering peak, next-day electricity at $27.00-$28.00.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, firm, peak power prices for Friday was quoted near $26.00 with offers talked as high as the low-$30s.</p>
<p>Today's values at the Ga./Fla. border compared with Wednesday's $26.00-$28.00.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak at the Ga./Fla. border for next-day delivery remained flat in the $16.00-$18.00 range.</p>
<p>Peak, firm power scheduled for Thursday's delivery in the Florida pennisula ended near $23.50 after talked as high as $28.00 in early trading, traders and marketers said.</p>
<p>--R Leong, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
