<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189270" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bishops recall Bernardin's humble leadership.</title>
<headline>Bishops recall Bernardin's humble leadership.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Zabarenko</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cardinal Joseph Bernardin's brother bishops recalled him Thursday as a humble leader who guided American Roman Catholics through turbulent times and faced death &quot;not as an enemy but as a friend.&quot;</p>
<p>Hours after the 68-year-old prelate died of cancer in Chicago, Bishop Anthony Pilla of Cleveland, president of the National Conference of Catholic Bishops, remembered him as a personal friend.</p>
<p>&quot;I think very genuinely every bishop feels they've lost a friend, because that's the way the cardinal would relate,&quot; Pilla told reporters at the conclusion of the group's semi-annual meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;He was a cardinal who was probably one of the most prominent ecclesial figures of our century in this country ... and yet anyone, the least experienced, the youngest member of this conference I'm sure would be made to feel comfortable with Cardinal Bernardin,&quot; Pilla said. &quot;There were no airs, no sense of superiority here, no arrogance; this was a wonderful, wonderful, warm human being whom we miss.&quot;</p>
<p>Bernardin, an active member of the conference for 30 years and author of one of this session's key documents, managed to make his presence felt even though his last illness prevented his attendance.</p>
<p>In what may have been one of his last written communiques, he sent a hand-written note to Pilla before the conclave opened on Monday: &quot;I had every hope of attending the bishops' meeting in Washington. Unfortunately, my rapidly deteriorating health will not make it possible ... My only request of them is that they pray that God will give me the strength and grace I need each day ... Peace and love, Joseph.&quot;</p>
<p>In a move considered typical of Bernardin's low-key, conciliatory manner, the cardinal took up the thankless task of refining the structure and mission of the bishops' group, involving such nitty-gritty but important points as whether laypeople could serve alongside bishops on committees.</p>
<p>In their final act this session, the bishops approved an amended version of Bernardin's document on structure.</p>
<p>His overall legacy was one of finding common ground between the conservative and liberal elements of the U.S. church during the upheavals occasioned by the Second Vatican Council and the societal changes that began in the 1960s, the Rev. Thomas Reese of Georgetown University said.</p>
<p>Reese, who observed the bishops' proceedings, singled out Bernardin's chairmanship of a committee that wrote a pastoral letter on war and peace noting ethical and moral principles that should be applied to the possibility of nuclear war.</p>
<p>In a statement announcing Bernardin's death, Pilla said, &quot;His acceptance of death not as an enemy but as a friend could only come from the deep faith of a person who knows that our destiny is not for this life only.&quot;</p>
<p>To Auxiliary Bishop John Dunne of Rockville Centre, N.Y., who learned of Bernardin's death at an early morning Mass, there was a real sense of loss, he said, but also &quot;there's a sense of his spirit and I think that will prevail.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
