<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189393" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Food summit told more disasters like Zaire loom.</title>
<headline>Food summit told more disasters like Zaire loom.</headline>
<byline>Vera Haller</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.N.-sponsored World Food Summit confronted the Zairean refugee crisis on Thursday, amid warnings that failure to feed people will spawn future disasters of conflict and hunger elsewhere.</p>
<p>The summit, convened by the world organisation to adopt a global plan to fight hunger into the next century, debated the Zaire crisis and a global population explosion.</p>
<p>As the United States and other countries readied troops for a relief force in eastern Zaire, the country's Deputy Prime Minister Mutombo Bakafwa Nsenda accused the world of indifference.</p>
<p>In a speech during the summit's second day, he spared no-one's feelings in accusing the international community of ignoring the starving Hutu refugees in the eastern part of his country.</p>
<p>&quot;The fate of one million human beings is being played out amid the total indifference of the international community and of the governments of the places these people are from,&quot; the minister said.</p>
<p>He called on countries to send any aid for the refugees, who fled past ethnic slaughter, to Rwanda and Burundi to encourage their return home.</p>
<p>Burundi Prime Minister Pascal Firmin Ndimira told Reuters in an interview that he agreed its refugees should be encouraged to come home but said those guilty of massacres or genocide must be separated out.</p>
<p>Other speakers at the summit, held at the headquarters of the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO), spoke of horror in the Zaire situation.</p>
<p>&quot;How many times over is the deprivation being experienced by the people in Zaire repeated around our globe...because of poverty, political conflict and natural disaster?&quot; Australian primary industries and energy minister, John Anderson, asked.</p>
<p>He announced his country had pledged money for logistical support for humanitarian efforts in eastern Zaire. It was not clear whether this aid was associated to a multinational force being organised to go to Zaire to help the refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;Emergency measures alone will not rid the world of hunger,&quot; New Zealand's Agriculture Minister Lockwood Smith said.</p>
<p>He urged national governments to adopt policies that would bring political stability and respect fundamental rights in an effort to remove the root causes of poverty and hunger.</p>
<p>As the summit's delegates focused on what could be done to resolve the world's newest human disaster in Zaire, the representative of Bosnia-Herzegovina thanked the international community for its help during the recent Balkans war.</p>
<p>&quot;The generous assistance of the world community in supplying food to our people helped us to survive and overcome the horrors of aggression,&quot; Agriculture Minister Refik Numic said.</p>
<p>The five-day summit opened on Wednesday with adoption of a plan to halve the world's hungry from 840 million people in 20 years. FAO says the main challenge to meeting that goal is increasing food production by 75 percent over the next 30 years as the planet's population of 5.7 billion grows by a further three billion by the year 2030.</p>
<p>A forum of non-governmental organisations (NGOs), meeting at a former railway station a short distance away from FAO, adopted a statement to be presented to the summit in which it said the key to future food security lay with small farmers.</p>
<p>The statement urged more investment in local producers so countries could become food self-sufficient and said the summit had to be followed by concrete steps.</p>
<p>&quot;The shame of global hunger and malnutrition compels action by all,&quot; the NGO forum said.</p>
<p>Not all the messages delivered to the summit's delegates were filled with doom.</p>
<p>An Italian dressed as a vivid orange carrot paraded on the nearby ancient Capitoline Hill carrying a message for world leaders at the nearby food summit -- &quot;Don't eat meat!&quot;</p>
<p>The seven-foot-high (two metres) &quot;Chris P. Carrot&quot; drew bemused glances from tourists admiring Michelangelo's 16th century palace on Piazza Campidoglio. He toured the square, bearing placards declaring &quot;Eat your veggies, not your friends&quot; and &quot;Life for All.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
