<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189381" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: FCB Financial, OSB Financial to merge.</title>
<headline>FCB Financial, OSB Financial to merge.</headline>
<dateline>NEENAH, Wis. 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>FCB Financial Corp. and OSB Financial Corp., two Wisconsin-based savings institutions, said Thursday they have agreed to a merger of equals.</p>
<p>The surviving company, to be known as FCB Financial, will be based in Oshkosh, Wis., and have 13 full service branches. It will be the largest independent thrift based in Wisconsin's Fox River Valley, with assets of more than $500 million, about $390 million in loans, $310 million in deposits and mortgage holdings of more than $220 million.</p>
<p>Under the definitive agreement, FCB will offer 1.46 shares of its stock for each OSB share in a tax free purchase.</p>
<p>Neenah, Wis.-based FCB had 2.46 million shares outstanding and OSB had 1.11 million shares outstanding as of Sept. 30.</p>
<p>The banking subsidiaries of each firm are expected to merge and operate under the name Fox Cities Bank FSB.</p>
<p>The companies said they expect the combination of various functions and other economies of scale to result in annual pretax cost savings for the combined firm of about $800,000.</p>
<p>The merger is expected to be completed during the 1997 second quarter, subject to approval by both companies' shareholders and regulators.</p>
<p>On Nasdaq, FCB's stock closed Wednesday at $19.25, while Oshkosh, Wis.-based OSB rose 75 cents to $25 at mid-morning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEENAH, Wis."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
