<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189422" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Canadian general's headquarters to be in Goma.</title>
<headline>Canadian general's headquarters to be in Goma.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Lt-General Maurice Baril said on Thursday he intended to establish his headquarters for the new humanitarian intervention force in Central Africa in Goma, Zaire.</p>
<p>Speaking at a news conference, the commander for the new international force said, &quot;The proposed location of my main headquarters will be in Goma. Of course Goma is partly if not all destroyed and I will have rear elements of my headquarters that will be both in Kigali and Kinshasa.&quot;  </p>
<p>Baril said he intended to establish staging bases for the force, which eventually would number more than 10,000 troops, in Kigali, the capital of Rwanda, Entebbe in Uganda and Nairobi, the Kenyan capital with two &quot;secure forward operations bases&quot; in Goma and Bukavu in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;Self-contained units will radiate outward from those forward operating bases to facilitate the delivery of humanitarian aid,&quot; he said, adding that the force would open a land corridor from Rwanda, Uganda or Kenya to get the humanitarian supplies and the soldiers to eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Gordon Smith, Canada's deputy foreign minister, stressed that the multinational troops would not use force to separate militias or &quot;intimidators&quot; from others in the refugee camps or to disarm any of the fighters lodged there because the level of violence would be high and refugees would be among the victims. But he said if anyone got in the way of the force &quot;they would be dealt with accordingly&quot; under &quot;robust rules of engagement.&quot;</p>
<p>He also said that the force was expected to be in the region for a maximum of six months after which &quot;a follow on force&quot; would be needed. Diplomats said this would probably be a U.N.-led force with some of the same troops going to the region now.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
