<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189449" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Mbeki calls on EU to honour spirit of trade deal.</title>
<headline>Mbeki calls on EU to honour spirit of trade deal.</headline>
<byline>David Fox</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African Vice-President Thabo Mbeki called on Thursday for the European Union to honour the spirit of a 1994 agreement to negotiate a trade deal.</p>
<p>Mbeki, in Belgium to address an ACP group (Africa, Caribbean, Pacific) meeting, said the EU's stance in trade negotiations had been disappointing.</p>
<p>&quot;The initial position as outlined in their opening negotiation mandate is not one which lives up to our expectations nor to original promises,&quot; Mbeki told a meeting of ACP ministers.</p>
<p>South Africa, considered significantly more economically advanced than most ACP countries, is currently negotiating membership of the 70-nation group, made up primarily of former European colonies which have special trade privileges with the EU.</p>
<p>South Africa is due also to start soon the final stages of what have been lengthy negotiations with the European Commission -- the EU's executive -- for a formal free trade agreement.</p>
<p>Talks have been bogged down by differences over South African agricultural products and also the special relationship it has with its Southern African neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;Our democracy, stability, reconstruction and development remain linked to that of the region and the continent as a whole,&quot; Mbeki said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our negotiations for improved market access and economic cooperation with the European Union proceeds from this strategic objective.&quot;</p>
<p>The EU is concerned that South Africa's membership of regional economic and customs organisations -- which are striving for regional free trade -- will allow goods from countries with which the EU does not have an agreement to make their way to Europe.</p>
<p>Mbeki earlier met European Commission President Jacques Santer and Joao de Deus Pinheiro, the commissioner responsible for relations with South Africa, to discuss relations.</p>
<p>A statement from the commission said both sides had agreed &quot;the regional dimension&quot; of any agreement would require regular consultations.</p>
<p>Mbeki, who has also been to France, Britain Germany, Italy, Ireland and Norway during this visit, said part of his mission was to remind European leaders of their commitment to help develop and reconstruct South Africa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
