<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189472" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian police arrest former ENI executive.</title>
<headline>Italian police arrest former ENI executive.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The former vice president of energy group ENI, Alberto Grotti, was arrested on Thursday after a court upheld a jail sentence against him on graft charges, police said.</p>
<p>The charges had also involved former prime minister Bettino Craxi and eight other defendants.</p>
<p>Grotti, sentenced to just over four years in jail for a scandal over bribes paid by insurance firm SAI to win contracts from ENI, was arrested in Rome.</p>
<p>Italy's highest court on Tuesday confirmed Grotti's conviction as well as sentences against Craxi, financier Sergio Cusani and seven others.</p>
<p>Police are still searching for convicted former ENI executive Antonio Sernia and insurer Aldo Molino.</p>
<p>Cusani, who helped expose the rampant graft in Italy's political old guard, turned himself in to prison authorities on Wednesday to begin serving a four-year sentence for his role in the ENI-SAI saga.</p>
<p>Craxi, who lives in self-imposed exile in Tunisia, was sentenced to 5-1/2-years for illegal party financing. Premier from 1983 to 1987, the former Socialist has more than 25 years of jail sentences accumulated against him from other trials.</p>
<p>Italy's vast graft scandals broke in February 1992 when the manager of a Milan old people's home confessed to taking bribes on behalf of Craxi's Socialist party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
