<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189580" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India begins burying air disaster victims. [CORRECTED 18:51 GMT]</title>
<headline>India begins burying air disaster victims. [CORRECTED 18:51 GMT]</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>CHARKHI DADRI, India 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Adila Fatima, aged four months, was the first to be laid to rest on Thursday as India began burying or cremating the victims of the world's worst mid-air collision in which 349 people died.</p>
<p>She was buried in a tiny plot alongside two 40-foot (13-metre) trenches excavated by a mechanical digger for mass graves for up to 100 people in a roadside Moslem graveyard beside farmland about 80 km (50 miles) west of New Delhi.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't found the bodies of her parents,&quot; her uncle, Abdul Nadeem, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Next to be buried was Rehana Akhtar, mother of eight-month-old Timur, who was accompanying her husband Tahir back to his job in Saudi Arabia after a holiday extended for a week when her son caught pneumonia, uncle Mushirul Azim said.</p>
<p>Scores of remains have not been identified following the collision on Tuesday between a Saudi Arabian Airlines Boeing 747 with 312 people abaon board and a Kazakh Ilyushin Il-76 transport aircraft carrying 37 people.</p>
<p>The burials continued until well after sunset. Pickup trucks brought the bodies, swaddled in white sheets, to the graveyard. Relatives wept by the light of hurricane lanterns.</p>
<p>Two Moslem clerics said prayers as about 30 bodies were lowered into one grave, and 18 in the other.</p>
<p>Nearby 15 Hindus were laid on a 25-foot (eight-metre) round pyre, clarified butter was poured over their bodies and they were cremated as a senior Hindu priest chanted hymns in Sanskrit.</p>
<p>Leaders of the two religions met to decide which bodies were Moslem and which were Hindu. In some cases, guesses were made because many bodies were unidentifiable after the fiery crash.</p>
<p>They decided 76 bodies would be buried as Moslems and 15 cremated as Hindus (corrects by removing extraneous sentence &quot;About 91 Hindus would be cremated&quot;). Three Christians, none identified, were buried in a local Christian cemetery.</p>
<p>Stunned and weeping relatives were still trying to identify their loved ones, many of them charred and some mangled beyond recognition after the two aircraft plummeted to earth.</p>
<p>&quot;The sky has eaten up my daughter,&quot; wailed the distraught mother of Saudi Airlines stewardess Maneesha Malhotra, who was on her last flight before resigning to enter a major Indian beauty pageant.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't even found anything that belongs to her.&quot;</p>
<p>People examined belongings spread out on tables under awnings outside the local hospital in hope of identifying some possession of a relative.</p>
<p>Authorities said 32 bodies were still among the wreckage of the Saudi jumbo spread over four sq km (1.5 sq miles) and three cranes were lifting chunks of it in hope of finding them.</p>
<p>&quot;Bodies with clearly recognisable features are in the civil hospital, where their families can come and identify them,&quot; said senior police official V.B. Singh. &quot;There's no deadline for their disposal, but we asked doctors to help preserve them.&quot;</p>
<p>About 122 bodies had been identified, officials said. Relatives had claimed 105. Some had been taken away, others were being embalmed for the last journey home.</p>
<p>A Saudi Arabian Airlines plane would carry the 13 crew members and one Saudi passenger on the Saudi jumbo jet home on Friday, an airline official said in Jeddah.</p>
<p>The Saudi airliner and the incoming Kazakh plane collided seven minutes after the Saudi 747 had taken off from New Delhi at nightfall on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Aviation experts said the cause of the crash could be known in the next two weeks. Indian officials denied that inadequate ground equipment or misunderstood instructions from the control tower were to blame.</p>
<p>Authorities have not yet released an official passenger list indicating nationalities.</p>
<p>All 37 victims on the chartered KazAir plane, which was taking businessmen to Delhi to buy goods, have been identified. A Saudi newspaper said the victims on the Saudi airliner included 215 Indians, 13 Saudis, and three Pakistanis.</p>
<p>Nepal said there were 53 Nepalis on board, most of them headed for jobs as manual labourers, drivers and plumbers. There were three Americans and one Briton aboard, officials said.</p>
<p>At least 60 bodies were mutilated beyond recognition after the Saudi airliner cut a deep crater in a mustard crop field.</p>
<p>Bodies were being kept on ice blocks in a nearby hospital. Horse-drawn carriages drew up with newly made wooden coffins.</p>
<p>Speculation on the cause of the tragedy ranged from inadequate equipment at New Delhi airport to pilot misunderstanding of instructions from ground controllers.</p>
<p>Yogesh Chandra, the top civil servant at India's Civil Aviation Ministry, ruled out both. He said the transcript of the final conversations between the pilots and ground control showed both understood their instructions.</p>
<p>The transcript, which Chandra read to reporters, showed the pilots of both aircraft appeared to have understood instructions to maintain altitudes 1,000 feet (300 metres) apart.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARKHI DADRI, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
