<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189655" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: FEATURE - Hope for Kabul's blind in midst of war.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Hope for Kabul's blind in midst of war.</headline>
<byline>Tim Johnston</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mohammed Ashoq has not been able to work for a year. He had to close his barber's shop in a small town southwest of Kabul when his eyesight began to fail.</p>
<p>But now he hopes to re-open his shop.</p>
<p>&quot;I had great difficulties. I could not see well and my work depended on my eyes. But, God willing, I will re-open my shop soon,&quot; said Ashoq.</p>
<p>The source of Ashoq's hope is the Noor eye hospital in Kabul. In a converted private house -- the hospital was destroyed some years ago in the fighting -- doctors and nurses perform operations, conduct eye tests and prescribe medication.</p>
<p>In another facility Noor provides rehabilitation for blind people, many of them victims of the seventeen-year-old war which has intensified in recent weeks as radical Islamic Taleban fighters battle forces loyal to the ousted government.</p>
<p>Tom Little is project manager for the International Assistance Mission (IAM), which supports the hospital with doctors and material.</p>
<p>In a curtained cubicle he tests Ashoq's sight with a lightboard on which are painted a number of &quot;E's&quot; rotated so that they are facing up, down, or back to front.</p>
<p>&quot;In Afghanistan blindness was regarded as a stigma, almost as a judgement from God,&quot; Little told Reuters. &quot;There were no facilities, and very little in the way of rehabilitation for the blind.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard enough to get a job here if you are sighted, but almost impossible if you are blind.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen drivers who can hardly see anything, but they are forced to carry on working to earn a living,&quot; Little said.</p>
<p>IAM has been supporting the Noor hospital for 30 years.</p>
<p>&quot;We try not to get involved in politics,&quot; says Little. &quot;We do sometimes get into trouble with governments, but it is not because we are favoring the other side.</p>
<p>&quot;The main problem is the war. We build up a facility and it gets destroyed, so we build it up again and again it is destroyed.&quot; he says.</p>
<p>&quot;We train staff and they are killed, or they leave. Over the last 15 years we trained a lot of women, because they were the only ones around. Most of them are still working, but it is difficult.&quot;</p>
<p>One of the first edicts of the Taleban on their takeover of Kabul in late September was to ban women from the workplace, but enforcement appears to have been relaxed slightly.</p>
<p>Despite Afghanistan's ever-present political uncertainties, IAM is still expanding.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, they managed to restart their lens-grinding shop. When it is fully operational, most lens prescriptions will be fabricated in Kabul.</p>
<p>The previous facility was destroyed when it was engulfed by the factional fighting that broke out after the Moscow-backed government in Kabul fell to the anti-communist mujahideen in 1992.</p>
<p>The machinery -- some of it 50 years old -- was shipped from the United States. &quot;The whole outfit cost us $23,000. It was shipped to Karachi (in Pakistan), then it was put onto a truck and then somehow we managed to get it through the front lines into Kabul,&quot; says Little.</p>
<p>&quot;We are training up the technicians to operate the machines and it should become self-supporting.&quot;</p>
<p>To sustain itself, Noor charges for all but emergency sight-saving operations.</p>
<p>However, by Western standards, their products are not expensive. Spectacles start at 26,000 afghanis ($1.50) a pair and a small bottle of eye drops is 1,200 afghanis (7 cents).</p>
<p>For people like Mohammed Ashoq, it is a price well worth paying. &quot;For a year I have lived off my savings, and now they are almost finished. Without this clinic I would not have been able to go back to work.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
