<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189606" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - November 14.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - November 14.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for Reuters by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi. Tel:3326806, 3326813, 3326849  Fax:+91-11-3351006 E-mail:</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Hindustan Times</p>
<p>MORE THAN 300 AIR CRASH BODIES RECOVERED</p>
<p>Salvage operations continued at the wreckage site of the two Saudi Arabian and Kazakhstan aircraft that collided near Delhi on Tuesday. More than 300 of the 351 bodies of passengers and crew were retrieved from the debris. The government named Justice R.C. Lahoti, a sitting judge of the Delhi High Court, to head the judicial inquiry into the disaster. Official sources said the black boxes of both the planes had been recovered. The boxes would reveal significant information about the causes behind the mid-air collision. The Flight Data Recorder of both the planes had also been recovered, sources said.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>PRUDENTIAL LAUNCHES FUND FOR EMERGING MARKETS IN ASIA</p>
<p>The British-based Prudential Corporation has announced the launch of InvestDirect Asia (PIDA), a $1-billion fund dedicated to investments in emerging markets in Asia. It is aimed at making direct investments in Asia, especially India, China, and Vietnam. The PIDA will source funds from Prudential's own businesses in Britain and Asia. The fund will provide capital for infrastructure projects and for growing companies in Asia. The PIDA will start off in early 1997, with an initial funding of $130 million. The fund underscores Prudential's long-term commitment to Asia and commitment to boost its long-term investments in India.</p>
<p>CALL RATES SHOOT UP TO 11 PCT</p>
<p>Call money rates rose to 11 percent from the previous close of nine percent. Money market dealers, who were expecting call rates to drop to 3-4 percent levels this week, following the second phase of the Cash Reserve Ratio cut on Saturday, were surprised by the high call rates. The tight call money markets had a dampening effect on the government securities market. The gilts market witnessed few trades. Prices dropped by 50-60 paise on the shortest dated securities. Since traded volumes were small, prices were not indicative, dealers said.</p>
<p>IMPORT RESTRICTIONS TO GO</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram said India would lift quantitative restrictions imposed on imports in four years. This would lower import tariff to the Asian level and to global levels in the next few years, he said. Regarding the fears of foreign investors about investing in India, he said foreign investment proposals worth $5 billion had been cleared in the last few months. This showed that India was committed to pursue a proactive policy towards foreign direct investment, he added.</p>
<p>TAX ON DIVIDENDS MAY BE REVIEWED</p>
<p>The finance minister asked the Central Board of Direct Taxes to set up a cell to expand the tax-payer base. He suggested accessing lists of sales tax assessees and owners of vehicles, houses and telephones for this purpose. The minister also said the inclusion of a chapter on property evaluation in the Income-tax Act might be reviewed as it had yielded little revenue. Hinting at a review of the tax on dividends, he asked the annual Income Tax commissioners' conference to suggest if the system of double taxation of dividends should be changed or modified.</p>
<p>ELECTRONIC ENTERTAINMENT INDUSTRY DELICENSED</p>
<p>The Cabinet Committee on Economic Affairs approved the proposal to delicense the entertainment electronics industry. The decision would include production of items such as video cassette recorders, colour televisions, compact disc players and tape recorders. The delicensing move would provide opportunity to entrepreneurs to set up units all over the country depending on market requirements. The process of deregulation and delicensing would be continued, official sources said.</p>
<p>ING BARINGS BULLISH ON STATE-RUN FIRMS</p>
<p>In its November report on India, ING Barings said it believed the stock market was going to form a long-term bottom, recognising recessionary trends and evaporating corporate earnings growth. Early recessionary signals included falling foreign trade growth, low tax collections, rising inventories, growing deposits and falling advances by banks and a downward growth rate of industrial production since the second quarter of 1996. It advised investors to restructure their portfolios to overweight shares of state-run firms and underweight private sector businesses. Barings recommended investors to buy oil, refineries, telecommunications, banks, utilities and petrochemicals and sell automobiles, cement and steel.  </p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>STOCKS JUMP ON FIRST DAY OF NEW YEAR</p>
<p>Stocks rallied to help the Bombay bourse sensitive index gain 55 points to close at 3135.69 points. Wednesday was the first day of the Samvat year, the first day of an Indian almanac considered auspicious for business. The National bourse index closed at 896.84, gaining only 5.57 points over the previous close. The jump in indices was largely due to short covering and expectations of good results from some blue chip companies in the next 10 days.</p>
<p>MAJOR OIL REFINERIES FACE PARTIAL SHUTDOWN</p>
<p>Public sector refineries at Cochin, Madras and Bongaigaon may face a partial shutdown due to liquidity crunch. The petroleum ministry raised the alarm in view of the growing outstandings of these refineries from the oil pool account. The ministry said, Mangalore Refinery and Petrochemicals could also face the same fate. The Indian Oil Corporation, the sole canalising agency for crude, also faced an acute liquidity crisis. The outstandings due to oil companies may touch 136 billion rupees by the end of this financial year. The oil pool account itself is into high deficit due to rising global oil prices. The ministry said unless domestic oil prices were raised to reduce the oil pool account deficit, there would be a shortage of petroleum goods in the near future.</p>
<p>DOWNTREND IN US IMPORTS OF INDIAN TEXTILE</p>
<p>U.S. imports of textile products from India grew by a sluggish 11 percent in 1995, a U.S. International Trade Commission report said. Compared with other South Asian countries, India's performance was quite poor. U.S. imports from Bangladesh and Sri Lanka grew 24 and 21 percent, respectively. Pakistan matched India's 11 percent figure. According to the report, U.S. imports of Multifibre Agreement (MFA) products from India increased from $1.12 billion in 1992 to $1.61 billion in 1995. From January 1, 1995, the trade governed by MFA was replaced by Agreement on Textiles and Clothing (ATC) as part of the World trade Organisation (WTO) agreements. The U.S. textile and apparel trade may be less restrictive under the ATC. India, being a WTO country, is likely to benefit from this.</p>
<p>SMALL SCALE INDUSTRIES TO GET WIDER SCOPE</p>
<p>The Expert Committee on Small Enterprises, set up by the government, is considering a proposal for expansion of the definition of small scale units from two to three categories. The committee is looking into the possibility of creating a third category for micro-enterprises in addition to the two existing categories for tiny and small enterprises. It is also considering the proposal to raise the limit on investment in plant and machinery for defining these different categories of small scale enterprises.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>ITC EXECUTIVES DENIED BAIL</p>
<p>Former ITC chairman J.N.Sapru, chairman emeritus K.L.Chugh and four other ITC executives were denied bail in the 3.5 billion rupee foreign exchange regulations' violation case. Meanwhile, BAT Industries, ITC's parent company, and financial institutions decided against a quick revamp of the board of the beleaguered cigarette giant. The two were preparing a joint report for the company's board meeting scheduled for November 15, 1996. The meeting will take stock of the new developments after the Enforcement Directorate found evidence against ITC regarding foreign exchange violations and its impact on the company.</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>TATA TECHNODYNE, FLUOR DANIEL SIGN PACT</p>
<p>Tata Technodyne, the consortium of five Tata engineering firms, signed an MoU with Fluor Daniel-India, the Indian arm of the U.S. based construction major Fluor Daniel. The two companies have agreed to cooperate in engineering, procurement and construction work in core sectors like steel, power, hydrocarbons, ports and cement. Technodyne was formed as a holding company earlier this year with the merger of Tata Korf, TRF Ltd, Tata Construction and Project Services, Stewarts and Lloyds and Tata MANN GHH. Technodyne would bid for contracts in the core industrial sector while consortium members continued functioning as separate units, sources said.</p>
<p>LYONNAIS LINES UP HUGE INVESTMENTS</p>
<p>Credit Lyonnais Securities Asia will invest between 10 and 15 percent ($600 million/$900 million) of its total allocation of $6 billion in the Indian capital markets on a long-term basis. This was stated by Michael McCoy, the managing director of Credit Lyonnais Securities Asia. McCoy said the Indian markets were facing a slump, but recent developments could improve the sentiment. He welcomed the setting up of the depository and the government's efforts to ease the liquidity crisis. McCoy said the settlement and transfer process in the bourses should be made smooth to attract the foreign financial institutions into the country.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
