<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18968" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: NEC takes Johnnic stake in landmark deal.</title>
<headline>NEC takes Johnnic stake in landmark deal.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo American Corp of South Africa Ltd said on Wednesday it had reached agreement for the National Empowerment Consortium (NEC) to acquire a significant stake in industrial holding company Johnnies Industrial Corp Ltd.  </p>
<p>Anglo American and its associate De Beers currently hold 47.4 percent of Johnnic.</p>
<p>With effect from July 1, 1996, the NEC will purchase an initial shareholding of at least 20 percent in Johnnic at 50 rand per share.</p>
<p>The black empowerment group will also have the option to purchase additional shares to take its stake up to 35 percent. The option is valid for 18 months and the price of shares under the option will be the 60-day average price seven days prior to exercise, discounted by five percent.</p>
<p>Johnnic shares closed on Wednesday at 56.00 rand.  </p>
<p>Up to six percent of Johnnic's issued share cpaital will be made available via a retail offering by the NEC to smaller NEC members and others within the black community, at the same price as the initial purchase, Anglo and the NEC said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>Both parties will contribute shares to a voting pool comprising 35 percent of Johnnic, in such a way that:</p>
<p>- the NEC will control the voting rights of all the shares in the pool;</p>
<p>- Anglo will have certain minority protection rights;</p>
<p>- the shares in the pool will be subject to reciprocal pre-emptive rights.</p>
<p>The NEC will have a five-year right of first refusal to remaining Johnnic shares held by Anglo and De Beers and Johnnic's board of directors is to be reconstituted to comprise 20 members, of whom 10 will be nominated by the NEC.  </p>
<p>The most important suspensive condition of the deal is obtaining a ruling from the Securities Regulation Panel that the NEC will not have to make a comparable offer to other Johnnic shareholders should it acquire a stake of 35 percent or more.</p>
<p>The NEC will also have until October 28 to conduct a due diligence investigation into the affairs of Johnnic. During that period it will also finalise the funding required for the purchase of the initial tranche of Johnnic shares.</p>
<p>Johnnic's assets include a 13.9 percent stake in South African Breweries, 26.4 percent in Toyota South Africa, 27.5 percent in Premier Group and 43.0 percent of Omni Media, which controls Times Media .</p>
<p>The NEC said it would not be giving any contractual undertakings on editorial independence for Times Media titles, which include Business Day, Financial Mail and Sunday Times. But it said it would discuss the issue of assuring independence with editorial staff.</p>
<p>Anglo said late in 1994 it intended to sell off its holding in Johnnic, which was unbundled from the JCI group of companies in May 1995.</p>
<p>Anglo said the deal with the NEC, representing 50 different black interest groups, met its criteria for black economic empowerment.</p>
<p>The deal, worth some 2.7 billion rand for the 35 percent stake, is the largest black empowerment venture to date.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
