<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189646" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan forex reserves seen swelling by December.</title>
<headline>Pakistan forex reserves seen swelling by December.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's liquid foreign reserves, now at $670 million, could reach $1 billion by December, despite a widening trade gap and a cut in the country's credit ratings, analysts and bankers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan will be able to manage to raise the cash reserves up to the $1 billion mark by December,&quot; analyst Nauman Sheikh of KASB &amp; Co predicted.</p>
<p>Foreign reserves, excluding gold and special drawing rights, fell to $573 million on October 31, but jumped to $670 million on November 7. Bankers expect the upward trend to continue.</p>
<p>&quot;Though the interbank forex market is short of dollars and the trade deficit is alarming, restoration of investor confidence has resulted in forex inflows from abroad,&quot; said one foreign banker, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>Battered Pakistani markets have taken some heart from the November 5 dismissal by President Farooq Leghari of Benazir Bhutto, who was replaced by Meraj Khalid as interim premier.</p>
<p>The foreign banker said economic and political uncertainty in September and October had prompted individuals to withdraw an estimated $200 million from forex bank accounts, sending the six-month forward dollar premium to a record 0.76 rupee.</p>
<p>The premium has since dropped to the 0.50 to 0.65 rupee range, he said.</p>
<p>The chief forex dealer at a local bank said the government had attracted an estimated $150 million from some Middle East-based banks, out of which $75 million had already been placed in a special deposit of the central bank.</p>
<p>In October, Muhammad Yaqub, governor of the State (central) Bank of Pakistan, offered a 17 percent annual return to banks bringing in foreign currency deposits from abroad in an effort to replenish depleting reserves.</p>
<p>He said banks could get the 17 percent return on the rupee equivalent of foreign currency they deposited in a special central bank account between October 22 and November 28.</p>
<p>Bankers said foreign banks had told the central bank they would bring in about $350 million to exploit the offer, but the commitments shrank to $150 million after Moody's Investors Services Inc cut Pakistan's credit ratings on November 6.</p>
<p>&quot;The downgrading was a major shock to all foreign banks operating in Pakistan,&quot; one banker said. It had made it harder to arrange forex deposits for Pakistan in markets abroad.</p>
<p>He said the downgrade had slowed inflows into the central bank's special account, but added that local banks were trying to bring in around $50 million to benefit from the high yield.</p>
<p>Sheikh said resumption of a stalled $600 million standby loan from the International Monetary Fund, on which an agreement is expected soon, would boost confidence in Pakistan's finances.</p>
<p>&quot;We think if Pakistan gets the $160 million in the two delayed tranches of the standby loan and some progress is made on negotiations for a new extended structural adjustment facility, things will start looking better,&quot; Sheikh said.</p>
<p>Analyst Amir Peracha said the trade deficit, which surged to a provisional $443 million in September from $264 million in October, was likely to start narrowing from November as the impact of the latest rupee devaluation begins to show.</p>
<p>The central bank knocked 7.86 percent off the rupee's dollar value on October 22. It has kept the rate unchanged since then.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
