<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="18988" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURUNDI: Graves stand out in Burundi's largely hidden war.</title>
<headline>Graves stand out in Burundi's largely hidden war.</headline>
<byline>Corinne Dufka</byline>
<dateline>KIRIBA, Burundi 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hutu peasants in one small area of central Burundi have shown reporters mass graves which they say contain the bodies of 77 villagers killed by the Tutsi-dominated army after its coup on July 25.</p>
<p>Peasants in one area of Giheta district in the troubled province of Gitega said on Tuesday they buried and had made lists of the names of the dead -- 75 Hutus and two Tutsis.</p>
<p>A few graves, hidden in banana plantations, were marked by simple Christian crosses woven from reeds. Others were unmarked.</p>
<p>&quot;The soldiers came and they installed an armoured personnel carrier on the top of the hill. When my mother saw it she fled and they shot her and she died,&quot; said Gaspar Berakumenya, adding she was killed at Gisarara hill, next to Kariba hill.</p>
<p>The journalists were not able to verify reports by civilians that other recent mass graves littered the surrounding hills.</p>
<p>The London-based human rights group Amnesty International said last week 4,050 unarmed civilians were buried across Giheta after being killed by the army between July 27 and August 10.</p>
<p>It said troops came ostensibly to obtain information on rebel movements but apparently after villagers said they knew nothing soldiers gathered them together and gunned them down.</p>
<p>It said the 4,050 killed by the army were among more than 6,000 people killed in Burundi since the coup which deposed Burundi's president, a member of the Hutu majority.</p>
<p>Burundi's new Tutsi military ruler, Pierre Buyoya, who has said elements of the army were guilty of excesses, denied the Amnesty International report as exaggerated. But he added he could not be expected to bring peace to Burundi overnight.</p>
<p>He says the coup was aimed at putting an end to killings.</p>
<p>Soldiers escorted the journalists to Giheta district and took notes, questioned and listened to witnesses, apparently underlining Buyoya's promise to tackle long-standing impunity in Burundi.</p>
<p>The Hutu peasants, watched by the soldiers, pointed out the mass graves near Kiriba and explained how their relatives were killed.</p>
<p>&quot;Around 10 a.m. we were building a house for my son who was going to get married,&quot; said an old man at Kiriba hill who declined to give his name but said his son Antoine was killed.</p>
<p>&quot;Suddenly we heard gunfire and everyone building the house fled. But my son didn't have time to flee. When I came back some days later I found his body.&quot;</p>
<p>The peasants said outrage led them to break the silence that normally surrounds killing in one of Africa's most violent but least visible wars. &quot;The truth must be known,&quot; a villager told Reuters.</p>
<p>Farmers said they listed 25 people buried at Kiriba hill and 35 on a section of neighbouring Gishuha and Gisarara hills. There were also graves for 10 women and children and graves for seven other people, including two Tutsis.</p>
<p>Soldiers at Kiriba accused the Hutu peasants of manipulating the numbers in a bid to exaggerate the extent of the killings.</p>
<p>They said they had retrieved a Kalashnikov assault rifle, a pistol and two-way radio at Kiriba after battling Hutu rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;Local civilians are used as human shields (by rebels) and sometimes they get caught in the crossfire,&quot; said Buyoya's spokesman Jean-Luc Ndizeye in the capital Bujumbura on Tuesday.</p>
<p>More than 150,000 people have been killed in massacres and three years of vicious civil war in Burundi which have prompted fears among international leaders of an outbreak of killings on a scale similar to neighbouring Rwanda's genocide in 1994.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIRIBA, Burundi"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURUNDI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
