<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189868" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Greycoat seeks more details from Moorfield.</title>
<headline>Greycoat seeks more details from Moorfield.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chairman of British property company Greycoat Plc told shareholders at an extraordinary meeting on Thursday that the board had asked for a more detailed proposal from smaller rival Moorfield Estates which has proposed a paper merger of the two firms and a demerger of key assets.</p>
<p>Michael Beckett told the meeting -- called to vote on a different proposal by rebel shareholders to sell off the company's assets -- that &quot;your board has asked Moorfield to let us have a full and detailed proposal. If and when it arrives we will consider it carefully.&quot;  </p>
<p>Saying that he wished to use the opportunity to clarify the situation, Beckett said that the initial Moorfield proposal received a week ago had been &quot;vague and in outline only&quot;.</p>
<p>But he said demerger, at the heart of Moorfield's plan, was something that the company felt would face major obstacles.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to make it abundantly clear that a demerger is something that we considered in great detail only nine months ago and have kept under review since. Our conclusion was, and remains, that there are major technical and financial obstacles to a demerger which are unlikely to be capable of being overcome without the sacrifice of significant shareholder value.&quot;  </p>
<p>After making his chairman's address, Beckett introduced the main reason for the meeting -- to consider a resolution by rebel shareholders led by Brian Myerson of Active Value Advisors to seek purchasers for the company's assets forthwith.</p>
<p>He said that he would call for a poll on that resolution when it came about, but in the meantime Myserson sought to adjourn the meeting today in order allow the Moorfield proposal to be considered by all shareholders.</p>
<p>A quick show-of-hands vote at the meeting was against the move, but Myerson said he wanted a detailed poll of all shareholders and this was expected to be done later in the day.</p>
<p>The meeting was suspended for a time and was due to reconvene at 1330 GMT.</p>
<p>If the proposal for an adjournment is rejected, however, the meeting was still due to vote on Myerson's original resolution.</p>
<p>This idea is backed by rebel shareholders who include the UK Active Value Fund, IMP UKAV Inc and Chaddesley Investments, which together control 11 percent of the company. They argue it would significantly enhance shareholder value.</p>
<p>However, Myerson has also said that the Moorfield option should also be considered in case it turns out to be the better option. -- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
