<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189971" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Palestinians to put $800 mln programme to donors.</title>
<headline>Palestinians to put $800 mln programme to donors.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Palestinian Authority will ask donors for $800 million towards its public investment programme for 1997 at a consultative group meeting in Paris next week, Palestinian minister Nabil Shaath said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The Authority, which runs the Gaza Strip and West Bank, has increased the portion of that allocated to private sector development to 20 percent from six percent this year, he told the Middle East economic conference in Cairo.</p>
<p>Shaath, minister of economic planning and international cooperation, did not give a figure for this year's public investment programme but said donors had disbursed about $1 billion of the $3 billion they pledged after Israel and the Palestinians made their first agreement in 1993.</p>
<p>But much of the donor grants and remittances by Palestinians this year have gone on keeping the Palestinians alive after the Israelis closed the borders of the Palestinian areas on security grounds.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a devastating year,&quot; Shaath said. &quot;It was not just a question of physical closure...but also of destruction of the rules of the game -- political and economic pressure when we need all support to get ahead.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The closure is also absolutely inconsistent with why Israel is here. Israel is here to tell all the Arab partners: 'Give me free trade in your countries, give me free access to your projects, give my people free access to your lands'.</p>
<p>&quot;This calls upon Israel to give free access to Palestinian people inside their territory, to give Palestinian people free trade opportunities, and to allow a real mechanism whereby the Palestinians independently build their own future but jointly build the future of this region.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking forward...to financing the new investment programme, always hoping that the closure will be over and the peace process will be on rails so that we can use it in catching up with the delays we have had over the last year,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
