<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="189975" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE - Johnsburg Central School Dist, NY.</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE - Johnsburg Central School Dist, NY.</headline>
<text>
<p>SUMMARY NOTICE OF BOND SALE</p>
<p>				  $3,050,000</p>
<p>		   JOHNSBURG CENTRAL SCHOOL DISTRICT</p>
<p>				(WARREN COUNTY)</p>
<p>				   NEW YORK</p>
<p>GENERAL OBLIGATION SCHOOL DISTRICT (SERIAL) BONDS, 1996</p>
<p>	  (BOOK-ENTRY-ONLY)  (CALLABLE)  (BANK QUALIFIED)</p>
<p>SEALED PROPOSALS will  be received  and considered  by the President of  the Board  of Education  of Johnsburg  Central School District, Warren County, New  York at the offices  of Fleet Bank, Private Banking Department, Mezzanine Level, One  East Avenue, Rochester, New York   14638, until 11:00  A.M.,</p>
<p>Prevailing Time, on at which time  and place the  bids will be  opened, for  the purchase IN FEDERAL FUNDS at not  less than par and  accrued interest of $3,050,000 School District (Serial) Bonds, 1996, (the &quot;Bonds&quot;), maturing on June 15 of each year as follows:</p>
<p>				   MATURITIES</p>
<p>1997 . . . . . $200,000 2002 . . . . . $225,000  2007 . . .  $225,000</p>
<p>  1998 . . . . .   200,000	   2003 . . . . .   225,000</p>
<p>	  2008 . . . .    225,000</p>
<p>  1999 . . . .  .  200,000	   2004 . . . .  .  225,000</p>
<p>	  2009 . . . . .  225,000</p>
<p>  2000 . . . . .   200,000	   2005 . . . .  .  225,000</p>
<p>	  2010 . . . . .  225,000</p>
<p>  2001 . . . . .   225,000	   2006 . . . .  .  225,000</p>
<p>The Bonds will  be dated December  15, 1996 and  will bear interest payable semi annually on June 15 and December 15 of each year commencing June 15, 1997.</p>
<p>The Bonds  will  be  awarded  to  the bidder  offering  to purchase the Bonds at such rate or rates of interest as will produce the lowest net interest cost in accordance with  the terms set forth in the Notice of Sale.</p>
<p>The Bonds maturing on  or after June 15,  2005 are subject to redemption  at  the  option of  the  School  District  in accordance with the terms set forth in the Notice of Sale.</p>
<p>The School District will designate the Bonds as &quot;qualified tax-exempt obligations&quot; pursuant to Section 265(b)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</p>
<p>The Bonds  will be  issued by  means of  a book-entry-only system with  The Depository  Trust  Company, New  York,  New York, which will act as securities depository for the Bonds.</p>
<p>The School District will furnish the Bonds and the approving legal opinion  of Ruberti,  Girvin &amp;  Ferlazzo, Albany,  New York, on or about December 19, 1996.</p>
<p>  Requests  for  copies   of  the  Notice   of  Sale  herein</p>
<p>summarized and the Official Statement relating to the  Bonds and such  other information  as  the State  Comptroller  may prescribe by rule  or order may  be directed  to Bernard  P.  Donegan, Inc., PO  Box 70, Victor,  New York   14564;  Phone</p>
<p>(716) 924-2145; Fax (716) 924 4636.</p>
<p>	    Dated:  November 12, 1996    William Conner</p>
<p>		  Johnsburg, New York    President, Board of Educ</p>
<p>			  (From The Bond Buyer)</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
