<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190075" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Suspected Algerian Islamists kill 18 in raids.</title>
<headline>Suspected Algerian Islamists kill 18 in raids.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Suspected Moslem fundamentalists killed 18 people in two attacks overnight in Medea province, south of Algiers, Algerian security forces said on Thursday.</p>
<p>News of the killings, carried by the official Algerian news agency APS, brought to nine the number of attacks reported on civilians in the past two weeks, during which more than 90 people have died.</p>
<p>In a first statement, the security forces said 11 people in Ain-Dema were &quot;assassinated in a cowardly way&quot; -- the term used by security officials for killings by Moslem fundamentalists, usually with victims having their throats cut.</p>
<p>Less than one hour later they issued another statement to say seven people had been killed -- using the same description -- in Douar Zemala, also in Medea province.</p>
<p>The provincial capital, Medea, lies some 50 km (30 miles) south of Algiers.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, security forces reported the overnight slaughter of 12 Algerians, including four women and three children, in the tiny community of Douar Ben-Salah, in Blida province.</p>
<p>That killing took place near the scene one week earlier of the massacre of 32 people in another village, in the same province whose capital, Blida, is headquarters of Algeria's Number One military region.</p>
<p>Algerian newspapers said on Thursday, before news of the latest killings broke, that 76 people had been victims of mass killings blamed on Moslem fundamentalists.</p>
<p>The rise in attacks on civilians, unrelated to members of the security forces and apparently not involved in the five-year-old conflict, started shortly after the authorities announced a referendum would be held on November 28 to change the constitution.</p>
<p>One of the main changes will be to ban political parties based on religion.</p>
<p>Violence broke out in Algeria early in 1992 after the authorities cancelled a general election in which radical Islamists took a huge lead.</p>
<p>Western estimates last year put the death toll at 50,000, while legal Algerian opposition parties put it between 70,000 and 100,000. The outlawed Islamic Salvation Front says 120,000 people have died.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
