<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190065" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norway shares set record, resistance seen at 900.</title>
<headline>Norway shares set record, resistance seen at 900.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bullish Norwegian shares closed at an all-time high on Thursday for the fourth consecutive session this week, underpinned by lower money-market rates, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Total index closed 0.34 percent higher at 897.28 crowns in trade worth 882 million crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is clearly liquidity-driven,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;Because interest rates are falling, even the most conservative (investor) now rushes into the stock market. In the short term, 900 (points) is a resistance level which, if broken, could spark some profit-taking,&quot; the dealer said.  </p>
<p>Shipping group Bergesen announced a nine-month, pre-tax profit of 97 million crowns, whereas analysts polled by Reuters had expected 208 million crowns. Bergesen's A share shed four crowns, closing at 141.</p>
<p>Forestry group Norske Skogindustrier's A share climbed seven crowns to 192 crowns in brisk trade worth 76.6 million crowns.</p>
<p>&quot;(Pulp and paper federation) Norscan's inventory figures which were released today fell far below expectations, boosting Norske Skogindustrier&quot; said one dealer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
