<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190029" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hevesi says NYC cannot afford a new Yankee stadium.</title>
<headline>Hevesi says NYC cannot afford a new Yankee stadium.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City Comptroller Alan Hevesi said on Wednesday the city could not afford to build the New York Yankees a new $1 billion stadium even though the team was worth $307 million to the city's economy in 1995.</p>
<p>The comptroller, seen as a potential Democratic challenger to Republican Mayor Rudolph Giuliani, said at a news conference that the team's owner, George Steinbrenner, should instead rely on private funding for any new stadium.</p>
<p>The comptroller would have to approve any bonds issued by the city to pay for a new stadium.</p>
<p>Giuliani has taken a more flexible position, arguing that it might be better to help the Yankees, which won the World Series in October, build a new home on Manhattan's West Side rather than risk losing the team to another state.</p>
<p>The Yankees' owner has said he wants to abandon the 73-year historic stadium in the Bronx because it is so decayed and the neighborhood so dangerous that fans were scared away.</p>
<p>While pointing out that the Yankees contribute much more than just dollars to the city, Hevesi said New York faced more urgent problems -- such as crumbling schools and hospitals -- than paying for a new home for the team.</p>
<p>&quot;What the Yankees have accomplished by way of raising the self-confidence of New Yorkers and the pride and joy we have in their great victory in the World Series is incalculable, beyond the numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>Hevesi said the city should spend a couple of hundred million dollars fixing up Yankee Stadium and improving transportation to the site.</p>
<p>&quot;To put a platform over the West Side probably is beyond the financial and political ability of New Yorkers,&quot; Hevesi said, referring to the proposal to build a new stadium in Manhattan.</p>
<p>Steinbrenner's spokesman, Howard Rubenstein of Howard Rubenstein and Associates, said the team would meet with city officials and expected to make a decision on a stadium soon.</p>
<p>&quot;They're studying the different reports that come in and will be having meetings with different public officials and community leaders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hevisi also noted the city is within &quot;several months&quot; of hitting its constitutional debt ceiling, which could make it difficult for New York to help pay for a new stadium. There was only $895 million of borrowing capacity left as of September 30.</p>
<p>City sources, who declined to be named, said that New York City hoped to find some additional room under the ceiling by checking with agencies to discover if they have fully used the contracts for capital projects that have been registered.</p>
<p>In addition, the Giuliani admnistration is scaling back its demands for a new infrastructure agency, whose debt would not count under the limit. While the new authority would have to be approved by the state, a new bill might include a role for the comptroller, cap how much debt could be issued and define for what purposes funds could be raised, the sources said.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5010031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97911">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
