<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190099" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Iraq, Libya slam sanctions at food summit.</title>
<headline>Iraq, Libya slam sanctions at food summit.</headline>
<byline>Vera Haller</byline>
<text>
<p>ROME, Nov 14 (Rome) - Iraq and Libya complained bitterly to a U.N.-sponsored World Food Summit in Thursday that sanctions imposed against them were unjust, criminal and contrary to the gathering's goal of stamping out hunger.</p>
<p>&quot;The unjust economic, trade and financial sanctions do not only inflict great damage on the Libyan economy but also harm the direct economic interests of citizens in six neighbouring countries,&quot; Libyan Agriculture Minister Ali Ben Romdhan told the summit.</p>
<p>Libya has been under U.N. sanctions since 1992, including an air and arms embargo, over its refusal to hand over for trial two Libyan men accused of blowing up a Pan Am airliner over the Scottish town of Lockerbie in December 1988.</p>
<p>The United States imposed economic sanctions of its own more than 10 years ago, and in August President Clinton signed a law aimed at preventing new foreign investment in Libya and Iran, two countries which it alleges back &quot;international terrorism&quot;.</p>
<p>Ben Romdham, without specifying the United States, said &quot;some of the states concerned with the imposition of those sanctions are still rejecting the peaceful, legal settlement of disputes&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;This attitude by those states only perpetuates some dangerous principles that contradict with international instruments, charters and endeavours that aim at achieving development and food security,&quot; the minister said.</p>
<p>Iraq, whose representative to the five-day summit has yet to speak, lodged its complaint from Baghdad through an editorial in the official newspaper al-Qadissiya.</p>
<p>Iraq has been subject to stringent U.N. sanctions imposed after Baghdad's 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>The &quot;Rome Summit is urged to stop the embargo crime on Iraq and announce clearly that such crime violates international norms and laws...It also contradicts the theme of the summit,&quot; the editorial read.</p>
<p>&quot;...the World Food Summit should end all embargoes which are being imposed by the U.S. against nations in order to dominate them,&quot; the paper said.</p>
<p>The head of the U.N. Children's Fund, UNICEF, who is attending the summit, has said low fuel and food supplies meant Iraq faced a hard winter.</p>
<p>&quot;What we know is that we're coming into winter (and) given fuel supplies, given food supplies, given available resources, it is going to probably be the toughest winter they've gone through so far,&quot; Carol Bellamy, UNICEF's executive director, told Reuters in an interview on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Another country under U.S. sanctions, Cuba, is expected to be represented at the summit, being held at the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO), by President Fidel Castro. The veteran communist is expected to speak on Friday.</p>
<p>Ben Romdhan said Libya was unhappy with the contents of the summit's Declaration and Plan of Action which were adopted by acclamation at the opening session on Wednesday.</p>
<p>He said the documents should have enshrined &quot;the right to food for all&quot;. Some rich countries like the U.S. were opposed to the phrase because they were concerned it could lead to lawsuits demanding aid or special trade provisions.</p>
<p>The documents instead reaffirm &quot;the right of everyone to have access to safe and nutritious food, consistent with the right to adequate food and the fundamental right of everyone to be free from hunger&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
