<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190313" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PowerGen H1 results rise, offers buyback.</title>
<headline>PowerGen H1 results rise, offers buyback.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>British electricity generator PowerGen Plc turned in a slight increase in first half pretax profits on Thursday and said it would buy back 10 percent of its shares &quot;when appropriate.&quot;</p>
<p>PowerGen said first half pretax profits rose four percent to 138 million pounds ($227.9 million) excluding an exceptional credit of 69 million pounds and paid out a dividend of 7.8 pence per share, up from 6.5 pence previously.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are committed to deliver sustained shareholder value by balancing immediate returns through a share buy back programme with investments that will secure the long term growth of the business,&quot; chairman Ed Wallis said in a statement.</p>
<p>PowerGen has already spent 400 million pounds buying back 10 percent of its shares earlier this year but had been expected to offer another benefit to shareholders after its bid for regional electricity company Midlands Electricity was blocked.</p>
<p>The exceptional credit of 69 million pounds came from the sale of a 21 percent stake in Midlands which PowerGen had built up in anticipation of a takeover.</p>
<p>The company said that its Kinetica gas joint venture with Conoco (UK) traded at a loss and that it was &quot;actively addressing this problem and a long term resolution is still anticipated in the second half,&quot; adding that this was not expected to exceed the first half exceptional credit. ($1=.6054 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
