<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190332" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian forces search for missing rescue helicopter.</title>
<headline>Canadian forces search for missing rescue helicopter.</headline>
<dateline>HALIFAX, Nova Scotia 1996-11-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Forces searched Wednesday night for a rescue helicopter with four crew members missing in Labrador.</p>
<p>The Griffon helicopter was last heard from by radio at about 6:30 p.m. EST Tuesday after it had landed in northern Labrador in northeastern Canada to wait for inclement weather to pass, officials said.</p>
<p>Lieutenat Commander Glenn Chamberlain of the Halifax Search and Rescue Center told Reuters that the helicopter crew had set down after being unable to proceed to the scene of a dramatic sea rescue by Canadian forces of a man taken ill aboard a Dutch ship off Canada's east coast.</p>
<p>By late Wednesday night, Canadian forces were still unable to contact the Griffon crew by radio or locate them via the helicopter's emergency locator transponder (ELT).</p>
<p>&quot;Why that is, we don't know. We hope to be able to detect something,&quot; Chamberlain said.</p>
<p>The Griffon was also equipped with a satellite communications system, warm clothing, food and other survival equipment.</p>
<p>The search was being hampered by high winds and cold weather. Temperatures in the area were minus 10 degrees centigrade (14 degrees Fahrenheit) during Wednesday and expected to plunge lower overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;They are still fighting the elements up there,&quot; Chamberlain said.</p>
<p>A Hercules aircraft and Aurora maritime patrol plane were to join the search Thursday morning.</p>
<p>The Griffon ran into trouble as it was on a mission to rescue an ailing man on board a fishing vessel in Baffin Bay, a vast stretch of water between Canada's Baffin Island and Greenland.</p>
<p>Two search-and-rescue technicians (SARtechs) parachuted from a Hercules aircraft into Baffin Bay's frigid waters Tuesday and swam in rough seas to the ship to treat the man.</p>
<p>The Griffon helicopter crew had been dispatched to airlift the stricken man from the ship, but inclement weather prevented it from reaching the scene.</p>
<p>The missing helicopter crew includes two pilots, a SARtech, and a flight engineer. Canada's SARtechs are highly trained specialists who conduct search-and-rescue missions across a vast territory, including the high Arctic and Canada's eastern, western and northern coasts.</p>
<p>&quot;They are a tightknit group, and they are anxious for news of their colleagues,&quot; Chamberlain said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HALIFAX, Nova Scotia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
