<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190476" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: China oils and fats consumption to outpace output.</title>
<headline>China oils and fats consumption to outpace output.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's oils and fats consumption will continue to outstrip production, leading to imports of over one million tonnes annually over the next few years, a Chinese Agriculture Ministry official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Li Tieshen and Wang Jijun, agronomists with the Agriculture Ministry, said in a report at the Asian Oilseeds conference here that Chinese vegetable oil output may rise to 25 million tonnes by 2000 from 22.5 million tonnes in 1995.  </p>
<p>&quot;China will need (large) imports to meet the people's increasing demand,&quot; the two said in a report. &quot;In the coming 3-5 years, the contradiction of supply and demand in China would be hard to solve.&quot;</p>
<p>The two estimated that annual imports will reach a minimum of more than one million tonnes annually from now until 2000. Up to 60 percent of the imports will be palm oil, mainly from Indonesia and Malaysia.  </p>
<p>Chinese imports of vegetable oils this year will probably reach 1.5 million tonnes against imports of 1.2 million tonnes in 1995. Of the total, palm oil imports represented 1.0 million tonnes.</p>
<p>To help ease the squeeze on local supplies, China plans to farm 33 million hectares of wasteland and raise yields of rapeseed from the current 1,500 kg a hectare, Li and Wang said.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
