<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190487" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore bars demonstrations at WTO conference.</title>
<headline>Singapore bars demonstrations at WTO conference.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Non-governmental organisations (NGOs) will not be allowed to hold demonstrations during the World Trade Organisation's (WTO) ministerial meeting in December, a police official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Benedict Cheong, director of operations at the Singapore Police Force, said NGOs would be given space of their own to hold press briefings during the December 9-13 conference but they would not be allowed to protest publicly.</p>
<p>&quot;Our laws in Singapore are very clear, public demonstrations require a police permit. These permits are seldom if ever granted. We will not be granting any permits for public demonstrations during the WTO ministerial conference,&quot; Cheong told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;Such demonstrations are disruptive to traffic. They are disruptive to the general law and order situation, which we feel that the participants of the conference should enjoy so that they can have a successful...incident free (meeting),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Cheong said extensive arrangements had been made for NGOs, which had registered with the WTO to play their &quot;legitimate role at the conference&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;With these arrangements we hope that NGOs will see no need...to hold public demonstrations,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>More than 300 NGO participants were expected to attend the WTO meeting, he said.</p>
<p>More than 2,500 police would be involved in the operations during the conference, he said.</p>
<p>Police had rented eight X-ray baggage machines, similar to those found in airports, to be installed at all official venues.</p>
<p>Heavily armed men from the Police Special Tactics and Rescue unit would provide additional security coverage from discreet vantage points, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
