<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190405" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia palm olein heads higher in late trade.</title>
<headline>Indonesia palm olein heads higher in late trade.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian palm olein prices continued to rise steadily in late trading on Thursday while crude palm oil was sharply higher, traders said.</p>
<p>They said olein was quoted at 1,410-15 rupiah/kg in Jakarta, up from 1,405-1,410 rupiah at the opening. Some players were trying to test the 1,420-rupiah level.</p>
<p>The traders said crude palm oil was done at an equivalent of 1,215 rupiah/kg at a 500-tonne tender in the North Sumatran city of Medan, compared with the highest bid of 1,195 rupiah/kg at a similar tender last Friday. The oil is to be collected at the seller's factory.  </p>
<p>&quot;The tender price is likely to keep olein prices on the boil,&quot; one trader said. &quot;Crude palm oil is going higher and so olein prices will have to adjust.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said speculators were also showing interest in buying olein in anticipation of higher prices.</p>
<p>Data from Belawan Port showed that the MT Istana-V will leave the North Sumatran port on Thursday with 1,950 tonnes of olein for Jakarta. The MT Azija will leave for Kuala Enok, Batam on Sunday with 27,450 tonnes of crude palm oil.</p>
<p>The MT Sappire will leave for Jakarta next Monday with 1,400 tonnes of olein. -- Jakarta newsroom + 6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
