<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19048" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo companies see brighter second quarter 1996.</title>
<headline>Yugo companies see brighter second quarter 1996.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslav companies are modestly optimistic business prospects will improve in the second half of 1996, according to a survey released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Almost 65 percent of the companies polled expected a rise in industrial production and sales, said the survey published by the Institute for Market Research (IZIT).</p>
<p>Only six percent expected lower production. The remaining 29 percent expected business to stagnate. Most of the companies based their outlook on a rise in export orders, but economists said their optimism may be premature.  </p>
<p>&quot;The local market cannot absorb what they can produce and domestic demand, stifled by deteriorating purchasing power, cannot give a fresh impulse to greater industrial output,&quot; Jovan Todorovic, head of IZIT, told journalists.</p>
<p>&quot;Producer optimism seems to be unfounded because the list of barriers to an improved performance and healthy economic environment is too long.&quot;  </p>
<p>The survey said managers cited a myriad of problems stifling growth, including: persistent shortage of working capital, high internal debts, problems with the payment system between Yugoslavia and the outside world, fiscal liabilities, a shrinking domestic market, outdated equipment and high prices of goods and services provided by state monopolies such as electricity and raw materials.</p>
<p>Managers also complained about the prohibitively high cost of borrowing, with interest rates on commercial bank loans running from eight to 15 percent per month -- far higher than the average monthly inflation rate of 5.1 percent.  </p>
<p>The IZIT survey said producers wanted the government to provide fresh funds for working capital, both from domestic and foreign sources.</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates on bank loans must be cut down to a more realistic level and credits provided for truly viable programmes,&quot; the survey quoted managers as saying.</p>
<p>They suggested banks reintroduce consumer credits to stimulate sales dragged down by extremely low purchasing power. In July, average montly wages were 656 dinars ($134), 4.2 percent lower in real terms compared with salaries paid in the same month last year.  </p>
<p>Producers said strict control of the price of energy and raw materials was necessary until the economy's structural problems were addressed. Yugoslav companies also favoured social programmes that would allow them to lay off surplus workers driving up costs at state-run firms.</p>
<p>The IZIT survey showed 64 percent of Yugoslav companies had surplus labour.</p>
<p>The companies called on state authorities to stop insisting on party membership as a prerequisite for promotion and to reward managers based on merit instead.</p>
<p>Rump Yugoslavia -- Serbia and Montenegro -- has so far resisted carrying out free-market reforms and its centrally- planned economy lags far behind post-communist countries in Central and Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>-- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
