<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19086" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romanian leu stays trapped vs dlr, ignores news.</title>
<headline>Romanian leu stays trapped vs dlr, ignores news.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's leu closed locked at 3,155/65 to the dollar on Wednesday in a market unmoved by mixed economic news and president Ion Iliescu's bid for a new term in November polls.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has yet to digest the news. With present hard currency shortages and the market stuck for months I doubt there will be any reaction soon,&quot; said a trader with one of the four dealer banks.</p>
<p>Latest statistics show Romanian exports, its main hard currency earner, sank by 16.1 percent to $575.8 million in July, reversing the previous month's rise of 10.3 percent.</p>
<p>But on Wednesday central bank governor Mugur Isarescu said Romania will ease stringent exchange controls imposed earlier this month by excluding most state companies and oil firms from the measures.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think this makes much difference,&quot; said one broker adding that the main problem on the forex market is generated by the artificially firm leu rate against the dollar.</p>
<p>Iliescu, in power since the 1989 fall of communism, officially launches his bid for a fresh term in office at a party rally late on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Operators said trading was lethargic and sporadic with most hard currency sellers unhappy with current rates. Some said they had heard of a fairly significant interbank deal but overall turnover remained scant.</p>
<p>Short-term money market rates closed a shade up near 49 percent from 48 percent in early trading following a rush for leu funds linked with the month's end, when banks should match minimum reserve targets. -- Mirela Eremia, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
