<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="190994" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss cancel Mobutu's visa.</title>
<headline>Swiss cancel Mobutu's visa.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Switzerland has cancelled its visa for Zaire's ailing ruler Mobutu Sese Seko after his departure this month, a foreign ministry spokesman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Mobutu, who said this week that he intended returning to Lausanne for a medical check-up, left Switzerland on November 4 for the French Riviera where he has a villa. He underwent more than two months of treatment for prostate cancer in Lausanne.  </p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, told French TF-1 television on Monday he would have a three-day check-up in Switzerland, where he has more than $4 billion in numbered bank accounts according to Swiss media, and then return to his strife-torn country.</p>
<p>But Swiss Foreign Ministry spokesman Jean-Philippe Tissieres said Mobutu's visa had been extended for medical treatment until November 27 on condition that he did not leave the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of his (Mobutu's) departure, the visa has been automatically cancelled and there is no new visa demand at the moment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The spokesman declined to say whether a new visa would be granted to Mobutu, whose presence in Switzerland sparked protests from local deputies in Lausanne who appealed to the federal government to block the dictator's return.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
