<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="191046" id="root" date="1996-11-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Bank of Ireland sees satisfactory year.</title>
<headline>Bank of Ireland sees satisfactory year.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Ireland said the group is undergoing a period of rapid and succesful change with a strong financial performance that leads directors to expect a satisfactory full-year result.</p>
<p>Profitability in the half year was impacted by very good profit growth in the retail division and in other group activitities but profits in the Corporate and Treasury division fell compared to the year-ago period.</p>
<p>The group reported pre-tax first-half profits of 193.1 million Irish pounds, marginally ahead of last year's figures and an interim dividend of 6.1 pence against 5.0 pence.  </p>
<p>The post-tax figure reflected an increase in the effective tax rate after the completion of the Citizens transaction in New England in which the group received compensation for tax losses carried forward as part of the consideration, it said.</p>
<p>Bank of Ireland merged its U.S. operation, First Holdings, with Royal Bank of Scotland's Citzens Financial Group earlier this year. It now has a 23.5 percent interest in Citizens and the U.S. operations contributed 13.5 million punts to group profits.</p>
<p>Pre-tax profit in the retail division rose by 6.4 percent to 104.4 million with growth in the United Kingdom and Ireland.  </p>
<p>Total lending was up 11 percent compared to a year ago with increased volume compensating for lower margins.</p>
<p>Mortage lending was considerably higher and there was strong demand for fixed rate products. Loan losses were low, reflecting the strength of the Irish economy and good management, it said.</p>
<p>But pre-tax profit in the corporate and treasury division of 36.9 million was down 11 percent on the year-ago period although it was up 10 percent on the preceding six months.</p>
<p>The fall was due to lower treasury income reflecting a more difficult environment and and lower loan loss recoveries in corporate banking.  </p>
<p>The divisional results were regarded as satisfactory given the climate, it said.</p>
<p>Profit from other group activities increased by 15 percent to 42.1 million in the first half.</p>
<p>Lifetime Assurance reported strong increases in sales and profitability and Bank of Ireland Asset Management continued its growth in domestic and foreign markets.</p>
<p>Davy Stockbrokers substantially increased its market share in equities and adapted well to the introduction of market-making in the Irish government bond market. Bank of Ireland said profits at the broker were up on last year.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353-1-6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
