<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19100" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish chemical trader Ciech buys two soda plants.</title>
<headline>Polish chemical trader Ciech buys two soda plants.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's large state-controlled chemicals trading firm Ciech SA on Wednesday bought 75 percent stakes in the country's two main soda producers for 213.1 million zlotys, the Privatisation Ministry said.</p>
<p>It said in a statement that Ciech, in which the treasury holds 53 percent of shares, pledged to additionally invest 350.9 million zlotys over the next 10 years in the two firms -- Janikosoda SA and  Soda-Matwy SA, both in central Poland.</p>
<p>Ciech also promised to increase the two firms' capital by 43.7 million zlotys over the next five years through new share issues and keep employment at the current 3,000 jobs.</p>
<p>Workers of the two companies will get up to 20 percent of shares for half price and five percent stakes will be put aside for a government scheme to compensate former owers for property confiscated by the communist authorities after World War Two.</p>
<p>Ciech, Poland's biggest chemical trader, is earmarked for flotation on the Polish bourse in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>The firm, which employs 750 people, had a net profit of 50 million zlotys against 48 million in 1994. It expects to net 43 million this year.</p>
<p>The foreign trade ministry has prepared a plan to consolidate Poland's state-owned chemical sector companies into a holding group, led by Ciech, but the privatisation ministry opposes the scheme.</p>
<p>France's Rhone-Poulenc was interested in buying stakes in Janikosoda and Soda-Matwy but the privatisation ministry earlier said Ciech presented a better offer.</p>
<p>Janikosoda SA employs 1,600 workers and had a 4.1 million zloty net profit on 155.5 million zloty sales in 1994. No figures were available for 1995.</p>
<p>Matwy SA, employing 1,900 workers, had 5.9 million zlotys of net profit and 155.6 million zlotys of sales in 1994.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
