<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="191185" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Heavy trading in OEX Novembers.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Heavy trading in OEX Novembers.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heavy volume was crossed in four November S&amp;P 100 index .OEX options as market participants took advantage of the market's gyrations on the day the November options expired.</p>
<p>In addition, some of the volume was from investors waiting until the last minute to exercise positions, mainly on the put side, traders said.</p>
<p>The November 710 put traded 69,382 contracts. Its open interest going into the expiration was 21,899.</p>
<p>The November 715 put traded 60,695 contracts. Its open interest was only 2,594.  </p>
<p>The underlying index ended up 0.80 at 712.59 after trading between 717.14 -- an all-time high -- and 709.73.</p>
<p>&quot;To a large degree there were a lot of people positioned on the downside,&quot; said Robert Rack, research analyst at Investment Research Institute in Cincinnati.</p>
<p>&quot;As those positions got unwound we saw a lot of choppiness,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Open interest on the November OEX puts rose steadily through Thursday's close, indicating investors continued to take on puts to hedge for a market decline.  </p>
<p>Call open interest, on the other hand, flattened out and then declined into the expiration.</p>
<p>Among OEX calls, the November 715 traded 59,121 contracts and the November 710 traded 49,292. Open interest was 17,628 and 17,905 contracts, respectively.</p>
<p>Michael Schwartz, managing director at Oppenheimer &amp; Co, said some of the volume in the November 710 and 715 calls and puts could have been from investors flipping positions as the OEX bounced around the 710 and 715 strikes.  </p>
<p>&quot;They're going back and forth in and out of the money,&quot; added Harrison Roth, a first vice president at Cowen &amp; Co. &quot;It's a little bit crazy.&quot;</p>
<p>Schwartz said an early pop in volume linked to opening imbalances on the buy side probably boosted futures.</p>
<p>&quot;This thing is chasing its own tail,&quot; he said of the futures and the cash market.</p>
<p>The Dow industrial average, which ended up 35 points at 6,348, rallied to a record 6,378 and then backed off to nearly unchanged before recovering to close at yet another record, its eighth consecutive record closing high.  </p>
<p>Rack said short covering futures positions by index option market makers probably contributed to the rally.</p>
<p>&quot;When a lot of people go for those puts, the market makers are going to be shorting futures to hedge, and as (the puts) unwind, you tend to get some explosive action,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the December OEX series, the 710 put traded 13,595 contracts and the 710 call traded 11,738, making them the most active in the group.</p>
<p>Trading was busy, however, in strikes from 700 to 750 in the December calls and from 660 to 715 in the puts. --G. Crawford, 312 408 8750/E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
