<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="191163" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Citing Peru crash, U.S. seeks maintenance change.</title>
<headline>Citing Peru crash, U.S. seeks maintenance change.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. safety officials on Friday recommended that airlines find ways to ensure that flight indicator vents are not accidently taped shut, thought a cause of the crash of an AeroPeru Boeing 757 last October 2.</p>
<p>Air intake vents that show the crew the plane's airspeed and altitude were taped shut by ground staff during a routine exterior cleaning and the tape not removed before the 757's flight from Lima to Santiago, Peru.</p>
<p>All 70 people aboard the plane were killed.  </p>
<p>The National Transportation Safety Board, which helped to investigate the crash, urgently recommended that the Federal Aviation Administration order conspicious covers for the vents to ensure they are reopened after being closed for cleaning.</p>
<p>It said the crew, on takeoff, noticed the 757's airspeed was too low, its altitude was not increasing properly and its windshear warning activated, even though the wind was calm.</p>
<p>The board said the crew expressed confusion and attempted to return to Lima, when the jet crashed into the Pacific.  </p>
<p>It said during the descent, the indicators were still erroneous, showing higher than actual conditions, and &quot;flightcrew's confusion about airspeed and altitude was evident as the airplane continued its final descent.&quot;</p>
<p>The board said that at impact, the plane's flight instruments read 9,500 feet and 450 knots.</p>
<p>It said &quot;the circumstances of this accident raise concerns about the practice of applying masking tape inconspicuously to static ports, and the potential for castastrophic results if the tape is not removed.&quot;  </p>
<p>The board said interviews with ground staff revealed that masking tape was applied during cleaning and an inspection of the wreckage showed it had not been removed.</p>
<p>It noted that some plane-makers, including McDonnell Douglas and Airbus Industrie, have designed brightly colored protective covers, with warning flags, to make sure the covers are seen and removed before flight.</p>
<p>And, it added, at least one U.S. airline has a procedure to attach a colored streamer to the tape.  </p>
<p>The board said that tape alone did not attract enough attention and could easily be overlooked.</p>
<p>It said &quot;the FAA should take immediate action to review and amend, if necessary, all airplane maintenance manuals to require operators to use only standard, highly conspicuous covers with warnring flags attached in any situation in which static ports would need to be covered.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
