<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="191537" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Washington National, PennCorp to merge.</title>
<headline>Washington National, PennCorp to merge.</headline>
<dateline>LINCOLNSHIRE, Ill. 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Washington National Corp said Friday it had signed a definitive agreement to merge with PennCorp Financial Group Inc in a transaction valued at about $400 million.</p>
<p>The deal, which is subject to approval by shareholders of both companies and regulatory agencies, is expected to be completed during the first quarter of 1997, Washington National said.  </p>
<p>Under the agreement, each share of Washington National would be exchanged for $29.50 in cash, PennCorp stock or a combination of cash and stock, the companies said.</p>
<p>The aggregate purchase price is subject to a reduction of up to $3 million, or about $0.23 a share, depending on the price obtained in the sale of Washington National's commercial mortgage portfolio, they said.</p>
<p>The companies said about $73 million in cash will be available on a pro-rated basis to Washington National shareholders who elect to receive cash for their stock.  </p>
<p>In addition, about $27 million will be used to purchase shares held by a Washington National pension plan, to redeem shares of Washington National's $2.50 convertible preferred stock, and to retire outstanding Washington National options and shares of restricted stock. The convertible preferred stock will be redeemed prior to the close of the merger.</p>
<p>The deal also calls for two Washington National board members to be named to the PennCorp board.  </p>
<p>The amount of PennCorp common stock swapped in the deal will depend on the average closing price of the shares during the 20 trading days ending on the third trading day prior to the merger closing.</p>
<p>If the average closing price is between $31.66 and $38.69, the value of PennCorp common stock received by Washington National stockholders will remain at $29.50 per Washington National share, subject to the mortgage portfolio adjustment. If the average closing price is between $28.14 and $31.66, Washington National holders will receive the equivalent of $31.66 in PennCorp stock.  </p>
<p>If the average closing price is below $28.14, the transaction may be terminated by Washington National unless PennCorp provides addiional shares to maintain the value equivalent to $28.14.</p>
<p>If the closing price is between $38.69 and $42.21, the PennCorp stock received will be equal to $38.69 a share.</p>
<p>If the average closing price is greater than $42.21, the transaction may be terminated by PennCorp unless Washington National agrees to adjust the number of PennCorp shares to maintain a value of at $42.21.</p>
<p>Washington National markets and underwrites life insurance and annuities for individuals and specialty health insurance for educators. PennCorp, headquartered in New York, underwrites and markets life insurance and fixed benefit accident and sickness insurance to the middle market in the United States, Canada, Puerto Rico and the Caribbean.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LINCOLNSHIRE, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
