<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19168" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: MOL, Cofinec seen down on flat Budapest bourse.</title>
<headline>MOL, Cofinec seen down on flat Budapest bourse.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices are expected to remain stagnant or firm a shade on the Budapest Stock Exchange on Wednesday, but oil company MOL, printed packaging firm Cofinec and chemical firm TVK are likely to stay on the losing side, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect most of the leading shares to remain steady or firm a bit,&quot; said Attila Hunyadi of Buda-Cash Brokerhaz Kft.</p>
<p>&quot;MOL, however, will continue to fall as a result of the delayed energy price increase and the fact that it has not yet published its first half results,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>MOL has applied to delay releasing its figures saying as it is making a full audit in preparation for a further phase of privatisation later this year.</p>
<p>&quot;I also expect Cofinec to go lower as it has not submitted its first half figures yet,&quot; Hunyadi said. &quot;Very few investors buy it.&quot;</p>
<p>Cofinec was given permission to release its January-June figures by August 31, instead of the usual August 15 deadline.</p>
<p>Other traders questioned whether chemical company TVK could rise.</p>
<p>The market's longer-term outlook was much better, however, traders said, and Hunyadi referred to Austrian newspaper reports which saw the east European bourses as attractive.</p>
<p>Attila Gazdik of New York Broker Budapest said he saw demand on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;After the Fed left the interest rates unchanged American investors' buying interest spread across to here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday the BUX index ended at 3,359.54 points, up 0.06.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
