<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="191777" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London gold price levels off after early dive.</title>
<headline>London gold price levels off after early dive.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gold's strong performance this week turned sour on Friday after heavy selling linked to speculators and mining firms erased recent gains, dealers said.</p>
<p>But prices held steady after an early sharp drop, and analysts said the spent gains had nevertheless strengthened gold's position to stave off falls below recent lows.</p>
<p>Bullion fixed considerably weaker at $379.25 an ounce in the London afternoon and $379.85 in the morning, compared to $383.00 on Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>In New York's Comex futures market, the price of December gold was down $1.50 an ounce at $380.30.</p>
<p>&quot;What we're seeing is technically driven fund-related selling,&quot; a dealer said. &quot;The move up above the $383 area was shown to be a false break out on the charts when gold dipped below $382 yesterday.&quot;</p>
<p>Prices had notched up steadily earlier in the week from just under $380 an ounce on Monday to the week's high bid of $384.70. The rise was attributed to cash-rich investment funds deciding that gold would hold above the $377-$379 area.</p>
<p>But gold's failure to hang on above $384 disappointed investors, and trade buyers who had emerged below $379 had turned sellers above $383, helping cap the upside, dealers said.</p>
<p>Some dealers and analysts also noted that substantial volumes of gold may have been sold recently by South African gold miners, due to an attractive rand gold price.</p>
<p>&quot;Gold had a look at the late October peak above $384 this week, but it's been unable to push beyond that,&quot; said technical analyst Susan Rigg of Chart Analysis, Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it may come back down and look at the trough we had in late September and early November.&quot;</p>
<p>But support levels at recent lows around $377 an ounce would likely hold again, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The extent of the recent rally has allowed these pictures to improve considerably -- the threatened major breakdown may be averted yet,&quot; technical analyst Elli Gifford of Investment Research of Cambridge said in a commentary.</p>
<p>Silver prices eased in sympathy with gold to $4.84/$4.86 an ounce, a loss of five cents from Thursday's London closing. But its movements have been less volatile than gold recently.</p>
<p>Platinum also spiralled back down to $383.75/$384.75 an ounce, down $1.50 after a brisk rally earlier this week which took prices to a a high bid of $389.25 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Palladium was down $2.00 at $117.50/$118.50 an ounce.</p>
<p>-- Lida Poletz, London newsroom +44 171 542 2936</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
