<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="191729" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Russia Eurobond spread talk narrows after roadshow.</title>
<headline>Russia Eurobond spread talk narrows after roadshow.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's debut Eurobond is likely to have a narrower spread over U.S. Treasuries than previously expected, bankers said on Friday after they returned from a jam-packed London roadshow presentation.</p>
<p>Spread talk was now between 300 and 335 basis points over U.S. Treasuries, down sharply from around 400 b.p. over a week ago, dealers said.</p>
<p>Officials at joint lead managers J.P. Morgan and SBC Warburg declined to comment on the potential terms of the deal.</p>
<p>Traders said a $500 million five-year bond was widely expected, though official indications remain $300-$500 million and three to five years.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems pretty much confirmed it will be a $500 million five-year deal,&quot; said a syndicate manager at a European bank who attended the 450-strong presentation.</p>
<p>&quot;And I heard spread indications from bankers and fund managers of 300 to 335 b.p. over. On Thursday it was 350 to 375 b.p. over and the day before it was 400 b.p. over,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would be very aggressive but the sheer size of the roadshow attendance today makes it possible,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A London-based investor said he expected to deal to come at 315-325 b.p. over Treasuries.</p>
<p>Dealers said there were still a number of issues to be resolved regarding the documentation of the bond such as withholding tax.</p>
<p>Earlier, Finance Minister Alexander Livshits told reporters terms on the Eurobond would not be determined until presentations had been completed in New York on November 20.</p>
<p>-- Aline van Duyn, London Newsroom +44 171 542 7748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
