<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192028" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: PRESS DIGEST - Zimbabwe - Nov 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Zimbabwe - Nov 15.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Zimbabwe press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>ZIMBABWE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's home affairs minister Dumiso Dabengwa early this week temporarily banned all public demonstrations in the interest of law and order, a move strongly contested by lawyers and human rights activists.</p>
<p>- Over Z$2.3 billion worth of property purchased in South Africa for war-related purposes by Zimbabwe's colonial governments can no longer be accounted for, the Zimbabwe Independent learnt earlier this week.</p>
<p>- Some Zimbabwean medical workers, part of a group currently on a strike to press for better salaries and working conditions which has paralysed the country's health system, have gone back to work on compassionate grounds to help attend to desperate cases.</p>
<p>- Regional investment group Trans Zambezi Industries whose diversified portfolio has been built through acquisitions, is understood to have bought a substantial shareholding in Zimbabwean discount company DCZ which made its stockmarket debut a few months ago.</p>
<p>THE HERALD</p>
<p>- The Zimbabwean government has appointed a six-member sub-committee of the cabinet to solve the health crisis brought about by a strike by junior health workers now nearing its fourth week, while the Zimbabwe Congress of Trade Unions has started mediating between government and workers.</p>
<p>- Zimbabwe's Supreme court on Thursday reserved judgement on an application by TS Masiyiwa chairman Strive Masiyiwa for an order to force the government to issue his company's subsidiary Econet with a cellular telephone licence.</p>
<p>---Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 28/9.----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
