<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192004" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi bourse eases after price drop.</title>
<headline>Nairobi bourse eases after price drop.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE) 20-share index eased 5.26 points on Friday after a steady decline in key share prices, brokers and bourse officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices on most shares have dropped and many investors do not want to position themselves as buyers. Like a normal Friday, the market was terribly dull,&quot; a broker said.</p>
<p>The index stood at 3033.98 with turnover posted at 5.749 million shillings traded on 146,730 from 10.804 million shillings traded on 268,177 shares on Thursday.</p>
<p>Brokers and bourse officials said the downward movement of prices across the board contributed to the index's decline.</p>
<p>&quot;Once prices start going down, everyone starts selling. After all, it makes more sense to buy from a rising market,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors' morale is very low. Kenya Airways is one of those shares where many investors felt they burned their fingers,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kenya Airways price has declined steadily from an initial offer price of 11.50 to an average market price of 9.50.</p>
<p>Independent analysts said market prices are undervalued due to misconceptions about the extent of political and economic investment risk and a lack of market coverage.</p>
<p>&quot;Investing in the market is a recent phenomenon to the public and understanding it is the key issue here, not necessarily a lack of demand,&quot; a senior broker said.</p>
<p>Kenya Airways and Kenya Commercial Bank (KCB) continued to trade actively maintaining foreign interest.</p>
<p>Foreign investors bought 25,000 shares of KCB between 56 and 57.50 and 7,000 shares of Kenya Airways at 11.20.</p>
<p>KCB has been the most active share, trading over 200,000 shares during the week, mainly foreign investors looking to fill their orders.</p>
<p>Total Kenya eased to 66 from 66.50 while Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee shed 1.50 to close at 53.</p>
<p>--Wambui Chege, Nairobi Newsroom 254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
