<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192092" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Ex-communist faces centrist in Romania poll.</title>
<headline>Ex-communist faces centrist in Romania poll.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romania's presidential run-off vote on Sunday pits incumbent Ion Iliescu against centrist rival Emil Constantinescu -- two politicians with radically different views of the country's future.</p>
<p>Iliescu, in power since the 1989 fall of communism, held a slim lead over Constantinescu in the first round of polls earlier this month, 32 percent to 28 percent.</p>
<p>He defeated Constantinescu in the 1992 election.</p>
<p>But for the first time in seven years of power, Iliescu looks isolated on the political scene. His leftist Party of Social Democracy, defeated in the parliamentary polls this month, is the only major force backing him for a new term.</p>
<p>Here are profiles of the two contenders.</p>
<p>ION ILIESCU, 66, President of Romania, is an ex-communist who won power by masterminding the ousting of Stalinist dictator Nicolae Ceausescu in the 1989 revolution.</p>
<p>He was confirmed as president by a landslide 85 percent in elections in May 1990 and re-elected in September 1992.</p>
<p>Moscow-educated Iliescu is the candidate of the leftist Party of Social Democracy, successors of the communists.</p>
<p>Iliescu says he offers stability and cautious economic reform to protect Romanians from the pain of change.</p>
<p>His opponents say the man who was once heir apparent to Ceausescu is a remnant of an old order mired in corruption. They say he lacks the vision to guide Romania into the next century.</p>
<p>Iliescu has moved to the political centre in recent years. But his foes recall the coal miners' riots of 1990 and 1991, which toppled reformist Prime Minister Petre Roman, and say it is evidence of an authoritarian streak.</p>
<p>Iliescu, favorite among less educated rural people, won the first round with 32.25 percent, but was defeated in towns, including Bucharest, where his rival led by 17 percentage points.</p>
<p>- - - - -</p>
<p>EMIL CONSTANTINESCU, 56, is the candidate of the Democratic Convention (CDR), a centrist opposition alliance, which won the country's third parliamentary elections earlier this month.</p>
<p>A geologist and law faculty graduate, he rose to political prominence because of his untarnished reputation.</p>
<p>Although Constantinescu had little experience of top-level politics and was soundly beaten by Iliescu in 1992 he has grown in self-confidence during the 1996 campaign.</p>
<p>Slim, soft-spoken and bearded, he was among teachers who joined students on the streets in the December 1989 revolution. He also joined a protest movement which was bloodily crushed by pro-Iliescu coalminers in June 1990.</p>
<p>Constantinescu's American-style &quot;Contract with Romania&quot; promises swifter social, economic and political reforms, guarantees of the rule of law and a fierce attack on corruption and abuse of privilege.</p>
<p>Constantinescu got 28.21 percent of votes in the first round, less than his CDR, which leads in the two parliament houses -- in the lower Chamber of Deputies with 30.17 percent and in the upper house, the Senate, with 30.70 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
