<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192115" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: OTP ends lower after results in mixed mkt.</title>
<headline>OTP ends lower after results in mixed mkt.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungarian share prices closed mixed on Friday what traders attributed to the disappointment of investors following the release of January-September earnings reports by most companies.</p>
<p>The BUX index closed at 3,562.09 points, down 18.91.</p>
<p>November 15 was the deadline for companies in the listed A category of the Budapest Stock Exchange to submit their nine-month reports. Investors still wait for the results of Fotex and financial consultant Dunaholding.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's optimism seems to decline,&quot; said Attila Hunyady of Buda-Cash Brokerhaz Kft. &quot;This is well reflected by futures prices.&quot;</p>
<p>On Friday BUX index futures closed lower for five maturities by between 13.50 and 27.50 points, and remained steady for one maturity.</p>
<p>December BUX futures fell the most -- 27.50 points -- to 3,663.00 points.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the fact that nine-month results were generally good, expectations of very strong results were already built in prices,&quot; Hunyady said. &quot;Therefore when figures were not very strong just good, prices began to decline.&quot;</p>
<p>Friday's batch of earnings reports included those of OTP Bank, Primagaz, Ibusz and Cofinec.</p>
<p>OTP dropped 35 forints to close at 2,690, Cofinec closed unchanged at 4,100 forints. Ibusz remained untraded, while Primagaz advanced 40 forints to finish at 6,500.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
