<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192101" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Investors wary of Hungary energy price decision.</title>
<headline>Investors wary of Hungary energy price decision.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Western investors in Hungary's energy sector expect a meeting with Hungarian officials next Wednesday to show whether Hungary is likely to fulfil its promise to ensure an eight percent profit margin for energy firms from 1997.</p>
<p>Investors said the eight percent margin is essential if they are to make further investments, totalling billions of dollars, in Hungary's energy sector.</p>
<p>Jacques Peyrusaubes, general representative of the French electricity company EdF in Hungary said that, one week before Hungary's final decision on next year's energy price rise, the information investors had was insufficient to judge whether price increases would be enough to provide the eight percent margin.</p>
<p>Hungary promised last year to raise energy prices to world market levels from 1997, and also assure an eight percent return on assets to western investors which bought large stakes in energy companies in 1995.</p>
<p>The government postponed an energy price rise to domestic consumers which had been planned for October 1 1996 to January 1, 1997. It said the price rises are likely to average between 20 and 25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;But this is only one side of the thing,&quot; Peyrusaubes said.</p>
<p>He added that energy companies also need to know the of the energy they would receive.</p>
<p>&quot;(Western investors) will learn the details at a meeting (with top government officials) on Wednesday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Government spokesman Elemer Kiss said on Thursday that the government would decide on the price increases at its meeting on November 21, after a final consultation between government officials in charge of the price rises and the western investors.</p>
<p>Minister of industry and trade Szabolcs Fazakas said in an interview with Reuters earlier this week that price rises in the pipeline would assure Western investors the eight percent profit margin.</p>
<p>Francois Ailleret, the vice president of EdF, which bought large stakes in two Hungarian electricity distributors last year, told a news conference on Friday that EdF planned new investments in Hungary depending on the energy price decision.</p>
<p>&quot;If the government does not fulfill its promise, it would have consequences,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;It would affect the size of further investments (in the energy sector).&quot;</p>
<p>-- Sandor Peto, Budapest newsroom (36 1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
