<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192226" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Winds, rain lash Cuba, Castro delays Rome trip.</title>
<headline>Winds, rain lash Cuba, Castro delays Rome trip.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heavy rain and wind lashed Cuba on Friday, forcing thousands of people to evacuate their homes, damaging hundreds of houses and delaying a trip to Rome by President Fidel Castro.</p>
<p>Forecasters said the bad weather, which began last weekend, was caused by a low pressure system south of the island. They warned this system could intensify and produce worse weather in the coming days.</p>
<p>State media said that by noon (1700 GMT) on Friday some 5,700 people had been evacuated from homes in low-lying areas as a precautionary measure, mostly in eastern provinces. More than 1,300 houses were at least partly damaged, the Cuban news agency Prensa Latina said.</p>
<p>The bad weather prevented Castro from flying to Rome to attend the U.N.-sponsored World Food Summit, where he had been expected early Friday, officials at the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation in Rome said. They now expected him in the Italian capital in time to speak on Saturday.</p>
<p>His rare trip to Europe was widely expected to include what would be an historic meeting with Pope John Paul II.</p>
<p>There was no word on Castro's travel plans in Havana, but this is usual on the communist-ruled island, where officials never confirm the 70-year-old leader is set to travel anywhere, or say he has departed abroad, citing security concerns. The first official word on Castro's travels is invariably when he arrives at a destination.</p>
<p>Despite the weather, Havana's international airport was not closed on Thursday or Friday. It could be that Castro, who toured badly hit areas immediately after Hurricane Lili swept over the island last month, did not want to travel if there was a threat of another storm emergency.</p>
<p>The worst of the weather hit eastern Cuba. But there has also been heavy rain and strong winds in Havana. City authorites reported that one house crumbled completely and 27 homes partially collapsed in the capital.</p>
<p>Hurricane Lili, which hit western and central Cuba on Oct. 17-18, damaged crops and homes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
