<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192318" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian stocks end at record closing high.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian stocks end at record closing high.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------------(Snapshot  4.05 p.m./0505 GMT)----------------</p>
<p>AORD cl	   2387.30  +24.80   DJIA  cl	6313.00  +38.76</p>
<p>SPI futures	  2410     +35   US 30yr cl	 6.42   -0.03</p>
<p>10yrbond futs    92.915  +0.050   Gold (NY cl)  $381.00   -1.65</p>
<p>AUD	   0.7905 (Thu 0.7897)   CRB Index cl   243.41   +1.08</p>
<p>NIKKEI	   20971.45  -59.59   FTSE cl	 3926.10   -0.80</p>
<p>S&amp;P500(Globex)   738.25   -0.20   NZSE40 cl     2351.94   +7.77</p>
<p>--------------------------(Nov 15)-----------------------------</p>
<p>*Stocks ended at a new record close with the market inspired by the Dow's continued rise. Volume 359.3 million shares, value A$803.1 million, 1,071 stocks traded, 352 steady, 450 up, 269 down.</p>
<p>Australian shares set a new record close on Friday with the market inspired by the remarkable rise of the Dow Industrials, which closed above the 6300 level for the first time on Thursday.</p>
<p>The All Ordinaries index finished 24.8 points up at 2,387.3, its highest close since October 24 when it ended at 2,377.5. The index touched an intra-day all-time high of 2,391.2.</p>
<p>December share price index futures closed up 35 points at 2,410 and at a 22.7 point premium to the index.</p>
<p>Stocks rose across the board with resources leading, despite softer base and precious metal prices on Thursday.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Dow has finally installed confidence in our market and subsequently we saw buying across the board from local and offshore investors today,&quot; said Peter Struk, a dealer at Sydney broker, Reynolds and Co.</p>
<p>Struk said another factor working in the market's favour was a growing perception that the Australian share market was still relatively undervalued compared to other world markets.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market's strong performance was underpinned by solid buying support for key resource issues BHP, WMC and CRA, as well as by the four major banks, property and finance group, Lend Lease and diversified manufacturer Pacific Dunlop.  </p>
<p>Pacific Dunlop topped turnover with a number of large parcels put through the market on the day of its annual meeting.</p>
<p>Dealers said the last two sessions had seen a significant turn around in sentiment and predicted further gains next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. market is looking strong and I think our rise will continue so long as the U.S. (rise) does. But if the U.S. has a hiccup we will do exactly the same,&quot; Struk said.</p>
<p>In other local markets, Australian bonds saw an early rally curbed by pre-weekend profit-taking with the 10-year T-bond yield ending at 7.07 percent, 0.05 percentage points below Thursday's close.  </p>
<p>The Australian dollar was holding above 79 cents in late afternoon trade but was seen making little progress in the face of an unstable US$/yen.</p>
<p>By 4.35 p.m.(0535 GMT),the unit was quoted at US$0.7904/09.</p>
<p>FUTURES/OPTIONS - Futures trading was busy as players adjusted to the market's strong gains of the past two sessions while options business eased as investors sat back to watch portfolios mostly adjusted on Thursday.</p>
<p>Total options traded 48,719 (67,527)</p>
<p>Turnover in December SPI contracts totalled 11,108 (8,212)  </p>
<p>-------------------------(TECHNICALS)---------------------------</p>
<p>Short-term range    Support   Restnce   RSI-14  MA-10  MA-20</p>
<p>AORD   2350/2380     2340	2380	63.15   2359   2352</p>
<p>SPI    2370/2400     2350	2400	63.03   2369   2363</p>
<p>-------------------------(KEY ACTIVES)--------------------------</p>
<p>*Pac Dunlop A$2.83 (+.05) 2.77/2.88 Vol: 13,922,590</p>
<p>Manufacturer sees solid interest on day of annual meeting.</p>
<p>*CRA A$19.34 (+.16) 19.16/19.38 Vol: 1,166,910</p>
<p>*BHP A$17.52 (+.31) 17.23/17.55 Vol: 6,120,340</p>
<p>*WMC A$7.83 (+.10) 7.74/7.85 Vol: 4,764,490</p>
<p>Miners favoured as investors take long term view on metals.</p>
<p>*C-C Amatil A$17.54 (-.06) 17.45/17.65 Vol: 577,499 Food and beverage group said after the close of trade it saw little change to its earnings in calendar 1996.</p>
<p>*News A$6.79 (+.05) 6.75/6.80 Vol: 4,055,656 Media shares found support after selldown following Q1 profit.</p>
<p>*Nat Aust Bank A$13.94 (+.18) 13.80/13.97 Vol:2,193,435 *Westpac A$7.05 (+.07) 6.97/7.13 Vol: 4,656,554 Bigger banks firmed but focus remained on miners.</p>
<p>-- Michael Stapleton 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
