<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192303" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian stocks drift lower in thin trade.</title>
<headline>Colombian stocks drift lower in thin trade.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks drifted slightly lower on Thursday in thin trading in Bogota and in a sluggish session in Medellin.</p>
<p>The Bogota IBB index dropped 0.06 percent to 852.24 on a 281.8 million peso volume, about $280,000. Meanwhile Medellin's IBOMED general price index edged down 0.15 percent to 13,363.36 on a 867 million peso volume.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no buyers out there today. The markets were really slow because foreign investment funds stopped buying because it seems they have now consolidated their portfolios of Colombian shares,&quot; one Bogota trader said.  </p>
<p>On the Bogota exchange, brewer Bavaria dropped 0.99 percent to 4,000 on volume of 40.1 million pesos. Banco de Bogota fell 0.67 percent to 5,860 on trading worth 33.6 million pesos.</p>
<p>Cement manufacturer Cementos Caribe rose 0.82 percent to 4,300, and Banco Ganadero ordinary shares edged up 0.39 percent to 254 each.</p>
<p>&quot;Stocks are becoming more attractive because prices seem quite low at present. For that reason there's likely to be a slight upturn in coming weeks, but a lot will depend on what foreign funds are doing,&quot; the Bogota broker added.  </p>
<p>In Medellin, shares worth 370 million pesos changed hands in insurance company Suramericana de Seguros, which finished unchanged at 18,500.</p>
<p>Brokers traded a total of 234 million pesos in cigarette maker Coltabaco, also steady at 3,000.</p>
<p>--Javier Mozzo, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
