<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192396" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam urges party journal to fight for ideology.</title>
<headline>Vietnam urges party journal to fight for ideology.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam's Communist Party newspaper, Nhan Dan, said on Friday it had been urged to step up its circulation and broaden its news coverage to fight as an army for the country's politics and ideology.</p>
<p>&quot;Our party -- the leading party, the party in power -- considers the newspaper a weapon for struggling on the political and ideological front,&quot; Politburo member Lieutenant-General Le Kha Phieu was reported to have said in a meeting with the paper's staff.</p>
<p>&quot;You are the soldiers on that front, so a certain sacrifice is required...&quot; Military Political Commissar Phieu said.</p>
<p>Nhan Dan (The People) is typical of old-style communist publications which generally paint a glowing picture of industrial, economic or diplomatic achievements.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the daily pledged to liven up its somewhat arid columns in a bid to win the loyalty of a public which is now faced with a vast and unprecedented choice of newspapers and magazines.</p>
<p>Although it recognised that each of its soldiers was &quot;a revolutionary soldier in the field of culture and ideology&quot;, the newspaper recognised that changes were needed to reflect the mood of a party which had launched a raft of reforms.</p>
<p>Phieu noted that the new market-oriented environment had triggered a scramble for readership, with some newspapers deviating from objectivity and hindering others.</p>
<p>&quot;Therefore, on the front line of the press, from the central to the local level, tight control is needed,&quot; Phieu said.</p>
<p>He said party cells should be instructed to buy Nhan Dan, which currently has a daily circulation of 170,000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
