<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192448" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China punishes bank branches for stock deals.</title>
<headline>China punishes bank branches for stock deals.</headline>
<byline>Graham Earnshaw</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>China has punished two state bank branches for illegal stock-related deals as a warning to the financial sector that non-securities firms must not dabble in share markets, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>The official Xinhua news agency said branches of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC) and the China International Trust and Investment Corporation (CITIC) had been disciplined for lending money to securities firms.</p>
<p>The ICBC's Hefei branch was accused of extending nearly 12 billion yuan ($1.4 billion) in loans to 15 securities companies from frozen funds deposited by people subscribing for a new share listing.</p>
<p>A similar mismanagement of funds occurred in the Jinan branch of CITIC, which lent 4.8 billion yuan in frozen subscription funds to six securities companies.</p>
<p>The borrowers, who were not named, received a serious warning from China's securities watchdog, the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC), for taking the unauthorised loans, Xinhua said.</p>
<p>&quot;The amounts involved in the illegal lending by the two banks was huge and the social influence was very bad,&quot; said a front-page editorial in the People's Daily, organ of the Chinese Communist Party, which rarely comments on the stock market.</p>
<p>&quot;The punishment demonstrates the determination of the state to further strengthen the supervision and management of the banking and securities markets,&quot; the newspaper added.</p>
<p>A stock analyst with a major Chinese securities house said the incident was part of a campaign to clearly separate the activities of banks and securities houses.</p>
<p>&quot;Punishment of banks for stock market involvement such as this is very rare,&quot; he said. &quot;It sends a chilling signal that the central government is now determined to bring the market under control.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The action comes after the surge in domestic stocks this year with Beijing's blessing,&quot; said a second analyst. &quot;The authorities are afraid that the market, with official support, will go out of control with speculative activity growing.&quot;</p>
<p>Since early this year, Beijing has repeatedly said it supports the development of the stock markets and analysts believe it wants to make the nation's two bourses, in Shanghai and Shenzhen, more competitive in the run-up to China's takeover of Hong Kong in mid-1997.</p>
<p>Shanghai's domestic A share index has risen around 100 percent and Shenzhen more than 250 percent since January and analysts believe price surges and overheated trading, especially in Shenzhen, have alarmed the central government.</p>
<p>In the past few weeks, the China Securities Regulatory Commission has issued four sets of regulations, re-affirming a ban on trading on credit and market manipulation and setting rules for brokerages trading on their own account.</p>
<p>Rumours in the market have said the CSRC, in cooperation with the central People's Bank of China, is also investigating bank credit involved in stock trading, which is banned by China's commercial bank law and securities rules.</p>
<p>The official Shanghai Securities News on Friday quoted CSRC chairman Zhou Daojiong as saying strengthening market supervision was now a priority to curb irregularities.</p>
<p>&quot;There are still many problems on the markets including institutions illegally borrowing money for speculation and wealthy individuals colluding to manipulate prices,&quot; Zhou told officials of provincial securities supervisory commissions at a meeting in Beijing this month, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular, excessive speculation is an outstanding problem,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>($1 = 8.3 yuan)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
