<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="192436" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Tung leads as three square off to lead Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>Tung leads as three square off to lead Hong Kong.</headline>
<byline>Diane Stormont</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A shipping tycoon vying to take over as leader when the British colony of Hong Kong is handed over to China next year opened up a commanding lead in the first stage of balloting on Friday.</p>
<p>Three contenders obtained the required 50 votes needed to go through to the second ballot next month, but Tung polled 206 votes, more than double that of his nearest rival in the balloting of a 400-member Selection Committee set up by China.</p>
<p>Former Chief Justice Ti Liang Yang won 82 votes and businessman Peter Woo, at 50 the youngest candidate, polled 54.</p>
<p>Five other contenders, including a former appeal court judge, failed to obtain the necessary 50 votes.</p>
<p>The Selection Committee members, all of them Hong Kong citizens, are charged with choosing a 60-member controversial appointed legislature as well as the future Chief Executive.</p>
<p>China's Foreign Minister Qian Qichen made his first official visit to Hong Kong on Friday to inaugurate the selection caucus.</p>
<p>He called the committee's activities the beginning of genuine democracy in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Outside, pro-democracy activists who have branded the Selection Committee undemocratic staged noisy protests.</p>
<p>If Hong Kong people were able to vote on the candidates in a real general election, 42.6 percent would vote for Yang and 33.5 percent would back Tung, a recent opinion poll showed.</p>
<p>The poll was conducted by telephone last weekend by Hong Kong University's Social Sciences Centre on 576 people.</p>
<p>But many in Hong Kong believe Tung, 59, is the favoured candidate of China's President Jiang Zemin, media reports say.</p>
<p>They point to an incident earlier this year when Jiang singled Tung out for a personal handshake during a meeting in Beijing.</p>
<p>The Selection Committee meets again on December 11 to pick the Chief Executive.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
