<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193166" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Two Chinese bank branches punished for stock deals.</title>
<headline>Two Chinese bank branches punished for stock deals.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two branches of Chinese state banks have been punished for illegally lending money to securities companies to cover subscriptions for share issues, the Xinhua news agency reported on Friday.</p>
<p>The agency said the heads of the two branches had been disciplined. One was removed from his post.</p>
<p>The offices involved are the Hefei branch of the Industrial and Commercial Bank of China (ICBC), and the Jinan branch of the China International Trust and Investment Corporation (CITIC).</p>
<p>The borrowers, who were not named, have also received a serious warning from China's securities watchdog, the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC), for taking the unauthorised loans, the agency said.</p>
<p>The ICBC's Hefei branch was accused of extending nearly 12 billion yuan in loans to 15 securities companies from the frozen accounts of stock subscribers of a newly-listed company.</p>
<p>A similar mismanagement of funds occurred in the Jinan branch of CITIC, which lent out 4.8 billion yuan from the frozen funds belonging to people subscribing to a stock issue of a diesel machinery company, to six securities companies.  </p>
<p>The companies used the money to subscribe for more of the stock.</p>
<p>&quot;The misuse of frozen funds should be combated firmly, because it severely harms the interests of the stock investors, and may cause disorder in the issuance of new stocks,&quot; a CSRC official was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>The president of any bank found to be involved in such irregularities will be removed and administratively punished, according to a newly-passed resolution of the central bank.</p>
<p>An editorial in the People's Daily said the punishments against the two bank branches demonstrated the determination of the state to further strengthen the supervision and management of the banking and securities markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
