<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193397" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: USDA considers return to on-farm grain stockpile.</title>
<headline>USDA considers return to on-farm grain stockpile.</headline>
<byline>Charles Abbott</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>In what would potentially be a reversal of a new law minimizing the federal role in agriculture, Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said Friday that creation of a U.S. grain stockpile on farms is worth consideration.</p>
<p>The Republican-run Congress eliminated the Farmer Owned Reserve, the major U.S. grain-stockpiling program, as part of this year's &quot;Freedom to Farm&quot; law. The reserve gave farmers nearly three years to sell their grain.</p>
<p>&quot;I do think it is appropriate to look at the area of reserves,&quot; Glickman said during a telephone news conference with farm broadcasters, pointing to concerns about volatile prices.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what we'll come up with but I would be interested in working with Congress and, again, it has to be a bipartisan Congress or we won't get this thing done,&quot; he said when asked if the reserve would be reauthorized.</p>
<p>Proponents say reserves would stablize prices and assure an adequate supply during times of small crops. Critics say the real story has been the opposite -- reserves lock up grain supplies and set a ceiling on prices because buyers know the trigger price that will release a flood of grain.</p>
<p>In remarks from the World Food Summit in Rome, Glickman said &quot;responsible reserves&quot; were among four farm policy issues for Congress in the new year. The others were landlord-tenant relations, farm credit rules and &quot;risk management&quot; tools.</p>
<p>Nebraska Sen. Bob Kerrey, a Democrat, was interested in restoring the Farmer Owned Reserve, an aide said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's hard to say if it would be in the cards,&quot; said Bob Peterson of the Coalition for a Competitive Food and Agriculture System group. &quot;We'll have to see what ideas people would offer.&quot;</p>
<p>The Farmer Owned Reserve allowed up to 1.35 billion bushels of wheat and feed grains to be held in storage for up to 33 months and paid farmers a monthly storage fee while they waited for more attractive market prices. Still in effect is the Food Security Commodity Reserve, which holds up to 4 million metric tons, or about 147 million bushels, for hunger relief worldwide.</p>
<p>Private consultant John Schnittker said the issue of a grain reserve might become linked to debate over higher loan rates -- a frequent request from farm-state lawmakers -- and extending the nine-month loan available to farmers at harvest time.</p>
<p>The consumer group Public Voice for Food and Health Policy has promoted creation of a grain reserve as a standby against weather damage to U.S. crops.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
