<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193394" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Finger leads police to carjack suspect.</title>
<headline>Finger leads police to carjack suspect.</headline>
<dateline>CHULA VISTA, Calif. 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police often use fingerprints to nab criminals; this time they had the whole finger to lead them to a suspected carjacker.</p>
<p>Police say the suspect, Victor Arreola, allegedly stopped a van in National City, north of San Diego, and ordered out the driver, Emmanuel Balbuena, his wife and three children.</p>
<p>But when Arreola tried to get into the van on the driver's side, Balbuena, still in his seat, slammed the door, severing the middle finger on the suspect's right hand.</p>
<p>After contacting several hospital emergency rooms, police were told a patient had checked into Scripps Hospital in Chula Vista claiming he lost a finger in a motorcycle accident.</p>
<p>Prosecutor Patrick Espinoza on Friday picked up the story.</p>
<p>&quot;They had a conversation with Mr. Arreola and brought the finger with them. One of the officers said, 'I think I have something for you.'</p>
<p>&quot;'Yeah, that's my finger,' he (Arreola) said. The doctors were ready to reattach it, then the officers said, 'You're under arrest for carjacking.' That's when he changed his mind and said, 'That's not my finger.'&quot;</p>
<p>It didn't matter. According to Espinoza, Balbuena showed up later and &quot;fingered him there at the hospital&quot; following the incident last month.</p>
<p>According to Friday's San Diego Union-Tribune newspaper, too much time had passed for the finger to be reattached.</p>
<p>Arreola is in jail awaiting a Jan. 9 trial on five counts of attempted carjacking and five counts of attempted robbery.</p>
<p>And the finger is in a refrigerator at National City police headquarters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHULA VISTA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
