<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193396" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NASD regulator adopts new rules, bigger budget.</title>
<headline>NASD regulator adopts new rules, bigger budget.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kelley</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The regulatory arm of the National Association of Securities Dealers said Friday it adopted new rules governing the way securities industry disputes are resolved through arbitration.</p>
<p>NASD Regulation Inc.'s board of directors approved several recommendations first proposed last January by a panel led by former Securities and Exchange Commission Chairman David Ruder.</p>
<p>Under the new arbitration rules, punitive damages would be subject to a cap of $750,000 or two times the compensatory damages, whichever is the smaller amount. The rules must still be approved by the NASD board and the SEC.</p>
<p>Other arbitration measures include doing away with the &quot;eligibility&quot; rule that calls for claims to be filed within six years of an event leading to a securities dispute.</p>
<p>The new provision, also subject to SEC approval, would allow cases to be brought up even if the alleged wrongdoing happened more than six years earlier. But there would be no guarantee that a particular case would finally go through the arbitration process.</p>
<p>Under the new plan, brokers or firms involved may object and the NASD regulators may hold a forum to determine whether the case should go to arbitration.</p>
<p>&quot;The significance for investors is that we have improved the arbitration system in our attempts to maintain it as a swift and less costly means to resolve disputes,&quot; NASD Chairman Mary Alice Brophy told reporters in a conference call.</p>
<p>Punitive damages and eligibility issues involving arbitration disputes have long generated controversy in the securities industry and in the investment community.</p>
<p>The NASD has taken steps to revise arbitration policies in response to concerns that the current system has favoured the industry over investors.</p>
<p>Arbitration allows parties to resolve their differences in a securities dispute before a hearing officer rather than in a courtroom. Last year, the NASD accepted more than 6,000 cases for arbitration, up from about 5,400 in 1994.</p>
<p>NASD Regulation President Mary Schapiro said the board also voted to boost the regulatory division's budget by roughly 24 percent to about $220 million in 1997.</p>
<p>NASD regulation, which currently has 1,500 employees, oversees more than 510,000 securities industry registered brokers and 5,400 brokerage firms.</p>
<p>The extra money will go toward adding 130 additional staffers to focus primarily on enforcement, regulation and surveillance.</p>
<p>In an August settlement of an SEC probe into NASDAQ practices, the NASD agreed to spend more money, in lieu of a penalty, to upgrade its surveillance systems.</p>
<p>The NASD regulatory board also adopted a rule barring an issuer or promoter from paying a market maker to put out quotes in a stock.</p>
<p>It also created two registrant categories for government securities and corporate equity traders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
