<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193492" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: MUNI BUYSIDE - Munis should weather $4 bln deluge.</title>
<headline>MUNI BUYSIDE - Munis should weather $4 bln deluge.</headline>
<byline>Kathie O'Donnell</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fresh municipal debt totalling $4 billion is set to flood the market next week, but at least one portfolio manager believes it will do little to dampen prices.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the muni market is going to handle it well, quite frankly,&quot; said Reid Smith, a senior portfolio manager and principal at Vanguard Group. &quot;We are at cheap enough ratios (to U.S. Treasuries) that it has brought in crossover buyers, arbitrage buyers (and) I think the insurance companies continue to be strong buyers in here.&quot;</p>
<p>Bond fund participation is likely to remain &quot;somewhat anemic&quot; given poor cash flows, Smith said.</p>
<p>Another market participant said AMG Data Services reported outflows of $93.916 million from municipal bond funds in the latest reporting week.</p>
<p>While recent flows have been thin, Smith said they are probably sufficient to provide &quot;at least some buying from that sector.&quot;</p>
<p>Duration-wise, some funds may now find themselves a little shorter than they would like given the market's recent rally, he said, and may decide to venture out longer on the curve.</p>
<p>&quot;So they may chase it a little bit,&quot; Smith said, adding that fund managers can justify purchases because municipals are cheap to Treasuries.</p>
<p>&quot;So it's an opportune time to get some fresh cash bonds into the portfolio,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Players can also look ahead to the January effect, when a substantial fresh cash from Jan 1 coupons and calls typically pours back to investors.</p>
<p>A municipal analyst who preferred to remain anonymous said he agreed in part with Smith, but was less confident that municipals would stand up well.</p>
<p>While the analyst expects the deals to go &quot;reasonably well,&quot; much will depend on &quot;where the Street kind of stands,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I mean it was a heavy week for bid lists, and I think people are okay from position standpoints,&quot; the analyst said. &quot;But (if) you get heavy supply and it doesn't go away, it could get backed up in a hurry.&quot;</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
