<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193528" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Japan seeks compromise in insurance talks with US.</title>
<headline>Japan seeks compromise in insurance talks with US.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>An influential Japanese Finance Ministry official said Friday U.S. and Japanese negotiators were still looking for a way to resolve differences in opening up Japan's insurance market.</p>
<p>&quot;Both sides are still searching (to see) how this can be resolved,&quot; Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the ministry's International Finance Bureau, said as he entered the hotel in San Francisco where a two-day meeting between the two nations was starting on Friday.</p>
<p>He declined to comment on foreign exchange rates.  </p>
<p>Sakakibara said the meeting was basically groundwork for further talks at the ministerial level, possibly at the Asian Pacific Economic Cooperation forum meeting later this month.</p>
<p>Asked if Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's plans for sweeping financial deregulation by 2001, the Big Bang announced last week, meant the insurance market will have to be fully deregulated by the year 2001, Sakakibara said, &quot;There is the question of consistency between them (Hashimoto's plans and the insurance market).&quot;</p>
<p>At stake is Japan's $382 billion domestic insurance market. Washington is pressing Japan to liberalize its primary insurance markets before a niche area called the &quot;Third Sector,&quot; where U.S. firms have been dominant, is further opened up to Japanese insurers.</p>
<p>The Third Sector includes areas such as personal accident and nursing care, such as stand-alone cancer policies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
