<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193540" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CMS settlement gets commission approval.</title>
<headline>CMS settlement gets commission approval.</headline>
<dateline>DEARBORN, Mich. 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>CMS Energy Corp said the Michigan Public Service Commission granted final approval of a settlement that allows it to recover in customer rates the final 325 megawatts of power purchased from the Midland Cogeneration Venture L.P.</p>
<p>The settlement, which covers three cases, was granted to CMS' Consumers Power Co subsidiary, the largest utility in Michigan. The commission reaffirmed a $46.5 million increase in electric rates provided in a February 1996 commission partial order rather than the $49.7 million filed in the settlement, CMS said.  </p>
<p>It also adopted a proposal to end rate skewing, which is the subsidization of residential rates by industrial and large commercial customers. The first step occurred in February 1996. The second step will be implemented December 1, 1996.</p>
<p>The commission granted partial acceptance of the proposed settlement's change in depreciation for certain utility assets. The settlement will have the effect of reducing future transition costs, CMS said.</p>
<p>The commission granted expansion of a proposed limited direct access program to 240 megawatts from 100 megawatts. That amounts to about 5 percent of the company's commercial and industrial load and three percent of its total load.</p>
<p>According to CMS, the commission acknowledged that utility customers should be responsible for their &quot;fair share&quot; of costs incurred by changing their status from full-service customers to either retail, wheeling or direct access customers.</p>
<p>CMS has annual sales of about $4 billion and assets of $8 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DEARBORN, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
