<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19359" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Luoyang Glass sees no profit growth '96.</title>
<headline>Luoyang Glass sees no profit growth '96.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Luoyang Glass Co Ltd said on Wednesday it did not expect earnings growth this year to exceed 1995, but 1997 would beat 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;Profit in 1996 will not exceed that in 1995,&quot; chairman Guo Xiaohuan told a news conference on the firm's interim results.</p>
<p>The H-share glass maker, which makes mainly float sheet glass and processed vehicle glass, reported an 85.6 percent fall in 1996 first-half net profit to 18.92 million yuan.</p>
<p>Guo blamed the drop on a tougher business environment and China's austerity policies which hit infrastructure business.</p>
<p>He also cited intense competition, selling price drops and rises in raw material costs, operating costs and expenditure.</p>
<p>The firm was forced to cut its selling prices by an average 29.74 percent in the first half, pushing its gross margin down to 24 percent, versus 38 percent in full-year 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;These are just temporary difficulties. Luoyang Glass's prospect is very good,&quot; Guo said.</p>
<p>&quot;Profit in 1997 will be better than that in 1996.&quot; He said the firm should benefit from a cooperative technology agreement reached in the first half with Siemens AG of Germany.</p>
<p>The two companies agreed to cooperate on the automatic control of float glass production and related services.</p>
<p>Luoyang expected the cooperation, which would give it new technological support, to add momentum to its development.</p>
<p>Guo said the firm would also benefit from a joint venture set up in June with a registered capital of 10 million yuan with China's Xiangfan Automobile Industry Economic and Technological Development Corp.</p>
<p>Luoyang holds 66.7 percent of the joint venture, Xiangfan Luoshen Vehicle Glass Co Ltd in Xiangfan city in central China's Hubei province, which makes glass products for Dong Feng Automobile Corp's 1.5 tonne light duty trucks.</p>
<p>Guo said competition on glass prices would ease in the second half as 22 major Chinese glass makers, accounting for 80 percent of the country's float glass production capacity, had agreed to fix a price for clear glass.</p>
<p>Clear glass accounted for 28.2 percent of Luoyang's turnover in 1995. In the first half, the company altered its product mix to adjust to market needs, improved sales service and financial management, reduce costs and increase product quality.</p>
<p>&quot;The company believes by taking these remedial measures, it can effectively prevent further decreases in its returns and retain its market leadership in the industry,&quot; Guo said.</p>
<p>&quot;More business opportunities will arise as this is the peak season for the glass industry and the government has increased investment in infrastructure projects in the second half of 1996. It is expected the operating environment will improve.&quot;</p>
<p>China's recent rate cuts would also benefit it, he said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6590</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
