<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193521" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: OPTIONS- US December T-bond options expire quietly.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS- US December T-bond options expire quietly.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Implied volatilities for U.S. debt options were flat to softer just before noon on Friday and December T-bond options were poised to expire quietly at noon, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got the usual frustration with expiration in that there's pretty much an equally distributed open interest in the 114-00, 115-00 and 116-00 calls,&quot; said Brad Tyl, senior vice president at Aubrey G Lanston.</p>
<p>As a result, the expiration was having little effect on the underlying futures markets, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just not dramatic,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The only expiration-related excitement stemmed from a rumor, in the morning, that a large options player held 10,000 December 115-00 calls.  Traders who were short the calls were concerned the player would take profits above that level, which may have had some effect on the market, Tyl said.</p>
<p>Another options dealer said open interest in the December 115-00 call was slightly higher than other strikes, at 25,000.</p>
<p>As a result, he belived it unlikely the underlying futures market would close above that level. &quot;I don't expect the market to settle above 115-00 even...that's about the excitement so far this expiration day,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>At 1145 CST/1745 GMT, implied volatility for January serial T-bond options was flat at 9.4 percent. Implied volatility for March T-bond options was down 0.15 percentage point at 9.75 percent, dealers said.</p>
<p>One large investment house was said to have bought 1000 March 110-00 puts and sold the same number of March 120-00 calls.</p>
<p>&quot;That was the biggest bearish trade I've seen coming into the option pit,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Another house sold 3000 March 114-00/116-00 call spreads, which helped depress implied volatility, he said.  </p>
<p>Implied volatility for March eurodollar options was also flat at 10.5 percent, said one dealer speaking from Chicago Mercantile Exchange.</p>
<p>After a brisk morning, December T-bond futures appeared to have stalled near 115-00 and March euros were stuck near 94.50, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're stuck in a range right now. That's how you've got to play it out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said one investment house sold 2000 June 94.50 calls.</p>
<p>Tyl said trade in T-bond options indicates the underlying futures market may be topping out.  </p>
<p>The put-to-call ratio for T-bond options, which had been showing a two-to-one bias for calls, has begun to narrow with fewer calls in demand, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's weaning...meaning the market is running out of steam,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-Danielle Bochove (312)408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail:derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
