<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19373" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian soymeal prices seen dipping on Indian supply.</title>
<headline>Asian soymeal prices seen dipping on Indian supply.</headline>
<byline>Ang Bee Lin</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian soymeal prices are seen dipping initially when Indian exports hit he market in November following the onset of the soybean harvest, but should then pick up quickly as brisk demand sets in, traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Traders expect Indian soymeal prices to hit a floor of $280 a tonne C&amp;F Southeast Asia before climbing to above $300 in late November. They said current bids were around $290-$295 against offers at $310.  </p>
<p>A trader in Hong Kong said China had purchased a total of 1.2 million tonnes of soymeal between January and August and is expected to import 600,000 tonnes more this year.</p>
<p>Malaysia is seen buying between 120,000 to 150,00 tonnes of Indian soymeal for November/December shipment, traders said. While some importers are holding back in anticipation of receiving soymeal from the new Argentine crop in October, a trader with European company said shipments are unlikely to make their way to Southeast Asia as freight costs are seen rising.  </p>
<p>In the corn market, traders said activity was sluggish. Prices in Thailand and Indonesia have eased, but have held steady in Malaysia.</p>
<p>A major feed producer said the new Thai harvest, mostly from eastern Prachinburi and Chantaburi provinces and some from north east and north central Thailand was a major depressing factor.</p>
<p>In Indonesia, corn prices were also lower amid amply supply. Traders said most buyers are waiting for the U.S. harvest to come on to the market before making their purchases. They said the impact of the U.S. harvest supply on prices will only become clear in late September.  </p>
<p>Sri Lanka has issued a tender to buy 30,000 tonnes of rice for delivery in September, October and November, but otherwise the market is quiet, traders said. They said most rice buyers in Indonesia and Malaysia have already covered their requirements for the rest of the year.</p>
<p>Traders forecast a soft wheat market as China has cancelled recent contracts. But they said prices could still rise in the mid-term if Chinese demand re-emerges and as U.S. wheat supplies are expected to be limited due to excessive rainfall.  </p>
<p>A trader in Hong Kong said that while China had recently cancelled import contracts, the cancellation was &quot;technical&quot; as Chinese importers could not open letters of credit on time and this opened up the prospect of imports reviving.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
