<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="193823" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss bond market closing report.</title>
<headline>Swiss bond market closing report.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss bonds ended sharply lower after a volatile trading day in which the confederate bond futures contract moved in a nearly one-point range.</p>
<p>Traders said the Swiss franc's further decline versus the mark was the main factor pushing prices lower. Mark/Swiss hit a new 20-month high of 84.76 centimes. The franc's drop led to a pronounced drop in prices of shorter Swiss maturities, with the three-month EuroSwiss futures contract traded on LIFFE down at one stage by 18 points on the day.</p>
<p>&quot;As the EuroSwiss fell, there was panic,&quot; one Zurich bond trader said, but added that selling volume was fairly light.  </p>
<p>Many large investors appear to have already closed their books for the year, leaving the market less liquid and prices more volatile. &quot;It is a yo-yo game,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The U.S. University Michigan consumer sentiment index rose to 98.9 in November on a preliminary basis from 96.5, which was generally negative for bond prices. But while U.S. and German bonds were fairly steady, Swiss bonds fell sharply.</p>
<p>The spread between Swiss and German 10-year yields has narrowed to nearly 190 basis points from over 200 seen recently YLDS3. Swiss swap rates also rose by about 10 points during the day, but drifted back from highs towards the close.  </p>
<p>Two-year swaps were quoted late at 2.66 percent, down from level as high as 2.72 percent earlier in the afternoon.</p>
<p>-- Friday closing prices as follows:</p>
<p>Dec Conf futures down 56 at 115.04.</p>
<p>Dec Comi medium-term bond down 36 at 109.75</p>
<p>March Euro Swiss francs down 12 at 97.66.</p>
<p>4-1/2 Apr 2006 bond 104.57/67 yield 3.893 pct</p>
<p>(Thursday close 105.30/40 yld 3.802 pct)</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
