<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194043" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Portugal says supports East Timor at food summit.</title>
<headline>Portugal says supports East Timor at food summit.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Portugal expressed its support for self-determination in East Timor at a U.N.-sponsored World Food Summit on Friday just hours before Indonesian President Suharto was expected to address the meeting.</p>
<p>Indonesia invaded East Timor in 1975 after Portuguese colonisers left and annexed the territory a year later in a move never recognised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>&quot;For the suffering people of East Timor we express our solidarity with them and we reaffirm that their struggle for freedom will be successful in the long run,&quot; Portuguese Agriculture Minister Fernando Gomes da Silva said in a speech.</p>
<p>Indonesia's delegation, led by Suharto, is one of the biggest to the food summit at the U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation in Rome.</p>
<p>Suharto was due to address the five-day summit later on Friday at about 1330 GMT.</p>
<p>The Lisbon government reacted with delight last month to the award of the Nobel peace prize to two leading defenders of human rights in East Timor, Roman Catholic bishop Carlos Belo and independence activist Jose Ramos-Horta.</p>
<p>Portugal saw the tribute as strengthening its hand in largely fruitless negotiations with Jakarta over the future of East Timor. The United Nations still recognises Portugal as the administering power.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
