<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194116" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - November 15.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - November 15.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of stories reported in the Irish press on Friday.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- Ireland's minister for justice, Nora Owen, has said she does not believe she will have to resign if any of the prisoners released and re-arrested as a result of a legal blunder are freed by the courts next week.</p>
<p>- British sources on Thursday appeared encouraged by a speech by leading Sinn Finn member, Martin McGuinness, and his references to &quot;an indicative time-frame&quot; for the talks process and to John Hume and Gerry Adams's identification of &quot;the means by which this conflict could be permanently ended.&quot;</p>
<p>- The Irish police force could receive up to three million Irish pounds worth of free telecommunications services annually by leasing its masts to the private mobile telephone company Esat Digifone.</p>
<p>- Sterling has surged again on international currency markets, driven higher by speculation of further increases in British interest rates.</p>
<p>- An inquiry launced into the remuneration of semi-state chief executives has found that five cases clearly breached Irish government guidelines, it has emerged.</p>
<p>.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- A government U-turn on plans for an independent prisons authority was revealed on Thursday.</p>
<p>- Angry employers hit out on Thursday at proposed new European legislation which says their staff cannot be compelled to work more than 48 hours in a week.</p>
<p>- The state agencies which provide support to small businesses should be abolished and replaced by one new body, a report published on Thursday by a government committee has recommended.</p>
<p>- The former Phoenix Park racecourse site has been sold in a deal worth 13.5 million Irish pounds.</p>
<p>-- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
