<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194143" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India orders crash probe report by Feruary 15.</title>
<headline>India orders crash probe report by Feruary 15.</headline>
<byline>Sabyasachi Mitra</byline>
<dateline>CHARKHI DADRI, India 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian searchers probed the scattered debris of the world's worst mid-air disaster for 51 people still missing on Friday with growing indications that the catastrophe had almost been avoided.</p>
<p>A senior aviation official told Reuters initial evidence suggested that one of the planes had swerved moments before a Saudi Arabia Airlines Boeing 747 and a Kazakh Ilyushin IL-76 hit each other near New Delhi and killed 349 people on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;From all accounts it was not a head-on collision. There are indications of banking by one of the planes, possibly to get out of the other's way,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Civil Aviation named a four-member team on Friday to investigate the collision and asked it to present the report by February 15.</p>
<p>It said Delhi High Court Judge R.C. Lahoti would lead a probe team which also included officials of the state-run international carrier, Air India, the Indian Air Force and the airworthiness department of the Directorate of Civil Aviation.</p>
<p>Residents near the crash site 80 km (50 miles) west of Delhi said earlier they believed the Saudi pilot had made a superhuman effort to avoid their villages. One described the escape of hundreds of people on the ground as miraculous.</p>
<p>The blazing jumbo, carrying 312 people, left a 20-foot (six-metre) crater in a mustard field and the wreckage was scattered over four sq km (1.5 sq m).</p>
<p>Searchers have faced huge difficulties in locating the remains of all the passengers, most of them Indians going to work in Saudi Arabia. The authorities have the gruesome task of identifying the charred and mangled bodies.</p>
<p>Police said 298 bodies had been recovered but only 124 identified. About 50 were sent to Delhi on Thursday and 80 followed on Friday in trucks lined with ice.</p>
<p>Relatives gathering at one major Delhi hospital to retrieve bodies for private funerals were being badgered by profiteers trying to sell them coffins at three or four times the normal price, Indian newspapers reported on Friday.</p>
<p>They also said the Delhi hospital was overwhelmed.</p>
<p>&quot;More than 12 hours after their arrival, the bodies were yet to be embalmed and put in crude coffins. Some of them lay in the sun with crows hovering overhead,&quot; the Times of India said.</p>
<p>At Charkhi Dadri, dazed relatives continued to trickle into the hospital hoping to identify relatives. Some had travelled more than 1,000 km (625 miles) to get there.</p>
<p>Bodies, some charred beyond recognition, had been kept on melting ice slabs in an open courtyard and in rooms hastily converted into morgues.</p>
<p>Some of the bodies were given funerals on Thursday with 76 Moslems laid in a mass grave and 15 Hindus cremated on a huge pyre. Three Christians were buried in a local cemetery.</p>
<p>The Moslem burials continued into the night by the light of hurricane lamps as relatives wept.</p>
<p>What caused the collision, India's worst aviation disaster, remained unclear on Friday but New Delhi said ageing airport equipment and language problems were not to blame.</p>
<p>Most experts said one or both of the planes appeared to have been at the wrong height.</p>
<p>Ground controllers had told the Saudi plane to climb to 14,000 feet (4,270 metres) as it took off for Dhahran and Jeddah. The KazAir pilot was told to stay at 15,000 feet as he approached New Delhi airport.</p>
<p>&quot;We all know that at least one of the planes had not kept its prescribed height. Why? We will only know after the flight data recorders and their cockpit voice recorders are studied,&quot; said one aviation official involved in the investigation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHARKHI DADRI, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
