<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194290" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: TENNIS-BECKER HAS FORM FOR MAJOR TRIUMPH ON HOME SOIL.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-BECKER HAS FORM FOR MAJOR TRIUMPH ON HOME SOIL.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>German tennis fans are realising that the days of watching Boris Becker winning a major tournament on his home soil are coming to an end. Next week's ATP world championship is therefore precious.</p>
<p>Becker travels to Hanover for the season-ending tournament as defending champion and has the psychological boost of some brilliant performances at last month's Stuttgart Open when he beat world number one Pete Sampras in the final.</p>
<p>There are rumours circulating in Germany that the Australian Open champion, who celebrates his 29th birthday during the tournament, may be thinking of bringing his career to an end in the next 18 months.</p>
<p>Becker's son Noah Gabriel will be three in January and it is believed that the player wants a more stable family life with less of the travelling that the tennis tour demands.</p>
<p>Becker is expected to have another crack at his favourite tournament Wimbledon next year. If he were to win it for a fourth time, some observers seriously believe he would announce his retirement from the game almost immediately.</p>
<p>It may be a long time before a player comes along who can stir the emotions of the often staid Germans as much as Becker has done in the last decade -- especially in an indoor arena where the incessant clapping and cheering can be deafening.</p>
<p>Local fans have snapped up tickets for the first championship to be held in the central German city.</p>
<p>The event, which starts on Tuesday, brings together the world's top eight players and is contested over two round-robin groups in the early stages. Each player is therefore guaranteed at least three matches.</p>
<p>Becker and Sampras are joined by Americans Michael Chang and Andre Agassi, Croat Goran Ivanisevic, Russian Yevgeny Kafelnikov, Austrian Thomas Muster and Dutchman Richard Krajicek.</p>
<p>It is regarded as the most important competition after the four grand slams -- Wimbledon and the Australian, French and U.S. Opens.</p>
<p>Just a few months ago Becker was in plaster after his Wimbledon campaign was destroyed by a wrist injury. But the German has surprised himself with his return to form on the fast indoor courts which suit his serve-and-volley game.</p>
<p>Becker traditionally plays some of his best tennis at this time of year. He has won the championship, formerly known as the Masters, three times -- 1988 when the event was held in New York and in 1992 and 1995 in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Sampras knows the German will be a formidable opponent on his home soil. &quot;He is one of the best indoor players I have every played,&quot; the American said.</p>
<p>Sampras, who has won the championship twice, and Becker must be the two favourites. But Agassi won the tournament in 1990 and Chang, who has improved his game dramatically on faster courts in recent years, reached last year's final.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
