<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194259" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: SOCCER-FANS ASKED TO AVOID ROWDY POST-MATCH BEHAVIOUR.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FANS ASKED TO AVOID ROWDY POST-MATCH BEHAVIOUR.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fans of top Turkish clubs Galatasaray and Besiktas have been asked to avoid rowdy post-match behaviour at a crucial derby clash between their teams on Friday night.</p>
<p>Istanbul residents were bracing themeslves for more over-exuberant victory celebrations, as Turkish soccer supporters often fire guns randomly in the air with joy, regularly wounding or injuring people.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, fans of the losing team can take to the streets to vent their anger on opposition supporters.</p>
<p>Consequently, Galatasaray chairman Faruk Suren and Besiktas chairman Suleyman Seba met to have lunch ahead of the match and appealed to their fans to support the teams in a &quot;gentlemanly manner&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;May the best team win,&quot; said Suren, as the two men shook hands and exchanged bouquets of flowers.</p>
<p>League leaders Galatasaray's coach Fatih Terim said: &quot;This is a match of three points. But it is all the more important because we are playing our championship rivals -- if we win it will be like gaining six points.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
