<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194295" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER-SPANISH FIRST DIVISION WEEKEND MATCHES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SPANISH FIRST DIVISION WEEKEND MATCHES.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spanish first division matches over the weekend:</p>
<p>Saturday:</p>
<p>Atletico Madrid (6) vs Espanyol (13) (kickoff  1700 GMT)</p>
<p>Atletico face an Espanyol side that tends to do well in the Calderon stadium without injured striker Leonardo Biagini, but with defender Toni Munoz back from suspension.</p>
<p>Compostela (18) vs Deportivo Coruna (3)  (1930)</p>
<p>Deportivo are still unbeaten and do well away from home, but will be without both Mauro Silva and Martin Vazquez in their bid to avenge last year's 4-0 drubbing in the Galician derby.</p>
<p>Tenerife (10) vs Hercules (21) (2000)</p>
<p>Russian defender Andrei Moj is out for struggling Hercules, while goalkeeper Marcelino Ojeda is back for Tenerife. Tenerife start as strong favourites.</p>
<p>Valencia (12) vs Extremadura (22)  (2015)</p>
<p>Valencia's Francisco Camarasa, Ivan Campos, Claudio Lopez and Fernando Gomez all injured, but even so Extremadura should present no problems.</p>
<p>Sunday:</p>
<p>Sporting Gijon (17) vs Athletic Bilbao (7)  (1600)</p>
<p>Sporting hope to have new Russian signing Cheryshev fit to make his debut against a rapidly-improving Athletic where Inigo Larrainzar takes over from injured defender Aitor Larrazabal.</p>
<p>Logrones (19) vs Celta Vigo (16)  (1600)</p>
<p>Celta welcome back international forwards Haim Revivo and Alexander Mostovoi for a game which will tell whether Logrones' draw at Real Madrid was a fluke or the beginning of a recovery.</p>
<p>Zaragoza (20) vs Real Betis (5) (1600)</p>
<p>Zaragoza fans are hoping Victor Esparrago's first game in charge will also produce the first home win of the season against a Betis side unbeaten in six away games.</p>
<p>Real Sociedad (9) vs Rayo Vallecano (11) (1600)</p>
<p>After a run of bad luck and worse refereeing, Real will look to Romanian striker Gheorghe Craioveanu for leadership against a Rayo side that continues to surprise.</p>
<p>    Racing Santander (8) vs Oviedo (14)		   1600</p>
<p>Oviedo are missing Peter Dubovsky, Jose Gay, Pablo Maqueda and Ivan Ania through injury for a trip to a club that have gone five home games without winning.</p>
<p>Sevilla (15) vs Real Madrid (2) (1830)</p>
<p>Brazilian striker Bebeto is set to make his first appearance since signing for Sevilla against a Real Madrid side that is struggling both to entertain and to win.</p>
<p>Monday:</p>
<p>Barcelona (1) vs Valladolid (4) (2030)</p>
<p>Surprise side Valladolid are cast as extras in the much-heralded reappearance of striker Ronaldo and swansong of veteran Barcelona captain Jose Maria Bakero.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
