<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194244" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: OLYMPICS-SYDNEY GAMES TO BE LIMITED TO 10,200 ATHLETES.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-SYDNEY GAMES TO BE LIMITED TO 10,200 ATHLETES.</headline>
<byline>Martin Langfield</byline>
<dateline>CANCUN, Mexico 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Olympic Committee (IOC) has agreed with organisers of the Sydney Olympics that no more than 10,200 athletes will take part in the 2000 Summer Games, a top IOC official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The total number of participants in the Sydney Olympic Games will be very close to the total number of athletes who actually participated in the Atlanta Olympic Games, that is to say no more than 10,200 athletes,&quot; IOC director-general Francois Carrard told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The exact number is not yet known but it is somewhere between 10,000 and 10,200 athletes, and from what we know this is quite agreeable to the Sydney organising committee.&quot;</p>
<p>IOC President Joan Antonio Samaranch said on Wednesday that 10,700 athletes attended the Atlanta Games, which were marked by transportation and logistical glitches, but Carrard said not all of them had actually competed.</p>
<p>Sydney organisers have been worried at the prospect of a deluge of extra athletes beyond the 10,000 they had budgeted for, while IOC officials had said the host city contract stipulates provision for at least that number.</p>
<p>Asked whether the limit on numbers would guarantee no more Atlanta-type bungles, with athletes enduring long waits to register or travel to their events, Carrard expressed optimism but added: &quot;A number is not a guarantee of anything.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that canoe slalom, also known as white water kayaking, would not be part of the Sydney Games.</p>
<p>&quot;Slalom will not be on the programme for Sydney,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sydney had been reluctant to build the expensive course required for the discipline, seeing little use for it after the Games end.</p>
<p>Otherwise no changes are expected in the sports line-up.</p>
<p>Triathlon and taekwondo have already been added, while Atlanta saw the debut of beach volleyball, women's soccer and women's softball.</p>
<p>IOC medical chief Prince Alexandre de Merode said a decision had been taken to place the substance bromantan on the schedule of banned drugs from February 1 next year, as both a stimulant and a masking agent.</p>
<p>This followed controversy at the Atlanta Games when some athletes said the situation with regard to bromantan was not clear.</p>
<p>But he said it had been decided that dextropropoxyphene, a substance found in aspirin and other common drugs, would not be considered a banned substance.</p>
<p>De Merode said progress was continuing with a test for erythropoietin (EPO), one of the most dangerous drugs in sport which is believed to have killed several athletes.</p>
<p>The main problem in developing a test concerned the volume of urine required, and that was still being worked on, he said.</p>
<p>He had said in October that a test might be introduced by the end of this month, but he made no such prediction on Friday.</p>
<p>A shot of EPO stimulates the production of red blood cells which transport oxygen around the body, boosting performance in endurance events.</p>
<p>It is produced naturally by the human body but when introduced artificially can be fatal, provoking high blood pressure, thrombosis and even heart attack.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANCUN, Mexico"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
