<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194247" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: SOCCER-CHILAVERT INSPIRES VELEZ TO SUPERCUP FINAL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-CHILAVERT INSPIRES VELEZ TO SUPERCUP FINAL.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine champions Velez Sarsfield drew 1-1 with Santos to reach the South American Supercup final on Thursday after another piece of inspiration from goalkeeper Jose Luis Chilavert.</p>
<p>Chilavert set up the Velez goal in the 26th minute with a 70 metre clearance from his penalty area that landed on the foot of striker Martin Posse.</p>
<p>Posse eluded a Santos defender and then fired the ball past goalkeeper Edinho into the net for a goal of stunning simplicity.</p>
<p>Santos striker Robert equalised for the Brazilian team in the 78th minute of the semi-final, second leg game but Velez went through to the final thanks to a 2-1 win in Brazil two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Chilavert scored the winner from the penalty spot in the first game to claim his eighth goal of the year. The tally includes four penalties and four free kicks.</p>
<p>On Sunday, one of his huge kicks upfield set up the only goal of the game as his country Paraguay beat Ecuador 1-0 in a World Cup qualifier.</p>
<p>Velez meet two times Supercup champions Cruzeiro of Brazil in the final of the tournament, which features past winners of the Libertadores Cup.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
