<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194242" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: OLYMPICS-OLDEST LIVING OLYMPIC CHAMPION TURNS 98.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-OLDEST LIVING OLYMPIC CHAMPION TURNS 98.</headline>
<byline>Novica Mihajlovic</byline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The oldest living Olympic champion, Slovenia's Leon Stukelj, turned 98 this week, 72 years after winning his first gold medal.</p>
<p>Stukelj, who in July attended the Centennial Games in Atlanta as a guest of honour of International Olympic Committee (IOC) President Juan Antonio Samaranch, is only two years younger than the Olympic movement.</p>
<p>Awarded the Olympic Order in 1988, Stukelj is still energetic and exercises regularly.</p>
<p>&quot;The secret to a long life is: don't drink too much, don't smoke, run every day and don't eat too much,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the 1924 Games in Paris, Stukelj clinched his first Olympic gold medals on the horizontal bars and in the all-round event at a time when athletes were true amateurs.</p>
<p>&quot;Most gymnasts are professionals today. They live off gymnastics. In my days nobody was paid, we were doing it for recognition and respect.</p>
<p>&quot;I had no idea how other people exercise because I had never seen anyone else in action. I had no-one to look up to. I only realised I was good when I won my first medal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>His golds were the first for Yugoslavia, then a new country created on the remnants of the Habsburg and Ottoman empires which crumbled in World War One.</p>
<p>Five years ago, the same fate befell Yugoslavia and Stukelj is now a citizen of the independent Republic of Slovenia.</p>
<p>A smile of joy spreads over his face when he remembers the thousands of people who greeted him on the streets of Ljubljana when a national holiday was declared in his honour.</p>
<p>In 1928 in Amsterdam, Stukelj captured his third gold on the rings and two bronzes -- in the all-round event and the team competition.</p>
<p>&quot;We did not have an Olympic Village then, we had to look for hotels and find our own way around. The athletes travelled by tram to the stadium,&quot; he said. &quot;Nothing was organised but the stadium was very beautiful.&quot;</p>
<p>The then tiny Yugoslav team did not have their own locker room and instead shared one with competitors from Luxembourg. They transported their own horizontal bars with them by trainin case the organisers did not have the correct ones.</p>
<p>Stukelj's medals, diplomas and old photographs can be admired at the University of Maribor where he studied law to later become a judge and attorney.</p>
<p>Next to a photograph of him shaking hands with American sprinter Jesse Owens -- who won four golds in Berlin in 1936 -- hangs a black-and-white photograph of a beautiful young woman.</p>
<p>The dedication reads: &quot;Fuer Leon zur errinnerung (To Leon in memory of)&quot; and is signed Leni Riefenstahl -- Hitler's propaganda film-maker and producer of the famous &quot;Olympia&quot; movie about the Berlin Games.</p>
<p>In Germany, Stukelj took silver on the rings at the age of 37. He missed the Los Angeles Games because the Yugoslav federation was unable to finance the trip.</p>
<p>In 1987, Stukelj set down the memories and experiences of his exceptional career in a book.</p>
<p>The Slovenian still practices gymnastics on a pair of improvised rings which hang in his flat and is still able to land softly.</p>
<p>The only difference he sees between gymnasts of his time and those of today are the acrobatic elements which were introduced by the Soviets after World War Two.</p>
<p>&quot;We set up the basics but modern gymnastics has some extra elements which only professionals can master,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
