<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194298" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: ZIMBABWE RESERVE BANK SAYS KEY T-BILL RATE WRONG.</title>
<headline>ZIMBABWE RESERVE BANK SAYS KEY T-BILL RATE WRONG.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's central Reserve Bank (RBZ) on Friday said the rate at which it issued treasury bills to local discount houses -- which dropped sharply at Thursday's weekly auction -- was incorrect.</p>
<p>It said the drop to 15.44 percent from last week's 19.36 percent in the treasury bill's buying rate for treasury bills -- a pointer for other short-term money market rates -- was due to an incorrect bid by one of the tenderers.</p>
<p>&quot;It has.... been established that one of the tenderers submitted an incorrect bid. This only became apparent after the results had been published when the institution involved acknowledged their error,&quot; the RBZ said in a statement.</p>
<p>The statement was issued after capital markets had closed for the weekend at 1300 GMT, and comment was unavailable.</p>
<p>On Friday morning, money dealers said the drastic fall in the rate had shaken the market, leaving most players reluctant to do any trade.</p>
<p>&quot;We think one institute must have made a mistake on its tender price and the Reserve Bank takes the lowest price, hence the fall in the TB (treasury bill) rate,&quot; one dealer said then.</p>
<p>&quot;But other rates have not come down substantially in line with the treasury bill rate and people are generally keeping a low profile on the market. No one is keen to sell at this point in time,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Stock brokers said industrial shares on the Zimbabwe Stock Exchange rallied from a previous lull in active trade as local institutional investors deserted the money market after the drop in the treasury bill rate.</p>
<p>&quot;Money market rates are coming down, with the treasury bill rate having fallen to around 15 percent today. That's why the market is getting firm and we are beginning to see a lot of interest in almost all the counters,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The indicative buying rate for NCD bills maturing after 30, 60 and 90 days was on Friday unchanged at 20 percent while bankers acceptances eased slightly to 19.25 from 19.50 percent.</p>
<p>Call money however tumbled to a zero to 15 percent range from 18 percent in a market which opened with an unsettled surplus of Z$943.6 million.</p>
<p>-- Stella Mapenzauswa, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 28/9</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
