<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194312" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: TAIWANESE DEFENCE MINISTER VISITS CZECH REPUBLIC.</title>
<headline>TAIWANESE DEFENCE MINISTER VISITS CZECH REPUBLIC.</headline>
<byline>Klara Gajduskova</byline>
<text>
<p>PRAGUE, Nov 15 (Rauter) - Taiwanese Defence Minister Chiang Chung-ling is in the Czech Republic, the Foreign Ministry said on Friday, in the latest in a series of high-level Taipei visits even though Prague recognises only China.</p>
<p>&quot;It is true the minister is here,&quot; said Karel Boruvka, a Foreign Ministry spokesman. &quot;It is (part of) his visit to Central Europe, but it is purely a private visit.&quot;</p>
<p>Boruvka told Reuters he did not know how long Chiang would stay in Prague nor where is he to leave for.</p>
<p>Although the Czech Republic has no diplomatic relations with Taiwan, the government defends the country's right to do business with the island state which China regards as a renegade province.</p>
<p>A number of Czech companies export arms although sales abroad have to be approved by several government departments including the Foreign Ministry.</p>
<p>Boruvka denied that government officials would meet Chiang but made no direct comment on suggestions that he was in the Czech Republic to buy weapons.</p>
<p>&quot;He will not meet any Czech official. Whether he has got meetings with companies, I do not know,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An official at the Taipei Business Chamber in Prague said he had no information about Chiang's visit.</p>
<p>Czech media have reported that Taiwan is interested in cooperating with troubled aircraft maker Aero Vodochody, which makes military trainers, albeit to build small business jets.</p>
<p>Last year Beijing reacted angrily when Taiwanese Premier Lien Chan visited the Czech Republic for a supposedly private but highly-publicised visit which included talks with President Vaclav Havel and Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus.</p>
<p>Havel also irritated China by expressing regret that Taiwan was not a member of the United Nations.</p>
<p>Taiwanese Economics Minister Chiang Pin-kung met government officials in Prague last year, announcing amid great fanfare a $100 million industrial park would be opened in the western city of Plzen this year. So far nothing has materialised.</p>
<p>Relations with Beijing improved in April this year when Chinese Foreign Minister Qian Qichen visited Prague.</p>
<p>The Czech Defence Ministry also denied any contact with the Taiwanese defence minister. &quot;Nobody contacted us, nobody talked to us, nobody demanded anything,&quot; said spokesman Vaclav Tichy.</p>
<p>A Trade and Industry Ministry official also said Chiang's visit was news to him.</p>
<p>-- Prague newsroom (42 2) 24 23 0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
