<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194470" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Three billion marks cut from 1997 German budget.</title>
<headline>Three billion marks cut from 1997 German budget.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German government has pared three billion marks off its 1997 budget deficit as it put final touches on spending plans meant to ensure Bonn qualifies for Europe's single currency, deputies said on Friday.</p>
<p>Adolf Roth, budget expert for Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats, said that billions earned from privatising the postal services bank Postbank would help reduce the planned deficit from 56.5 billion to 53.3 billion marks next year.</p>
<p>Roth said the government also sell its 35.7 percent stake in the airline Lufthansa AG to contribute another 2.9 billion marks to state coffers while selling a six percent stake in DG Bank would add another 500 million marks.</p>
<p>The Bonn coalition shaved three billion marks off planned spending last weekend to ensure the 1997 deficit did not exceed Maastricht's limit of three percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Officials stressed this further three billion mark savings could not be seen as &quot;window dressing&quot; to meet the Maastricht criteria because Bonn's draft budget already did that.</p>
<p>But it would give the centre-right government some leeway in next year's budget if unexpected spending needs meant Finance Minister Theo Waigel had to run a larger deficit.</p>
<p>According to Roth, overall 1997 spending should be 439.9 billion marks, or 2.5 percent below this year's budget.</p>
<p>A panel of independent economic advisers on Friday predicted Germany's total federal, state and local government deficits would amount to 3.3 percent of gross domestic product in 1997, missing the Maastricht treaty's three percent limit.</p>
<p>But after the panel's announcement, Waigel repeated his view Germany would have little trouble qualifying for EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;Fiscal policy has created the conditions so that the state deficit in 1997 will fall below three percent fo gross domestic product with an ample margin of safety,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The business daily Boersen Zeitung reported Bonn also plans to sell DG Bank next year. Stakes in the highway restaurant chain Tank und Rast AG and the real estate company Frankfurter Siedlungsgesellschaft could also be up for sale next year.</p>
<p>Roth said Bonn's 1996 deficit has ballooned to 76 billion marks, far more than the government's target of 59 billion marks, but could narrow if the government books some of the proceeds from the Lufthansa sale before the year's end.</p>
<p>The independent economic advisers -- Germany's so-called &quot;wise men&quot; -- forecast total public deficts of 122.5 billion marks and recommended cutting 11 billion marks from federal, state and local government spending.</p>
<p>Opposition Social Democrats criticised the government's cutbacks, accusing the government of using financial &quot;tricks,&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The coalition's cutbacks in investments will burden the economy and raise unemployment,&quot; said SPD budget spokesman Karl Diller. &quot;The coalition is incapable of fighting unemployment with an effective growth and jobs policy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
