<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194429" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian Airlines unit's board resigns.</title>
<headline>Canadian Airlines unit's board resigns.</headline>
<dateline>CALGARY, Alberta</dateline>
<text>
<p>The board of directors of struggling Canadian Airlines Corp.'s operating company, Canadian Airlines International Ltd., resigned on Friday at the recommendation of legal counsel, the parent company said.</p>
<p>Canadian Airlines Corp. said the resignations reflected the directors' concern about growing personal liability to the airline's creditors.</p>
<p>The board of Canadian Airlines Corp. remains unchanged, the company said.</p>
<p>The airline has asked its unionized employees to take a 10 percent wage cut as part of a survival plan to save the company, the smaller of two national airlines in Canada.</p>
<p>&quot;Notwithstanding this event, I believe that the company and its unions are very focused on solving the issues facing us. Wednesday's discussions with unions raised a number of ideas which are being evaluated and meetings will continue within a week,&quot; President Kevin Benson said in a statement.</p>
<p>Until a new board is appointed, the affairs of CAI will be directed by its shareholders, Canadian Airlines Corp. and Aurora Airline Investments Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of AMR Corp., parent of American Airlines.</p>
<p>Fort Worth, Texas-based AMR has a 33 percent ownership interest and 25 percent voting interest in CAI.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALGARY, Alberta"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
