<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194452" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: IBM hits pre-1987 stock market crash highs.</title>
<headline>IBM hits pre-1987 stock market crash highs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>IBM stock soared Friday to levels not seen since before the October 1987 stock market crash, boosted by bullish comments by Merrill Lynch, which raised its price target on the stock.</p>
<p>International Business Machines Corp. climbed $7.50 to $144.375 as more than 6.8 million shares traded on the New York Stock Exchange, where it was the most active issue.</p>
<p>The rally was fuelled by comments by influential Merrill Lynch analyst Daniel Mandresh, as well as some recent buying by Magellan, the nation's largest mutual fund, traders said.</p>
<p>In September, IBM appeared in the top 10 holdings of the Magellan Fund, which is gradually moving to increase its holdings in tech stocks under its new manager Robert Stansky.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a combination of those things,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Mandresh said his new price target for the stock was $195, up from $155 previously.</p>
<p>An IBM spokesman said the last time IBM closed above $140 was on Oct. 15, 1987, days before Black Monday, Oct. 19, when the Dow Jones industrial average fell 508 points, or 22.6 percent. IBM's stock hit a high of $175 in August 1987.</p>
<p>The rally in IBM, one of the 30 stocks in the Dow industrials, boosted the broader market. The Dow was up 37.64 points at 6,350.64 in late trading.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
