<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194400" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>LUXEMBOURG: BELGIAN PM CALLS ON EU LEADERS TO BURY EMU DOUBTS.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN PM CALLS ON EU LEADERS TO BURY EMU DOUBTS.</headline>
<dateline>LUXEMBOURG 1996-11-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene said on Thursday European Union leaders must remove remaining uncertainties over European economic and monetary union (EMU) at their Dublin summit next month.</p>
<p>&quot;It is essential that the council...agrees the legal framework for EMU including a stability pact and monetary system that governs the relationship between the ins and the outs,&quot; Dehaene said.</p>
<p>He was speaking at an awards ceremony where he received the 1996 &quot;Vision for Europe&quot; award from the Edmond Israel Foundation, named after the former Luxembourg bourse chairman and founder of the Cedel clearing bank.</p>
<p>Dehaene said he was convinced monetary union would happen in 1999, according to the Maastricht Treaty, &quot;not only because the economic and technical point of no return has been reached, but above all because I see there is a firm political will.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;One must realise that EMU is first of all a political project,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>EMU should pave the way for further European integration and enlargement of the EU to the countries of eastern Europe, and also make Europe more visible and tangible to its citizens, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;EMU is also essential to preserve Europe's weight and autonomy in the global economy taking shape each day,&quot; Dehaene said.</p>
<p>Dehaene also called for Europe's leaders to agree to a multi-speed European Union once the bloc expands to the countries of the former Warsaw Pact.</p>
<p>&quot;Countries which are partisan to faster integration fear that common policies will be crushed under the weight of the divergent interests of 25 member states. We must work out a mechanism that avoids countries that want to go faster having to...go at the speed of the slowest,&quot; Dehaene said.</p>
<p>EU countries are currently discussing the future decision making processes and structure of the bloc in a series of weekly meetings known as the inter-governmental conference (IGC).</p>
<p>The meetings began in March with the aim of thrashing out a new EU treaty by the end of next year.</p>
<p>Dehaene said the IGC must also lead to a stronger foreign and security policy and new cooperation in defence, police matters and immigration and asylum policies.</p>
<p>&quot;On this last point, the Benelux countries have the same view and...yesterday made concrete common proposals to the IGC,&quot; Dehaene said, referring to Belgium's Benelux partners, the Netherlands and Luxembourg.</p>
<p>Belgium would also resist any efforts by other countries to use the IGC to weaken existing EU institutions, such as the Commission or European Court of Justice, he said.</p>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major said this week he would use Britain's power of veto to bloc the IGC if other countries did not agree to remove powers from the court.</p>
<p>Dehaene said he did not expect Britain to be among the first wave of European countries adopting the euro as their currency on January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>But Dehaene, whose bid two years ago for presidency of the European Commission was blocked by Major, said Britain would eventually bow to pressure from the City of London and join.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the history of the European Union will repeat itself -- that in 1998 Britain will decide it's not in its national interest to go into monetary union and then two or three years later decide it is,&quot; Dehaene said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BENLUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LUXEMBOURG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
