<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194473" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Lira readies for ERM return after four giddy years.</title>
<headline>Lira readies for ERM return after four giddy years.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is a chronology of events leading up to the lira's expected return to Europe's exchange rate mechanism (ERM), which many analysts see likely before or around the European Union's Dublin summit on December 13-14.</p>
<p>-----------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>March 1979 - ERM formed. Mark, French franc, Belgian franc, Dutch guilder, Danish crown and Irish punt join with 2.25 percent bands. Italian lira joins with six pct bands.</p>
<p>September 1992 - ERM currencies suffer heavy selling against the mark as a result of investors' doubts over Europe's plans for a single currency and high German interest rates which force other European countries, including Italy, to keep rates high.</p>
<p>Sept 13 - First major realignment of the ERM since January 1987 as behind-the-scenes deal brings seven per cent devaluation of the lira in return for a cut in German interest rates. Lira's central parity against mark is 802.49 lire.</p>
<p>Sept 16 - &quot;Black Wednesday.&quot; Markets attack pound, lira and peseta. Britain suspends pound from ERM.</p>
<p>Sept 17 - After a six-hour meeting, EC's monetary committee suspends lira from ERM. Within days lira drops to 875 per mark and continues fall in coming months.</p>
<p>April 1993 - Widespread Italian corruption scandal taints government of Giuliano Amato who tenders resignation. This and strike by millions of workers forces lira through 1,000 barrier to hit record 1,005 low on April 2. Following a referendum in favour of electoral reform and the appointment of former Bank of Italy governor Carlo Azeglio Ciampi as prime minister, the lira manages to hold between 900 and 1,000 for the next year.</p>
<p>Aug 1-2 - After days of intense selling pressure in ERM, EU finance ministers and central bank governors widen fluctuation bands to 15 percent for all ERM currencies except the mark and Dutch guilder which maintain a 2.25 percent range.</p>
<p>March 28, 1994 - Italian media tycoon Silvio Berlusconi rides to whirlwind election victory with centre-right Freedom Alliance. In euphoria lira firms to around 945 from near 1,000.</p>
<p>September - Investors lose confidence in ability of bickering Berlusconi government to pass tough budget measures; lira breaks past 1,000 and fall accelerates.</p>
<p>Dec 20 - Berlusconi resigns after seven months in office. Lira at 1,050 and beyond in subsequent crisis.</p>
<p>Jan 17, 1995 - Former central bank director general Lamberto Dini forms technocrat government, makes return of the lira to the ERM a top priority. But lira continues to plummet in next two months on heightened political uncertainty and rising CPI.</p>
<p>March 17 - Lira sets historic low of 1,275 per mark as investors dump Italian assets following alarmingly narrow win for Dini government in confidence vote to pass mini-budget. Currency holds near the low for next month before strengthening to 1,076.50 over next five months as political turmoil abates.</p>
<p>Sept 20 - German Finance Minister Theo Waigel says Italy will not qualify for first tier of EMU. Lira plummets past 1,100 per mark in one day and to 1,171 over next month.</p>
<p>Jan 11, 1996 - Dini resigns, unable to rely on parliamentary majority but lira holds steady around 1,090.</p>
<p>April 21 - Centre-left Olive Tree coalition led by Romano Prodi wins general election. In weeks following, Prime Minister Prodi vows to tame inflation to lower interest rates and put Italy in a position to join EMU.</p>
<p>June 20 - Prodi says Italy should be among EMU founders. Five days later lira at 1,000 for first time since 1994.</p>
<p>July 24 - Bank of Italy cuts discount and Lombard rates 75 basis points to 8.25 and 9.75 percent after inflation slows to 3.7 percent.</p>
<p>Aug 12 - Prodi says he expects the lira to enter the ERM soon after the 1997 budget bill is passed by parliament.</p>
<p>Sept 27 - Cabinet approves larger than expected 62.5 trillion lire ($42 billion) deficit cutting budget which Prodi says will ensure Italy is a founding EMU member.</p>
<p>Oct 1 - French President Jacques Chirac says Italy may not be one of the first in EMU. But, as Franco-Italian row brews, he adds he hopes Italy will be in the first wave. France says the next day the lira must rise before ERM entry. Lira hits 990.25.</p>
<p>Oct 12 - Finland puts markka into ERM, spotlight turns on Italy as candidate.</p>
<p>Oct 23 - Italian discount and Lombard rates cut to 7.5 and 9.0 percent after inflation slows to 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>Nov 5 - France's Chirac says he expects negotiations on lira's return could be completed by the year end.</p>
<p>Nov 6 - Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi says Italy is likely to seek ERM return in late November. Finance Minister Vincenzo Visco says 1,000-1,050 is likely range for mark parity.</p>
<p>Nov 14 - Main body of 1997 budget is passed in lower house of parliament. Remainder expected to be approved by Sunday.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +39 2 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
