<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194407" id="root" date="1996-11-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. gives four airlines rights to fly to Toronto.</title>
<headline>U.S. gives four airlines rights to fly to Toronto.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Transportation Department on Friday tentatively awarded rights to four U.S. carriers for service to Toronto that would begin next year.</p>
<p>It said winners were Continental Airlines to fly from Newark, New Jersey; Delta Air Lines from Atlanta; Midway Airlines from Raleigh/Durham, North Carolina, and Northwest Airlines from Minneapolis.</p>
<p>The department said the new carriers each may make two new daily round-trip flights starting Feb. 24. It said Trans World Airlines was named as backup to fly to Toronto from St. Louis if one of the four decided not to exercise its rights.</p>
<p>&quot;With these route awards,&quot; Transportation Secretary Federico Pena said, &quot;we continue the process begun by President Clinton last year with the achievement of our historic open-market aviation agreement with Canada.&quot;</p>
<p>He added the gradual opening of the market, to be completed in 1998, had already benefited passengers, shippers and the economies of both countries.</p>
<p>The department said it believed the four carriers named could offer the strongest competition to foreign carriers and other airlines in the U.S.-Toronto market.</p>
<p>It said objections to the naming of the four would be considered until Nov. 26 and answers to objections by Dec. 6, with a final decision to follow shortly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
