<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194546" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-TOULOUSE AND LEICESTER SET UP ANGLO-FRENCH CRUNCH.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-TOULOUSE AND LEICESTER SET UP ANGLO-FRENCH CRUNCH.</headline>
<byline>Robert Kitson</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Holders Toulouse survived some anxious moments against French rivals Dax before emerging with a 26-18 victory which earned them a European Cup semifinal against England's only remaining representatives Leicester.</p>
<p>The French champions recovered from 18-3 down after half an hour to dash Dax's hopes, a breakaway second-half try from centre Michel Marfaing, converted by centre Thomas Castaignede, finally making the difference.</p>
<p>Leicester, who also came from behind in a domestic duel to beat Harlequins 23-13, will host the semifinal in the first weekend in January, with Cardiff, exciting 22-19 home winners over Bath, playing the winners of the Brive/Llanelli tie on Sunday. If Brive win, they will stage the second semifinal by virtue of their pool performances.</p>
<p>French rugby has seen some spectacular Toulouse-Dax encounters in recent times and the latest meeting was billed as a showdown between international centres Castaignede and Richard Dourthe.</p>
<p>It was Castaignede who emerged on top again, frustrating a Dax side who lost 14-13 to the same opponents in the French championship in September. He and fellow goalkicker Christophe Deylaud contributed 16 points between them, with Dourthe restricted to two penaties and a conversion.</p>
<p>Things looked very different when Dax's former Toulouse wing Ugo Mola, who left the champions because he could not command a first team place, scored two tries in the opening half hour, the first after picking up a superb chip ahead by centre Pascal Giordani.</p>
<p>Toulouse's superb pack brought the champions back into the match with some driving play, scoring a penalty try and winning a string of penalties.</p>
<p>Toulouse's French international prop Jean-Louis Jordana was lucky to remain on the field after felling his opposite number Olivier Gouaillard with a right hook early in the match. He merely received a yellow card.</p>
<p>Unlike Dax, Cardiff and Leicester each made home advantage count in gripping encounters.</p>
<p>Bath, who have managed only win at Cardiff Arms Park in 70 years, were denied again despite a dramatic late comeback which produced 10 points in inury-time.</p>
<p>They were sunk in the end by the boots of Jonathan Davies and replacement full-back Lee Jarvis who kicked five penalties between them as Bath's commitment spilled over. Davies, back in the Welsh squad to face Australia next month, also converted a superb second-half try by former test winger Nigel Walker.</p>
<p>Walker was on the end of some wonderfully creative rugby by scrum-half Robert Howley and centre Mike Hall to wrong-foot Bath's tacklers and celebrated with a raised arm as he crossed under the posts.</p>
<p>New England fly-half Mike Catt kicked four penalties for Bath, but missed three others, and new national captain Phil de Glanville has now finished on the losing side in both matches since his appointment was announced.</p>
<p>Leicester, under the control of former Wallaby coach Bob Dwyer, trailed 10-3 early in the second-half when former England captain Will Carling crashed over for Harlequins second try.</p>
<p>But the home pack responded with characteristic vigour, scoring a converted try through hooker Richard Cockerill and moving ahead with two more penalties from fly-half Rob Liley.</p>
<p>Liley burst through to score a further try in injury-time, denying French pair Laurent Cabannes and Laurent Benezech the chance of a semifinal appearance against their countrymen.</p>
<p>England forward Dean Richards believes the trip across the Channel will test Toulouse's resolve, already shaken by a heavy defeat to Wasps in London.</p>
<p>&quot;Against Toulouse it will be a massive boost for us to play in front of our own noisy, loyal crowd.&quot; Richards admitted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
