<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194529" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-OUT-OF-FAVOUR LECHKOV COULD GO ON TRANSFER LIST.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-OUT-OF-FAVOUR LECHKOV COULD GO ON TRANSFER LIST.</headline>
<dateline>MARSEILLE, France 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yordan Lechkov has fallen a long way from the dizzy heights of a World Cup semifinal two years ago.</p>
<p>The Bulgarian playmaker, singled out as the chief culprit in Marseille's faltering return to the French first division, could go on the transfer list, club sources said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Coach Gerard Gili has dropped Lechkov from his squad in favour of Ludovic Asuar, a product of the club's nursery. Lechkov was not even on the bench for their last match.</p>
<p>&quot;Asuar suits me much better in the same position. The fame of a player should not smother an emerging talent,&quot; said Gili, who steered the former European champions, relegated in 1994 for disciplinary reasons, back to the top flight last season.</p>
<p>Lechkov, an off-season signing from Hamburg and the biggest outfield name to come to a country stunned by a mass exodus of its leading internationals, has lost his way since a promising debut in August.</p>
<p>Gili said: &quot;The door is not shut (for Lechkov). But for the moment, Asuar has passed to the front.&quot;</p>
<p>Lechkov lost his place when Marseille were on the verge of a crisis after two consecutive home defeats against sides lower in the table. Angry fans accused the Bulgarian and other leading players of being unworthy of the club's famous colours.</p>
<p>A fine home win over Monaco last week followed by a goalless draw at Cannes in midweek have put Marseille back on track without Lechkov in the side.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MARSEILLE, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
