<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194657" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Kaunda tries to scupper Zambian election.</title>
<headline>Kaunda tries to scupper Zambian election.</headline>
<byline>Richard Meares</byline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Zambian president Kenneth Kaunda, defying police warnings that he could be arrested for breaking the law, pressed ahead on Saturday with a campaign to scupper Monday's elections, which he is boycotting.</p>
<p>Kaunda, barred from trying to regain the presidency he lost five years ago, called a final mass rally in the capital Lusaka to coincide with one in another part of town by his arch-foe, President Frederick Chiluba.</p>
<p>Chiluba looks set to win the elections, which he refused to postpone despite a public appeal by South African President Nelson Mandela, after Kaunda's United National Independence Party (UNIP) and six smaller parties called a boycott.</p>
<p>UNIP says Chiluba, heralded as a champion of democracy when he took office, has been corrupted by power, abandoning his principles and changing the rules to remain in office.</p>
<p>Only a quarter of the 4.6 million eligible voters have received voter cards and new constitutional rules adopted in May bar Kaunda from running because his parents were foreign.</p>
<p>Foreign donor nations have frozen some aid in protest at the constitutional changes, attacks on the opposition media and other political developments. The freeze has further hit the economy in the copper-rich but heavily indebted country.</p>
<p>Chiluba's four remaining rivals do not pose a major threat, but his Movement for Multiparty Democracy (MMD) could lose support in the simultaneous parliamentary poll, analysts said.</p>
<p>Kaunda, the main opposition leader since he lost power in 1991 after three decades of one-party rule, is trying to ensure the vote loses legitimacy by encouraging people to stay away. UNIP officials have been collecting the election cards of disffected voters, a move police say is illegal.</p>
<p>&quot;Requesting people to surrender their voters' cards is an offence,&quot; the Police Service said in a notice published in Saturday's newspapers, warning that culprits could be jailed.</p>
<p>Police watched but took no action as Kaunda collected 200 voter cards on Friday at rally in the northern Copper Belt area and stuffed them in a bag.</p>
<p>&quot;All you have to do to show that you are unhappy with these elections is to simply stay away,&quot; Kaunda urged his followers.</p>
<p>Kaunda, who has survived in politics despite still being reviled by many for three decades of secret police control and economic mismanagement, has called for civil disobedience but has warned against violence.</p>
<p>Lusaka's university was shut down this week after students rioted, calling for Chiluba to restart political dialogue with his rivals, and members of the two parties have also clashed.</p>
<p>Mandela urged Chiluba on Thursday to declare a state of emergency if that was the only way he could stop the polls, and to reopen dialogue &quot;in the interests of a peaceful settlement&quot;.</p>
<p>Chiluba refused, replying in a letter: &quot;There is no threat to internal stability and security to warrant a draconian move like a state of emergency.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
