<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194694" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico's airport sale details due early 1997.</title>
<headline>Mexico's airport sale details due early 1997.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's plan to privatize its 57 airports should be ready for private investors within the first three months of 1997, a communications and transport ministry spokesman said Friday.</p>
<p>The privatization fits with the government's aim of selling off industries it could no longer afford to maintain properly, according to the ministry source, who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to group the airports to be attractive to private investors,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>But some foreigners have been waiting more than two years to operate Mexico's airports, as the government repeatedly postpones its own deadlines in the privatization process.</p>
<p>&quot;The airport system is a good one and we don't want to rush things. We don't want to repeat the errors made in the past administration.&quot; the ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>Privatizations begun under former President Carlos Salinas have been criticized for favoring the president's cronies and resulting in impractical and costly projects.</p>
<p>Communications and Transport Minister Carlos Ruiz Sacristan has suggested grouping smaller, in-the-red sites with larger, more profitable airports in the same region, according to the source, but the format for granting private operating rights for airports has not yet been decided.</p>
<p>Hampering the privatisation is the fact that the four biggest airports -- Mexico City, Cancun, Guadalajara and Monterrey -- concentrate a huge share of the traffic and almost all of its profitability.</p>
<p>Most of the nation's largest airports have seen growing traffic in the past year, such as Mexico City's Benito Juarez, where passenger flow rose to 9.16 million in the first six months from 9.06 in the same period the year before.</p>
<p>The nation's second largest airport in Cancun, Quintana Roo hosted 3.24 million passengers in the first six months of the year, compared with 3.04 million in the first half of 1995, while the Guadalajara airport saw passenger levels drop to 2.22 million in 1996, from 2.37 million in the first half of 1995.</p>
<p>--Timna Tanners, Mexico City newsroom +525 728 7903</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
