<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194753" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Women's group says poor to bear brunt of free trade.</title>
<headline>Women's group says poor to bear brunt of free trade.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A conference of women from the Asia-Pacific region vowed on Saturday to oppose the APEC group's goal of trade liberalisation, saying it could endanger food security and ravage the economies of some Asian nations.</p>
<p>The delegates, including academics and social workers from the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) countries, said that the massive conversion of agricultural lands to commercial purposes, and the shift to capital-intensive export crops endangered subsistence farmers and rural communities.</p>
<p>&quot;Liberalisation, APEC's banner cry, jeopardises the food security of our countries, especially those with agriculture- based economies,&quot; the 74 delegates said in a statement at the end of their two-day conference.</p>
<p>The delegates urged their government to &quot;resist rapid, blanket trade liberalisation&quot;. APEC has 18 member countries and its official aim is to promote multilateral economic cooperation on issues of trade and investment.</p>
<p>&quot;Everywhere in the APEC member countries we see the ravages of trade liberalisation,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Delegates accused the Indonesian government of wanting to be one of the world's biggest producers of pulp and paper &quot;with little regard to the country's fast dwindling forests.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Logging activities in Sarawak, Malaysia as well as in Papua New Guinea go hand in hand with the repression of indigenous peoples. The Mekong River will soon be dotted with dams whose construction threatens to displace communities,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Philippine government's push to develop industrial estates has made it go back on its promise of land redistribution and abdicate its responsibility to ensure public housing,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>The activities of multinational firms should be subject to &quot;strict environmental standards,&quot; they said.</p>
<p>They also complained that women still remained second-class citizens in their own societies. &quot;The neo-liberal order has made women more vulnerable to market forces,&quot; they said, citing the rise of women trafficking within the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Trafficking in women is second only to the drug trade as the region's booming industries,&quot; they said. The conference did not give statistics.</p>
<p>APEC groups Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, Philippines, Singapore, Taiwan, Thailand, and United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
