<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194884" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian demonstrators demand cannabis legalisation.</title>
<headline>Belgian demonstrators demand cannabis legalisation.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Up to 2,000 mostly young Belgians demonstrated in central Brussels on Saturday to demand the legalisation of cannabis.</p>
<p>Demonstrators, some of them smoking cannabis cigarettes, carried banners advocating that the use of the drug be made legal.</p>
<p>&quot;Cannabis is not prohibited because it is dangerous, it is dangerous because it is prohibited,&quot; one of the banners said.</p>
<p>Matthew, 19, complained he felt like an outlaw because the drug is illegal in Belgium while his parents could drink wine without any problems.</p>
<p>&quot;I like to smoke a joint every weekend,&quot; he told Reuters, stressing, however, that the drug should be used in moderation.</p>
<p>Police estimated that between 1,500 and 2,000 people took part in the event, Belga news agency reported.</p>
<p>Last year, Belgian Interior Minister Johan Vande Lanotte, who admitted using drugs when he was younger, said he opposed legalising soft drugs, crushing a proposal by a parliamentarian to lift the ban.</p>
<p>Francophone socialist member of parliament Patrick Moriau, whose party is part of the centre-left government, has advocated legislation to legalise the use of soft drugs in Belgium. Moriau attended Saturday's demonstration, Belga said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
