<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194821" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan plans 10 percent cut in bread price.</title>
<headline>Jordan plans 10 percent cut in bread price.</headline>
<byline>Dominic Evans</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan plans to cut bread prices by 10 percent by the end of the year, cashing in on a weak world grain market to soften price hikes in August which sparked widespread unrest, an official said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Adnan Odeh, Director of Trade at the Ministry of Supply, said the government aimed to cut the price of bread, the main food for millions of poorer Jordanians, by 20 fils (three U.S. cents) to 160 fils per kilo, or 200 fils for bread made from higher quality flour.</p>
<p>&quot;We would expect prices to stay at this level throughout next year,&quot; Odeh told Reuters. He said the proposed prices, yet to be formally endorsed by the government, were recommended by a ministry study.</p>
<p>The price cut could be implemented as soon as wheat which Jordan bought in an international tender last month found its way into local markets, Odeh added.</p>
<p>Jordan, following advice from the International Monetary Fund, virtually doubled bread prices overnight in August to slash its bill for subsidies as world grain prices reached record highs.</p>
<p>Its modest compensation offer to the most needy failed to prevent the worst outbreak of unrest in the impoverished south since riots in 1989, also sparked by price rises.</p>
<p>King Hussein declared a general amnesty on Tuesday for detainees arrested over the protests and instructed Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti to review bread prices in light of the lower grain costs.</p>
<p>Jordan bought 150,000 tonnes of wheat last month which is due to be delivered in three separate lots in November, December and January. At $164.90 per tonne, it was 40 percent cheaper than prices just six months ago.</p>
<p>Odeh said the government could not pass on to consumers all the savings in purchase costs because it still had to pay for wheat storage in silos, transport from the southern port of Aqaba and distribution around the country.</p>
<p>Officials say the government, as part of its wider overhaul of the subsidies programme, is trying to encourage private sector traders to import grain.</p>
<p>But most Jordanian importers have no storage or distribution facilities to compete with the government and say they are unwilling to launch into major purchases until the government clarifies its plans for liberalisation of imports and sales prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
