<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="194822" id="root" date="1996-11-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Lebanese warlord suffering &quot;slow death&quot; - lawyers.</title>
<headline>Lebanese warlord suffering &quot;slow death&quot; - lawyers.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-11-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lawyers for Lebanon's jailed former Christian warlord Samir Geagea complained that his prolonged solitary confinement in an underground defence ministry cell is subjecting him to &quot;a process of slow death&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Dr Geagea's state of health arouses concern,&quot; lawyers said in a communique published in Beirut newspapers on Saturday demanding that authorities treat him in accordance with the Lebanese constitution and international humanitarian norms.</p>
<p>Geagea, 44, who led the Lebanese Forces Christian militia in the 1975-90 civil war, has been in solitary confinement since his arrest in April 1994.</p>
<p>He has been convicted of two murders and is serving two life sentences.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot believe that the desire to take revenge against him, his sympathisers and those who share his convictions, or even those related to him, can reach such animosity,&quot; the lawyers said.</p>
<p>&quot;He has become slim, pale coloured, and his eyes are deeply set after being detained since nearly three years in a narrow underground cell, where fresh air and sunshines can not reach,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>&quot;He breathes fresh air only one hour daily, and he is not allowed to any radio, television, newspaper or magazine. such conditions violate the Lebanese constitution,&quot; the lawyers added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
