<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195005" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND CALL EMERGENCY MEETING OF IRB.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-ENGLAND CALL EMERGENCY MEETING OF IRB.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>England have called an emergency meeting of the International Rugby Football Board next Tuesday after the latest impasse between the Rugby Football Union (RFU) and the leading clubs.</p>
<p>The English Professional Rugby Union Clubs (EPRUC), which represents the leading English clubs, will not release its players for a series of tour matches over the next month.</p>
<p>The two sides have been locked in an acrimonious dispute over television rights, control of the game and shareout of money.</p>
<p>RFU secretary Tony Hallett said: &quot;We want to ensure that our proposed agreement with the clubs is acceptable to the International Board.&quot;</p>
<p>Cliff Brittle, chairman of the RFU's executive committee, added: &quot;We need to be clear that only the RFU can be in control of the game in this country and not representatives from the leading clubs.</p>
<p>&quot;We have to comply with IB laws and the EPRUC clubs cannot take overall control of competitions and sponsorship.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
