<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195015" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-QUEENSLAND BOWLERS EMBARRASS NSW.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-QUEENSLAND BOWLERS EMBARRASS NSW.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Queensland's bowlers tore through</p>
<p>a near test strength New South Wales batting line-up on Sunday</p>
<p>to set up an almost certain win in their Sheffield Shield match.</p>
<p>In a worrying sign ahead of the first test between Australia</p>
<p>and West Indies which starts on Friday, Queensland dismissed New</p>
<p>South Wales in their second innings for 141 on the third day.</p>
<p>Australia captain Mark Taylor and test batsmen Mark Waugh</p>
<p>and Michael Slater all failed, Taylor making 15, Slater three</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>Waugh a duck.</p>
<p>Steve Waugh followed his first innings century by</p>
<p>top-scoring with 35. Adam Dale, Geoff Foley and Scott Muller</p>
<p>each took two wickets for Queensland.</p>
<p>The second innings capitulation by New South Wales left</p>
<p>Queensland needing just 108 to win and, but for rain</p>
<p>shortening the day's play by an hour, they could have reached</p>
<p>their target with a day to spare.</p>
<p>At stumps Queensland were 44 for one, with Trevor Barsby 30</p>
<p>not out and Martin Love two after opener Troy Dixon was bowled</p>
<p>by leg-spinner Stuart MacGill for 12.</p>
<p>In Melbourne, South Australia reached 214 for five in their</p>
<p>second innings but were still 47 runs behind Victoria's first</p>
<p>innings total going into Monday's final day.</p>
<p>South Australia were forced to follow on after being bowled</p>
<p>out for a paltry 84 on Saturday. Geoff Parker led an apparently</p>
<p>hopeless fight with 52 not out in the second innings.</p>
<p>In Perth, Justin Langer and Tom Moody scored centuries to</p>
<p>rescue Western Australia from a parlous position in their</p>
<p>rain-affected match against Tasmania.</p>
<p>Langer and Moody put on 213 for the fourth wicket after</p>
<p>Western Australia had been in trouble at 64 for three.</p>
<p>Moody, in the hope of forcing a result, declared his side's</p>
<p>innings closed at 326 for four in reply to Tasmania's first</p>
<p>innings 473 for four declared.</p>
<p>That tactic appeared to backfire as Tasmania reached 133</p>
<p>without loss at stumps on the third day, a lead of 280.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
