<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195094" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dallas Cowboys' turf offered to diehard fans.</title>
<headline>Dallas Cowboys' turf offered to diehard fans.</headline>
<dateline>DALLAS 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>For years, diehard Dallas Cowboys fans have worshipped the turf their team walks on. Now, they can buy it too.</p>
<p>Starting from Monday, the recently replaced turf from the reigning National Football League champions' home stadium is going on sale at Texas-sized prices.</p>
<p>A simple six-inch star of Dallas Cowboys turf will cost $24.95 while $100,000 will buy you an entire end zone.</p>
<p>The turf was used from 1981 to the end of last season, a 15-year period that saw the Cowboys first slump and then bounce back to win three of the last four Super Bowl titles.</p>
<p>The Cowboys organisation has long been a master of commercialism and, in promoting the turf sale, is recalling the team's sporting glories and its world-famous cheerleaders.</p>
<p>&quot;Women in white boots, short shorts and frilly cowgirl outfits kicked up their heels on it. Grown men laughed, cried, swore, played, prayed, sweated, ran, passed, slipped, fell, froze, fought and even bled on it. And legends were created on it,&quot; one publicity release said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DALLAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
