<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195189" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romanian gypsies vote for new political tune.</title>
<headline>Romanian gypsies vote for new political tune.</headline>
<byline>Roxana Dascalu</byline>
<dateline>CLEJANI, Romania 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gheorghe Tanase put down the violin which five generations of Gypsies had played before him and voted on Sunday for a change of political tune in Romania.</p>
<p>&quot;It's Mr Emil (Constantinescu). He said we would be free to travel to get work,&quot; muttered Tanase, 65, his face creased in a smile as he plodded down &quot;Musicians' Street&quot;, a dirt road in this forlorn village 40 km (25 miles) southeast of Bucharest.</p>
<p>For lack of curtains, the windows of Tanase's home were covered with posters of Emil Constantinescu, the geology professor out to oust incumbent President Ion Iliescu in Sunday's run-off elections.</p>
<p>&quot;I voted for Mr Emil before and I'll vote for him now, because I can't make a living from music any more. Nobody gets Gypsy bands at weddings. People are too poor.&quot; said Tanase.</p>
<p>Census data shows there are 400,000 Gypsies in Romania. Their leaders say the figure is closer to 2.3 million.</p>
<p>Neither the ex-communist Iliescu nor his reformist rival mentioned Gypsies in campaign debates, which focused on more prominent issues plaguing the Balkan country -- corruption, crime, soaring prices and plunging living standards.</p>
<p>The race between Iliescu and Constantinescu is too close to call. But in parliamentary polls on November 3 Iliescu's leftist party was removed from power for the first time since the 1989 fall of communism.</p>
<p>Three Gypsy parties were in the parliamentary race and one got a single seat in a quota set aside for minorities.</p>
<p>Madalin Voicu, elected to the lower Chamber of Deputies for his &quot;Roma Party&quot;, is a different sort of Gypsy from the downtrodden Tanase. Son of one of Romania's top violin virtuosos, he lives in a villa in a rich Bucharest suburb.</p>
<p>&quot;Post-communist governments have done nothing for our minority,&quot; Voicu said. He said he was &quot;sentimentally close&quot; to Iliescu, but declined to say if he had voted for him.</p>
<p>During World War Two, hundreds of thousands of Romanian Gypsies were deported to Nazi death camps. They were given homes and jobs in the communist era, but remained the target of prejudice and discrimination.</p>
<p>Education, pensions and social assistance are high on Voicu's agenda for parliament -- matching welfare promises made by the centrists who will form the new government.</p>
<p>Descendants from old nomadic tribes said to have come from India in the early Middle Ages, Romanian Gypsies were freed from serfdom in the 19th century.</p>
<p>Ancient crafts are still practised by a few -- tinkers, goldsmiths, bear trainers or musicians. Some still travel around the country in horse-drawn caravans, pitching their tents by the road side and lighting fires for the night.</p>
<p>After voting, Tanase and his mates in the &quot;Ploughmen's Band&quot; met at one of Clejani's many pubs to peer down the road for visiting cars, hoping for a rare booking at a wedding.</p>
<p>&quot;We are only musicians in this village. We learned our music from our grandparents,&quot; said Florea Burcea, 65, hugging his old Russian accordion.</p>
<p>Burcea also voted for Constantinescu, hoping that a new president will make it easier to get visas to travel and perform abroad.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CLEJANI, Romania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
