<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195172" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian Mars probe likely to burn up - officials.</title>
<headline>Russian Mars probe likely to burn up - officials.</headline>
<byline>Philippa Fletcher</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Russian space probe launched on a mission to Mars ran into problems after liftoff and officials said on Sunday it would probably re-enter the Earth's atmosphere and burn up.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got a problem. The probe had been due leave the Earth's orbit last night but it is still there,&quot; said Vladimir Ananyev, a spokesman for the Russian Space Agency.</p>
<p>&quot;The specialists are still working...but it's probably too late,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An official at the Space Communication Centre in Crimea later told journalists the probe was not likely to last long.</p>
<p>&quot;It will probably soon enter the Earth's atmosphere and cease to exist,&quot; Vladimir Molodtsov, deputy flight manager and head of the control team, was quoted saying by Interfax news agency.</p>
<p>The probe could spend a maximum of 30 days orbiting Earth and another official said the team, which had lost contact with the craft, would continue trying to trace it.</p>
<p>&quot;We will carry on looking for it for days,&quot; flight manager Konstantin Sukhanov told Reuters by telephone from the centre.</p>
<p>The six-tonne probe, which lifted off from Kazakhstan's Baikonur space centre on Saturday at 11.48 p.m. Moscow time (2048 GMT), had been due to reach Mars on September 12 next year.</p>
<p>Interfax quoted Molodtsov as saying the fault occurred when booster rockets on the fourth stage failed to ignite.</p>
<p>&quot;Experts think the booster rocket failed in its second ignition while the spacecraft was in the shadow zone. It should have cut in over the Atlantic, in the area of the Gulf of Guinea,&quot; the agency said.</p>
<p>Ekho Moskvy radio suggested that underfunding of the project might be to blame.</p>
<p>Russia's Mars-96 mission was launched two years behind schedule due to cash shortages in its hard-pressed space sector. The probe is carrying 1.1 tonnes of scientific equipment from 20 European countries and the United States.</p>
<p>The radio said scientists working on the project had only received emergency money from the government after pressure from the other countries involved. As a result the project had to be rushed, leaving room for mistakes.</p>
<p>Molodtsov told journalists at the Space Communication Centre in the Crimean town of Yevpatoriya that the first ignition had been successful and the craft had then entered the shadow zone.</p>
<p>Contact was established with the spacecraft after it emerged from the shadow zone, but 12 minutes later than scheduled. It was maintained for three minutes, and then lost.</p>
<p>The $64 million Russian mission is the second of three planned trips from Earth to Mars in just over a month. The United States launched one robot voyage to the Red Planet two weeks ago and a second mission will blast off on December 2.</p>
<p>All were tasked to check for signs of water on the far-away planet -- a key clue to whether there was once life on Mars.</p>
<p>The Russian probe includes two dart-like penetrators designed to pierce the Martian soil and take samples from below ground level and beam information back to the orbiting probe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
