<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19519" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida high court to hear arguments on sugar tax.</title>
<headline>Florida high court to hear arguments on sugar tax.</headline>
<dateline>TALLAHASSEE, Fla. 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida's highest court will hear arguments on Thursday on a trio of proposed constitutional amendments that would place a penny-a-pound tax on raw sugar to pay for the cleanup of the Everglades.</p>
<p>Championed by environmentalists and decried by the sugar industry, the tax package would cost growers an estimated $30 million a year over the next 25 years. The money would go into a trust fund for the cleanup.</p>
<p>Attorneys for both sides will square off Thursday in front of the Florida Supreme Court, which must approve proposed constitutional amendments. The court must agree that each proposed amendment deals with a single subject only and that the ballot summary accurately explains the impact of each.</p>
<p>Industry officials say the tax would be a death knell for the sugar industry. A penny-a-pound tax would cut profit margins in half and threaten the 16,000 jobs, including 3,000 union machinists, directly related to sugar production in southern Florida, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;When you take away a farmer's financial incentive to continue to farm, they are going to turn their resources in another direction,&quot; said Barbara Miedema, spokeswoman for the Belle Glade-based Sugar Cane Growers Cooperative of Florida.</p>
<p>The amendments come to the court after an environmental group, Save Our Everglades, succeeded in garnering 429,000 voter signatures to put each issue on the ballot. This is the second time organizers have faced the state Supreme Court, which struck down a similar proposal in 1994.</p>
<p>One amendment would establish a 1 cent-a-pound tax on raw sugar grown in southern Florida. A second would establish a trust fund and a third would make polluters pay for damage. If approved by voters, the tax also would fund the purchase of land in the Everglades farming area.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the step in the legal process where we were knocked off in 1994,&quot; said Joe Garcia, spokesman for Miami-based Save our Everglades, which is spearheading the drive. &quot;But we are confident that we have made the necessary adjustments and will receive high court approval this year.&quot;</p>
<p>The court is expected to rule on the issue within the next few months. The general election is Nov. 5.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100136">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLAHASSEE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
