<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195225" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Nov 18.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News-Nov 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Coles Myer has rejected a written submission by the Australian Shareholders Association for a full explanation of its recent A$12 million settlement with Yannon Pty Ltd. On the eve of the annual meeting in Sydney, Coles claimed confidentiality on several financial performance issues. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Competition and Consumer Commission chairman Professor Allan Fels believes foreign ownership of Australian media outlets should be determined by a public interest test and not be legislated percentages. Fels said a general interest-test could apply to all Australian media acquisitions, not just to foreign media investors. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following a strong defence of the present superannuation system and an attack on the Treasury submission to the Wallis inquiry by Insurance and Superannuation Commissioner George Pooley, Association of Superannuation Funds of Australia executive director Susan Ryan has said the ASFA is concerned the role of trustees in the operation of super funds might diminish if the inquiry took on the suggestions in the Treasury submission. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Under a joint-venture deal with Ric Stowe's Western Australia-based Griffin Group, Discovery Petroleum will embark on the biggest and most comprehensive exploration programme conducted over Western Australia's Perth Basin. The deal could delay a planned takeover of Discovery Petroleum by Oil Search Ltd. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After last week completing its A$230 million purchase and recapitalisation of Coal Mines Australia Ltd, South African coal giant Ingwe Coal Corp Ltd executive chairman Mick Davis has announced plans to produce 20 million tonnes of steaming coal a year from Australia over the next 10 years. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Goodman Fielder Ltd chairman David Clarke told shareholders at the company's annual general meeting on Friday that as long as the economic environment remained flat and the food industry remained competitive the company was able to predict at least 10 percent profit growth for 1996/97. Page 23.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Coles Myer Ltd annual general meeting will be held in Sydney this week and will see shareholders rallying the company's 14-member board over grievances such as the controversial Yannon transaction, chief executive Peter Bartels A$2.9 million salary pckage, and the previously-discussed issue of director dealings. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian Securities Commission is due to send a letter to the board of rural distribution company IAMA Ltd after the discovery that IAMA was involved in intense negotiations to secure an option over a share parcel in a potential takeover bid at the same time as its chairman, former New South Wales Premer Nick Greiner, sold 300,000 shares at a profit of A$165,000. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Author and corporate consultant Bob Garratt says in his book The Fish Rots From The Head that barely 10 percent of company directors are aware of what their job is about. He said this explains the dramatic under-performance of many companies around the world. Garratt believes that faulty corporate cultures start at the very top. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The High Court agreed on Friday in Sydney to hear an appeal from the Full Federal Court judgment in June which upheld the validity of key provisions in the Corporations Law. The constitutional challenge to the Corporations Law by Favelle Favro Holdings and Armann Aviation has the potential to have great significance for Australian company life. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Bank of Queensland Ltd directors are pushing for plans to put a share buyback mechanism in place. However, the Queensland Government has been reluctant to embrace the bank's offer to acquire and cancel two-thirds of its 44.5 percent holding. The bank's annual general meeting on December 5 will consider a special resolution seeking to amend the banks articles to allow share buybacks. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Figures released by industry group Rice Kachor Research indicate life insurance sales are stagnating as people turn to do-it-yourself superannuation and direct share market investing in an attempt to improve investment returns. The figures show that lump sum rollovers, insurance bonds, and deferred annuities recorded sharp sales falls for the year to June 30. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Market sources have indicated Colonial Retail Property Trust is planning a A$100 million issue to buy the Corio Village shopping centre in Geelong for A$42 million from AMP Investments and the Golden Grove shopping centre in Adelaide for A$35 million from Colonial Investments. The move is another sign that Australia's struggling retail property market may be staging a revival. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Food companies that are reliant on rural commodities as the major input costs, such as Goodman Fielder and Arnotts are predicting better times ahead after a recent dramatic fall in wheat and grain prices. Stockbroking analysts are re-rating food stocks to take into account the positive impact of the lower grain prices. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Westpac chief executive Bob Joss has predicted the aggressive competition in the home lending market will continue, and that the incursion of mortgage managers into the home lending market was here to stay. Speaking on Business Sunday, Joss said he also expected further competition in the credit card market. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Former directors of the once prominent Cut Price Deli Holdings Pty Ltd, Frank Rechichi and Enzo Sgambellone, met in Sydney with creditors of bankrupts and will stage a further meeting to discuss the appointment of a new bankruptcy trustee. Cut Price Deli collapsed over a year ago and remains in voluntary administration. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>International Olympic Committee marketing director Michael Payne said at the IOC's executive board meeting that it was looking at how it could use the Internet for the benefit of the Olympic movement and the kind of role it could play in the Sydney Olympics. By 2000, the use of the Internet is set to increase, and the Sydney Olympics organisers are pushing for the Internet to be the way open for companies other than Olympic sponsor IBM to be involved in the 2000 Games. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australia and New Zealand Banking Group Ltd will today unveil a new &quot;no-frills&quot; home loan that it hopes will put it back into the competitive home loan lending market. The bank plans to undercut discount mortgage lenders with the loan, which would have a variable interestrate of 7.8 percent and allow for weekly, fortnightly or monthly repayments. Page 38.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Coles Myer annual general meeting will be held this week at the Sydney Entertainment Centre. Chairman Nobby Clark will head the meeting which is expected to be a painful review of a year of fear, loathing, litigation and plummeting profitability. Items to be discussed include the Yannon deal, Coles' war and A$1.75 million peace deal with former finance director Philip Bowman, and the decision to back Solomon Lew for another term as director. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In a case handed down by Administrative Appeals Tribunal Deputy President McMahon, Boral has lost its case against the Australian Customs Service over whether quarrying is mining. The decision jeopardises A$100 million of claims from Boral, CSR and Pioneer International. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian Competition and Consumer Commission chairman Professor Allan Fels said yesterday the federal government should consider a public-interest test covering potential changes to foreign media ownership. Speaking on the Face to Face programme, Fels said Parliament should define what ownership level was in the public interest. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>If estimates on a number of paintings due to go up for sale over the next 10 days are any guide, the value of Australian art works appear to have increased by up to 100 percent in the past four years. As an example. Sotheby's is offering a Rupert Bunny piece that was sold for A$253,000 in April 1992 but which is estimated at bringing in A$500,000. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Market economists predict resources will push the overall sharemarket's next big shift to higher ground. However they are unable to agree on when this might occur. The market closed at a record high of 2,387.3 on Friday, spurred by another record on Wall Street and a jump in BHP shares. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite the release of an all-new range of the Magna/Altera, Mitsubishi Australia is virtually banking its entire future on 1997 as fleet generation for the car has fallen well below expectations and the car maker's share of the vehicle market is down to 9.2 percent year-to-date from last year's 10.3 percent. Page C3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
