<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195388" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel says spy suspect treated well in Egypt jail.</title>
<headline>Israel says spy suspect treated well in Egypt jail.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Israeli detained in Egypt on suspicion of spying for the Jewish state is being treated well in prison, Israel's Foreign Ministry said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;Israeli consul in Cairo Yehoshua Gabbai met Israeli citizen Azam Azam at his place of detention in Cairo,&quot; the ministry said in a statement. &quot;Gabbai reported to the Foreign Ministry that Azam Azam is well and that he said during the meeting that he is receiving good treatment and suitable conditions.&quot;</p>
<p>Azam, 35, chief mechanic at an Israeli-owned textile factory in Egypt, was arrested in Cairo last week by security authorities along with Egyptian national Emad eddin Abdel Hamid.</p>
<p>Egyptian security sources have said Hamid confessed to spying for Israel and receiving espionage equipment. Israel has insisted Azam, of Arab origin, was innocent and demanded his release.</p>
<p>Egypt will this week issue an official charge sheet detailing accusations against the two men, an Egyptian public prosecution source said.</p>
<p>The source said Azam could have the lawyers he requested. Israel said it would continue to take any action that could assist Azam.</p>
<p>Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak said on Friday Israeli leaders had squandered the chance to secure Azam's release through quiet diplomacy by making the affair public.</p>
<p>Egypt in 1979 became the first Arab state to sign a peace treaty with Israel but relations have cooled sharply since right-wing Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu took office in June.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
