<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195327" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Sino-Russian trade seen topping $6 billion in 1996.</title>
<headline>Sino-Russian trade seen topping $6 billion in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sino-Russian trade is likely to total more than $6 billion in 1996, fuelled by increased Chinese demand for heavy industrial goods, the Business Weekly said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Trade between the two giant neighbours was $4.7 billion from January to August this year, a rise of 46.5 percent compared with the same period in 1995, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>China's imports of Russian goods jumped 67 percent during the eight months to total $3.67 billion, said the newspaper, which is published by the official China Daily.</p>
<p>Chief imports were chemicals, metal products and spaceflight products, it said. It did not say what China's main exports to Russia were.</p>
<p>&quot;The development of certain fields of infrastructure construction this year have stimulated market demand for such heavy-duty Russian products as steel,&quot; the paper quoted Zhang Chunlai, an official with the China Foreign Trade Research Institute, as saying.</p>
<p>A cut in export tariffs and non-tariff barriers by Russia had also contributed to the rise in imports, Zhang said but did not elaborate.  </p>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov arrived in China on Sunday for an official visit.</p>
<p>Primakov started his visit in the country's industrial and commercial capital of Shanghai, where he will spend one day before meeting Chinese leaders in Beijing on Monday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
