<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195495" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Zairean leader meets Gabon head of state in France.</title>
<headline>Zairean leader meets Gabon head of state in France.</headline>
<dateline>ROQUEBRUNE-CAP MARTIN, France 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gabonese head of state Omar Bongo met convalescing Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko on Sunday and said afterward that a planned multinational force would solve Zaire's problems.</p>
<p>&quot;We discussed the problems that Zaire is experiencing. The solutions have been found. We are going to send security forces there,&quot; Bongo said after 45 minutes of talks at the palatial French Riviera villa where Mobutu has been convalescing since undergoing prostate cancer surgery in Switzerland.</p>
<p>&quot;All of the parties will have to understand -- Zaire, Burundi and Rwanda -- that everyone must return home and that we must facilitate the return home of the refugees. That's all,&quot; Bongo told reporters.</p>
<p>Under a U.N.-approved plan, a multinational peace force under Canadian leadership is to be dispatched to eastern Zaire to help refugees stranded by fighting between Zairean forces and Tutsi rebels.</p>
<p>The mission has gotten off to an uncertain start after hundreds of thousands of the refugees it was intended to help began streaming back home to Rwanda, prompting Washington to consult allies over whether the plan should be rejigged.</p>
<p>Mobutu, who has been keeping a low profile since arriving at his villa from Switzerland on November 4, held talks on Saturday with Zairean Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo.</p>
<p>The premier told reporters afterwards that Mobutu, who has appeared weak and thin during his few recent public appearances, would soon return to Kinshasa.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GABON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROQUEBRUNE-CAP MARTIN, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
