<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195415" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel money supply down 1.2 percent in October.</title>
<headline>Israel money supply down 1.2 percent in October.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's M1 money supply fell a preliminary 1.2 percent in October to 16.63 billion shekels following a 1.5 percent rise in September, the Bank of Israel said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year M1 has expanded 9.55 percent.</p>
<p>Total credit in October rose 2.3 percent to 246.6 billion shekels, led by a 3.5 percent increase in unlinked shekel credits to 81.2 billion shekels, it said.</p>
<p>The increase in credit followed slower rises of 0.8 and 1.0 percent in August and September, respectively.</p>
<p>Money supply figures are one of several the central bank uses to determine short-term interest rates, which are due to be announced on October 25. The current base rate is 15.2 percent and has been falling since August.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Central Bureau of Statistics reported that the October consumer price index rose 0.8 percent. The figure marked a sharp rise from the 0.4 percent increases in August and September, but economists said October inflation was usually higher due to seasonal factors.</p>
<p>($1 = 3.24 shekels)</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
