<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195490" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Cuba holds out hope of end to U.S. embargo.</title>
<headline>Cuba holds out hope of end to U.S. embargo.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Nicholas Doughty, Diplomatic Correspondent</p>
<p>Cuban President Fidel Castro, describing the U.S. economic blockade of his country as &quot;attempted genocide&quot;, said on Sunday he hoped President Bill Clinton would act to ease it following his re-election.</p>
<p>But Castro, speaking at a news conference at the World Food Summit in Rome, said the communist government he has led for nearly four decades on the Caribbean island had achieved &quot;miracles&quot; and that it was not about to change course.</p>
<p>The 70-year-old leader said he hoped a reference in the U.N.-sponsored Rome summit declaration that food should not be used as an economic or political weapon would lead Washington to ease the blockade that has lasted for more than 30 years.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that the election campaign is over in the United States of America, I think President Clinton and his administration...will be able to do something to follow this agreement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Castro, who holds an historic first meeting with Pope John Paul at the Vatican on Tuesday during a rare trip to Europe, said he also hoped for support from the Pontiff and international opinion for ending the embargo.</p>
<p>&quot;One day, these injustices against Cuba will cease.&quot;</p>
<p>Acknowledging that it could be difficult to end the embargo in the face of opposition from the Republican-dominated U.S. Congress, Castro described U.S. policy as &quot;attempted genocide against our country&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;You are not allowed to sell Cuba even one aspirin to help with a headache, nor any medicines against cancer to save life. I think this is a crime against humankind,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Clinton won a second term in U.S. elections this month but has given no sign so far that he is ready to ease the embargo.</p>
<p>Recent U.S. legislation has actually tightened the noose, enraging Washington's European allies because it seeks to punish them for investment in Cuba.</p>
<p>Castro dismissed questions about economic shortages and political freedoms in his country, making clear that he had no intention of ditching the communist ideology like many other countries since the fall of the Berlin Wall.</p>
<p>Saying infant mortality had been cut to eight percent and that Cubans had a life expectancy of 76, he said:</p>
<p>&quot;We have achieved things which I do think deserve respect..We are achieving miracles.</p>
<p>&quot;How have we done this? Thanks to the revolution, because the revolution opened the door -- with no need for any other opening, which would be called counter-revolution.&quot;</p>
<p>Castro noted that Pope John Paul had spoken out against economic embargos. Asked whether a papal visit to Cuba would increase world support for ending the U.S. embargo, he said it would be a &quot;very important event&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
