<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195586" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India air disaster sparks national media outcry.</title>
<headline>India air disaster sparks national media outcry.</headline>
<byline>Clarence Fernandez</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A blizzard of outrage in Indian newspapers after the world's worst mid-air collision over New Delhi last week has focused on the nation's inadequate disaster management plans.</p>
<p>The Indian government has dismissed initial fears that obsolete equipment and language problems were to blame for the crash, in which a Saudi Arabian jumbo jet and a Kazakh cargo freighter collided, killing all 349 people on board.</p>
<p>But whatever the real cause of the disaster was, many commentators said the inefficiency and foot-dragging of government agencies' were almost as much to blame.</p>
<p>&quot;If the nations of the world ever met for a beauty contest, they'd probably crown India Calamity Jane,&quot; the Sunday Times of India said. &quot;India has first world aspirations, Third World resources, and a netherworld sense of priorities.&quot;</p>
<p>A boom in air travel after economic reform began in 1991 has strained India's airport infrastructure badly. Domestic air travel is growing 11 percent a year, officials say, and international traffic is rising seven percent annually.</p>
<p>Bombay-based media analyst M.V. Kamath said the media outcry over the lack of a coordinated diaster management plan was a breast-beating impulse that comes naturally to Indians.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the natural Indian breast-beating which comes through on every occasion, which says the government is useless, the bureaucracy is terrible and so on,&quot; Kamath told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a little overdone, because I don't think we are that bad, but it's a little better to overreact than be complacent.&quot;</p>
<p>The crash, India's worst air disaster, followed swiftly after a cyclone in the southeastern state of Andhra Pradesh the previous week that killed more than 840 people -- and found the government machinery just as unprepared, commentators said.</p>
<p>&quot;What India has done is to convey a unique message to the world community: that our air is poisonous, that our cities are disease-prone, that we can't act on weather forecasts and that we can't even guarantee air miles which can be redeemed,&quot; the Indian Express newspaper said in an editorial.</p>
<p>Other commentators criticised the government for losing sight of the human dimensions of the tragedy in its haste to cover up what they said were its deficiencies.</p>
<p>&quot;To keep the heads firmly fixed on the necks that carry them, the government of India decides to use all the information, statistics, rhetoric, talent at its command and establish that 'it was right',&quot; the Asian Age said.</p>
<p>A brand new $92-million radar and communications system, due to become operational at major airports six months ago, has been delayed by technical snags, officials said.</p>
<p>Angry commentators sniped at the use officials have made of another new offshoot of technology -- the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;After the recent cyclone, Andhra Pradesh Chief Minister Chandrababu Naidu sent a message on the Internet seeking charity from the 'philanthropists of the world',&quot; the Sunday Times said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Indian genius has just reshaped the Internet into a state-of-the-art begging bowl.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
