<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19551" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot natgas holds, swing prices talked lower.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot natgas holds, swing prices talked lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. September spot natgas prices held mostly steady Wednesday as nomination deadlines expired on many of the pipes and there was talk of much weaker prices for the first few days of the month, sources said.</p>
<p>Louisiana Gulf Coast prices languished mostly in the mid-to-high $1.70s per million British thermal units in sparse trading.</p>
<p>At the Henry Hub, La., prices ranged anywhere from the mid-$1.80s to the mid-$1.70s, with sporadic talk of the $1.60s for the first three days of September.  </p>
<p>In the Midcontinent, September pricing remained in the $1.60s, but there was talk of swing prices in the $1.70s as forecasters called for above-normal temperatures in the northern part of the region next week.</p>
<p>For Thursday delivery, Midcontinent prices slipped about five cents to the high-$1.50s.</p>
<p>Expectations for hot weather next week in the West but forecasts for normal to below-normal temperatures in Texas left the Permian basin market at a stalemate today. As a result, traders reported closing most deals in the low-to-mid $1.60s.</p>
<p>Meanwhile at the southern California border prices also held firm in the high-$1.60s, still down about 50 cents from August's index.</p>
<p>In the Appalachian region, the market was also quiet as talk of prices hovered in the low-to-mid $1.90s, down about 50 cents from August 1 levels. August swing gas was selling in the mid-$1.90s, traders said.</p>
<p>The upcoming Labor Day Holiday has left many traders on the sidelines as they await the flow of nominated gas. Several traders said they are expecting an active aftermarket next week when warmer temperatures return to the northern states and western U.S.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
