<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195506" id="root" date="1996-11-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kinkel tells Iran to protect German nationals.</title>
<headline>Kinkel tells Iran to protect German nationals.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel called on his Iranian counterpart Ali Akbar Velayati on Sunday to do everything possible to calm tensions between their countries, and called on him to protect German nationals.</p>
<p>The Foreign Ministry said Kinkel had held &quot;detailed conversations&quot; with Velayati on Saturday and Sunday.</p>
<p>Relations between the two countries have plunged since a German prosecutor last week accused Iranian supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei and other Tehran officials of ordering the deaths of three senior Kurdish opposition figures and their translator at a Berlin restaurant in 1992.</p>
<p>Kinkel explained to Velayati that the German judiciary is independent and that the government has no right to interfere in court proceedings, the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Kinkel pointed out to his Iranian counterpart that Iran is obliged by international law to protect the Germans, and German diplomatic personnel, in Iran,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>About 5,000 Iranian students marched to Germany's embassy in Tehran on Sunday and threw eggs and tomatoes at the compound to protest against the prosecutor's accusations.</p>
<p>Velayati told Iranian television, monitored by the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC): &quot;We will not compromise with anyone or anything over Islamic values and the values of the Islamic Republic of Iran.&quot;</p>
<p>Germany was &quot;gravely mistaken&quot; if it thought Iran would ignore such an insult, Velayati said.</p>
<p>Tehran has denied any role in the killings and protested on Thursday to Bonn over the charges.</p>
<p>&quot;In our view, that move is not a judicial one, but a totally political one,&quot; Velayati said on television.</p>
<p>Kinkel urged Velayati to do everything to avoid a further escalation of the situation, and said both sides must keep a cool head in the present difficult situation.</p>
<p>Potentially at risk are trade ties worth $1.4 billion last year and Europe's &quot;critical dialogue&quot; with Iran -- championed by Kinkel as an alternative to U.S. sanctions aimed at isolating the Islamic republic.</p>
<p>German prosecutors demanded life sentences for an Iranian and a Lebanese on Friday, after accusing Tehran of ordering the deaths of the three Kurdish opposition leaders and their translator.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
