<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="19553" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rating upgrade from S&amp;P not in cards for Illinois.</title>
<headline>Rating upgrade from S&amp;P not in cards for Illinois.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>It wasn't the upgrade state of Illinois officials wanted, but Standard &amp; Poor's Corp on Wednesday did improve the state's rating outlook to positive from stable.</p>
<p>Illinois' AA-minus general obligation rating was affirmed by Standard &amp; Poor's for more than $5 billion of outstanding debt, as well as for a $185 million GO bond issue the state has scheduled for a competitive sale Sept. 4.</p>
<p>&quot;We thought it was appropriate to recognize the state's strong budget progess,&quot; said Joe O'Keefe, a director at Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
<p>However, he pointed out that Illinois' rating was not upgraded because the state still faces a number of critical challenges over the next few years. Those include pension funding, education funding reform and implementation of a managed-care program for Medicaid recipients.</p>
<p>Mike Colsch, Illinois' deputy budget director, said he was &quot;slightly disappointed&quot; that the rating upgrade the state had sought did not materialize.</p>
<p>Still, he said he was pleased that Standard &amp; Poor's recognized the financial progess the state has made by improving the rating outlook.</p>
<p>As for the critical challenges ahead cited by Standard &amp; Poor's, Colsch said that the state has a mechanism in place to address funding of state pension funds.</p>
<p>But that funding system is currently being contested in a lawsuit brought by the state's five pension funds and their beneficiaries. If successful, the 1991 lawsuit could force the state to appropriate $2 billion to $3 billion for the pension funds, according to lawyers representing the plaintiffs.</p>
<p>Colsh said education funding reform is &quot;clearly on the agenda&quot; for the administration of Gov. Jim Edgar. Earlier this year, state lawmakers rejected Edgar's plan to place a proposed constitutional amendment on the ballot that would have required the state to fund a greater share of education.</p>
<p>In the area of Medicaid, Colsh said the state believes its MediPlan Plus managed-care system, which received federal approval last month, will result in improved monitoring, cost controls and services.</p>
<p>Illinois plans to place more than 1.1 million of Medicaid recipient into the system sometime next fiscal year.</p>
<p>Illinois is also awaiting ratings for its upcoming $185 million GO bond issue from Moody's Investors Service and Fitch Investors Service.</p>
<p>The Fitch rating will be the state's first since that rating agency was recapitalized and reactivated in 1989.</p>
<p>Colsh said contacts with market participants led the state to seek a third rating. He pointed out that most states now have a Fitch rating and that Fitch &quot;has a strong municipal rating team.&quot;</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
