<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195663" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: SOCCER-HONDURAS SCORE 11 BUT STILL GO OUT OF WORLD CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HONDURAS SCORE 11 BUT STILL GO OUT OF WORLD CUP.</headline>
<byline>Brian Homewood</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Honduras hammered 11 goals</p>
<p>past hapless St Vincent on Sunday, beating the Caribbean</p>
<p>amateurs 11-3, but were still knocked out of the World Cup as</p>
<p>rivals Jamaica beat Mexico 1-0 at home.</p>
<p>Jamaica had needed only a point from their game in Kingston</p>
<p>to reach the final stage of the CONCACAF World Cup qualifying</p>
<p>tournament at the Hondurans' expense but took all three thanks</p>
<p>to an 82nd-minute goal by Ian Godison.</p>
<p>Jamaica finished top of semifinal stage group three, one</p>
<p>point ahead of the apathetic Mexicans, who had already</p>
<p>guaranteed their place in the six-team final.</p>
<p>St Vincent, who lost all six group games and conceded 32</p>
<p>goals, also let in 11 goals in a World Cup qualifier against</p>
<p>Mexico four years ago.</p>
<p>Honduras, whose only appearance in the World Cup finals was</p>
<p>in Spain in 1982, had to make up a difference of 10 goals as</p>
<p>well as hope for a Jamaica defeat.</p>
<p>The two games kicked off at the same time and by halftime</p>
<p>there was a glimmer of hope for Honduras as they led 5-1 in the</p>
<p>country's second city of San Pedro Sula while Jamaica were being</p>
<p>held 0-0.</p>
<p>Milton Nunez and Nicolas Suazo both scored hat-tricks for</p>
<p>Honduras, who were left to lament their failure to beat Jamaica</p>
<p>at home last month. That game ended 0-0.</p>
<p>Mexico did Honduras no favours by selecting a depleted squad</p>
<p>which featured seven uncapped players. The stars, such as</p>
<p>goalkeeper Jorge Campos and strikers Carlos Hermosillo and</p>
<p>Zague, were involved in club matches in the Mexican</p>
<p>championship, which carried on regardless of the national team's</p>
<p>World Cup commitment.</p>
<p>Despite this, the Mexicans had the better of the game before</p>
<p>a capacity 30,000 crowd. Striker Ricardo Pelaez hit the post</p>
<p>just before halftime then saw his header from the rebound</p>
<p>miraculously scrambled away.</p>
<p>Godison's strike gave Jamaica, who have little tradition in</p>
<p>the sport, one of the best results of their soccer history.</p>
<p>Costa Rica beat Guatemala 3-0 at home to join the United</p>
<p>States at the top of group one, which is still in its early</p>
<p>stages. Costa Rica and the United States are clear favourites to</p>
<p>qualify from the group, which also contains Trinidad.</p>
<p>Canada are already through from group two, with El Salvador</p>
<p>and Cuba fighting for the second spot. The final CONCACAF round,</p>
<p>to be played next year, will decide the region's three</p>
<p>representatives at the 1998 World Cup.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SVIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
