<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195636" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-BRONCOS BREEZE BY PATRIOTS, BILLS STOP BENGALS.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-BRONCOS BREEZE BY PATRIOTS, BILLS STOP BENGALS.</headline>
<dateline>FOXBORO, Massachusetts 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Terrell Davis scored three touchdowns to help Denver build a 24-0 halftime lead and the Broncos coasted to a 34-8 victory over the New England Patriots on Sunday.</p>
<p>Davis rushed for 154 yards on 32 carries and leads the NFL with 1,209 rushing yards. It was the sixth 100-yard rushing game for Davis this season.</p>
<p>&quot;It's real hard to cut on that field and I knew my moves had to be a little more subtle today,&quot; said Davis. &quot;I just told myself to run hard today and once I got into the secondary, I tried not to go down on the first hit.&quot;</p>
<p>The win was the seventh in a row for the Broncos, who own the NFL's best record at 10-1.</p>
<p>In Buffalo, Jim Kelly threw for a touchdown and ran for another and Thurman Thomas rushed for 78 yards as the Buffalo Bills stopped the Cincinnati Bengals, 31-17.</p>
<p>Kelly was 13-of-22 for 199 yards and one interception, which was returned 31 yards for a TD by cornerback Ashley Ambrose in the second quarter.</p>
<p>In Atlanta, Bobby Hebert passed for 229 yards and two touchdowns for the Falcons who scored all of their points in the first half, but held on for a 17-15 victory over the New Orleans Saints in a battle of NFC West cellar-dwellers.</p>
<p>Hebert completed 26-of-39 passes, including scoring strikes of eight yards to Eric Metcalf in the first quarter and five yards to Terance Mathis in the second period.</p>
<p>In Detroit, Jason Hanson kicked a 43-yard field goal with 4:32 remaining and Barry Sanders rushed for 134 yards as the Detroit Lions snapped a four-game losing streak with a 17-16 victory over the Seattle Seahawks.</p>
<p>The Seahawks had a chance to win on the final play, but Todd Peterson's 42-yard field goal try sailed wide right as time expired.</p>
<p>In Indianapolis, Cary Blanchard kicked four field goals, including a 37-yarder with 8:10 to play to provide the go-ahead points as the Indianapolis Colts rallied past the New York Jets, 34-29.</p>
<p>Blanchard, a former Jet, added a 50-yard field goal with 1:24 left to give Indianapolis (6-5) a five-point lead.</p>
<p>The Jets have lost 10 games for the third straight season.</p>
<p>In Kansas City, Kimble Anders scored on a 10-yard run in the second quarter and Mark Collins made two key defensive plays in a scoreless second half to lead the Kansas City Chiefs to a 14-10 victory over the Chicago Bears.</p>
<p>Anders' 10-yard touchdown run with four-and-a-half minutes left in the first half gave Kansas City the lead for good at 10-7.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Gus Frerotte found tight end Jamie Asher for two touchdowns passes and Scott Blanton kicked four field goals as the Washington Redskins regained first place in the NFC East with a 26-21 victory over the Philadelphia Eagles.</p>
<p>Washington (8-3) moved a game ahead of the Eagles (7-4) for the top spot in the division.</p>
<p>The Redskins got 84 yards on 25 carries from Terry Allen, while Watters ran for 87 on 26 attempts for Philadelphia.</p>
<p>In Pittsburgh, Yancey Thigpen caught his first two touchdown balls of the season and the Pittsburgh defence scored once and forced another costly turnover as the Steelers cruised past the Jacksonville Jaguars, 28-3.</p>
<p>The Steelers (8-3) avenged a 24-9 opening-day loss to Jacksonville (4-7) by forcing four turnovers, but the two fumbles they forced on Jaguars quarterback Mark Brunell made the difference.</p>
<p>&quot;A game of big plays -- we made more of them than they did,&quot; Steelers coach Bill Cowher said.</p>
<p>In St Louis, Anthony Johnson rushed for 121 yards, including a seven-yard scamper with 1:31 left in the third quarter that snapped a tie and boosted the Carolina Panthers to a 20-10 defeat of the St. Louis Rams.</p>
<p>It was Johnson's fourth 100-yard effort of the season. Beuerlein completed 13-of-28 passes for 136 yards with one interception and one touchdown.</p>
<p>One week after scoring 59 points against Atlanta, St. Louis was held to one touchdown and 243 total yards against the Panthers (7-4).</p>
<p>At Arizona, Boomer Esiason passed for 260 yards and two first-half touchdowns and Anthony Edwards recovered a key fumble in the fourth quarter as the Arizona Cardinals held off the New York Giants, 31-23.</p>
<p>&quot;For some reason, somehow, somewhere we started believing in ourselves,&quot; Esiason said. &quot;I'm real happy for all of us. It was nice to get off to a good start.  However, it's a sign of a young team that we didn't put them away.</p>
<p>Esiason struggled in a 16-8 loss at New York two weeks ago, but he was 18-for-26 and put Arizona ahead to stay with an 18-yard scoring strike to Rob Moore 5:33 into the game.</p>
<p>New York has lost four of its last six games.</p>
<p>In Houston, Dan Marino hit tight end Troy Drayton with a 51-yard pass to set up Joe Nedney's 29-yard field goal as time expired, giving the Miami Dolphins a come-from-behind 23-20 victory over the Houston Oilers.</p>
<p>&quot;I did not expect to have so much room in front of me,&quot; Drayton said.  &quot;Danny made a great read and O.J McDuffie made a great block.&quot;</p>
<p>Rookie linebacker Zach Thomas had a clutch 26-yard interception return for a touchdown for the Dolphins (6-5).</p>
<p>In San Diego, Michael Husted kicked four field goals and Trent Dilfer passed for a career-high 327 yards as the Tampa Bay Buccaneers won consecutive games for the first time this season with a come-from-behind 25-17 victory over the San Diego Chargers.</p>
<p>Husted's third field goal of the game 6:28 into the fourth quarter drew the Buccaneers within 17-16. On San Diego's next possession, safety John Lynch intercepted Stan Humphries' pass and returned it 18 yards to the San Diego 18, and Errict Rhett's one-yard plunge gave Tampa Bay a 22-17 lead.</p>
<p>In Oakland, Scott Sisson bounced back from a fourth-quarter miss to cap a masterful drive with 31-yard field goal in overtime that gave the Minnesota Vikings a 16-13 victory over the Oakland Raiders that snapped their four-game losing streak.</p>
<p>After stopping the Raiders on the first possession of overtime, the Vikings moved 71 yards in 16 plays, chewing up nearly 8-1/2 minutes. Sisson, who missed a 38-yarder with 3:20 to play in regulation, split the uprights with 3:07 left in overtime, his third field goal of the game.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FOXBORO, Massachusetts"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
