<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195681" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SOCCER-FIFA NOT TO TAKE PART IN PORTUGUESE BRIBERY PROBE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FIFA NOT TO TAKE PART IN PORTUGUESE BRIBERY PROBE.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>FIFA, world soccer's governing body, said on Monday it would not be part of the Portuguese Football Federation's investigation into allegations of bribery and match-fixing.</p>
<p>Following a 75 minute meeting with Gilberto Madahil, chairman of the Portuguese federation, FIFA general secretary Sepp Blatter indicated he was satisfied with the way the investigation was proceeding.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an internal matter and FIFA will not get involved,&quot; said Blatter, adding that it was the Portuguese federation that sought the meeting and not FIFA.</p>
<p>&quot;We've taken note of the problems and the Portuguese federation deserves our complete trust and time to investigate. We appeal to the media to give the authorities time to do their job.&quot;</p>
<p>Madahil is scheduled to fly to Amsterdam on Tuesday where he will meet with UEFA officials to discuss the allegations.</p>
<p>UEFA, however, having demanded a thorough investigation of the various charges and accusations, may require greater assurances from the Portuguese federation that it is capable handling the matter on its own.</p>
<p>Portuguese soccer has been plunged into crisis by the allegations that Porto sought to bribe a referee ahead of a Cup Winners' Cup semifinal match against Aberdeen 12 years ago.</p>
<p>Businessman Fernando Barata has told police that he was asked to approach the Romanian referee in charge of the game and offer him money to secure a 3-0 win for the Portuguese side in the home leg.</p>
<p>Porto won both legs 1-0. Both Porto and the match official have denied any bribery attempt was made.</p>
<p>Porto are also at the centre of another controversy over the payment of a holiday in Brazil for referee Carlos Calheiros in the summer of 1995.</p>
<p>The club has officially admitted that it picked up the 700,000 escudo ($4,600) bill but says that it did so without realising who it was for.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
