<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195821" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IRA &quot;rumour-mongering&quot; on N.Irish truce - Trimble.</title>
<headline>IRA &quot;rumour-mongering&quot; on N.Irish truce - Trimble.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pro-British leader David Trimble accused the outlawed Irish Republican Army on Monday of rumour-mongering about a truce in the Northern Irish conflict.</p>
<p>The Ulster Unionist Party (UUP) leader also attacked Britain for fuelling fears that it might ease terms to give guerrillas a voice in peace talks.</p>
<p>&quot;The IRA (Irish Republican Army) have set in process a whole series of rumours about ceasefires,&quot; Trimble said after weekend reports that a guerrilla truce had been operating for the past six weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think there's much substance to this because I don't think they (the IRA) can meet the requirements (specified by Britain and Ireland),&quot; he told BBC radio.</p>
<p>Britain and Sinn Fein, the IRA's political wing, have both repudiated a Dublin Sunday newspaper report of an unofficial truce which added to a flurry of speculation over the strategy of IRA hawks who ended a truce in February, plunging peace efforts into chaos.</p>
<p>Some 200 members of Sinn Fein, which is currently excluded from multi-party talks because of IRA violence, are to hold a special conference in the Irish Republic on Saturday.</p>
<p>A party spokesman in Dublin said it was being held &quot;for the purposes of discussing the processes of conflict resolution&quot; and would take place in private at an undisclosed location.</p>
<p>The conference is to be addressed by Martin McGuinness, the party's chief strategist who said last week that the IRA would not call a truce unless Britain agreed to give Sinn Fein a place in unconditional peace talks.</p>
<p>Trimble, who wants the IRA to disarm before Sinn Fein is admitted to the talks, said the IRA aimed to persuade London to abandon its demands for a truce and a firm commitment to peace as the price of Sinn Fein's entry into the negotiations.</p>
<p>The UUP leader, whose party has a nine-vote bloc in the British parliament that is increasingly crucial to the Conservative government's survival, chided British Northern Ireland Secretary Sir Patrick Mayhew for making a public reply to McGuinness's demands on the terms of entry to talks.</p>
<p>&quot;He clearly appears to be trying to semaphore something to the IRA,&quot; Trimble said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's bound to give rise to a certain amount of unease among people when...they wonder is there any fire behind this smoke.&quot;</p>
<p>Earlier, Gary McMichael, leader of the political arm of the UDA, a banned pro-British extremist group, said secret British deals with the IRA could wreck peace efforts.</p>
<p>McMichael said he believed Sinn Fein was seeking concessions as a reward for a new IRA ceasefire.</p>
<p>The IRA's last attack in its guerrilla war against British rule of Northern Ireland was on October 7, when it bombed Britain's army headquarters in Northern Ireland, killing a soldier and injuring 30 people.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
