<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195860" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Europe gasoline prices seen falling after UK budget.</title>
<headline>Europe gasoline prices seen falling after UK budget.</headline>
<byline>John Hanley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>European gasoline prices are vulnerable to a sharp selloff after the U.K. budget on November 26 when bearish fundamentals are likely to reassert themselves, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;After the budget you would expect to have mogas up to the roofs in the tanks. Any volume after that date has to be sold,&quot; a trader in the Netherlands said.</p>
<p>Premium unleaded in the NWE barge market rallied about 20 percent or $40 per tonne to $245 fob as the industry built up inventories ahead of the U.K. budget and crude and gasoline futures rallied sharply.</p>
<p>The British government has committed itself to raising excise duty of gasoline by five percent annually plus the rate of inflation, so a hike of 3.0-3.2 pence a litre at the pump is expected.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not see much demand because the U.K. is completely filled up and they won't want the stocks and it will probably take all of December&quot; to sell off extra inventories, said another trader in Amsterdam.</p>
<p>Gasoline crack spreads were also expected to drop to $2 per barrel from above $3, which would put premium unleaded prices near $208 per tonne, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;These are temporary factors that come into the market now and then and then dissipate,&quot; said Peter Bogin, associate director at Cambridge Energy Research Associates in Paris.</p>
<p>&quot;We look at the market as fundamentally weak but one that has pockets of strength where there is a demand surge,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Another prop that may be knocked away, traders said, was the arbitrage to the U.S., which opened in the last two weeks when U.S. prices soared after shortages from traditional suppliers in Latin America and outages hit several domestic refineries.</p>
<p>Traders estimated almost 650,000 tonnes will be loaded in November cross the Atlantic from Europe, a traditional gasoline exporter to the U.S.</p>
<p>That compares with 3.3 million barrels or 396,000 tonnes in Nov 1995, according to the U.S. Energy Information Administration.</p>
<p>Traders said a sharp selloff that would open the arbitrage again or encourage some stockbuilding may not be enough to bolster prices.</p>
<p>&quot;Certainly there is not a shortage of gasoline in Europe,&quot; said Bogin, noting the regular unleaded to Brent crude crack was negative in September for the first time in six years.</p>
<p>Euroilstock data show gasoline inventories in Europe fell 3.74 million barrels in October from September, to 153 million, but were 2.97 million above a year ago.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
