<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195958" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Boycotted Zambian polls draw to close peacefully.</title>
<headline>Boycotted Zambian polls draw to close peacefully.</headline>
<byline>Richard Meares</byline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambian elections drew peacefully towards their close on Monday, marred by an opposition boycott and disapproval from Western donors who fear it was largely a cosmetic exercise in democracy.</p>
<p>President Frederick Chiluba is set for a second term after barring a challenge from his only strong rival, &quot;Father of the Nation&quot; Kenneth Kaunda, whom he beat in the first free elections in 1991 on a free-market and democracy platform.</p>
<p>Enraged, Kaunda's United National Independence Party (UNIP) walked out of parliament and led a seven-party boycott of the presidential and parliamentary polls they call a farce.</p>
<p>Chiluba, 53, voted in his Copperbelt region stronghold and Kaunda, 72, went to play his favourite sport, golf.</p>
<p>Kaunda said he would call for the results to be annulled but would denounce violence as a means of change.</p>
<p>&quot;These people did more damage in five years than I did in 27,&quot; he told reporters aid as he teed off. &quot;But violence is not my way.&quot;</p>
<p>Voting, held up in many polling stations by bureaucratic bungles, was extended into the evening in some places to enable everyone queuing to vote. No official western observers came.</p>
<p>Police said the day passed without much-feared violence.</p>
<p>Final results were not due until Tuesday or Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Turnout appears to have been very, very low,&quot; said UNIP central committee member Proff Desai. &quot;It was hundreds rather than thousands at all of the polling stations I visited.&quot;</p>
<p>State officials said voting was brisk despite a flawed registration system that omitted half the 4.6 million adults.</p>
<p>&quot;Voters in their numbers braved the rain to vote and are throwing election boycotts to the wind,&quot; state radio said.</p>
<p>Kaunda, who led Zambia to independence from Britain in 1964 and founded a one-party state on African-Christian-socialist &quot;humanism&quot;, was ruled out under a new constitution passed in May by Chiluba's Movement for Multiparty Democracy (MMD) because his parents were not Zambian-born. They were from Malawi.</p>
<p>Whatever the outcome of the vote, political strife and economic hardship are set to intensify.</p>
<p>UNIP has launched a campaign of civil disobedience and predicted Chiluba's downfall within six months, assuming he beats his four remaining challengers who stood on Monday.</p>
<p>Foreign donors, upset by the bar on Kaunda and by other political developments in what had been a model of African progress, have frozen aid which helped copper-rich but impoverished Zambia cope with its $6.4 billion external debt.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of the hard-won gains of the last five years of reform are now at risk from the donor freeze,&quot; said the Standard Chartered bank group's September report on Zambia.</p>
<p>The World Bank says privatisation and economic reform in landlocked Zambia are second to none in Africa.</p>
<p>After the vote donors will face a dilemma -- to watch Zambia's economic promise fade away; or to eat humble pie and resume aid, having failed, like South African President Nelson Mandela, to make Chiluba reopen dialogue with UNIP.</p>
<p>Ironically most political analysts believe Chiluba would easily have beaten Kaunda in a free contest between the parties, which they said differ little on policy nowadays.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
