<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="195941" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FEATURE - Internal trade barriers slow canada's economy.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Internal trade barriers slow canada's economy.</headline>
<byline>Paul Simao</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's national unity problems don't begin and end with Quebec's separatist aspirations.</p>
<p>Economic fault lines, caused by trade barriers between the provinces, pose an equally serious threat to the brittle foundations of Canadian statehood.</p>
<p>Much of this erosion is caused by arcane and often contradictory laws governing internal trade among Canada's 10 provinces and two territories.</p>
<p>The laws, rooted firmly in the protectionist past, have been passed through generations like the family silver. But the inheritance is an awkward one.</p>
<p>Everywhere Canadians go -- from the seashore to the liquor store -- they suffer restrictions on the right to work where they choose, buy what they want and pay what they should.</p>
<p>The condition is widespread, with the bigger provinces leading the way and the smaller ones nipping close behind.</p>
<p>Ontario, the richest, most populous province and Canada's economic engine, is one of the &quot;enfants terribles&quot; of internal trade barriers. Ontario's government-run liquor commission -- just one of the lucrative enterprises controlled by provincial bureaucrats -- routinely reserves its premium shelf space and best marketing for Ontario-based companies.</p>
<p>Beers and wines from further afield rarely get the chance to compete against Ontario brands. When out-of-province brews do make it to market, they are treated rather like gatecrashing nudists at a church-hall revival.</p>
<p>&quot;Nobody talks to you, and (they) just hope you go away,&quot; said an exasperated Bob Telder, owner of a speciality winery in Nova Scotia that has tried unsuccessfully to sell its wines though Ontario stores. &quot;I'm not getting a fair shake from Ontario.&quot;</p>
<p>Telder's family-owned Telder-Berry-Wines has seen its efforts to sell wine outside Nova Scotia blocked by government-run liquor commissions and punitive provincial duties. While a bottle of Telder-Berry wine sells for nine Canadian dollars ($6.71) on average in Nova Scotia, it would fetch C$16 if sold in neighbouring New Brunswick.</p>
<p>The difference -- much of it due to a regulation that requires Canadian wine to be double-bonded before shipping -- prices Telder's wines out of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;It would just sit on the shelf for $16 and make us look bad,&quot; Telder told Reuters.</p>
<p>Not even tiny Prince Edward Island, a province that courts outsiders during the summer tourist season, is immune to the fortress mentality. The island's rust-red sands may be the stuff that dreams are made of, but staking your claim is pure nightmare. Amazingly, non-residents must gain approval from the provincial cabinet to buy oceanfront property.</p>
<p>&quot;P.E.I is very small, and there is the wish to maintain control of the land so that it is not all bought up by speculators,&quot; Sandy Stewart, the province's internal trade representative, told Reuters.</p>
<p>INTERNAL BARRIERS BLAMED ON FEDERAL GOVERNMENT</p>
<p>Internal trade barriers exist in part because the federal government has defended inter-provincial trade with a fawn-like shyness. While the United States brooks little interference with the sacrosanct commerce clause of the U.S. Constitution, the Canadian government nudges rather than mandates the provinces to negotiate lower trade barriers.</p>
<p>A case in point is a 1994 Agreement on Internal Trade (AID). The agreement, signed by all of Canada's first ministers, is so vague and toothless that one year after its implementation, Canadian workers and businesses continue to find themselves shut out of markets.</p>
<p>&quot;The enforcement of it (the agreement) is voluntary, and there are all sorts of exceptions,&quot; said Filip Palda, an economist with the right-leaning Fraser Institute. Provinces can ignore anything in the agreement provided they are pursuing a &quot;legitimate objective&quot;, Palda said.</p>
<p>INTERNAL BARRIERS COST ONE PERCENT OF GDP ANNUALLY</p>
<p>The federal government estimates that internal trade barriers cost Canadians C$7 billion each year -- about one percent of the country's Gross Domestic Product. More than 1.9 million Canadians' jobs are linked to inter-provincial trade.</p>
<p>Despite their obvious costs, trade barriers have a long and healthy history in Canada. Protectionism first found a home in Canada in the 19th century when fear of U.S. hegemony was the rage. Pushed by the infant manufacturing sector, politicians imposed tariffs and barriers on a range of imported goods.</p>
<p>Despite occasional moves toward continental free trade, the tariff wall persisted for more than a century. It even grew stronger as the spectre of U.S. domination was revived in the 1960s and early 70s by successive Liberal governments.</p>
<p>The 1981 recession and the subsequent emergence of the global economy later in the decade forced a review of Canadian trade policy. The offshoots -- the 1988 Free Trade Agreement, the 1992 North American Free Trade Agreement and the 1994 General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade -- confirmed Canada's new-found love affair with free trade.</p>
<p>Now, the Canadian government wants its own provinces to try a little tenderness.</p>
<p>&quot;When the Fathers of Confederation built a transcontinental dominion, their objective was not a loose federation of provinces, each of which jealously guarded its own economic development and hoarded the prospects for jobs and growth,&quot; Industry Minister John Manley told an Ottawa crowd.</p>
<p>Free trade supporters are confident evolution is on their side. &quot;Governments that recognise the benefits of free trade are simply going to out-compete everyone else,&quot; Palda said. &quot;They may be dragged kicking and screaming into it, but they're going to have to go.&quot; ($1=1.3405 Canadian Dollar)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
