<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196068" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian PM seeks to avoid government crisis.</title>
<headline>Estonian PM seeks to avoid government crisis.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The prime minister of the Baltic state of Estonia on Monday sought to pull his administration back from the brink of collapse, calling on coalition allies to stay in government.</p>
<p>The coalition, the sixth government since Estonia quit the former Soviet Union in 1991, has been plunged into crisis after Prime Minister Tiit Vaehi's Coalition Party signed a cooperation pact with the leading opposition party, the Centre Party.</p>
<p>The deal was a huge slap in the face for Vaehi's coalition partners, the Reform Party, which gave him until Wednesday to cancel the pact or it would consider quitting the government.</p>
<p>Vaehi has already ruled out scrapping the deal but appealed to the Reform Party to stay in the one-year old coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;It would be regrettable if the Reform Party left the coalition, which would interrupt the work of its ministers, since the state needs stability,&quot; Vaehi said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The Coalition Party proposes to the Reform Party to continue our cooperation, not to rule it out,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Despite its political problems, Estonia has managed to keep on the path of reform and is deemed one of the most successful of eastern Europe's former Communist states.</p>
<p>Vaehi said he wanted to discuss the problems with the leaders of his coalition allies on Friday.</p>
<p>The statement adopted a softer tone than his earlier statements on radio, when he said he was tired of being blackmailed by Reform Party threats to quit the government.</p>
<p>The coalition has been beset by problems since the start but tensions increased after recent local government elections when the two campaigned against each other with much mud slinging.</p>
<p>Vaehi used to rule in alliance with the Centre Party but that government collapsed amid scandal after Centre Party leader Edgar Savisaar was found to have taped confidential conversations with leading politicians.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
