<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196097" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary says Romania vote outcome should boost ties.</title>
<headline>Hungary says Romania vote outcome should boost ties.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary said on Monday that Emil Constantinescu's victory in the Romanian presidential election should greatly improve the often-troubled relations between the two neighbours.</p>
<p>&quot;I am convinced that bilateral Hungarian-Romanian relations will expand during Constantinescu's presidency,&quot; Hungarian Foreign Minister Laszlo Kovacs told the Hungarian MTI news agency after Constantinescu won in Sunday's second round.</p>
<p>He said that under Constantinescu, &quot;the rights of the Hungarian minority (in Romania) will be enforced and Romania's Euro-Atlantic integration, its membership aspirations in NATO and the European Union, will receive a new impetus&quot;.</p>
<p>Hungary and Romania signed a basic treaty of friendship in September aimed at ending old quarrels by settling the status of Romania's 1.6 million ethnic Hungarians and guaranteeing Romania's western borders.</p>
<p>Hungary made no secret during the two-round polls of its preference for Constantinescu and his Democratic Convention (CDR) party, over the incumbent President Ion Iliescu, a Moscow-trained communist.</p>
<p>Hungary saw the CDR as more supportive than Iliescu of the basic treaty while ethnic Hungarians in Romania thought Iliescu's party was pitting them against majority Romanians for political purposes.</p>
<p>Kovacs said Constantinescu's stated commitment to democracy and pro-Western policies augured well for relations.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hungarian side is ready to establish the highest-level contacts after the president and his government are sworn in, and to review the tasks of implementing the terms of the basic treaty and lend support to Romania's Euro-Atlantic integration efforts,&quot; Kovacs said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
