<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196102" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish small firms' growth slows - statsoffice.</title>
<headline>Polish small firms' growth slows - statsoffice.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a rapid expansion in the early 90s, the growth of Poland's small-enterprise sector slowed as markets become saturated with new firms, a Central Statistical Office (GUS) report showed on Monday.</p>
<p>The report on activities of firms employing no more than five people, showed that the number of such registered firms rose to 1.9 million in 1995 from just above 1.7 million in 1993 but the number of active ones dropped slightly over the period.</p>
<p>&quot;Our research shows that the period of a rapid expansion of the small-enterprise sector is over and it seems that in Poland we already have a state of saturation,&quot; Roman Sawinski, GUS deputy president, told a news conference.</p>
<p>According to the report 1.06 small firms were active in Poland in 1995, down from about 1.2 million in 1993. Sawinski said that in relation to population Poland has already reached a similar level of saturation with small firms to European Union countries.</p>
<p>Last year Poland had 38 companies per 1,000 inhabitants against the EU ratio of 43 per 1,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Small companies have already to a high extent filled market niches, especially in large cities, and now the opportunities exist in less developed areas,&quot; Sawinski said.</p>
<p>He said the GUS study showed a shift in the dominant areas of activities with the number of retail companies falling relative to manufacturing and service firms.</p>
<p>Sawinski said GUS studies confirmed the findings of an earlier study of East and Central European countries by the European Commission which showed that many newly created companies faced demand and financing barriers and suffered from competition from larger organisations.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
