<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196216" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: No risk from plutonium in failed Mars probe - Russia.</title>
<headline>No risk from plutonium in failed Mars probe - Russia.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian officials on Monday said there would be no risk from deadly plutonium which fell to earth after their Mars-96 probe failed on Saturday, but admitted the mishap was a blow to the Russian space programme.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a terrible blow for all of us...We put a lot of hope into this mission, a mission which has no parallel in the world,&quot; Yuri Milov, director of Russian Space Agency's automated flight programme told a news conference.</p>
<p>Russia launched its Mars-96 probe from the Baikonur cosmodrome in Kazakhstan on Saturday. But the planned 10-month mission failed hours after lift-off and the six-tonne probe tumbled towards earth.</p>
<p>Milov said the probe was carrying 270 grams (10 ounces) of plutonium 238, a very potent carcinogen that causes lung and bone cancer if inhaled.</p>
<p>But he insisted that tiny canisters used to hold the deadly material would not pose any threat after the destruction of the probe.</p>
<p>&quot;The production process does not allow its breakdown in any extraordinary situation,&quot; he said. &quot;There is no danger that the isotope will disintegrate.&quot;</p>
<p>Mars-96 was Earth's second mission to the Red Planet in less than two weeks. It aimed to find about more about the possibility that there once was life on Mars.</p>
<p>Milov said he had no reason yet for the failure of the mission. &quot;We have got to look at all the information,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Experts say that most of the probe probably burned up when it re-entered the earth's atmosphere, but some parts could have crashed into the sea off Chile.</p>
<p>A Chilean navy officer said there was little chance that any of the debris would be recovered because the sea around the crash site was very deep.</p>
<p>U.S. scientists said plutonium 238 had no military uses and has a half-life of 87.5 years, much shorter than other radioactive materials which stay radioactive for thousands of years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
