<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196327" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's Malan says Oct trade deficit not a trend.</title>
<headline>Brazil's Malan says Oct trade deficit not a trend.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian Finance Minister Pedro Malan said a record $1.308 billion October trade deficit was exceptional and did not represent a trend.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't see any problem with the country posting a trade deficit. This does not indicate a trend,&quot; Malan told an audience of businessmen during a seminar on the future of the Americas.  </p>
<p>&quot;To take the October trade deficit and project it over time is like not seeing the forest for the trees,&quot; he told a member of the audience who asked whether the government was concerned about the unusually high October trade figure.</p>
<p>Malan said the government was not considering any modification to the exchange rate mechanism in place, which allows for a gentle devaluation of the real within a predetermined band, so as to promote exports and improve the trade balance.</p>
<p>&quot;There are better ways than (changing) the exchange rate to boost exports,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said alternatives being explored would along the lines of a recent decree that eliminated a value added tax (ICMS) on certain exports.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no doubt that exports will soon show an improvement,&quot; said Malan.</p>
<p>-- Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 248 5412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
