<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196378" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia seeks compromise in U.S. trade row.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia seeks compromise in U.S. trade row.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia has drafted a compromise deal to settle a trade dispute with the United States, ahead of U.S. President Bill Clinton's first official visit to Australia, a newspaper reported on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Cabinet on Monday agreed to a proposal to restructure assistance for a small car upholstery company, Howe Leather, which has broken into the U.S. market, The Australian Financial Review newspaper Said.</p>
<p>The move follows negotiations with Washington and would see the U.S. drop a World Trade Organisation complaint over aid to the car and textile, clothing and footwear industries.  </p>
<p>The Howe Leather row had threatened to be one of the most contentious issued during Clinton's visit, which both sides were keen to use to reaffirm their commitment to a close relationship and co-operation in the region.</p>
<p>Under the compromise plan, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative would also agree to strictly scrutinise future U.S. industry challenges to Australia's car and textile industry plans, the Review said.  </p>
<p>Howe Leather would be isolated from the government's import credit scheme, at the centre of the U.S. complaint, and given alternative assistance that complied with world trade rules, the paper said.</p>
<p>Further details were yet to be settled.</p>
<p>Clinton is due to arrive in Sydney later on Tuesday for his first official visit to one of the United States' key allies in the Asia-Pacific region and his first trip abroad since being re-elected earlier this month.  </p>
<p>He is scheduled to talk with Prime Minister John Howard for an hour on Wednesday, a meeting where Howard has said bilateral and international trade issues will figure heavily.</p>
<p>Clinton will leave on Saturday night for Monday's summit of Asia-Pacific Economic Co-operation (APEC) forum leaders in the Philippines.</p>
<p>APEC comprises Australia, Brunei, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, South Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, Papua New Guinea, the Philippines, Singapore, Taiwan, Thailand and the United States.</p>
<p>-- Canberra bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I44000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
