<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196342" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - November 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - November 18.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- TOP BRAZIL OFFICIAL DEFENDS EXCHANGE RATE POLICY</p>
<p>Central Bank international chief Gustavo Franco, in an exclusive interview, defended the bank's exchange rate policy and called proposals to devalue the real to improve the trade balance &quot;an old idea.&quot;</p>
<p>-- BAMERINDUS: THE SHAREHOLDER IS NUMBER ONE</p>
<p>Troubled bank Bamerindus's infrastructure director, Maria Cristina de Andrade Vieira, wrote a front-page article defending the institution's credidibility and commitment to its shareholders.</p>
<p>-- BRAZIL USING IMPORT TARIFFS TO CONTROL TRADE DEFICIT</p>
<p>Having posted its worst monthly trade deficit in Brazil's history, the government is taking measures to restrict importation of some products.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- RIO'S CONDE WILL HAVE 950 MLN REAIS FOR NEW INVESTMENT</p>
<p>With expenses down, Rio de Janeiro's 1997 budget foresees a 950 million-real reserve for new investments. Mayor-elect Luiz Paulo Conde will inherit a fiscal house in order.</p>
<p>-- RIO FACES TEST OF ITS OLYMPIC DREAM</p>
<p>With next Thursday's arrival of 20 International Olympic Committee members, Rio de Janeiro will face its first major test of its dream to become the site of the 2004 Olympic Games. Committee members will be visiting until next Monday.</p>
<p>-- ECONOMY TO GET 15 BLN-REAL INJECTION WITH EXTRA WAGE</p>
<p>The Brazilian economy will receive an injection of 15 billion reais in December when workers receive their 13th monthly salary payment for the year, as stipulated by law.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- BRAZIL RESISTS PRESSURE TO OPEN UP ECONOMY FURTHER</p>
<p>The Brazilian government is preparing to resist pressure by industrialized countries to cut further its import tariffs starting in 1997.</p>
<p>-- POLITICAL MANIFESTO SLAMS VALE SELLOFF PLANS</p>
<p>Former president Itamar Franco has issued a manifesto opposing the governvernment's plans to privatize Brazil's state mining giant Cia Vale do Rio Doce and the state-run electrical sector.</p>
<p>-- AIRFORCE PLAN CRASHES, KILLING NINE CREW MEMBERS</p>
<p>A Brazilian air force patrol plane crashed in northeastern Brazil on Sunday, killing all nine airmen aboard. The plane, a twin-engine Bandeirante, was made by local manufacturer Embraer.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified the stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 232 4411</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
