<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196328" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina's Fernandez sees unemployment still high.</title>
<headline>Argentina's Fernandez sees unemployment still high.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Unemployment figures to be released next month are unlikely to show any improvement on the near-record level of 17 percent attained last May, Argentina's Economy Minister Roque Fernandez said.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not expect the October figures to vary significantly from those of May, when the jobless rate rose above 17 percent,&quot; he told the daily La Nacion in an interview published Monday.</p>
<p>Argentina releases unemployment figures twice a year based on surveys carried out in May and October.  The October figures will be released on December 18.  </p>
<p>In May they stood at 17.1 percent.</p>
<p>Several government officials have stated they expect the jobless data to fall in coming months but Fernandez said he anticipated &quot;just a fall of one percentage point in the jobless rate&quot; in May 1997.</p>
<p>The minister also said he expects the current signs of a rebound in growth to become plain to see for everybody in the months to come.  &quot;Probably it will take a while to see the rebound clearly , but not a year.  I think that in March or April we will see a completely different economic situation to what we see today,&quot; said Fernandez.</p>
<p>He said the recent economic indicators, most notably the release last week of third quarter gross domestic product figures of 6.6 percent growth, show there are reasons to be optimistic for the economy.</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 3180668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
