<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196482" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Copper price surge expected to boost Q4 earnings.</title>
<headline>Copper price surge expected to boost Q4 earnings.</headline>
<byline>Huw Jones</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The surge in copper prices to five-month highs will boost U.S. red metal producer earnings in the fourth quarter and beyond, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Fourth quarter results will be significantly better than third because of the recovery in copper prices,&quot; said Dan Roling of Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>U.S. producers generally don't sell forward material, so they should be able to capture all the increase in copper prices, Roling said.</p>
<p>On Monday COMEX copper's December contract rose 4.20 cents to 105.65 cents per pound, building on a 5.60 cent gain made Friday.</p>
<p>The market is worried about the low level of LME exchange stocks, down to six-year lows, and has largely dismissed stories of huge, off-exchange hoards of metal.</p>
<p>Extra fourth quarter gains will come from marking-to-market sales contracts which have not been finalised, and from product which had been marked to market in the third quarter but whose sales will now be closed out at a higher price in the fourth quarter, Roling said.</p>
<p>Some producers will also top up gains from these two factors by sales of their put options.</p>
<p>ASARCO Inc said with each one cent change in copper prices, the company's annual net earnings per share moves 15.4 cents.</p>
<p>Victor Lazarovici of Smith Barney forecast an average fourth quarter copper price of 93 cents per pound, above the third quarter's 90 cents average, boosting earnings in the year's final earnings period.</p>
<p>&quot;We opened the fourth quarter at 87.85 cents per pound and we are up 12 cents. I may have been too conservative in my forecast,&quot; Lazarovici said.</p>
<p>But Vahid Fahti of Everen Securities, said producer fourth quarter results will benefit very little from the current copper price surge. &quot;Most of the benefit we will see in the first and second quarter of next year,&quot; Fahti said. &quot;And that is already factored into the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Several copper majors sold all or some of their put options during the third quarter.</p>
<p>Put options were bought from financial institutions to cover the risk of copper prices plunging as they did after the Sumitomo scandal was announced.</p>
<p>&quot;That was a very bullish sign - they believed the copper market had bottomed out,&quot; said Fathi.</p>
<p>Roling said producers who sold put options will earn 4 to 8 cents per pound on the tonnage covered.</p>
<p>Fathi said copper was oversold down in the low 80 cents per pound, and strength was regained because inventories have shrunk and the large offtake which went to China was for consumption.</p>
<p>A price of $1.05 to $1.12 per pound would correspond to current supply and demand, Fathi added.</p>
<p>The surge in copper prices will also help the higher cost producers.</p>
<p>BHP Copper said third quarter cash costs at the Magma operations acquired in the U.S. were 85 cents per pound, 17 cents above what the Australian company had expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Magma has finally got its act together, it seems. Apparently their costs are back in line,&quot; said Lazarovici. &quot;Operationally they should do better in the fourth quarter, and the price should help as well.&quot;</p>
<p>-- New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
