<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196690" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mattel/Tyco a logical fit - arbitrageurs.</title>
<headline>Mattel/Tyco a logical fit - arbitrageurs.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mattel Inc's $755 million stock deal with Tyco Toys Inc would be a far smaller conquest than Mattel's recent failed hostile bid for Hasbro Inc but accomplish many of the same goals on far friendlier terms.</p>
<p>The fact that Tyco -- which boasts one-fourth the annual sales of Hasbro and is losing money in the process -- would receive as full a price as $755 million indicates Mattel sees a chance to close a key gap with the deal, arbitrageurs said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think Mattel needs this deal,&quot; one arbitrageur said. &quot;They need more merchandise to put through their distribution network.&quot;  </p>
<p>Arbs also noted that the Tyco deal is superior to the Hasbro bid in one obvious way: It is far more likely to withstand antitrust scrutiny.</p>
<p>&quot;I have a feeling they'll be able to walk this thing through&quot; the examination, an arb said.</p>
<p>In contrast, during Hasbro's battle to fend off Mattel's bid, Hasbro used the likelihood the combination would never withstand an antitrust review as part of its aggressive defense.  </p>
<p>Arbs also viewed the deal as favorable for Tyco, citing the companies' complementary businesses and the fact that the $12.50 per share price reflected a 78 percent markup from Friday's close, which some said was about the best Tyco could expect.  &quot;Given the fact that Tyco has a poor track record and has been losing money for years, this is a fair price,&quot; one arb said. &quot;Of course if you've been a Tyco shareholder from 1992 (when Tyco traded in the low 20s), it hurts to lose $10 per share.&quot;</p>
<p>Shares in Tyco rose 4-3/8 to 11-3/8, while Mattel shares dipped 7/8 to 29-3/4.</p>
<p>Arbitrgeurs had less to say on the acquisition of Unocal Corp's 76 Products business by Tosco Corp, seeing little play in the cash for assets deal, though one did note that &quot;the market must like the fundamentals of the deal because both shares are up.&quot;</p>
<p>The sale by Unocal frees it of a low margin operation it has been shopping around for some time and creates what Tosco said would be the largest independent refiner and marketer in the U.S.</p>
<p>Unocal rose 3/4 to 40-1/4 and Tosco surged 5-3/8 to 65-1/2.</p>
<p>-- Richard Melville, Wall Street desk, 212-859-1731</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
