<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196695" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Nov 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Top Japan business news - Nov 19.</headline>
<text>
<p>NIHON KEIZAI SHIMBUN</p>
<p>Mitsui &amp; Co Ltd plans to tie up with Bertelsmann AG in multimedia businesses, including broadcasting, publishing, mail-order sales and computer software development. The two companies will start a mail-order service in Japan next spring and catalogue sales on European television. Mitsui will buy a stake in an affiliate of the Bertelsmann television station and become the first Japanese company to become involved in broadcasting in Europe.</p>
<p>----  </p>
<p>Precision equipment makers are considering starting joint production ventures in China to gain a foothold in the local market. Olympus Optical Co Ltd plans to set up a factory for compact cameras by next spring. Canon Inc will also start production of copy machines by early next year.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Toshiba Corp plans to postpone sales of digital video disc (DVD) players in the United States to late January or early February, due to a delay in transferring U.S. movies to the DVD-compatible format. Toshiba planned to sell the DVD players by the end of this year.  </p>
<p>-----</p>
<p>Dai Nippon Printing Co Ltd, Sumitomo Chemical Co Ltd, Toray Industries Inc and Mitsubishi Chemical Corp plan to start mass-production of colour filters used for liquid crystal display (LCD) panels.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
