<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196745" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Reuters 3rd ex-Hong Kong air cargo market report.</title>
<headline>Reuters 3rd ex-Hong Kong air cargo market report.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Current average ex-Hong Kong air cargo market rates in Hong Kong dollars per kg for a 100kg shipment, with volume-to-weight of six to one.</p>
<p>				 NOV 15	    OCT 17</p>
<p>				 EUROPE</p>
<p>HK-LHR			 24.30	   22.25</p>
<p>HK-FRA			 24.50	   22.40</p>
<p>				 USA</p>
<p>HK-JFK			 24.60	   20.70</p>
<p>HK-LAX			 25.31	  21.05</p>
<p>				 MIDDLE EAST</p>
<p>HK-DXB			 15.90	   15.80</p>
<p>				 ASIA PACIFIC</p>
<p>HK-SIN			  9.20	    9.10</p>
<p>HK-TAIPEI		     4.60	    4.10</p>
<p>*The rates quoted in this report were obtained by Reuters journalists on a confidential basis from a range of airlines, large forwarders and smaller air cargo agents.</p>
<p>*All prices quoted in Hong Kong dollars.</p>
<p>*The tariffs represent average rates calculated from a range of prices and are indicative or current market activity. Hong Kong air cargo busiest market for many years</p>
<p>By Jim Gilchrist</p>
<p>Hong Kong, Nov 15. (Reuter) - The Hong Kong air cargo market is reporting its busiest peak period for many years with especially high demand on both trans-Pacific and European routes, a Reuter survey revealed.</p>
<p>In addition there has been a substantial increase in rates giving what the airlines say is a welcome increase in yields.</p>
<p>But a common complaint from freight forwarders is &quot;too much cargo, not enough aircraft&quot; adding that they are having to contend with a sizeable and stubborn backlog.</p>
<p>The airlines are in general said to be &quot;making hay while the sun shines&quot; by increasing their rates by up to 30 per cent on trans-Pacific routes where demand is reported to be intense as manufacturers demand their goods get to the Christmas shops on time or face large contract penalties.</p>
<p>One airline agent said he had never seen trans-Pacific rates so high. Agents selling prices quoted to Reuters varied from US$1.25 to 1.80 per pound .</p>
<p>Anthony Lau, the vice chairman of the Hong Kong Association of Freight Forwarding Agents and chairman of Baltrans Limited said business was &quot;too good&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The current peak season is what we used to have in the seventies and eighties which is very good to see. Rates are very firm and most airlines have a backlog which means a lot of shipments are having to be stored,&quot; Lau said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very, very tough with a big squeeze on capacity, most dramatically to anywhere in the US. There's a backlog and freight is sitting for four or five days. We just can't move it,&quot; said Mark Wilson of cargo agents Benair Freight (HK) Ltd.</p>
<p>Thomas Miu, general manager of the air freight division of Jardine Freight Services, said some cargo is having to wait over a week to clear Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;I have never known it to be so busy for the past six or seven years,&quot; Miu said.</p>
<p>Northwest cargo sales and marketing manager Alexander Wong said his airline's eight freighters operating trans-Pacific flights to the U.S. have been very busy.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a very good month for nearly all airlines as long as you have a freighter. Rates have been increased by 25-30 percent depnnding on the type of customer being served,&quot; Wong said.</p>
<p>The cargo division of Cathay Pacific said the peak season is strong both east and west bound.</p>
<p>&quot;There has also been a very welcome increase in yields because of the peak season rate rises,&quot; said a Cathay spokesman.</p>
<p>Frank Berweger, general manager for Lufthansa Cargo in Hong Kong, Macau and south China, said an additional Boeing 747-200 freighter with around 100 tonnes capacity recruited to the Hong Kong to Frankfurt route at the end of October has still not been enough to satisfy demand. Lufthansa Cargo now operates 11 freighters a week to Germany in a joint venture with Cathay Pacific Cargo with additional belly capacity on Lufthansa's daily passenger flights.</p>
<p>Berweger said Lufthansa Cargo has also tried to charter additional aircraft or reroute aircraft from other parts of its network but without success because of lack of aircraft availability.</p>
<p>&quot;There is very, very strong demand on European routes and it is a big concern for us to try to clear the backlog. Demand is higher than capacity available,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lufthansa said because business was booming on trans-Pacific routes for leading Asian carriers such as Japan Airlines and Korean Airlines, that was having a constraining effect on services to Europe.</p>
<p>Another factor for increased demand was the rise in 'Just in Time' traffic. Manufacturers, especially in the garment industry, who have already sent early Christmas stock by sea need to get re-ordered lines to the shops quickly and air cargo is benefitting, Berweger said.</p>
<p>Because of the backlog, on-time performance targets are not being met, some shippers reported. And consignments are being split up with some goods arrivnng at different times with cargoes of more than five tonnes having to be carried by a different airline because of pressure on space.</p>
<p>Some freight forwarders are said to have suffered considerable losses because some airlines have been unable to meet demand and emergency charter aircraft have been unavailable.</p>
<p>Demand for warehouse space in Hong Kong is also reported to be high as freight forwarders cannot fly out especially large shipments because of the backlog.</p>
<p>Hong Kong Air Cargo Terminals Limited (HACTL), which handles all air cargo flying in and out of the territory, said both import and export levels were &quot;very encouraging.&quot; Because of pressure on space, HACTL said it has imposed an embargo at weekends on accepting freight from forwarders</p>
<p>&quot;We won't accept pre-packed cargoes until 24 hours before the flight departs which can cause freight forwarders problems if they do not have the warehousing space. Previously we have been relatively relaxed about when we accept deliveries but now we are fairly close to saturation levels ourselves and have to impose this peak period restriction,&quot; said HACTL's managing director Anthony Charter.</p>
<p>One factor said to have exacerbated the backlog is the Hong Kong weather. Northerly winds has forced aircraft to take off over Kowloon which especially on long haul flights to Europe has meant belly hold cargo has been restricted to mail and express freight only.</p>
<p>One major cargo carrying airline said the weather had caused &quot;severe capacity constraints.&quot;</p>
<p>But British Airways said it has not been affected because its twice daily passenger flights are now utilising a new, shorter route to London through Chinese air space.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the beginning of the month, all our passenger flights now take the Urumqi routing so we need less fuel and can carry more which offers us quite a competitive advantage,&quot; Chris Humphrey, BA's regional cargo manager Pacific said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hong Kong market is extremely strong our aircraft are full every night and we see that continuing for the forseeable future,&quot; Humphrey added.</p>
<p>Another factor said to have added to the backlog headache is some airlines cancelling flights at short notice reportedly because of technical problems.</p>
<p>But one industry expert told Reuters that more than one airline has cancelled a scheduled flight at the last minute and the aircraft has been used shortly after on charter.</p>
<p>&quot;Normally if one or two aircraft have engine problems, it doesn't really matter but in the peak season when everyone is under severe pressure to get their goods to market it does and there is no back-up aircraft,&quot; said Sam Chung, the chairman of the Hong Kong Association of Freight Forwarding Agents said.</p>
<p>Tokyo's Narita airport is reported to be a particular bottleneck for ex Hong Kong cargo and trans-Pacific traffic is taking much longer to transit than normal.</p>
<p>Japan Airlines said it too is facing very high demand for trans-Pacific flights. A spokesman said there was also unusual spot demand for shipments of Japanese manufacturered goods to the U.S. such as auto parts and office automation equipment.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a backlog at Narita but we are doing our best to keep things rolling, In the early part of the week that backlog includes the weekend build-up of imports waiting to be cleared by Monday,&quot; said a spokesman for JAL Logisitics, the cargo division of Japan Airlines in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Latest statistics from Hong Kong's Civil Aviation Department show that Tokyo Narita is the number one destination for ex-Hong Kong air cargo closely followed by Taipei.</p>
<p>Traffic to Australia is also booming, especially of electronics being air freighted down under in time for Christmas. A spokesman for Qantas in Hong Kong said it was the best quarter he had experienced for many years. Qantas would wait and see whether it too would impose a fuel surcharge, he added.</p>
<p>The imposition by some airlines flying to Europe from Hong Kong of an 80 Hong Kong cents fuel surcharge has caused controversy in the territory. The Hong Kong Shippers' Council, which represents 15 of the leading trade assocations, has lobbied Hong Kong's Civil Aviation Department to tell the airlines that the surcharge is illegal. The airlines which have already imposed it, including Lufthansa Cargo and Air France, say they are within their rights.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's de facto national airline Cathay Pacific Airways Limited said until the Hong Kong government clarifies the situation it will not impose a fuel surcharge in Hong Kong but has followed suit at around half its European destinations.</p>
<p>A key discussion point is over how long the heavy demand will last. In the past America's Thanksgiving Day, November 28 this year, has signalled the end of the peak and then activity slows and rates soften.</p>
<p>HAFFA expects the peak season to be over by the end of the November but many airlines hope HAFFA is wrong and the peak season and high rates will continue into December. -- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
