<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196757" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares close higher, Sampoerna rises.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares close higher, Sampoerna rises.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jakarta share prices closed higher in active trading on Monday, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said rises in cigarette, consumer and property shares seemed to have injected some fresh impetus to the market.</p>
<p>The composite index ended up 0.64 percent, or 3.97 points, at 620.86 points, hovering firmly above the psychological 600-point level on offshore support.</p>
<p>Gainers beat losers by 64 to 43, with 63 issues unchanged.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a good day. We see some fresh funds coming in from offshore, even into the property sector,&quot; one broker said.  </p>
<p>He attributed the fresh inflows into this long depressed sector to the fact that it was undervalued and some analysts seemed to have made some revaluations in the wake of a possible interest rate reduction next year.</p>
<p>The gainers in the property sector included Ciputra Development, Lippo Land and Dharmala Intiland. However, the property index eased 0.52 percent on declines in Jababeka.</p>
<p>Brokers said strong rises in the consumer sector, soaring 4.34 percent, seemed to have helped keep the index firming above the critical support level of 600-points.  </p>
<p>They said the strong rise in the consumer sector was led by cigarette shares after Standard &amp; Poors affirmed its BBB-plus local currency corporate credit rating on Sampoerna.</p>
<p>It also affirmed its BBB foreign currency rating on the US$200 million note issue of Sampoerna's wholly-owned subsidiary Sampoerna International Finance BV.</p>
<p>It said the rating outlook is stable. Sampoerna rose almost eight percent to 13,200 rupiah, which also drove Gudang Garam up 5.38 percent to 10,275 rupiah, brokers said.</p>
<p>One broker said profit-taking in index-heavyweight Telkom and Bank Internasional Indonesia failed to kill the momentum.  </p>
<p>Other losers included Indah Kiat and Tjiwi Kimia.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall sentiment remained firm at the close. I think the uptrend could be sustained on Tuesday,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Telkom shed 125 rupiah, 2.94 percent, to 4,125 rupiah after the lock-up period of the shares held by its employees passed.</p>
<p>Brokers said anticipation of a new tariff schedule next year, pending government approval, failed to excite investors.</p>
<p>One local broker said investors might want to buy now ahead of the listing of Bank Negara Indonesia (BNI) shares next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall market sentiment appears to be upbeat after the overwhelming response to BNI's share offering,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>He said people wanted to move in now because they hoped the listing on Monday would give another boost to the market.</p>
<p>Danareksa Sekuritas, lead underwriter of BNI share offering, said the issue was oversubscribed 4.46 times.</p>
<p>Banking shares which had risen during the BNI share offer declined on profit-taking. The finance index fell 0.89 percent on sharp fall of Bank Internasional Indonesia.</p>
<p>It fell 200 rupiah to 2,400 rupiah.</p>
<p>But brokers said overall sentiment on banking stocks remained positive despite increased profit-taking on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
