<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="196800" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Lockheed Martin to cut 1,600 jobs.</title>
<headline>Lockheed Martin to cut 1,600 jobs.</headline>
<dateline>BETHEDESA, Md.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lockheed Martin Corp. said Monday it would cut 1,600 jobs and close eight domestic facilities -- just two days after surviving the first cut in the multibillion-dollar competition to build a 21st century jet fighter.</p>
<p>The job cuts amount to less than 1 percent of the Bethesda, Md.-based aerospace company's worldwide work force of 190,000 and will eliminate 2.5 million square feet of excess capacity, according to Lockheed.</p>
<p>The company said the closings and other actions would complete the consolidation of its businesses with the defence electronics and other operations of Loral Corp., which Lockheed Martin acquired last spring.</p>
<p>Lockheed said in a statement that the moves would further enhance its competitiveness &quot;against the background of significantly reduced defence spending.&quot;</p>
<p>The moves are expected to be completed in 1998, with savings building up to $300 million a year by 1999, the company said. Combined with other savings, the latest moves will add up to $2.7 billion in annual savings by 1999.</p>
<p>The plan will not result in any material charge to 1996 earnings, Lockheed said. Lockheed has annual sales of nearly $30 billion.</p>
<p>Lockheed stock rose $1.875 to $95.625 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>On Saturday, the Defence Department selected Lockheed Martin and Boeing Co. of Seattle to compete for the right to build 3,000 new fighter jets that could mean more than $170 billion to the winner.</p>
<p>Lockheed and Boeing will each build test models for final selection in the year 2001. A third team headed by McDonnell Douglas Corp. did not make the cut.</p>
<p>Lockheed said Monday it would close office or factory facilities in New York City, Great Neck, N.Y., Bloomfield, Conn., Glendale and Rancho Santa Margarita, Calif., Paoli, Pa., and Goodyear, Ariz.</p>
<p>It also said it would close an aircraft components plant in Charleston, S.C., as part of moves unrelated to the Loral consolidation.</p>
<p>In addition to factory closings, the company announced reorganizations of various businesses.</p>
<p>The company said any employee who is laid off will be offered assistance finding a new job, including work at Lockheed, and benefits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BETHEDESA, Md."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
