<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197095" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Socialists back Right to block Le Pen.</title>
<headline>French Socialists back Right to block Le Pen.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's opposition Socialists urged their supporters to rally behind the ruling conservatives on Monday to stop the extreme-right National Front of Jean-Marie Le Pen capturing control of a fourth town in a local election.</p>
<p>National Front candidate Marie-France Stirbois topped the poll in Dreux, a town of 36,000 west of Paris, in Sunday's first round with 36.5 percent of the vote, closely followed by outgoing Gaullist mayor Gerard Hamel with 34.7 percent.</p>
<p>Socialist Maurice Ravanne, whose united Left list came third with 24.8 percent, said on Monday night he had decided not to contest the run-off in a move calculated to swing the election for Hamel.</p>
<p>&quot;The Left in Dreux is acting responsibly...so that our town does not become the fourth in France to fall into the clutches of the National Front,&quot; Ravanne said. His first round score was enough to let him contest the run-off if he decided to hang on.</p>
<p>Ravanne and Hamel's supporters ruled out any formal alliance between Left and Right that might have given Socialist candidates places on a joint slate. And Ravanne stopped short of formally recommending his followers to vote for Hamel.</p>
<p>The Socialist party's national leadership also said on Monday that the top priority was to stop the anti-immigration hard right taking over the town and urged its voters to block the National Front.</p>
<p>Despite a personal visit by Le Pen to Dreux, where the Front scored its first breakthrough in politics in 1983, Stirbois barely improved her score from last year's municipal election, invalidated by a court due to irregularities involving Hamel.</p>
<p>Unemployment is well above the national average of 12.6 percent in a town heavily populated by North African immigrants.</p>
<p>In her campaign, Stirbois fulminated against immigrants who she says intimidate &quot;native French people&quot; and take their jobs. She pledged to give the local police paramilitary training and dog squads to stamp out delinquency.</p>
<p>The Front last year won control of the southern towns of Toulon, Orange and Marignane, boosted by voter disenchantment with both mainstream blocs, accused of corruption and failure to halt unemployment and crime.</p>
<p>But Hamel said Sunday's first round result, in which he gained nearly seven points over last year, showed voters in Dreux did not want the National Front.</p>
<p>&quot;The National Front will never win Dreux,&quot; he declared.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
