<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197074" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. poultry exports hit record highs -- USDA.</title>
<headline>U.S. poultry exports hit record highs -- USDA.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Exports of U.S. broilers, other chicken, turkeys and eggs ran at record levels through the first eight months of 1996, the U.S. Agriculture Department's Economic Research Service said Monday.</p>
<p>In a quarterly report, USDA's research arm forecast poultry meat exports at 5.4 billion pounds in 1996 and said exports would hit about 5.8 billion pounds in 1997. It pegged the value of all poultry exports in 1996 at $2.4-2.5 billion.</p>
<p>It said the export increase is expected to slow in 1997 chiefly due to uncertainties about growth in the Russian market and the impact of Hong Kong's handover to China.  </p>
<p>The report estimated broiler exports for 1996 at 4.6 billion pounds, about 18 percent above 1995, and driven largely by strong Russian demand. It said U.S. broiler exports are seen rising 450 million pounds to 5.1 billion in 1997.</p>
<p>Through August, exports to Russia totalled 1.2 billion pounds, 33 percent above 1995, while exports to former Soviet Union countries hit 151 million pounds. USDA said exports to that region accounted for 45 percent of U.S. broiler exports.</p>
<p>It also noted strong growth in shipments to China, South Africa and Mexico. Direct exports to China so far in 1996 have been more than double those of 1995.</p>
<p>USDA said its broiler production forecast for 1997 has been upped by 100 million pounds to 28 billion, due to lower feed costs forecasts for 1997 and the recent strength in wholesale broiler prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The strength in prices, driven by strong export and domestic demand, led to an increase of 2 cents in the forecast for fourth-quarter broiler prices, to 60 cents per pound,&quot; the USDA report said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
