<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197176" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks hit by profit-taking, close off lows.</title>
<headline>French stocks hit by profit-taking, close off lows.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks fell on Monday on profit-taking on the bourse's 1.6 percent rise last week, but traders said sentiment remained positive and they expected the market to resume its advance after a brief pause.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed down 11.52 points, or 0.51 percent, at 2,228.81, while the CAC-40 November futures contract fell 11 points to 2,231.</p>
<p>&quot;The market needed to catch its breath,&quot; said a trader, but he added that the mood remained bullish.</p>
<p>Volume was 5.7 billion francs, swollen by active trading in insurance merger partners Axa and UAP.</p>
<p>Axa and UAP fell 1.53 percent and 0.22 percent, respectively, on heavy selling by U.S. funds, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said the selling was probably spurred by U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission rules which do not recognise the &quot;certificates of guaranteed value&quot; offered by Axa as part of the complex share swap agreement announced last week. It entails an exchange of four Axa shares plus four certificates -- guaranteeing a minimum price -- for 10 UAP shares.</p>
<p>Shares in Suez fell 1.38 percent to 221 francs. A broker said its move to sell four billion francs in property loans suggests its real estate problems have not been solved.</p>
<p>Shares in textile firm DMC fell 7.11 percent on continuing disappointment with a 14 percent drop in its nine-month sales and loss forecast for the year.</p>
<p>The share has lost more than 10 percent since announcing its lower nine-month sales on Thursday and forecasting a full-year loss of around 550 million francs in a newspaper interview on Friday.</p>
<p>Euro Disney rallied 7.51 percent ahead of its full-year results on Tuesday morning. Analysts expect a rise in net profit for the year ended on September 30 to between 160 million and 220 million francs. Excluding exceptionals, analysts expect a profit between 100 million and 140 million francs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
