<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197161" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Rates stable as ex-Paris cargo mart seeks pickup.</title>
<headline>Rates stable as ex-Paris cargo mart seeks pickup.</headline>
<byline>Stuart Todd</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air cargo rates have been stable in the last month but the background to the market was not calm, a Reuter survey revealed.</p>
<p>Shippers and agents have protested strongly about the imposition of fuel surcharges in a market facing heavy seasonal demand ahead of Christmas and the traditional rush to fly the young Beaujolais nouveau wine around the world beforfe its official release on Thursday.</p>
<p>The majority of French shippers and agents were up in arms over the way the fuel surcharges were applied earlier this month - claiming they had received next to no warning of their application.</p>
<p>While their position has mellowed in the past few days, the issue is far from being settled.</p>
<p>&quot;We've come to recognise the economic necessity of the surcharges but we stick to our guns on being accorded, along with thousands of our customers, a reasonable period of prior notice,&quot; Bruno Charrois, general secretary of France's air freight forwarding association, SNAGFA, told Reuters.</p>
<p>SNAGFA members voted unanimously to accept the fuel surcharges but only from November 16, almost two weeks after some airlines, notably Lufthansa, Air France and KLM, had implemented them.</p>
<p>Air France's said it had no intention of going back on its decision to apply surcharges on ex-Europe routes, effective November 4.</p>
<p>Fuel surcharges aside, the Paris market has sought temporary relief in rising demand this year for Beaujolais nouveau especially from the wine's two principal overseas markets, the U.S. and Japan.</p>
<p>Beaujolais wine growers asociation, the UIVB, is forecasting that shipments of the young wine by air will exceed the 4,000 tonnes flown worldwide in 1995.</p>
<p>Airlines' have fine-tuned their logistics operation to ensure the wine reaches consumers worldwide in time for its traditional uncorking day, on the third Thursday in November and this year has been no exception.</p>
<p>Air France, the biggest shipper among airlines, put on seven Beaujolais-dedicated Boeing 747-200 freighters, as part of an operation to transport 1,200 tonnes of Beaujolais nouveau, up almost 30 percent on last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the fact that cargo capacity is tight at this time of the year and that some airlines go to the trouble to implement dedicated transport and logistics operations, they can command rates for Beaujolais well-above the normal average levels. For example, Beaujolais shipped on a prime route, between Paris and Tokyo, has attracted rates of between 17 and 18 French francs kilo compared to standard rates of between 15 and 16 kilo,&quot; an industry source told Reuters.</p>
<p>However, even taking into account the upturn in demand this year, several airlines said that Beaujolais nouveau had lost some of its &quot;lucrativeness&quot; in recent years as a result of air cargo markets being hit by the economic recession and the relative decline in volumes as the wine lost some of its fashion appeal.</p>
<p>Air Canada's Beaujolais shipments this week on its daily Paris-Montreal Boeing 747 combi service are set to double this week on 1995 levels reaching 130 tonnes.</p>
<p>But the Canadian carrier will be shipping the wine at &quot;more or less the current going rate,&quot; Air Canada's director Sales and Freight Services, France and Western Europe, Daniel Bregere, said.</p>
<p>&quot;France-Canada cargo rates have been subjected to downward pressures for a good part of 1996 and this was reflected in the rates we negotiated for Beaujolais nouveau,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Bregere said there had been a minor recovery in rates on ex-Paris routes to Montreal and Toronto since the beginning of Autumn while in recent weeks demand had picked up too.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hoping that this is not simply a result of the withdrawal last month of Canadian Airlines 'S Paris- Toronto Boeing 767 passenger service, but the signal of a genuine upturn which will continue beyond the pre-Christmas peak of mid-December.&quot;</p>
<p>Canadian Airlines' five-times weekly Paris-Toronto service could handle up to 15 tonnes of freight per flight and this traffic was now effectively up for grabs between Air Canada and Air France, the only two direct carriers left on the route, Bregere added.</p>
<p>Paris-U.S. routes, depressed for most of 1996, had, in the words of one major U.S. carrier, produced a &quot;mini-boom&quot; in the past two to three weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;The volume of  French exports, mainly a broad range of industrial goods, has quite frankly gone crazy. For most of the year, we have depended on our off-line European stations as well as inter-line services to Paris, to compensate for the low demand generated in France for airfreight but this is no longer the picture,&quot; a cargo official for the airline said.</p>
<p>At the moment, in order to obtain end-of-week capacity, customers were having to reserve five to seven days in advance which illustrated how tight space had become from Paris to certain U.S. cities, the official added.</p>
<p>&quot;It's difficult to explain the sudden surge in demand nor predict how long it will last. Hopefully, it's a genuine case of the market coming out of the doldrums mixed with the pre-Christman rush.&quot;</p>
<p>One possible explanation was that the majority of U.S. carriers operating from Paris have not yet introduced fuel surcharges in contrast to Air France which did so from November 4.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a sufficient &quot;critical mass&quot; of U.S operators on Transatlantic routes to enable forwarders to turn their backs on Air France over the surcharges issue and use other carriers. Some U.S. airlines are set to introduce surcharges this week so there will be a clearer idea whether they have been a factor.&quot;</p>
<p>Airlines wil be hoping stronger demand will have a stabilising effect on rates which continue to be under atttack.</p>
<p>One major French forwarder said rates had fallen by between 20 and 35 centimes a kilo on the main U.S. destinations - New York, Chicago and Los Angeles - over the past month.</p>
<p>Another U.S. carrier, TWA, pointed to reduced transatlantic capacity as the reason behind an improvement in its ex-Paris throughput.</p>
<p>&quot;We are probably doing a little better in tonnage terms compared to the same last year which is encouraging,&quot; a TWA cargo official said.</p>
<p>Early next month, the airline will discuss implementing ex-Paris rate increases, from January 1997, the official added. &quot;We have consistently maintained our rates during a difficult period for the market. Maybe there is now scope to raise to them but this remains hypothetical for the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>On Far East routes, rates have firmed slightly to Taipei and Hong Kong, amid a general stabilty in the sector .</p>
<p>Last month, Taiwan airline, Eva Air, increased its ex-Paris rates by 50 centimes to one franc/kilo following a reduction in capacity on the route and a surge in demand.</p>
<p>In recent days, Cathay Pacific announced a five percent increase in rates from Paris to Hong Kong, Taipei and Seoul.</p>
<p>Cathay had decided on rate increases in preference to implementing fuel surcharges for &quot;commercial and technical reasons.&quot;</p>
<p>Elsewhere, cargo rates have increased on routes to Reunion (Indian Ocean) and the French West Indies following French airline, Corsair's decision to up its tarifs to these two destinations.</p>
<p>By contrast, ex-Paris rates to Dubai and Johannesburg were reduced to a minor degree with off-line capacity added on the latter destination in the past few weeks in the form of Virgin Atlantic's A340 passenger service from London.</p>
<p>-- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
