<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197335" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka Siamese twins die hours before U.S. trip.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka Siamese twins die hours before U.S. trip.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Siamese twins born in Sri Lanka this month died of cardiac arrest hours before they were to fly to the United States for separation surgery, a hospital official said on Monday.</p>
<p>The two girls, Hansani and Hansika, died on Sunday evening, 13 days after their birth launched a campaign to transfer them to a country where separation surgery was possible.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the girls suffered cardiac arrest, but we were unable to massage the heart because they were joined at the chest,&quot; said Dr Harsha de Silva, deputy director of Colombo's Lady Ridgeway Hospital.</p>
<p>The girls, born on November 4 in a village 15 miles (25 km) outside the capital Colombo, were joined at the chest but did not share any organs and appeared healthy enough to survive, he said.</p>
<p>The girls, the second set of Siamese twins born in Sri Lanka in 10 years, were to leave on Sunday for the United States, where they were to undergo surgery at California's Loma Linda University Children's Hospital.</p>
<p>Admission at the U.S. hospital was arranged by a Sri Lanka-based U.S. citizen after a local campaign on the Internet to find an overseas hospital received offers from 24 institutions around the world, de Silva said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
