<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197348" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tosco to buy 76 Products for about $2 billion.</title>
<headline>Tosco to buy 76 Products for about $2 billion.</headline>
<byline>Tony McAuley</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tosco Corp. said Monday it agreed to buy 76 Products Co., the refining and marketing unit of Unocal Corp., in a deal worth about $2 billion that will create a powerhouse gasoline retailer on the West Coast.</p>
<p>The price includes $1.4 billion for 76 Products' fixed assets, about $400 million for inventories and up to $250 million in future profits if gasoline profit margins rise in the next seven years, the companies said.</p>
<p>El Segundo, Calif.-based Unocal said it expects to record a $375 million after-tax loss from the sale.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition makes Tosco the largest independent refiner and marketer in the United States,&quot; said Thomas O'Malley, Tosco's chairman and chief executive officer.</p>
<p>&quot;On the retail side, the 76 retail system, added to Tosco's existing California properties, makes Tosco the third-largest retailer in the state of California.&quot;</p>
<p>The 76 system includes about 1,350 gasoline stations and three refineries in California with capacity of 250,000 barrels a day. As part of the deal, Tosco will acquire the 76 brand name in refining and marketing worldwide.</p>
<p>The deal also includes a distribution system including 13 oil storage terminals, three modern tankers and 1,500 miles of crude oil and product pipeline, as well as Unocal's extensive lubricants manufacturing, distribution and marketing business.</p>
<p>Tosco will assume limited environmental liabilities.</p>
<p>With the ability to process about 1 million barrels of crude oil a day, Tosco will rival the nation's largest refiners, Amoco Corp., Exxon Corp. and Mobil Corp., Salomon Brothers analyst Paul Ting said.</p>
<p>Costa Mesa, Calif.-based 76 Products also has retail outlets and terminals in Hawaii, which will provide a new market for Tosco, which operates Circle K convenience stores.</p>
<p>Wall Street applauded the deal, and Tosco stock jumped $11.625 to $71.75 on the New York Stock Exchange. Unocal added $1.125 to $40.625, also on the NYSE.</p>
<p>The deal is expected to close in the first quarter of 1997, subject to approval by both companies' boards, Tosco shareholders and regulators.</p>
<p>The companies and analysts said they do not expect regulators to hold up the deal on antitrust grounds.</p>
<p>Stamford, Conn.-based Tosco said the merger will generate substantial selling, general and administrative cost savings.</p>
<p>Tosco will fund the acquisition with a combination of debt and equity.</p>
<p>Unocal said the sale is part of the company's long-term strategy to grow by pursuing large projects in Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;With this sale, we can focus on expanding our role as a major international energy producer and project developer and on strengthening our domestic U.S. oil and gas operations in the Louisiana/Gulf of Mexico region,&quot; Unocal Chairman Roger Beach said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;They got a good value out of this,&quot; said Anit Sen at Wall Street brokerage Oppenheimer &amp; Co., noting that the sale will reduce Unocal's debt and save $200 million to $250 million in capital expenditures.</p>
<p>Tosco, with more than $11 billion in annual revenues, is one of the nation's largest independent refiners and marketers of petroleum products, and is the nation's largest operator of company-owned convenience stores.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
