<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197616" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British banks use Internet to create new customer links.</title>
<headline>British banks use Internet to create new customer links.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Adler</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's main banks and building societies all have Websites on the Internet, but most of the Websites are regarded as experimental ventures.</p>
<p>All of the seven banks and building societies that rank in Britain's top 100 advertisers have Websites, Reuters found in its survey, &quot;Advertising and Marketing on the Internet&quot;.</p>
<p>The seven include Abbey National; Alliance &amp; Leicester; Barclays; Halifax; Midland; Nationwide and NatWest.</p>
<p>Three of the respondents said it was too early to know if their investment in Websites will pay off, while two said the Websites were worth the money they had spent.</p>
<p>People and companies are using websites, private electronic pages on the Internet, to communicate about almost anything, including selling things to advising investors to chatting with Internet users.</p>
<p>One financial institution said it created its Website as a way to &quot;add value from a delivery of content and information perspective&quot;. Another institution called its Website &quot;the first step of many. We are developing expertise and knowledge, whilst gaining a good reputation.&quot;</p>
<p>But each financial institution said that much progress had to be made to unlock the Internet's potential as an advertising and marketing medium.</p>
<p>A spokesman for another financial institution called the Internet &quot;good in parts&quot;. But its usefulness is undermined, he said, because &quot;some financial companies seem to believe that dumping point of sale material verbatim on to the screen is adequate&quot;.</p>
<p>Another bank said that there are &quot;not enough clear objectives set, leading to sites copying other advertising material rather than using the technology effectively&quot;.</p>
<p>One bank, however, said the Internet allowed it to add value at a low cost.</p>
<p>Each of the seven financial institutional sites offers consumer information on financial services, ranging from current accounts, mortgages, insurance, home banking and stockbrokerage. Some of the sites allows users to make mortgage payment calculations, such as Barclays which requires users to download a spreadsheet to calculate mortgage qualification.</p>
<p>The Alliance &amp; Leicester site allows users to easily calculate monthly payments under various mortgage schemes.</p>
<p>Users of each of the seven Web sites can make on-line requests for further information, but users cannot actually carry out transactions, such as applying for a loan, on-line.</p>
<p>A separate Web site for BarclayCard, the credit card issued by Barclays Bank, does, however, offer on-line shopping via links to other Web sites, such as Eurostar, Sainsbury's, Victoria Wine and Debenhams.</p>
<p>Although there is a marked difference in the graphical presentation in each of the financial insitution's sites, they offer very similar services to the user. In addition to providing consumer information, most also offer corporate information, such as financial results and biographies of senior executives.</p>
<p>The Halifax site stands apart in one aspect, by offering specialised information for British and non-British residents. The section for expatriates provides links to a variety of other Web sites offering news and financial services, including the Electronic Telegraph, Moneyworld Magazine, stock prices, and Expat World magazine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
