<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197700" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Falling spacecrafts have done little harm.</title>
<headline>Falling spacecrafts have done little harm.</headline>
<byline>Steve Young</byline>
<dateline>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla. 1996-11-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Russian probe that fell to Earth on Sunday is one of several spacecraft that have crashed through the atmosphere in recent years, but the man-made space debris has caused no deaths or injuries.</p>
<p>The six-tonne Mars probe lifted off from Kazakhstan on Saturday but failed to leave Earth's orbit after a rocket misfired and burnt up in the atmosphere on reentry on Sunday.</p>
<p>Debris of the spacecraft, which carried four canisters of radioactive plutonium, was believed to have crashed in the South Pacific between Easter Island and the coast of Chile.</p>
<p>The largest spacecraft to plunge from orbit was NASA's 77-tonne Skylab space station, which in 1979 strew more than 15,000 pieces of wreckage along a 2,700-mile (4,400-km) sparsely-populated swath of Western Australia.</p>
<p>One of the largest pieces to survive reentry was a 176-pound (80-kg) lump of aluminium.</p>
<p>Parts of Russia's Salyut 7 space station are thought to have survived reentry when it tumbled out of orbit in 1991. Most of the 39-tonne space laboratory fell into the Atlantic Ocean but some pieces reportedly crashed in Argentina.</p>
<p>The worst nuclear space accident occurred in 1978 when a Soviet Cosmos spy satellite burnt up over northern Canada, scattering radioactive debris from its nuclear reactor over a wide area. The Soviet authorities were forced to pay for a massive clean-up operation.</p>
<p>Very little of the tens of thousands of pieces of space debris orbiting Earth reaches the ground. Most wreckage that survives the fiery plunge through the atmosphere falls in uninhabited regions or into the oceans.</p>
<p>The Russian probe, which had been due to reach Mars in September next year, had two strongly built landing vehicles that were expected to survive reentry into Earth's atmosphere.</p>
<p>NASA officials said the vehicles were built to survive a landing on Mars and weighed 110 pounds (50 kilos) each. Two 6.5-foot (2-metre) penetrators designed to ram into the surface of Mars and weighing 143 pounds (65 kilos) each, were also expected to survive re-entry into the Earth's atmosphere.</p>
<p>The landing vehicles each carried two tiny plutonium batteries about the size of 35mm film canisters containing a total of seven ounces (200 grams) of the radioactive material.</p>
<p>This was also not the first accident involving plutonium batteries used for heat or power. In 1964, a U.S. satellite failed to achieve orbit and disintegrated about 50 miles (80 km) above the Earth's surface, dispersing some 3.5 ounces (100 grams) of plutonium.</p>
<p>In 1968, the U.S. Nimbus B-1 mission aborted following a launch failure, but two plutonium batteries were eventually recovered from the Pacific Ocean and reused in subsequent flights.</p>
<p>Plutonium batteries aboard a lunar lander jettisoned from the 1970 mission Apollo 13 presumably went into the Pacific Ocean as well, but have never been recovered.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
