<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197779" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Deutsche Telekom paints Frankfurt pink.</title>
<headline>Deutsche Telekom paints Frankfurt pink.</headline>
<byline>Emma Thomasson</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Telekom painted the town pink on Monday, blazoning chandeliers, baseball caps and even the walls of the Frankfurt stock exchange with its corporate colour, as a razzmatazz advertising campaign to promote the flotation of Telekom shares came to its climax.</p>
<p>Curious onlookers sat outside the bourse on large glowing pink cubes, symbolising data bits heralding in the information age of the 21st century, as inside the first Telekom shares changed hands in Europe's biggest ever public offering.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a historic day for Germany's financial sector,&quot; Finance Minister Theo Waigel told reporters at the glitzy launch party to celebrate the sale of shares to the public.</p>
<p>A blue-sparkly piano and double bass played in the corner of the bourse function room as politicians, executives, industry analysts and journalists were plied with champagne.</p>
<p>Amongst the guests was 91-year-old Andre Kostolany, who has written a popular column on the Frankfurt stock market for over 30 years. Kostolany was quoted as saying, &quot;Hold onto your Telekom shares and don't sell them until they double in price.&quot;</p>
<p>Investors in the shares made an immediate gain of over 16 percent as the stock, which had been issued on Sunday at a price of 28.50 marks, started trading at 33.20 marks.</p>
<p>The Telekom campaign, aimed at wooing usually-cautious German private investors into the potential risky share market, has bombarded Germany for months with relentless advertisements and has been dubbed an unqualified success.</p>
<p>Ordinary Germans bought just under half of the 713 million shares floated by Telekom on the bourse.</p>
<p>&quot;The high demand from private investors in Germany was unexpected,&quot; said Telekom finance director Joachim Kroeske.</p>
<p>Journalists asked Waigel if he, too, had bought shares.</p>
<p>&quot;As an insider I couldn't buy Telekom shares. But if I wasn't finance minister I definitely would have bought them,&quot; he said. But that did not stop him from enjoying the action.</p>
<p>As frantic order activity erupted at 1130 GMT with over 100 dealers waving order books and scrambling to make the first trades in the stock, Waigel and Telekom chief executive Ron Sommer stood grinning in a sea of trading activity.</p>
<p>Outside the bourse, a ten-metre wide televison screen burst into life, flashing images of people from all-walks of life making a &quot;T&quot; shape with their hands -- the logo used to promote the sale of the shares and a team of Telekom officials handed out pink baseball caps and free telephone cards to passersby.</p>
<p>In the weeks before the share launch, Dresdner Bank, one of the issue's coordinators, lit up its Frankfurt skyscraper with multicoloured lasers depicting a pink &quot;T&quot; climbing the walls to symbolise the hopes of two million Germans who bought the shares.</p>
<p>Telekom rounded off its campaign with a full-page advertisement in national newspapers thanking its new shareholders for their trust in the company. &quot;We will make ourselves strong for you,&quot; the advert said. &quot;Going onto the stock market obliges us to succeed.&quot;</p>
<p>As trade in the new stock settles down and the party-atmosphere subsides, millions of Germans will be eagerly watching to see if their trust has been well placed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
