<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197797" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FORECAST-Italy Nov CPI seen falling to 2.6 pct y/y.</title>
<headline>FORECAST-Italy Nov CPI seen falling to 2.6 pct y/y.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's inflation rate should continue falling in November due to further economic slowdown and stagnating demand, a Reuter poll of 12 economists and analysts showed on Monday.</p>
<p>The poll showed November's consumer price index (CPI) rising on average 0.25 percent from October's 0.1-percent gain. On a yearly basis, CPI was seen up 2.6 percent yearly compared to October's yearly figure of up 3.0 percent.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the cities of Milan, Genoa, Trieste, Bologna, Perugia and Palermo are due to publish their November inflation figures. On Friday, Turin, Florence, Naples and Venice will announce their CPI. Istat will publish the national figure on Thursday, December 5.</p>
<p>This past weekend, Treasury minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi said in a newspaper interview that November CPI should fall to about 2.7 percent year-on-year and then, stabilize there for some time.</p>
<p>Analysts polled said this month's increase in electricity tariffs and the quarterly recordings of durable goods could be negative on November CPI.</p>
<p>But JP Morgan said in a market note &quot;The quarterly increase in household appliances and furniture (prices) should be lower than the seasonal average as a result of weak consumer demand.&quot;</p>
<p>Also, &quot;the usual seasonal hike in auto prices did not take place this year,&quot; JP Morgan noted, adding that this reflected the weakness in the domestic auto market.</p>
<p>Analysts also saw evidence that at the wholesale level, food prices remained subdued in November.</p>
<p>&quot;The progressive fall in food raw materials since June guarantees the current non-inflationary trend in the food sector,&quot; Banco di Sardegna said in a note.</p>
<p>Analysts also said November CPI would benefit from a positive comparison with the data in November 1995, when prices grew 0.6 percent monthly and 6.0 percent yearly. National statistics body Istat, however, revised the basket it uses to calculate the country's inflation figures in January 1996.</p>
<p>Following are the analysts' forecasts:</p>
<p>					 Month/Month	  Year/Year</p>
<p>    Banca di Roma		    0.2		     2.6</p>
<p>    Banco di Sardegna		0.2		     2.6</p>
<p>    Bank of America		  0.3		     2.6</p>
<p>    Caboto			     0.2		     2.6</p>
<p>    Chase Manhattan Bank	   0.1-0.2		 2.5</p>
<p>    BCI				  0.3		     2.6</p>
<p>    Credito Italiano		 0.4		     2.7</p>
<p>    CS First Boston		  0.2-0.3		 2.5-2.6</p>
<p>    Deutsche Bank		    0.3		     2.6-2.7</p>
<p>    JP Morgan			  0.2		     2.5-2.6</p>
<p>    Paribas			    0.2		     2.6</p>
<p>    San Paolo Bank		   0.3		     2.6</p>
<p>============================================================</p>
<p>    CONSENSUS			 0.25		     2.6</p>
<p>------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom ++392 66129526</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
