<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197764" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>COFFEE - World market for November 15, 1996</p>
<p>Robusta futures in London closed higher on keen buying interest and inspired by New York amid hopes of bullish U.S. GCA stock figures. January ended $10 higher at $1,442 a tonne while expiring November was $2 off at $1,501. News of a small drop in London's October certified coffee stocks to 1,410 5-tonne lots was within trade expectations and was viewed as neutral.</p>
<p>In New York arabica futures ended higher, buoyed by expectations of a drawdown in GCA coffee stocks. Traders expected a decline of between 200,000 and 300,000 60-kg bags. The actual drawdown was slightly higher than expected at 351,000 bags to 1.260 million bags. Already in September supplies of green coffee in US warehouses fell to 1.611 million bags, their lowest level since the GCA began tracking inventories eight years ago.</p>
<p>The fall in GCA stocks underlines the tight supply situation. While more coffee begins to trickle into the market, this is apparently not enough to ease supply concerns. But the recent fall in futures prices failed to spark offtake, as roasters seemed content to hang on and wait for the CSCE spot December contract to go off the board.</p>
<p>Traders said prices must be expected to remain firm up to the end of the month, but thereafter the outlook becomes much more uncertain as new supplies might start to become available.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - Supplies of green coffee housed in U.S. warehouses fell in October by 351,000 60-kg bags to 1.260 million bags, their lowest level since the Green Coffee Association of New York began tracking inventories in January, 1988. In October last year stocks were still at 2.195 million bags. The drawdown underlines current tight nearby supplies.</p>
<p>UNITED KINGDOM - London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE) certified coffee stocks fell to 1,401 5-tonne lots in October from 1,591 lots in September, traders said. This was in line with expectations and had no impact on prices.</p>
<p>VIETNAM - According to official sources the country exported 3.850 million 60-kg bags of coffee in 1995/96 (October/September), a rise of 9.8 per cent from the previous year.</p>
<p>However, export earnings in 1995/96 were down to $420 million, a drop of 25 per cent from 1994/95, largely because of a fall in world coffee prices. Production in 1996/97 is estimated at between 4.0 to 4.5 million bags.</p>
<p>DENMARK - Denmark imported 82,722 bags of coffee in August 1996, 5 per cent more than was imported the same month the previous year. That brought total imports since the beginning of 1996 up to 662,300 bags, nearly 23 per cent more than was imported the same period in 1995. Total imports in calendar year 1995 dropped by 14 per cent to 873,700 bags.</p>
<p>The main supplier of green coffee in January/August 1996 was Brazil with 157,200 bags up from 207,600 bags shipped the same period in 1995. The country exported 63,300 bags of coffee in January/August 1996, 12 per cent more than was exported the same period in 1995. Total exports in calendar year 1995 dropped by 5.5 per cent to 91,200 bags.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
