<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197810" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: FOCUS-CSHolding reports flat 9-mth profit.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-CSHolding reports flat 9-mth profit.</headline>
<byline>Greg Calhoun</byline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of Swiss banking's &quot;big three&quot;, CS Holding, reported a 12 percent rise in 1996 nine-month gross profits on Monday, but said net profits were only on a par with last year and full-year earnings would depend on financial markets and on this year's provisioning levels.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect our operating result for 1996 to be higher than last year, however, business performance in the final quarter will depend to some extent on the state of financial markets and the net result will depend upon provisions for credit risks which will remain at a high level,&quot; a company statement said.</p>
<p>Like Swiss rivals Union Bank of Switzerland and Swiss Bank Corp, CS Holding said profit growth slowed in the third quarter as market activity stagnated somewhat as compared to the first half of the year.</p>
<p>The third quarter slowdown had been expected at CS Holding as well. Nonetheless, analysts said the group's year-to-date performance report was a letdown.</p>
<p>&quot;The cost developments were disappointing,&quot; said Bank Vontobel analyst Susan Borer.</p>
<p>Along with its warning about provisions, CS Holding said overall costs rose by 18 percent as compared to the first nine months of 1995. This despite the fact that business slowed in the third quarter.</p>
<p>CS Holding's net income from balance sheet business, net commission income and trading income were all between 3.5 percent and 6.5 percent below the average for the first half of 1996. But in the aggregate were 18 percent higher as compared to the first nine months of 1995.</p>
<p>One analysts pointed out that high personnel costs were probably a factor in view of the likelihood that the group has been spending heavily to prevent defections at its Credit Suisse First Boston operations in the U.S. since the announcement of the group's restructuring plans in July.</p>
<p>Looking at 1996 as a whole, CS Holding, like its rivals in Switzerland, continues to face high provisioning requirements in view of the depressed real estate sector in particular and the stalled domestic economy in general.</p>
<p>A CS Holding spokesman declined to elaborate on the group's statement regarding provisions.</p>
<p>&quot;All we are saying is that provisions remain high. It is the same situation as in the report for the first half,&quot; CS spokesman Peter Walser said.</p>
<p>CS Holding said in its half year report in August that it expected provisions for credit risk to remain high for the rest of 1996 but it did not elaborate.</p>
<p>The six month report also said full year results should be better than in 1995, depending on provisions and the situation on world financial markets in the second half.</p>
<p>CS, probably has the highest real estate holdings of the three big banks and this was a big part of the reason for the high provision, Christoph Bieri at Zuercher Kantonalbank said.</p>
<p>&quot;Swiss Bank Corp revalued its real estate portfolio, but the other two big banks' portfolios are still too highly valued,&quot; Bieri said.</p>
<p>Swiss Bank Corp said in September that as part of a restructuring of its domestic operations it was revaluing its real estate portfolio, a move that would result in a one-time write-off of 910 million Swiss francs ($713 million).</p>
<p>However, Hanna Kudelski at Darier Hentsch &amp; Cie was not too disappointed with today's report in light of the fact that CS Holding has undertaken a major restructuring.</p>
<p>She said CS Holding would probably take some aggressive action this year with regard to provisions and writedowns.</p>
<p>This, together with the basis effect of the divestiture of some activities, which should take place next year, will probably make for a more favourable longer-term outlook.</p>
<p>($1=1.2763 Swiss Franc)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
