<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197804" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Ergobank holders meet on rights issue Tues.</title>
<headline>Ergobank holders meet on rights issue Tues.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Private Ergo Bank will hold a shareholders' meeting on Tuesday, November 19 on its planned 27.3 billion drachma rights issue, it said in a statement.</p>
<p>The shareholders' meeting will take place at 1900 local at the Hilton hotel, Ergo Bank said.</p>
<p>Its board will seek shareholder approval for a rights issue of 2,880,000 shares at 9,500 drachmas a share. The terms for shareholders of record on Tuesday will be three new shares for every 20 outstanding.</p>
<p>The issue includes 162,000 shares earmarked for the bank's staff also at 9,500 drachmas a share.</p>
<p>Ergo Bank will also seek approval for a bonus share issue of 4,200,000 shares arising from a capitalisation of reserves. It will distribute two bonus shares for every 10 outstanding. The new shares from the rights issue will be entitled to the bonus distribution.</p>
<p>&quot;For example, a shareholder of 200 shares at today's close may participate in the rights issue for another 30 shares at 9,500 drachmas a share. The resulting 230 shares will become 276 with the bonus distribution of another 46 shares,&quot; Ergo Bank said.</p>
<p>Ergo Bank shares closed up 3.44 percent or 420 drachmas at 12,615 on Monday as the market rebounded 2.74 percent to 914.82 points. --George Georgiopoulos, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
