<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="197861" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SNB official sees y/y M0 growth about 4 pct in Q4.</title>
<headline>SNB official sees y/y M0 growth about 4 pct in Q4.</headline>
<dateline>BERNE 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Swiss National Bank (SNB) director said growth in the benchmark M0 central bank money supply aggregate would likely be around four to 4.5 percent at the end of the fourth quarter versus the year-earlier quarter.</p>
<p>Director Erich Spoerndli said the growth was somewhat in excess of the SNB's mid-term target for monetary growth but was still acceptable.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect central bank money supply to be up about four to 4.5 percent at the end of the fourth quarter versus a year ago,&quot; Spoerndli told reporters.  </p>
<p>Spoerndli said the purpose of setting a medium-term target for monetary growth was to allow for fluctuations like the expected fourth-quarter growth.</p>
<p>Spoerndli said the medium-term target was for an average annual growth of one percent in M0 over five years.</p>
<p>&quot;We are a little bit above this target but not enormously,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether the expected four-quarter growth was acceptable, he said, &quot;Yes.&quot;  </p>
<p>He said the expected fourth-quarter growth was caused by special factors, including the need to increase money supply to help boost Switzerland out of a sluggish economic period.</p>
<p>M0 consists of notes in circulation plus commercial banks' sight deposits at the SNB.</p>
<p>-- Zurich newsroom +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
