<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198096" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Boral to review European assets.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Boral to review European assets.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Building materials and energy group Boral Ltd chairman Peter Cottrell said the company was undertaking a review of its European assets following poor financial performances from the operations there.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a review of the assets at present, some assets have been sold off in the U.K., we are looking hard at those in mainland Europe, primarily Germany,&quot; Cottrell told the annual meeting in reponse to a shareholder's question about Europe.</p>
<p>&quot;There may be further changes it is too premature to comment, but we are certainly looking at whatever is required to achieve an adequate return (from Europe),&quot; Cottrell said.  </p>
<p>Boral sold its British masonry business in April.</p>
<p>Cottrell said Boral's clay bricks operations in the Netherlands, Germany and Poland and roof tiles in Germany are major investments retained by Boral and strategies are being implemented to improve the performance of these businesses.</p>
<p>Profits from Boral's European businesses fell 73.7 percent to A$7 million in 1995/96, while sales fell 13.9 percent to A$205 million.</p>
<p>Cottrell and the Boral board were also grilled by shareholders over the group's overall financial performance and its timber logging and woodchipping activities.  </p>
<p>Environmental group, the Wilderness Society, protested outside the hotel where Boral held its annual meeting over the company's timber activities in native forests.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the Wilderness Society said the environmental group was calling for a consumer ban on all of Boral's timber products.</p>
<p>Managing director Tony Berg told the meeting the company was on target to deliver more than A$80 million in savings in the 1996/97 year. Berg said Boral was ahead of budget for the first quarter with savings of over A$20 million being achieved.</p>
<p>-- Kevin Morrison 61-2 9373-1813</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
