<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198079" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Palmer says sells 40 mln ANI shares.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Palmer says sells 40 mln ANI shares.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former ANI Ltd director Ross Palmer confirmed on Monday that his company Tube Securities Ltd had sold 40 million of its shares in ANI.</p>
<p>Palmer, previously ANI's biggest individual shareholder, said in a statement thta Tube Securities would retain its residual holding. No price was disclosed.  </p>
<p>Earlier on Monday ANI topped turnover lists after a trade of 41 million ANI shares, or about five percent of the heavy engineering company's shares, changed hands at A$1.27 per share.</p>
<p>Palmer, who assumed the ANI stake following the takeover of his former company Palmer Tube Mills Ltd last year by ANI, was involved in a dispute with the ANI board after his removal from the ANI board at last month's annual meeting.</p>
<p>Palmer last week requested an extraordinary meeting of shareholders be held to consider the removal of ANI directors Peter Joseph and Howard Stack.  </p>
<p>&quot;While I have not spoken with all of the institutional shareholders, I am extremely disappointed with the response I have had to my notice and, in the circumstances, I have decided that I can do no more for this company,&quot; Palmer said in the statement on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;While ANI has some outstanding underlying businesses, the board's inability to face its own poor record and the reluctance of its major shareholders to deal appropriately with that board dictate that TSL is no longer prepared to be a substantial shareholder,&quot; Palmer said.  </p>
<p>Palmer's removal from the ANI board followed a dispute with Joseph over the board's handling of the purcahse of German environmental waste business ABT by its Holter unit of Germany.</p>
<p>ANI shares were one cent firmer at A$1.27 at 3.50 p.m. (0450 GMT) on turnover at 42.28 million shares.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
