<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198023" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Hickson Intl sells unit, takes charge.</title>
<headline>Hickson Intl sells unit, takes charge.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Specialty chemicals group Hickson International Plc said on Monday it had agreed to sell its Hickson Manro unit to a management buyout team for 26.5 million stg.</p>
<p>The company said the sale resulted in an exceptional loss, net of expenses, of about 16 million stg, after charging 18 million stg of goodwill previously written-off to reserves.  </p>
<p>Hickson said it had sold the surfactants unit, which has plants in Stalybridge, England, and Renory, Belgium, to Broomco Ltd.</p>
<p>The buyers intended to operate the business under the Manro name, Hickson said in a statement.</p>
<p>The company said it would use proceeds from the sale to reduce its debt, which was about 70 million stg at June 30 on a pro forma basis, taking into account the disposal.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, the group's trading performance remains in line with the board's expectations,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>The sale is the latest in a series of disposals aimed at turning round Yorkshire-based Hickson.</p>
<p>The company crashed to a pretax loss of 45 million pounds in 1995 after a pretax profit of 19.2 million stg a year earlier.</p>
<p>It was hit by poor trading conditions and the cancellation of a key detergent supply contract late in 1994.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
