<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198152" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan upstart airline's plans begin to take flight.</title>
<headline>Japan upstart airline's plans begin to take flight.</headline>
<byline>Yuzo Saeki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A plan to launch a major airline in Japan for the first time in more than 40 years took off on Monday with the announcement to the set up a company to oversee operations and a share offering in the not-too-distant future.</p>
<p>Tokyo-based discount ticket agency H.I.S. Co Ltd has formed Skymark Airlines Co Ltd, aiming to fan competition by offering cheap tickets on domestic flights.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to become a new breeze in the Japanese aviation industry,&quot; Junichi Ogawara, president of the new carrier, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;And we would like to trigger a move so that Japan can have genuine competitiveness as international competition is getting stronger,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Media reports say Skymark has become the first major airline company to enter the highly competitive domestic aviation market in more than 40 years,</p>
<p>Ogawara expects Skymark to go public within five years and double its capital to six billion yen ($54.0 million) by the time it actually begins services.</p>
<p>Currently, All Nippon Airways Co Ltd (ANA), Japan Airlines Co Ltd (JAL), and Japan Air System Co Ltd (JAS) dominate key domestic routes.</p>
<p>The Japanese aviation industry has been protected for many years by various regulations, but the government is gradually abolishing them to promote competition.</p>
<p>This year the government started allowing carriers more leeway in setting their domestic fares.</p>
<p>Media reports have said the government plans to give small airlines and new carriers priority when it allocates new slots at Tokyo's Haneda airport, which is mostly used for domestic flights, in an effort to promote competition.</p>
<p>Lack of competition in the past has made Japanese domestic air fares expensive by international standards, analysts said. A return flight on ANA between Tokyo and Sapporo in Hokkaido, Japan's northernmost main island, costs 48,500 yen ($433) for an 895 km (560 mile) journey.</p>
<p>Skymark aims to start offering services on key domestic routes from Haneda airport and the Itami airport near Osaka, which is at the heart of western Japan, Ogawara said.</p>
<p>It expects to offer services within two years, he said, and that the new airline aims to provide those services nationwide.</p>
<p>&quot;We initially said we wanted more than 10 slots at Haneda and Itami but we would need more if we want to offer services to Kyushu and Okinawa as well as Sapporo,&quot; Sawada said.</p>
<p>To keep operating costs low and offer cheaper tickets, the new firm would lease three medium-sized aircraft and hire foreign pilots at lower salaries than those paid to Japanese crew, Sawada said.</p>
<p>Sawada said, however, that there are still hurdles to overcome before the new airline gets off the ground.</p>
<p>It needs approval from the Ministry of Transport and cooperation from existing airlines on safety and maintenance issues. The new company may have to be disbanded if it cannot clear those hurdles, Sawada said. Skymark will apply to begin business by the middle of 1997, he said, adding that the new company was negotiating with its rivals on several issues.</p>
<p>($1=111 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
