<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198133" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul stocks close lower after early rebound.</title>
<headline>Seoul stocks close lower after early rebound.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seoul stocks closed lower on Monday after selling in the afternoon more than offset the rebound in the late morning session, brokers said.</p>
<p>They said selling increased in the afternoon because of the disappointment among investors at the lack of fresh news from the meeting between the President and economic ministers.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors who hoped for new steps to help revive the economy were disappointed at the results from the meeting and sold shares,&quot; said Koh Soon-shik of LG Securities.</p>
<p>The composite index closed at 750.82, down 5.85 points from the previous close. </p>
<p>The Ministry of Finance and Economy said it would allow local firms buying more than 50 percent of their machinery purchases from domestic manufacturers to borrow up to $2 billion in foreign loans next year.</p>
<p>But this was just a follow-up to an earlier announcement.</p>
<p>President Kim Young-sam told his ministers to make efforts to reduce next year's current account deficit to half of the level for this year. But he did not elaborate.</p>
<p>&quot;The news on President Kim's remarks also failed to impress investors,&quot; said Koh. </p>
<p>Brokers said initial public offerings by nine companies, due Tuesday and Wednesday, also hurt the buying sentiment as investors expected funds to outflow from the market for the offerings.</p>
<p>Nine companies will receive subscriptions for their 448 billion won worth of new shares for the two days.</p>
<p>Decliners beat advancers by 619 to 254, with 130 stocks closing unchanged. Volume were a low 22.48 million shares.</p>
<p>The index futures December contracts closed 0.55 points lower at 80.15 and the KOSPI-200 index ended 0.66 points down to 79.02. --YOO CHOON-SIK (822) 727 5646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
