<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198136" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Nov 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Nov 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Indonesian press on November 18. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOMPAS</p>
<p>An Indonesian actress who fled to the United States after being arrested for possessing almost 30,000 pills of the designer drug Ecstasy was brought home to Indonesia by police on Sunday. Zarima had been arrested in Houston, Texas by American police on charges of overstaying her visa but had agreed to return home voluntarily to face drug charges.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>The trial of a man on charges of alleged blasphemy against Islam that led to riots last month is to resume in the East Java town of Situbondo today. A mob went on rampage in October killing five people and burning churches after the court hearing of the defendant, saying that the sentence demanded by the prosecution was too lenient.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MEDIA INDONESIA</p>
<p>President Suharto, returning from the World Food Summit in Rome, said that Indonesia had been asked to explain to the conference how they had reached a level of self-sufficiency in rice production.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BISNIS INDONESIA</p>
<p>The Indonesian government's credit rating agency, Pefindo, has given an &quot;A&quot; rating to state electricity firm PT Perusahaan Listrik Negara (PLN).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
