<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198137" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - Nov 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK Newspaper Headlines - Nov 18.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- HONGKONG STANDARD -- The Association for Democracy and People's Livelihood faces mass resignations by at least 18 members over the party's decision to field candidates for the Provisional Legislature while still opposing its formation.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO -- Although Hong Kong people are reserved about the Provisional Legislature, various political groups are trying to get seats on it, viewing it as a stepping stone to the first Special Administrative Region (SAR) Legislative Council. It was estimated there will be at least 90 candidates, including 34 members of the present Legco.</p>
<p>-- Fifty Chinese central government officials have been sent to work temporarily in Shenzhen to beef up Beijing's control over the area bordering Hong Kong during the handover.</p>
<p>-- TA KUNG PAO -- Deputy director of the New China News Agency's Hong Kong office Zhang Junsheng said the Provisional Legislature would be representative because members of the Selection Committee came from all walks of life.</p>
<p>-- EXPRESS NEWS -- The Government has tightened control over Taiwan officials entering Hong Kong. Two Taiwan officials who had been to Hong Kong many times before were refused entry when trying to come to Hong Kong via Macau recently.</p>
<p>-- TIN TIN DAILY -- Hong Kong's Mark Six lottery has become popular among underground hawkers in China's Guangdong province.</p>
<p>-- ECONOMIC JOURNAL -- A company under the Ministry of Radio, Film and Television in Beijing plans to complete a satellite network that will start operation by the year 2000.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- Aviation Industries of China plans to raise at least US$500 million through Hong Kong listings of its car, motorcycle and other businesses next year.</p>
<p>-- Developers said China's cabinet was expected to endorse a &quot;flurry of decrees&quot; by year-end to bolster housing, which had been struggling since a credit squeeze launched three years ago. -- China International Trust and Investment Corp planned to set up a national general insurance company early in 1997 to expand the conglomerate's presence in the financial sector.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
