<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198171" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: U.S. auto industry leader warns against weaker yen.</title>
<headline>U.S. auto industry leader warns against weaker yen.</headline>
<byline>Mitsuo Suzuki</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. car industry leader voiced concern about the yen's weakness on Monday, saying it would put a brake on the recent shrinking trend in Japan's politically sensitive trade surplus.</p>
<p>The warning came on the same day that Japan announced a jump of over 30 percent in its contentious trade surplus with the United States -- the first increase in 20 months -- to 354.79 billion yen ($3.19 billion) as Japanese carmakers took advantage of the weak yen to export more vehicles.</p>
<p>Japan's global trade surplus, however, remained on a shrinking trend in October, showing a 13 percent drop from a year earlier to 470.86 billion yen ($4.24 billion), the 23rd consecutive month it has declined on a year-on-year basis.</p>
<p>&quot;The value of the yen still remains weaker than (the level which Japan's) economic and financial fundamentals would justify,&quot; Andrew Card, president of American Automobile Manufacturers' Association (AAMA), told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I personally would like to see the dollar at about 100 yen,&quot; he said. &quot;I clearly feel the (yen) level over 110 is much, much too weak and when you get into the 115 range, you are in a danger zone. There is nothing that can support or justify a level that will be in a 114-115 range.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar stood at around 111 yen in Tokyo on Monday, against 100 yen a year ago.</p>
<p>The yen's weakness helps growth in Japan's exports of cars and other products by making them cheaper in terms of foreign currency. Dollar weakness against the yen has an identical effect on American manufacturers' competitiveness in Japan.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, the yen briefly weakened to about 115 to the dollar, and Card said this was helped by dollar-buying intervention by Japan's central bank.</p>
<p>Card said it was one thing if economic fundamentals dictated a weak yen, but the reality was that the Bank of Japan had deliberately pushed the yen lower over the past 18 months, far lower than the market alone would dictate.</p>
<p>A weaker yen would increase Japan's exports, reversing progress made in reducing Japan's trade surplus, he said.</p>
<p>The weaker yen has prompted Honda Motor Co Ltd and Toyota Motor Corp to decide to shift their output of station wagons in the United States back home to Japan, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan's auto exports are rising again,&quot; Card warned.</p>
<p>In recent years, Japanese manufacturers have moved production bases overseas in search of lower costs and also to escape the effect of the yen's strength, and have been shipping some of this output back to Japan. But a few companies are now bringing some of their production bases back home.</p>
<p>Honda is expected to move output of its popular Accord Wagon from the United States back to Japan next autumn because of the shrinking market for station wagons in the United States, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Toyota has stopped making Scepter Wagons in the United States due to slack demand there. Industry sources said it would start producing the model in Japan from the end of this year.</p>
<p>Sales in Japan of vehicles made by the overseas units of Japanese makers in the January-October period fell 13 percent from the year before to 76,423 cars, industry data shows.</p>
<p>Japan's vehicle exports in October, meanwhile, rose 18 percent from a year earlier to 374,748 units, the Finance Ministry said on Monday. ($1=111 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
