<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198117" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: FROM THE HILL - Rumours, rumours and a few &quot;facts&quot;.</title>
<headline>FROM THE HILL - Rumours, rumours and a few &quot;facts&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Vernon Small</byline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Before we get a few rumours on the record, let's just restate the salient fact: no one outside knows what is going on inside that windowless room in Wellington's Bowen House where coalition talks have now been running for four weeks.</p>
<p>The hints are that even if we could see into the room we would be little wiser.</p>
<p>Journalists staking out the talks saw what on the surface was a better period for National last week.  </p>
<p>Without a doubt National sources and businesses have been confident and rife with rumours, while Labour sources appear more downbeat. Labour leader Helen Clark herself has been attacking National's lack of principle, as if she feared it was prepared to give away more than Labour to gain office.</p>
<p>But to the rumours.</p>
<p>It was going the rounds last week that a National-NZ First deal has been stitched up, to be announced in two weeks time. It would see more spending on Maori issues, less spending overall than NZ First wanted but, amazingly, United's sole MP Peter Dunne would get the finance portfolio.  </p>
<p>Next came former NZ First policy advisor Michael Laws' newspaper column advocating Winston Peters as finance minister. Somehow it got to Europe as fact, and was linked to an impending deal over the weekend. The New Zealand dollar sold off in London late on Friday on the strength of it.</p>
<p>National sources at the weekend dismissed the idea of either Peters as finance minister or of a deal in the immediate future. But they were less dismissive of a prominent role for Peters in the finance area -- perhaps as the chair of a &quot;gatekeeping&quot; committee similar to a cabinet finance subcommittee -- to help dilute the autocratic power that he perceives finance ministers  </p>
<p>in recent administrations have wielded.</p>
<p>Then there was the well-sourced suggestion National was looking at a capital gains tax to help curb inflation in the property market and thus take the heat out of the dollar to ease the pain of exporters.</p>
<p>RBNZ Governor Don Brash told Reuters the bank had done no investigation of the impact of a capital gains tax. He would not comment on whether he had spoken to politicians about the issue.  </p>
<p>But it appears National MPs in the caucus economic committee met with the Reserve Bank and at least one MP mooted such a tax -- which all concede would have a deflationary effect, although it may not be long-lasting.</p>
<p>Chair of the caucus committee Max Bradford told Reuters no such tax was on the National Party agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way the National Party is going down that route,&quot; Bradford said.</p>
<p>He said there was a lot of talk at the meeting about the pressures the housing market was putting on monetary policy and there were all sorts of &quot;off the wall&quot; things talked about.  </p>
<p>The strongest rumour yet -- so strong it must be part of the National Party &quot;spin&quot; -- is that National is looking at deferring the July 1997 tax cuts it has already passed into legislation.</p>
<p>Tied to a deferral of NZ First's compulsory superannuation policy, it would represent a major concession by both sides and would remove the inflationary impact of the cuts, enabling the RBNZ to ease monetary policy sooner. There is no doubt National is increasingly concerned at the impact of the high dollar and is casting about for creative solutions.  </p>
<p>New Zealand First had been getting advice from unnamed economists and costings of its policy options. Without knowing the stripe of the economists in question, it's near impossible to assess the effect that advice is having, but the odds are the advice is fiscally conservative.</p>
<p>Given Brash's warning last Monday of the dangers of extra spending plus tax cuts, the rumours and hints have fuelled the impression that National was inching ahead. Yet Peters' close friend and former adviser Laws in his column labelled Brash's statement an &quot;injudicious attempt to influence coalition talks...by speculating that increased government investment in  </p>
<p>the crisis areas of child health, law and order, and education would be inflationary -- and hence wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>One-all for fiscal restraint.</p>
<p>Part of the impression National is &quot;ahead&quot; was the &quot;informal&quot; meeting between Finance Minister Bill Birch and Peters on Friday.</p>
<p>The parallel meeting with Labour's Michael Cullen was due to be held today, Monday, but may have to be postponed to Tuesday if Clark, who comes back from Australia on Monday evening, is to attend.</p>
<p>That meeting may well restore the balance. Hold all tickets.  </p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
