<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198255" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: China should expand air cargo fleet - expert.</title>
<headline>China should expand air cargo fleet - expert.</headline>
<byline>Humphrey Hudson</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>China should expand its air freighter fleet to provide both civilian and military uplift capability, possibly through the acquisition of used aircraft, Indoswiss Aviation managing director Jim Eckes told an air cargo conference on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;China has the smallest fleet of all-freighter and combi aircraft in northeast Asia. It is in its own interest to expand the freighter fleet for national security. Countries like Thailand and Malaysia have greater military uplift capability than China,&quot; he told the Asian Air Cargo Summit conference.</p>
<p>The country was losing &quot;a great opportunity to earn foreign exchange by moving air cargo... as around 90 percent of China's air cargo exports are carried in foreign freighter aircraft or in the belly of foreign passenger aircraft,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>China could handle air cargo much more cheaply than its higher cost competitors such as Japan Airlines Ltd and Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd, and although investment is needed in freighters and cargo handling facilities, the return would surely interest bankers, Eckes said.</p>
<p>&quot;One easy way to prepare such military airlift capability is to develop a large civil airfreighter market,&quot; which is badly needed given the relative inefficiencies of road, rail and river transport systems.</p>
<p>Eckes said there was a strong demand in China for an efficient air express and postal service, but that nothing had been achieved to date.</p>
<p>&quot;Yet the revenues from an overnight China postal service would easily pay for the purchase of used aircraft for aircargo...Airfreight does not need new aircraft.&quot;</p>
<p>China could also convert its older passenger planes, such as its early Boeing 737s, to freighters, he added.</p>
<p>There is also a serious shortage of pilots, with only Chinese pilots being allowed to fly on domestic routes and &quot;perhaps the Chinese air force could provide the necessary pilots or even run the postal service&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
