<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198583" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Ninghe Chemicals says to list A shares in Shenzhen.</title>
<headline>Ninghe Chemicals says to list A shares in Shenzhen.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ningxia Ninghe National Chemicals Co Ltd said on Monday it is due to list 18 million A shares in Shenzhen on November 20.</p>
<p>The China Economic Development and Investment Co has been appointed the listing promoter of the shares, which were issued at 4.50 yuan per share last month, Ninghe said in a notice published in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>The securities code for the stock has been set as &quot;0635&quot;, Ninghe said.</p>
<p>Ninghe said it expects to have net earnings of 11.23 million yuan in 1996, compared with 6.09 million yuan last year and 3.45 million yuan a year earlier. It said it had net profits of 4.17 million yuan in the first five months of this year.</p>
<p>A company spokesman told the Hong Kong-based newsletter China Securities Bulletin that the earnings growth this year would be based on an expansion in its core operations -- raw materials for fertilizer and pharmaceuticals.</p>
<p>Ninghe said it plans to use the proceeds from the offer to expand its core business. It now has total share capital of 51.80 million shares, comprising 21.80 million state shares, 10 million founder shares, 18 million A shares and two million staff shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
