<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198652" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan trade surplus still on declining trend - MOF.</title>
<headline>Japan trade surplus still on declining trend - MOF.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's overall trade surplus is continuing on a declining trend, a Ministry of Finance official told reporters on Monday.</p>
<p>The official added that he did not think the declining trend in the surplus with the United States had changed, despite a 31.3 percent rise in the surplus with that country in October.</p>
<p>The ministry earlier announced that Japan's customs-cleared trade surplus fell 12.9 percent in October from a year ago to 470.86 billion yen, the 23rd consecutive month it has declined on a year-on-year basis.</p>
<p>The surplus with the United States, often a source of trade friction, rose to 354.79 billion yen from a year earlier. The figures were not adjusted for seasonal factors.  </p>
<p>Although it was difficult to say anything certain about the trade data, as it was affected by movements in currencies, oil prices and domestic and foreign economies, the MOF official said the value of imports had been showing two-digit growth for over a year, surpassing that of exports.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade surplus has been falling for 23 consecutive months and is still on a declining trend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that it was not correct to judge trade prospects from currency movements alone. MOF used a rate of 110.98 yen against the dollar for October, compared with 100.95 yen a year ago.</p>
<p>Trade with the United States rose for the first time in 20 months, mainly due to rise in car exports, which grew 44.4 percent from a year ago, MOF data showed.  </p>
<p>&quot;I cannot say that the trend (of a declining trade surplus with the United States) has changed, despite the rise (seen in October data),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The MOF official said the jump was mainly due to low levels of car exports to the United States in October 1995.</p>
<p>Japanese car makers were also exporting cars and stockpiling them overseas now, as they would not be able to export as many during the January to March period, due to an expected surge in domestic demand before a consumption tax increase scheduled from April 1997, the MOF official said.</p>
<p>Given the low level of car exports last year, which continued until around June 1996, car exports to the United States would continue to grow for a while, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
