<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198609" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: NAP to come under scrutiny after Thai poll win.</title>
<headline>NAP to come under scrutiny after Thai poll win.</headline>
<byline>Rajan Moses</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new government formed by Thailand's New Aspiration Party (NAP) could run into trouble with the public and markets quickly because of its similarity to the unpopular departing administration, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Leaders of four of the political parties, who flanked NAP leader Chavalit Yongchaiyudh to show solidarity with him following Sunday's general election, were partners in the chaotic government of caretaker Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa.</p>
<p>Banharn's government was blamed for many of Thailand's economic problems, including sagging exports, a widening current account deficit and a stock market that is near three-year lows.</p>
<p>Analysts, who expect the five parties to form the new coalition government, said Chavalit should appoint economic ministers acceptable to all sectors to avoid running into trouble early in his rule.</p>
<p>&quot;If Chavalit's government turns out to be pretty much the same as the previous one, investors' confidence will be eroded,&quot; said Vicharat Vichit-vadakarn, president of the Thai Brokers' Association.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the markets will adopt a wait-and-see stance. Investors will watch who the NAP would name to its key portfolios, especially economic portfolios,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Before the election, Thai businessmen had pinned their hopes on a victory for the Democrats, who have a strong economic team.</p>
<p>But Chavalit's NAP was declared the winner by just two seats.</p>
<p>The NAP took 125 seats to the Democrats' 123 in the 393-seat parliament. The election, billed the most violent and dirty in two decades, was seen as a close race between the two front-running parties from the outset.</p>
<p>The leader of the Democrat Party, former Prime Minister Chuan Leekpai, had earlier acknowledged unofficial reports that put NAP ahead but refused a NAP proposal to join hands with it to form a national government to solve national woes.</p>
<p>A Thammasat University political scientist, Somjai Phagaphasvivat, told reporters the NAP would certainly form the new coalition government.</p>
<p>&quot;When the five from the outgoing coalition government met and held a press conference, it was a clear indication that the NAP would lead the next coalition,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Suchit Bunbongkarn, dean of political science at Chulalongkorn University said a NAP coalition was set to control a majority of seats as a result of support from its allies.</p>
<p>Of the NAP allies, the Chart Thai party led by Banharn won 39 seats, the Social Action Party 20, the Prachakorn Thai party 18 seats and the Muonchon party two.</p>
<p>Combined with the NAP's projected 125 seats, the allies were set to control a clear majority of over 200 seats in parliament, said Prachakorn Thai leader Samak Sundaravej.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
