<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198677" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Reduced Iranian flows cut Oct OPEC oil output - MEES.</title>
<headline>Reduced Iranian flows cut Oct OPEC oil output - MEES.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>OPEC crude output fell to 25.64 million barrels per day (bpd) in October mainly because of lower exports from Iran, the Middle East Economic Survey (MEES) newsletter reported on Monday.</p>
<p>Iran's output fell to 3.443 million bpd in October from 3.810 million bpd in September with exports, its lowest level since May, MEES reported.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not easy to pinpoint the causes for such a sharp decline...a possible explanation might be found in upstream bottlenecks combined with month-to-month shifts in loading logistics,&quot; the Cyprus-based weekly said.</p>
<p>MEES estimated Iranian crude exports at 2.343 million bpd in October, down from 2.710 million the previous month.</p>
<p>Crude exports from onshore fields accounted for 1.913 million bpd and 430,000 bpd from offshore fields.</p>
<p>&quot;The momentum of increasing Iranian supply to the Asia Pacific region has been maintained with deliveries to that area registering 1.078 million bpd,&quot; MEES said.</p>
<p>Venezuela remained the biggest quota violator, producing 3.1 million bpd versus its quota of 2.359 million bpd.</p>
<p>Nigerian crude output reached its highest level so far this year, averaging 2.14 million bpd in October.</p>
<p>OPEC ministers will meet in Vienna on November 27 to set the group's ceiling for at least the first half of 1997.</p>
<p>Leading OPEC ministers have already called for a roll-over of the group's current ceiling of 25.033 million bpd.</p>
<p>OPEC chairman and UAE acting oil minister Rakad bin Salem bin Rakad on Saturday said that ministers meeting in Vienna would also look into overproduction by member states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OPEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
