<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="198682" id="root" date="1996-11-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Nov 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Lebanon -  Nov 18.</headline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-11-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Beirut press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AN-NAHAR</p>
<p>-Lebanese police shot dead a Palestinian accused of belonging to a gang charged with forging revenue stamps and selling for private gain genuine stamps supplied by a finance ministry official</p>
<p>--Foreign exchange reserves rose by $153.45 million in the first half of November.</p>
<p>-President Hrawi: Let us call a war on corruption and slander those who cover it up.</p>
<p>-The new government to issue policy statement tomorrow.</p>
<p>AS-SAFIR</p>
<p>-Foreign Minister Bouez discussed with Prime Minister Hariri preparations for the December 16 meeting of the international consultative group in Washington.</p>
<p>The group, which will assist Lebanon in its reconstruction programme, was formed under an April ceasefire understanding which ended 17 days of Israeli onslaught on the country.</p>
<p>AL-ANWAR</p>
<p>-Some 215 Arab bankers arrived in Beirut to participate in a two-day conference on the role of banks in economic reform and reconstruction in the Arab world. The conference is organised by Union of Arab Banks.</p>
<p>AD-DIYAR</p>
<p>-Critics of Prime Minister Hariri made demands for economic changes at a mass meeting on Friday night.</p>
<p>NIDA'A AL-WATAN</p>
<p>-Lebanon and Germany denied reports that security officials were tracing from Germany missing Israeli airman Ron Arad who was shot down over Lebanon in 1986.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
