<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199157" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: SOCCER-JARDEL LIKELY TO START AGAINST AC MILAN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JARDEL LIKELY TO START AGAINST AC MILAN.</headline>
<byline>Alberto Pontes</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian striker Mario Jardel is likely to start Porto's European Champions' League group D match against AC Milan on Wednesday after his two goals in the upset 3-2 win in Milan.</p>
<p>&quot;They are strong but we are the favourites,&quot; said Jordel, who came on for the second half of the first match.</p>
<p>Porto, unbeaten so far in the qualifying group, need only draw against the five times European champions to ensure top place.</p>
<p>&quot;Our aim is to guarantee first place in the group, but we recognise that the task will not be easy,&quot; Porto trainer Antonio Oliveira said.</p>
<p>AC Milan, strengthened by the return of  captain Franco Baresi, forced a 0-0 draw against reigning European champions Juventus in a Serie A clash in Turin on Sunday.</p>
<p>Baresi, whose steadying influence helped his side keep their first clean sheet of the season in the Italian league, is expected to line up against Porto, with in-form Roberto Baggio also likely to start in attack alongside Liberian George Weah.</p>
<p>But the Italians will be without influential midfielder Demetrio Albertini, who like Porto defender Paulinho Santos, is ruled out after picking up two yellow cards in the competition.</p>
<p>Porto, who are bidding for their third successive domestic league title, are at the centre of a series of allegations of attempted match fixing.</p>
<p>But there was no sign that the off-field controversies were affecting their play when they beat Rio Ave 1-0 away at the weekend to strengthen their grip on the league.</p>
<p>The club expects 50,000 spectators, the maximum allowed by UEFA at Porto's Antas ground for European matches, to give them rousing support against the Italians.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Porto (probable) - 24-Henrique Hilario; 2-Joao Pinto, 4-Aloisio Alves, 22-Jorge Costa, 5-Fernando Mendes, 7-Sergio Conceicao, 11-Ljubimko Drulovic, 21-Edmilson Pimenta, 25-Zlatko Zahovic, 14-Artur Oliveira, 16-Mario Jardel.</p>
<p>Milan: to be announced.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
