<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199363" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Burundi rebels head to Tanzania from Zaire bases.</title>
<headline>Burundi rebels head to Tanzania from Zaire bases.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Bigg</byline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burundian Hutu rebels, driven out of refugee camps in eastern Zaire, are regrouping in Tanzania after fighting their way across Burundi, diplomats and senior Burundian officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The movement of Forces for Defence of Democracy (FDD) rebels to Tanzania via Burundi has led to an upsurge in fighting and put a severe strain on relations between the two countries.</p>
<p>Hutu rebel leader Leanord Nyangoma met both Tanzanian President Benjamin Mkapa and mediator Julius Nyerere last week to request permission to establish bases in Tanzania, a senior diplomat said.</p>
<p>&quot;Tanzania has welcomed all the FDD units onto its territory and it's getting to the point that it's obvious they will have to choose if they are going to stay neutral,&quot; Jean-Luc Ndizeye, spokesman for Burundi's military leader Pierre Buyoya, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Nyerere's neutral role as the internationally recognised mediator on Burundi could be undermined by the welcome being accorded rebels, Ndizeye said. He added that Hutu militants were being given free run of Burundi's embassy in the Tanzanian capital Dar es Salaam.</p>
<p>Tanzania's foreign ministry rejects claims that Hutu rebels are being allowed to use bases inside its borders.</p>
<p>&quot;The (Tanzanian) government's position is clear. It does not and will not allow its territory to be used for political activity by refugees,&quot; the foreign ministry's director of information, Cyprian Majengo, said.</p>
<p>Tanzania plays reluctant host to around 670,000 refugees including 539,986 Rwandan Hutus and 122,158 Burundian Hutus, according to U.N. refugee agency figures.</p>
<p>Regional states led by Kenya and Tanzania imposed sanctions on Burundi six days after Buyoya came to power on July 25, demanding among other measures unconditional talks between the new military government and Hutu rebels.</p>
<p>Hundreds of FDD fighters fled bases north of east Zaire's Uvira last month along with around 225,000 Rwandan and Burundian refugees because of battles between Zairean Tutsi rebels who now control much of eastern Zaire and the Zairean army.</p>
<p>Unable to travel north or west they were forced to flee east into Burundi and make their way towards Tanzania, sustaining heavy losses en route in clashes with Burundi's Tutsi-dominated army.</p>
<p>&quot;They have had a very bad time from the Burundian army,&quot; a senior diplomat in the Burundian capital told Reuters.</p>
<p>The rebels entered Cibitoke province staging a series of ambushes, tried and failed to establish bases in a former stronghold in the Kibira forest, before heading east to Tanzania via Kayanza and south towards Bururi province, diplomats said.</p>
<p>Aid workers report a recent upsurge in fighting in eastern Burundi in line with the rebel movement, though army officials say the border area remains calm.</p>
<p>Rebels also fled south from Uvira and hid among tens of thousands of Burundian and Zairean refugees crossing Lake Tanganyika by boat for the Tanzanian port of Kigoma, the Burundian army said.</p>
<p>The number of refugees in Kigoma has doubled to more than 118,441 since the crisis in eastern Zaire and is increasing rapidly, UNHCR spokesman for Tanzania Vincent Parker said.</p>
<p>&quot;The rebels are on their way to Tanzania and we know that a number have arrived. Some have already arrived via the Lake to Kigoma among the refugees,&quot; Burundian army spokesman Lieutenant-Colonel Isaie Nibizi said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>The fall of the Uvira camps plus the fall of much larger camps Goma in North Kivu has dealt a severe blow to Hutu rebels now denied bases from which to attack Rwanda and Burundi. Around 150,000 people have died in Burundi's three-year civil war.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
