<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199341" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria to allow wide Commonwealth consultation.</title>
<headline>Nigeria to allow wide Commonwealth consultation.</headline>
<byline>Felix Onuah</byline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Commonwealth mission hoping to help Nigeria return to democracy will meet a wide group of society in Africa's most populous nation including traditional rulers and civil rights activists, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Details of meetings between the seven Commonwealth ministers with non-governmental groups were being worked out, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;They will see civil rights leaders, they will also be briefed by NECON (the electoral commission) and the Transitional Implementation Committee,&quot; said one foreign ministry official.</p>
<p>The committee is overseeing military ruler General Sani Abacha's transition to civilian rule programme under which he is to hand over to an elected president on October 1, 1998.</p>
<p>Nigeria was suspended from the Commonwealth last November when its military government defied an international plea for clemency and hanged nine minority rights activists including writer Ken Saro-Wiwa.</p>
<p>The club of Britain and its former colonies then set up the Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group (CMAG) to pressure Nigeria to restore democracy before the next biannual meeting of Commonwealth heads of state in Edinburgh, Scotland next year.</p>
<p>CMAG ministers, led by their chairman Zimbabwean Foreign Minister Stan Mudenge met behind closed doors with a 20-member Nigerian delegation led by Foreign Minister Tom Ikimi.</p>
<p>&quot;Nigeria considers the immediate lifting of her suspension from the Commonwealth as the only means for restoring confidence and mutual understanding between us and the Commonwealth,&quot; state radio quoted Ikimi as telling the opening session.</p>
<p>&quot;This meeting is being used to restate our position and the delegates should emphasise to the governments of the Commonwealth the need to rescind the decision of last November.&quot;</p>
<p>On the eve of the talks, the United Nations detailed gross human rights abuses in Nigeria, which has been in political turmoil since 1993 when the army annulled a presidential vote that would have established democratic rule.</p>
<p>The U.N. human rights report released in New York said Nigeria's military government has done little to stop summary executions, arbitrary arrests and systematic torture of political prisoners.</p>
<p>It gave a long list of lawyers, journalists, human rights advocates and politicians it said were killed, arrested without trial, tortured in prison or shot while demonstrating peacefully.</p>
<p>&quot;Between our suspension and now many detainees have been freed and it is crystal clear that the transition is on course,&quot; said Alex Akinyele, chairman of a government commission charged with reconciling Nigeria's aggrieved groups and a member of the official delegation to the meeting with CMAG.</p>
<p>The two sides met for the first time in May in London where Nigeria insisted its suspension was unfair and that until the issue was settled there could be no progress on other matters.</p>
<p>The CMAG team is without Canada which has taken a hard line against Nigeria's military government on the twin issues of rights abuses and democracy.</p>
<p>CMAG is made up of foreign ministers of Britain, Canada, New Zealand, South Africa, Zimbabwe, Ghana, Jamaica and Malaysia and its report will be submitted to the Commonwealth secretariat in London.</p>
<p>Nigeria's opposition appealed in an open memorandum to the CMAG ministers to press for the release of political detainees during the Abuja talks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
