<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199344" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>RWANDA: Rwanda says few refugees left in Zaire.</title>
<headline>Rwanda says few refugees left in Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>KIGALI 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwanda's foreign minister said on Tuesday a planned multinational force was no longer needed since there were hardly any refugees left in eastern Zaire, contrary to U.N. estimates that more than half a million remained.</p>
<p>&quot;These refugees who have returned home number 500,000 people, which broadly matches the real number of Rwandan refugees previously in eastern Zaire, in North and South Kivu,&quot; Foreign Minister Anastase Gasana said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not saying that there's not a single refugee in eastern Zaire,&quot; Gasana told a news conference. &quot;There could be a few who are tired and can't walk, but the great mass has returned.&quot;</p>
<p>Gasana's statistics bore no relation to figures provided by the United Nations and aid agencies.</p>
<p>The United Nations relief agency UNHCR says there were 1.1 million Rwandan Hutus and 150,000 Burundian Hutus in camps in eastern Zaire before the start of a rebellion by Zairean rebels last month which led to the mass return of Rwandan Hutus.</p>
<p>The UNHCR is the source for the estimated 500,000 returning refugees since November 15, but it and aid agencies on the ground say there are hundreds of thousands more Rwandan and Burundian refugees scattered in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>In his statement Gasana said Hutu refugees thought to be in Zaire's South Kivu province had pushed north because of the fighting and had concentrated in the Mugunga and Lac Vert camps in North Kivu, eventually joining the refugees from those camps in a mass return to Rwanda.</p>
<p>In Paris, Foreign Ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt said there were still 300,000 refugees in Bukavu and 200,000 in Uvira in South Kivu province and 200,000 near Goma in North Kivu.</p>
<p>&quot;The threat of an unprecedented humanitarian disaster remains. We must ensure the security of relief convoys,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gasana's statement repeated the Rwandan view that the original purpose of the force -- to help feed the refugees and clear a way for them to go home, if they wanted to -- had been rendered null and void by the voluntary return of the 500,000.</p>
<p>&quot;If a force were to come in, it would be coming in because it had another agenda, not a humanitarian one. Maybe it would be a political or military agenda, but not a humanitarian one,&quot; he told the news conference, declining to elaborate.</p>
<p>The Rwandan government wants the resources originally set aside for the armed intervention force to be used for humanitarian aid to resettle the returnees instead, he added.</p>
<p>About 14 countries who have pledged troops for the 10,000-strong force are due to meet in Germany on Thursday to review their plans in the wake of the mass Hutu return.</p>
<p>The Pentagon said the United States has tentatively decided not to send troops to Zaire and will instead use U.S. military cargo planes to fly humanitarian aid to Rwanda.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIGALI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RWANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
