<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199422" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: FEATURE-Ritual child murders poison eastern Nigeria.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Ritual child murders poison eastern Nigeria.</headline>
<byline>Matthew Tostevin</byline>
<dateline>OWERRI, Nigeria 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Revelations from an inquiry into the decapitation of a child for witchcraft purposes are tearing apart the eastern Nigerian town of Owerri.</p>
<p>A commission charged with looking into the murder is searching for evidence among 40 buildings destroyed in the riots which followed the discovery of the headless body.</p>
<p>Old poverty is pitted against new wealth, Pentecostal churches against the Roman Catholics and many families against the authorities they say did not act quickly enough to stop the kidnapping and murder of their children.</p>
<p>&quot;For now, the disappearances have stopped, but the criminals have only scattered and the children have been taken for ritual murder or sold into slave labour,&quot; said hospital doctor Darlington Amamasi.</p>
<p>Amamasi's son Obinna would be 10 years old now -- if he was still alive. He was abducted in April 1995 and has not been seen since, despite the fact that his father paid a ransom of $5,000 to the kidnappers.</p>
<p>Nobody gives an exact figure for the number of children who disappeared, but about Ikechukwu Okoronkwo there is no doubt.</p>
<p>The head of the 11-year-old groundnut hawker was found by police in September in the possession of a worker at a flashy hotel.</p>
<p>Exhumation of the body triggered two days of rioting in which all those who, like the hotel's owner, flaunted new wealth were targeted and their property burned.</p>
<p>The windows of offices and supermarkets belonging to the suspects were smashed. Smears of ash stretch up from the doors of what had been the town's grandest buildings.</p>
<p>&quot;People saw that a few years ago a new class of people arrived in town living ostentatiously -- we call them '419',&quot; said Modestus Unalaka, correspondent of The Champion newspaper.</p>
<p>The &quot;419&quot; is the section of the Nigerian criminal code dealing with a particular type of fraud, but is now used in Owerri to describe anyone who appears to have got their money through unorthodox means.</p>
<p>&quot;The newcomers could offer high rents and pay prices. They carried on like small gods, they could live their lives more cheaply, get their women more cheaply,&quot; said Unalaka.</p>
<p>The &quot;new faces&quot; were not really new. They came from Owerri but had made their money from other parts of Nigeria or overseas.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year, there were a lot of kidnappings, but it could not be proved that the big men were involved. This time the discovery of the corpse at the hotel was all the people needed to mete out their own justice,&quot; Unalaka said.</p>
<p>Parts of ritually killed people are said to be used in witchcraft by people trying to win power and influence.</p>
<p>Rioters accused some churches of playing a part in both the murders and the riots, generating religious strife as an added source of tension.</p>
<p>The rioters said they had found two human skulls and a pot containing pepper soup in the Pentecostal Overcomers Church.</p>
<p>The claims were debunked, but the Pentecostal Federation of Nigeria has accused Roman Catholics of whipping up youths to stamp out the growing influence of Pentecostal churches among largely Roman Catholic people.</p>
<p>The Roman Catholic Church denies the accusations.</p>
<p>Father Christopher Ejizu, at the archdiocese of neighbouring Onitsha town, said: &quot;The riots in Owerri were a social phenomenon and not a religious one. They were about people's anger at others getting rich too quickly.&quot;</p>
<p>It is not the job of the commission to put the accused on trial, which is what many in Owerri are now hoping for. But some of those accused by the mob have already left the area and nobody expects them to return quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;The departure of these people has big implications. Even if they pushed up rents, they were also big spenders. And if the people have driven them off, they will also have to live without their money,&quot; said Unalaka.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OWERRI, Nigeria"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
