<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199418" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FEATURE - South Africa edges towards new competition policy.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - South Africa edges towards new competition policy.</headline>
<byline>Paul Richardson</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's status as the economy with the most conglomerates in the world comes under the spotlight this month as debate begins on how to revamp the country's competition law.</p>
<p>Business, labour and government will square up to decide on how to deal with an economy dominated by a handful of firms through pyramid structures -- a system taken to task in the government's Reconstruction and Development Programme (RDP).</p>
<p>&quot;Through the country's pyramid system and the resultant control over a vast network of subsidiary companies, a small number of very large conglomerates now dominate the production, distribution and financial sectors,&quot; the RDP document said.</p>
<p>More than 70 percent of assets on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange are controlled by four groups -- Anglo American Corp, the Rembrandt Group, and mutual insurance giants Old Mutual and Sanlam, according to McGregor Information Services.</p>
<p>Deputy President Thabo Mbeki recently criticised this dominance as a deterrent to much-needed foreign investment.</p>
<p>&quot;They (foreign investors) simply find it difficult to access the South African market, which is dominated by big conglomerates that aren't too friendly to competitors,&quot; Mbeki said in an interview with Time magazine in September.</p>
<p>POLICY DOCUMENT TO BE DISCUSSED THIS MONTH</p>
<p>A discussion document on competition policy will be put to the National Economic Development and Labour Council (Nedlac) this month for debate by the council's three constituents -- government, labour and business -- while Trade and Industry Minister Alec Erwin drafts new legislation.</p>
<p>It has all been a long process. Changes to existing competition law were first mooted three years ago.</p>
<p>An attempt last year to redraft the 1979 Competition Act was rejected out of hand by Erwin's predecessor Trevor Manuel, who was reported to be incensed at the absence of measures to deal with the concentration of economic power in South Africa.</p>
<p>That draft proposed measures such as imposing fines on companies found guilty of anti-competitive behaviour and removing government from decision-making on anti-competitive behaviour. But it contained no measures that actively promoted the breakup of conglomerates.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a draft that made piecemeal amendments to the 1979 Act,&quot; said Ronald Roberts, an anti-trust specialist at the legal firm Moseneke &amp; Partners.</p>
<p>An expert close to the process of drafting the latest discussion document believes Erwin's approach to the debate marks a departure from his predecessor's aggressive stance.</p>
<p>&quot;Erwin's position is an attempt to scale competition law down to more realistic and attainable goals while looking more broadly at other areas of law,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>TRADE MINISTRY LOOKING AT WIDER REFORM</p>
<p>Erwin himself acknowledged this month that his department was looking at wider reform:</p>
<p>&quot;There is clearly a distinction between competition policy, which is a matter which can be affected by a wide range of legislation, and the competition law which is a body to achieve certain things, and you can't achieve everything with the law.&quot;</p>
<p>Officials who will take part in the debate are tight-lipped about the specific contents of the discussion document, apparently under Erwin's instruction.</p>
<p>But one proposal experts say will be included is an overhaul of the current Competition Board -- widely regarded as toothless -- giving it more powers to deal with anti-competitive behaviour and impose stiff penalties on those found guilty.</p>
<p>Current chairman Pierre Brooks, who has had little success in prosecuting anti-competitive cases and who was partly responsible for last year's draft, is not expected to continue in office.</p>
<p>A key difference between the latest document and last year's draft is that its authors are believed to have drawn on a variety of overseas examples.</p>
<p>The draft presented last year was described as favouring the European model of punishing anti-competitive behaviour.</p>
<p>The latest version is expected to draw on a several international models -- including British, Canadian and U.S. law -- but shy away from full-blooded U.S.-style anti-trust restrictions, which are rejected by business.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't mind strong competition policy, but it has to be balanced and it has to take cognisance of South African realities,&quot; says Stef Naude of Business South Africa. &quot;We are not a mature industrial society.&quot;</p>
<p>But Roberts believes the case for conglomerates is fading.</p>
<p>&quot;The argument that you have this highly competent, multi-talented head office staff which has a critical mass of executive skills in which it can feed down into a diverse range of activities has flopped,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The left-leaning National Institute for Economic Policy (NIEP) argues that the challenge for public policy is not only to prevent anti-competitive policies, but to restructure the economy to achieve social objectives.</p>
<p>&quot;The effects of the pyramid system are generally accepted to include excessive corporate inefficiency, disregard of minority shareholders, excessive political power, and racial/ethnic non-representivity,&quot; it says.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition, concentrated wealth and power lead easily to monopolistic or oligopolistic control of markets.&quot;</p>
<p>Business rejects this notion. Naude says competition policy cannot right past wrongs.</p>
<p>The blueprint for a new competition policy was laid out in the government's macro-economic strategy unveiled in June.</p>
<p>&quot;The main objectives of competition policy are to encourage competition among firms, protect consumers and downstream firms from restrictive practices, and to open up new investment opportunities.&quot;</p>
<p>Getting all sides to agree how to get there is likely to drag well into next year with a new competition bill unlikely to pass through parliament before the second quarter of 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
