<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199692" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine FIEL head sees Q4 GDP up 7.4 pct - daily.</title>
<headline>Argentine FIEL head sees Q4 GDP up 7.4 pct - daily.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Abel Viglione, the chief economist at Argentina's private FIEL consulting group predicted Tuesday growth of 7.4 percent in the fourth quarter.</p>
<p>In an interview with daily Ambito Financiero, Viglione expected gross domestic product growth of 7.4 percent in the last quarter of 1996 compared with provisional figures for the third quarter of 6.6 percent growth.</p>
<p>Viglione anticipated 3.2 percent growth for the whole of 1996, up from a slump of 4.6 percent last year.  </p>
<p>Viglione added that the engines of growth in 1997 will be the construction and auto sectors, which will post &quot;increases of more than 10 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The cycle which is starting now is more solid because it is based on investment and exports compared to the last one, which was driven by consumption,&quot; commented Viglione.</p>
<p>FIEL's chief economist said exports, which have risen 140 percent since 1989, should continue to grow sharply. &quot;There is no factor that can stop the trend of increasing exports.&quot;</p>
<p>Viglione recommended that once the recovery becomes more broad-based in coming months the government should cut taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;The Economy Ministry has to choose between lowering value added tax or reducing labor costs.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Axel Bugge, Buenos Aires Newsroom, 541 3180668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
