<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199631" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentine minister rejects Cavallo dishonesty slur.</title>
<headline>Argentine minister rejects Cavallo dishonesty slur.</headline>
<byline>Stephen Brown</byline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine Economy Minister Roque Fernandez defended his reputation on Tuesday against allegations by his predecessor, Domingo Cavallo, that he is &quot;not capable or not honest.&quot;</p>
<p>Cavallo, who is heading a crusade against corruption, lashed out at Fernandez on Monday for describing as &quot;normal&quot; a businessman Cavallo accuses of graft.</p>
<p>Cavallo, fired by President Carlos Menem in July after doing a widely praised job of reforming the Argentine economy, is battling in the courts with Alfredo Yabran, a businessman close to Menem, who he says heads a &quot;mafia&quot; in the customs and postal services. Yabran denies the accusations.</p>
<p>&quot;I have said that Fernandez was a capable and honest man. A capable and honest man does not commit these mistakes. One or the other, or he is not capable or he is not honest,&quot; the ex-minister told local television after Fernandez said he believed Yabran was a &quot;normal businessman.&quot;</p>
<p>Fernandez, who keeps a low profile and avoids controversy, made a restrained defense. &quot;Since August this year, when President Carlos Menem put me in charge of the Economy Ministry, I have known that what was expected of me was exactly what I know how to do: to work transparently, honestly and hard for Argentina and the Argentine people,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He expressed &quot;shock&quot; in a statement that Cavallo should make such allegations at a time when Argentina is pulling out of a deep recession following Mexico's late-1994 devaluation.</p>
<p>&quot;I am sure the Argentine people will know how to value seriousness and effort above noise that achieves nothing,&quot; the Chicago University-trained academic said.</p>
<p>Menem's Peronist government, which includes several senior officials who have also been accused by Cavallo and have threatened to sue him, rallied around Fernandez.</p>
<p>Cabinet Chief Jorge Rodriguez called Cavallo's comments &quot;regrettable&quot; and said: &quot;None of us should try to become the judges of our peers, whether we are in the cabinet or not, because that is what the courts are for.&quot;</p>
<p>But Cavallo is not the only ex-minister to accuse Menem's government of graft. Former Interior Minister Gustavo Beliz, once Menem's protege, refused before a judge on Monday to retract comments that Menem had &quot;no credibility&quot; to combat corruption.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
