<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199718" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Nov 20.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST - Australian General News - Nov 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Federal Cabinet has guaranteed vocational education and training funding to the states and territories worth over A$4.5 billion, clearing the way for Canberra's planned overhaul of the training system, which is hoped will give industry greater control and make the provision of training more competitive. Page 1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>A new study by Griffith University's Dean of Engineering and Applied Science, Professor Ralf Buckley, has found that less than a quarter of Australian resort projects in the past 15 years have been completed as planned, with many never realising their full economic goals. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Transport Minister John Sharp has urgently directed the Civil Aviation Safety Authority to investigate senior executive Robert Liddell's claims that internal budget cuts had put air safety at risk, following the resignation of Liddell over his concerns. Page 3.  </p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Queensland backbencher Alex Somlyay took the opportunity yesterday to tell Prime Minister John Howard and Treasurer Peter Costello that small business operators were growing impatient waiting for the benefits they expected from the new Government, when all they feel at the moment is the squeeze of weak economic activity. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN  </p>
<p>United States President Bill Clinton became only the third US head of State to come to Australia when he arrived in Sydney last night, where he was greeted with a full ceremonial welcome at sunset. Prime Minister John Howard is hoping the visit will emphasise Australia's upgraded relationship with Washington. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Tasmanian Director of Public Prosecutions Damian Bugg QC told the Tasmanian Supreme Court yesterday an amateur video showed Martin Bryant laughed as he killed 20 people within two minutes at Port Arthur on April 28 this year, in a rapid-fire  </p>
<p>rampage that could only be termed a slaughter. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A jointly-agreed paper entitled Commonwealth-State Financial Relations: Framework for Reform, prepared for the Council of Australian Governments meeting scheduled for last week, indicates all State Governments have agreed to pressure the Howard Government on the need for major tax reform. Page 3.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Deputy chief press secretary Geoff Crawford, an Australian former career diplomat, has been appointed to one of the most challenging public relations roles in Britain, as the Queen's chief press secretary. Crawford will take over the position from Charles Anson in January. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Speaking at the last of the Wood Royal Commission hearings, Police Commissioner Peter Ryan unveiled the most wide-ranging reforms of the New South Wales Police Service in its 134-year history, including plans to send sergeants back on street  </p>
<p>patrol, rostering inspectors around the clock and sacking police with criminal records. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Arriving in Sydney after a nine-hour flight from Honolulu, United States President Bill Clinton was greeted by Australia's heads of State amid much pomp, ceremony and security. Clinton then walked over to the spectator pen, where he greeted everyone he could reach with a handshake. Page 1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>The Tasmanian Supreme Court heard yesterday graphic details of Martin Bryant's massacre at Port Arthur, in which 35 people lost their lives. The court was also told Bryant had begun stockpiling an arsenal of high-powered weapons and ammunition in his house months before hand and that he had planned the murders. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A Graduate Careers Council of Australia study has found the salaries graduates command in their first full-time jobs out of university have fallen to a median of only A$27,000 a year - their lowest level in almost two decades - compared with the  </p>
<p>average weekly earning rate of A$33,900. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Tasmanian Supreme Court was told yesterday how Martin Bryant killed 35 people at Port Arthur on the 28 April. The court was told Bryant appeared to laugh aggressively as he murdered 12 people in 15 seconds at the beginning of his shooting rampage. Page A1.</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Labor MP Theo Theophanous was dumped yesterday by his Socialist Left faction, but said that he would continue to push for an overhaul of ALP policies. Theophanous has been a strong supporter of attempts by Victorian Opposition Leader John Brumby to revamp the party. Page A1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Only the third serving American President to visit Australia, William Jefferson Clinton and his wife Hillary enjoyed the crowds that greeted them in Sydney yesterday, taking the time out to shake hands with those lining the streets. Page A1.  </p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Victorian Premier Jeff Kennett has put his State at the forefront of electronic service delivery systems, yesterday announcing that NEC Australia and Aspect Computing would develop a system using software and hardware designed in Melbourne that will make p-aying water bills or checking driving demerit points as easy as surfing the Internet. Page A3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
