<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199874" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. shuttle crew board for liftoff.</title>
<headline>U.S. shuttle crew board for liftoff.</headline>
<byline>Steven Young</byline>
<dateline>CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Five astronauts boarded the shuttle Columbia on Tuesday for blastoff on a 16-day science mission that will include two satellite deployments and a pair of spacewalks.</p>
<p>The astronauts, wearing bright orange pressure suits, began taking their seats in the cockpit of the $2 billion spaceship shortly after noon EST (1700 GMT).</p>
<p>Columbia's crew includes Story Musgrave, who at 61 will become the oldest space traveller ever. This will be his sixth trip in orbit, matching the record held by veteran astronaut and moonwalker John Young.</p>
<p>Musgrave, known for his eccentricities, left astronaut quarters for the launch pad wearing his official name tag upside down.</p>
<p>The weather looked promising for the planned 2:53 p.m. EST (1953 GMT) liftoff from the launch pad at the Kennedy Space Centre. The mission had been delayed for 11 days by booster rocket problems and gusty winds but NASA meteorologists had given Tuesday an 80 percent chance of fair weather.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything looks really good,&quot; said U.S. Air Force meteorologist Captain Scott Jacobs. High winds had died down and there was only a slight chance low clouds would interfere with the countdown.</p>
<p>Launch pad workers loaded super-chilled liquid hydrogen and liquid oxygen rocket fuel aboard Columbia's giant rust-coloured fuel tank earlier on Tuesday. The three-hour operation was held up briefly when a leak of explosive hydrogen was detected in the shuttle's engine compartment, NASA spokesman Bruce Buckingham said.</p>
<p>But engineers quickly solved the problem and fuelling resumed shortly afterwards. &quot;We're moving right along,&quot; Buckingham said. &quot;There's no impact to launch.&quot;</p>
<p>Seven hours after blastoff Columbia's crew will release the first of two satellites, a U.S.-German space telescope. The orbiting observatory was to fly free for nearly two weeks before the shuttle returned to pick it up.</p>
<p>A second satellite will be dropped off to test an innovative process for manufacturing ultra-pure semiconductors for the electronics industry. It will orbit close to the shuttle for three days and also will be retrieved.</p>
<p>Astronauts Tom Jones and Tammy Jernigan will make two spacewalks to practice construction of NASA's planned international space station.</p>
<p>Columbia, NASA's oldest shuttle, is due to return to earth at the Kennedy Space Centre on Dec. 5.</p>
<p>In addition to Musgrave, Jones and Jernigan, the mission's all U.S. crew includes commander Ken Cockrell, who was making his third spaceflight, and pilot Kent Rominger.</p>
<p>Tuesday's launch procedure was the first to be carried out under a new, $7 billion, contract that places day-to-day running of the shuttle programme in the hands of a single company, United Space Alliance of Houston, a joint venture of Rockwell International Corp and Lockheed Martin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE CANAVERAL, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
