<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199821" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Thailand's Amnuay stresses need for good government.</title>
<headline>Thailand's Amnuay stresses need for good government.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thailand's caretaker deputy prime minister and foreign minister, who is considering an offer to join the new coalition government, said on Tuesday corruption is a losing proposition for Asian countries.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's their own affairs and they would realise that in order to make a good governance, to deliver the goods to the people...and to promote prosperity in their countries, they will have to have a good government,&quot; Amnuay Viravan told Reuters after speaking at a plenary session of the World Economic Forum.</p>
<p>&quot;Otherwise, you would be at the losing end because we are now in a competitive world and if you are operating at a higher cost -- either cost by the government or by the business -- then you cannot succeed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thai caretaker prime minister Banharn Silpa-archa was forced to resign and call elections after a no-confidence debate in which he and his party were accused of corruption and mismanagement. He won the debate but chose a week later to dissolve parliament for fresh elections.</p>
<p>Amnuay said issues of corruption had not been raised at meetings of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), which groups Brunei, Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Singapore, Thailand and Vietnam.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that this is something which has been really brought up to a formal discussion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Amnuay said on Monday he was considering an offer from the winning New Aspiration Party, which is expected to form the next government as part of a coalition, to take charge of Thailand's economic policy.</p>
<p>If he were to take the post, he said, it would be as an independent without party affiliations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
