<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="199968" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US CREDIT OUTLOOK-5-yr note sale, room for gains.</title>
<headline>US CREDIT OUTLOOK-5-yr note sale, room for gains.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Treasury's sale of $12.5 billion in five-year notes will be the focal point of government securities trading on Wednesday and a well-bid sale could spur bond prices to new highs, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The five-year auction will be the main event for the fixed-income market,&quot; said Kathy Bostjancic, money market analyst at UBS Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;People are focused on the five-year auction,&quot; said Anthony Karydakis, senior financial economist at First Chicago Capital Markets.  </p>
<p>Karydakis said the &quot;mild apprehension&quot; about Wednesday's five-year Treasury note auction was &quot;the main thing&quot; that held bonds back from a push to new highs on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Early in Wednesday's session, the market will get its only economic news for the day -- September international trade data. Economists polled by Reuters estimated, on average, that the U.S. trade gap narrowed to $9.5 billion in September from a $10.83 billion deficit in August.</p>
<p>But analysts said the trade data would make little difference to the bond market.  </p>
<p>&quot;A, it's old news; and B, it's impossible to interpret,&quot; said William Sullivan, senior vice president and head of fixed-income research at Dean Witter Reynolds Inc.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the trade report is of much relevance to the market,&quot; agreed Karydakis. &quot;In all likelihood, it will be a non-event.&quot;</p>
<p>Position adjusting before the five-year Treasury note auction will characterize the first half of Wednesday's trade, participants said. In late Tuesday trade, the five-year notes scheduled for sale on Wednesday at 1300 EST/1800 GMT were yielding 5.94 percent in when-issued trade.  </p>
<p>&quot;The (when-issued) yield can't go higher than six percent (on the five-year notes) because there would be tremendous interest at that level,&quot; said Sullivan. &quot;If it gets close to six percent, (the auction) is going to be as easy as selling an air conditioner in Miami in July.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders and analysts said a sharper than expected decline in October U.S. housing starts and negative readings on weekly surveys of chain and department store sales gave the market another lift on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no reason to think that Tuesday's bullish sentiment won't carry through on Wednesday,&quot; Bostjancic said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We should see some caution in the first part of the day,&quot; said Karydakis. &quot;Then, depending on how the auction goes, we'll accordingly have some price action that could send us to new highs.&quot;</p>
<p>Karydakis said once the market accomplishes another move to the upside, &quot;the next frontier will immediately be perceived as 6.25 percent for the bond (yield).</p>
<p>&quot;We may not go there in a straight line,&quot; said Karydakis, but once we show that we're still interested in exploring the upside, 6.25 percent will be on everyone's mind.&quot;  </p>
<p>In the next two weeks, there are few obstacles to block the market's current path, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a light calendar of economic data so there are not too many chances for disruptions in the next few days,&quot; said Karydakis.</p>
<p>&quot;Bonds have genuine support and since we lack a lot of quality statistics until the (November) payroll data in early December, the only area where we can take our cue from is the dollar and that has bounced back nicely,&quot; said Sullivan.</p>
<p>The 6-1/2 percent 30-year bond finished at 100-27/32, yielding 6.44 percent on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers indicated that Fed funds would open between 5-3/8 percent and 5-1/2 percent.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
