<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200046" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYCE cotton ends modestly higher, trade rangebound.</title>
<headline>NYCE cotton ends modestly higher, trade rangebound.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYCE cotton futures ended modestly higher but near the top of a recently established trading range between 75.00 and 71.50 cents a lb basis the most-active March contract, floor sources said.</p>
<p>March settled 0.03 cent higher at 74.10 after trading between 74.10 and 73.87. The balance added 0.05 to 0.25.</p>
<p>Aggressive trade selling capped an early short-covering rally which lifted the market to the top of its range at 75.00 in March, dealers said. But prices came off session highs by the close and are expected to drift lower during the week.</p>
<p>Locals were noted getting out of long positions and ran stops around 74.00 in March.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks weak. I think we'll go down to the bottom of the range in the next few days,&quot; a dealer said.</p>
<p>The speculator/hedge report said the speculators added 1,091 new short positions, bringing the total to 12,502 contracts.</p>
<p>Next Friday is the first notice day for the spot-December contract. Open interest fell only 1,562 lots to 12,115 lots.</p>
<p>Volume was estimated at 15,000 lots.</p>
<p>-- Suzanne Rostler, New York Commodities 212-859-1646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
