<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200196" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Euro Disney says no dividend despite profits.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Euro Disney says no dividend despite profits.</headline>
<byline>Christine Tierney</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Euro Disney reported a 77 percent jump in profits after drawing a record 11.7 million people to its Paris theme park in the past year, but the debt-laden company sounded a cautious note on Tuesday about the future.</p>
<p>Net income rose to 202 million French francs ($39.7 million) in the year to September 30 from 114 million a year earlier. A nine percent increase in revenues to five billion francs more than offset rising costs and finance charges on its 15.1 billion franc debt.</p>
<p>&quot;We've earned money for a second consecutive year,&quot; chairman Philippe Bourguignon told a news conference. &quot;The park is an enormous popular success.&quot;</p>
<p>But he said it had no plans to pay shareholders a dividend in the next two to three years. &quot;In the foreseeable future we prefer to use cash to pay down debt than to make dividend payments,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sluggish consumer spending, coupled with increases in financial costs, were clouding the outlook, particularly for the 1996/97 year begun on October 1, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Persistent weakness in the economy, constant pressure on our prices, and the strong increase in financial charges constitute several real challenges for the future, particularly in 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Euro Disney's stock, which rallied 7.5 percent on Monday ahead of the results, fell back to close on Tuesday at 11.40 francs, down 0.44 percent.</p>
<p>Traders said investors were taking profits after the results came in line with expectations.</p>
<p>Euro Disney, which lost more than seven billion francs in its first two years, emerged from the red for the first time last year after slashing entry prices and adding new attractions like the Space Mountain rollercoaster.</p>
<p>&quot;The management's turning it around reasonably well given the poor economy,&quot; said analyst Nick Bevan at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell. &quot;But there's a long way to go before people can start to feel truly comfortable.&quot;</p>
<p>The company's results contained a double irony. The nine percent rise in attendance confirmed that the Disney park, which had been predicted to flop in Europe, was a winner. Nearly a third of the visitors had been to the park before.</p>
<p>Theme park revenues increased nine percent to 2.7 billion francs, and hotel revenues increased 11 percent to 2.0 billion francs as occupancy rates rose to 72 percent from 68 percent.</p>
<p>On the other hand, a 1994 six-billion-franc financial restructuring hailed for having saved the company from collapse poses a challenge as charges suspended during a debt holiday are gradually phased in.</p>
<p>Lease and financial charges rose 103 million francs to 568 million in 1995/96. The company estimates they will rise by a further 200 million in 1996/97 and 100 million more in 1997/98.</p>
<p>From 1998/99, royalties and management fees to 39-percent U.S. owner The Walt Disney Co will also be reinstated.</p>
<p>But the weak spending climate in much of Europe limits Euro Disney's scope to raise prices to offset the rising charges.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not easy to improve year after year, but that's our plan,&quot; chief financial officer Xavier de Mezerac said.</p>
<p>The company's spending plans are prudent. Bourguignon said the company did not plan to invest in new attractions in the theme park this year.</p>
<p>This year it aims to maintain the momentum with a year-long celebration of its fifth anniversary, including the unveiling of a new castle at the park in January and a springtime festival.</p>
<p>It is proceeding with ambitious commercial and residential projects adjacent to the theme park but they will be financed mostly by third parties. Euro Disney has previously said that someday it plans to build a second Paris theme park. ($ = 5.083 French Francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97412">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C1511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
