<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200179" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek banks want interbank tax reconsidered.</title>
<headline>Greek banks want interbank tax reconsidered.</headline>
<byline>Dimitris Kontogiannis</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greek bankers warned the socialist government on Tuesday against imposing a planned withholding tax on interbank deals, saying it would send interest rates higher and hurt the sale of state securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The tax was hastily devised and should be reconsidered,&quot; said Nikos Sikiaridis, treasurer at Barclays Bank PLC. &quot;I have no doubt that it would negatively affect sales of FRNs, T-bills and other instruments if left intact.&quot;</p>
<p>The government announced the tax, effective from January 1, while unveiling some of its plans to raise revenues in its 1997 budget -- due by the end of this month.</p>
<p>Banks reacted angrily in the morning and refused to quote bid and offer rates for periods over one month in the interbank market, where banks lend money to each other.</p>
<p>The Hellenic Bank Association authorised its president, Theodore Karatzas, to consult with the government and the prime minister on Tuesday night, to try to sort out the mess.</p>
<p>&quot;Depending on what Karatzas tells us tomorrow, we will act,&quot; said a senior foreign banker. &quot;I expect to have no market at the opening.&quot;</p>
<p>Other senior bankers and traders said the government should explain whether the tax will be imposed on interest or net interbank transactions.</p>
<p>The government has also refrained from saying how much the tax will be or stating clearly whether it can be offset against the corporate tax which they already pay.</p>
<p>&quot;If the tax is imposed on interest on interbank deals, the result will be to increase the cost of borrowing for the state and put small banks at the mercy of larger banks with huge drachma deposits,&quot; said a senior official at a foreign bank.</p>
<p>Non-resident investors, whose funding costs for securities would go up because of the tax, could dump securities and send yields skyrocketing in the domestic secondary bond market. That could prompt foreign exchange outflows as well, he said.</p>
<p>Many questions relating to the tax were unclear, such as whether it would be levied on net income from interbank deals or on interest payments.</p>
<p>&quot;The government must understand that this is a serious matter that could have a domino effect on the economy and should be clarified quickly,&quot; said the banker, who requested anonymity.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be clarified if the tax will be netted against other bank corporate taxes. If not, it amounts to double taxation on Greek and foreign investors and will drastically raise their funding cost to purchase T-bills and FRNs,&quot; said the head of European money market trading at JP Morgan, London Peter Christodoulou.</p>
<p>&quot;The tax risks eliminating this customer base for the Greek state,&quot; he said. &quot;Lack of clarity is also not helping the market which at the moment is virtually frozen,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Other issues remained unresolved was when the tax would be calculated and whether banks with losses would be entitled to a refund.</p>
<p>&quot;The past history of the Greek state tells me that there will be no refund,&quot; said the senior foreign bank dealer.</p>
<p>Another negative effect could be a rise in interbank money rates and the possibility that some banks might reduce their base savings rates to restore profit margins.</p>
<p>Ecu/drachma was trading above 303.80 in late dealings from 303.73 at the central bank fixing.</p>
<p>&quot;There is confusion and light buying of ecus from abroad continues in alte trade,&quot; said a forex dealer at a foreign bank. --Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
