<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200214" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.S. vetoes candidacy of U.N. chief Boutros-Ghali.</title>
<headline>U.S. vetoes candidacy of U.N. chief Boutros-Ghali.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Tuesday stood alone in vetoing a second term for Boutros Boutros-Ghali as U.N. secretary-general while all other 14 members of the Security Council voted in favour.</p>
<p>The vote, at the request of the United States, was by secret ballot on a resolution sponsored by 10 of the 15 Security Council members. It would have put the 74-year-old Egyptian in office for another five years, until 2001.</p>
<p>Washington's veto was expected to open the way for other candidates to enter the race for a five-year term as secretary-general beginning January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>The council has agreed to give priority to candidates from Africa on the grounds that if Boutros-Ghali is denied the second term given his predecessors, he should at least be followed by another African.</p>
<p>But the vote also indicated how little support the United States had mustered since June, when it announced it would veto Boutros-Ghali, saying he was not strong enough on reforming the world body.</p>
<p>U.S. officials also argue that the Republican-dominated U.S. Congress will not provide the money needed to pay off $1.4 billion in U.S. dues to the United Nations unless Boutros-Ghali is replaced.</p>
<p>Many members, however, believe that Boutros-Ghali has been made a scapegoat for failures in U.S. foreign policy and Republican opposition to the world body.</p>
<p>The United States, Britain, France, Russia and China all have veto power on the council.</p>
<p>The purpose of the resolution was to put on record the council's overwhelming support for Boutros-Ghali and isolate the United States.</p>
<p>Washington has been criticised for using the New York Times to announce its opposition to Boutros-Ghali and for precipitating a financial crisis by refusing to pay the $1.4 billion it owes the United Nations.</p>
<p>If the council were unable to choose an African, the contest would eventually be thrown open to candidates from other parts of the world.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
