<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200231" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France denies it broke arms embargo to Hutus.</title>
<headline>France denies it broke arms embargo to Hutus.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>France denied on Tuesday reports that it supplied arms to the former Rwandan government after their genocide of one million mostly minority Tutsis in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;I clearly and absolutely deny it. Arms sales and arms contracts have ceased completely since April 8, 1994,&quot; Foreign Ministry spokesman Jacques Rummelhardt told a news briefing.</p>
<p>The United Nations decided an arms embargo on Rwanda in May 1994 after soldiers of the former Rwandan army and Hutu militia began slaughtering Tutsis.</p>
<p>Documents found by British reporters near the abandoned Hutu refugee camp in Goma, eastern Zaire, appeared to show that certain French companies had continued shipping arms to the Hutus.</p>
<p>&quot;The document found in the refugee camp is a document offering a service. It was never agreed. The delivery was never carried out,&quot; Rummelhardt said.</p>
<p>According to a still unpublished U.N. report on arms shipments to Zaire, a copy of which was obtained earlier this month by Reuters, Rwandan Hutu rebels have been amply supplied with arms from Europe and South Africa.</p>
<p>The report, prepared for the U.N. Security Council by a four-man, U.N.-appointed Commission of Inquiry, is part of a series documenting violations of the arms embargo.</p>
<p>After the killings, a million Hutus fled to eastern Zaire, including soldiers and militia. The crisis escalated recently when ethnic Tutsis in Zaire fought the Zairean army, with the refugees caught in the crossfire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
