<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200383" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Poland says no quick free tract pact with Russia.</title>
<headline>Poland says no quick free tract pact with Russia.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland wants to liberalise trade with Russia but cannot sign a free trade agreement with Moscow soon because it is not a member of the World Trade Organisation (WTO), Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot rule it out (signing free trade agreement with Russia), but it would have to be subject to negotiations that would not be easy and short,&quot; said Cimoszwicz, who last week visited Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;We have our standards of signing such agreements and these include a WTO membership,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said that under a joint declaration on trade liberalisation he had signed in Russia, the two countries' experts would work until March next year to lay the groundwork for further talks on the issue.</p>
<p>Cimoszewicz said any trade relaxation with Russia would be discussed with the European Union, which Poland wants to join at the start of the next century.</p>
<p>Trade between Poland and Russia collapsed in 1990 after the fall of communism but has begun to grow in the last few years. It is forecast to rise by about $1 billion in 1996 to $4 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
