<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200680" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Unigate half year profits edge higher.</title>
<headline>Unigate half year profits edge higher.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>British dairy and distribution company Unigate Plc posted a slight increase in half-year profits on Tuesday, helped by its acquisition of Kraft's European margarine and spreads business in August.</p>
<p>Pretax profits in the half year to September 30 were up 0.3 percent at 60.6 million pounds ($101.1 million), compared with stockmarket forecasts in a range of 57 to 59 million. Unigate's European foods business, which includes Kraft, reported a 3.1 million increase in trading profits to 44.1 million.</p>
<p>&quot;These results reflect good progress in integrating the recent acquisitions as well as tight control of costs and were achieved despite weaker world prices for butter and milk powder products,&quot; said chief executive Ross Bucland.</p>
<p>Unigate's dairy business reported profits down 2.9 million pounds at 17.6 million due to lower prices for butter and milk powders which Unigate estimated cost it about 4.0 million in the period. But from October 1 Unigate said it has seen a small reduction in raw milk prices.</p>
<p>The company recommended a half year dividend of 7.0 pence per share, an increase of 5.3 percent. Unigate shares were up 2-1/2p at 431p in early trade.</p>
<p>Unigate, which acquired Kraft's European margarine and spreads business in August for some 77 million pounds, reported net cash held of 57.9 million at September 30.</p>
<p>The group sold its U.S. restaurant business Black-eyed Pea for 42 million pounds in July.</p>
<p>Since the half year the company has completed its exit from the U.S. restaurant business with the sale of Taco Bueno and Casa Bonita for 27 million pounds, enabling Unigate to focus on developing its core European food and distribution business.</p>
<p>The company also sold its minority stake in Dutch food company Nutricia for 360 million in January.Cash at the bank and in hand amounted to 292 million at the half-year stage and finance director John Worby told Reuters the company was actively seeking acquisitions.</p>
<p>($1=.5994 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
