<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200698" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egyptian tourism keeps booming in September.</title>
<headline>Egyptian tourism keeps booming in September.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tourism to Egypt continued to boom in September, pushing the figures up towards what is likely to be a record year for the industry.</p>
<p>About 367,000 people visited the country in September, compared with 311,000 in the same month of 1995, the cabinet office said in statistics available on Tuesday.</p>
<p>It was below 387,000 people in August, but August is the peak tourist period because of summer holidays in Europe, the main source of tourists to Egypt.</p>
<p>The cumulative total for the first nine months of the year is 2.822 million visitors, against 2.271 million at the same stage last year, the statistics show.</p>
<p>Receipts from tourism, based on the number of nights tourists stay and their nationalities, were $428.5 million, up on $364.5 million in August because people stayed longer.</p>
<p>An official in the cabinet office said receipts in the first nine months of 1996 amounted to $2.463 billion, compared with $1.998 billion in the same period of 1995.</p>
<p>The years 1995 and 1992 were close rivals for the title of record year for tourism to Egypt, at about three million visitors each. In the intervening the industry suffered from attacks on tourists by Islamist militants.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
