<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200832" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German banks seek to cash in on Telekom follow-up.</title>
<headline>German banks seek to cash in on Telekom follow-up.</headline>
<byline>Hans Obermeier</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following the successful first phase of the Deutsche Telekom flotation on Monday, the tug-of-war between Germany's banks for lucrative follow-up business has kicked off in earnest.</p>
<p>Many private investors received only a fraction of the shares they applied for in Germany's major telecommunications company. This leaves billions of marks, originally earmarked for Telekom shares, lying in bank vaults.</p>
<p>Investment groups and credit institutions are now trying to harness this surplus capital by offering new investment opportunities, including special offers and new telecoms funds.</p>
<p>At the same time, banking experts have urged investors to be cautious.</p>
<p>&quot;Not every product is right for every investor,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Although only 930 million marks ($618.5 million) worth of Telekom stock was issued to private investors, Commerzbank had total orders from the would-be individual shareholders worth around 2.8 billion marks.</p>
<p>Dresdner Bank, one of the flotation's global coordinators, said around two billion marks of money allocated for Telekom investment is still sitting in bank accounts.</p>
<p>While Dresdner said it is recommending that its customers continue to buy Telekom shares, its main focus is to get its customers interested in investment funds.</p>
<p>The Deka umbrella group of savings banks on Tuesday issued a telecoms-media fund, composed of companies like Deutsche Telekom, AT&amp;T and Mannesmann, and is recommending that its customers round off their telecoms portfolios with the fund.</p>
<p>Union Investment launched the AMF Communication Fund, which is made up of communications stocks and which the company sees as an investment alternative to Telekom shares.</p>
<p>Union managing director Gerhard Langenbach said his company would not try to buy more Deutsche Telekom shares in the near future.</p>
<p>The Adig group is offering investors special conditions to invest in its technology funds before the end of the year. Other banks and fund management companies are making similar offers.</p>
<p>Credit institutions often prefer to sell funds to private customers, rather than individual shares, as administrating individual shares, paying out dividends and sorting out tax returns, is expensive for the banks.</p>
<p>At the same time, the small investors themselves are often happier with funds than they are with individual shares.</p>
<p>Someone holding 100 Telekom shares who cashes them in to get a forecast pre-tax dividend of 60 marks in 1997, will have to pay a hefty portion of the payout in charges to the bank. Just how much depends on the institution.</p>
<p>As far as funds are concerned, the devil is in the detail. Not only can there be a mark-up of up to five percent on the buying price at entry, but there can also be charges for administration or charges from the custodian bank.</p>
<p>Banking experts say it is also important for the private investor to examine a fund's investment management policy.</p>
<p>Commerzbank spokesman Peter Pietsch said: &quot;For an investor who pays relatively little tax, it is hardly worthwhile investing in a fund that optimises their tax situation.&quot;</p>
<p>For risk-conscious investors, many German banks are offering options on Deutsche Telekom shares. For a small premium, these give investors the chance to buy Telekom stocks at a particular price within a given timeframe.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($1=1.5034 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
