<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200823" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Mobile phones push Mannesmann sales.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Mobile phones push Mannesmann sales.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>German engineering group Mannesmann AG said on Tuesday it expected a slight improvement in its operating results for the full year after reporting better nine-month sales.</p>
<p>Sales rose to 23.9 billion marks ($15.90 billion) from 22.6 billion. Order intake was unchanged at 27 billion marks, with changes in group consolidation resulting in a one percent drop in the figure.</p>
<p>Mannesmann gave no profit figure, but said the &quot;favourable development of group earnings&quot; was mainly attributable to its telecommunications and automotive operations. Its traditional engineering and tubes businesses posted weaker results.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a case of a massive improvement in telecoms offsetting a poor market in German engineering,&quot; said analyst Alan Coats at Merrill Lynch in London.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not changed our view, which is neutral in the short term, and positive in the longer term,&quot; he said. &quot;But there is good reason to see a downside for earnings. The third quarter was a bad quarter in European engineering and the fourth quarter doesn't look any better.&quot;</p>
<p>Mannesmann Mobilfunk's D2 German mobile telephone network boosted earnings, but start-up losses in its fixed-line businesses increased.</p>
<p>Mobile phone sales jumped to three billion marks from 1.9 billion, with the number of D2 subscribers increasing to 2.1 million at the end of September. Customer growth outstripped the first nine months of 1995 by 63 percent.</p>
<p>Some analysts said D2 sales were disappointing, and the share price came under pressure as a result.</p>
<p>Shares in Mannesmann fell to a low of 620 marks before rebounding by midday to 621.50, down one mark on the day. The DAX index of 30 leading shares was slightly firmer.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks like the net additions to its (D2 mobile telephone) network in the third quarter disappointed because they were lower than in the preceding quarters,&quot; Niall O'Connor, analyst at CS First Boston in London said.</p>
<p>This could have been compounded by concern over the impact on margins of a new lower pricing policy for its telecom service.</p>
<p>&quot;But it should not be too worrying in the long-term,&quot; he said, noting that price erosion in mobile telephony was an expected and normal development.</p>
<p>Coats said Mannesmann posed a lot of questions as restructuring costs on the negative side were balanced against asset sales on the positive.</p>
<p>Mannesmann's workforce had fallen by 3,000 to 120,000 people, the company said. ($1=1.5034 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
