<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200820" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Eight in hospital after Channel Tunnel blaze.</title>
<headline>Eight in hospital after Channel Tunnel blaze.</headline>
<byline>Olivier Hamoir</byline>
<dateline>CALAIS, France 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eight people were taken to hospital after fire broke out on a train carrying trucks through the Channel Tunnel, the first big accident since the opening of the Anglo-French link two years ago, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There were...big macho drivers and I think that every single one of them was praying to God,&quot; said driver Jeff Waghorn, aged 32 from Essex, east England who was among those trapped by choking fumes in the blaze on Monday night.</p>
<p>Franco-British Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel, trying to shake off a litany of breakdowns, cost over-runs and huge debts, said it hoped to resume partial service on Tuesday afternoon through the 51-km (32-mile) tunnel.</p>
<p>Seventy fire-fighters from Britain and France, in special breathing suits, put out the blaze aboard the England-bound freight train after an all-night battle, a first test of systems designed to counter everything from earthquakes to guerrillas.</p>
<p>The 34 truck drivers and train crew were evacuated from toxic fumes after a blaze apparently broke out in a truck. Unconfirmed reports said it was carrying polystyrene.</p>
<p>Eight people were taken to hospital, two of them in serious condition including the train driver. The other 26 were checked for lung damage after inhaling toxic fumes in the accident 17 km (10 miles) from the French mouth of the tunnel.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel said the rescue went smoothly -- and that all were out of the stricken train within 28 minutes of it stopping. Some drivers faulted a lack of breathing gear and sprinklers.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody was moaning on the floor, lying on the floor. One pregnant lady was getting pretty hysterical,&quot; said Ian Edmonds, 33, a British lorry driver. &quot;I sat in the corner preparing to die. I thought I was a goner.&quot;</p>
<p>Eurotunnel shares, which peaked at 130 francs ($25.5) in 1989 on optimism for the first fixed link between Britain and mainland Europe since the Ice Age, fell 0.15 franc ($0.3) to 7.65 ($1.5) in Paris in early afternoon.</p>
<p>Passengers were being re-routed on Tuesday via the Channel Tunnel's arch rivals, ferries and planes.</p>
<p>French SNCF state railways said passengers using a combination of buses and ferries between Paris and London would get ticket refunds because the trip took seven hours, far longer than the usual three-hour service.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to be running Eurostars and freight in the course of the afternoon on a single line,&quot; said Annabel Salmon, a Eurotunnel spokeswoman in Paris.</p>
<p>Shuttle services for cars, like trucks loaded aboard trains at Calais or Folkestone, would be the last to resume, not before Wednesday at the earliest. The tunnel comprises three parallel tunnels -- two for trains, one for maintenance and emergencies.</p>
<p>Salmon said wiring and electrical cables were damaged in the fire but that it was impossible to say how long repairs might last. The stricken train was still blocked in the tunnel.</p>
<p>The cause of the fire, which gutted six trucks aboard the train, was unknown. A French legal probe would be opened.</p>
<p>The freight shuttle train, used to transport trucks and their drivers, was halted and evacuated between nine and 10 p.m. (same GMT).</p>
<p>The fire broke out towards the back of the 730-metre (yard) long train, which has locomotives at both front and back and can carry up to 28 large trucks.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the first time the tunnel has been closed for an emergency. We have had safety drills in the past but this is the first real event,&quot; a Eurotunnel spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>More than 20 fire appliances gathered at the British end of the tunnel near Folkestone and up to six French fire engines were reported at Calais.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALAIS, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
