<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200835" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy ex-premiers Berlusconi, Craxi to go on trial.</title>
<headline>Italy ex-premiers Berlusconi, Craxi to go on trial.</headline>
<byline>Malcolm Whittaker</byline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Italian prime ministers Silvio Berlusconi and Bettino Craxi go on trial for corruption on Thursday in a showcase hearing widely seen as a test of credibility for Milan's elite anti-graft magistrates.</p>
<p>The &quot;Clean Hands&quot; anti-graft team have been under attack for waging a witch-hunt against Italy's establishment. The team's symbol, ex-magistrate Antonio Di Pietro, resigned from the government last week after himself coming under investigation for alleged malpractice.</p>
<p>Berlusconi, billionaire boss of the Fininvest media empire, is accused of acquiescing in payments by his company of 10 billion lire ($6.5 million) alleged to have been channelled to Craxi through a Fininvest-linked off-shore company, All Iberian, and various Swiss bank accounts.</p>
<p>Judicial sources said Thursday's trial against a total of 12 defendants will probably be immediately adjourned until January because the court's case calendar is already full.</p>
<p>Berlusconi's lawyers maintain the operation was a regular payment for television rights bought from Franco-Tunisian film producer Tareq ben Ammar, who has been asked to testify.</p>
<p>The media mogul, prime minister for seven stormy months in 1994, is leader of the centre-right Freedom Alliance coalition which was defeated in a general election in April this year.</p>
<p>Italian magistrates are also investigating a wider aspect of alleged Fininvest slush funds. Masses of documents relating to this enquiry were recently handed over to Milan magistrates by Britain's Serious Fraud Office after a six-month legal battle.</p>
<p>According to a London High Court judgement, the documents had brought to light some 100 billion lire &quot;surreptitiously removed from Fininvest and used for criminal purposes&quot;, also including the money channelled through All Iberian.</p>
<p>The trial will start just days after Di Pietro's resignation as Minister of Public Works in Prime Minister Romano Prodi's centre-left government, which won the April election.</p>
<p>Di Pietro said in an open letter to Prodi that people were attacking him to undermine his former magistrate colleagues who have been under fire for alleged abuse of their powers.</p>
<p>He quit the magistrature in December 1994 amid rumours he had been forced out but emerged with his reputation intact this April from allegations of corruption and abuse of office that were thrown out of court. He then joined Prodi's government.</p>
<p>Di Pietro and his supporters believe a string of investigations against his former colleagues of the anti-graft pool are part of a vendetta by players in the Tangentopoli (Bribesville) scandals he and his team exposed.</p>
<p>Together with Berlusconi's former defence minister, Cesare Previti, Berlusconi's brother Paolo, already convicted for corruption in another Clean Hands case, is on trial in the northern city of Brescia accused of involvement in a plot to force Di Pietro to resign from the magistrature.</p>
<p>Berlusconi, already on trial in Milan on a separate charge of alleged complicity in the payment of Fininvest bribes to tax inspectors, is also accused of false accounting, a more serious offence than that of illegally financing political parties.</p>
<p>Former Socialist leader Craxi, charged with receiving the illegal funds, lives in self-imposed exile in Tunisia.</p>
<p>Italy's highest court of appeal last week confirmed a five and a half year prison sentence against Craxi for illegal party financing, meaning he would go to jail if he returned to Italy.</p>
<p>Premier from 1983 to 1987, Craxi has appeals pending against three other court convictions for which he has been sentenced to jail terms totalling a further 20 years and three months.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
