<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="200982" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan OKs $200 million in foreign telecom investments.</title>
<headline>Taiwan OKs $200 million in foreign telecom investments.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI, Taiwan</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan approved three foreign-led telecommunications ventures Tuesday, including one led by a unit of AT&amp;T Corp., to invest a combined $200 million in the island's fast-liberalising telecommunications market.</p>
<p>The Economics Ministry's investment commission approved a plan by AT&amp;T Wireless Services of Taiwan and partner Cheung Hing Development Ltd to invest $65.46 million.</p>
<p>It also approved a plan by Sweden's Telia Overseas AB to invest $58.18 million, a ministry statement said.</p>
<p>The ministry also gave a go-ahead to Hong Kong-based New World Telephone Ltd., a unit of New World Development Co. Ltd., to invest $76.36 million in local value-added telecommunication services.</p>
<p>These can include Internet services, airline reservations systems and teleconferencing.</p>
<p>Reforms passed in January give unprecedented though still limited access to the market by foreign interests, which had long been barred outright from telecom operations.</p>
<p>Foreigners now can own up to 20 percent of any Taiwan firm offering common-carrier services, a ratio design to ensure local control.</p>
<p>Foreign companies are free to own and operate value-added services.</p>
<p>Taiwan is also reviewing bids by 17 consortiums, including one led by AT&amp;T, to operate eight lucrative mobile telephone franchises, with a decision expected by year's end.</p>
<p>Tuesday's approvals were not directly related to that competition.</p>
<p>Mobile telephone service is one of several telecom sectors liberalised by parliament in January, opening them up for private and limited foreign investments.</p>
<p>Before the reforms, telephone, data and other telecom services had been monopolised by the government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI, Taiwan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
