<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201118" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Ingwe aims to make CMAL a coal force.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Ingwe aims to make CMAL a coal force.</headline>
<byline>Michael Byrnes</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African-based Ingwe Coal Corp Ltd plans to make just-acquired Coal Mines Australia Ltd (CMAL) one of the biggest coal producers and exporters in Australia, the world's largest coal export nation.</p>
<p>Ingwe, which paid A$230 million in acquisition costs and recapitalisation expenditure for CMAL in a deal completed last week, said it would boost the Australian company's production to 20 million tonnes a year within the next ten years.  </p>
<p>CMAL is presently a medium-sized operation producing four million tonnes of saleable coal a year from its two ventures in the Newcastle-Hunter Valley districts of New South Wales.</p>
<p>It expects to produce five million tonnes in 1997.</p>
<p>At 20 million tonnes a year, CMAL would rival Australian output from the country's second-biggest producer, worldwide mining giant RTZ Corp Plc-CRA Ltd, and put itself in the topline producing category dominated by The Broken Hill Pty Co Ltd (BHP).  </p>
<p>In the year to May 31 1996, BHP produced 26 million tonnes of metallurgical coal and 22 million tonnes of thermal coal, while RTZ-CRA produced 22 million tonnes of coal of all types from its Australian operations in 1995.</p>
<p>A CMAL official confirmed that Ingwe's aim of boosting CMAL production to 20 million tonnes a year was based on expanded output from existing operations.</p>
<p>Ingwe's executive chairman, Mick Davis, is yet to reveal how massive production expansion will be achieved at CMAL, but has stated the South African group was attracted to buy CMAL largely because of its significant growth plans and opportunities.  </p>
<p>Ingwe itself produces 60 million tonnes of steaming coal a year from 12 mines in South Africa and is the largest exporter of steaming coal in the world. It is currently the world's third-largest publicly-owned steaming coal producer.</p>
<p>Ingwe's acquisition of CMAL brings to a halt the Australian company's planned A$300 million float to the Australian Stock Exchange, until recently planned for November this year. But the absorption of CMAL into Ingwe will give the Australian company added international marketing clout, company officials said.  </p>
<p>BHP, as the world's largest single exporter of coal would continue to hold leading clout in dealing with buyers such as the Japanese, they said.</p>
<p>Ingwe announced last Friday that it had completed its acquisition of CMAL by buying 96.3 percent of the company's shares from AMP Investments Australia Ltd for A$85.4 million and the remaining 3.7 percent from existing CMAL management on similar terms.</p>
<p>As part of the acquisition Ingwe is injecting more than A$100 million in new equity to recapitalise the company and allow it to meet capital expenditure commitments.  </p>
<p>These were associated with substantial planned increases in production at Bayswater No. 3 and Moonee mines, Ingwe said.</p>
<p>CMAL's main projects are the 80 percent-owned Wallarah Coal Joint Venture, comprising the Wallarah, Chain Valley and Moonee underground mines and the 85.5 percent-owned Bayswater Colliery Joint Venture, comprising Bayswater No. 2 and No. 3 mines in the Huinter Valley near Muswellbrook.</p>
<p>The company also holds a 42 percent interest in the Wyong Areas Coal Joint Venture which was awarded the right to explore and develop the Wyong Development Areas in October 1995.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
