<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20121" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - Aug 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - Aug 28.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Walt Disney Co's ABC network has bought an 11-title package of theatrical films from Time Warner Inc's Warner Brothers studio, Daily Variety reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They include three that still haven't hit the theaters yet: &quot;Sleepers,&quot; with Brad Pitt, Robert De Niro and Dustin Hoffman; &quot;Michael Collins,&quot; with Liam Neeson and Julia Roberts; and &quot;The Glimmer Man,&quot; with Steven Seagal and Keenen Ivory Wayans.</p>
<p>The deal, which also includes &quot;Tin Cup&quot; and the 1991 &quot;Ricochet,&quot; is only the latest example of a buying frenzy for theatrical movies that has swept the broadcast networks.</p>
<p>The newspaper also reported:</p>
<p>* General Electric Co's NBC has captured its 12th straight weeklong prime-time Nielsens victory, prevailing in the August 19-25 results.</p>
<p>* J.P. Morgan &amp; Co Inc's hopes of advancing its foothold in the banking side of Hollywood may rest on the outcome of a meeting of commercial bankers held Tuesday afternoon to consider the syndication of Morgan's $800 million bank loan to the team acquiring Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Inc.</p>
<p>* Faye Dunaway will star as opera diva Maria Callas in the national company of Terrence McNally's &quot;Master Class&quot; and in any feature film eventually made of the play.</p>
<p>* Theater marquees in more than two dozen cities dimmed Tuesday night in memory of Bernard B. Jacobs, president and co-CEO of the Shubert Organization and a central figure in New York's theater community for four decades. Jacobs died Thursday from complications following heart bypass surgery. He was 80.</p>
<p>* The 53rd Venice International Film Festival kicks off Wednesday with a high-voltage shot of star power setting the tone.</p>
<p>* Barry Diller's much talked-about &quot;sizzle&quot; among investors fizzled out Tuesday as investors dumped stock both in his Silver King Communications Inc and in Home Shopping Network Inc, which Silver King is planning to buy.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
