<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201246" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Sumitomo copper sales plunge on trading scandal.</title>
<headline>Sumitomo copper sales plunge on trading scandal.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Sumitomo Corp said on Tuesday its refined copper sales in the first half of the 1996/97 business year ending in March plunged to 181.2 billion yen ($1.63 billion), in the wake of a major copper scandal.</p>
<p>This is down by 243.3 billion yen ($2.19 billion) or 57 percent against the same period of the previous year.</p>
<p>&quot;Since (former chief trader) Hamanaka was dismissed in June, we've being handling only necessary copper business such as long term contracts,&quot; Sumitomo executive vice president Takehiko Yonezu told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no plan to withdraw from the copper business at the moment, but are working out future strategy at the non-ferrous metal department,&quot; Yonezu said.</p>
<p>Before Sumitomo fired him in mid-June of this year, Yasuo Hamanaka was considered the most influential and controversial player in the world copper market.</p>
<p>It has blamed Hamanaka for racking up estimated losses of $2.6 billion from unauthorised copper trading, and this has been called the world's biggest-ever loss on financial markets.</p>
<p>Hamanaka was recently arrested on suspicion of fraud and forgery in connection with those trades.</p>
<p>Sumitomo recorded a net loss in the April-September half of 212.12 billion yen ($1.91 billion) on a consolidated basis, reflecting the impact of its copper losses. The firm expected a consolidated net loss of 147 billion yen ($1.32 billion) for the full business year.</p>
<p>Asked about its trading policy at the London Metal Exchange (LME), Sumitomo's Yonezu said: &quot;Our copper trading at the LME was cut drastically (after the scandal broke out). But we can't carry out metal business without it.&quot;</p>
<p>Another Sumitomo official said, at a separate news conference, the firm expected copper sales in the full 1996/97 business year to be less than 300 billion yen ($2.7 billion).</p>
<p>The giant trade house also dismissed a market rumour that it was involved with an alleged unrecorded stockpile of as much as 500,000 tonnes of copper in Rotterdam warehouses.</p>
<p>Asked about a report last week on the possible stockpile in Europe, Yonezu said: &quot;I have read the reports... It is not us.&quot;</p>
<p>The World Bureau of Metal Statistics (WBMS) released a report last week stating that statistics from 1990 to 1995 suggested a stockpile of 500,000 tonnes of copper may have been built up in Rotterdam during that time.</p>
<p>Traders were sceptical of the report, although some speculated such a stockpile could be connected with Hamanaka.</p>
<p>Hamanaka was thought by many traders to have amassed a huge amount of physical copper that he used to prop up world prices.</p>
<p>Many traders have speculated that he kept copper prices artificially high in recent years through skillful use of complex derivatives transactions and his iron grip on a large portion of copper stocks in London Metal Exchange warehouses.</p>
<p>&quot;We're fully cooperating with overseas authorities for probing the price manipulation allegations. But I can't tell you the details about it at this stage,&quot; Yonezu said.</p>
<p>Late last month, the general manager of Sumitomo's legal department said they have found no evidence that Hamanaka manipulated the world copper market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22460">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
