<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201298" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Sumitomo plans copper changes - Taiwan division.</title>
<headline>Sumitomo plans copper changes - Taiwan division.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Sumitomo Corp has plans to restructure its Asian copper business, but its Taiwan copper division does not intend to cut back on its staff or operations, a Sumitomo official in Taipei said.</p>
<p>&quot;Sumitomo has plans to restructure its copper business, but the Taiwan division will not be affected,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>She declined to comment on the wider plans in detail, but confirmed that Sumitomo was likely to pull out of Thailand in the restructuring effort.</p>
<p>&quot;Sumitomo may have to pull out of Thailand due to market size, cost and other considerations,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>Earlier on Tuesday the chief executive officer of Bangkok Cable Co. told Reuters in Tokyo that Sumitomo would not be supplying any copper cathodes to Thailand next year.</p>
<p>Taiwan industry sources said Sumitomo's reputation remained good in the country and the company continued to maintain a key role in the island's copper market.</p>
<p>&quot;Sumitomo is a highly reputable company here,&quot; a Minchali Metal executive said, adding that Sumitomo was a major if not the largest supplier in Taiwan.</p>
<p>The executive declined to estimate Sumitomo's market share.  </p>
<p>Taiwan is on track to import about 500,000 tonnes of copper in 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
