<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201201" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Economic jitters help Singapore stocks close weak.</title>
<headline>Economic jitters help Singapore stocks close weak.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore shares closed lower on Tuesday, reflecting some uncertainty over the state of the local economy, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the government is optimistic about our economy, the man in the street and in business is more cautious and this is beginning to filter through into the markets,&quot; said one dealer at a local broking house.</p>
<p>The key Straits Times Industrials (STI) index ended off 7.85 points at 2,170.18, after a quiet day's trading. Total volume was only 111.93 million shares with 136 gainers and 172 losers.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very quiet, even for Singapore,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>An off-market sale of 13.3 million Keppel Engineering shares to its sister company Far East Levingston Shipbuilding was the day's dominant trade in volume terms. Keppel Engineering ended up 10 cents at Singapore $1.54.</p>
<p>Snack food firm Want Want Holdings also saw 6.15 million shares crossed off-market, helping the shares rise three cents to a day high of US$2.50.</p>
<p>Dealers said institutions were sidelined after buying in the wake of interim results which pushed prices up in recent weeks. Few saw any immediate upturn in the STI index.</p>
<p>-- Nick Edwards, Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
