<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20152" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Copenhagen Zoo puts Homo Sapiens on display.</title>
<headline>Copenhagen Zoo puts Homo Sapiens on display.</headline>
<byline>Steve Weizman</byline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>In what it says is a unique experiment, Denmark's Copenhagen Zoo has added two new primates to its collection of baboons, orang-utangs, chimps and lemurs -- a local couple representing Homo Sapiens.</p>
<p>Living out their daily lives in a perspex-walled mini-apartment between the baboons and a pair of ruffed lemurs, acrobat Henrik Lehmann and newspaper employee Malene Botoft say they hope to make visiting humans think about themselves and their origins.</p>
<p>&quot;The most visited animals in the zoo, apart from the predators, are the apes, because we see in them something of ourselves. This puts that similarity into context,&quot; Lehmann told Reuters on Wednesday over a beer in the couple's small but cosy air-conditioned enclosure.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a mirror, you can look at yourself,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Lehmann and Botoft moved in last Sunday, doing much of the installation work themselves.</p>
<p>&quot;We were near fainting from exhaustion and I could hardly get up but I made a cup of coffee with warm milk,&quot; Botoft wrote in her diary, published in the Danish daily Berlingske Tidended, where she works as a secretary and motorcycle writer.</p>
<p>&quot;I drank it on the sofa and ate a meatball with cheese while people looked at us. Henrik slept,&quot; she wrote.</p>
<p>They will remain on display until September 15.</p>
<p>The neighbours, particularly the baboons, she finds entertaining during the day but the lemurs next door are an annoyance at night.</p>
<p>&quot;There are only two of them but they make a noise as if they were at least 30. Exactly once every hour they mark their territory with uninhibited screaming,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the enclosure, complete with a standard zoo label giving details of Homo Sapiens' habitat, diet and other key statistics, was surrounded by enthusiastic children and slightly more reticent adults.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's cool,&quot; said 10-year-old Peter Hansen.</p>
<p>&quot;It's certainly an interesting idea,&quot; his mother added.</p>
<p>Lehmann said that adults seem to feel more comfortable looking at &quot;the real apes&quot;, where they are uninhibited by social conventions against staring, while children have no reservations about pressing their noses against the humans' perspex walls.</p>
<p>He said he is frequently asked if the couple intend to publicly display the more intimate areas of human activity, but said that was not their intention as &quot;it's not interesting&quot;.</p>
<p>The enclosure has a combined kitchen-living room, an adjoining bedroom and a small workshop where Lehmann works at his passion -- restoring classic British motorcycles.</p>
<p>It also boasts a sofa, chairs, bookshelves and other typical features of the human habitat; fax, computer, television, stereo and telephone.</p>
<p>Toilet and washing facilities are in a nearby zoo building.</p>
<p>Zoo information official Peter Vestergaard said that the Homo Sapiens display was partly for fun but, like Lehmann, he hoped it could also encourage people to confront their origins.</p>
<p>&quot;We are all primates. (Lehmann and Botoft) are monkeys in a way but some people find that hard to accept. This is a way to maybe help people realise that,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
