<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201677" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR: World market November 18, 1996</p>
<p>Raw sugar futures in London ended mixed amid a dearth of fresh fundamental news. The March contract ended at $303.10 per tonne, up $0.90 from Friday with other positions mixed. In New York raw sugar futures closed near the highs but below key resistance pegged at 10.50 cents/lb basis March. Traders said the contract will need to pierce the key level in order to rack up future gains since it twice reached but failed to take out 10.50 in March, last week. However, slack physical offtake continues to plague the market. Symptomatic is China's restrained buying policy, which has put Thai premiums under pressure. Without fresh physical demand, there is no great chance for a recovery.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>CHINA - China imported 15,300 tonnes of sugar, raw value, in October 1996 down from 133,000 tonnes imported the previous month and 288,200 tonnes imported in October 1995. This brought total imports in the first two months of 1996/97 up to 148,300 tonnes down from 569,100 tonnes the same two months in 1995/96. Exports in October reached 36,300 tonnes, raw value, down from 102,200 tonnes exported in September and 64,500 tonnes exported in October 1995. This brought exports in the first two months of 1996/97 up to 138,500 tonnes up from 96,900 tonnes exported the same two months in 1995.</p>
<p>USA - Two US consumer groups called on the Food and Drug Administration to conduct a new safety review of the sweetener aspartame. This comes in response to an recent study which suggests a connection between rising rates of brain cancer in the US in the 1980s and aspartame. The study in the November issue of the Journal of Neuropathology and Experimental Neurology said the rise of brain cancer in the 1980s was not a &quot;fleeting phenomenon.&quot; The study said brain cancers increased by about 10 per cent, corresponding to 1,500 new brain-cancer cases annually, following the introduction of aspartame into US foods and beverages in 1981 and 1983, respectively. Tom Pirko, president of Bevmark Inc., a soft- drink-industry consultant said according to press reports that this could rock the entire diet-drink business.</p>
<p>ED&amp;F Man - Trade house ED&amp;F Man in its latest sugar report raised its estimate of EU sugar production in 1996/97 by almost 300,000 tonnes to 15.63 million tonnes, white value, up 300,000 tonnes from the September estimate of 15.34 million tonnes after a late boost from favourable weather. Production in 1995/96 was put at 15.61 million tonnes.</p>
<p>BRAZIL - Sugar production in October 1996 reached 2.233 million tonnes, raw value, up from 1.867 million tonnes produced the previous month and 1.881 million tonnes produced in October 1995. This brought total production in May/October 1996 up to 11.316 million tonnes, up from 9.972 million tonnes produced the same period in 1995. Total production in crop year 1995/96 (May/April) reached 13.636 million tonnes up from 12.598 million tonnes produced in 1994/95.</p>
<p>POLAND - Poland imported 77,032 tonnes of sugar, raw value, in September/June 1995/96 up from an estimated 66,223 tonnes imported the same period 1994/95. Total imports in crop year 1994/95 are estimated at 100,248 tonnes sharply up from the 1993/94 figure of 2,729 tonnes. Exports in September/June 1995/96 were only 3,092 tonnes compared to 14,569 tonnes the same period in 1994/95. Total exports in 1994/95 (September/August) dropped sharply to 14,828 tonnes down from 217,000 tonnes the previous year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
