<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201682" id="root" date="1996-11-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: 34 evacuated from Channel Tunnel freight fire.</title>
<headline>34 evacuated from Channel Tunnel freight fire.</headline>
<byline>Olivier Hamoir</byline>
<dateline>CALAIS, France 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A fire inside the Channel Tunnel aboard a train carrying trucks forced the evacuation of 34 people and put eight of them in hospital suffering from smoke inhalation, two in serious condition, officials said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The accident late on Monday, which forced the closure of the tunnel, was the worst since the 51-km (32-mile) undersea rail link opened two years ago.</p>
<p>A total of eight people, most of them truck drivers, were taken to hospital and given treatment for varying degrees of smoke inhalation after the fire spread from a lorry towards the back of a freight train running towards Britain late on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The two most affected are railway staff, including the train guard, who both stayed behind to help evacuate the others,&quot; Mady Chabrier, spokeswoman for Franco-British operator Eurotunnel SA Plc, told Reuters.</p>
<p>The two were taken by helicopter to hospital in Lille (near Calais) but their lives were not in danger, she said. Six passengers were hospitalised in Calais and 26 others were placed under medical surveillance after inhaling the smoke.</p>
<p>After a night-long struggle, fire-fighters from both sides of the Channel in special breathing gear brought the fire under control 17 kms (10 miles) from the French mouth of the tunnel.</p>
<p>A few isolated patches were still smouldering in the morning however, hours after the train was halted and evacuated between 9 and 10 p.m. (same GMT) on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Officials said they could not confirm a French television report that the blaze started in a truck carrying a load of inflamable polystyrene.</p>
<p>&quot;The fire started on the lorry a third of the way into the tunnel. It spread to other trucks and the locomotive at the back of the train, cutting the electricity supply,&quot; Alain Bertrand, Eurotunnel's development director, told Europe-1 radio.</p>
<p>The French state-owned railway SNCF said Eurostar passenger express services between Paris and London were suspended as was the Le Shuttle service for trucks and cars between Calais in France and Folkstone on the British side.</p>
<p>Officials hoped to reopen the tunnel during the day after removing the damaged train. Passengers booked on cancelled services were offered seats on planes or ferries.</p>
<p>All the truck drivers, who were riding in a lounge car in the shuttle, were evacuated initially through a service tunnel. The first fire-fighters arrived within about 10 minutes.</p>
<p>&quot;Firefighters are basically having to feel their way along the tunnel and they can only stay down there for a maximum of 10 minutes before we have to bring them back because of the heat,&quot; said commander Bill Welsh of the Kent County fire brigade.</p>
<p>&quot;The heat is so intense and all the lights have gone out and there is falling debris everywhere but crews on both sides are working very well together,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A legal probe would be opened in France into the blaze, the latest in a series of woes for the tunnel, dogged by cost over-runs and fierce competition from ferries.</p>
<p>&quot;The fire is under control but the train is still too hot. We hope to pull it out later today. We could use a parallel tunnel but for now it is being used by firemen,&quot; Chabrier said.</p>
<p>When reopened, the tunnel would be reduced for a while to a single track from its normal twin north-south tracks.</p>
<p>The fire started at the back of the 730 metre (yard) long train, which has locomotives at front and back and was carrying 29 trucks, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the first time the tunnel has been closed for an emergency. We have had safety drills in the past but this is the first real event,&quot; a Eurotunnel spokeswoman in London said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALAIS, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
