<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201960" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAFRICA RESERVE BANK TO STREAMLINE FX ADMIN - PAPER.</title>
<headline>SAFRICA RESERVE BANK TO STREAMLINE FX ADMIN - PAPER.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reserve Bank deputy governor Timothy Thalane has announced a major overhaul of the Bank's administration of exchange controls to remove red tape and facilitate deals,  Business Day newspaper reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>At the Islamic Bank in Johannesburg, Thalane also said he hoped government would be able to hasten the scrapping of exchange controls by implementing its macroeconomic policy package as soon as possible.</p>
<p>Deregulation of the administration of exchange controls would be a phased process, with banks being given the authority to take routine decisions formerly handled by the Bank, he said.</p>
<p>He stressed that the Bank would be flexible on the remaining controls.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to make the remaining controls as esay as possible and are open to discussion. We hope government's progress (on the macroeconomic strategy) will make it possible to remove them as quickly as possible&quot;.</p>
<p>The Bank wanted to cut the decision-making time &quot;very short&quot; and wanted to create a more efficient and less &quot;bothersome&quot; system of administering controls.</p>
<p>&quot;This means the dealers will have to know the rules. If, on inspection, we find the rules have been broken, it would be serious&quot;.</p>
<p>The changes contemplated could not be implemented overnight as banks needed to build capacity. Meetings had been held with authorised foreign exchange dealers to inform them of the Bank's new approach to administration.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
