<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="201914" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: SOCCER-ROSENBORG BEAT GOTHENBURG TO KEEP EUROPEAN HOPES ALIVE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ROSENBORG BEAT GOTHENBURG TO KEEP EUROPEAN HOPES ALIVE.</headline>
<dateline>TRONDHEIM, Norway 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Midfielder Bent Skammelsrud scored a penalty to lead Norway's Rosenborg to a 1-0 victory over IFK Gothenburg of Sweden on Wednesday and keep their hopes of a European Cup quarter-final place alive.</p>
<p>Rosenborg are third in Group D of the European Champions' League with six points, seven behind Porto and one behind AC Milan with one round of matches still to come.</p>
<p>Skammelsrud was the dominating player of a match played on a pitch kept green by under-soil heating while snow covered the surrounding field.</p>
<p>He fired the penalty past veteran Swedish international goalkeeper Thomas Ravelli in the 66th minute after Niclas Alexandersson was sent off for stopping handling the ball on the goal line.</p>
<p>It was Rosenborg's second Champions' League win over Gothenburg, following their 3-2 victory in Sweden in September and put paid to Gothenburg's chances of reaching the quarter-finals. Gothenburg's best chance came in the 73rd minute when Peter Eriksson had only Ravelli to beat but shot wide.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TRONDHEIM, Norway"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
