<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202049" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products mostly steady, fuel oil firm.</title>
<headline>Med oil products mostly steady, fuel oil firm.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Med oil products were mostly steady on Wednesday but fuel oil was firmer amid good cold-weather transatlantic demand, traders said.</p>
<p>Gas oil was dominated by talk that Turkish state oil company Tupras had awarded five or more cargoes of 25,000 tonnes each of 0.5 percent sulphur gas oil for December. Traders had understood earlier that only four cargoes would be awarded.</p>
<p>Heating oil premiums were seen around high fob +$3.50/4.00 basis Genoa and around fob high +$4 for low sulphur diesel.</p>
<p>Demand came from France and Spain for 0.2 percent sulphur and low sulphur for Dec delivery from France, Spain and Italy.</p>
<p>But the focus of the market remained the east Med with firm news of tenders awaited from Turkey and Greece.</p>
<p>Gasoline was steady with some interest seen from the U.S. for lower quality grades, where an oversupply has weighed on both low and high octane supplies.Demand for lower octane came from eastern Mediterranean destinations, including Turkey.</p>
<p>Naphtha was steady to firm, tracking firmer NWE prices where an arbitrage window was seen opening to the U.S.</p>
<p>Traders said naphtha was supported by news Algeria's Skikda port closed on Tuesday and it was unclear when it would reopen.</p>
<p>High sulphur fuel oil was firm.</p>
<p>Bids from a trader, who has already moved product across the Atlantic from NWE, were at $110 fob Lavera for high density barrels. Dec Med cargo swaps were traded at $112.50 fob Med.</p>
<p>Low sulphur markets were firm too. An Italian utility this week has bought a Cameroonian straight-run cargo from a trader, as well as a 50,000 tonne cracked cargo out of Rotterdam at $10 over the quoted fob NWE high. The utility has also bought from a trader who holds 50,000 tonnes out of western Sweden.</p>
<p>&quot;They have been hoovering it up,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Fixed-price offers out of ARA were heard close to $130/$131 fob NWE.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
