<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202006" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: ALGERIAN HELD IN BELGIUM GIVEN MONTH TO LEAVE.</title>
<headline>ALGERIAN HELD IN BELGIUM GIVEN MONTH TO LEAVE.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Algerian Ahmed ZAOUI, convicted in Belgium of playing a central role in a criminal network here, was moved into house arrest on Wednesday and given one month to find a country that would accept him.</p>
<p>Zaoui, a member of the Algerian Islamic Salvation Front, was sentenced to four years in prison in November 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very difficult for me,&quot; he told RTL Television, denying claims by Belgian authorities that he is a leading member of the militant Armed Islamic Group GIA. &quot;I don't know what to do. I don't know where to go.&quot;</p>
<p>Zaoui and several other North Africans were tried on charges which included possession of forged documents and illegal possession and transportation of arms and explosives.</p>
<p>Most of the sentence was suspended, technically freeing Zaoui, but the Belgian Interior Ministry has kept him in jail while his request for political ayslum was being processed on the grounds that he is a potential danger to the public.</p>
<p>GIA has claimed responsibility for killing hundreds of people in the wave of violence which has swept Algeria since early 1992, when the authorities cancelled a general election in which the banned FIS took a huge lead.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
