<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202179" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: South African business laments Bank rate increase.</title>
<headline>South African business laments Bank rate increase.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's key business federation Sacob lamented a one point Bank rate hike as a &quot;severe blow&quot; to economic prospects in the short term, and urged the government to act urgently to induce market confidence.</p>
<p>&quot;While Sacob appreciates the reasons for this step, the rise in interest rates at this time will have a negative effect on business and consumer confidence, will tend to reduce sales and generally put a dampener on economic activity,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The central Reserve Bank announceed earlier on Wednesday it was increasing its key Bank rate to 17 percent from 16 percent, effective from November 21.</p>
<p>Sacob said the move created doubts that a forecast five percent real increase in retail sales over the Christmas period would now be achieved.</p>
<p>Consumers and the small business sector would suffer most because of the increased cost of borrowing resulting from a rise in lending rates, Sacob added.</p>
<p>Given the background reasons for the Reserve Bank's decision, Sacob said the government needed to inject a greater sense of urgency into the implementation of its growth, employment and redistribution strategy (GEAR).</p>
<p>&quot;Until such times as a more comprehensive package of confidence-building measures is introduced in accordance with the macro-economic strategy...there is a danger that the latest measures will prove insufficient in addressing foreign and local investor perceptions.&quot;</p>
<p>Sacob said progress with privatisation, deficit reduction and the removal of the remaining exchange controls in line with the macro-economic strategy was needed to counter balance of payment constraints and inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
