<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202215" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria plays carrot-and-stick with Commonwealth.</title>
<headline>Nigeria plays carrot-and-stick with Commonwealth.</headline>
<byline>Felix Onuah</byline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria's military government is using a carrot-and-stick appraoch in talks with a Commonwealth team seeking to nudge the country towards democracy and respect for human rights, sources at the talks said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The government on Tuesday freed three political activists held without a charge for nearly a year while blasting leading Commonwealth members Britain and Canada for their &quot;anti-Nigeria stance.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is a classic carrot-and-stick approach, freedom for dissidents to appease us and attack on some of our members,&quot; said a senior member of the mission who asked not to be named.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commonwealth is already split over Nigeria and it is obvious that the aim of the Nigerians is to maintain this split into the next summit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The next summit of the 53-member club of Britain and its former colonies is due to be held in Edinburgh, Scotland next year and Nigeria will be high on the agenda.</p>
<p>Africa's most populous nation is treated as a pariah for alleged human rights abuses and last year's hanging of nine minority rights activists including writer Ken Saro-Wiwa, which caused its suspension from the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>The eight-member Commonwealth Ministerial Action Group (CMAG) was then set up to pressure Nigeria to restore civil rule and respect human rights in line with the Commonwealth's Harare declaration on good governance.</p>
<p>Nigeria says the two-day Abuja meeting, which will end on Wednesday, is a continuation of contacts with the Commonwealth which Nigeria hopes will lead to its readmission to the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>During a meeting with CMAG ministers on Tuesday, Foreign Minister Tom Ikimi launched a blistering attack on Canada for pulling out of the CMAG visit, accusing it of trying to destabilise Nigeria.</p>
<p>&quot;We have overwhelming evidence that both at home in Canada and as well as here in Nigeria, Canada is providing substantial financial assistance to agencies and individuals working for the destabilisation of our country,&quot; Ikimi told the opening session.</p>
<p>Canada pulled out of the meeting at the last minute in protest against the non-issuance of visas to two officials it said were to provide security to its delegation.</p>
<p>But Ikimi said &quot;Canada tried to bring in armed soldiers as part of its delegation to this CMAG under the guise that they are diplomats.&quot;</p>
<p>Canada has been pushing hard for the Commonwealth to take tough action against Abuja on human rights and democracy.</p>
<p>Ikimi also attacked Britain, saying remarks by British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind in a London television programme that Nigeria could be expelled from the Commonwealth, were provocative.</p>
<p>The CMAG ministers met military ruler General Sani Abacha late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Although it was a courtesy call, the meeting went quite well,&quot; Zimbabwean Foreign Minister Stan Mudenge told Reuters, adding: &quot;We are progressing well, no hitches yet.&quot;</p>
<p>Tuesday's release of the three activists still leaves a number of government opponents in detention, including Moshood Abiola, the presumed winner of a 1993 presidential election whose annulment plunged Nigeria into political turmoil.</p>
<p>Nigeria wants its suspension to be lifted, a decision that can only be taken by the Commonwealth summit on recommendation of CMAG, which is made up of foreign ministers of Zimbabwe, Ghana, New Zealand, Jamaica, Britain, South Africa, Malaysia and Canada.</p>
<p>The CMAG ministers were being briefed on Wednesday by the electoral and the body implementing Abacha's programme to restore democracy in 1998, a period considered too long by his critics as well as the Commonwealth.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
