<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202542" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Amoco wants Venezuela tax rule clarified.</title>
<headline>Amoco wants Venezuela tax rule clarified.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Value-added tax and dollar accounting procedures for profit-sharing contracts in new oil areas in Venezuela must be clarified soon to avoid jeopardising the process.</p>
<p>&quot;VAT and dollar accounting need to be resolved. These are very serious issues,&quot; Amoco President William Lowrie told reporters after addressing an oil conference in Caracas.</p>
<p>Lowrie said failure to resolve the issues could see Amoco and other foreign majors freeze investment in areas purchased by auction in January. &quot;We were told that these things would be taken care of,&quot; Lowrie said.  </p>
<p>Lowrie was referring to a law approved by Venezuela's congress in July. While the law exempts companies from paying a 16.5 percent tax on the start-up costs of capital intensive projects, the enabling mechanism that supported it was left unformulated and remains hanging.</p>
<p>Dollar accounting means oil companies will not be taxed on unrealised income during the pre-operative stage of exploration and drilling projects.</p>
<p>Under current Venezuelan accounting practices, the value of assets are written-up to keep in line with inflation. The gain in value is then taxed.  </p>
<p>Venezuelan inflation over the past 12 months has been over 100 percent.</p>
<p>In January, Amoco acquired interests in two Venezuelan oil blocks, Punta Pescador and Guarapiche. Lowrie noted tax conditions were tough with rates of up to 90 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The terms and conditions in Venezuela, quite honestly, are tough and its going to take large discoveries to make these economics work,&quot; he said. But he added that Amcoco's operations in Venezuela would &quot;add value to shareholders&quot; and that &quot;when a company like Amoco looks at a country like Venezuela it doesn't just look at the fiscal situation.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Paul Hughes, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
