<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202567" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Three consortia to compete for Brazil's Cerj.</title>
<headline>Three consortia to compete for Brazil's Cerj.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three consortia will be participating in today's privatization auction of Rio de Janeiro state's power firm Companhia de Eletricidade do Estado do Rio de Janeiro (Cerj), a state planning department spokesman said.</p>
<p>The state is selling off its 78 percent stake in Cerj, with 10 percent of the stake going to Cerj employees and the remaining 70.2 percent of total Cerj share capital being sold in a closed envelope auction for a minimum price of 464.7 million reais ($451.2 million).</p>
<p>Recently privatized electricity firm Light is leading one consortium which includes Electricite de France (EDF), Houston Industries Brazil and AES, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Privatized power utility Escelsa heads the second one with GTD Participacoes e Servicos and Iven.</p>
<p>Chilean power firm Chilectra leads the third one which includes Spain's Endesa and Electricidade de Portugal (EDF).</p>
<p>Up to 10 million reais of Cerj's sale price can be paid in privatization bonds, the rest in cash. The buyers of the controlling stake in Cerj will have to make a public offer, giving Cerj's minority shareholders the option to sell their stakes for the auction price.</p>
<p>Cerj, which is the first of Rio de Janeiro state's companies to be privatized, supplies 75 percent of the state's electricity and serves around 1.2 million customers.  </p>
<p>Rio de Janeiro is the first of Brazil's states to privatize one of its public sector companies, and the state has included 21 of 26 state-owned companies in its privatization program which is expected to generate $5 billion overall.</p>
<p>State bank Banco do Estado do Rio de Janeiro (Banerj is next in line with the privatization auction expected to take place in the first two weeks of December.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
