<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202663" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Argyle, Gannett to swap TV stations.</title>
<headline>Argyle, Gannett to swap TV stations.</headline>
<dateline>SAN ANTONIO, Texas 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argyle Television Inc said on Wednesday that it has entered into a definitive agreement to swap two television affiliates with Gannett Co Inc.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Argyle will swap its WZZM-TV, ABC affiliate in Grand Rapids, Mich., and WGRZ-TV, BNC affiliate in Buffalo, N.Y., for Gannett's WLWT-TV, NBC affiliate in Cincinnati and KOCO-TV, ABC affiliate in Oklahoma City.</p>
<p>Argyle Chairman and Chief Executive Bob Marbut said in a statement the deal allows Gannett to comply with a divestiture order from the Federal Communications Commission.  </p>
<p>Marbut added the deal would allow Argyle to increase its NBC-related broadcast cash flow and increase total market advertising revenues. He added that it would give the company a &quot;growing ABC market with no competing ABC affiliate.&quot;</p>
<p>As part of its acquisition of Multimedia Inc MMEDC.O in December 1995, Gannett acquired WLWT in Cincinnati, where it owns the Cincinnati Enquirer newspaper, and certain cable systems in Oklahoma City, where it owned KOCO.</p>
<p>Gannett received a temporary waiver from the FCC of rules barring cross-ownership of television properties and daily newspapers in the same market. That waiver is set to expire in December 1996. The deal with Argyle is designed to resolve the cross-ownership issues. It is expected to close in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN ANTONIO, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
