<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202791" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: D'Amato says concerned about new OCC bank rule.</title>
<headline>D'Amato says concerned about new OCC bank rule.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Senate Banking Committee Chairman Alfonse D'Amato said he was &quot;deeply troubled and concerned&quot; over a new bank regulation finalized Wednesday by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency.</p>
<p>The New York Republican issued a statement saying the rule would allow certain banks to expand into securities and insurance underwriting, data processing and real estate sales.</p>
<p>The rule &quot;may subject federally insured banks to excessive risks and expose the bank insurance funds, and therefore taxpayers, to unnecessary liability,&quot; he said in a statement.  </p>
<p>House Banking Committee Chairman James Leach, R-Iowa, in a statement said elements of the new OCC regulations were a step toward &quot;common-sense bank moderinization.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added, &quot;it is conjectural whether the courts will pass muster on such sweeping regulatory discretion or whether the Comptroller's actions will have the effect of precipitating or retarding a more comprehensive legislative approach.&quot;</p>
<p>The American Council of Life Insurance said it would &quot;mount a major effort&quot; to block the OCC action. The American Bankers Association's securities association praised the rule.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
