<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202821" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GTE sees resale deals soon.</title>
<headline>GTE sees resale deals soon.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>GTE Corp said on Wednesday it expects to cement new resale deals to allow it to offer long distance services over the networks of other carriers.</p>
<p>&quot;We're negotiating several of these as we speak,&quot; said Rob McCoy, president of GTE's Long Distance Services</p>
<p>GTE already uses WorldCom Inc to carry its long distance voice traffic but has additional needs to carry high speed data, too.  </p>
<p>McCoy, addressing an investor conference, did not say which companies GTE was likely to choose but said that AT&amp;T Corp, MCI Communications Corp and Sprint Corp had responded enthusiastically.</p>
<p>&quot;The big three were the most aggressive respondents,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>MCI already supplies GTE with calling card hardware and software, while AT&amp;T has been the biggest target for GTE's assault on the consumer long distance market.  </p>
<p>McCoy said that GTE's long distance unit expected to break even in the final quarter of 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We're expecting the fourth quarter of 1998, with a positive contribution for the full year of 1999,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>McCoy said that GTE has 650,000 long distance customers and expects it to rise to 750,000 by the end of this year.</p>
<p>He noted that AT&amp;T and other rivals had tried very hard to win back GTE's new customers but said that 30 percent of those who left GTE were immediately won back by an aggressive follow up campaign.  </p>
<p>McCoy said that they were aiming for a customer that would spend an average of $25 a month on long distance and so far customers were spending $17.30 and rising fast. He predicted that bills would rise further as more customer emerged from the first few promotional weeks of GTE service.</p>
<p>He said that churn -- the porportion of customers leaving -- was at the moment higher than the industry average but this was of course because the customer base was relatively small and new to the company and he predicted that it would fall.  </p>
<p>&quot;The danger zone is the first 30 or 45 days when AT&amp;T comes back aggressive,&quot; McCoy said.</p>
<p>-- Nick Louth, 212 859 1612</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
