<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202842" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kmart cost cuts bring $9 million Q3 profit.</title>
<headline>Kmart cost cuts bring $9 million Q3 profit.</headline>
<dateline>TROY, Mich. 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Using cost cuts to offset flat same-store sales, discount retail giant Kmart Corp. Wednesday reported a $9 million third-quarter profit, compared with a year-ago loss of $69 million.</p>
<p>The results, equal to 2 cents a share, slightly exceeded Wall Street analysts' consensus expectation that the company would break even during the third quarter.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Kmart shares lost 25 cents to $10.875 in morning trading the New York Stock Exchange, where it was the most heavily traded issue.</p>
<p>The stock was driven up $1.625 on Tuesday by rumors that Kmart was the target of a possible takeover by leveraged buyout specialists Kohlberg Kravis Roberts &amp; Co. Kmart and KKR declined to comment on the rumors.</p>
<p>Kmart Chairman Floyd Hall and Warren Flick, president and chief operating officer of U.S. Kmart stores, were scheduled to appear later Wednesday in New York City at the opening of the retailer's second Manhattan store.</p>
<p>In a statement, Hall said Kmart is &quot;beginning to see meaningful progress toward a recovery.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;While much work still needs to be done, we are encouraged by our progress in executing our merchandising and operational initiatives through the first nine months of 1996,&quot; Hall said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our biggest challenge of the year lies just ahead in the fourth quarter, and we remain cautiously optimistic about our near-term outlook.&quot;</p>
<p>Kmart's total revenues for the quarter fell 1.6 percent to $7.85 billion. Company-wide sales at stores opened at least a year rose 0.1 percent from a year ago and same-store sales for U.S. Kmart stores increased 0.8 percent.</p>
<p>Hall said revenues did not meet the company's growth expectations for the period, but savings from store closings, outsourcing of certain functions and other costs cuts resulted in a $370 million reduction in Kmart's year-to-date selling and administrative expenses.</p>
<p>But Kmart's gross margin rate for the third quarter increased to 22.6 percent of sales from 21.2 percent last year, reflecting fewer markdowns related to the clearance of aged inventory and a lower level of overall promotional activity, Kmart said.</p>
<p>Kmart, the second largest retailer in the U.S., operates 2,143 Kmart and 168 Builders Square retail outlets, and operates 129 stores internationally.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROY, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
