<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202880" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Confident Clinton takes up foreign policy priority.</title>
<headline>Confident Clinton takes up foreign policy priority.</headline>
<byline>Laurence McQuillan</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A clear message is emerging from U.S. President Bill Clinton's first overseas trip since re-election -- having once shied away from foreign issues he plans to make the Asia-Pacifc a top priority in his second term.</p>
<p>Clinton's 12-day trip, built around the annual 18-member Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) leaders summit next week in the Philippines, has been designed to combine some leisurely relaxation with a serious message.</p>
<p>After arriving in Australia on Tuesday, Clinton's opening public remark of his Asia trip on Wednesday focused squarely on Washington's commitment to the region.</p>
<p>&quot;Everywhere I go, I will...deliver again a simple, loud and clear message -- the United States is more determined than ever to create an Asian Pacific community of shared efforts, shared benefits and shared destiny,&quot; Clinton told the Australian parliament on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Four years ago, when Clinton entered the White House after 12 years as governor of mostly rural Arkansas, he was cautious when dealing with diplomatic matters -- prefering to concentrate on the domestic issues that he understood better.</p>
<p>His first trip to Asia as president, in July 1993, took him to the annual gathering of the G-7 leaders of the seven major industrial nations -- which took place in Tokyo.</p>
<p>He appeared tentative as the junior member of that group, and offered few ideas of his own.</p>
<p>Now, with the November 5 elections making him the first Democrat to win re-election since Franklin Delano Roosevelt in the 1940s, Clinton has far more confidence striding the world stage.</p>
<p>He has gone from being a newcomer to diplomacy to being a veteran of its battles. Among the so-called G-7 members, now only German Chancellor Helmut Kohl has more experience.</p>
<p>That is why on this foreign trip Clinton has confidence as he talks about ambitious goals such as improving relations with China despite tensions over trade and human rights.</p>
<p>He meets on Sunday with China's president, Jiang Zemin, when both go to the APEC summit and also plans private talks with Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto and South Korean President Kim Young-sam.</p>
<p>&quot;As we enter the 21st Century...I say to you that America not only has been, she is and will remain a Pacific power,&quot; Clinton told the assembled leaders of Australia's government.</p>
<p>&quot;We want America's involvement and influence to provide the stability among nations which is necessary for the people of the Asia-Pacific region to make the routines of normal life a reality and to spur the economic progress that will benefit all of us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The most telling sign of just how much Clinton has changed in his attitude about exercising world leadership rests in the fact that he doesn't know exactly who will be serving in his administration's key foreign policy posts when his second term starts in January.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Warren Christopher and Defence Secretary William Perry have both announced they will be stepping down, and Clinton has yet to announce their replacements. Once he chooses replacements, there is no guarantee the Republican-controlled Senate will confirm them.</p>
<p>What has changed about Clinton is that he knows what he wants to do, even before the people who would carry out his wishes are in place. In the early days of his presidency, he awaited the recommendations of his key advisers.</p>
<p>Now, Clinton has a much firmer grasp of where he wants to go, and how to get there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
