<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="202847" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Oshkosh Truck &quot;repositioned&quot; for growth.</title>
<headline>Oshkosh Truck &quot;repositioned&quot; for growth.</headline>
<dateline>OSHKOSH, Wis. 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oshkosh Truck Corp said it is repositioned for long-term growth and has focused its resources on fire and emergency, defense and commercial vehicles for 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;While our fiscal 1996 earnings are quite disappointing, we have repositioned the company for sustainable long-term earnings growth,&quot; said chairman/chief executive officer Eugene Goodson late on Tuesday in an earnings statement. &quot;To improve long-term earnings, we are now focused on our three vehicle businesses of fire and emergency, defense and commercial trucks.&quot;  </p>
<p>Oshkosh Truck on Tuesday reported a net loss for the 1996 fiscal year of $3.1 million, or $0.35 per share, compared to net income of $9.2 million, or $1.04 per share for 1995.</p>
<p>The 1996 results included an $11.3 million in after-tax charges and after-tax benefits of $2.0 million on reversal of income tax provisions and related accrued interest.</p>
<p>For the fourth quarter ended Sept 30, 1996, it reported a net loss of $2.3 million, or $0.26 per share, on net sales of $118 million. During the same 1995 period, it had net income of $3.3 million of $0.36 a share on net sales of $109 million.</p>
<p>The company said its board on November 18 decided to no longer rely on an alliance formed in June 1995 between Oshkosh Truck and Freightliner Corp, which it said &quot;had not achieved any of its objectives and was not likely to do so.&quot; It said the firms are negotiating to continue supplying some components and systems to each other.</p>
<p>Goodson also said Oshkosh Truck's acquisition in September 1996 of Pierce Manufacturing Inc provides a &quot;leading position in the U.S. fire apparatus industry and a strong distribution system for Oshkosh's commercial products.&quot;</p>
<p>He called Pierce sales since the acquisition &quot;outstanding&quot; and said the company is achieving its cost-reduction targets.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSHKOSH, Wis."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
