<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203041" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nutraceuticals join fray as fountain of youth.</title>
<headline>Nutraceuticals join fray as fountain of youth.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Commins</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO</dateline>
<text>
<p>The old saying &quot;You are what you eat&quot; is taking a new twist.</p>
<p>From baby boomers fearing the loss of their youthful vigour to the elderly battling chronic diseases, consumers are turning increasingly to special food products known as nutraceuticals as a means to be healthier.</p>
<p>&quot;It's explosive,&quot; said Dr. Stephen DeFelice, president of the Foundation for Innovation in Medicine, who coined the term nutraceutical.</p>
<p>Nutraceutical is an umbrella term, encompassing a market that DeFelice's estimates accounts for up to $250 billion in estimated sales in the United States.</p>
<p>Admittedly, DeFelice uses the broadest definition possible for nutraceuticals, lumping together dietary supplements containing vitamins and minerals, functional foods geared to people with specific diseases, and &quot;good-for-you&quot; products, such as orange juice with added calcium, and low-fat foods.</p>
<p>Whatever the definition, industry executives agree that the nutraceuticals market is growing quickly as more people make the connection between what they eat and how they feel.</p>
<p>&quot;We call it an emerging category, the same way we look at China and call it an emerging market,&quot; said Joseph Stewart, senior vice president of corporate affairs for Kellogg Co.</p>
<p>Kellogg, best known for its breakfast cereals such as Corn Flakes and Rice Krispies, plans to develop functional foods for consumers with specific health problems -- including high cholestrol, hypertension, osteoporosis and heart disease.</p>
<p>The functional food category is a high-growth niche within nutraceuticals. Simply put, these functional foods, or medical foods as they are also called, serve specific health conditions.</p>
<p>For example, Baker Norton Pharmaceuticals recently launched a functional food called Zbar, which is aimed at helping diabetics avoid incidents of hypoglycemia, or low-blood sugar.</p>
<p>Although they make health claims, nutraceuticals are not regulated by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Still, many companies say they have conducted, or plan to conduct, clinical trials to verify the health claims.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not going to sell snake oil off the back of the wagon,&quot; said Gary Draper, senior vice president of Baker Norton, which is part of IVAX Corp. &quot;We're going to look for compounds where you've actually got good science.&quot;</p>
<p>The American Dietetic Association, in a position statement, acknowledged that specific substances in foods may have a beneficial role as part of a varied diet.</p>
<p>&quot;The association supports research regarding the health benefits and risks of these substances,&quot; the ADA said. &quot;Dietetics professionals will continue to work with the food industry and government to ensure that the public has accurate scientific information in this emerging field.&quot;</p>
<p>The functional food category is attracting wide interest from pharmaceutical and food companies, looking to capitalise on the growth in this market.</p>
<p>Nestle SA, the world's largest food company, has launched a clinical nutrition division to develop meal replacements and supplements for elderly and critically ill patients. Products include meals fed by tube and liquid diets.</p>
<p>&quot;Our charter within the Nestle organisation is to work on foods that have special dietary purposes,&quot; said Jerry Carino, president of Nestle Clinical Nutrition.</p>
<p>Among the small players, Reliv International Inc. has entered functional foods with Arthaffect, which it says has been clinically shown to combat arthritis and degenerative joint conditions.</p>
<p>Beyond functional foods are a host of products that promise consumers will look or feel better. These nutritional supplements include blends of herbs, vitamins, minerals and even fiber.</p>
<p>For example, Ensure, by Abbott Laboratories Inc.'s Ross Products Division, is an over-the-counter product that can be used as a meal replacement or nutritional supplement.</p>
<p>&quot;There are 76 million baby boomers that live in the U.S. who are driven to be strong and to stay on top of their game,&quot; said Lindsey Duncan, president of 4Health Inc., which makes nutritional supplements. &quot;These people want to stack the odds in their favour and they have the income to do so.&quot;</p>
<p>Duncan said 4Health plans to conduct clinical trials on all its products, including its UnDo herbal blend, which the company says helps eliminate toxins from the body.</p>
<p>&quot;Companies that don't have the science and the efficacy behind their products will fall by the wayside,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Beyond making food products that promise better health, companies are looking at more ways to make food more healthful.</p>
<p>&quot;One is the removal of negative (elements) from food -- the removal of fat and calories and salt,&quot; said Norm Jangaard, vice president of business development for the NutraSweet/Kelco division of Monsanto Co.</p>
<p>&quot;The next step is to put better, positive things into foods.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
