<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203195" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Brady debt ambles higher as Russia roadshow ends.</title>
<headline>Brady debt ambles higher as Russia roadshow ends.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emerging market debt prices firmed slightly on the back of a firmer U.S. Treasury market as players marked time before the launch of Russia's long-anticipated inaugural Eurobond, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;People were just not really involved today,&quot; one Brady bond trader said. &quot;Everything is responding to the Treasury market strength. It's very quiet.&quot;</p>
<p>In late afternoon trade, Argentine FRBs inched up 1/8 to a bid price of 84-3/4, and Brazilian Cs slipped 1/8 to 71-5/8, while the benchmark U.S. T-bond rose 11/32 to yield 6.41 percent.  </p>
<p>Brady bond dealers described the market as relatively slow, but maintaining a healthy tone as Treasuries gained.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still in a phase where you are in cautious mode where you're trying to protect your gains for year-end,&quot; said Olivier Lemaigre, debt strategist at Citicorp Securities. &quot;The fact that it's staying at these levels and consolidating higher is rather positive.&quot;</p>
<p>The Russian roadshow continued to captivate the market, even though smaller numbers of investors than expected attended the presentation, sources said.  </p>
<p>Analysts said the issue, for which JP Morgan and SBC Warburg acted as lead managers, was more likely to appeal to banks and retail investors than to major institutional houses.</p>
<p>The market firmly expected the issue to be successful, and to price as early as Thursday, but what spread would emerge from these extensive roadshows remained open to question.</p>
<p>Most observers expected the issue to prise between 300 and 350 basis points over comparable U.S. Treasuries, and the size to expand to about $750 million from $500 million.  </p>
<p>&quot;I would say it will be in the low end of the range,&quot; one emerging market analyst said. &quot;They ought to have no problem placing that.&quot;</p>
<p>But another analyst suggested that a price of 300 basis points might be pushing the market too hard. &quot;I think there was resistance from some investors at 300-325 and amount being raised to $750 million.&quot;</p>
<p>Ahead of the launch, Russian debt gave back some of its recent gains, as Russian Vnesh dollar loans slipped 1/2 to 79-1/4 bid, while the mark loans slipped 1-1/4 to 82-1/2.</p>
<p>A Russian official reportedly ordered the release of some frozen MinFin bonds, and the paper responded positively. MinFin 3s  were unchanged at 83-1/8 and MinFin 4s were 1/2 stronger at 60-3/8.</p>
<p>-- George Lerner, 212-859-1671</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
