<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203105" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sudanese activist wins human rights award.</title>
<headline>Sudanese activist wins human rights award.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Sudanese activist won the 1996 Robert F. Kennedy human rights award on Wednesday, but the name of the recipient was withheld because of fear of retaliation by Sudan's government.</p>
<p>&quot;For the first time, the name of the recipient of the Robert F. Kennedy Human Rights Award must be kept secret because the ability of this courageous Sudanese activist to carry out this important work would be imperilled,&quot; Sen. Edward Kennedy, brother of the assassinated U.S. attorney general, said at the award ceremony.</p>
<p>&quot;The winner is a leading opponent of the persecution of minorities in Sudan and the imposition of the harsh form of Islamic law. The winner also opposes the war in the southern part of Sudan, which has resulted in so much devastation,&quot; Kennedy said.</p>
<p>He called the Sudanese government &quot;a brutal and repressive regime&quot; and accused it of widespread human rights abuses including torture and slavery.</p>
<p>The winner, in an unsigned written statement, said: &quot;My colleagues in the Sudanese human rights movement and I are highly appreciative, greatly honoured and immensely encouraged by the Robert F. Kennedy award. This award proves that we are not alone.&quot;</p>
<p>The award was presented on what would have been Robert Kennedy's 71st birthday by his widow, Ethel.</p>
<p>It was accepted on behalf of the anonymous winner by Abdullahi an-Na'im, an Islamic law scholar from Sudan who is a professor at Emory University School of Law in Atlanta.</p>
<p>Robert Kennedy, who was attorney general for his brother President John F. Kennedy, was assassinated in 1968 in Los Angeles on the night he won the California Democratic presidential primary.</p>
<p>Sudan has been on Washington's list of countries that support terrorism since 1993.</p>
<p>The United Nations imposed diplomatic and travel restrictions on Sudan in May. An air embargo was approved in August but implementation was suspended for three months.</p>
<p>The U.N. curbs were imposed in response to Sudan's failure to extradite to Ethiopia three Egyptians accused of taking part in a plot to assassinate Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak in Addis Ababa in June, 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SUDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
