<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203216" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. banks seen thriving under looser reins.</title>
<headline>U.S. banks seen thriving under looser reins.</headline>
<byline>Cal Mankowski</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A loosening of regulations that will permit U.S. banks easier entry into other financial service businesses is bullish for the banks, analysts said.</p>
<p>Bank stocks, which have for decades traded at a discount to the market valuation for stocks in the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index, will command a price-to-earnings multiple closer to the S&amp;P, said Robert Bonelli, executive vice president at Ernst &amp; Co.</p>
<p>He said as banks shift their revenue mix away from interest-sensitive businesses, earnings will increase and higher valuations will create a &quot;multiplying effect.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;What banks really want is to provide a whole litany and array of financial solutions to corporate and business customers,&quot; said Anthony Davis, analyst at Dean Witter Reynolds. He said surveys have shown that U.S. consumers also want to buy insurance and other services through banks.</p>
<p>The latest victory for the banks in their rivalry with securities firms and insurance companies was an announcement by Comptroller of the Currency Eugene Ludwig of a new rule that could allow banks on an individual basis to conduct new activities through subsidiaries.  </p>
<p>Davis noted that the debate about who should be allowed to do what in the U.S. financial services industry has become the object of a turf war between various groups in Washington.</p>
<p>&quot;The Fed has been loosening revenue restrictions (on the amount of underwriting in a securities affiliate of a bank) in step-like fashion since 1989,&quot; he said. &quot;Along comes Gene Ludwig who has clearly been the most proactive comptroller that we've had in 20 years saying 'if you're nationally-chartered, send us your application.'&quot;</p>
<p>Davis also noted that the U.S. Congress, which failed to resolve the problem in 1996, is expected to try again in 1997.  </p>
<p>While the American Bankers Association praised the rule, the American Couincil of Life Insurance said it would &quot;mount a major effort&quot; to block the action.</p>
<p>The Securities Industry Association (SIA), trade group for brokers and investment banks, said the OCC move was &quot;a misguided step because it will only benefit part of the financial services industry.&quot; Steve Judge, senior vice</p>
<p>president for government affairs, said Congress should do the job of re-shaping the financial services. He said the OCC move will allow banks to own full-service securities firms but securities firms will not be able to own banks.  </p>
<p>Davis said while the turf battles may have slowed reform earlier this year, with the OCC's move today &quot;right now it seems to be accelrating things.&quot;</p>
<p>The analyst said it is clear that &quot;the banking industry is going to build or buy these businesses.&quot; He noted that NationsBank Corp, First Union Corp and others have been importing talent from Wall Street to build investment banking businsses.</p>
<p>First Union agreed in September to acquire Keystone Investments Inc, a large asset manager. And Barnett Banks Inc earlier this year won a key court decision allowing it to sell insurance in small towns.  </p>
<p>Bonelli noted that Minneapolis-based Norwest Corp is grandfathered into the insurance brokerage business and derives as much as 25 percent of its earnings from this activity. &quot;It's one of the top performing banks in the country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thomas Andes, chairman and chief executive of St. Louis-based banking company Magna Group Inc, told Reuters in an interview this week that he sees the banking branch of the future as a facility offering &quot;total financial services, be it brokerage, insurance or whatever, a 'financial retail store.'&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
