<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203252" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soy products close higher on soybean rally.</title>
<headline>CBOT soy products close higher on soybean rally.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soy product futures closed sharply higher on a rally in soybeans tied to fund buying, bull spreading and a surge to one month highs in the neighboring wheat pit, traders said.</p>
<p>Recent active export sales of U.S. soybeans and soy products also nudged some shorts out of the market.</p>
<p>&quot;In the complex, people wanted to be long before the export sales report tomorrow,&quot; said Mark Cermak of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>At 0730 CST Friday, USDA will release its updated weekly export sales report.</p>
<p>Trade sources said the net export sales tally for soyoil were expected at 50,000 to 65,000 tonnnes and soymeal at 150,000 to 200,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>After the close, U.S. exporters reported 20,000 tonnes of U.S. soyoil sold to China for quick shipment.</p>
<p>Soyoil closed 0.12 to 0.23 cent higher, with December up 0.21 at 23.37 cents a lb. Soymeal settled $1.70 to $3.60 higher, with December up $3.60 at $240.00 per ton.  </p>
<p>Soyoil futures volume was estimated at 15,000 contracts, below the 17,560 traded Tuesday, according to CBOT. Soymeal volume was estimated at 25,000 contracts, up from 23,478 traded Tuesday.</p>
<p>--Sam Nelson 312-408-8721</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
