<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203223" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT--Charts point to rally in CBOT soybeans.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT--Charts point to rally in CBOT soybeans.</headline>
<byline>Emily Kaiser</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wednesday's rally in Chicago Board of Trade soybeans marked a key technical reversal in the January contract and charts suggested prices could climb above $7.14 a bushel in the next few weeks, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;We do in fact, have what appears to be a breakout here which would imply a minimum move to $7.14 and a further move to $7.28 or $7.30 in the January,&quot; said Jack Scoville, analyst with Price Futures Group, a division of LIT Futures.</p>
<p>Support was pegged at $7.00 per bushel with initial resistance at $7.19, Scoville added.  </p>
<p>The January contract on Wednesday settled up 11-1/2 cents per bushel at $7.07, the highest close since October 11.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the harvest low is being formed right now,&quot; said Hans Kashyap, president of Analytics Research Corporation in Bethesda, Md. &quot;Odds are (the January) is likely to head up into the $7.20 to $7.30 level.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the market will likely retest the lows near $6.80 or $6.90 but added &quot;the next swing up past $7.25 or so would signal a pretty large (upward) move over the next few months.&quot;  </p>
<p>Floor traders noted active buying interest Wednesday when the January contract first moved above $7.00 per bushel at about 1153 CST. The January peaked briefly at $7.08 before settling at $7.07.</p>
<p>&quot;It was an outside day, up and good,&quot; said a floor trader who declined to be named. &quot;It was higher than yesterday's high and lower than yesterday's low and it closed higher which could mean a key move to the upside.</p>
<p>&quot;But it has to be followed by two more days up. On a technical basis, this was a big indicator,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Kashyap noted charts had indicated trading Wednesday would be on the down side and could retest Monday's lows of $6.92-1/2 per bushel.</p>
<p>&quot;On a very short-term basis, the fact that we did not break under the low of November 18 is very significant,&quot; Kashyap said.</p>
<p>On the fundemental side, Scoville said strong export and domestic demand for U.S. soybeans was supportive and prompted much of the buying interest on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is room for this market to move higher,&quot; he said. &quot;Certainly the market appears to have turned a corner.&quot;</p>
<p>(Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8749)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
