<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203434" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy names new public works minister.</title>
<headline>Italy names new public works minister.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian President Oscar Luigi Scalfaro on Wednesday swore in a university professor as new public works minister to replace former graft-busting magistrate Antonio Di Pietro who resigned last week in a corruption probe.</p>
<p>The president's office named the new minister as Paolo Costa, the rector of the Ca' Foscari University in Venice.</p>
<p>Costa, 53, studied economics in Venice and Paris and has taught in Britain and Italy. He has collaborated on a public works project for the Venice lagoon and worked on the technical elaboration of a national transport plan.</p>
<p>Di Pietro, a non-elected technocrat and one of Italy's most popular public figures, stormed out of government last Thursday after coming under investigation for alleged malpractice during his time with Milan's &quot;Clean Hands&quot; pool of magistrates.</p>
<p>Investigations by the team unearthed the &quot;Tangentopoli&quot; (Bribesville) scandals in the early 1990s that toppled Italy's corrupt ruling old guard.</p>
<p>Di Pietro came under investigation in an earlier judicial probe but a court dropped all charges against him. He denies wrongdoing and has vowed to clear his name and defend the work of the elite Clean Hands team he spearheaded.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi had tried to persuade Di Pietro to reconsider but the impulsive former magistrate, who quit the judiciary two years ago with no explanation, flatly refused.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
