<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203560" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks close weaker but above day's lows.</title>
<headline>French stocks close weaker but above day's lows.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks finished lower on Wednesday but above their session lows after the bourse took heart from an early advance on Wall Street to new highs.</p>
<p>The bourse's weak tone was set early by the German Ifo index signalling greater than expected business confidence in the German economy, and it sank further in the afternoon on a larger than expected U.S. trade deficit for September.</p>
<p>But the market cut its losses after Wall Street shrugged off trade data. Traders said the consolidation was probably a good thing after the market's recent gains. The blue-chip CAC-40 index closed down 6.66 points, or 0.3 percent, at 2,233.39.  </p>
<p>The CAC-40 November futures contract finished 8.5 points lower at 2,235.50.</p>
<p>Trading volume was a heavy 7.12 billion francs.</p>
<p>&quot;We're consolidating but there's no panic,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar's not looking good, New York makes us nervous and we need to pause for a breath,&quot; said another trader. But he said the market's underlying trend was still upward.</p>
<p>* Club Mediterranee shares finished up 3.98 percent at 321 francs on market rumours that Accor might launch a buyout bid. Both companies declined comment.  </p>
<p>Club Med had gained more than five percent at one point, but came off its highs as analysts said the scenario was unlikely.</p>
<p>Accor, which closed down 0.45 percent at 665 francs, briefly rose on another rumour that Britain's Granada might be interested in buying it out with cash from the planned sale of its Exclusive luxury hotels.</p>
<p>Some analysts said Accor's rise was probably more likely due to an 8.4 percent rise in its nine-month turnover.</p>
<p>* Eurotunnel shares closed down 3.25 percent at 7.45 francs. Eurostar ticket agents said they would not take bookings until Monday because of the Channel Tunnel fire.  </p>
<p>* Renault fell 3.7 percent on concerns sparked by a newspaper interview by Industry Minister Franck Borotra that there was political opposition to early retirement plans proposed by French carmakers to rejuvenate their staffs.</p>
<p>Analysts said the share was also pressured by Fiat's disappointing results and by the announcement by Turkey's leading carmaker Tofas that it was putting workers on six-day compulsory leave due to falling demand. They said it suggested Renault and its Turkish partner may be having difficulties, but a Renault spokeswoman said there were no plans to reduce work hours in the next few weeks at its Turkish plant.  </p>
<p>* Euro Disney fell 2.19 percent to 11.15 francs. It reported profits up 77 percent for 1995/96 on Tuesday but sounded cautious note about the current-year outlook.</p>
<p>* Research consultancy Detroyat replaced Lagardere with Lafarge on its favoured stock list, portfolio managers said. Lagardere's shares fell 1.73 percent to 153.50 francs, while Lafarge gained 1.05 percent to 318.30 francs.</p>
<p>* Cie Bancaire  CICP.PA rose 1.08 percent to 560 francs. The market applauded the rise in its nine-month turnover and ignored a drop in profit that had been anticipated.</p>
<p>* Total rose 1.58 percent on higher 9-month sales.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
