<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203511" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French reshuffle seen in early 1997 under Juppe.</title>
<headline>French reshuffle seen in early 1997 under Juppe.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Despite rumours of an imminent French government reshuffle, official sources said on Wednesday a shakeup will probably only occur early next year and Prime Minister Alain Juppe will stay on despite deep unpopularity.</p>
<p>Reshuffle talk is rife in the corridors of parliament, with some aides and media commentators forecasting the replacement of Finance Minister Jean Arthuis and Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre as early as next week.</p>
<p>But a source in President Jacques Chirac's office said rumours of imminent change had no foundation.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is a reshuffle, it would probably be at the start of 1997,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Another senior official said: &quot;Juppe will stay. When a reshuffle comes, it will be to give the government fresh oxygen, not to change direction or prime minister.&quot;</p>
<p>Veteran Gaullist parliamentarian Pierre Mazeaud joined a chorus of calls for a shakeup on Wednesday, telling Radio Shalom it was &quot;necessary to envisage a ministerial reshuffle&quot; and a change in monetary policy.</p>
<p>But Chirac made clear in a speech in Tokyo on Tuesday there was no question of abandoning France's austere economic and budget policies despite the unpopularity, since they were aimed at cutting the budget deficit and qualifying for a single European currency.</p>
<p>Reshuffle speculation has been prompted by polls showing Juppe is now the most unpopular prime minister in the history of the 1958 Fifth Republic, beating even the ill-fated Socialist Edith Cresson, who served for a mere 10 months in 1991-92.</p>
<p>A survey showing that the opposition Socialists' alternative economic programme adopted this month, featuring an uncosted pledge to create 700,000 jobs for the young, is highly popular has accentuated pressure on the government.</p>
<p>Juppe has made several policy U-turns on secondary issues since September to avoid a repeat of last year's labour unrest.</p>
<p>Talk of cabinet changes has also been fuelled by the return to grace of several senior supporters of former prime minister Edouard Balladur, Chirac's unsuccessful fellow-Gaullist rival in last year's presidential election.</p>
<p>Balladur's closest associate, former budget minister Nicolas Sarkozy, has had two highly publicised meetings with Juppe in recent weeks and has muted his previously waspish criticism of the government's economic policies. The so-called &quot;Balladurians&quot; are now saying the time has come for reconciliation and unity.</p>
<p>Insiders say some of the reshuffle talk is coming from the potential beneficiaries, who explain that Juppe needs to broaden his political base and unite the centre-right ahead of the 1998 parliamentary elections.</p>
<p>Some analysts suspect Chirac and Juppe may be dangling the carrot of a reshuffle to keep Balladur's supporters on their best behaviour while the government pushes an austere 1997 budget through parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;All prime ministers facing strong grumbling from their own coalition have used this tactic,&quot; wrote political commentator Thierry Brehier in the newspaper Le Monde.</p>
<p>It has the dual advantage of keeping backbench critics who hope for ministerial office quiet and keeping disloyal ministers who fear they could lose their jobs in line.</p>
<p>Apart from Sarkozy, leading candidates for a return to ministerial office include centrist former justice minister Pierre Mehaignerie but probably not ex-defence minister Francois Leotard, who is now leader of the centre-right Union for French Democracy, the junior coalition partner.</p>
<p>Political sources say Juppe may also try to broaden the coalition by bringing in moderate figures who served in past Socialist-led cabinets, such as ex-labour minister Jean-Pierre Soisson or former environment minister Brice Lalonde.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
