<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203533" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-M3, Ifo show German economy picking up steam.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-M3, Ifo show German economy picking up steam.</headline>
<byline>David Crossland</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German business confidence and money supply data released on Wednesday confirmed that Europe's industrial locomotive is gathering steam and dashed any lingering hopes for another interest rate cut, economists said.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank said strong bank lending and the flotation of Deutsche Telekom kept M3 money supply growth, its main policy indicator, stuck at 8.4 percent in October, well above its target of four to seven percent growth for 1996.</p>
<p>Outlining M3, which comprises cash in circulation, time, sight and short-term savings deposits, the Bundesbank said the money supply had been boosted by a 46 billion mark ($30.6 billion) rise in domestic bank lending, with loans to public authorities up sharply.</p>
<p>Sight deposits also surged during October, probably because investors set money aside to buy a slice of telephone giant Deutsche Telekom, listed on Monday in Europe's largest ever bourse flotation, the Bundesbank said.</p>
<p>Economists said the effect of the Telekom issue should dissipate in November as investors draw down their cash holdings to pay for the shares.</p>
<p>M3 growth, which has consistently grown beyond target this year, is therefore expected to slow down in November.</p>
<p>Separately, the respected German Ifo economics institute reported a sharp rise in business confidence in October, with the west German business climate index rising to 97.4 from 95.7. Markets had expected a far smaller increase to 96.</p>
<p>Ifo's index for business expectations, seen as a leading indicator, jumped two full points to 103.1.</p>
<p>German bond prices tumbled as dealers saw the data as virtually ruling out another interest rate cut in this economic cycle. The yield on the benchmark 10-year German government bond rose to 5.85 percent from 5.78 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;A rate cut is now virtually out of the question for most market participants,&quot; said Peter Kerger, a portfolio manager at Credit Suisse in Frankfurt.</p>
<p>Analysts said the mark would have to appreciate sharply to prompt the Bundesbank to cut rates again.</p>
<p>Economists said both sets of data allayed fears that Germany's tentative economic upturn was stalling after surprise drops in industrial output and orders in September. The economics ministry has said it expects the output and orders figures to be revised upwards.</p>
<p>M3 and the Ifo index confirmed the economy was staging a steady if unspectacular recovery driven by exports which were being fuelled by the mark's recent depreciation against major currencies, economists said.</p>
<p>The upturn was set to continue into 1997 if investment in plant and equipment, still sluggish, picked up.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports are driving the economy,&quot; said Thomas Mayer, an economist at Goldman Sachs in Frankfurt. &quot;Investment should add to growth in 1997. If it does not, there's a big danger that the upturn will fizzle out.&quot;</p>
<p>If growth does grind to a halt, tax revenues will fall and Germany's chances of qualifying for European economic and monetary union in 1999 will diminish.</p>
<p>The Council of Economic Advisors, or &quot;Five Wise Men,&quot; warned the Bonn government last week that its budget deficit in 1997 would total 3.3 percent of gross domestic product, exceeding the three percent limit set by the Maastricht Treaty.</p>
<p>The Council forecast German GDP would grow 1.5 percent this year and 2.5 percent in 1997. It said Bonn must cut spending further to meet the Maastricht criteria in 1997, the key year for deciding whch nations will join EMU. --Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
<p>($1=1.5011 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E121">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
