<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203592" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India wary of Islamic fundamentalism in region.</title>
<headline>India wary of Islamic fundamentalism in region.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>India said on Wednesday that the emergence of Islamic fundamentalism in Central Asia would hurt its interests and reiterated support for the collapsed Afghan government of President Burhanuddin Rabbani.</p>
<p>&quot;We continue to recognise President Rabbani,&quot; Foreign Minister Inder Kumar Gujral told Asian News International in an interview.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda met Rabbani in Rome while attending the World Food Summit earlier this week.</p>
<p>Gujral said India had sent representatives to meet Uzbek militia leader Abdul Rashid Dostum in his stronghold of Mazar-i-Sharif in northern Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Dostum heads an alliance against the purist Islamic Taleban militia that also includes forces led by Ahmad Shah Masood, Rabbani's military chief.</p>
<p>Gujral said India wanted &quot;to see that peace comes back and the duly established regime that was Rabbani is placed in position again&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;But at the same time, I would say when we say the Rabbani regime must come in, we are also of the opinion that all elements of Afghan polity must get together and form a government of the type that the Afghan people want and not outsiders,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gujral accused Pakistan of trying to &quot;destabilise&quot; Afghanistan. Pakistan has denied India's claims that Islamabad backs the Taleban, which captured the Afghan capital Kabul in late September.</p>
<p>&quot;We are interested that there should be peace there. We believe that no outside factors should intervene there, and any emergence of fundamentalism in that region hurts India's interests,&quot; the Indian foreign minister said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
