<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203667" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan orders Hanwa Bank to halt operations.</title>
<headline>Japan orders Hanwa Bank to halt operations.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>For the first time in 51 years, Japanese regulators Thursday ordered a bank to halt most operations, the latest sign of problems in the nation's troubled financial sector.</p>
<p>The Ministry of Finance ordered Hanwa Bank Ltd., a regional bank, to suspend all its operations except deposit withdrawals because it was unable to recover bad loans.</p>
<p>The bank, employing about 900 people and operating mostly in western Japan around the city of Osaka, would be the first bank to come under a government suspension order since the end of World War II.</p>
<p>A ministry official said details of the bank's troubles would be announced at a news conference at 10:15 a.m. in Tokyo Thursday (8:15 p.m. EST Wednesday).</p>
<p>But deposits at the bank would be fully protected, the official said.</p>
<p>Established in 1941, the bank is not one of Japan's &quot;Big 20&quot; first-tier national banks. Like much of Japan's financial system, Hanwa was hard hit by the collapse of real estate prices in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>Last year Japan went through its first bank failure since the war when Hyogo Bank, also based in western Japan in Kobe adjacent to Osaka, was a victim of bad loans.</p>
<p>The government's effective shutdown of Hanwa is the latest attempt by authorities to solve the problem of bad loans burdening the nation's financial system.</p>
<p>Japan's banking system has been struggling with problem loans since the bursting of the late 1980s &quot;bubble economy&quot; that had sent prices of land and stocks soaring.</p>
<p>While most of Japan's biggest banks are over the worst the collapse, smaller institutions still face difficulties.</p>
<p>&quot;The ministry made the decision following the judgment that Hanwa Bank will most likely incur about 30 billion yen ($270 million) in liabilities ... making it extremely difficult to turn around on its own,&quot; Kyodo news service said.</p>
<p>On Nov. 5, Hanwa revised its forecast for parent current earnings for the first half of the current fiscal year to a loss of 280 million yen ($2.52 million).</p>
<p>Previously, the bank had forecast profit of 60 million yen ($540,000) for the first half against a profit of 232 million yen ($2.09 million) in the year-earlier period. Current profit includes gains or losses on securities sales and other non-banking business.</p>
<p>The news of Hanwa Bank's shutdown played into currency markets.</p>
<p>In New York, the dollar had dipped under 111 Japanese yen after news the U.S. trade deficit jumped 10 percent in September. But it recovered to 111.70 yen after news about Hanwa Bank prompted speculation that Japanese authorities would push interest rates lower to help the country's financial institutions.</p>
<p>Lower rates in Japan would tend to weaken the yen against the dollar and other currencies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
