<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20371" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia to press Japan over rice deferral.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia to press Japan over rice deferral.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A decision by Japan to defer its next round of rice imports until November would severely disadvantage Australia and prompt official representations in Tokyo, a spokesman for the Ricegrowers Cooperative Ltd said.</p>
<p>Chris Black was was commenting on a Reuters report from Tokyo that Japan was likely to defer its next round of rice imports until November because of a bumper domestic harvest and sluggish sales of foreign rice,  </p>
<p>&quot;Any tender after the beginning of September relegates Australia to second position because northern hemisphere suppliers -- the rest of the potential suppliers -- have their new harvest coming in,&quot; Black said.</p>
<p>With Australia the world's only counter-seasonal rice producer, northern hemisphere producers include all other rice suppliers in the world, including Japan, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Australia is then in a position of being disadvantaged against those suppliers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Australia understood Japan's problems with domestic rice availability, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;But there are very good reasons from the point of view of the Japanese consumer (to have the) opportunity to have a very high quality product at a time when no one else has it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This was a point which Australia had been promoting in Japan, both through the trade and through trade representatives, he said.</p>
<p>Australia would be seeking to clarify the latest tender position with Japanese officials in Tokyo, he said.  </p>
<p>If the tender schedule followed last year, there would be progressive tenders from the end of July. Earlier tenders were to the advantage of Australia, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are maintaining pressure to attempt to have the tendering process initiated as early as possible in the year and we'll continue with that message,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Continuing controversy over Japan's rice imports imports follows a 1993 GATT deal under which Japan agreed to gradually open its rice market to import 511,000 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>Japan's Food Agency said Japan had so far bought 39,500 tonnes of this year's quota, mainly from China and Australia.  </p>
<p>Black said Australia had won exports of 833 tonnes to Japan from the July 26 tender through the sale of 170 tonnes of high-quality koshihikari and 612 tonnes of japonica rice.</p>
<p>This shipment would have arrived in Japan in the past couple of days, he said.</p>
<p>The Japanese rice market was worth &quot;tens of millions of dollars&quot; in overall trade, although extreme variability in annual trade made it impossible to put an accurate yearly figure on the trade, Black said.  </p>
<p>Short-term projected availability of Australian rice for Japan was about 200,000 tonnes a year by year 2000, or about one-quarter of the market, he said.</p>
<p>-- Michael Byrnes, Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
