<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203981" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS-Robust spending data shows UK powering ahead.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Robust spending data shows UK powering ahead.</headline>
<byline>Richard Murphy</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>British consumer spending bounded higher in October and money supply growth surged, suggesting the economy is powering ahead and there is a risk that inflation could take off again.</p>
<p>The Office for National Statistics (ONS) said on Wednesday that retail sales rose 0.4 percent in October from the previous month, giving a robust annual rate of 4.1 percent.</p>
<p>The Bank of England said M4 money supply, a broad measure widely seen as a pointer to future inflation, jumped to 10.3 percent year-on-year in October, well outside the government's monitoring range of three to nine percent.</p>
<p>The Conservative government, anxious to boost the &quot;feelgood factor&quot; in the run-up to a general election now little more than six months away, welcomed the sales figures.</p>
<p>&quot;Rising high street sales show that people have the cash to spend and the confidence to do it,&quot; said Economic Secretary to the Treasury Angela Knight.</p>
<p>But City economists said evidence was mounting that the economy could be beginning to overheat, making it likely that finance minister Kenneth Clarke will have to raise official interest rates again soon.</p>
<p>The figures make it even less likely that Clarke, the Chancellor of the Exchequer, will make substantial cuts in personal taxes in his last pre-election budget next week.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly, with consumer confidence rising, a housing market recovery firmly underway and windfall handouts likely to supplement incomes over the coming year, the last thing the consumer needs is another shot in the arm from tax cuts,&quot; said Alex Garrard, an economist at stockbrokers UBS.</p>
<p>He was referring to billions of pounds of &quot;windfall&quot; gains many Britons will receive when several large mutually-owned building societies convert to banks in 1997. Most economists expect tax cuts of up to three billion pounds ($5 billion) in the budget, with a headline-grabbing reduction in the standard rate of income tax to 23 percent from 24 percent offset by spending cuts elsewhere.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major's Conservatives are likely to make their handling of the economy the cornerstone of their campaign for re-election, pointing to steady economic growth, falling unemployment, low inflation and lower taxes.</p>
<p>But recent statistics, including a shock jump to 3.3 percent in underlying annual inflation in October, have threatened to cloud that picture.</p>
<p>Wednesday's figures will provide fresh ammunition for the Bank of England in its campaign to get Clarke to raise official interest rates from their present 6.0 percent.</p>
<p>The Chancellor unexpectedly yielded to months of pressure from the Bank on October 30 and raised rates by a quarter of a percentage point.</p>
<p>Further increases would push up the cost of home loans for millions of home-owners, something any government would be anxious to avoid ahead of an election.</p>
<p>&quot;Even the non-monetarists will recognise the danger signals in such high rates of monetary growth,&quot; said David Coleman, chief economist at CIBC Wood Gundy.</p>
<p>&quot;But a tough, credible budget next week still offers Mr Clarke his best chance of avoiding a politically damaging increase in base rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Jonathan Loynes, an economist at HSBC Markets said that while high-street sales were still heading higher, the growth rate had tailed off from the rapid pace seen in the summer.</p>
<p>&quot;Fears of a consumer boom are overdone,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>($1=.5950 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
