<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203999" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Eurotunnel may face bill in tens of mlns stg.</title>
<headline>Eurotunnel may face bill in tens of mlns stg.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anglo-French Channel Tunnel operator Eurotunnel Plc could face a repair bill running to tens of millions of stg as a result of serious damage from Monday night's fire, a source close to the company told Reuters.</p>
<p>The source said, &quot;The cost will be millions (of stg) and could get into double figures, if you consider the damage to the 15 wagons and a locomotive, plus severe tunnel damage.&quot;</p>
<p>Added to that would be the repairs to the tracks which had melted because of the intensity of the heat, the source added.  </p>
<p>The source said the wagons and locomotive affected by the fire constituted about half a train. Eighteen months ago Eurotunnel paid around 50 million stg for two trains.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of it (the train) will be a write-off,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel has indicated that it should be insured for most of the costs which will be incurred for repairs, loss of business revenue and compensation. But is has not given any official figures on the costs involved.</p>
<p>The tunnel remains closed until it receives clearance from the Intergovernmental Commission which is the supervisory authority for the tunnel's safety.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel closed one of two rail tunnels after a serious fire broke out on a goods carriage on Monday night, injuring eight and causing widespread damage.</p>
<p>--London newsroom +44 171 5427717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
