<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="203991" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain will not re-enter ERM - minister.</title>
<headline>Britain will not re-enter ERM - minister.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain has no intention of taking sterling back into the European exchange rate mechanism, Treasury minister Phillip Oppenheim said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Oppenheim told a parliamentary committee examining legislation required to prepare for the single currency: &quot;The government has no intention of re-entering sterling in the exchange rate mechanism.&quot;</p>
<p>Oppenheim was addressing the committee on three documents, one on the regulations for setting up a new exchange rate mechanism, another regarding a stability pact to ensure budgetary discipline in a single currency and a third on rules for introducing the new Euro currency.</p>
<p>Members of the committee have been angered that the government has not been prepared to allow a debate of the full House of Commons on the three documents.</p>
<p>The documents have re-opened divisions in the Conservative Party between those who say they inevitably take Britain closer to membership of a single currency and those who say they are merely technical documents which must be studied whether or not Britain joins.</p>
<p>Oppenheim said the government still believed there was no need for a full parliamentary debate on the three papers although it would have no problems if in the end such a debate was held.</p>
<p>He said all three papers had to be reviewed as the successful operation of the stability pact and the exchange rate mechanism were essential for the health of Europe's economy and therefore for Britain, whether or not London decided to go into a single currency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
