<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204000" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LIFFE signs deal with CME to link rate contracts.</title>
<headline>LIFFE signs deal with CME to link rate contracts.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange said on Wednesday it signed an agreement with the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME) to link their short-term interest rate futures and options contracts.  </p>
<p>&quot;This agreement initiates the establishing of a trading and clearing arrangement whereby LIFFE's own short-term interest rate futures and options can be traded on CME after LIFFE has closed, thus effectively extending the trading day for these LIFFE's contracts,&quot; LIFFE said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a key element in LIFFE's EMU strategy,&quot; Jack Wrigglesworth, LIFFE chairman, said in the statment.</p>
<p>&quot;The Euromark is the most liquid short-term interest rate future in Europe and will settle against euros if EMU goes ahead. The link strengthens the contract and will distribute this benchmark instrument in the American time zone,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>A LIFFE official said the Euromark interest rate future would be the first contract to start trading under the new arrangement but no start data had yet been set.</p>
<p>&quot;LIFFE and the CME must assess the regulatory and technical issues before reaching a formal agreement on a start date,&quot; he said. &quot;We're at stage one, and we want to start as soon as possible.&quot;</p>
<p>The CME will be entitled to trade the three month Euromark future and option in Chicago from 1625 London time until 1400 Chicago time (2000 London time), LIFFE said.</p>
<p>Jack Sander, CME chairman, said in the statment the link lays the groundwork for EMU.  </p>
<p>The link will be similar to those arrangements that are planned for the CBOT link, LIFFE said.</p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, it allows for additional LIFFE short-term interest rate contracts and potentially, some CME short-term interest rate contracts to be added to the link in due course,&quot; LIFFE said.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
