<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204102" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Kuwait union in talks with KNPC on possible strike.</title>
<headline>Kuwait union in talks with KNPC on possible strike.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Kuwaiti oil workers' union started talks on Wednesday with the Kuwait National Petroleum Company (KNPC) on a possible strike at the oil export terminal of Mina al-Ahmadi.</p>
<p>The talks are headed by KNPC labour union chairman Hamad al-Souyan and chairman of KNPC Ahmad al-Mutair.  </p>
<p>Souyan told Reuters ahead of the meeting that exports of crude and refined products were still flowing out of Ahmadi which has a 420,000 barrel per day (bpd) refinery and oil export facilities.  </p>
<p>KNPC officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>About 120 workers out of 919 at Ahmadi have asked the union to help in a dispute with KNPC over its promotion system, Souyan said.</p>
<p>&quot;If there was no solution there will be a strike,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not in the union's policy to resort to strike,&quot; he said. &quot;(But) the nature of Kuwaiti unions is that if any union declares a strike it seeks expanding it to make it work.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope to solve the problem in today's meeting...A strike does not serve the economic situation,&quot; he earlier told Reuters.</p>
<p>KNPC is the refining arm of the state-owned oil conglomerate Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC). Kuwait has an OPEC quota of two million bpd and a local refining capacity of 830,000 bpd.</p>
<p>In March 1995 Kuwait Oil Co (KOC) labour union launched a strike aimed at halting Kuwait's three percent share of world production to demand a reshuffle of employment grades.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
