<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204116" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Conrail board member says still seeks value.</title>
<headline>Conrail board member says still seeks value.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A member of Conrail Inc's board of directors testified Tuesday that the struggle over securing the best deal for the railroad may not be over. &quot;I think the process is still continuing. I'm hopeful that we're going to be recognizing improved values,&quot; said board memner Bradley Jones, who testified in a U.S. district court hearing in which rival bidder Norfolk Southern Corp is trying to block a merger of Conrail with CSX Corp.</p>
<p>CSX is proposing to buy Conrail in an $8.5 billion cash and stock transaction that values Conrail shares at about $93 each.  Terms call for CSX to pay $110 cash per share for 40 percent of Conrail's shares and CSX stock for the rest. CSX is seeking shareholder approval to permit it to buy 40 percent of the shares in a tender offer.  Under Pennsylvania corporate law, it is not permitted to buy more than 20 percent without shareholder approval.</p>
<p>&quot;The greatest hope that we have is that there will be a recognition by CSX that they have a great chance of losing on the opt-out (shareholder) vote,&quot; Jones said.</p>
<p>Norfolk Southern has offered to buy Conrail for $110 cash per share, or about $10 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
