<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204172" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Former Orange County treasurer gets year in jail.</title>
<headline>Former Orange County treasurer gets year in jail.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ANA, Calif. 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A judge Tuesday ordered former Orange County, Calif., Treasurer Robert Citron to spend a year in jail and pay a $100,000 fine for his role in the largest municipal bankruptcy in U.S. history.</p>
<p>Superior Court Judge J. Stephen Czuleger sentenced Citron, the central figure in the financial crisis, to six years in state prison, but suspended the sentence and ordered the ex-treasurer to instead serve a year in the county jail.</p>
<p>He also sentenced Citron to five years on probation, ordered him to pay a $100,000 fine, and to serve 1,000 hours of community service. He was also barred from managing public funds and would not be allowed to run for public office again.</p>
<p>Deputy District Attorney Matthew Anderson said Citron was likely to serve only nine months in custody of the one-year term, provided he receives credit for good behavior.</p>
<p>&quot;If he gets all his behavior credits, he'd do nine months actual time in custody,&quot; Anderson said.</p>
<p>Citron had faced up to 14 years in prison after pleading guilty in April 1995 to six felonies, including counts of making untrue statements in the sale of securities and misusing public funds.</p>
<p>&quot;You failed in your oath and you failed in your obligation,&quot; Czuleger told Citron, 71, who sat during the sentencing. &quot;Are others culpable? Yes. But it was and is Mr. Citron's ultimate responsibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Before he was sentenced, Citron took the stand and read a brief statement, saying he was &quot;deeply sorry&quot; for his actions and that he hoped the court sentence would allow him to &quot;serve the public and take care of my wife.&quot;</p>
<p>His wife broke down in tears when the sentence was read.</p>
<p>Orange County filed for bankruptcy protection from creditors on Dec. 6, 1994, after sustaining losses of more than $1.6 billion on risky investments. It was the largest municipal bankruptcy in U.S. history. The county emerged from bankruptcy last June.</p>
<p>Orange County District Attorney Michael Capizzi had recommended Citron be sentenced to seven years in prison and fined $400,000.</p>
<p>Still, officials expressed satisfaction with Tuesday's decision.</p>
<p>&quot;It's really hard to question Czuleger's analysis. This was a very serious sentence, a very strong sentence,&quot; said Anderson.</p>
<p>Citron's attorney, David Wiechert, told reporters that this was &quot;the absolutely right sentence.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It was a very fair sentence,&quot; Wiechert said. He told reporters he hoped Citron would qualify for home confinement instead of county jail time.</p>
<p>During the two-day sentencing hearing, Czuleger heard testimony from Citron's friends, who warned that sending the ex-treasurer to prison could kill him, and psychologists, who described Citron as mentally impaired.</p>
<p>The judge said he chose not to give Citron a longer sentence because the former treasurer pleaded guilty and cooperated with investigators.</p>
<p>Wiechert argued that Citron's psychological &quot;deficits&quot; had rendered him susceptible to advice from &quot;trusted&quot; counselors, such as investment giant Merrill Lynch &amp; Co. &quot;In the end, his mind and his counselors failed him,&quot; he said in court papers.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch has said Citron was an experienced and sophisticated treasurer who made his own investment decisions.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ANA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
