<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204214" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Northeast lawmakers give DOE heating oil proposals.</title>
<headline>Northeast lawmakers give DOE heating oil proposals.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three northeastern lawmakers urged the Energy Department on Tuesday to speed up its study on building a heating oil reserve, and weigh four other ideas for shielding consumers from high heating oil prices.</p>
<p>The proposals came from Democratic Representative Joseph Kennedy of Massachusetts, and Senators Joseph Lieberman and Christopher Dodd of Connecticut, also Democrats, who last month offered to submit ideas for coping with potential heating oil supply shortfalls.</p>
<p>In a November 19 letter to Energy Secretary Hazel O'Leary, they called for the &quot;pros and cons of Congressionally-mandated inventory levels of refined petroleum products.&quot;</p>
<p>They also recommended the Energy Department should study ways for homeowners to buy heating oil in bulk at fixed prices, and should study the possibility of encouraging the industry to fill consumers' home tanks in the summer.</p>
<p>The letter said the Energy Department should give more consideration to swapping crude oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve for heating oil, an idea which it dismissed last month.</p>
<p>&quot;Again, it is our belief that government intervention should be avoided if possible,&quot; the lawmakers said.</p>
<p>Although heating oil stocks had grown over the last month in the critical northeastern region, the lawmakers remained concerned about low inventories and price spikes.</p>
<p>&quot;New England consumers are paying 25 cents a gallon more for their heating oil today compared to last season, and they have yet to adjust their thermostats for the winter,&quot; the letter said.</p>
<p>The Energy Information Administration and industry experts have said that a large portion of the price increase from last year was due to higher crude oil prices.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
