<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204228" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Soy crushers struggle with low protein in east US.</title>
<headline>Soy crushers struggle with low protein in east US.</headline>
<byline>Anna Driver</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>New-crop soybean protein content in the eastern Corn Belt is so low this year that some U.S. crushers will now only guarantee their soymeal is 47.5 percent rather than 48 percent protein.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen in our eastern district that the protein content has been so deficient that we just can't guarantee our customers 48 percent,&quot; said Mike LeSage, commercial manager at a Cargill Inc crushing facility in Gainesville, Ga.</p>
<p>LeSage said Cargill, which normally guarantees 48 percent on high-protein sales, changed its guarantee on Monday.  </p>
<p>Sources at other crushing facilities in the eastern Corn Belt said that 47.5 percent protein meal would soon become the temporary industry standard.</p>
<p>Soybean protein content in the western Corn Belt has been higher, and crushers there are not having trouble producing soymeal with a protein content of 48 percent</p>
<p>&quot;Everything east of the Mississippi is basically 47 percent,&quot; one soymeal broker said. &quot;That's all they can squeeze out of the new crop right now.  </p>
<p>The 47.5 percent soymeal has been actively traded in eastern truck markets, and there has been some trade in rail markets, cash sources said.</p>
<p>Some meal brokers worried that a flood of lower-protein meal into the market could pressure basis levels and spreads, which have traded at historically high levels during the 1996 harvest.</p>
<p>But other market observers said the lower-protein soymeal would not have any serious effect on prices or the market.  </p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's going to cause any problems because 47.5 is still considered the industry standard,&quot; said Dale Gustafson, analyst with Smith Barney brokerage in Chicago.</p>
<p>Industry sources said they were unsure of the reason for the lower protein in the eastern belt soy crop.</p>
<p>Soybeans in the eastern Midwest were planted later than usual this year and were subjected to unusually wet weather.</p>
<p>Some livestock feeders might have to reformulate their rations to compensate for the lower protein content, but most end-users of soymeal should not be affected, Gustafson said.  </p>
<p>The soymeal contract at the Chicago Board of Trade requires a &quot;minimum protein content of 48 percent&quot; but officials at the exchange said that 47.5 to 49 percent soymeal is considered high protein and could be delivered without penalty.</p>
<p>Demand for soymeal in domestic and export markets is so strong now that delivery against CBOT contracts is highly unlikely any time soon.</p>
<p>&quot;With the cash meal basis so tight right now, I don't see it (delivery) posing any problems,&quot; LeSage said.</p>
<p>The first harvested soybeans of the season typically are more fibrous and contain less protein than those that have had a chance to &quot;season&quot; in storage, so the problem could ease somewhat as soybeans age in storage bins, cash sources said.</p>
<p>--Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8720</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100223">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
