<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204379" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SKW Trostberg details 9-mo sales at units.</title>
<headline>SKW Trostberg details 9-mo sales at units.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>German specialty chemicals group SKW Trostberg AG on Wednesday reported a five percent rise in construction chemicals sales, saying the business fared well despite sluggish industry conditions.</p>
<p>In the first nine months of the year, SKW Trostberg's construction chemicals business, making up 27 percent of total sales of 2.97 billion marks, climbed to 800 million marks from 760 million marks a year earlier.</p>
<p>For the full year, management board chairman Wilhelm Simson predicted results will be slightly above 1995 levels. Results for the specific units are not broken down at the moment.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we would have had an excuse to deliver weaker results (in the construction chemicals sector) this year, business picked up after the very poor first three months,&quot; Simson said, adding results showed that SKW Trostberg has become more immune to a economic swings.</p>
<p>SKW Trostberg has become the world's largest construction chemicals group after it said it will acquire Master Builders Technologies from Swiss group Sandoz AG. MBT will be officially taken over before the end of this year.</p>
<p>The group's construction chemicals are used in the construction as well as renovation industry.</p>
<p>In its chemicals division, SKW Trostberg also posted a five percent sales jump to 960 million marks, boosted primarily by fertiliser sales. This business contributes 32 percent of total sales.</p>
<p>Natural food stuffs, SKW Trostberg's largest business group contributing 41 percent of all sales, posted sales of 1.21 billion marks in the first nine months of the year, nearly unchanged from last year's 1.23 billion mark turnover. Salt sales, used during the particularly icy winter, helped boost sales in the early part of the year, Simson said.</p>
<p>-- Svea Herbst-Bayliss, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
