<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204533" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Beaujolais Nouveau rebounds after nuclear boycott.</title>
<headline>Beaujolais Nouveau rebounds after nuclear boycott.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beaujolais Nouveau, the heavily hyped young wine hit hard last year by a boycott over French nuclear testing, is set to make a comeback when it goes on sale after midnight on Wednesday, wine industry officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Happily, the boycott is over,&quot; said Bernard Georges, export manager for the Duboeuf winery, France's largest exporter of the world-famous wine.</p>
<p>&quot;Beaujolais is not dead. Our export volumes are up, and this year's new wine is remarkable,&quot; Georges told Reuters.</p>
<p>The new wine, harvested just two months ago, goes on sale just after midnight on Wednesday in what has become an annual rite in major cities around the globe.</p>
<p>Bottles of the new wine have already been shipped via jet, rail and lorry around the world, with the understanding that it cannot be uncorked until seconds after midnight -- the traditional third Thursday of the month.</p>
<p>Some wine industry figures had predicted last year's boycott would do irreparable damage to Beaujolais. They said consumers would turn permanently to new wines of similar -- or better -- quality from Australia, Chili and California.</p>
<p>It looked like the end of the heady days of yore, when yuppies in Tokyo and New York would pay up to $20 a glass.</p>
<p>But exporters said the Beaujolais myth has, if anything, spread even further this year, with bottles shipped to such far-flung destinations as Damascus, Hanoi, the Fiji Islands, Cuba and Maputo in Mozambique.</p>
<p>France's final series of six nuclear tests, which triggered international outrage before ending in January, had cut deeply into last year's sales of Beaujolais Nouveau.</p>
<p>Eighteen percent less of the trendy young wine was sold during the 1995 campaign compared to the previous year, said the National Interprofessional Wine Office (ONIVINS).</p>
<p>Sales in Japan and the Nordic countries were hit hardest by consumer boycotts while U.S. sales were also down, industry officials said.</p>
<p>This year, however, feedback from forwarders suggested an increase in demand from North America while the Japanese market was showing signs of recovery, the Beaujolais Wine Board said.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports to Japan are doing extremely well this year,&quot; confirmed Duboeuf's Georges.</p>
<p>Ironically, the 1996 vintage had been virtually written off in late August after heavy rains threatened to bring on a bad outbreak of rot in the Beaujolais region.</p>
<p>But two weeks of cool sunshine in early September saved the crop, earning it the nickname &quot;the miracle vintage.&quot;</p>
<p>Beajolais Wine Board experts who have sampled it have high praise for its &quot;refreshing and lively taste&quot; and &quot;nose of red berries.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
