<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204592" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FKI up on strong H1 profit, dividend gains.</title>
<headline>FKI up on strong H1 profit, dividend gains.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in diversified engineering company FKI Plc rose on Wednesday on the back of a solid jump in its half year profits and dividend, analysts said.</p>
<p>The shares rose 3p at 201-1/2p by 1004 GMT in volume of 1.3 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The shares are up because the results are positive and the numbers are slightly stronger than expected,&quot; said one analyst, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>FKI's six month pretax profit rose 30.5 percent to 51.4 million stg from 39.4 million stg in the same period last year.</p>
<p>The company raised its interim dividend to 3.1p per share versus 2.2p per share last year.</p>
<p>Chairman Jeff Whalley said in a statement accompanying the results that FKI was determined to continue its strategy of investment in new capital equipment, product development and further acquisitions.</p>
<p>&quot;By investment in modern capital equipment we have revitalised many of our old-established businesses to the extent that we are now competing more successfully in our markets with lower cost, higher quality products,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 7972</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
