<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20465" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end up, lifted by laggards.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end up, lifted by laggards.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks ended firmer on Wednesday as late buying of market laggards erased earlier losses, traders said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index closed 40.56 points higher at 11,379.49 after falling to a session low of 11,295.53. Turnover was HK$3.65 billion compared to HK$3.50 billion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Lately there has been a lot of attention on laggards and investment property stocks, and conglomerates have been the most important laggards up until now,&quot; said Glenn Lesko, head of sales trading at HG Asia.  </p>
<p>Among them, Swire Pacific gained HK$1.00 to HK$69.75 and Wheelock added HK$0.20 to HK$16.15. Wharf Holdings rose HK$0.35 to HK$30.10 and Henderson Investment rose HK$0.05 to HK$8.60.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen some switching out of outperformers and rotational buying,&quot; said  Alex Tang, head of research at Yamaichi International.</p>
<p>He said utility stocks had particularly benefited with the Hang Seng utilities sub-index closing on a gain of 99.33 points at 9,789.07.  </p>
<p>&quot;Earnings season is always the worst season for them. It's just one disappointment after another,&quot; said Lesko.</p>
<p>Guangshen Railway posted a 21.2 percent drop on interim net profit to 510.15 million yuan. The stock ended the session HK$0.05 lower at HK$3.00.</p>
<p>Shares of Hwa Kay Thai Holdings Ltd plunged to an all-time low after the company announced a rights issue plan and also reported a sharp fall in earnings. The stock closed HK$0.22 lower at HK$0.54 after hitting a low at HK$0.52.</p>
<p>-- Jennifer Genevieve (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
