<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20466" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan to charge doctor in AIDS scandal - reports.</title>
<headline>Japan to charge doctor in AIDS scandal - reports.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prosecutors are set to charge the former head of AIDS research in Japan with negligence for the deaths of haemophiliacs who were given HIV-contaminated blood products, Japanese media reported on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The reports said the Tokyo District Public Prosecutors Office plans criminal charges against Takeshi Abe, former head of the Health Ministry's AIDS team, for using blood products that had not been heat-treated on patients despite medical reports that they may be tainted with the HIV virus.</p>
<p>The Mainichi Shimbun said prosecutors may act before the end of the week.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the prosecutors office and Abe had no comment on the reports.</p>
<p>Abe has been under investigation since complaints filed against him by the family of a haemophiliac who received untreated blood products at the hospital where Abe worked. The patient died of AIDS in late 1991.</p>
<p>The 80-year-old professor and specialist in haemophilia served as head of a Health Ministry research team set up in 1983 to investigate the source of mushrooming AIDS cases in Japan.</p>
<p>Media reports have said Abe is believed to have influenced the team's conclusion in March of 1984 to favour use of untreated blood products, instead of a safer product, cryoprecipitate.</p>
<p>Investigators believe they have enough evidence to prove Abe was aware of the risks of using unheated blood products in 1985, when the patient whose family complained was infected with the HIV virus, the Yomiuri Shimbun, a mass-circulation daily, reported.</p>
<p>The expected action against Abe would be the latest development in the decade-long scandal in which over 2,000 haemophiliacs contracted HIV, the human immunodeficiency virus which can cause AIDS.</p>
<p>Osaka public prosecutors last week raided the offices of Green Cross Corp, a blood supply company, and questioned former company president Renzo Matsushita, who is accused of negligence in the death of a patient from AIDS.</p>
<p>The raids rekindled media interest in the case after a series of parliamentary hearings failed to shed light on the responsibility of health officials, doctors and drug firms.</p>
<p>Abe testified in a parliamentary session as an unsworn witness in July that he had no choice but to use untreated blood products in the 1980s.</p>
<p>Specialists however said it was possible to use other safer products, contrary to Abe's claim that such products easily became clogged in needles and blood vessels, Mainichi reported.</p>
<p>The Health Ministry, after maintaining for years it could not find key documents, in February made public files from a 1983 study group which indicated health authorities were aware of the danger of HIV infection from untreated blood products.</p>
<p>In March, Japanese haemophiliacs accepted an out-of-court settlement in which the plaintiffs agreed to a one-time payment of 45 million yen ($424,000) each, putting an end to a seven-year legal battle against the state and five pharmaceutical firms.</p>
<p>Recent health ministry figures show that there are 1,154 people with AIDS and 2,942 infected with the HIV virus in Japan, a nation of 123 million. About 400 haemophiliacs have already died from AIDS and AIDS-related complications, activists say. ($1=108 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
