<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204686" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Martin Bryant a loner with grudge against the world.</title>
<headline>Martin Bryant a loner with grudge against the world.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>HOBART, Australia 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's most notorious killer Martin Bryant is a loner who vainly travelled the world in search of a friend before violently venting his grudge against society, shooting down 35 people at Port Arthur.</p>
<p>In a detailed biography presented to Bryant's court sentencing hearing on Wednesday, the blond youth who unleashed modern Australia's worst mass murder emerged as a man bereft of any friends and of severely limited intelligence.</p>
<p>Bryant has confessed to killing 35 people at the Port Arthur historic convict site in the island state Tasmania on April 28 and will be sentenced on Friday.</p>
<p>A childhood bully who liked to torment animals, Bryant grew up friendless in the close-knit island state and as an adult nursed a deep grudge against the world, the Tasmanian Supreme Court heard.</p>
<p>&quot;Bryant was clearly a distressed and disturbed young man. He was not mentally ill,&quot; said Bryant's lawyer John Avery, quoting from a medical report as Bryant appeared to blush in the dock.</p>
<p>Bryant, who grew up in the Tasmanian capital Hobart as the only son of a dock worker and his wife, is on the edge of mental disability according to recent intelligence tests which put him in the lowest two percent of the population, the report said.</p>
<p>It also said Bryant, 29, suffers from a personality disorder known as Asperger's Syndrome, which affects three percent of the population, and in some ways is similar to autism. Asperger's Syndrome cannot be treated and its origins are unknown.</p>
<p>Bryant left school at 15 years of age, never took a job and his first sexual experience was with prostitutes, Avery said.</p>
<p>During the past few years Bryant travelled the world, using money bequeathed to him by an elderly woman who in recent years had been his only companion.</p>
<p>The eccentric middle-aged Helen Harvey had employed Bryant to perform chores for her in the late 1980s and took him in as a live-in companion in 1990. An heir to a fortune, she died in a car crash in 1992 and left her estate to Bryant.</p>
<p>Bryant's father, Maurice, the only other supportive or controlling influence in Bryant's life, drowned himself on a farm dam near Port Arthur in August 1993, the court heard.</p>
<p>Bryant soon took to jet-setting, taking numerous overseas trips within a matter of weeks &quot;to meet up with normal people&quot; in city cafes in Asia, Europe and the United States, Avery said.</p>
<p>He tried to strike up conversations with strangers but became &quot;enraged by the frequency with which people would move away from him&quot;, said Avery quoting from the medical report.</p>
<p>In two years, Bryant took about 10 trips abroad and visited Singapore, Bangkok, Kuala Lumpur, Tokyo, Auckland, Los Angeles, Miami, London, Frankfurt, Vienna, Amsterdam, Copenhagen, Sweden and Poland. Each time he returned to Australia disappointed.</p>
<p>The best part of his journeys seemed to be when he was flying, as he had a captive audience sitting next to him on the aircraft, the report said.</p>
<p>&quot;He became increasingly unhappy and angry at not having any friends,&quot; the medical report said, adding Bryant began to dwell on his life-long feelings of rejection. About a year ago he decided he had &quot;had enough&quot;, it quoted Bryant as saying.</p>
<p>He contemplated suicide but a plan formed in his mind in early 1996 of a murderous rampage among the ruins of Port Arthur, a convict settlement where some of Australia's most brutal colonial history was written.</p>
<p>Bryant took a girlfriend in the months before the massacre, but his mind was made up. He has never explained why he went ahead with his deadly shooting spree at Port Arthur.</p>
<p>&quot;It was set in my mind. It was just set that Sunday. I wasn't worried about losing my property or never saw my girlfriend again. It was just in my mind to go down...and kill a lot of people,&quot; the report quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>Asked why he chose Port Arthur, he replied: &quot;A lot of violence has happened there. It must be the most violent place in Australia. It seemed the right place.&quot;</p>
<p>Psychiatrist Ian Sale, hired by the prosecution, said: &quot;I think he is basically wired up badly...I think he has always been that way, something of a child in a man's body&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps people should see him as some freak of nature, some natural disaster, rather than some malicious human being,&quot; Sale told reporters on Wednesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOBART, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
