<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204797" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's vehicle output climbs in October.</title>
<headline>Japan's vehicle output climbs in October.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four of Japan's five main carmakers announced jumps in October output on Wednesday, thanks to a weaker yen and strong demand for new models.</p>
<p>Industry sources said overall domestic production for the month was likely to rise by 12 percent from a year earlier to about 941,000 vehicles, after a 7.3 percent gain in September.</p>
<p>They added that output for the full year was likely to exceed the 10.2 million vehicles produced last year.</p>
<p>Official figures for October will be announced by the Japan Automobile Manufacturers Association next week.</p>
<p>Japan's biggest car maker Toyota Motor Corp said its domestic automobile production rose 20 percent to about 337,000 units in October over the same month last year, helped by strong demand for new models.</p>
<p>Honda Motor said its domestic production jumped 40 percent due to strong domestic demand for its new recreational vehicles, and higher demand for Civics in the United States.</p>
<p>Mazda Motor Corp and Mitsubishi Motors also announced gains in their October production, helped by good demand for Mazda's new Demio and Mitsubishi's new Galant and Legnum models.</p>
<p>Mazda said it produced 67,272 vehicles in Japan in October, up 21.6 percent on October 1995, while Mitsubishi increased its October domestic output by 6.2 percent to 102,073 vehicles.</p>
<p>But Nissan Motor Co Ltd, Japan's number two car firm, said its domestic production fell 5.6 percent to 132,000 vehicles in October, reflecting slow domestic sales as the &quot;new model effect&quot; wore off several models introduced last year.</p>
<p>Toyota's production in the first 10 months of 1996 was up 5.8 percent at 2.82 million units, and a Toyota spokesman said output for the full year was likely to reach 3.35 million units, up from 3.17 million in 1995.</p>
<p>Overseas vehicle demand was helped by a weaker yea, which stood at around 111 to the dollar on Wednesday, compared with about 100 a year ago.</p>
<p>The cheaper yen makes Japanese products more competitive in overseas markets.</p>
<p>Toyota and its affiliates were operating their plants for one to three extra days this month to keep up with strong demand for new models, he said.</p>
<p>Honda's domestic sales in October rose 30 percent from a year earlier to about 66,000 units as its recreational vehicle series were a big hit in Japan.</p>
<p>A Honda spokesman said the firm had planned to make 975,000 vehicles in Japan in 1996 but had revised that up to 1.07 million units. Its 1995 production was 969,200 units.</p>
<p>Honda plans to operate several of its domestic plants for extra days in December and January to meet the extra demand, especially for Civics for the European and U.S. markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
