<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204838" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Household energy demand to rise in ageing Japan.</title>
<headline>Household energy demand to rise in ageing Japan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's rapidly ageing society is expected to push up household energy demand by increased use of electronic gadgets designed to make life easier, a private energy think-tank said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Toshiaki Yuasa, an economist with the Institute of Energy Economics (IEE), told reporters that with the number of elderly people increasing, it was likely that more and more households would install heaters in traditionally unheated rooms like lavatories.</p>
<p>&quot;The use of heated washer-equipped toilets, home elevators and floor heating is also expected to increase,&quot; Yuasa said.</p>
<p>By 2010, Japanese household spending on lighting and heating is expected to increase by 1.38 times from 1995, Yuasa said. &quot;Almost half of the increase will be attributable to households occupied by owners who are over 65,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In Western countries, household energy demand had hardly increased in spite of an increase in the population of aged people, he said.</p>
<p>This was because central heating is widespread and governments had taken measures to conserve energy, Yuasa said.</p>
<p>In 1995, 15 percent of Japan's population was over 65 years of age, a proportion forecast to rise to more than 25 percent by 2025 and to reach 30 percent by 2050.</p>
<p>Only 2.9 percent of Japanese households have central heating. Most Japanese heat rooms only when they are in use.</p>
<p>Lavatories are not normally heated.</p>
<p>That is one of the reasons why computer-controlled toilets, which have warm seats and deodorising, washing and drying functions, are becoming popular in Japan.</p>
<p>By 1995, 25 percent of Japanese households had a high-tech toilet, a proportion expected to rise to 35 percent by 1998, Yuasa said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
