<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204913" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: BOJ says monetary policy aims at economic recovery.</title>
<headline>BOJ says monetary policy aims at economic recovery.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of Japan Governor Yasuo Matsushita said on Wednesday that the central bank's monetary policy is geared to ensuring economic recovery.  </p>
<p>He told a news conference that Japan's economy is recovering gradually, with private consumption resuming a gradual recovery after being somewhat sluggish in the summer.</p>
<p>&quot;The BOJ's monetary policy is geared to ensuring a firm basis for economic recovery,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Matsushita said he expects the government to quickly carry out the &quot;Big Bang&quot; financial reforms unveiled last week.</p>
<p>The reforms, put forward by Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, are reasonable principles on which to rebuild Japan's markets and financial system to a level where they would be as effective as those in New York and London.  </p>
<p>Matsushita said reform of Japan's postal savings system was not contained in the proposals, but a debate on this issue from a broad perspective would be useful.</p>
<p>Reform of postal savings, as a public financial system, should be considered in a way in which it would support private-sector finances, and managed so that any changes would not cause confusion in the activities of private financial institutions, he said.</p>
<p>Asked if the BOJ intended to continue outright purchases of government bonds, he said the BOJ would continue to watch if such purchases were needed in light of the money supply.  </p>
<p>Matsushita said Japan's economic recovery seemed to be becoming solid. &quot;Japan's economy is continuing its gradual recovery, but at the moment, the economic recovery appears to be becoming solid,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can well expect the economy's cyclical mechanism centring on private-sector demand to strengthen further as the economy moves towards a self-sustainable recovery track. However, we must still make sure this is on the way,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said Japan's industrial output is on an upward trend after moving sideways in the first half of this year. Inventory adjustments in some materials industries are making steady progress, he said.</p>
<p>On the demand side, steadiness in machinery orders showed good corporate capital investment. A decline in net exports, which was hindering the economy, had come to a halt, he said.</p>
<p>Housing investment remained at a high level, he said. He added that private consumption had recovered and was showing a gradual growth this autumn, centring on durable goods, such as cars, after stalling in the summer due to changeable weather.</p>
<p>Matsushita said the pace of improvement in employment levels and a rebound in corporate capital investment, including at small and medium-sized firms, needed to be watched.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
