<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="204914" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul shrs end down as investors stick to sideline.</title>
<headline>Seoul shrs end down as investors stick to sideline.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares ended Wednesday's trading slightly lower after moving in a tight box-range, and brokers said investors would hold their wait-and-see posture until the market showed a firm direction.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed provisionally at 744.14, down 2.91 points. It stayed in a 740 to 750 range throughout the day.</p>
<p>&quot;In recent days, 750 has proved to be a strong level of resistance, said a Coryo Securities broker. &quot;There are no particular bad or good factors at the moment, so investors are waiting to see what happens.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Securities Supervisory Board announced it had found illegal manipulation of share prices in the stocks of Sam Yang Foods and Orient Co. Sam Yang shares fell 2,200 won to their lower limit of 34,800, and Orient lost 1,000 won to 42,600, after hitting its low of 41,000.</p>
<p>&quot;This news will have a bad effect on individual shares that have risen rapidly over the past several months, because investors will be wondering who will be the next target (of a manipulation probe),&quot; said Hur Gyung-shik of Samsung Securities.</p>
<p>Declining shares beat advancers 574 to 268.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
