<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20509" id="root" date="1996-08-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Top Japan court says yes to U.S. bases on Okinawa.</title>
<headline>Top Japan court says yes to U.S. bases on Okinawa.</headline>
<byline>Eugene Moosa</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-08-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's Supreme Court ordered Okinawa on Wednesday to forcibly appropriate land for U.S. military bases, rejecting an appeal by the island's governor that the huge U.S. military presence was unconstitutional.</p>
<p>The unanimous decision by the 15-member Grand Bench headed by Chief Justice Toru Miyoshi removed one of the biggest roadblocks to securing long-term leases on private land for U.S. bases on the southern Japanese island.</p>
<p>&quot;This court rejects the appeal,&quot; Miyoshi said in his brief ruling.</p>
<p>In his presentation to the court, Governor Masahide Ota argued that U.S. bases on his island -- the biggest concentration in Japan -- violated the constitutional right of citizens to a peaceful livelihood and the principle of equality before the law.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto's central government said a provincial governor had no right to block leases for military bases, since local governments were not responsible for the defence of the country.</p>
<p>Legal experts had not expected the Supreme Court, one of Japan's most conservative institutions, to rule against the central government.</p>
<p>With Ota's backing, 35 landowners who own plots on eight of 40 U.S. military facilities on Okinawa, were refusing to renew leases which expire this year.</p>
<p>About 3,000 Okinawans lease land to the military, some of it in tiny plots.</p>
<p>The issue came to a head last September soon after the rape of an Okinawan schoolgirl by three U.S. servicemen who were jailed for up to 10 years.</p>
<p>The rape case highlighted the concentration of U.S. bases on Okinawa, a small island in the East China Sea and the poorest of Japan's 47 prefectures.</p>
<p>The island, scene of one of the fiercest battles of World War Two, covers less than one percent of Japan's land area but is home to 75 percent of U.S. military facilities in Japan.</p>
<p>Half of the 47,000 U.S. military personnel in Japan -- including a full Marine Corps division plus the personnel of a regional Air Force base -- live on Okinawa, the most strategic U.S. outpost in Asia because of its location close to China, Taiwan and North Korea.</p>
<p>Okinawa was under U.S. rule for 27 years until 1972, during which U.S. authorities forcibly appropriated land for their military. Only 15 percent of the acreage used by the U.S. military has been returned to Okinawans since 1972.</p>
<p>While the judicial aspect of the Okinawa versus Tokyo row has apparently been settled, the political wrangling is by no means over.</p>
<p>Okinawa holds a referendum on the bases' future on September 8, the first referendum by a prefecture over any issue.</p>
<p>A huge &quot;yes&quot; vote for Ota's plan to reduce the bases and review the Status of Forces Agreement, which governs the legal status of U.S. military personnel, would mean a prolonged confrontation with Tokyo.</p>
<p>The referendum is non-binding and does not call for immediate scrapping of U.S. bases, but a phased withdrawal until 2015.</p>
<p>In April, Hashimoto and President Bill Clinton announced plans to streamline 15 of the 40 bases, giving back to Okinawans 20 percent of the land they occupy.</p>
<p>But the efforts backfired.</p>
<p>Alarmed by what it saw as a move to institutionalise the U.S. presence on Okinawa, Ota's government stepped up its efforts to close the installations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
