<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205385" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - November 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Ireland - November 20.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the highlights of stories reported in the Irish press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>IRISH TIMES</p>
<p>- An inquiry into irregularities in the Department of Justice has baulked at blaming individual civil servants for the &quot;quite inexcusable&quot; failure to implement the government decision to delist a judge from the Special Criminal Court.</p>
<p>- The former Irish prime minister, Albert Rynolds, now facing one million sterling legal costs, is planning to appeal against the decision by a London jury to award him no damages in his libel action against the Sunday Times newspaper.</p>
<p>- One of Ireland's biggest beef farmers had a six-month prison sentence for possessing illegal growth promoters doubled to 12 months when he appealed against the severity of the original sentence.</p>
<p>- An attempt to move the multi-party Northern Ireland talks process beyond decommissioning to substantive negotiations will be made at tonight's Anglo-Irish Conference meeting at Stormont.</p>
<p>- Loyalist politicians have warned that unionist attempts to turn the decommissioning issue into an insurmountable barrier could bring about the collapse of the Stormont talks &quot;within days&quot;.</p>
<p>- Four new cases of BSE confirmed by the Department of Agriculture brings the total to 54 so far this year, the highest on record since 1989.</p>
<p>IRISH INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>- A major row will explode in parliament on Wednesday over the government's decision to defer questions to the prime minister and the minister for justice on a judicial controversy.</p>
<p>- The British medical insurer BUPA's basic health care scheme will on average be seven percent cheaper for all age groups than the Irish VHI.</p>
<p>- The errors which led to a judicial fiasco that has rocked the government in recent weeks were condemned by an inquiry team as &quot;inexcusable&quot;.</p>
<p>- Ireland's retail and export sectors received an electronic boost on Tuesday when Bank of Ireland launched the country's first Internet Shopping Mall. --Dublin Newsroom +353 1 676 9775</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
