<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205305" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. says Afghan meeting sent &quot;resounding message&quot;.</title>
<headline>U.N. says Afghan meeting sent &quot;resounding message&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-11-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali believed a meeting on Afghanistan at U.N. headquarters on Monday sent a &quot;resounding message to the Afghan factions&quot; that there was no military solution to the conflict, U.N. spokesman Sylvana Foa said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The meeting was attended by participants from 19 countries and the Organisation of the Islamic Conference, which all have influence on one or more of the factions.</p>
<p>&quot;The secretary-general feels the meeting sent a resounding message to the Afghan factions,&quot; Foa said. All participants &quot;expressed their conviction that there is no military solution to the conflict there.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;They want an immediate ceasefire, which in the view of almost all of them should include the demilitarization of Kabul. They want the Afghan parties to join in a genuine effort to find a political settlement to their conflict. They all expressed their readiness to join in coordinated international efforts to help the Afghans achieve this.&quot;</p>
<p>All the delegations said the &quot;present situation cannot be allowed to continue,&quot; Foa said. It was &quot;intolerable in terms of the suffering it imposes on the Afghan people...in terms of the threats it presents to the region and the world -- the threats of regional destabilisation, of drugs, of illegal arms flows, of terrorism.&quot;</p>
<p>The delegations also showed a keen interest in collective action to curb or halt the flow of arms and ammunition into Afghanistan.</p>
<p>Afghanistan's radical Taleban movement, which captured Kabul, the capital, in late September, on Tuesday dismissed the U.N. meeting as contrary to the wishes of the Afghan people.</p>
<p>&quot;Any conference, meeting...regarding Afghanistan without Afghanistan's representatives is a useless action,&quot; said a commentary by the official Bakhtar news agency broadcast by the Taleban-controlled Kabul Radio.</p>
<p>The head of the U.N. special mission in Afghanistan, German diplomat Norbert Holl, who attended Tuesday's meeting, told a news conference he would attend an &quot;Afghan forum&quot; originally scheduled for Dec. 2-3 in Peshawar, across the border in Pakistan, but now likely to be held elswhere due to &quot;political problems.&quot;</p>
<p>Another U.N. source said the gathering, mainly to discuss humanitarian activities in Afghanistan, might now take place in Geneva on Dec. 3-4.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
