<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205437" id="root" date="1996-11-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: FEATURE - Bangladesh looks to fish for jobs, protein.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Bangladesh looks to fish for jobs, protein.</headline>
<byline>Serajul Islam Quadir</byline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-11-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bangladesh could slash its high unemployment rate rapidly by developing freshwater fish-farming, already a major export industry, fishery officials say.</p>
<p>&quot;Fish have endless possibilities. If we can develop the sector, it is possible to get rid of the curse of high unemployment within the next three to five years,&quot; said Fisheries and Livestock Secretary Ershadul Haque.</p>
<p>About 10 million people are unemployed in Bangladesh.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has already launched a countrywide programme to promote fish farming and is trying to turn it into a major success towards ending unemployment,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>At present the contribution of this sector to gross domestic product is more than three percent. As a producer of freshwater fish, Bangladesh rates third only to China and India, they said.</p>
<p>The programme includes management training, supply of high-yielding and fast-growing fish fry, counselling on fish food, health matters, financial assistance and legal support.</p>
<p>Haque said: &quot;The government will soon introduce a gold medal award for both producers and village-level officials, and provide foreign training facilities for officials who can fulfil the target both in quality and quantity.</p>
<p>&quot;We need 45 grams (1.6 ounces) of animal protein for each adult person per day. Out of this 80 percent could come from fish. According to this estimate, the country needs over 1.5 million tonnes of fish per year, but it produces only 1.2 million tonnes and the rest is imported,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Fishery officials said that under a special investment scheme, a credit facility is given to any individual or a group from a particular area. No collateral is required for a loan up to 50,000 taka ($1,200).</p>
<p>The Sonali Bank, the country's major state-owned commercial bank, has offered 5,531 million taka ($131 million) to 7,247 farmers for aquaculture development since 1973, of which 3,388 million taka ($80.6 million) has been recovered while the rest remains outstanding.</p>
<p>In the mid-1960s, artificial fish breeding techniques were developed in Bangladesh. Nearly 400 fish hatcheries have since been established across the country of nearly 120 million people, producing about 50 tonnes of spawn every year, which meets over 90 percent of country's requirements.</p>
<p>The State Minister for Fisheries and Livestocks, Satish Chandra Roy, said: &quot;Around 1.2 million people have found full-time employment in the country's fish sector while another 10 million people have part-time jobs there.</p>
<p>&quot;Eight percent of Bangladesh's total export income comes from this sector,&quot; he told reporters. Most of the production is shrimp but various varieties of carp are also produced.</p>
<p>In 1995-96 Bangladesh earned over $335 million by exporting 39,000 tonnes of fish, officials said. This makes it the third most important exporter after readymade garments and jute.</p>
<p>An unidentified virus has affected fish production along the country's coast over past two to three years, keeping exports down, officials said.</p>
<p>The United States, Japan, Belgium, Taiwan, Britain, the Netherlands and most Middle East countries import shrimps from Bangladesh.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I03000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
