<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205629" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Laboratory Corp settles test claims - U.S. Justice.</title>
<headline>Laboratory Corp settles test claims - U.S. Justice.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Laboratory Corp. of America agreed to pay $182 million to settle civil allegations that it submitted false claims for unnecessary tests to federal and state health-care programs, the U.S. Justice Department said Thursday.</p>
<p>In addition, it said a Laboratory Corp. subsidiary pleaded guilty in North Carolina to submitting a false claim for an unnecessary blood test to the federal Medicare program and the California Medicaid program. The unit was fined $5 million.</p>
<p>The Justice Department said the settlement was the largest ever reached between the government and a clinical laboratory.  </p>
<p>The settlement was announced by the U.S. attorney in North Carolina in a statement and at a news conference there. The Justice Department made available a copy of his news release.</p>
<p>According to the criminal charges, Laboratory Corp.'s Allied Clinical Laboratories in San Diego would add a high-density lipoprotein cholesterol test to a battery of procedures requested by a doctor, even though the cholesterol test was unneeded for the patient's treatment or diagnosis.</p>
<p>The Justice Departrment said the company then billed the federal and state governments for the cholesterol tests, knowing they were unnecessary.</p>
<p>In the civil case, the federal government alleged that Laboratory Corp submitted false claims for cholesterol and other &quot;add-on&quot; tests, knowing they were unneeded for the treatment of the patients.</p>
<p>&quot;Often, doctors were led to believe that there would be little or no additional cost for the extra tests or that they had no choice regarding ordering options,&quot; a department official said.</p>
<p>The government said the doctors were unaware that the labs would bill federal or state insurance programs a separate amount for the extra tests.</p>
<p>June Gibbs Brown, inspector general of the Department of Health and Human Services, said in a statement the agreement was the third-largest financial settlement involving health-care fraud in the history of the false-claims law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
