<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205664" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Handleman says seeing benefits of efforts.</title>
<headline>Handleman says seeing benefits of efforts.</headline>
<dateline>TROY, Mich. 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Handleman Co said on Thursday it was beginning to see results from its efforts to increase sales and cut inventories and operating expenses.</p>
<p>&quot;We are beginning to see the benefits of the strategic initiatives the company has implemented to improve sales as well as reduce inventory and operating expenses,&quot; said Stephen Strome, president and chief executive officer, in a statement accompanying earnings. &quot;These efforts should help the company in its recovery period. Our endeavors to improve performance continue unabated.&quot;  </p>
<p>Handleman reported earnings for the second quarter ended October 26 of $0.20 per share, up from $0.10 a year earlier. Net sales rose 18 percent to $347.1 million.</p>
<p>The company has three operating units: Handleman Entertainment Resources, North Coast Entertainment and International.</p>
<p>It said higher music sales stemmed from improved sales to major customers through more promotional activity, and it linked the higher level of video sales to increased sales of &quot;mega-hit&quot; releases and fewer customer product returns.</p>
<p>Gains in book sales resulted mainly from new store openings with a major customer, while a drop in personal computer software sales stemmed from efforts to realign inventories with key customers to better reflect retail selling patterns, it said.</p>
<p>Handleman supplies and merchandises music, video, book and personal computer software products to North American retail chains.</p>
<p>Its shares were up 5/8 at 7-5/8.</p>
<p>-- Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TROY, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
