<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205742" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CompuServe quits Wow!, goes back to basics.</title>
<headline>CompuServe quits Wow!, goes back to basics.</headline>
<byline>Eric Auchard</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Acknowledging its failure to attract U.S. consumers, CompuServe Corp said it would disband its family-oriented Wow! online service and plans to defend its business and technical customer base.</p>
<p>The world's second-largest online service also said it would accelerate the way it expenses customer marketing costs and that it was taking a $28.6 million charge in the latest quarter for previously incurred subscriber acquisition costs.</p>
<p>Instead, it said it would pursue higher margin businesses, including international consumer markets, such as Europe.  </p>
<p>&quot;For CompuServe, this represents a strategic retreat back to its basics,&quot; said Peter Krasilovsky, a veteran analyst of the online industry at Arlen Communications in Bethesda, Md.</p>
<p>&quot;CompuServe will never contend for the King's mantle among the online service/Internet service providers in North America again,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>CompuServe stock fell 1-5/8, to 10-1/8, in early trading. H&amp;R Block Inc, which several months ago suspended plans to spin off its remaining 80 percent stake in CompuServe to shareholders, fell 1-1/2, to 26-7/8.  </p>
<p>Earlier today, H&amp;R had reported a substantial loss for its quarter ended October 31, citing CompuServe's turmoil, and said it planned to go ahead with a cut in its quarterly dividend payment to $0.20 per share from $0.32 previously.</p>
<p>In its own report, CompuServe said it lost $0.63 per share for the second quarter ended in October, after charges for exiting the Wow! business and other accounting changes. This compared to a $0.19 a share profit in the year-ago quarter.</p>
<p>Disbanding Wow! resulted in an after-tax charge of $4.9 million, or $0.06 a share, and amortization of prior marketing costs led to the charge of $28.6 million, or $0.31 a share.  </p>
<p>&quot;CompuServe's core users have always appreciated that service most for its independent forums and bulletin boards. They don't have any other place in cyberspace to get those services,&quot; Krasilovsky said.</p>
<p>CompuServe officials stressed that no new layoffs would result from the latest moves. Wow!'s 35 employees have already been absorbed into CompuServe Interactive, they said. The company's total headcount stands at about 3,200 worldwide.</p>
<p>In a telephone interview, CompuServe spokesman Steve Conway maintained that while his company was abandoning further mass marketing efforts aimed at U.S. consumers, &quot;If you are currently a subscriber, you will not notice a change.&quot;  </p>
<p>Nontheless, the Columbus, Ohio-based company said it would focus its efforts and investments going forward on business and professional markets, its traditional selling point.</p>
<p>Besides defending its core online services customer base, they said CompuServe will focus on other profitable operations like its network systems infrastructure unit, which generates 30 percent of total revenues.</p>
<p>In disbanding its Wow! service, the company blamed new market entrants, or Internet service providers, pricing competition and the high costs of consumer marketing.</p>
<p>The company announced plans to launch early next year a new &quot;CompuServe for Business&quot; serivce, an enhanced version of its core CompuServe Interactive with a new software interface and added content from &quot;thousands&quot; of information providers.  </p>
<p>Despite a series of missteps in the United States, growth remains robust overseas, where CompuServe's brand is the best recognized name among online and Internet access providers.</p>
<p>Conway said CompuServe Interactive's service has nearly doubled in its number of subscribers in Europe during the past 12 months, rising to more than 800,000 from about 450,000. &quot;It's a growing market for these services, and we outpaced the market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>About 60 percent of CompuServe's European customers are for business, professional and technical users, while 40 percent fall in the consumer category, Conway said.</p>
<p>That's roughly the inverse of North America, where about 55 percent of CompuServe's main service are consumers.</p>
<p>The 800,000 customers represent the bulk of CompuServe's international base, which totaled 1.12 million at October 31.</p>
<p>The Wow! service had been introduced only seven months ago to much fanfare, but failed to get off the ground.</p>
<p>CompuServe Vice President Scott Kaufman, the man in charge of developing the Wow! service, promised at the time Wow! was lauched to carpet bomb consumers with free software disks promoting the new service.</p>
<p>&quot;They'll be falling out of cereal boxes,&quot; he had vowed at the time.</p>
<p>-- New York newsdesk, 212-859-1736</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
