<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205968" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH PARLIAMENT SEALS 20, 32, 44 PCT TAX SCALE.</title>
<headline>POLISH PARLIAMENT SEALS 20, 32, 44 PCT TAX SCALE.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's lower house of parliament, the Sejm, passed a 20, 32 and 44 percent income tax scale for 1997 on Thursday giving final approval to the bill which now needs only the president's signature to become law.</p>
<p>Deputies voted 260 to 135 with 31 abstentions in favour of the Senate bill lowering tax levels by one point from the current 21, 33 and 45 percent, which implies a 1997 budget deficit of 2.8 percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>The tax scale adopted by the Senate last week was one of the alternatives the government said it was ready to accept.  </p>
<p>The government's own proposals for a slightly deeper cut to 20, 31 and 43 percent was defeated in the lower house, which adopted a four-level tax scale of 17, 20, 33 and 45 percent, sharply cutting taxes for the lowest-paid.</p>
<p>The ruling coalition's junior partner, the Polish Peasant Party, which helped defeat the government scheme in the lower house, tried to uphold the four-level scale during the Wednesday vote.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Grzegorz Kolodko has opposed the deep tax cut for the poorest in society, saying it would boost the 1997 budget deficit beyond acceptable limits.</p>
<p>He has said the Senate's proposal was compatible with his 1997 budget draft, which seeks to cut inflation to 13 percent at the end of 1997 from current 19.5 percent while maintaining the growth rate at 5.5 percent.</p>
<p>Kolodko told reporters after the vote he would sign on Friday an amendment to the budget draft which would accomodate changed tax levels.</p>
<p>Parliament has until January 28 to approve the budget draft.</p>
<p>The tax bill also lowers the personal income tax levels to 20, 30 and 40 percent in 1998 and provides for reducing the corporate tax by two points annually from 1997 so that it reaches 32 percent in the year 2000.</p>
<p>The new regulations scrap or reduce some tax reliefs, notably for individuals' investments in government securities, tax write-offs for residential construction and for corporate investments.</p>
<p>Under the bill, capital gains would remain untaxed until 2000.</p>
<p>The government says the bill is designed to stimulate the economy and to simplify the tax system but some opposition politicians say effective tax burden would grow next year as modest tax cuts would fail to offset the removal of many tax reliefs.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
