<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="205987" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Major blasts MPs over Sinn Fein meeting.</title>
<headline>UK's Major blasts MPs over Sinn Fein meeting.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major accused some opposition parliamentarians on Thursday of &quot;stunning naivety&quot; in allowing members of the IRA's political wing to roam around Britain's parliament building.</p>
<p>Major told the lower House of Commons that some Labour legislators recently invited representatives of Sinn Fein to visit them without giving parliamentary authorities prior notice &quot;and that they were from time to time left unattended&quot;.</p>
<p>But Ken Livingstone, one of the members of parliament involved, said it was ludicrous for a newspaper to suggest that senior officials of the outlawed Irish Republican Army, fighting to end British rule over Northern Ireland, had come to parliament to prepare for a bomb outrage.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea that the IRA army council members would come to London actually to case the joint for bombing runs...these are the most wanted people in Britain, they would not risk them on that sort of exercise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Independent newspaper reported that while the MPs were talking to the Sinn Fein officials in a cafeteria, one of them said he was going to the lavatory, and then disappeared for 20 minutes.</p>
<p>It said Britain's MI5 security service, alarmed that this unnamed individual suspected of being a member of the IRA's ruling army council, had complained to Labour.</p>
<p>But the Home Office, the government department responsible for MI5, denied this, saying security officers had not conducted surveillance within parliament.</p>
<p>Major said cabinet minister Tony Newton had written to House of Commons speaker Betty Boothroyd about the incident.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what the outcome of this inquiry will be but I think it is stunning naivety of any member not to realise the connection between Sinn Fein and the IRA,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Labour's Home Affairs spokesman, Jack Straw, said the incident had been taken &quot;very seriously indeed&quot; by the party.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a breach of the rules to leave guests unattended, whichever organisation they have come from. But obviously there are greater concerns about that if they do come from an organisation like Sinn Fein or the IRA,&quot; he told BBC radio.</p>
<p>Livingstone, a long-time supporter of a united Ireland, said Sinn Fein chairman Mitchel McLaughlin was accompanied on the visit by two party officials. One ran its London office and the other was its expert on British policy.</p>
<p>The three were met in the Central Lobby, where Britons go to see their MPs, and taken to a cafeteria, Livingstone said, adding: &quot;These are places that virtually anybody can get into.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
