<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206057" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Supply to keep marine insurance rates low- broker.</title>
<headline>Supply to keep marine insurance rates low- broker.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Over capacity in the marine insurance market will keep rates soft for the foreseeable future, UK broker Lowndes Lambert said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We think there's about twice as much capacity available for decent marine business as there is business to feed it,&quot; chief executive David Margrett told Reuters in an interview after the company reported six month results.</p>
<p>Lowndes Lambert said declining marine rates contributed to a fall in its half year pre-tax profits to 5.0 million stg from 6.0 million stg last time.</p>
<p>Rates had fallen by as much as 50 percent in extreme cases on hull risks with a good record or a good approach to risk management. Margrett said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're assuming there won't be any improvement and running our business accordingly, so if it does (improve) that will be the icing on the cake,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On the protection and indemnity side (P&amp;I), rates are holding firm and some P&amp;I groups have made supplementary calls on their ship-owner members, while cargo rates are flat, Margrett said.</p>
<p>Despite the difficult market conditions, Lowndes Lambert sees opportunities to expand its marine broking operations, partly through exploiting a wider customer base built on recent acquisitions, Margrett said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're winning new business...we have a lot of opportunities to cross sell products that we've developed for our people...we have put on additional business including some quite substantial shipbuilding business and some political risk business on marine construction business and on protection and indemnity reinsurance business.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly the adverse rating environment is affecting most brokers in the same way and we perceive that gives us opportunities to acquire high quality income streams at cheap prices,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Lowndes Lambert's marine and aviation division accounts for about 13 percent of total group income.</p>
<p>The company is also expanding its fee income based business with new services. Stand alone fee income business accounts for around three percent of gross revenue, while 25 percent of the UK retail business is fee driven.</p>
<p>&quot;We're either selling risk management, or advice on health and safety, or self insurance, claims management work, where we're adding value to the operation of the client without necessarily disturbing the insurance transaction itself,&quot; Margrett said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're growing this as fast as possible, but one of our difficulties is finding capable professionals in the risk management field who can translate their skills into something the client understands.&quot;</p>
<p>-- John Sanders, Reuters Insurance News 44 171 542 2769</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
