<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206251" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian coalition partner quits government.</title>
<headline>Estonian coalition partner quits government.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The junior partner in the government of the Baltic state of Estonia on Thursday announced it was quitting the coalition, ending its one-year term.</p>
<p>&quot;We have taken the vote to leave the government,&quot; a spokesman for the Reform Party, which rules as junior government partner with the Coalition Party, told Reuters.  </p>
<p>The vote was taken after the Reform Party ruling council met for almost three hours and the spokesman said the vote in favour of quitting the government was overwhelming.</p>
<p>The Reformists quit after Prime Minister Tiit Vaehi, head of the Coalition Party, signed a cooperation pact with the leading opposition party, the Centre Party.</p>
<p>The Reformists asked Vaehi to scrap the deal but he refused. The government also includes a smaller bloc of rural parties.</p>
<p>Estonia has been plagued by political instability since it quit the former Soviet Union in 1991 but has always managed to keep on the path of economic reform. Many commentators expect the Coalition and Centre Parties to try to form a new coalition, a rerun of the previous government.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
