<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206203" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Nov 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Nov 21.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Thursday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- Banks are expected to lift their prime overdraft rates one percentage point to 20.25 percent after Reserve Bank governor Chris Stals announced a similar increase in Bank rate to 17 percent.</p>
<p>- The cabinet has given the green light for revolutionary change to South Africa's water laws, which would abolish the link between water rights and land ownership.</p>
<p>- New Africa Investment Ltd has strengthened its bid for mining house JCI by swelling the membership of its African Mining Consortium to 17, including a number of black-owned mining companies.</p>
<p>- Inflation shot up to 9.1 percent in October from 8.4 percent in September, scaring the bond and currency markets which had expected it to remain below nine percent.</p>
<p>- The state South African Broadcasting Corporation said it planned to eliminate a projected 500 million rand deficit in the next financial year by slashing running costs and asking the government to take over certain high-deficit projects.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- The Reserve Bank said it was raising Bank rate to 17 percent from 16 percent.</p>
<p>- Tiny Rowland, founder and former chairman of Lonrho said that Anglo American Corp's acquisition of a 28 percent stake in Lonrho was unlikely to be approved by the European Commission.</p>
<p>- Fraud running into hundreds of millions of rand will push the Unemployment Insurance Fund into deficit in the financial year to December 31, after management had budgeted for a surplus.</p>
<p>- The spectre of double-digit inflation in the near future loomed large after the announcement that inflation jumped to 9.1 percent in October from September's 8.4 percent.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- The Reserve Bank's announcement last night of a one percentage point increase in Bank rate will see the public paying more on home and car loans, hire purchase contracts, overdrafts and credit cards.</p>
<p>- Legislation to end the private owneship of water will be introduced in South Africa next year.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
