<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206236" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian opposition leader claims wife kidnapped.</title>
<headline>Serbian opposition leader claims wife kidnapped.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbian opposition leader Vuk Draskovic accused authorities on Thursday of kidnapping his wife, hours after she made inflammatory remarks urging her supporters to resort to violence.</p>
<p>&quot;This afternoon Milosevic's criminals kidnapped my wife. Nobody knows where is she now,&quot; he told Reuters Television referring to Serbia's President Slobodan Milosevic.</p>
<p>Serbian police denied they had arrested Danica Draskovic.</p>
<p>Vuk Draskovic, leader of the biggest Serbian opposition party, the Serbian Renewal Movement (SPO), was speaking after leading thousands of supporters through the streets of Belgrade in protest at what they say was widespread fraud denying them victory in Sunday's local elections.</p>
<p>Vuk said witnesses saw her being forced into a car by two men in the early afternoon in central Belgrade.</p>
<p>He accused Serbian state media of launching &quot;an incredible campaign against her last night.&quot;</p>
<p>State television and radio repeatedly broadcast comments Danica Draskovic made to reporters on Wednesday evening.</p>
<p>Asked if &quot;terrorist&quot; groups should be formed, she had replied: &quot;I can't wait for this to happen.&quot;</p>
<p>Danica Draskovic's radicalism has alienated many SPO supporters and forced some leaders to leave the party.</p>
<p>&quot;Danica is a source of major embarrassment for the party. She is too outspoken, too radical and her timing is impeccable -- for the benefit of the ruling party,&quot; one political analyst said.</p>
<p>State television used her statement to corroborate its portrayal of the opposition movement as bent on resorting to violence to achieve its goals ahead of run-off elections on November 27.</p>
<p>The Draskovic couple spent a month in jail in 1993 after leading demonstrations against the federal parliament. One policeman died in the demonstrations.</p>
<p>They were released after the West applied pressure on Milosevic and after Vuk Draskovic wrote a letter to Milosevic's wife Mirjana Markovic asking her to intercede on their behalf.</p>
<p>The opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition claimed victory in a number of major towns across the country in run-off municipal elections held on Sunday.</p>
<p>Opposition leaders have accused the authorities of committing extensive fraud to alter the results.</p>
<p>The authorities have confirmed the opposition victory in the capital Belgrade but local electoral commissions in other towns failed to announce final results by Tuesday evening as required by law.</p>
<p>The commissions, dominated by the Socialists, have cited a large number of unspecified irregularities and ordered another round of voting in towns where the opposition says it won.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
