<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206280" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Russian premier due in Minsk - Sharetsky.</title>
<headline>Russian premier due in Minsk - Sharetsky.</headline>
<text>
<p>MINSK, Nov 21 (Reuter) Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin is to leave Moscow at 7 p.m. (1600 GMT) to mediate in the Belarussian political crisis, parliament speaker Semyon Sharetsky told parliament on Thursday.</p>
<p>Earlier Itar-Tass news agency reported that Chernomyrdin had already arrived in the Belarussian capital with Russian parliamentary leaders but this appeared to be premature.  </p>
<p>Sharetsky said Chernomyrdin would initially hold separate talks with President Alexander Lukashenko while Russian speakers Yegor Stroyev and Gennady Seleznyov would meet their parliamentary counterparts.</p>
<p>&quot;Chernomyrdin will go to Lukashenko's residence and Seleznyov and Stroyev will come to parliament,&quot; Sharetsky told deputies. &quot;Later there will possibly be a joint meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Mikhail Podgainy, head of Lukashenko's information department, said Lukashenko would meet Chernomyrdin at the airport.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the Belarussian leader snubbed the Russian mediation effort, refusing to go to Smolensk for peace talks with Sharetsky. So far he has defiantly turned down pleas to drop plans to extend his powers in a referendum on Sunday which his critics say will turn the country into a dictatorship.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
