<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206237" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian prosecutor to question top Yeltsin aides.</title>
<headline>Russian prosecutor to question top Yeltsin aides.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Prosecutor General has ordered a criminal investigation of the removal of $538,000 from Russian government headquarters during the presidential election in June, Russian news agencies said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The incident pitted two camps of Kremlin advisors against each other and triggered charges of a plot to scrap the second round of the election on July 3.</p>
<p>Presidential chief of staff Anatoly Chubais, first deputy prime minister Viktor Ilyushin and their bitter enemy, former presidential bodyguard Alexander Korzhakov, would all be questioned in the next few days, the agencies said, quoting sources in the prosecutor's office.</p>
<p>Investigators led by a deputy prosecutor general will examine events of the night of June 19, between election rounds, when two men close to the presidential administration were detained and questioned for 11 hours by Korzhakov's men.</p>
<p>Sergei Lisovsky, one of the architects of Yeltsin's election campaign, and Arkady Yevstafyev, a former aide to Chubais, were accused by Korzhakov of taking the money from government headquarters.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin sacked Korzhakov and two other hardliners on June 20.</p>
<p>After Yeltsin's re-election on June 3, Chubais was named presidential chief of staff, making him one of the most powerful men in the country.</p>
<p>Lisovsky told Reuters at the time the money had been planted. But a clear explanation of the night's events has not been forthcoming.</p>
<p>Prosecutors also have launched an investigation into a newspaper's publication of an alleged transcript of a conversation between Chubais and Ilyushin on June 22. Chubais has denied holding the conversation in which the two men conspire to stop an investigation of the arrest incident.</p>
<p>The State Duma lower house of parliament, led by the dominant communist bloc, will also investigate the November 15 newspaper report, which fuelled the feud between Chubais and Korzhakov.</p>
<p>The newspaper, Moskovsky Komsomolets, hinted that the trascript came from Korzhakov's supporters, although Korzhakov denied having anything to do with it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
