<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206268" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo government adopts 1997 draft budget-Tanjug.</title>
<headline>Yugo government adopts 1997 draft budget-Tanjug.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslav government adopted the 1997 draft budget, Tanjug news agency reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget will amount to 9.238 billion dinars ($1.86 billion) or 8.94 percent of the GDP, Tanjug quoted the Federal Information Ministry statement as saying.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia's gross domestic product (GDP) is expected to grow 13 percent in 1997 to reach 103.28 billion dinars, the statement said.</p>
<p>According to the draft budget, qualified by the government as restrictive, the share of the federal budget in the country's GDP will be 0.84 percent lower than in 1996.</p>
<p>Total public spending will account for 49 billion dinars or 47.5 percent of the GDP.</p>
<p>The largest part of the federal budget -- 6.5 billion dinars -- is destined for the Yugoslav Army. This brings the share of the defence budget to 6.29 percent of the GDP from seven percent in 1996, the statement said.</p>
<p>Sales tax will be the key source of budget income in 1997, accounting for 50 percent of total budget revenue. Customs duties, import and other taxes will account for another 33 percent of the total revenue.</p>
<p>The draft is based on the government's firm commitment to continue to finance public spending from &quot;real sources&quot;, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;The 1997 federal budget is in keeping with proposed economic policy for next year, based on creating an export-oriented open market economy, and on structural changes and ownership transformation, while maintaining price and currency stability,&quot; said the statement carried by Tanjug.</p>
<p>($1 = 4.9625 dinars) -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
