<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206291" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine '96 refined sugar output seen at 3.3 mln T.</title>
<headline>Ukraine '96 refined sugar output seen at 3.3 mln T.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's refined sugar output will reach 3.3 million tonnes, including 2.8 tonnes from this year's sugar beet harvest and 561,000 tonnes from raw imports, said a top official from the state sugar concern UkrSukor on Thursday.</p>
<p>Output in 1995 was 3.49 million tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;We forecast that we will sell 1.8 million tonnes on the domestic market and the rest, 1.5 million tonnes, may be exported to our traditional buyers in neighbouring countries,&quot; deputy head Olexander Bohatarenyk told Reuters.  </p>
<p>Bohatarenyk said that Ukraine's 191 sugar refineries had so far produced 2.1 million tonnes of refined sugar and expected to refine 2.8 million tonnes from sugarbeet this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the beginning of the year we also produced 561,000 tonnes of refined sugar from imported cane or raw sugar.&quot;</p>
<p>He said that 58 refineries have finished work and processed 17.4 million tonnes of sugar beets, down from last year's levels of 24.5 million tonnes at this time.</p>
<p>Valentyn Tymoshenko, deputy head of the Agriculture Ministry's crop department, said the sugar beet harvest was nearly finished.</p>
<p>&quot;The campaign is over with 23.9 million tonnes gathered, but private farmers may add a bit more,&quot; Tymoshenko said.</p>
<p>Bohatarenyk said a drop in sugar prices to 600 hryvnia ($333) on the domestic market could result in the closure of many of the ageing refineries next year.</p>
<p>&quot;It costs each refinery 1,200 hryvnia to make a tonne of sugar. That's the real price,&quot; he said. &quot;The more sugar we produce, the worse it is for producers.&quot;</p>
<p>Ukraine's market is glutted with sugar left over from last year, when average prices were $450-460 per tonne. Many refinery workers are being paid with sugar.</p>
<p>He said Ukraine was most interested in exporting sugar to ease pressures on the domestic market.</p>
<p>But its traditional buyer, Russia, imposed a quota of 1.15 million tonnes on Ukraine earlier this month to prevent what it called dumping on its market.</p>
<p>Ukraine also expects to export to other former Soviet republics. --Yuri Kulikov, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
