<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206248" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia sees growth by 2000, problems with IMF now.</title>
<headline>Russia sees growth by 2000, problems with IMF now.</headline>
<byline>Julie Tolkacheva</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian officials on Thursday promised a thriving economy by the year 2000, but acknowledged they had problems in the latest round of talks with the International Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>Hinting the IMF might deny Russia the November tranche of a three-year $10 million loan, Economy Minister Yevgeny Yasin said: &quot;The situation is difficult. We have problems and there will be certain problems with 1997.&quot;</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund last month delayed payment of the next tranche of its $10 billion loan to Russia over concern about low levels of tax revenue.</p>
<p>An IMF mission is currently working in Moscow to assess whether to issue the tranche. Yasin said tax revenues in November were better than in October but were still too low.</p>
<p>Poor tax collection is among the toughest problems facing Russia's economy, which by many indicators is stabilising after years of decline since the Soviet Union collapsed.</p>
<p>Yasin said the cabinet had on Thursday given its blessing to a blueprint for economic development which foresees output growth of five percent a year by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an exceptionally difficult task, but we cannot do it any other way,&quot; Yasin told a news conference.</p>
<p>Russia's economy, as measured by gross domestic product, shrank by six percent in the first nine months of this year and Yasin has previously forecast a five percent GDP fall in 1996.</p>
<p>Officials have been predicting a return to growth in Russia for years but it has yet to materialise.</p>
<p>President Boris Yeltsin said after he was re-elected in July that reviving production was a key economic task.</p>
<p>The new programme foresees annual inflation of five to eight percent and a boom in foreign investment to a least $10-12 billion by 2000, Yasin said, from an expected $3.5-$4 billion this year.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very difficult programme,&quot; Yasin said. &quot;The main goal is renewal of economic growth.&quot;</p>
<p>The state statistics committee said on Thursday that if current trends continued, inflation this month could tick up to two percent, the highest monthly rate since April, from 1.3 percent last month. It also said inflation for the year could be 22 percent.</p>
<p>While high by Western standards, this would be a huge fall from last year's 131 percent.</p>
<p>The economic plan forecasts a fall in interest rates and lower yields on government securities, which economists say are needed to boost investment in Russian industry.</p>
<p>After winning cabinet approval for the programme, the economy ministry will start working out how to implement it.</p>
<p>Changes it wants include a shift to international accounting standards for Russian firms, higher gas and electricity prices for households but lower prices for industry.</p>
<p>Problems with the IMF failed to mar Russia's return to international capital markets on Thursday with its debut eurobond.</p>
<p>The issue was heavily oversubscribed despite a higher than expected $1 billion volume. The bond, paying a coupon of 9.25 percent, also had a longer-than-expected maturity of five years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
