<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206249" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine 97 budget deficit at 5.5 pct of GDP - agency.</title>
<headline>Ukraine 97 budget deficit at 5.5 pct of GDP - agency.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's 1997 budget deficit will total 5.8 billion hryvnia, or 5.5 percent of gross domestic product, Unian news agency reported Finance Minister Valentyn Koronevsky as saying on Thursday.</p>
<p>Koronevsky, speaking at an all-day government meeting to approve the draft budget, said that 2.4 billion hryvnia would be covered by foreign credits and the rest from internal sources such as Treasury bill sales, Unian said.</p>
<p>Government officials are expected to announce on Friday in parliament details of the draft budget, which under Ukrainian law must be passed by January 1.</p>
<p>Deputy Prime Minister Viktor Pynzenyk announced earlier this week that Ukraine had reached agreement with the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to raise its budget deficit to 5.8 percent of GDP, or four percent by Western calculations.</p>
<p>The agreement, which also requires Ukraine to implement tax reform next year, is expected to pave the way for the country to receive a three-year, $2.5-3.0 billion Extended Fund Facility (EFF) loan in 1997. --Irene Marushko, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
