<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206206" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SIERRA LEONE: FEATURE - Reforms boost Sierra Leone banks amid war.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Reforms boost Sierra Leone banks amid war.</headline>
<byline>Claudia McElroy</byline>
<dateline>FREETOWN 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sierra Leone's two international banks, despite economic decline and civil war in the West African country, are well on their way to recovery largely because of internal reforms, bankers say.</p>
<p>Barclays Bank of Sierra Leone Ltd, a unit of Barclays Plc, and Standard Chartered Bank Sierra Leone Ltd, part of Standard Chartered Plc, reported pre-tax profits for calendar 1995 of 1.2 billion leones ($1.3 million) and 1.3 billion leones ($1.4 million) respectively.</p>
<p>Standard Chartered said that although its assets did not grow over the year, its profits (operating and trading) trebled. Both say improved performance and better customer service, along with adequate provision for bad and doubtful debts, will continue to boost their activities and profitability.</p>
<p>Their success was in spite of all the odds stacked against the banking sector in Sierra Leone, where the productive sectors of the economy have been crippled by the rebel war with a consequent decline in the Gross Domestic Product.</p>
<p>ECONOMY ON ROCKS AS CONFLICT HITS OUTPUT</p>
<p>The closure of mainstay bauxite and rutile mines following rebel attacks in early 1995, as well as a cessation in diamond mining activity, had a drastic impact on export levels and foreign exchange earnings.</p>
<p>Diamonds, gold, iron ore, bauxite and titanium, a strategic mineral used in planes and rockets, accounted for two-thirds of the country's foreign exchange before rebels took up arms in 1991 in a campaign that has shut the foreign-owned mines.</p>
<p>Manufacturing declined, as did agricultural activity with less coffee, cocoa and tobacco available for export. These adverse conditions stoked inflation which stood at 34.5 percent at the end of last year.</p>
<p>In addition, both banks were forced to close several of their provincial branches for security reasons, and both lost important corporate customers.</p>
<p>The banks are generally guarded about how they maintained their performance, although they cite internal reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Following World Bank diagnostic studies in early 1994, the banks have been through a process of self-reform, with early provision for bad debts and generally improved performance,&quot; Standard Chartered's Managing Director John Janes told Reuters.</p>
<p>Provision for bad debts increased in 1995 from 183 million leones to 494 million, thus ensuring a 100 percent provisioning for all provincial accounts in war-affected areas.</p>
<p>Loans and advances rose from 4.7 billion leones to 5.2 billion while deposits rose from 13.2 billion leones to 14.5 billion. The bank also slashed its workforce to about 200 from 374 in 1994, while sharply raising productivity per head, Janes said.</p>
<p>BANKS COMPETE AND THRIVE DESPITE INSECURITY</p>
<p>Standard Chartered, which has been operating in Sierra Leone for more than a century, has a variety of corporate customers including Sierra Leone Brewery Ltd and two oil marketing firms.</p>
<p>It is also trading increasingly with China and Hong Kong, whose interests include fishing and diamond mining.</p>
<p>The bank is 80 percent owned by Britain's Standard Chartered Plc and 20 percent by individuals from Sierra Leone. Standard Chartered's pre-tax profit for 1995 was 661 million leones, a 30 percent improvement over the previous year.</p>
<p>There is a fair element of competition between the two international banks.</p>
<p>Barclays, which opened its first branch in Freetown in 1917, is now owned 60 percent by the British parent and 40 percent by Sierra Leone entities. It reported at the end of last year that it continues to enjoy increasing market share of the banking business with over 46 percent of the total funds raised by commercial banks, compared with 37 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>Barclays has also been able to offer competitive lending rates. In October 1996 it lowered its prime rate or minimum lending rate by five percent to 25 percent.</p>
<p>The minimum rate charged by the banks goes up to 33 percent, with Barclays prime the lowest at 25 percent, bankers say.</p>
<p>Barclays Bank's operations manager, Reginald Beury, said the prevailing climate of insecurity in various parts of the country continues to be a big problem.</p>
<p>&quot;We currently operate the only commercial bank in Northern Province, but the operational costs are now huge because we have to charter flights to get there,&quot; he said. &quot;The branch (at Makeni) is therefore running at a loss.&quot;</p>
<p>Although monetary policy is paying some dividend, there is still excess liquidity in the banking sector with low demand for banking credit.</p>
<p>There also appears to be little economic expansion. The most important pre-condition for recovery of the mining-based economy is undoubtedly lasting peace and stability, which will encourage the return of foreign investment.</p>
<p>Peace talks between the government and rebels on ending the conflict hit deadlock last May and both sides have since reported increased fighting. ($=900 leones)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SILEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FREETOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SIERRA LEONE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
