<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206322" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: Albania moves to probe spiralling pyramid schemes.</title>
<headline>Albania moves to probe spiralling pyramid schemes.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Albanian parliamentarians have called for the setting up of a parliamentary committee to investigate the Balkan country's 'get-rich-quick' pyramid schemes, an Albanian newspaper reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The parliamentary committee would consist of economic experts to control how the money invested into the pyramid schemes of companies is used, daily Rilindja Demokratike said.</p>
<p>Pyramid schemes started cropping up four years ago as new companies looked for other sources of cash, which the former Stalinist state's overstretched banking system could not supply.</p>
<p>They have lured hundreds of thousands of investors nationwide with pledges of big returns on small investments.</p>
<p>Currently, numerous firms offer interest rates of up to 50 percent a month on short-term loans for Albanians, many of them living hand to mouth.</p>
<p>The prospect of staggering returns has driven Europe's poorest citizens to hand over their hard-won savings, even selling their homes and livestock in order to join the goldrush.</p>
<p>But the schemes have begun distorting currency markets and have set off alarm bells at the international organizations.</p>
<p>The World Bank has expressed concern over the burgeoning pyramid schemes and last week, an International Monetary Fund delegation arrived in Albania to scrutinise the business.</p>
<p>Bankers warn the pyramid system could implode, robbing the man in the street of his life savings and paralysing the economy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
