<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206430" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: FOCUS - Mexican economy hums, but trade fears loom.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Mexican economy hums, but trade fears loom.</headline>
<byline>Henry Tricks</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexicans, long shell-shocked by economic crisis, may have begun to fuel growth by spending money again, according to a bullish report on the economy released on Thursday.</p>
<p>But tainting the good news was evidence that imports of consumer goods are rebounding, raising fears that Mexico may soon face its first trade deficit in almost two years.  </p>
<p>The Finance Ministry reported that gross domestic product grew 7.4 percent in the third quarter compared with the previous year, a higher figure than most analysts had expected.  It was the second consecutive quarter of year-on-year growth, and analysts said it showed the economy was on the mend after suffering its worst recession in half a century in 1995.</p>
<p>Many economists had been busily bumping up their forecasts up to hours before the report was released, on the strength of robust September industrial production data issued Monday that reflected the vitality of the export-led manufacturing sector.  </p>
<p>Projections still fell short, however, because few had expected the 5.4 percent bulge in the service sector of the economy, which accounts for some 75 percent of gross domestic product.</p>
<p>&quot;It's still early, but the very rapid growth in the manufacturing sector is beginning to trickle down,&quot; said Damian Fraser, head of Caspian Reserach in Mexico City.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a pickup in consumer spending as a result of growth in employment...and it does seem the service sector is responding to growth.&quot;  </p>
<p>In the aftermath of Mexico's traumatic December 1994 peso devaluation, Mexicans went into the consumer equivalent of a coma as more than a million people lost their jobs and soaring interest rates threw millions more into debt.</p>
<p>The only bright spot for the last two years has been the export sector, which has profited from a cheap peso and steadily dragged the economy back from the brink of collapse.  </p>
<p>Retail sales figures that reflect activity in the country's main shopping chains, have remained lackluster throughout 1996, prompting charges that the government of President Ernesto Zedillo is fostering a recovery that looks good on paper but is not improving living standards.</p>
<p>Thursday's GDP data may have changed that.  &quot;We were thinking it would be a good recovery, but not this good,&quot; said Carlos Rosales, an economist at Bancomer.</p>
<p>Analysts said it made the government's 3.7 percent growth forecast for 1996 excessively cautious.  They said the figure may end up closer to five percent than four percent.  </p>
<p>Mexico's stock market, however, failed to rally on the news, and analysts said it was checked partly by a preliminary October trade report released late Wednesday that showed a sharp decline in the trade surplus to $277 million.</p>
<p>Almost as an inevitable by-product of accelerating domestic consumption, imports of consumer goods surged more than 50 percent in October, the report showed.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry said imports were fueled in part by pre-Christmas spending, but their rebound raised fears that the days of bulging trade surpluses -- enjoyed by Mexico since its devaluation -- may be ending.  </p>
<p>&quot;The surplus is running out.  We're closer to seeing monthly deficits,&quot; said an economist who asked not to be identified, adding that exporters would begin to seek a renewed slide in the peso to keep the export impetus up.</p>
<p>For 21 consecutive months, Mexico has produced trade surpluses.  The psychological impact of ending that impressive record may also persuade the government that it should keep interest rates high to put a lid on imports, analysts said.</p>
<p>-- Mexico City newsroom +525 728-9560</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
