<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206436" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexican guerrilla group emerges with manifesto.</title>
<headline>Mexican guerrilla group emerges with manifesto.</headline>
<byline>Michael Stott</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new guerrilla force emerged on Revolution Day with a manifesto calling for an end to President Ernesto Zedillo's &quot;anti-popular and repressive&quot; government, excerpts in several newspapers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>In the seven-page document, the Revolutionary Army of Popular Insurgence (ERIP) declared it was an armed force &quot;from the people and for the people&quot; and demanded Zedillo's administration resign and call a special assembly to draft a new constitution.</p>
<p>The ERIP has not been heard of before but if its existence is confirmed it would be Mexico's third guerrilla group to arise in the last three years, after the Zapatista National Liberation Army (EZLN), which launched an armed rebellion in the southern state of Chiapas in January 1994, and the Popular Revolutionary Army (EPR), which appeared in June this year.</p>
<p>Zedillo and his key spokesmen were traveling in Asia and there was no immediate government reaction to the rebel manifesto, which was sent to media on Wednesday as Mexico celebrated the 86th anniversary of its 1910 Revolution.</p>
<p>The ERIP manifesto said it saluted and supported the &quot;heroic gesture&quot; of the armed struggle launched by the Zapatistas and the EPR in defense of Mexico's poor.</p>
<p>&quot;The ERIP is the armed expression of the popular masses who are rising up to oppose the anti-popular, repressive and servile policy of the current state which has been usurping power through fraudulent elections based on a small minority.&quot;</p>
<p>The new group said it was made up of peasants, Indians and workers as well as nationalist small businessmen who had been &quot;oppressed and exploited by the PRI-government.&quot; The PRI is the Spanish acronym for the Institutional Revolutionary Party, which has ruled Mexico for the past 67 years.</p>
<p>ERIP rebel activities would be concentrated in the center and north of Mexico, the manifesto said. The Zapatistas have operated in the southernmost state of Chiapas and the EPR has mostly attacked in the southern states of Oaxaca and Guerrero.</p>
<p>The appearance of the ERIP manifesto comes a week after Zapatista leader Subcommander Marcos said new guerrilla groups had sprung up in Mexico. &quot;There are three or four armed groups that the government does not want to recognize in (the states of) Hidalgo, Oaxaca, Veracruz and Puebla&quot;, Marcos said.</p>
<p>Asked about Marcos's assertion in an interview with Reuters on Tuesday, Zedillo said he had no knowledge of any new guerrilla group apart from the Zapatistas or the EPR. &quot;I don't know what the intelligence sources of Marcos are,&quot; he said. &quot;The only thing I know is the EZLN ... and the EPR.&quot;</p>
<p>El Universal newspaper said on Thursday that locals had spotted members of the new group since March in the mountains of the remote Papaloapan region of Oaxaca, about 145 miles (230 km) southeast of Mexico City near the border with Puebla state.</p>
<p>Residents in the area believed the new group might be led by followers of &quot;Commander Red,&quot; an army deserter named Jorge Alberto Vasquez Gallardo who led a small rebel group from 1989 until he was shot to death by security forces in 1993, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
