<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206524" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Raging inferno kills 39 on Hong Kong golden mile.</title>
<headline>Raging inferno kills 39 on Hong Kong golden mile.</headline>
<byline>Peter Humphrey</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fire engulfed a 16-floor shop and office block in a bustling Hong Kong tourist district, killing almost 40 people and injuring scores of others in the territory's worst building blaze on record.</p>
<p>The inferno flared up on Wednesday evening and raged through the night, gutting seven floors. Some 300 firemen and 50 fire took almost 24 hours to quell the blaze.</p>
<p>The confirmed death toll on Thursday reached 39, including one fireman, fire chief Peter Cheung said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still trying to identify bodies and relate those reported missing to those we already know have been killed but whose bodies have not yet been identified,&quot; Chris Patten, governor of the British colony, told its Legislative Council.</p>
<p>Officials said 81 were injured and more than 110 rescued. Of the injured, 46 were still in hospital.</p>
<p>Cheung said he had received reports that welding work had been under way in the building's elevator area, on the ground floor where a Chinese arts and crafts store was located.</p>
<p>&quot;An eye witness claimed that welding work was in progress in one of the lift shafts...and that a spark from the welding ignited combustibles at the bottom of the shafts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The fire spread quickly from the ground right up to the top floors, he added. Investigations were continuing, he stressed.</p>
<p>The closed design of the department store at the bottom of the Garley Building on Nathan Road, Kowloon, was believed to be a big factor in the fast spread of the fire.</p>
<p>The situation was worsened by the lack of an up-to-date fire protection system in the building, Cheung added. Many older buildings in Hong Kong have few, if any, anti-fire devices.</p>
<p>People trapped behind sealed windows on Wednesday night ripped off burning clothes, while others scrambled to safety.</p>
<p>A plume of flame lit up the sky above Hong Kong harbour but later gave way to a black cloud of smoke that hung over the building on the &quot;golden mile&quot; of the Kowloon tourist district.</p>
<p>In dramatic scenes, firefighters plucked survivors from the block, a maze of small offices, shops and workshops, and some were winched off the blazing roof by helicopter.</p>
<p>The fire rapidly engulfed the first four storeys of the building before racing up the lift shaft to the top three.</p>
<p>Smoke blanked out the vision of daring helicopter pilots who flew dangerous missions over rooftops to winch away survivors.</p>
<p>Others jumped from window ledges on to rescue ladders and some scrambled on to air conditioners, observed helplessly by friends and relatives far below in the crowded street.</p>
<p>One of the dead was a fireman killed while battling the blaze. Liu Chi-ho, 40, plunged down a lift shaft.</p>
<p>Another man fell from the building in a rush to escape. Witnesses said they saw him climb from a window and cling to an air conditioner which gave way and sent him tumbling several storeys onto a canopy, where he lay crumpled and still.</p>
<p>Officials said 17 of the charred bodies were found on the 15th floor on Thursday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;This was the most serious (tower block) fire and the one with the most number of deaths and injuries in the past 100 years,&quot; Cheung said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's worst fire on record was in 1918 when 600 people were killed and 400 injured in a blaze at the Happy Valley Racecourse on Hong Kong Island.</p>
<p>A disaster in 1947 killed 149 people when a ship burned in the harbour. In 1953 a Christmas blaze killed an unknown number of people in a squatter village and left 60,000 homeless.</p>
<p>Officials sounded alarm bells about building safety, an issue of protracted debate in the densely populated territory.</p>
<p>Patten visited the spot and later pressed for the speedy passage of legislation to tighten fire regulations. Many older buildings have few, if any, anti-fire devices.</p>
<p>Britain's Queen Elizabeth and Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind sent messages of condolence to Patten on Thursday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
