<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206521" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Paradise dresses up for the Clintons.</title>
<headline>Paradise dresses up for the Clintons.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>PORT DOUGLAS, Australia 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Even paradise needs to be spruced up when the U.S. president comes to town.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 palm trees in this tropical resort on Australia's northeast coast have been pruned and the town's four-mile (seven-km) beach swept for the arrival of Bill and Hillary Rodham Clinton and a few hundred security, media and government personnel.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there wasn't anything the locals could do about the unsociable box jellyfish, whose deadly sting has placed the tantalising aqua-blue Pacific Ocean off limits at this time of year.</p>
<p>The Clintons will have to settle for a plunge in the pool of the Sheraton Mirage resort -- one of Australia's most expensive and the Clintons' Australian beach house for two days after their arrival on Thursday night.</p>
<p>On Friday they go to the Great Barrier Reef, the world's largest coral reef system, 30 nautical miles offshore. In fact, it's actually 2,600 reefs linked for 2,500 km (1,550 miles) along the coast.</p>
<p>There are no box jellyfish out there, just lots of well-fed colourful fish and reef sharks.</p>
<p>The Clintons plan to snorkel on the reef on Friday and perhaps Saturday. They also plan to play golf or visit a rainforest after a hectic re-election campaign and before next week's Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation summit in the Philippines.</p>
<p>Port Douglas, a hideaway for the rich and famous on Australia's far northeast coast, was once simply a name on a map depicting a river estuary.</p>
<p>Its population swelled to 12,000 in 1882 with fortune hunters attracted by the gold rush on the Palmer River. To quench the gold diggers' thirst, 27 hotels opened.</p>
<p>At the turn of the century it became a busy port for the local sugar cane industry, but with the arrival of the railway it reverted again to a sleepy fishing village, boasting a population of 100 in 1960.</p>
<p>Port Douglas gained its international celebrity status in 1988 when Australian entrepreneur Christopher Skase built the opulent Sheraton Mirage resort on the town's beach.</p>
<p>Skase's businesses failed, and he is now holed up on the Spanish island of Majorca to avoid Australian extradition, but Port Douglas has continued to attract such celebrities as Mick Jagger, Jerry Hall and Tom Cruise.</p>
<p>Skase trucked in more than 1,000 palms to line the streets leading to his resort and this week those same palms have been pruned to their tropical best.</p>
<p>And if the president decides to take an early morning jog along Four Mile Beach, he'll find sparkling white sand -- the Queensland state government has spent A$20,000 (US$15,800) removing sugar cane trash deposited during recent storms.</p>
<p>&quot;The president probably won't notice the difference, or the palm trees, but there are two or three hundred other people coming and I think it's quite legitimate for us to say we want our town looking its best,&quot; says Mayor Mike Berwick.</p>
<p>But for the majority of Port Douglas' laid-back residents the arrival of the Clintons is a bit like a tropical downpour -- they come and they go.</p>
<p>&quot;I couldn't care less. I think we copy the Americans too much,&quot; said Dorothy Tobler who plays bingo at the local hall every Thursday night.</p>
<p>&quot;Anyway, it's too hot here, he's really going to feel the heat,&quot; Tobler said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT DOUGLAS, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
