<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206639" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Congressman says U.S. aiding China arms buildup.</title>
<headline>Congressman says U.S. aiding China arms buildup.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A House Republican committee chairman said Thursday that China was exploiting Clinton administration-approved U.S. arms sales to modernize its military as fast as possible.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very concerned that we're selling our edge in military technology to a nation that may well be our adversary some day,&quot; Rep. Floyd Spence, chairman of the House National Security Committee, said in a statement.</p>
<p>Spence said he was concerned that the Clinton administration had put the commercial arms sales interests above U.S. national security.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not compromise our national security by giving the Chinese the means to increase their military effectiveness,&quot; the South Carolina Republican said.</p>
<p>Spence made the comments in releasing four reports on U.S. trade with China and while Secretary of State Warren Christopher was in Beijing trying to improve U.S.-Sino relations.</p>
<p>&quot;When you add it all up, it is clear that China's military is exploiting the existing international technology transfer rules -- even breaking specific agreements and U.S. laws -- to modernize as fast as it can,&quot; Spence said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am particularly concerned about the recent expansion of sensitive military technology exports to China, he said.</p>
<p>He said that despite strong warnings from U.S. military and intelligence officials, the Clinton administration allowed a sale of advanced machine tools to China in 1994 that China diverted from civilian use to use in a factory that makes combat planes, ballistic missiles and cruise missiles.</p>
<p>Spence released a congressional General Accounting Office report saying McDonnell Douglas had used the parts-shaping machines to make U.S. military planes and missiles but sold them to China for its manufacture of civilian airliners.</p>
<p>But some of the machines were instead shipped to China's Nanchang Aircraft Co, which produces military planes and missiles as well as civilian products, the GAO report said.</p>
<p>It said that diversion was prohibited by conditions the U.S. government imposed on the sale and the machines were moved before they could be misused.</p>
<p>A second GAO report said AT&amp;T sold high-speed picture and sound telecommunications equipment, used for tele-conferencing and telemedicine, to HuaMei, a civilian joint venture that has a partner controlled by China's military.</p>
<p>The report said the U.S. exporter is responsible for assuring the equipment is sold to a civilian company. But it said the equipment could be used for military command and control and it is hard for the U.S. exporter to know whether HuaMei is a civilian company despite the military involvement.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
