<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206875" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs and pork bellies fall on technicals.</title>
<headline>CME hogs and pork bellies fall on technicals.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Technical fund liquidation kept CME hog and pork belly futures pressured at the close despite scattered short covering, tradres said.</p>
<p>Sell stops were hit early, but prices recovered somewhat late on short covering with hogs ending 0.950 to 0.100 cent lower and pork bellies closing 2.075 to 1.175 cents lower. December hogs finished 0.725 lower at 57.500 cents while February pork bellies paced the loss at 73.950 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't had a decent correction in some time and the market was overdue technically to adjust from the (recent) runup to a new high,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>December posted a new contract high Wednesday and broke shaprly to close lower. This was viewed as technically very neagative to the market which sparked long fund liquidation into sell stops, traders said.</p>
<p>Fundamental resistance was also starting to develop on indications of prices slipping in pork products and lower indications for cash hogs by next week, they said.</p>
<p>Expectations are that packers will show reduced demand for hogs during Thanksgiving week when kill rates decline. Pork prices also also will come under seasonal pressure as retailers turn to featuring traditional holiday items.  </p>
<p>&quot;You're not going to have the cutout on the pork side to support the kind of live hog prices that (packers) are paying right now,&quot; said John Nalivka, President of Sterling Marketing Inc.</p>
<p>All of the pork cuts are going to weaken and packers will likely lower bids for hogs, even though there is continued good competition among packers to fill the large slaughter capacity, Nalivka added.</p>
<p>Record high hog weights also made some traders nervous despite packers  looking for the heavier hogs which are more profitable to slaughter, analysts said.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture reported Iowa/southern Minnesota average hog weights the week ended November 11 at a record 255 lbs versus the previous record of 254.9 lbs  set in December 1994.</p>
<p>Pork bellies followed the lead of hogs with increased hog slaughter and easier tone to cash bellies weighing on values and sending futures into a technical correction. Even though hog kills are seen easing next week due to the holiday and stored stocks are at low levels, futures looked technically weak after meeting heavy chart resistance under 80.000 cents on Monday, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;They're (chartists) looking for a 50 percent correction from recent highs,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Commercial buying was evident at times on the scale down as well as from the expected lighter holiday hog slaughter rate next week and Friday's USDA monthly Cold Storage report.</p>
<p>The report is expected to show frozen pork belly stocks at historically low levels for this time of year. The average analyst estimate for the report was 16.0 million lbs in cold storage and compares with the average for the last 10 years of 22.8 million lbs.</p>
<p>--Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
