<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206879" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soybeans close lower on wheat break, setback.</title>
<headline>CBOT soybeans close lower on wheat break, setback.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT soybean futures closed lower on a late break in wheat futures plus a short-term technical setback on signals the market was overbought, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The wheat break weakened beans a little,&quot; said Ron Kucha of O'Connor and Co.</p>
<p>The wheat market rallied strongly Wednesday and was due for a setback amid signals the market was overbought and the soybean market also was viewed as short-term overbought.</p>
<p>Soybeans underwent a key technical reversal Wednesday and sagged slightly Thursday on profit taking.</p>
<p>Market sources said Wednesday's rally marked a key technical reversal in the January contract and suggested prices could climb above $7.14 per bushel in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>The session high for January was $7.12 per bushel which is where buying waned and the session low of $7.03 was set near the close.</p>
<p>Commercial buying was featured early in the session along with follow through from Wednesday's technical breakout.</p>
<p>Soybeans closed 3/4 to four cents per bushel lower, with January down one cent at $7.06.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
