<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="206905" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US spot natgas rises sharply on cold,storage fears.</title>
<headline>US spot natgas rises sharply on cold,storage fears.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot natgas prices gained an additional 30-40 cents Thursday, catapulted upward by cold U.S. weather forecasts through next week and concerns that storage supplies are not sufficient for the upcoming winter heating season, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Gulf Coast prices rose by about 30 cents to the mid-$3.60s to mid-$3.70s, with the lower-priced deals confirmed done late.</p>
<p>Many buyers said they were hesitant to venture into the December market before NYMEX's December Henry Hub contract expires this afternoon.  </p>
<p>November business continued at a harried pace in the New York city-gate market as temperatures were forecast to remain as much as 10 degrees Fahrenheit below-normal through next week in the region.</p>
<p>New York prices for Friday delivery ranged anywhere from the high-$4 area early to the $4.30s late.</p>
<p>Indications for December 1 delivery at the New York city-gate were about $1.35-1.45 over the NYMEX screen, placing the market near $5.</p>
<p>American Gas Association said Wednesday that in the week ending November 15, gas stocks in the Consuming East Region fell by 58 billion cubic feet to 92 percent of capacity.</p>
<p>In the Midcontinent, where storage levels were about 69 percent full and temperatures still hovered below-normal, prices were up nearly 50 cents to the $3.60s and $3.70s, with some early deals done as high as $4.00.</p>
<p>In south Texas prices rose by more than 30 cents to the mid-$3.50s as temperatures in the region ran five to 10 degrees above-normal. More seasonable weather was anticipated at the end of week.</p>
<p>In west Texas, Permian prices ranged anywhere from the $3.90s to the $3.30s, up an average of 50 cents, as most supplies moved westward to the California markets.</p>
<p>As a result, prices at the southern California border soared into the low-$4 area early but then settled back into the $3.60s late, up an average of 40 cents from Wednesday.</p>
<p>Early in the session, NYMEX's December Henry Hub natural gas futures jumped to a new contract high of $3.85.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
