<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207006" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian deputy PM probe to be continued - parliament.</title>
<headline>Belgian deputy PM probe to be continued - parliament.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium's parliament on Thursday supported a recommendation by a panel of its members to ask the country's highest court to investigate further under-age sex allegations against Deputy Prime Minister Elio Di Rupo.</p>
<p>A full session voted 103-20 in favour of the recommendation agreed by the parliamentary commission in the early hours of Thursday to request the Cour de Cassation to look into the allegations.</p>
<p>Di Rupo strongly denies he had sex with young boys.</p>
<p>In Belgium homosexuality is allowed by law, but paedophilia -- sex with children younger than 16 -- is a crime.</p>
<p>Raymond Langendries, the lower house chairman who also chaired the 11-member commission, said after the closed-door vote: &quot;The Chamber adopted by 103 to 20 votes the recommendation of the special commission on Mr Di Rupo.&quot;</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear how many abstentions or absentees there had been during the vote in the 150-seat parliament.</p>
<p>The vote was due to be followed by a question and answer session with Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene, who was expected to speak out on the issue for the first time since the allegations emerged in the Belgian press last weekend.</p>
<p>The court has been asked to submit a report on its findings by December 9 at the latest. The commission will then decide whether the evidence against Di Rupo, a discreet gay, is strong enough to recommend he be indicted and sent for trial.</p>
<p>Langendries said the parliament would send a fact-finding mission to the Cour de Cassation.</p>
<p>&quot;The public prosecutor and the court must detail whether they believe there are sufficient indications to justify starting the process of charging (Di Rupo),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The commission made its recommendation on the basis of a report presented by the Brussels public prosecutor, but ruled parliament would need more information for a more definite assessment of the allegations.</p>
<p>For Di Rupo to be charged, parliament would have to vote to lift his constitutional immunity. That would surely mean the end of his rapid rise in the francophone Socialist Party to the second most senior position in the Belgian government.</p>
<p>By deferring a final recommendation on his fate, the parliamentary commission set a bomb ticking under Belgium's centre-left coalition government.</p>
<p>Even if the case is thrown out Di Rupo has been politically weakened -- perhaps mortally wounded, although so far it is only opposition politicians who are openly calling for his head.</p>
<p>Di Rupo himself refuses to step down outright.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
