<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207058" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: One EU resident in three scared to go out after dark.</title>
<headline>One EU resident in three scared to go out after dark.</headline>
<byline>Janet McEvoy</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>One person in three living in the European Union does not feel safe walking in their own neighbourhood after dark.</p>
<p>A survey based on interviews with 16,000 EU residents since the beginning of the year showed that while EU citizens might not feel any safer than U.S. citizens, they were still more at ease than their neighbours in eastern Europe, where one in two is scared to go out at night.</p>
<p>Within the European Union, people living in the former East Germany feel most at risk from crime. There, almost two people out of three are afraid to go out after dark, the survey, which was commissioned by the Union, said.</p>
<p>Next in line are residents of Spain (39 percent), Ireland (37 percent), Portugal (34 percent) and western Germany (34 percent), the survey, presented to a seminar on urban delinquency and its links with drugs dependence, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Comparing the rates of global regions show that the EU safety level in urban areas is similar to that in North America and Asia,&quot; the European Commission said in a statement on the survey, prepared at the Dutch State University of Leiden.</p>
<p>It said that contacts with the drugs scene increased the fear.</p>
<p>Fourteen percent of those interviewed said they had seen people openly dealing with drugs, found syringes in parks or been victims of drugs-linked violent crime.</p>
<p>But the survey showed that people were also put off by teenagers loitering on street corners, litter on the streets, graffiti, beggars and tramps, along with abandoned houses and broken windows.</p>
<p>While 44 percent of women were afraid, 19 pecent of men were, although the survey admitted men might be too macho to admit that they were scared.</p>
<p>The fear increased according to the size of the city and was more prevalent in younger and older people and among people with less money.</p>
<p>&quot;The unequal distribution of fear...can be illustrated by a comparison between two extreme groups. Of the young males living in villages nine percent feel unsafe. By contrast 62 percent of women of 55 and older living in the Union's largest cities feels unsafe,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>People in Denmark, Finland, Sweden, the Netherlands and Austria feel the safest when compared to their EU partners about going out at night. Only 11 percent of Danes said they were too scared to go out.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
