<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207050" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Truck drivers made parties to Channel tunnel probe.</title>
<headline>Truck drivers made parties to Channel tunnel probe.</headline>
<dateline>CALAIS, France 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twenty-six lorry drivers have joined a French prosecutors' probe into the causes of a fire in the Channel Tunnel which injured eight people and temporarily shut down the Franco-British rail link, their lawyer said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;They want to ensure that light be shed on what happened in the tunnel,&quot; attorney Gilbert Collard said.</p>
<p>The 26 drivers allowed to join the French probe as civil plaintiffs were aboard the train when it burst into flames inside the tunnel late on Monday.</p>
<p>The suit, filed against unknown defendants, seeks to determine through an official investigation whether there was criminal fault in the fire or the subsequent rescue effort.</p>
<p>One key aspect of the French probe, the lawyer said, would be to determine if there were delays in efforts to rescue those caught on the train when smoke began pouring into their carriage.</p>
<p>The fire broke out on a truck-carrying shuttle train.</p>
<p>Collard said the drivers hoped to ensure that the fire would not erroneously be blamed on the truckers and that the true cause of the blaze would not be covered up for economic reasons.</p>
<p>The 51-km (32-mile) tunnel partially reopened on Thursday, after being closed since a fire on a truck transporter train badly damaged a section of track and cables late on Monday.</p>
<p>Seventy fire-fighters from Britain and France, in special breathing suits, put out the blaze aboard the England-bound freight train after an all-night battle, in a first test of the elaborate safety systems designed to counter everything from earthquakes to guerrillas.</p>
<p>The truck drivers and train crew were evacuated from toxic fumes created by the fire.</p>
<p>Unconfirmed reports said the fire broke out in a truck carrying polystyrene.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALAIS, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
