<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207068" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: FOCUS - Peseta romps ahead on inflation comments.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Peseta romps ahead on inflation comments.</headline>
<byline>Merissa Marr</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The peseta romped ahead against the mark on Thursday to levels not seen since May after positive inflation comments from the central bank and as traders tested the Bank of Spain's willingness to intervene.</p>
<p>But as the peseta steamed through the key psychological 84.00 per mark barrier to 83.85 traders said the Bank of Spain eventually entered the market to brake the currency's strength.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Bank of Spain was just trying to find out how serious the appreciation was,&quot; said Jose Luis Alzola, economist at Salomon Brothers in London.</p>
<p>Traders said the Bank of Spain sold pesetas around 83.85 per mark to stem the tide but the central bank declined to comment.</p>
<p>The Bank of Spain has been seen intervening in recent months to prevent the peseta from breaking the 84.00 per mark barrier but traders said it had been absent from the market for some weeks.</p>
<p>Analysts said Thursday's intervention proved that the peseta would remain in the grip of the central bank which is keen to hold the currency in the 84.00 to 85.00 per mark band in the run up to a single European currency.</p>
<p>By 1615 GMT the peseta was trading at 84.10 per mark, after hitting 83.85 earlier in the session and compared with late Wednesday levels of 84.11.</p>
<p>The Spanish currency was given an early boost by positive inflation comments from Bank of Spain governor Luis Angel Rojo.</p>
<p>Rojo said final 1996 inflation could be around 3.3 percent, lower than the government's target of around 3.4 percent.</p>
<p>He added that inflation would be below three percent in the first few months of next year and between 2.5 and 2.6 percent by the end of 1997, allowing Spain to get close to meeting the Maastricht inflation criteria.</p>
<p>&quot;The actual projections are not that different from the market consensus but the fact the central bank is actually saying them reflects a new confidence that it can achieve these projections,&quot; said Alzola.</p>
<p>Traders said the comments had temporarily reignited hopes for an interest rate cut on Friday but analysts said this was unlikley.</p>
<p>&quot;We are bound for monetary easing but probably not until December when the bank will have November CPI behind it as well,&quot; said Henrik Lumholdt, economist at Bank of America in Madrid, adding that he expected the central bank to cut rates by 100 basis points in December.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll on Thursday found that economists were still expecting the Bank of Spain to keep its key money rate unchanged at 6.75 percent on Friday at its regular repurchase auction.</p>
<p>In line with Lumholdt's view, economists said the central bank would wait for November inflation data to confirm a descending trend in consumer prices before sanctioning its seventh offical rate cut of the year.</p>
<p>On the peseta front, analysts said they expected the central bank to continue braking the peseta in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>&quot;Central bank intervention has been considerable this year as reflected in the level of the currency reserves which have increased by 45 percent since the beginning of the year,&quot; said Lumbholdt, adding that Spain's currency reserves currently stood around $58 billion compared with January levels of $40 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The peseta wants to get stronger but the central bank will not let it and so the currency reserves could go to ridiculous highs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He added that without Bank of Spain intervention the peseta would probably have strengthened to around 81.00 per mark considering the inflows of money into the Spanish bond market.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
