<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207036" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: EU raises wheat subsidy in test of pledge to U.S.</title>
<headline>EU raises wheat subsidy in test of pledge to U.S.</headline>
<byline>Tim Hepher</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union moved closer to a new spat with Washington on Thursday by appearing to let its wheat growers undercut U.S. prices for the first time in months as farmers raised fears of a global grain war, analysts said.</p>
<p>Meeting in Brussels under heavy industry pressure to counter unstable foreign wheat prices, EU officials said they had agreed to a slight increase in export subsidies to help the world's second biggest producing area tackle competition.</p>
<p>Subsidies went up by around $1 a tonne to around $22 a tonne, allowing farmers to sell wheat grown for $180 a tonne to developing countries for less than $160 without making a loss.</p>
<p>But in a break with weeks of shadow-boxing between the EU and Washington over prices, analysts said the new subsidies allowed European farmers to undercut U.S. wheat costs.</p>
<p>U.S. farmers are just about alone in seeing their wheat prices hold stable -- and even rise slightly this week -- because harvests there have been relatively disappointing.</p>
<p>That means that the EU would have had to cut subsidies this week to keep prices in line with the United States, analysts said. Subsidies close the gap between generally higher prices in Europe and lower prices in the United States and elsewhere.</p>
<p>&quot;I am surprised they did this. The EU is under a lot of pressure from Washington to hold the line on prices,&quot; said an analyst in Geneva where most of the grain business operates.</p>
<p>U.S. soft red winter wheat prices were around $165 on Thursday, giving Europeans an advantage of at least five dollars a tonne against the type of wheat Brussels uses as a beacon.</p>
<p>Despite efforts to ease past tensions, wheat remains one of the toughest areas for Brussels and Washington to agree on.</p>
<p>The EU drew Washington's wrath in September for reviving wheat export subsidies that once provoked bitter trade clashes between the world's food superpowers.</p>
<p>Both sides abandoned the costly hand-outs when wheat prices started a record-breaking streak last year. But the EU says subsidies are needed again now that world prices have collapsed beneath $200 a tonne from a peak of nearly $300 seen in April.</p>
<p>To placate U.S. critics who want the Clinton administration to fight subsidies with subsidies, Brussels has repeatedly pledged not to sell its wheat for less than U.S. growers can get on the world market without any government aid.</p>
<p>European officials were quick to play down the effects of Thursday's decision, saying it was meant to correct short-term imbalances and would not leave U.S. farmers at a disadvantage in the New Year when competition is expected to be intense.</p>
<p>One official said there had been no policy change.</p>
<p>But traders sensed victory in a decision they hailed as the reversal of an ill-judged experiment. Many had blamed the practice of tracking tight U.S. wheat markets for losing them business to cheaper selling from Argentina and elsewhere.</p>
<p>&quot;If this continues we are going to see our markets pinched by Argentina, Australia and Canada,&quot; veteran trader Jean-Pierre Dresti of French firm Soufflet said earlier on Thursday.</p>
<p>There was no immediate U.S. reaction but Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman said last week he had not ruled out bringing back U.S. subsidies to counter EU trade practices.</p>
<p>The growing fight for wheat sales is good news for importers just months after grain was being treated as gold.</p>
<p>Argentina's record wheat crop is being sold for less than $140 a tonne. And a rebound from drought in Australia leaves many predicting prices will tumble further in the New Year.</p>
<p>Australian farmers, who get no official export help, urged their government on Thursday to protect them from the threat of a new transatlantic subsidy war.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton said in Canberra this week that Washington would not harm free-trade exporters like Australia. But the Australian farm federation said it would only be convinced when all subsidy programmes were dismantled fully.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
