<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207182" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU says Russia must prepare more for WTO.</title>
<headline>EU says Russia must prepare more for WTO.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Gaunt</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union urged Russia on Thursday to prepare for membership of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) by pledging not to introduce measures that break its rules.</p>
<p>It also said it wanted commitments by Moscow to tighten up protection of intellectual property rights, to liberalise its steel and textile industries, the latter over four years, and to open its markets to a range of goods and services.</p>
<p>EU funds from its TACIS programme, the main development programme for the former Soviet Union, could be used to help Moscow reach these goals, the Commission said.</p>
<p>At a meeting with Russian Deputy Prime Minister Oleg Davydov, European Trade Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan and External Affairs Commission Hans van den Broek said the EU supported Moscow's goal of joining the WTO.</p>
<p>&quot;Being part of the WTO (will) build confidence in Russia and attract foreign investment,&quot; said an official of the EU executive, which negotiates trade for the 15-nation bloc. Such investment came to $3 billion last year, tiny for a massive country.</p>
<p>The official said the two commissioners had urged Russia to issue a standstill agreement under which it would agree not to introduce any trade measures that were incompatible with the WTO while its was preparing to join.</p>
<p>Brittan noted that China, which also wants to join the world trade body, had agreed to institute such an agreement.</p>
<p>The Commission official said that Davydov, who is also foreign trade minister, had dismissed any similarity between Russia and China.</p>
<p>China, he was reported as saying, was only interested in economic reform while Russia was seeking democratic reform as well, which complicated the idea of a standstill agreement and meant it needed tricky legislative approval.</p>
<p>In specific sectors, the Commission told Davydov it wanted an EU-Russia textile agreement that expires at the end of the year to be renewed along with a commitment by Moscow to liberalise the industry over a four-year period.</p>
<p>It said it wanted the agreement initialled by December 6 so that it could come into force in January.</p>
<p>&quot;Davydov said he was prepared to discuss it, but that Russia is a net importer (of textiles) and is in no way a threat to the EU,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Brittan and van den Broek listed a series of steps the Commission wanted Russia to take.</p>
<p>These included agreeing to liberalise the steel sector, enforcing and strengthening intellectual property rights, making &quot;serious&quot; market access offers, committing itself to opening up government procurement, and adopting international standards.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Davydov was basically prepared to accept these as a basis for discussion,&quot; the Commission official said.</p>
<p>He said Davydov had reiterated Moscow's wish to have a free trade agreement with the EU in the long run and repeated a suggestion that it might agree one first with Poland, which is likely to join the EU sometime early in the next decade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
