<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207193" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian shares end down on politics, result worries.</title>
<headline>Indian shares end down on politics, result worries.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>**  Indian shares finish lower on Thursday as disappointing corporate results continue to pour in, traders say</p>
<p>**  The adjournment of parliament for a second consecutive day makes investors in Delhi jittery</p>
<p>**  Bombay's benchmark index falls 19.2 points to 3043.30, National Stock Exchange index ends 6.79 points down at 869.82</p>
<p>**  Shares of Tata Chemicals hit after first half net falls below last year; Tata Tea ends lower as results fail to cheer</p>
<p>**  April-September industrial growth slows to 4.8 percent from 12.8 percent during the corresponding period last year</p>
<p>**  Finance firm IDBI reports modest 2.0 percent growth in net for the six months to September 30, 1996</p>
<p>--  </p>
<p>Indian shares closed lower on Thursday as disappointing first half results continued to pour in and traders said unpleasant surprises were still in store.</p>
<p>&quot;There was quite a bit of selling in pivotals probably due to the bad results and the news that industrial production figures are down,&quot; said a trader at a foreign brokerage.</p>
<p>India's April-September industrial growth has slowed to 4.8 percent from 12.8 percent during the corresponding period last year, according to the latest data released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are waiting for some positive signal,&quot; the trader said.  </p>
<p>A study by securities firm Dil Vikas Finance Ltd found first half results of Indian companies announced so far have shown a modest 4.0 percent growth in net profit and a 2.1 percent fall in earnings. The study included a sample of 181 firms which announced results until November 19.</p>
<p>R. Balakrishnan, president at Dil Vikas said second half performance would largely depend on commodity prices in the remaining part of 1996/97 (April-March).</p>
<p>&quot;Interest rates have not declined across-the-board as the prime lending rate (PLR) reduction benefits just a handful of companies,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Shares of Tata Chemicals -- which announced a fall in first half net on Wednesday -- fell 9.75 percent to 180.50 rupees.</p>
<p>Finance firm IDBI's results fell below market expectations.</p>
<p>Tata Tea shares were not cheered by a 25 percent jump in first half net. The firm said the year-ago figure was adjusted for impact of increased wages. It said profit margins in the second half would be hit on the back of falling tea prices.</p>
<p>In Delhi, shares ended sharply lower on nervous selling by foreign funds after parliament adjourned for a second successive day. The index ended 9.37 points down at 676.16. -- Priya Ramani, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
