<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207297" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Kirch's digital TV gets off to a slow start.</title>
<headline>German Kirch's digital TV gets off to a slow start.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bavarian media mogul Leo Kirch's digital pay TV network DF1, falling far short of its goals, said on Thursday that Deutsche Telekom was holding up development by blocking access to its cable TV network.</p>
<p>Just four months after its much-hyped launch, DF1 has obtained just 20,000 subscribers, making it impossible to reach its goal of 200,000 paying customers by the end of the year, said Kirch Group managing director Gottfried Zmeck.</p>
<p>Zmeck told reporters in Hamburg that the company still aimed to have three million subscribers by the year 2001.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom, which this week completed Europe's largest share offering, and Kirch have been in talks about broadcasting DF1 programming over Telekom's cable network, which reaches 16 million homes.</p>
<p>But after a bitter clash between Kirch and German media giant Bertelsmann AG over the basic pay TV decoder technology, in which Kirch emerged as victor, Telekom said it wants to develop its own decoder, stalling a deal with Kirch.</p>
<p>Zmeck said Telekom was preventing DF1's integration into the cable TV network because Telekom hoped to compete against Kirch in digital pay TV.</p>
<p>DF1 is currently only available to German households over the Astra direct-to-home satellite television network.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, DF1 plans a marketing offensive during the year-end holiday shopping season. It will launch a 15 million mark advertising campaign and plans to expand sports coverage.</p>
<p>DF1 is also expanding its basic programming package and has just completed a deal to include six channels from MultiThematiques, a pay TV programme package whose owners include Canal Plus and Telecommunications International, Inc.</p>
<p>The MultiThematiques package will include the documentary channel Planet, a European fishing and hunting channel called Seasons, a youth-oriented film and music channel called Jimmy, and Cyber TV, a computer channel.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 2609750</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
