<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207326" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: East German insolvents belie boom promise.</title>
<headline>East German insolvents belie boom promise.</headline>
<byline>Mark John</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The collapse of some 5,000 east German firms so far this year is proof that, six years after unification, Chancellor Helmut Kohl's promise of a &quot;blossoming landscape&quot; in the region is just not happening.</p>
<p>Official statistics on Thursday showed a 37 percent jump in east German company insolvencies in the first eight months of the year -- underlining that the ex-communist east still cannot stand on its own feet, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;East Germany was once seen as a possible boost, but now it's becoming more of a ball and chain for the rest of the country,&quot; Thomas Mayer, chief economist at investment house Goldman Sachs in Frankfurt said.</p>
<p>Gloom surrounding the figures was compounded by comments from Kurt Biedenkopf, premier of the eastern state of Saxony, who said in a speech on Thursday that the gap between east and west was more likely to grow further in the near future.</p>
<p>Subsidies to the east, running at some 150 billion marks ($100 billion) a year since unification in 1990, amount to around five percent of German Gross Domestic Product and are largely funded by a deeply unpopular 7.5 percent &quot;solidarity tax&quot; on incomes.</p>
<p>While nobody suggests that problems in the east could prevent Germany's entry into the single European currency, eastern jobless totals of 15 percent and rising animosity between east and west Germans are not without their economic and social costs.</p>
<p>That was not what Helmut Kohl, architect of the unification project, envisaged when he promised a &quot;blossoming landscape&quot; of economic regeneration for which west Germans would not have to pay with a rise in taxes.</p>
<p>But economists said the root problem is that the east, struggling with the legacy of an under-performing industrial base, is still living beyond its means.</p>
<p>A government report published in September showed the region's GDP made up only two-thirds of its consumption and blamed &quot;excessively high unit labour costs&quot;, estimated at an average 30 percent above western levels.</p>
<p>According to Goldman Sachs' Mayer, the German system of collective wage bargaining under which trade unions meet employer federations to hammer out industry-wide wage deals means that the problem will not go away quickly.</p>
<p>&quot;That system is being eroded as more and more firms start to make their own arrangements on wages, but the existence of these 'wage cartels' means this will be a lengthier process than it otherwise would be,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mayer bemoaned a decision last week by German building employers to agree a minimum wage for east German workers close to that in the west, despite what is widely seen as the east's lower productivity level.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to blame both the unions and the employer federations for this type of thing -- these contracts require two sets of signatures,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But other economists said that the wage issue aside, the structural problems presented to east German companies by the collapse of communism were inevitable and long-term.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not surprising that companies there are going belly up -- they had their markets taken away from them,&quot; Ros Lifton, senior international economist at Midland Global Markets Research.</p>
<p>Victims have included firms such Magdeburg-based machinery company, SKET GmbH, which as a major supplier to communist eastern Europe had a workforce of 18,000.</p>
<p>Now in liquidation after years of losses since unification and the collapse of communist governments in the east opened up its main markets to western rivals, the group is now facing an uncertain future supporting a workforce of under 600.</p>
<p>Lifton said that east German firms were still struggling either to compete for domestic demand with western companies offering goods perceived as more attractive, or to tailor their product line for other eastern European markets.</p>
<p>But Saxony premier Biedenkopf, in a speech delivered in the eastern town of Dresden, said that above all Germans must be &quot;realistic&quot; about how quickly the east could catch up with the more affluent west.</p>
<p>He said that even if eastern growth rates could continue above those seen in the west -- a possibility he thought was unlikely -- production levels there would only reach three-quarters of western levels by the year 2010.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($1=1.4986 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E61">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
