<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207415" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AMR orders 103 Boeing jets, has options for more.</title>
<headline>AMR orders 103 Boeing jets, has options for more.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>AMR Corp's American Airlines Thursday confirmed it had placed an order for 103 Boeing Co aircraft and purchase rights for 527 additional planes.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Boeing will be American's exclusive aircraft supplier through the year 2018.  </p>
<p>American said it will take delivery of the 103 aircraft over four years starting in 1998.</p>
<p>The order consists of aircraft models ranging from Boeing 737s to 777s, with the bulk of the order and purchase rights consisting of 737s, it said.</p>
<p>The deal is contingent on ratification of the tentative labor pact between American and the Allied Pilots Association, whose 9,150 members will vote on the agreement in December.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the APA board voted 10 to eight to accept the pact.  </p>
<p>Boeing said the list price for the 103 aircraft is $6.6 billion. List prices begin at $32-$39 million for each 737-600 ordered and run to $128-$146 million for each of 12 777s.  </p>
<p>American has also ordered four 767-300ERs that range in price from $97 to $107 million, and 12 757-200s publicly priced from $61 to $68 million.</p>
<p>American said the flexibility provided by &quot;purchase rights&quot; for additional aircraft is a key element in the deal.</p>
<p>&quot;The agreement will enable us to acquire the aircraft we need while avoiding the need to make larger firm commitments, thus preserving the strength of our balance sheet,&quot; the company said.  </p>
<p>The rights let American buy new aircraft with as little as 15 to 18 months' prior notice and choose among a mix of models. American said traditional options require 24 to 36 months.</p>
<p>American said the agreement also includes broad price protection provisions that ensure it will not be commercially disadvantaged as to aircraft prices for more than two decades.</p>
<p>The company said it is negotiating with manufacturers for engines to power the 777s.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
