<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207406" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed's Meyer says Fed to watch for bank merger risk.</title>
<headline>Fed's Meyer says Fed to watch for bank merger risk.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBUS, Ohio 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federal Reserve Governor Laurence Meyer said on Thursday the U.S. central bank would be watching for capital risks associated with the wave of bank mergers.</p>
<p>&quot;There appears to be two key challenges to regulators rearding consolidation. The first is to be sure there is adequate competition from banks and non-banks in local banking markets,&quot; Meyer told the Ohio Bankers Day Conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The second challenge is to make sure that mergers and acquisitions do not create excessive risks,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;In this regard, it is important that capital be sufficient to cover any problems during the transition period when the banks and systems are learning to work together, on top of the normal risks of ongoing operations,&quot; Meyer said.</p>
<p>He stressed the importance of the Fed's role as bank regulator &quot;to monitor and sometimes to act to control bank risks in order to protect the potential call on taxpayers.&quot;</p>
<p>He said consolidation in banking has raised new challenges for the industry and heightened the need for bank executives to manage risks associated with that trend.  </p>
<p>&quot;A goal of capital requirements -- along with bank supervision and quality risk management by the banks themselves -- is to make the safety net a moot issue for most banks,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Fed governor, however, does not favor more heavy-handed control of the banking system by regulators.</p>
<p>&quot;The more we can do to keep risk to the safety net under control using capital and other tools, the more powers we can safely grant to banks,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Meyer welcomed the Riegle-Neal Interstate Banking Act, which will remove inter-state banking barriers by June 1, 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The removal of these artificial barriers to trade is beneficial and will likely improve efficiency and diversification of risks in the bankig industry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He also said the Fed should ensure that if the Glass-Steagal Act, which separates the banking and brokerage businesses, is repealed, &quot;the proposed recent expansion of bank powers does not inadvertently expand the safety net protection afforded to banks to other, previously non-bank activities.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Isabelle Clary 212-859-1666</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBUS, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
