<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207645" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares jump 3.2 pct to new record close.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares jump 3.2 pct to new record close.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares jumped an average 3.2 percent amid heavy selective buying on Thursday, with the market index and trade volume reaching new records on fresh cash influx, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100  .ISEC closed at a new all-time high of 87,299.29, up 2,704.17 points from Wednesday and compared to a previous high of 84,692.20 on November 11.</p>
<p>Daily trade volume rose to a record 31 trillion lira from Wednesday's 28.11 trillion and compared to a previous record of 28.83 trillion on October 21.</p>
<p>Brokers said selective activity was led by shares of largely state-owned flat steel producer Eregli amid renewed privatisation hopes.  </p>
<p>Hectic trade in Eregli which strongly influences the market index due to the firm's large market capitalisation, made up 15.7 percent of the total turnover. It gained 2,000 lira to end at 14,500.</p>
<p>State Minister Abdullah Gul said in the afternoon that a 25 percent Eregli stake would be put on sale in coming days, following Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan's morning words that Eregli's selloff tender would be opened rapidly.</p>
<p>The total state share in Eregli stands at 51.66 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Eregli played a major role in the market's gains today. There was cash entry to the market, fuelled by the recent privatisation announcements,&quot; said Nazmi Sarikaya from Disbank.</p>
<p>Senior officials have repeatedly said Turkey's privatisation drive would be speeded up soon.</p>
<p>Other leading actives were T.Isbank's C series shares, up 1,750 lira at 16,000, utilities Cukurova Elektrik, down 2,000 lira at 100,000 and Aktas Elektrik, up 2,500 lira at 107,500. Turnover in each of the three stocks exceeded two trillion lira.</p>
<p>&quot;The index pierced the 85,000 critical barrier. The new target may be 89,000,&quot; Sarikaya said.</p>
<p>The market had failed in in three previous attempts to overcome the 85,000 resistane since late October.</p>
<p>Of the 230 shares traded, gainers sharply outdid losers by 154 to 37 and 39 closed stable. The 85-share industrial index .ISEI surged 3.29 percent to 92,981.85 and the 15-share financial index  .ISEF put on 2.99 percent to 82,981.72.</p>
<p>-- Aydan Eksin, Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
