<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207738" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Nov 21.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Nov 21.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>AT&amp;T Corp has set the terms to spin off its NCR Corp and distribute the unit's common shares to AT&amp;T shareholders on December 31, the Wall Street Journal reported.</p>
<p>Other top stories included:</p>
<p>- Coca-Cola Co plans to spend $50 million next year in an advertizing campaign to promote the products of its Minute Maid division.</p>
<p>- General Motors Corp and three Japanese automobile manufacturers have agreed to change their print and television commercials for car leases to settle U.S. state and federal charges of misleading advertizing.</p>
<p>- Boston venture capital firm TA Associates Inc will make a $583 million bid for Canadian mutual fund company Altamira Management Ltd.</p>
<p>- Texaco Inc has hired a black-owned advertizing agency called UniWorld Group to make commercials designed to improve its corporate image among minorities.</p>
<p>- Laboratory Corp of America Holdings is close to reaching an agreement with the U.S. federal government to pay $182 million for allegedly defrauding Medicare by billing it for unnecessary blood tests.</p>
<p>- Mattel Inc's planned purchase of Tyco Toys Inc is being slightly disrupted by some holders of Tyco preferred shares who do not want their stock to be converted into Mattel shares.</p>
<p>- A federal appeals court has allowed CSX Corp to go ahead with its plan to buy Conrail Inc.</p>
<p>- Pacific Gas and Electric Co agreed to buy TRT Holdings Teco Pipeline.</p>
<p>- Air France changed a previous order for smaller Boeing Co planes for another order for wide-body jets.</p>
<p>- The Securities and Exchange Commission charged CS First Boston Corp of CS Holding with securities fraud in relation to its underwriting of pension funds in California.</p>
<p>- U.S. Comptroller of the Currency Eugene Ludwig established a new rule to make it easier for banks to offer extra financial products.</p>
<p>- The Dow Jones rose to its 10th record high in 11 sessions.</p>
<p>- Redux has had a lot of success since its market introduction five months ago.</p>
<p>- Chicago's Mercantile Exchange will establish links with Europe's two top futures exchanges.</p>
<p>- AMD introduced a prototype of its K6 chip to rival Intel.</p>
<p>- The pilot union of American Airlines of AMR Corp approved a new six-year contract with the carrier.</p>
<p>- Companies that have cut jobs since 1990 were more likely to witness increases in stress-related disability claims than those who had not done so.</p>
<p>- The U.S. trade deficit widened to $11.34 billion in September.</p>
<p>- IBM Corp is riding a wave of panic buying of blue chip stocks like Intel Corp and Coca-Cola.</p>
<p>- The U.S. bond market went into a later rally, pulling the yield on the 30-year bond to an 8-1/2 month low following a recovery of the U.S. dollar and an auction in five-year notes.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
