<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207922" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Statoil sets 2005 energy output goal.</title>
<headline>Statoil sets 2005 energy output goal.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway's Den norske stats oljeselskap AS (Statoil ) said on Thursday its oil and gas production goal in 2005 is one million barrels of oil equivalents per day, with just under a third of this volume coming from outside Norway.</p>
<p>Set by the group's strategic plan, now under review by the company board, the production target would put Statoil among the world's leading oil and gas producers, the company Status Weekly magazine said.</p>
<p>&quot;The group already ranks as a major producer in international terms,&quot; it wrote. &quot;Achieving the million-barrel goal would call for an annual growth of seven percent in overall equity oil output.&quot;</p>
<p>On the Norwegian continental shelf, Statoil aims to reach a daily oil flow of 500,000 barrels per day (bpd) in the year 2000 from fields in which it has a stake. This level will be maintained in 2005. In addition will come gas and other energy production, Status Weekly said.</p>
<p>Norway, the world's second largest crude exporter after Saudi Arabia, currently pumps around three million bpd. This will be maintained for about four years and then gradually decline as large old oilfields in the North Sea dry up, according to the energy ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;Replacing the decline in production from major North Sea fields will be a demanding challenge for Statoil,&quot; the magazine said. &quot;To achieve its goal, the group must significantly improve resource utilisation in producing fields.&quot;</p>
<p>Internationally, Statoil's target is to achieve 100,000 barrels of oil equivalents in daily oil and gas production in the year 2000 before hitting the 300,000-barrel mark five years later, it said.</p>
<p>The group will be seeking to achieve an operating profit on its activities outside Norway in 1998, Status Weekly said.</p>
<p>--Rolf Soderlind, Oslo newsroom +47 22 42 50 41</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
