<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207949" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Moulinex rockets after Soros takes stake.</title>
<headline>Moulinex rockets after Soros takes stake.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in appliance manufacturer Moulinex surged on Thursday after the French stockmarkets association SBF said George Soros had taken a 5.5 percent stake in the company through three firms that he controls.</p>
<p>The stock was up 3.51 percent at 115 francs at 0945 GMT.</p>
<p>&quot;People think well of Soros and he has followers,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>The SBF said three firms controlled by the Hungarian-born investor, Quantum Partners LDC, Geosor Corp and Lupa Family Partners LP, bought 5.39 percent, 0.05 percent and 0.04 percent, respectively, of Moulinex's capital on November 12.</p>
<p>The stake contains 1.55 million Moulinex shares and 4.39 percent of the voting rights.</p>
<p>Moulinex officials were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Traders said they did not believe Soros's move augured a takeover bid but that it underscored Moulinex's relatively cheap price, given the restructuring programme announced in June.  </p>
<p>&quot;George Soros looks for shares with potential and he estimates that, at that price, the stock is worth it. As he has funds, he went in for a chunk,&quot; said analyst Lilyane Dufroid Reynaud at brokerage SGE Delahaye.</p>
<p>She said she did not believe a takeover was in the cards. &quot;This isn't speculative. Soros invests on fundamentals.&quot;</p>
<p>Assuming one has faith in Moulinex's restructuring plan, the stock has &quot;very significant&quot; upward potential, she said.</p>
<p>Moulinex announced the plan, entailing a cut in staff of more than 20 percent and two plant closures in France, in June after reporting a fourth consecutive annual loss.</p>
<p>The move was announced by chairman Pierre Blayau, installed earlier this year by the company's biggest shareholder, Euris, which was reported to be impatient with the recovery pace under the previous management.</p>
<p>Euris holds 33 percent of Financiere Moulinex, which in turn controls 28 percent of Moulinex and 41 percent of the voting rights.</p>
<p>The stock has gained 40 percent since the plan was unveiled but the management has drawn fire from workers and politicians for what is viewed as a brutal solution by French standards. The company's staff committee will examine the plan on December 6.</p>
<p>Another analyst, who spoke on condition of anonymity, said he also doubted that the move reflected bid intentions. He said it appeared to validate Blayau's strategy for the company.</p>
<p>Moulinex lost 720 million francs in 1995/96 after taking a 600 million franc charge for the restructuring.</p>
<p>Analysts blame Moulinex's troubles on high labour costs, an inefficient industrial structure and a dated product line.</p>
<p>-- Nathalie Meistermann, Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
