<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207983" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow Industrials seen higher after another record.</title>
<headline>Dow Industrials seen higher after another record.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. stocks were seen moving higher with bonds at the opening on Thursday following the 10th record close by the Dow Industrials Average this month and its first above the 6,400 mark.</p>
<p>Analysts said that high tech stocks remained among the market leaders and that they would be joined by car stocks which were higher in London.</p>
<p>&quot;The futures are firmer so we'll start on the upside and then see if we can sustain it,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, analyst at Prudential Securities.</p>
<p>He said a broad market correction was under way while the Dow moved ever higher.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a correction happening while the Dow rocks on. There is no telling where the Industrials will stop,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said that high techs would continue to surge despite profit-taking which set later in the day on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;IBM got tired when it reached 159. A lot of analysts had put their price target at 160,&quot; Wachtel said. &quot;But high techs are still the cutting edge and they will continue to flourish, hitting a wall from time to time.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
