<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="207977" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK GDP growth shows surging high street spending.</title>
<headline>UK GDP growth shows surging high street spending.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON</dateline>
<text>
<p>The British economy grew by 0.8 percent in the third quarter as consumer spending continued to power ahead, official figures showed Thursday.</p>
<p>Revised figures from the Office for National Statistics showed gross domestic product was 2.4 percent up on a year ago while consumer spending has risen 1.1 percent since the second quarter and 3.3 percent from last year.</p>
<p>&quot;That's the highest year-on-year rise since 1989 and confirms the message given by most of the recent data,&quot; Andy Cates, an economist at UBS, said.</p>
<p>Jeremy Hawkins, senior economic adviser at BankAmerica, said Thursday's GDP figures suggested consumer spending in the third quarter was even stronger than recent sales data suggested.</p>
<p>&quot;A fairly decent gain of 1.1 percent in consumer spending suggests that retail sales in the third quarter gave a slightly misleading negative impression of consumer sentiment,&quot; he said. &quot;Overall, consumption appears to be picking up rather more strongly.&quot;</p>
<p>In October, retail sales were 4.1 percent higher year-on-year.</p>
<p>However, gross domestic fixed capital formation actually fell by 2.2 percent in the third quarter, showing Britain's economy remains a twin-track one -- boasting high consumer demand but paltry levels of investment.</p>
<p>&quot;If we are to prevent the economy from overheating, we do need to see more capital expenditure,&quot; Cates said.</p>
<p>If domestic demand is not met by domestic producers, imports will rise. That could fuel inflation, particularly if the pound sterling's recent strength -- it has risen about 10 percent since early August -- starts to fade.</p>
<p>However, revised current account figures, released alongside the GDP data, showed that Britain was in credit with the rest of the world, meaning there is little reason for sterling to fall, analysts said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
