<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208098" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - SFE options, SYCOM trading set new records.</title>
<headline>RTRS - SFE options, SYCOM trading set new records.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Options trading on the Sydney Futures Exchange (SFE) and trading on the overnight computerised SYCOM system both set records in 1995/96, SFE said.</p>
<p>Options trading rose 9.7 percent to a record 3.1 million contracts. This included 30 percent growth in 90-day bank bill options and 13 percent growth in 10 year treasury bond options.</p>
<p>Share Price Index futures trading rose 16 percent to a record 2.6 million contracts. Bank bill futures trading was steady, down by 0.8 percent in nominal contract value.</p>
<p>Overnight SYCOM trading rose by 18 percent, the SFE said.  </p>
<p>Bond futures were down by 11 percent because of flat interest rate conditions, the exchange said.</p>
<p>SFE chief executive Les Hosking said 1995/96 mirrored trading activity in the cash and over-the-counter derivatives markets during an unprecedented period of stability in official government interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;While there was stability in official Australian interest rates, volatility in the U.S. bond and equity markets ensured further growth in trading activity on SFE's overnight trading system SYCOM,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>By being the only Australian market open through the night, SYCOM allowed Australian market participants to respond instantly to market changes, Hosking said.</p>
<p>So far in calendar 1996, overnight option trading was five times higher than 1995, reflecting the need for cover from overnight volatility, he said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
