<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208101" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Aussie dlr storms 6yr highs as funds flood in.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Aussie dlr storms 6yr highs as funds flood in.</headline>
<byline>Wayne Cole</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar stormed to six year highs Thursday as a horde of offshore and options buyers swept aside once daunting chart barriers.</p>
<p>Months of frustrating range trading were eclipsed in a single day of spectacular action as a break of key resistance galvanised funds and investment banks from all quarters and triggered panic stop loss buying from options dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;We've seen enormous volumes,&quot; said one harried trader at a local bank. &quot;U.S. investment banks, Japanese houses, big name funds, they've all been buying non-stop. It's incredible.&quot;  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0600 GMT) the dollar had sped to US$0.8080/90 from an early US$0.8005/15 and US$0.7962/67 late here Wednesday.</p>
<p>Its wake was strewn with wrecked resistance levels including US$0.7970, US$0.7990, US$0.8020 and US$0.8050. That last was the prize of the day since it had marked the dollar's high point for the year and was last cleared in October 1990.</p>
<p>The capture of such a long standing level made instant bulls of chart watchers and even turned the head of the most sceptical fundamentalist. &quot;It's broken through to blue sky territory,&quot; said Steve North, forex sales manager at Chase. &quot;The immediate target is US$0.8115 and then in one cent steps to US$0.8480.&quot;  </p>
<p>The oulook was equally upbeat on the crosses where the dollar vaulted to 90.19/29 yen from an opening 89.16/26 and just 88.54/64 late here Wednesday. Measured against a basket of currencies it was up at 59.2 from a previous 58.5 close.</p>
<p>The revival represented a remarkable seachange in sentiment for the currency which had been leaning heavily on US$0.7815 support only a fortnight ago.</p>
<p>Traders said underlying impetus had come from Japanese demand for high yielding A$ samurai bonds and the desire of local exporters to hedge their future currency exposure.</p>
<p>But the catalyst for the break was largely options-related.  </p>
<p>Dealers said U.S. and European banks led the buying offshore Wednesday which cleared the first couple of resistance levels and the cause was taken up by more U.S. and Japanese investors this morning. That snowballed when stop loss buy orders were triggered in waves from US$0.8020 to US$0.8050.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of banks had the view the AUD would range trade for months yet and were happy to write options with that in mind,&quot; said Michael Workman, a currency analyst at Commonwealth Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;So when the dollar suddenly exploded to the roof of that range it knocked the strikes out and they had to hedge huge amounts of exposure in a hurry.&quot;  </p>
<p>The transitory nature of the options demand made some feel the rally had been overdone and a correction was on the cards soon, although analysts reckoned the newly born uptrend would be safe as long as the currency remained above US$0.7950.</p>
<p>There was also reason to expect continued Japanese demand, they said, as the fragility of Japan's banking system meant interest rates there were unlikely to rise anytime soon so keeping the dollar's yield advantage intact.</p>
<p>This was highlighted by news the Ministry of Finance was winding up a heavily indebted regional bank, the first such suspension since the end of World War Two.  </p>
<p>Dealers also suspected there were other, less obvious, forces at work.</p>
<p>These included the dramatic improvement in Australia's inflation performance and the recognition by offshore investors that the Reserve Bank was serious about keeping it low.</p>
<p>These forces had partly supplanted traditional influences like commodity prices which were offering little direction. The influential Commodity Research Bureau index of futures contracts had bounced recently to stand at 246.19 having touched a year low of 235.99 on November 5, but was still far short of its April peak of 263.79. -- Sydney newsroom 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
