<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208133" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS - Southcorp says to stay in South Australia.</title>
<headline>RTRS - Southcorp says to stay in South Australia.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Diversified manufacturer Southcorp Holdings Ltd on Thursday rejected speculation its head office would be transferred to Victoria from South Australia.</p>
<p>In a statement, Southcorp said its head office would remain in Adelaide, although State Premier Dean Brown told a news conference it was planned Southcorp's chief executive office Graham Kraehe would at some stage be based in Melbourne.</p>
<p>&quot;That is the only change being made,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brown said there also was absolutely no truth in rumours that pharmaceutical manufacturer F.H Faulding and Co Ltd was also moving its headquarters from Adelaide.  </p>
<p>The speculation came amid reports that transport chief Alan Scott, head of the privately owned Scott Transport Industries and chairman and stakeholder in Scott Corp Ltd, had threatened to move his Mt Gambier-based companies to Victoria.</p>
<p>Brown, whose leadership has been under question in recent weeks following poor opinion polls and reports of backbencher unrest, rejected Scott's claim of excessive government subsidies to lure interstate and overseas companies to the State.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
