<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208669" id="root" date="1996-11-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Communists and kings -- APEC a study in contrasts.</title>
<headline>Communists and kings -- APEC a study in contrasts.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A communist and a king, retired generals and a former doctor will be among the leaders gathering this weekend in the Philippines for an annual Asia-Pacific trade summit.</p>
<p>Representing almost half of humanity, the 18 leaders meeting at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) conference are a study in diversity.</p>
<p>The APEC members include the two biggest economies in the world -- Japan and the United States -- and some of the poorest, including the Philippines, Papua New Guinea and Mexico.</p>
<p>China with 1.2 billion people is the world's most populous country. Brunei Darussalam with less than 300,000 is one of the smallest.</p>
<p>APEC embraces religions from Balinese Hindus in mainly Moslem Indonesia and Tibet's mystical Buddhists to the animism of North American Indians and the orthodox Catholics of Mexico, Chile and the Philippines. There are also Taoists, Protestants, Buddhists, Moslems, followers of Confucius and Japanese Shintos.</p>
<p>They speak English, Japanese, Spanish and Mandarin; the Bahasa of Indonesia, the Tagalog of the Philippines, the pidgin of Papua New Guinea and the many dialects of China.</p>
<p>The countries are home to an astonishing mix of peoples and lifestyles -- Inuit &quot;eskimos&quot; who once lived in ice igloos, Borneo tribes who still hunt birds with blowpipes, Mongolians who live in yurts and drive herds across the steppes and opium-smoking hill tribes of northern Thailand.</p>
<p>The leaders themselves reflect this diversity.</p>
<p>The tiny oil sultanate of Brunei on Borneo island is ruled by the world's richest man, whose net worth Fortune magazine estimates at around $40 billion.</p>
<p>The absolute monarch of Brunei undoubtedly is the leader with the longest name -- Sultan Haji Hassanal Bolkiah Muizzadin Waddaulah Ibni al-Marhum Sultan Haji Omar Ali Saifuddin Sa'adul Kaheri Waddien.</p>
<p>With 10 children, the 50-year-old Hassanal is the most prolific daddy as well among APEC leaders, edging out New Zealand's James Bolger who has nine.</p>
<p>Indonesia's President Suharto, 75, is one of the world's longest-serving leaders. The former army general became president in 1967 after an abortive coup against the late former President Sukarno blamed on leftists.</p>
<p>Joining him in the former generals' club is Philippine President Fidel Ramos, 68, who as head of the armed forces in 1986 played an instrumental role in the &quot;people power&quot; revolution that toppled the late Philippine strongman Ferdinand Marcos.</p>
<p>South Korean President Kim Young Sam, 68, on the other hand, is the first president who was not installed by the military.</p>
<p>This economic summit will also feature several leaders trained as economists, including Singapore's Goh Chok Tong, 55, and Mexico's 45-year-old Ernesto Zedillo y Ponce de Leon.</p>
<p>At least four leaders who trained as lawyers will be at the trade talk fest -- U.S. President Bill Clinton, 50, Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, 59, Canadian Prime Minister Jean Chretien, 62, and Australian Prime Minister John Howard, 57.</p>
<p>China's President Jiang Zemin, 70 and Chile's President Eduardo Frei y Ruiz-Tagle, 54, began their careers as engineers.</p>
<p>Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad, 70, was a medical doctor before he entered politics.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
