<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208910" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE MATCHES THIS WEEKEND.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ENGLISH PREMIER LEAGUE MATCHES THIS WEEKEND.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following matches are being played in the English premier league this weekend (league positions in parentheses, all kickoff times 1500 GMT unless stated otherwise)</p>
<p>Saturday</p>
<p>Chelsea (5) v Newcastle United (1)</p>
<p>Alan Shearer returns for Newcastle after a month out following groin surgery while Gianfranco Zola, Chelsea's new 4.5 million pound ($7.6 million) signing from Parma will make his home debut, against a side including his old Parma team mate Faustino Asprilla. Both teams have recently beaten Manchester United and another win for Chelsea would mean they would have to be taken as serious title challengers.</p>
<p>Coventry City (18) v Aston Villa (10)</p>
<p>Coventry have won only twice in 17 matches all season while Villa have won only three of their last 12 so this Midlands derby will be no place for the faint-hearted. Michael Oakes continues to deputise for injured Mark Bosnich in Villa's goal.</p>
<p>Leicester City (12) v Everton (7)</p>
<p>Everton, who beat Southampton 7-1 last week and had the better of a 1-1 draw with Liverpool on Wednesday, should have Duncan Ferguson back in the starting line-up for the first time in two months after injury.</p>
<p>Liverpool (2) v Wimbledon (4)</p>
<p>Liverpool missed the chance to go top on Wednesday when they drew with Everton and are likely to be without Steve McManaman (hamstring injury) for the first time in 105 matches. Wimbledon are Liverpool's bogey team, have not lost to them for two seasons and always have the 1988 Cup final victory over the Reds as an inspiration.</p>
<p>Middlesbrough (15) v Manchester United (6)</p>
<p>A fascinating duel between the new money of Middlesbrough and the aristocrats from Manchester who clinched the title in this fixture last season. United's former captain Bryan Robson, now Middlesbrough's boss, may well see his old club give his current one a severe test and take all three points.</p>
<p>Nottingham Forest (20) v Blackburn Rovers (19)</p>
<p>The two bottom clubs meet in a match which not so long ago would have been a top-of-the-table battle. Forest were woeful when they lost to Sheffield Wednesday on Monday while Blackburn have improved under caretaker coach Tony Parkes in the last month and could be good for at least a point -- if not all three.</p>
<p>Southampton (14) v Leeds United (17)</p>
<p>Until losing 7-1 at Everton last week, Southampton were showing definite signs of improvement after a poor start. Leeds have lost four of their last five and, hampered by injuries and inexperience, have shown very little improvement since George Graham took over 11 matches ago.</p>
<p>Sunderland (16) v Sheffield Wednesday (9)</p>
<p>Just one win in seven for Sunderland has seen them slide down the table but they have lost only once at home. Sheffield Wednesday won for the first time in 10 games when they beat Forest on Monday and could be good for at least a draw at Roker.</p>
<p>West Ham (13) v Derby County (11)</p>
<p>West Ham's Croatian defender Slaven Bilic and Derby's Croatian midfielder Aljosa Asanovic should have a fascinating battle in a mid-table match which could go either way.</p>
<p>Sunday</p>
<p>    Arsenal (3) v Tottenham (8)		1600</p>
<p>According to the pundits Arsenal have turned into Tottenham and Tottenham have turned into Arsenal this season -- in other words, Arsenal are playing expansive, entertaining football; Tottenham, safety-first football, based on solid defending. Arsenal will be without injured goalkeeper David Seaman but start favourites to win the 119th north London derby, although Arsenal have not beaten Tottenham since Gerry Francis took over at Spurs two years ago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
