<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208983" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FORECAST - SAFRICA GROWTH SEEN BELOW 3 PCT IN 1997.</title>
<headline>FORECAST - SAFRICA GROWTH SEEN BELOW 3 PCT IN 1997.</headline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following this week's one percentage point bank rate hike, the University of Stellenbosch's Bureau for Economic Research (BER) has cut growth projections for 1997 from 3.6 percent to below three percent.</p>
<p>Economist Pieter Laubscher told Reuters on Friday that in its Economic Prospects released this week, BER had scaled down its GDP growth projections of 4.2 percent made in April to 3.6 percent, but now had to scale it down even further to below three percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now talking about a somewhat deeper, a somewhat more prolonged downswing and bottoming out phase in the business cycle,&quot; Laubscher said.</p>
<p>&quot;The increase in the interest rate is unfortunate at this stage of the business cycle. The economy could have done without it were it not for the capital account of the balance of payments.&quot;</p>
<p>He said it was uncertain how much of the interest rate hike announced by Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals on Wednesday was due to temporary or fundamental factors.</p>
<p>BER believed the hike was due to &quot;probably half&quot; of each of these factors.</p>
<p>&quot;Half of it related to capital account outflows. October was the first month that we had a net outflow of foreign investment on the domestic and secondary capital markets,&quot; Laubscher said.</p>
<p>&quot;That is one factor behind the pressure on the money markets and on banks' margins that led to the rate hike&quot;.</p>
<p>Laubscher said he still believed there would be an interest rate cut towards the end of the first quarter of next year, followed by a further cut later in the year.</p>
<p>South Africa's key Bank rate stands at 17 percent after a one percentage point hike from 16 percent on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Cape Town newsroom +27 21 25-2238</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
