<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208979" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: POLICE SAY IRISH MAN STABBED TO DEATH IN S.AFRICA.</title>
<headline>POLICE SAY IRISH MAN STABBED TO DEATH IN S.AFRICA.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Irish man was found stabbed to death on Friday, apparently after entertaining guests at a party at his home in a Johannesburg suburb, police said.</p>
<p>Alexander Barnes, 31, had been stabbed several times and police said they seized a butcher knife and a sharpened knife made of corrugated iron. His naked body was found in the bedroom of the Jukskei Park house at abou0 GMT on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Detectives suspect he had entertained those who murdered him. The house was in a shambles and it appeared as if there had been a party,&quot; Inspector Andy Pieke said in a statement.</p>
<p>Barnes' television set, hi-fi and various other goods were removed. His attackers were believed to have tried to steal his luxury sedan. The overturned car was later found in Preto of the stolen goods and towed to a police station.</p>
<p>Pieke said Barnes' mother, who lived in Northern Ireland, had been informed of his death. Investigations were under way.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, a German man living in the Johannesburg suburb of Westdene was repeatedly stabbed to death. He was found naked in a bath. Various households goods were missing.</p>
<p>South Africa's wave of violent crime is cited as a factor in persuading skilled whites to emigrate and in scaring off foreign investors and tourists.</p>
<p>But police said on Wednesday they were winning their fight against crime and that car hijackings and armed robberies had declined by more than 34 percent in October, compared with the same period last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
