<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208995" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVAKIA: PRESS DIGEST - SLOVAKIA - NOV 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - SLOVAKIA - NOV 22.</headline>
<text>
<p>NARODNA OBRODA - Slovak and Russian delegations, led by Deputy Prime Ministers Sergej Kozlik and Vladimir Stepanovic, are discussing in Bratislava liberalisation and expansion of trade between the two countries.</p>
<p>- The ruling Movement for a Democratic Slovakia (HZDS) has expelled Frantised Gaulider from the party. Gaulider, who quit the HZDS parliamentary club earlier this month, said he would not give up his mandate.</p>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Steel producer VSZ said its modernisation programme will total some 3.6 billion crowns this year.</p>
<p>- Overall costs for modernisation of the thermal power plant at Vojany are estimated at around 270 million ECU. Half of the sum should be covered by loans from the European Investment Bank.</p>
<p>SME - The New York-based International Committee for the Protection of Journalist has expressed its concerns over the recent attacks againts freedom of information in Slovakia. The organisation was particularly concerned with the government's law suit against the independent daily SME and the withdrawal of government acreditations of four journalists for their hostile attitude toward Prime Minister Vladimir Meciar.</p>
<p>- The Slovak national Party, a junior mamber of the ruling coalition, said it had changed its mind and would support the 1997 budget in parliament.</p>
<p>- The opposition Party of the Demcoratic Left (SDL) said a ruling by the Constitutional Court, transferring responsibility for direct privatisation deals from the National Property Fund back to the government came too late.</p>
<p>-- Bratislava Newsroom, 42-7-563-3687</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVAK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVAKIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
