<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="208982" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: SAFRICA FOREST PARASTATAL SEES 96/97 PROFIT FELLED.</title>
<headline>SAFRICA FOREST PARASTATAL SEES 96/97 PROFIT FELLED.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>South African forestry parastatal, Safcol, said on Friday profits in the 1996/97 year would be felled as a Competition Board enquiry cast a pall over business and the sawn timber market remained in a slump.</p>
<p>The future of the South African Forestry Company Ltd (Safcol) also remained clouded by uncertainty amid a government probe into its restructuring and transformation.</p>
<p>&quot;Profits could be very seriously affected,&quot; Tienie van Vuuren, the group's chief executive said in the group's annual report.</p>
<p>In the 12 months to June, these inhibiting factors had already cut into earnings which slid to 4.3 cents a share from 7.3 cents last year on turnover of 466.8 million rand versus 360.0 million.</p>
<p>Safcol is under investigation by South Africa's watchdog body, the Competition Board, following complaints from three of its customers. The Board is also probing whether a parastatal should expand at the expense of the private sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Until this matter is resolved, Safcol is seriously inhibited...,&quot; chairman David Gevisser said in the report.</p>
<p>At the same time, government had halted its investigation into the possible privatisation of Safcol, wanting to first work out a way to manage forests in the former homelands. These forests are not part of its timber assets held by Safcol.</p>
<p>Looking ahead at trading prospects, Gevisser said the sawn timber market, which had in 1996 plunged to its weakest levels in many years, was unlikely to experience any upswing in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The sawn timber market will not recover soon from the present slump that is occasioned to some extent by the almost total absence of the long-awaited affordable house market,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I02000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
