<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209097" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: London freight - BFI down but signals are mixed.</title>
<headline>London freight - BFI down but signals are mixed.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shipbrokers reported mixed signals from the dry cargo freight market on Friday.</p>
<p>The BFI fell again, down 13 points to 1447, mainly as a result of another weaker US Gulf/Continent Panamax grain fixture. But there were also reports of firmer timecharter rates for modern Panamaxes from the Atlantic to the Far East.</p>
<p>Several brokers said they believed that the Atlantic market was generally picking up, not least for Handy-sizes in the US Gulf area. One broker described the Caper market as &quot;outrageously quiet&quot;.</p>
<p>GRAIN</p>
<p>Bunge booked the 1974-built Cornilios of 2,605,991 cft grain for Mississippi/Holland Nov 26/30 at a lumpsum equivalent of $13.00 basis 55 ft, down from $13.60 fixed by Dreyfus with Orjen earlier this week. But brokers believed that this fixture of a spot 22-year old vessel was not necessarily typical of the Panamax market. There was a great deal of debate about the correct level of First Steamship's reported fixture of the Continental-relet Ever Blessing for 54,000 heavy grain US Gulf/Japan for early Dec.</p>
<p>Some put the rate at $22.75 no combo, down 25 cents from Hanjin's mid-week fixture for Dec 6/18, but others suggested the true figure was $23.25 or even 23.50. NSAC were rumoured to have fixed a Panamax for US Gulf/Taiwan for first half Dec on private terms. China Joy or China Hope 70,000 dwt was rumoured taken delivery prompt Tarragona for a trip via US Gulf to the Far East at firm $14,500 daily by unnamed charterers.</p>
<p>Alescabalo 70,402 dwt was variously reported to have fixed US Gulf/Far East at $13,500 daily plus $280,000 bonus or US Gulf/Japan at $23.25 no combo. Brokers said Aifounarios 60,920 dwt, Ektor 64,285 dwt and Maria 61,451 dwt may have now been accounted for from US Gulf and that many of the early Atlantic Panamaxes had now been mopped up. Atlantic Pride 78,507 dwt open spot Ghent may have been fixed by Egyptian charterers on private terms, although some brokers linked her with Dreyfus grain business from St Lawrence.</p>
<p>Iranian charterers continued to be active and booked 65,000/5 wheat Canadian Pacific/Iran for end Dec at $18.00 and were linked with Horizon A 64,619 dwt for grain from E Coast S America. Eleni 73,040 dwt was understood booked by Marifran delivery spot French Bay for 2 laden legs via S America redelivery Skaw-Passero at $11,000 daily. Grain charterers were busy with Panamaxes from the North Pacific - Dreyfus were said to be closely working their barley parcel to Saudi Arabia, and NSAC were linked with Bright Days for 54,000/5 heavy grain for Dec 15/27 at a weaker $14.65.</p>
<p>Continental covered their NoPac/Japan order with Thalassini Niki 73,236 dwt either delivery prompt Far East at $12,000 daily for the round or delivery NoPac early Dec at $12,200 daily plus $225,000 bonus. New Panamax grain orders today included Cargill with 52-54,000 heavy grain US Gulf/Japan for Dec 7/12 and NSAC NoPac/Taiwan for mid Dec onward BTC on behalf of Russian interests quoted an order for a Panamax delivery Plate Dec 15/Jan 10 for a trip to the Baltic. Brokers spoke of stronger demand for Handies in grain from US Gulf but few fixtures emerged. Elsewhere there were unconfirmed reports of barley business completed - 25,000 tonnes Finland/Limassol for Nov shipment and 30,000 tonnes S Australia/China for Dec but full details were not available.</p>
<p>MINERALS</p>
<p>Brokers could not pinpoint the rate paid by Showa for Lowlas Trassey 165,000 dwt delivery Japan end Dec for a Pacific round, estimates ranging from $15,000 up to $16,500 daily. Grant were linked with China Act 151,699 dwt delivery Redcar mid Dec for 2 laden legs including Tubarao/Bahrain at about $14,000/14,250 daily. Although Cobelfret fixed Fortune 22 in a swap deal with total for 150,000/10 Coal Richards Bay/Rotterdam for end Jan at about $6.50 it is understood total paid well in excess of this rate for successor for a similar quantity to Rotterdam and Zeebrugge.</p>
<p>Amadeus 66,916 dwt was understood taken by Marc Rich for a transatlantic round with coal from Santa Marta to Inkoo redelivery Skaw at $10,750 daily, and the 1975-built AUK 65,000 dwt may have gone for coal business with Carbotrade US Gulf/Skaw-Passero range at $7,500 daily plus $140,000 bonus. Taipower fixed 55,000 coal Newcastle/Taiwan on subjects for Dec 18/31 at $9.20. NYK booked Corona Brave 69,043 dwt for long beach petcoke to Japan on a voyage basis said to equate to about $12,600 daily for a timecharter round voyage.</p>
<p>HANDY-SIZES</p>
<p>Pan Ocean were said to have booked a 43,000 dwt craned vessel delivery Continent trip Far East at about $10,700 daily and a very modern 29,000 dwt vessel delivery Dunkirk at $9,800/9,900 daily on the same route. Almar 37,000 dwt was rumoured fixed delivery Continent for 3-5 months, possibly at about $8,000 daily, and Alexandria 29,000 dwt fixed Continent/S Africa on private terms. M and R were rumoured to have taken a 7,000 dwt vessel delivery S Africa trip Far East at only $7,500 daily plus $75,000 bonus, and BHP booked a 32,000 dwt bulker from the Far East for an Australian round at close to $7,000/7,250 daily.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
