<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209046" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices lower on profit taking ahead of OPEC.</title>
<headline>Oil prices lower on profit taking ahead of OPEC.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices closed lower on Friday as traders took profits ahead of the weekend and next week's OPEC meeting in Vienna, where the group is expected to rollover its production ceiling into 1997, traders said.</p>
<p>Earlier, prices rallied to wipe out midweek losses as much of the United States remained in the icy grip of an early winter, prompting fears of heating oil shortages.</p>
<p>London January futures for North Sea Brent Blend closed down 10 cents at $23.03 a barrel, after earlier rising by as much as 41 cents.</p>
<p>Earlier, December gas oil futures chalked up a gain of $3.75 to close at $222.75 a tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the OPEC meeting next week for one thing and...there is no real clear pattern on the charts for people to rely on,&quot; said Jeff Potter, managing director of Univest Ireland Ltd in Dublin.</p>
<p>Jon Davis, Chicago-based meteorologist at brokers Smith Barney, on Friday forecast temperatures would be six to 12 degrees below normal from the U.S. Rocky Mountain region to the East Coast until the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;The weather should certainly place a floor under prices ahead of the weekend,&quot; said Leslie Nicholas, oil analyst at brokers GNI.</p>
<p>Dealers said low stocks of heating oil in the U.S. and Europe were keeping oil markets volatile as traders reacted to every snippet of new information on inventories, particularly from the U.S. northeast.</p>
<p>&quot;Heating oil stocks are still far lower than they should be for the time of year but the market gets reluctant approaching $24 Brent,&quot; said an oil trader in London.</p>
<p>Surging demand for heating oil as the result of the cold snap was also paving the way for a trouble-free meeting of Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) ministers next week, traders said.</p>
<p>Brent hit a six-year peak of $25.06 in mid-October and so far this year is averaging $3 a barrel more than in 1995.</p>
<p>Although prices have retreated nearly $2 a barrel in recent weeks, traders and analysts believe a rollover of OPEC's self-imposed but widely ignored 25.03 million barrels per day (bpd) ceiling should keep them strong well into next year.</p>
<p>&quot;(A rollover) is either neutral to slightly bullish. I believe it's already in the guts of the market but there could be an emotional reaction,&quot; said Russell Hill, senior crude trader in London for Austrian oil producer and refiner OMV.</p>
<p>With most producers apart from OPEC giant Saudi Arabia pumping as much as they can, freezing the OPEC ceiling would send a clear and bullish signal that the largest chunk of unused production capacity -- the Kingdom's two million bpd -- remains out of bounds for now.</p>
<p>Oil prices in London also found support from uncertainty over the delivery of a huge volume of heating oil into Rotterdam against the expiry of the November futures contract on the London futures exchange.</p>
<p>Dealers said a duel being fought between two big European trading houses had distorted supplies into the continent's biggest consumer Germany.</p>
<p>German heating oil consumers, struggling with historically low winter stocks, were being supplied by truck rather than the normal route up the Rhine while the two trading companies remained at loggerheads.</p>
<p>Traders said the continued cold blast, which brought early snow to parts of northwest Europe on Tuesday, and news on Wednesday of another weekly fall in U.S. oil stocks, would continue to provide support to prices.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					    Nov 22	Nov 21</p>
<p>					   2105 GMT     close</p>
<p> Dated Brent			    23.86	 23.10</p>
<p> IPE London Brent futures (Jan)   23.03	 23.13</p>
<p> NYMEX light crude futures (Jan)  23.75	 23.88</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
