<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209109" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain to stay outside Europe's currency club.</title>
<headline>Britain to stay outside Europe's currency club.</headline>
<byline>John Speck</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy may be on the brink of rejoining Europe's exchange rate mechanism (ERM) currency grid but in Britain, politicians from all sides are vowing never to rejoin.</p>
<p>Instead, they will continue to revel in a go-it-alone economic strategy aimed at sustainable economic growth.</p>
<p>Every since sterling's ignominous exit from the currency pact in September 1992, Britain's political elite have been keen to distance themselves from all forms of currency ties.</p>
<p>A case of once bitten, twice shy.  </p>
<p>&quot;The government has no intention of re-entering sterling in the exchange rate mechanism,&quot; British Treasury minister Phillip Oppenheim told parliament just this week.</p>
<p>And the possible election of a Labour government in an election widely expected next May will make no difference. Britain, only just now recovering from a stiff 1990-92 recession which co-incided with ERM membership, appears to have turned its back for good on all forms of currency pacts.</p>
<p>For most Britons, the ERM is seen more as an Extended Recession Mechanism, producing high unemployment levels and paltry growth, just as it currently helps impose across Europe.  </p>
<p>&quot;Our ERM membership during 1990-2 is widely seen as one of the worst monetary policy disasters in British economic history...no politician will want to repeat the experiment,&quot; said Nick Stamenkovic, economist at DKB International in London.</p>
<p>Britain joined the ERM hesitantly in October 1990, locking sterling in at a high exchange rate which crushed the domestic economy. Two years on, the currency crashed out.</p>
<p>Britain's ERM-exit allowed interest rates to be cut sharply and the pound to fall, making British exports more competitive in overseas markets and Britain the fastest growing major eocnomy in Europe in recent years.  </p>
<p>The economic rewards for Britain have been clear.</p>
<p>British unemployment has fallen to just 7.2 percent of the workforce against almost 11 percent across Europe. And British economic growth is set to rise to around 3.25 to 4.0 percent next year, leaving European partners chasing well behind.</p>
<p>Intense debate over whether Britain should join a planned single European currency of course flares up repeatedly across the political spectrum, and has become the main bugbear of Prime Minister John Major's embattled government.  </p>
<p>But any eventual decision to join would occur with virtual instant fixing of exchange rates, avoiding putting sterling alongside a basket of currencies which then evolve towards eventual union.</p>
<p>&quot;Any political party which suggested now we should re-join the ERM could wound itself quite seriously...an average voter would react quite badly,&quot; Jeremy Hawkins, senior economic advisor at Bank America, said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that the British economy is currently doing so well and any move to rejoin the ERM would impose constraints on the freedom of policy makers makes re-entry unattractive,&quot; Hawkins added.</p>
<p>Analysts said the British economy had long been much more in line with the U.S. economy rather than its European trading partners, making currency ties problematic, and more often than not, dangerous for the domestic economy.</p>
<p>Britain's reluctance to rejoin the system, however, may increasingly irritate its EU partners, since the ERM is meant to be the precursor for an eventual single currency embodied in the Maastricht treaty. The Treaty says a country's currency must be part of the ERM for two years prior to joining an eventual single European currency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
