<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20924" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GOLF-CLARK FACES FINE AFTER QUITTING MASTERS.</title>
<headline>GOLF-CLARK FACES FINE AFTER QUITTING MASTERS.</headline>
<dateline>NORTHAMPTON, England 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Howard Clark may be fined after joining fellow Ryder Cup player Sandy Lyle in a British Masters walkout on Thursday.</p>
<p>Clark, a member of last year's winning European Ryder Cup side, told his playing partners that he was not going on after nine holes of his second round.</p>
<p>Before play started tournament director Mike Stewart issued an apology to the entire field about the poor state of the Collingtree Park greens.</p>
<p>&quot;The circumstances are being investigated and Howard could be fined,&quot; said Stewart.</p>
<p>Lyle gave up even sooner, not completing the final hole of his first round after pitching into the lake in front of the green.</p>
<p>The former British Open and U.S Masters champion told officials that he had an arm injury and then revealed that his wife Yolande was in hospital.</p>
<p>&quot;I shouldn't be here,&quot; said Lyle, who had told his caddie on the 18th fairway: &quot;If I birdie this hole we'll carry on, but if I go in the water we won't.&quot;</p>
<p>A total of eight players had withdrawn before the second day of the rain-affected tournament was halfway through.</p>
<p>Ian Woosnam complained about having to work overtime before continuing his bid for a fifth win of the year.</p>
<p>The opening day of the 700,000 pounds ($1.09 million) event had been halted by two thunderstorms and Woosnam was one of 77 players who had to return to the course at dawn to complete their first rounds.</p>
<p>After a two-under-par 70, which left him four behind first round leader Gavin Levenson of South Africa, the Welshman said: &quot;I thought we could have played for another hour yesterday evening. It was throwing it down with more rain in the middle of the night and the course was in no better condition this morning. In fact, it was twice as difficult because there was a wind.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NORTHAMPTON, England"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
