<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209474" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Nov 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Kenya - Nov 22.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Kenyan press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAILY NATION</p>
<p>- Statistics released by Assistant Minister for Health Basil Criticos show that an average of 111 Kenyans die of AIDS daily.</p>
<p>- The High Court winds up the troubled Kenya National Assurance Company on the basis that it has failed to maintain solvency margins.</p>
<p>- Opposition member of parliament James Orengo, says powerful individuals are illegally importing a special type of paper used for printing banknotes in the name of a local company licensed to do the business, and using them to print fake notes.</p>
<p>EAST AFRICAN STANDARD</p>
<p>- Electoral Commission Chairman Zaccheus Chesoni says that there is no time for Kenya to hold constitutional reforms before the next general election.</p>
<p>- Thirty-two Opposition members of parliament reject a government proposal to start an agricultural bank saying the most viable bank would be one sponsored by coffee, tea, dairy and horticultural farmers.</p>
<p>KENYA TIMES</p>
<p>- The Democratic Party admits that it's activities are crippled because it has no money.</p>
<p>THE PEOPLE</p>
<p>- After years of an unchallenged parliamentary career spanning some 40 years, President Moi is likely to face a challenger in his Baringo Central constituency in the forthcoming general election, from a candidate sponsored by an alliance of several clans of his Tugen sub-tribe of the Kalenjin ethnic group.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
