<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209491" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Day-old Belarus peace pact close to collapse.</title>
<headline>Day-old Belarus peace pact close to collapse.</headline>
<byline>Yuri Svirko</byline>
<dateline>MINSK 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A compromise brokered by Russia to end the political crisis in Belarus looked close to collapse on Friday after parliament failed to approve it, ignoring a threat by President Alexander Lukashenko to scrap it unless deputies immediately approved it on his terms.</p>
<p>After hours of angry debates, shouting and an ultimatum by Lukashenko to back the agreement by 6 p.m. (1600 GMT), deputies failed four times to give it a simple majority of 100 of the 199 members of parliament.</p>
<p>Lukashenko left the chamber, telling reporters he would consult the Russian leadership and his government and decide his next move on Saturday. Parliament adjourned until Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, visiting parliament for the second time in the day, had bluntly told deputies late on Friday he would renege on the pact unless they backed it without further delay.</p>
<p>&quot;If you do not pass this resolution into law, I will be forced to return to the situation as it was the day before yesterday,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Parliament chairman Semyon Sharetsky accused Lukashenko of lying after the president complained that he had promised to make sure the deal was approved by the end of Friday's session.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, Sharetsky and Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin signed an agreement at dawn on Friday after all-night talks to defuse the conflict over a referendum this Sunday which the president wants to increase his powers.</p>
<p>The row has many parallels with the crisis which paralysed politics in Russia for most of 1993 and ended in bloodshed when President Boris Yeltsin put down an armed revolt led by his parliamentary opponents.</p>
<p>The deal ran into trouble straight away on Friday morning when deputies dismissed it as a sell-out. In Moscow, the Kremlin trumpeted it as a political masterstroke. &quot;I consider this to be a big victory,&quot; said Yeltsin, adding the conflict could have ended in violence.</p>
<p>Yeltsin and the pro-Russian Lukashenko agreed last April to unite their countries in a community. But until three days ago, Moscow appeared reluctant to intervene in the conflict.</p>
<p>Lukashenko wanted a two-thirds majority of 132 deputies to approve the deal, making it constitutionally binding. But opposition deputies wanted to merely approve it with a simple majority of 100.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, speaking in parliament on Friday afternoon, cast doubt on his side of the deal, which was to make the November 24 referendum advisory rather than legally binding.</p>
<p>&quot;As the head of state I will do my utmost to make the people's will mandatory,&quot; he defiantly told the chamber, adding after a pause: &quot;But within the framework of the deal.&quot;</p>
<p>Sharetsky and constitutional court chief Valery Tikhinya agreed they would drop impeachment proceedings against Lukashenko which began after more than 70 deputies handed in a list of signatures to the court.</p>
<p>But by late on Friday only seven deputies had withdrawn their signatures, and other judges on the court said he had no right to sign a political agreement.</p>
<p>Tikhinya told Reuters the court had suspended its consideration of the case against Lukashenko but would renew it if parliament asked it to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;The compromise is not ideal. We had to choose the lesser of two evils. If the president had gone on with a mandatory referendum it would have had bad consequences,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Many deputies were unhappy with the deal and said it was a betrayal. Under it a constitutional committee with 50 representatives each of parliament and of the president will draw up a new constitution over the next three months.</p>
<p>Headed by Lukashenko, it will base its decision on the referendum results. As things stand, the president will have a clear majority on the commission.</p>
<p>Russia has enormous influence in Belarus, while Lukashenko has shown himself impervious to criticism from the West and from his other neighbours.</p>
<p>Further proof of Moscow's powerful leverage came on Friday when his chief aide Vladimir Zametalin told Reuters that Belarus had completed the handover of its former Soviet nuclear missiles to Russia.</p>
<p>The handover of the last batch of 16 missiles was due by the end of 1996, but Lukashenko suggested this month that it be delayed in order to extract a promise from NATO that it would not deploy nuclear missiles on the territory of new member states such as Poland. Moscow quickly vetoed the idea.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
