<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209532" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukrainian parliament suspends some privatisations.</title>
<headline>Ukrainian parliament suspends some privatisations.</headline>
<byline>Yuri Kulikov</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's parliament on Friday suspended the privatisation of medium-sized and large enterprises designated for strategic investment tenders until it establishes rules to govern the process and cut out corruption.</p>
<p>The ruling came only hours after Deputy Prime Minister Viktor Pynzenyk told parliament that the government's main thrust in 1997 would be to attract new investment through privatisation of government enterprises.</p>
<p>No one from the State Property Fund (FDM), the state privatisation agency, whose head Yuri Yekhanorov was appointed by parliament, was available for comment.</p>
<p>The government earlier this year designated 208 enterprises to be made available for strategic investment tenders in an effort to attract foreign investment, and planned to increase the number in the future.</p>
<p>Serhiy Sobolev, a leader of the pro-market Reform group which put the motion forward, said no rules existed to regulate the privatisation of enterprises through strategic investment.</p>
<p>Parliament said it would lift the ban when rules were established. Unlike in Russia, where the government has pushed through privatisation with little reference to the legislature, Ukraine's constitution gives parliament the right to set the rules.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Pavlo Lazarenko earlier criticised the Fund's 1997 plan for not guaranteeing significant injections of foreign investment into the economy, and ordered it to re-submit a plan.</p>
<p>Ukraine, which has attracted only about $1.2 billion in foreign investment since independence in 1991, has been criticised by Western funding bodies for the slow pace of privatisation.</p>
<p>Speaker Olexander Moroz, supporting the move, said privatisation of the enterprises was taking place under murky circumstances.</p>
<p>&quot;The same thing happened in Russia, and now they're kicking themselves for it because it is too late to change things,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sobolev said the government decided to privatise three large steel plants including Zaporozhstal and two in the eastern Donetsk region during meetings on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said the the government unilaterally decided to reduce the state share to 26 percent from 51 percent.</p>
<p>The government press service said the government decided that metallurgical enterprises would be privatised only through investment tenders, and that the government would maintain a 26 percent share.</p>
<p>Parliament also ordered one of its committees to implement a review of the privatisation process to date.</p>
<p>The Fund has asked parliament to remove bans imposed in 1995 and 1994 on the sale of 1,250 of 6,000 strategic enterprises which were part of the military-industrial complex during the Soviet era.</p>
<p>All 6,000 are still excluded from privatisation. --Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
