<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209625" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian PM gets down to forming new government.</title>
<headline>Estonian PM gets down to forming new government.</headline>
<byline>Tarmu Tammerk</byline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Estonian Prime Minister Tiit Vaehi worked on Friday to form a new government for the Baltic state after his previous coalition partners walked out.</p>
<p>Estonia, which quit the former Soviet Union in 1991, is heading for its seventh government since regaining independence.</p>
<p>Government spokesmen have given reassurances that the new political problems will not divert the country from the path of economic reforms it has pursued for the last six years.</p>
<p>The junior government partner, the Reform Party, quit its alliance with Vaehi's Coalition Party on Thursday night in disgust at a pact the prime minister had made with a leading opposition party.</p>
<p>The Reform Party said the agreement threatened to take Estonia too close to huge neigbour Russia and slow down reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;Last night the prime minister started consultations about the make-up of the government after the Reform Party announced its departure,&quot; Vaehi's office said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Consultations are going on with all possible political forces. No decisions have been taken. Meetings with party leaders and all the possible ministerial candidates are taking place,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>Vaehi needs to fill six cabinet posts including that of foreign minister, formerly occupied by Reform Party leader Siim Kallas.</p>
<p>Vaehi, in alliance with a bloc of smaller rural parties, commands 40 seats in the 101-seat parliament.</p>
<p>Kallas was furious with Vaehi for signing the cooperation deal with the leading opposition party, the Centre Party.</p>
<p>The Reformists said the pact could lead to a situation where Estonia, the smallest of the Baltic states, would become too friendly with Russia.</p>
<p>Suspicion of Russia runs high in Estonia and many people believe it wants to reassert its influence over them.</p>
<p>Russia ruled Estonia and Baltic neighbours Latvia and Lithuania for most of the past 200 years and Balts bitterly resent the 50 years they spent as part of the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Observers now expect that Vaehi will try to forge a new coalition with the Centre Party, with which it ruled before the Reform Party coalition.</p>
<p>The previous Coalition/Centre Party government collapsed amid scandal after Centre Party leader Edgar Savisaar was found to have taped confidential conversations with other politicians.</p>
<p>The Reformists have alleged that linking up with the Centre Party, seen as a left-of-centre group, will slow down the country's reforms but Vaehi's office has dismissed this.</p>
<p>Despite its political instability, Estonia has managed to stay on the course of economic reform and is regarded as one of the most successful of the ex-Communist bloc states.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
