<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209655" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Nov 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Nov 22.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sarajevo press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- The Kras Company, which manufactures textiles and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) sign a long-term loan for one million German Marks, with Sarajevo's Union Bank serving as the loan manager.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- Since none of their wage and working condition requests have been met, Bosnia's health workers will go on strike on December 9, the president of Bosnia's health workers independent union says in an interview.</p>
<p>- Prime minister of the Moslem-Croat federation Izudin Kapetanovic will perform duties of the federal defence minister until the next federal parliament session, said the daily quoting reliable defence ministry sources. In the meantime Croats are expected to propose a candidate to replace Vladimir Soljic, who resigned from the top defense job this week.</p>
<p>VECERNJE NOVINE</p>
<p>- A delegation from Volkswagen AG visits Bosnia's capital to consider areas of possible cooperation with Sarajevo's car factory TAS, which was severely damaged in the war. --Sarajevo newsroom, +387-71-663-864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
