<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209671" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Belarus opponents said close to deal, talks go on.</title>
<headline>Belarus opponents said close to deal, talks go on.</headline>
<dateline>MINSK 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposing political forces in Belarus have agreed on a compromise in their standoff, but are still hammering out the details of a deal, an aide to President Alexander Lukashenko said early on Friday.</p>
<p>Crisis talks between the rivals, mediated by Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomrydin, were still going on at 5.30 a.m. (0330 GMT) more than five hours after they began, indicating that differences still separated the two sides.</p>
<p>But the head of Lukashenko's secretariat Ural Latypov told Reuters a compromise had been agreed at the closed-door meeting to avert an all-out clash between the president and his parliamentary opponents.</p>
<p>The standoff arose out of Lukashenko's plan to hold a referendum on Sunday on extending his powers. His opponents say the move is unconstitutional and are seeking to impeach him.</p>
<p>Latypov, confirming earlier reports by officials close to the talks, said that under the agreement, the referendum would proceed but its results would not be binding.</p>
<p>&quot;The referendum will have a consultative character and over three months there will be constitutional reforms taking into account the results of the referendum,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;A constitutional commision will be created to work out the new constitution. Lukashenko will head it and it will contain 20 representatives of parliament and 20 of the president.&quot;</p>
<p>In return the deputies had pledged to put a stop to their plans to impeach Lukashenko, he said.</p>
<p>Latypov said the participants of the talks, who include Lukashenko, his main opponent parliamentary speaker Semyon Sharetsky, Chernomyrdin and the speakers of the two houses of the Russian parliament, were just sorting out the details.</p>
<p>&quot;The debate is going on mainly around the exact wording of the document.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the agreement did not end the row but put off a possible clash between the two sides. The Russian mediators were trying to ensure the views of western countries -- who have condemned Lukashenko's actions -- were taken into account.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not a resolution of the conflict but a civilised way out of a head-on confrontation...Russia is expressing not only its own point of view but the point of view of the West, whose opinion it wants to take into account,&quot; Latypov said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
