<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209798" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: U.S. drug chief lauds Thais, slams Burmese.</title>
<headline>U.S. drug chief lauds Thais, slams Burmese.</headline>
<byline>Deborah Charles</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The top U.S. anti-drug chief lauded Thailand's advances in eradicating opium production on Friday but said Burma still presented a problem.</p>
<p>Barry McCaffrey, White House Drug Control Policy director, said Thailand -- part of the &quot;Golden Triangle&quot; drug zone that also incorporates Laos and Burma -- had made great strides over the past two decades in getting rid of its opium poppies, the source for heroin.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been enormous progress in Thailand in drug education and prevention. In the last 20 years there has been enormous improvement in the eradication of opium production,&quot; McCaffrey told reporters.</p>
<p>He said Thailand produces only about one percent of the region's opium. Sixty one percent of the world's opium crops are harvested in Southeast Asia.</p>
<p>In contrast, neighbouring Burma produces about 84 percent of the region's opium and presents a major problem, McCaffrey said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's all bad news,&quot; he said about production in Burma. &quot;Burma is a great dilemma.</p>
<p>The United Nations Drug Control Programme (UNDCP) estimates Burma produces 2,000 tonnes of opium a year.</p>
<p>&quot;Burmese opium production could generate 213 metric tonnes of heroin, 56 percent of the global production potential and more than 20 times as much as the total U.S. demand,&quot; McCaffrey told the American Chamber of Commerce earlier on Friday. Burma's ruling State Law and Order Restoration Counci (SLORC) has said it is making strides in getting rid of opium production, often citing the fact that opium warlord Khun Sa surrendered to Rangoon troops earlier in the year.</p>
<p>Khun Sa, who international narcotics officials say was responsible for about half of Burma's annual opium crop, gave himself up to government forces in January.</p>
<p>SLORC officials say he is under interrogation and deny reports by diplomats and former members of Khun Sa's Mong Tai Army that the druglord was doing business out of a luxury lakeside villa in Rangoon.</p>
<p>Khun Sa is wanted by the United States on an indictment for various charges of heroin trafficking. The SLORC has denied the request and said Rangoon would deal with him in its own way.</p>
<p>McCaffrey said the SLORC's human rights record and its refusal to recognise the democracy party led by Nobel Peace laureate Aung San Suu Kyi had resulted in Washington virtually ending all assistance in drug eradication programmes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LAOS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
