<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20981" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: PRESS DIGEST - MALAWI - AUG 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - MALAWI - AUG 29.</headline>
<dateline>BLANTYRE 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Malawi press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- Finance and economic minister Aleke Banda said on Monday it was naive to say there was a government on earth that was not free from corruption. Banda, believed to be leaving the country to scout for donor aid, said allegations that the Malawi government was corrupt would frustrate his efforts but admitted that there could be one or two corrupt people in government.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- A chick with four legs and three anal parts was hatched on Monday in a Blantyre district village among nine normal chicks hatched on the same day. Two of the four legs were suspended, said the owner but added that he had not established if the chick was using all three anal parts.</p>
<p>- Opposition Alliance For Democracy (AFORD) members of parliament on Wednesday boycotted an environmental seminar in northern Malawi after learning that it would be officially opened by a fellow AFORD MP Myinga Mkandawire, who accepted appointment as research and environment minister after his party severed coalition partnership with the ruling United Democratic Front party.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLANTYRE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
