<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209849" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC edges away from endorsing U.S. info-tech plan.</title>
<headline>APEC edges away from endorsing U.S. info-tech plan.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asia-Pacific nations on Friday backed away from fully endorsing a U.S. plan to free global trade in computers and telecommunications at the turn of the century, officials and delegates said.</p>
<p>Washington had hoped the 18 members of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum would give a ringing endorsement to its plan to cut tariffs to zero by the year 2000 on a broad range of information technology products.</p>
<p>Instead, trade and foreign ministers, who began a two-day meeting ahead of a summit of Asia-Pacific leaders on Monday, will issue a vaguely worded statement welcoming the ongoing negotiations in Geneva on such a pact.</p>
<p>&quot;We've worked out language that's acceptable,&quot; said a senior representative from a Latin American delegation. &quot;It will say that efforts in Geneva to conclude an ITA (information Technology Agreement) are endorsed by APEC.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But we don't want to prejudge the outcome in Geneva by having negotiations about it here (at APEC),&quot; the delegate said.</p>
<p>The stakes are high. Washington says the information technology business is worth $1.8 trillion and the United States accounts for 60 percent of it.</p>
<p>The United States wanted APEC's full endorsement of the ITA to give the pact a head start at next month's inaugural World Trade Organisation meeting in Singapore, where it is to be formally submitted.</p>
<p>Japan's Trade Minister Shinji Sato told Reuters on Friday that while Tokyo and Washington were enthusiastic, &quot;we should not push it too strongly here, because we might invite the suspicion of other members&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;If we emphasise this too strongly, then other countries are likely to start questioning what we are doing,&quot; Sato said.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, the United States remained optimistic about the pact's fate at APEC.</p>
<p>&quot;I won't be able to give you box score right now because (negotiations) are going on even as we sit here,&quot; said Ambassador John Wolf, the American coordinator for APEC.</p>
<p>&quot;But we're working and there's a lot of interest and we're going to continue working on it,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The United States has offered to lower tariffs on various products in return for individual countries' support for ITA.</p>
<p>Malaysia and some other developing countries object to the tariff targets and timeframes in the pact, saying it undermines the essential volunteerism of the diverse group.</p>
<p>&quot;I know we are under pressure over the ITA issue,&quot; a Japanese spokesman quoted Malaysian Minister of Trade and Industry Rafidah Aziz as saying after meeting Sato on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is impossible for many countries to make a commitment to it today,&quot; Rafidah told Sato.</p>
<p>APEC decisions are based on consensus, which means crafting language that is acceptable to all members.</p>
<p>Rodolfo Severino, the undersecretary in the Philippine Foreign Ministry, told reporters the ministers would reach a consensus on the accord.</p>
<p>It &quot;will probably be expressed&quot; either in the statement following the conference of trade and foreign ministers or in the joint declaration after the leaders' summit, or both.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that some formula will be arrived at with the approval of all ministers, which will take into account members' concerns,&quot; Severino said.</p>
<p>Gary Tooker, chief executive officer of Motorola Inc, said he was hopeful that the ITA would be endorsed by APEC. &quot;If they hold back, I think it will be a disadvantage to the entire APEC process,&quot; said Tooker, speaking to Reuters at a meeting of business leaders running parallel to the APEC conference.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
