<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209869" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish PM has &quot;no time&quot; for scandal probe letter.</title>
<headline>Turkish PM has &quot;no time&quot; for scandal probe letter.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan on Friday dismissed a letter from Turkey's opposition leader calling for an inquiry into a security scandal that has rocked the Islamist-led government.</p>
<p>Motherland Party leader Mesut Yilmaz had written to Erbakan and other political leaders urging the formation of an all-party commission to investigate the scandal which has raised doubts over links between security officials and organised crime.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no time for that kind of thing,&quot; the state-run Anatolian news agency quoted Erbakan as saying when asked if he would reply to the letter from Yilmaz.</p>
<p>A senior policeman, beauty queen and fugitive gangster died in the same car in an traffic accident earlier this month. Government MP Sedat Bucak, who heads an anti-guerrilla Kurdish militia, was also in the vehicle. The scandal forced the interior minister to resign two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Bucak told the HBB television station on Thursday night that the police officer was not aware of the mobster's record as a suspected right-wing hit man and heroin smuggler.</p>
<p>Motherland Party members laid a black wreath at the television channel's headquarters in Ankara to protest at not being allowed to be among phone-in guests who questioned Bucak live on the programme, Anatolian said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
