<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209944" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>WHEAT SALES - The CCC said Thursday it had purchased 16,100 tonnes of U.S. soft red winter wheat for export to Iraq. The wheat was bought from Cargill Inc for $170.71 per tonne, FOB Baton Rouge. Shipment was slated for Dec 5-30.</p>
<p>- The CCC said Thursday it had purchased 16,910 tonnes of U.S. hard red winter wheat for export to Mozambique. The wheat was bought from Farmland Industries for $183.34 per tonne, FOB Galveston. Shipment was due for December 5-31.  </p>
<p>WHEAT SALE - The Taiwan Flour Mills Association entered a contract for shipment of 34,000 tonnes of Canadian spring wheat in a private negotiation. The wheat was bought at US$238 per tonne and the shipment was slated for delivery from a Canadian port in late December.</p>
<p>Traders said the flour association would place tenders soon for two further shipments totaling 72,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat. Those shipments would be slated for delivery from December 15 and December 30, they said.  </p>
<p>WHEAT BRAN SALE - South Korea bought 12,000 tonnes Indonesian wheat bran pellet on Thursday from Bogasari Flour Mills. One trader said KFA bought the wheat bran pellet at 126.20 won/kilogram, C &amp; F. Others said it was for around $134 per tonne, C&amp;F. Shipment was set for Dec 17-Jan 5.</p>
<p>RAPESEED MEAL SALE - South Korea bought 8,000 tonnes of rapeseed meal at $159.99 a tonne C &amp; F, 8,000 tonnes of cottonseed meal at $154.50 a tonne, C&amp;F, and 7,000 tonnes at $155.00 a tonne, C&amp;F. But Korea passed on another tender for 7,000 tonnes of rapeseed meal due to high prices.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDER - Pakistan will tender on December 1 for about 225,000 tonnes to 270,000 tonnes of optional origin wheat -- U.S. grade 2 or better soft white wheat in bulk plus or minus 5 percent buyer's option under GSM-102, and/or Australian white milling wheat in bulk plus or minus 10 percent buyer's option under the Australian credit program. Delivery period was slated for December 11-31.</p>
<p>LENTIL TENDER - Syria's General Establishment for Cereal Processing and Trade offered 9,500 tonnes of lentils for export. December 16 was set as final date for bids and results would be announced on December 17.  </p>
<p>SOYBEAN TENDER - The Egyptian state's Food Industries Company invited bids for up to 50,000 tonnes of soybeans for loading by December 20 and delivery by January 15. The company has asked traders to send separate bids, one for 30,000 tonnes and one for 50,000 tonnes, both as single cargoes, one trader said. The trader said he expected it would select only one cargo. The soybeans could be any origin. Another trader said the company asked for 50,000 tonnes of U.S. soybeans, No. 2 or better. Food Industries Company was not available to clarify.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - Brazil could export up to two million tonnes of corn in 1997 given attractive world prices and the recent removal of a state export tax, the head of the cotton and corn committee at the Sao Paulo bourse said.</p>
<p>... Philippine wheat importers are likely to stay on the sidelines in the coming week, unless prices fall to interesting levels, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>... The EU is still pricing its wheat against U.S. wheat although U.S. prices now hardly reflect world markets.</p>
<p>--Doris Frankel 312-983-7305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
