<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209994" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Auditor readying report on Okla. City school dist.</title>
<headline>Auditor readying report on Okla. City school dist.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oklahoma State Auditor Clifton Scott said Friday his office hopes to have its report on the Oklahoma City School District in the county district attorney's hands by mid-December.</p>
<p>&quot;The District Attorney of Oklahoma County had some concerns and some complaints about the way (the district was) handlng some activity funds and their self-insured workers comp fund, and some other areas, and asked us to look into it,&quot; Scott said.</p>
<p>Scott's office is working in conjunction with both the district attorney's office, and the State Attorney General's office, the Auditor said.</p>
<p>The DA's office contacted the State Auditor in late spring or early summer, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The District Attorney's office contacted us and...said they had done some preliminary work at the request of the Oklahoma Police Department and asked us to help,&quot; Scott said.</p>
<p>While the report is essentially complete, the auditor's office is waiting for some additional information regarding the workers' compensation fund, he said.</p>
<p>If the information is still lacking by mid-December, Scott said his office will issue an &quot;events report&quot; on the workers comp issue at a later date, Scott. While the auditors office has been working closely with the both DA's office and the attorney general, it may issue subsequent reports should those agencies request them, he said.</p>
<p>Cynthia Reid, the school district's director of communications, declined comment Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Until we see the audit, it's kind of difficult for us to comment,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
