<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209912" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Trump hopes to trump with poker tourney.</title>
<headline>Trump hopes to trump with poker tourney.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTIC CITY, N.J. 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Donald Trump, facing growing competition from Connecticut and a revamped Tropicana casino in Atlantic City, sought help from some high rollers: the world's top poker players.</p>
<p>The 24-day United States Poker Championships, the first major tournament on the East Coast, was winding up Friday night at Trump Hotels and Casino Resorts Inc.'s Taj Mahal Casino.</p>
<p>In its first year, the Trump tournament has far outstripped the World Poker Finals, now entering its fifth year at Foxwoods Casino in Ledyard, Conn.</p>
<p>Measured by total stakes, the Poker Championships has topped $4 million in its first year. That's a tie with the Four Queens Classic in Las Vegas and second only to the 27-year-old World Series of Poker, the first and best known tournament that had $11 million in play last spring.</p>
<p>Tournament poker differs from the brand played around the kitchen table. Because it is designed to produce a single winner, players cannot quit while they're ahead. They must keep playing until one contestant holds all the chips.</p>
<p>No longer winner-take-all, tournaments now give some award to every player who is still in contention when the field has been reduced to a single table.</p>
<p>But the stars are the champions. And the Taj Mahal this week was full of them.</p>
<p>Many were Europeans, like Surindar Sunar of Wolverhampton, England, who found Atlantic City easier to reach than Las Vegas.</p>
<p>&quot;Poker is really exploding in Europe,&quot; said Donnacher O'Dea of Dublin, a poker professional.</p>
<p>The 100 players who paid the $7,500 entry fee are contesting for 18 playing places, with $500,000 guaranteed to the final player. The Taj Mahal added $100,000 to create a total purse of $850,000.</p>
<p>Two recent World Series winners, Johnny Chan and Huck Seed, were among the 55 entrants to fall victim to the intense competition in the first day.</p>
<p>Until this year, the Taj had dominated the Atlantic City poker scene with more tables in play than the other card rooms combined. Then the Tropicana casino opened a card room of equal size and hired away several key Taj Mahal managers.</p>
<p>In addition to local competitors, Trump's Atlantic City casinos face competition from two Indian-run casinos in Connecticut.</p>
<p>The Taj's card room manager, Tom Gitto, said, &quot;We did not expect to make money the first year, but we have been pleasantly surprised.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the contestants have spurred non-tournment play for higher stakes. The casino gets its poker revenues by taking a percentage of the bets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTIC CITY, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
