<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="20994" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: CENTRAL BANK STATEMENT ON HARD CURRENCY FUND.</title>
<headline>CENTRAL BANK STATEMENT ON HARD CURRENCY FUND.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is a translation of the text of a central bank statement easing controls on hard currency, imposed early this month.</p>
<p>Issued rules on the creation of a hard currency fund for energy product imports have led to speculations on a change in Romania's hard currency system. The National Bank of Romania (BNR), the sole authority which the law empowers to issue rules in the hard currency sector, specifies the following:</p>
<p>1. The norms on the creation of the hard currency fund for energy product imports does not represent a change in the hard currency system in operation. As some of the provisions of these norms were considered to represent administrative measures, the BNR decided to change those norms so that the hard currency fund would be created only through market mechanisms.</p>
<p>2. The National Bank will not change the hard currency system which allows residents to integrally retain their hard currency earnings and use them without restrictions for current account operations. This hard currency system is considered adequate not only to the current conditions but also to the strategic targets of the development of the national economy and the stepped-up integration into Euro-Atlantic structures.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Romania will continue a monetary and hard currency policy allowing it to increase its hard currency reserves, maintaining the target that these reserves stand at more than $1.0 billion, adding to which are the gold reserves.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
