<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209960" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. backs Croatian radio station 101.</title>
<headline>U.S. backs Croatian radio station 101.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. relations with Croatia could suffer if independent Croatian Radio 101 is forced off the air, a State Department spokesman said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the premiere independent voice in the country as we understand it. And we believe it ought to stay on the air,&quot; spokesman Glyn Davies told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States, as you know, believes that Radio 101 should have its license renewed at the same frequency or a comparable frequency to the very good frequency that it has.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if closing Radio 101 could adversely affect U.S. relations with Croatia, he replied, &quot;it might well,&quot; but would not be more specific. &quot;I don't want to speculate too broadly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A government-controlled telecommunications council on Wednesday failed to grant the radio a broadcasting license. But after a rally by 100,000 people on Thursday night in a Zagreb square, authorities annulled the decision and said a new tender would be opened.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the Croatian State Broadcasting Council's decision delaying action to take Radio 101 off the air is a step in the right direction. We don't believe that it goes far enough. They should be granted license and kept on the air,&quot; Davies said. He said Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott and U.S. Embassy officials in Zagreb have had discussions with Croatian officials on behalf of Radio 101.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
