<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209964" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: DC CFO orders city to make tough budget decisions.</title>
<headline>DC CFO orders city to make tough budget decisions.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>District of Columbia's finance chief said the city faces an $85.4 million deficit in fiscal year 1997 and ordered D.C. officials to choose among 38 tough budget cutting options to deal with the gap, according to a new city budget analysis obtained by Reuters.</p>
<p>The analysis, prepared by Anthony Williams, the city's chief financial officer, was presented to the D.C. city counsel this week, city sources said.  </p>
<p>The document tells D.C. agencies to put in place by early December roughly $25 million in budget initiatives they already have in the works.</p>
<p>Williams' office will then send agencies new budget reduction targets and require them to develop action plans for reaching the goals, the analysis says.</p>
<p>Agencies must report their progress monthly and participate quarterly in &quot;executive review session,&quot; the plan says. If necessary, agency heads will be asked to come up with daily action plans, the document says.  </p>
<p>If all else fails, Williams will refuse to approve funding for supplies, contracts and equipment in agencies. He will furlough employees or suspend pay. And finally, he will begin firing, the plan says.</p>
<p>The plan spells out 38 steps the city can take to cut spending, such as rolling back pay for union employees by six percent, laying off 1,000 full-time employees, and wiping out coveted programs such as summer camps for needy youths.</p>
<p>Williams told Reuters if city officials propose alternatives, his office will consider them.  </p>
<p>In other optional budget cuts, Williams said D.C. could save $2 million by halting recycling, $16 million by paying off a a University of the District of Columbia deficit, and $875,000 by wiping out arts and humanities programs.</p>
<p>The city also could save $2.1 million by dropping local funding for homeless shelters, $1 million by cutting day care funding, and $65,000 by slashing medical services for foster children.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got to move quickly, we've got to move together, and we've got to take one step at a time,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>&quot;Everybody's tired of talking about this,&quot; he said, including local officials, the District's five-member control board, and Congress.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year we took over a plane that was spiralling out of control,&quot; Williams said. &quot;We got it lined up for the runway at the last minute and made a landing. But it was not pretty.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Now, we're lining up our targets at the beginning of the year and taking a much more methodical, orderly approach,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
