<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="209920" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street thankful going into holidays.</title>
<headline>Wall Street thankful going into holidays.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street has plenty to be thankful for as the holiday season approaches, and if tradition is any guide, the week of Thanksgiving will bring even more cheer to investors.</p>
<p>Stocks have risen at a torrid pace, with the Dow Jones industrial average jumping more than 440 points since the end of October. As the momentum has built, so have cautions from market watchers that some kind of correction was inevitable.</p>
<p>But history shows that investors who hold on for the days just before and after Thanksgiving have usually been rewarded.</p>
<p>Until the crash of 1987, &quot;If you look at total gain for the day before and after Thanksgiving, outside of 1963 and '64 they're winners all the way through,&quot; said Yale Hirsch, a market historian and author of &quot;Stock Trader's Almanac&quot;.</p>
<p>In fact, in recent years, he said, players have sought to capitalise on the holiday spirit by shopping a day early, so now the seasonal swing is actually more noticeable on the Tuesday and Wednesday ahead of Thanksgiving.</p>
<p>Either way, the buying would be at lofty levels. The 30-share Dow added 53.29 points Friday to close at 6,471.76, its 11th record this month. Up 123.73 points for the week, the Dow has now gained at least 100 points in each of the last three weeks.</p>
<p>Anchoring the rally was International Business Machines Corp., which jumped $13.50 for the week and has soared a whopping $21.625 to $158.50 over the last six sessions.</p>
<p>By the end of the week, smaller tech stocks were taking part, with names like Applied Materials Inc. and KLA Instruments Corp. soaring Friday.</p>
<p>Depending on one's point of view, the resurgent technology sector was either just what the market needed or a sure sign matters were getting out of control.</p>
<p>&quot;We're at the point where we need to show some major firepower to keep the rally going,&quot; said Gregory Nie, technical analyst at Everen Securities. &quot;The techs could provide that kind of leadership.&quot;</p>
<p>But with the market overbought because of its rapid ascent since Election Day, investors need a clear sign the bull run is intact to justify pouring new money into stocks, Nie said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's fair to ask whether you can see enough potential to keep buying at these levels,&quot; he said. &quot;How much do you want to chase this market?&quot;</p>
<p>This week's gains took place against an unusually quiet backdrop of economic news.</p>
<p>Next week is another story. Analysts were already watching for the first glimpse into holiday spending, with weekly retail sales reports from Mitsubishi/Schroders and Redbook due Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have one less weekend in the retail Christmas season this year,&quot; said Richard Cripps, chief market strategist at Legg Mason Wood Walker. &quot;We're wanting to see people get in the stores this weekend.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;You've already had some chains go to a pre-Thanksgiving sale environment,&quot; he said, adding if early returns did not match retailers' expectations for a robust season, &quot;you could get panic pretty soon.&quot;</p>
<p>Other reports due this week include October existing home sales, due Monday. Revised third-quarter gross domestic product, weekly jobless claims and October durable goods orders data are all due Wednesday.</p>
<p>Markets will be closed Thursday for Thanksgiving and will hold shortened sessions Friday, when major U.S. stock exchanges will close at 1 p.m.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
