<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210019" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end mixed ahead of USDA report.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end mixed ahead of USDA report.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME live cattle futures continued to reflect trader evening of positions ahead of the USDA Cattle-on-Feed report and finished weak in deferreds on expectations of heavier fed supplies, traders said.</p>
<p>The monthly cattle report is expected to show feedlot supplies rising to year ago levels. Estimates for November 1 on-feed supplies at the seven primary cattle feeding states averaged 99.5 percent of a year ago with October placements averaging 105.7 percent and marketings averaging 97.3 percent of last year.</p>
<p>The expectations pressured deferred contracts on prospects of increasing cattle supplies while nearby December firmed on short covering, traders said.</p>
<p>Live cattle closed 0.450 higher to 0.200 lower with December up most at 66.975 cents.</p>
<p>December appeared somewhat oversold, especially considering current tight supplies of choice cattle. Although cash fed cattle prices fell $3 per tbf this week, choice numbers remain tight as shown by the large spread of choice beef over select, they said.</p>
<p>Trading was also light in live cattle options early with hedging cited in April.</p>
<p>Traders bought April 64 puts sold 70 calls, pit sources said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
