<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21004" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH COALITION AGAIN FAILS TO AGREE ON MINISTERS.</title>
<headline>POLISH COALITION AGAIN FAILS TO AGREE ON MINISTERS.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The two parties in Poland's ruling leftist coalition failed to agree on a planned cabinet reshuffle at a late night meeting, PAP news agency said on Thursday.</p>
<p>It quoted Franciszek Stefaniuk -- an official of the smaller Polish Peasant Party -- as saying that the two groupings would meet again to discuss appointments in new ministries, to be created under a coming government reform.</p>
<p>The reform, due to begin in October, provides for scrapping several ministries and creating new ones to make the work of the cabinet more efficient.</p>
<p>The Peasants and the ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) are divided over the legal mechanisms for transforming the current cabinet and over who should head the two new ministries of the treasury and the economy as well as the finance ministry.</p>
<p>PAP quoted Leszek Miller, a senior SLD official, as saying that coalition leaders also met Finance Minister Grzegorz Kolodko to discuss implementation of this year's budget.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
