<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210184" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FAO chief to Rwanda with advance food team.</title>
<headline>FAO chief to Rwanda with advance food team.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO) said on Friday it was sending an advance team of experts to Rwanda to help coordinate emergency agricultural help for refugees and displaced people in central Africa.</p>
<p>FAO director-general Jacques Diouf will lead the team whose brief is to assess the needs of people in Rwanda, Burundi and eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>The team will coordinate aid for more than a million people in the three countries.</p>
<p>It will include experts in food security, agronomy and water control. FAO technicians would follow next week to help Rwanda's Ministry of Agriculture and livestock rehabilitate the entire sector.</p>
<p>The U.N. organisation said some $5 million dollars in emergency agricultural aid was needed for some 2.3 million people in the Great Lakes region and Eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Diouf, who is from Senegal, said in a statement he was happy that the team was setting off less that a week after the end of the World Food Summit, which FAO hosted at its headquarters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had the World Food Summit. Now we have to play our part in the countries and in the field and one of the places we have to be now is clearly Rwanda,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>Pope John Paul, who opened the summit last week, made another appeal for international aid and for a stop to fighting in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;Once more, I appeal forcefully for a rapid return to peace,&quot; he said in an address to Zairean bishops visiting the Vatican.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing is resolved with violence, which only increases the sufferings and misery of the most poor,&quot; the Pope said. &quot;It is necessary to be put an end to this tragedy.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
