<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210342" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Frankfurt bourse ends lower, seen consolidating.</title>
<headline>Frankfurt bourse ends lower, seen consolidating.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares ended fairly thin-volume bourse dealings weaker on Friday after Wall Street closed lower overnight, with dealers saying the market was taking a breather following recent bullish trading.</p>
<p>The DAX index of 30 top blue-chip shares closed down 8.65 points, or 0.31 percent, at 2,763.69 points, off the day's lows after the dollar pulled above the 1.50 mark level.</p>
<p>&quot;We're just seeing a small correction,&quot; said one dealer. Trade is really quiet. But things have generally been busier in the afternoons this week so the market could pick up.&quot;</p>
<p>Newly-floated Deutsche Telekom was the heaviest-traded of the DAX stocks, but dealings were much lighter than in previous days.</p>
<p>Shares in the telecommunications giant ended bourse trade down 13 pfennigs at 32.02 marks, with dealers saying they were surprised the stock had fallen to $21 in New York overnight.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, shares in drug group Schering were weaker than the rest of the market, slipping three marks to 119.80 marks after a U.S. competitor, Biogen Inc, was granted European approval for a multiple sclerosis drug.</p>
<p>But traders said the news had not come as a major surprise and should not pressure the stock for too long.</p>
<p>Shares in retalier Karstadt ended bourse trade down 13 marks at 528 marks. Dealers said there was talk in the market that the research arm of a major German bank had downgraded the stock.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
