<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210346" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: PRESS DIGEST-Canada-Nov 22.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST-Canada-Nov 22.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top headlines from selected  Canadian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE GLOBE AND MAIL:</p>
<p>- Vast changes sought to aid natives: Action proposed on land claims, broken treaty promises, creation of aboriginal parliament.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister's past suggests caution: Report's recommendations overwhelm cabinet.</p>
<p>- Ontario not obligated to fund religious schools: Supreme Court's decision upsets minority groups.</p>
<p>- Winter wreaks havoc in the West: Temperature hits -44 in Alberta.</p>
<p>- Rwandan couple refuse to hate: Francois and Marie-Rose survived the massacres in which 30 family members died. Trying to create a future, they live in fear.</p>
<p>Report on Business Section:</p>
<p>- Trimac to split operations: Two firms to emerge from reorganization inspired by investor dislike of conglomerates.</p>
<p>- Altamira managers to hit jackpot in takeover: Top eight executives will pocket millions, documents show.</p>
<p>- TrizecHahn buys Houston complex: Peter Munk's firm one of top landlords in city.</p>
<p>- Ad agency buys shop to target retail trade: Bozell to reduce multinational reliance.</p>
<p>THE FINANCIAL POST:</p>
<p>- DMR to hire up to 500 in hard-pressed Montreal.</p>
<p>- Bre-X shares jump on hint of takeover.</p>
<p>- Veronika Hirsch affair spurring tougher standards for fund managers.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
