<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210739" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Thyssen shares up on dividend news.</title>
<headline>Thyssen shares up on dividend news.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in German steel group Thyssen AG rose on Friday after the company said it had cut its 1995/96 dividend to eight marks from 10 marks, a smaller cut than the market had been expecting.</p>
<p>The dividend cut came as Thyssen announced 1995/96 group net profit of 350 million marks, down from 775 million marks last year, and said group sales were 38.7 billion marks, down from 39.1 billion in the previous financial year.</p>
<p>&quot;The figures were bad,&quot; said one dealer, &quot;But we had expected a cut in the dividend down to six marks.&quot;</p>
<p>Other dealers said they had anticipated that the dividend could have been cut even further.</p>
<p>Thyssen shares spiked lower to touch 269.20 marks as the first figures came out, but then recovered to trade up 2.60 marks at 277.20 marks by 1423 GMT.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the rest of the market was slightly firmer, the IBIS DAX, reflecting all-day electronic dealings in the DAX index of top shares, up 2.29 points to 2,767.36 points.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't be sure where the stock will go next,&quot; said one trader, &quot;We need to look at the figures more closely.&quot;</p>
<p>Thyssen's share price has had a rocky ride over the last few days.</p>
<p>On Wednesday details of the group's restructuring strategy in the German press drove the share up to 283.50 marks, but the firm said there was nothing new in the reports.</p>
<p>On Thursday and early Friday, worries about the widely anticipated fall in profits drove Thyssen shares back down to end Friday bourse dealings at 275.50 marks.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
