<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21073" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Court thwarts British prisoners' release hopes.</title>
<headline>Court thwarts British prisoners' release hopes.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A London court frustrated the hopes of hundreds of British prisoners on Thursday and allowed embarrassed interior minister Michael Howard to block their early release.</p>
<p>Two judges sitting in Britain's High Court backed a move by Home Secretary Howard to halt a flood of releases from jails which began this month when the Prison Service adopted new guidelines for calculating the length of sentences.</p>
<p>The guidelines, under which more than 500  inmates have been freed, were described by one of the judges, Oliver Popplewell, as &quot;totally absurd&quot;.</p>
<p>The Prison Service believed previous court judgments showed that the time a prisoner spent in jail awaiting trial had to be deducted from each of his sentences -- even if the court ordered them served consecutively.</p>
<p>Thus a prisoner who spent six months on remand then received three consecutive one-year sentences would spend only 18 further months in prison, rather than 2-1/2 years.</p>
<p>Howard, an advocate of tough sentencing for whom the unexpected released was an acute political embarassment, gave Prison Service head Richard Tilt a severe dressing down this week and won an apology from him for &quot;serious failures&quot;.</p>
<p>Howard also instructed prison governors to revert to the previous interpretation of the law under which a period on remand was deducted only once from the total term of a prisoner serving consecutive sentences.</p>
<p>John Naughton, a 32-year-old serving a total of three years from robbery and possession of cannabis, challenged that instruction on behalf of hundreds of fellow inmates.</p>
<p>He sought immediate release, saying he should have been let out of jail on Christmas Eve last year rather than next month. Having lost, he may still appeal to Britain's most senior court, the House of Lords.</p>
<p>&quot;I am delighted that the court has reached a clear view that remand time cannot be counted twice,&quot; Howard said in a statement after the ruling.</p>
<p>&quot;The court will have more to say on this very complex matter next week. I have therefore decided that the suspension of the release of prisoners...will remain in place until we have the opportunity to consider the judgement carefully,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A Home Office (interior ministry) spokeswoman said she could not immediately comment on whether the prisoners released on what the court ruling indicates was a mistaken interpretation of the law will be asked to return to jail to serve out their sentences.</p>
<p>If Howard had lost Thursday's case, the government could have faced large claims for compensation from convicts who spent too long in prison.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
