<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210878" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: Norsk Hydro lifts Oslo Bourse to another high.</title>
<headline>Norsk Hydro lifts Oslo Bourse to another high.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Industrial conglomerate Norsk Hydro and other blue chip shares led a bullish Norwegian stock market to a record close for the 11th consecutive session on Friday.</p>
<p>The Total index finished 0.55 percent higher at 925.29 points in heavy trade worth more than one billion crowns.</p>
<p>Hydro, which has a 20 percent weighting on the Total index, climbed 2.07 percent to 320.50 crowns partly on rising aluminium prices, dealers said. Metals maker Elkem was up 4.76 percent at 99 crowns for the same reason.</p>
<p>Dealers said they believed the Total index would continue to rise in the short term and forecast no immediate correction.</p>
<p>The Norwegian stock market has been strengthened by falling interest rates and good liquidity in the past two weeks as well by Wall Street's rally.</p>
<p>Shipping group Bergesen also performed well, its A share rising 3.51 percent to 147.50 crowns.</p>
<p>Engineering and offshore group Aker's A share was the most traded stock of the day at 192 million crowns. It rose 0.35 percent to 144 crowns the day after Aker shareholders voted overwhelmingly in favour of merging the company with investment group RGI.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
