<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210803" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Newly-discovered Mondriaan to be sold at auction.</title>
<headline>Newly-discovered Mondriaan to be sold at auction.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>A lost watercolour by Dutch artist Piet Mondriaan, discovered by chance in May, will go up for auction in Amsterdam next month, Christies the auctioneers said on Friday.</p>
<p>The pastel-tinted picture of a blue chrysanthemum, one of several watercolours Mondriaan painted in the mid-1920s for 50 guilders a time to cover his living expenses, is expected to fetch between 80,000 and 120,000 guilders ($47,000-$71,000), Christies said. The picture was returned to the Netherlands from the United States, where it had hung unrecognised in the home of a woman from Mondriaan's home town of Amersfoort who emigrated in 1964.</p>
<p>After she died the watercolour went to her sister, who thought it might be a Mondriaan after seeing his work in leaflets put out by the Mondriaanhuis Museum.</p>
<p>Also going under the hammer in Christies' December 10 auction of modern art is the collection of Kees Groenendijk, the Dutch &quot;artists' dentist&quot; whose patients included leading post-war Dutch artists such as Karel Appel and Lucebert.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
