<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210978" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian bonds narrow sharply vs dlr bloc.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian bonds narrow sharply vs dlr bloc.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p> AUD VS   3-YR	   10-YR	* AUD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p> USD	 59 (- 12)    90 (- 07) * FUTURES   65.5 (+ 05.5)</p>
<p> CAD	203 (- 11)    91 (- 10) * CASH	67   (+ 05)</p>
<p> NZD	-67 (- 08)   -16 (- 05) *</p>
<p>---------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Australian bond spreads narrowed sharply to their dollar bloc counterparts as the short-end sped ahead on the recent strength of the Australian dollar, which sparked hopes of another cut in official interest rates.  </p>
<p>The local yield curve also steepened as the long-end continued to do battle at resistance around the 7.0 percent yield barrier on the benchmark 10-year bond.</p>
<p>However, the Australian/U.S. 10-year yield spread tightened to below 90 basis points at one stage, although this is also proving an obstacle.</p>
<p>U.S. Treasuries remained around their slightly softer levels seen in New York during Tokyo trading, having met resistance after this week's overall firm tone.  </p>
<p>The local market outpaced Canadian debt, which was fairly mixed on Thursday as its yield curve steepened on speculation of another easing by the Bank of Canada after a weaker than expected retail sales report.</p>
<p>The New Zealand market was firm, also taking its cue from a firm local currency, but still underperformed against Australia.</p>
<p>--Colin Brinsden 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
