<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="210980" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ shares under late selling pressure at close.</title>
<headline>NZ shares under late selling pressure at close.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>* New Zealand share prices end near lows</p>
<p>* GPG gains, but investment in DB seen as unlikely</p>
<p>* TrustPower rumour resurfaces. Northland gains post result</p>
<p>---------------------------(Nov 22)---------------------------</p>
<p>Price movements at close</p>
<p>	    LAST CHG</p>
<p>  130   -2  * NZSE-40 cap index -11.27 at 2,352.13</p>
<p>  323   +4  * NZSC cap index +8.97 at 4,876.24</p>
<p>  252   -7  * NZSE-10 cap index -8.78 at 1,171.73</p>
<p>  368   -2  * Volume NZ$45 million. Futures -6 at 1,173</p>
<p>  749  -10  * Other movers - +15 +8  </p>
<p>New Zealand share prices came under light selling pressure at the close on Friday after a mixed session on moderate turnover.</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 Capital Index ended 11.27 points down at 2,352.13 on turnover worth NZ$45 million. A 10-cent decline in Telecom to NZ$7.49 and a seven cent fall in Fletcher Paper were largely responsible for the decline.</p>
<p>Many of the other major issues were a touch weaker as well, the exception being a four-cent rise in Carter Holt Harvey to NZ$3.23.  </p>
<p>Speculation that GPG may be accumulating a stake in liquor company DB Group was losing credence by the close. &quot;I would be surprised if it were true, but obviously that's what has spurred some of the buying,&quot; Duncan Rutherford said at ANZ Securities said. GPG declined to comment on the rumour.</p>
<p>GPG ended two cents higher at NZ$0.81 but the rise could have been attributable to a strong market performance by some of GPG's other investments, notably Tyndall. GPG had also benefitted from some favourable broker recommendations.</p>
<p>The TrustPower rumour reared its head again, forcing the utility up 15 to NZ$2.55 on light turnover.  </p>
<p>Brokers were taking a wait-and-see approach on whether there would be a merger with Bay of Plenty Electricity.</p>
<p>&quot;But the market still seems to be in limbo,&quot; Rutherford said, adding it was likely to remain that way until there was further direction from the current coalition talks.</p>
<p>&quot;Until we get some firmer indications from them I suppose it's going to be a little bit sloppy,&quot; Rutherford said. &quot;It's getting close to crunch time one way or another.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the minor issues, Northland Port gained eight cents to to NZ$2.58 after reporting strong annual earnings on Thursday, but turnover in the stock was light. -- James Gray 64 9 302 1253</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
