<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21109" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: NWE fuel - HS barges up, cargoes wait for tender.</title>
<headline>NWE fuel - HS barges up, cargoes wait for tender.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>High sulphur cracked barges bounced higher on Thursday, but cargoes were unmoved.</p>
<p>Barges traded at up to $100 fob ARA and one unrepresentative deal was done at $101. The hike was backed by good bunker demand and brought physical prices in line with forward month paper.</p>
<p>The sharpness of the rise -- barges traded at $95-96 on Wednesday -- was an indication of just how aggressive selling had been in Wednesday's quiet market. Dealers had been keen to shift product before the end of the month.</p>
<p>High sulphur cargoes were steady in a tight market that was awaiting the EdP award on Friday.</p>
<p>Dealers said prices were stuck around $100 fob NWE with two end-users understood to be interested in securing cargoes.</p>
<p>Although the tender should give fundamental support to a reasonably tight market, some dealers thought prices might be pushed lower on a &quot;buy low, price high&quot; basis.</p>
<p>Low sulphur cracked cargoes were also steady, staying close to Sept paper at $105-106 fob NWE. A deal on Thursday into a U.K. end user at $109.25 cif NWE was not seen to reflect the true market level.</p>
<p>-- Matthew Jones, London Newsroom +44 171 542 8980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
