<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="211027" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia sheep/wool decline possible - WI.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia sheep/wool decline possible - WI.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>After a fall in the Australian sheep flock to 122 million in 1995/96, its lowest level for four decades, further declines in sheep numbers and wool production were possible, statutory authority Wool International (WI) said.</p>
<p>The declines were the result of drought and of poor relative profitability in the wool industry, it said in its annual report for the year to June 30.</p>
<p>The possibility of further declines were raised by the relative profitability of cropping enterprises, it said.  </p>
<p>WI's annual report shows that Australia's shorn wool production fell to 646 million kg of greasy wool in 1995/96, down from 683 million kg the year before.</p>
<p>Total trade clearances of Australian wool in 1995/96, including WI deliveries from the stockpile, fell to 701 million kg, the lowest level in a decade apart from 1989/90 when high floor prices caused distortions, WI said.</p>
<p>Auction sales were down by 16 percent to 2.67 million bales over the year.</p>
<p>WI chairman Dick Warburton said a more flexible sales strategy from the stockpile helped minimise market impact.  </p>
<p>The main contributing factor to the write-down was the slide in wool market prices while changes in stockpile composition also had an impact, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the gloom of 1995/96, a modest recovery in 1996/97 may be expected,&quot; Warburton said.</p>
<p>Economic growth should be stronger in some key developing economies, notably Japan, and this could lift consumer sentiment, he said.</p>
<p>Maintenance of Chinese purchases was also expected.  </p>
<p>&quot;However, WI added in total 19 percent to total supply out of Australia and this clearly had some effect,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Australia's wool stockpile fell by 739,813 bales over the year to 2.37 million bales at June 30 and has continued to decline to less than 2.0 million bales after year-end.</p>
<p>Ongoing processing trials confirmed that the performance of stockpile wool was not inferior to fresh wool provided attention was given to bale opening techniques, Warburton said.</p>
<p>The closing 1995/96 stockpile of 2.37 million bales was valued at A$1.62 billion, after a write-down of A$368 million.  </p>
<p>The Asian region was likely to gain from further expected rationalisation of wool processing and garment making capacity in Western Europe and Japan, he said.</p>
<p>In the longer-term, there continued to be a need for fundamental change in raw wool marketing, Warburton said.</p>
<p>A broadening of the range of price risk management products, growth of forward physical trading and sale by description were all required to move the industry into the next century, he said.</p>
<p>WI met its legislative requirement and delivered 741,349 bales over the last season.  </p>
<p>In addition, it had sold forward 97,946 bales at June 30 for delivery into 1996/97, the annual report shows.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100124">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
