<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21129" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: IPE gas oil targets $200 as backwardation widens.</title>
<headline>IPE gas oil targets $200 as backwardation widens.</headline>
<byline>John Hanley</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>IPE September gas oil's ascent toward $200 a tonne on Thursday reflects a widening in the futures market's backwardation that is discouraging inventory building ahead of the key fourth quarter demand period.</p>
<p>As a result, outright gas oil futures and gas oil spreads versus the back months and crude are expected to stay firm as the summer draws to a close, with lean distillate supplies in the United States offering little relief, analysts said.</p>
<p>But they cautioned that, for the near-term, the strength may be exaggerated due to the NYMEX Sept products expiries on Friday, the U.S. Labor Day holiday weekend, and talk that one player was a large buyer of Sept gas oil this morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of the backwardation there is no incentive to restock,&quot; said Geoff Pyne, oil economist at UBS in London. &quot;Also I think storage companies are looking for contango this time of year going into winter and they're not seeing it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think gas oil is the single strongest fundamental support in the oil market and that will continue lending support to crude in September,&quot; he added. &quot;Consumer inventories are low so there is quite a lot of potential demand to come in September.&quot;</p>
<p>European middle distillate stocks as of July were 282.53 million barrels, down from 293.02 million a year ago, according to Euroilstock Foundation.</p>
<p>Sept gas oil was up $5.75 at $197.50 a tonne in afternoon trade after reaching $198.50, a contract high and the strongest level for the spot month since $200 on April 9.</p>
<p>The year's high was registered on March 27 at $200.50, which in turn was the highest since $223 in November 1991 during the Gulf War.</p>
<p>The backwardation, or front-month premium over the second month, for Sept/Oct was trading at 50 cents on August 12 and widened out to $2 on Wednesday. It was trading at about $3.25 Thursday afternoon.</p>
<p>The Oct/Nov backwardation was trading at about $3.50. Sept gas oil expires September 12 while NYMEX Sept heating oil exits on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;If we see this backwardation holding then we could have problems going into winter because there is less financial incentive to hold inventories,&quot; said Leslie Nicholas, analyst at GNI Ltd in London. &quot;That's a potential problem.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Two hundred dollars could be a target to be attained but gas oil's instrinic fundamentals don't warrant sustained levels above $200 at the moment,&quot; he added. &quot;I don't see the market particularly tight in Europe versus in the U.S.&quot;</p>
<p>European distillate fundamentals are less bullish than in the U.S., where inventories are 19 million barrels below year-ago levels, but NYMEX heating oil prices could be a leader for the gas oil market, he said.</p>
<p>If prices are in contango, with the front month trading below the second month contract, the cost of carrying the inventory can be offset by not having to buy at a higher price later.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know how sustainable this whole rally is,&quot; said one oil broker.</p>
<p>But he still cited a host of factors underpinning the gas oil market -- Sept holding an uptrend line on the continuation chart that crossed at $188; worries over hurricanes and tropical storms in the Atlantic; and this week's U.S. inventory data.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8185</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
