<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21128" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: GEC may face revolt over &quot;fat cat&quot; pay deal.</title>
<headline>GEC may face revolt over &quot;fat cat&quot; pay deal.</headline>
<byline>Jane Merriman</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A fresh row has erupted over &quot;fat cat&quot; pay in Britain after General Electric Company Plc revealed a multimillion pound pay and bonus package for its new managing director George Simpson.</p>
<p>The defence and engineering group now faces a potential revolt by institutional shareholders angered by Simpson's contract, estimated to pay him 10 million pounds ($15.60 million) over the next five years.</p>
<p>Investor Norwich Union said on Thursday it had not discarded the possibility of voting against Simpson's appointment at the company's annual meeting on September 6.</p>
<p>Mutually-owned investment institution Norwich is concerned that performance criteria Simpson has to meet to receive a huge block of share options are not tough enough.</p>
<p>&quot;We're clearly concerned as things stand at present mainly about the performance criteria attached to the share options,&quot; a Norwich spokeswoman said. &quot;They are not challenging enough, in our view they're just too easy.&quot;</p>
<p>Simpson would receive the options if GEC's share price beat the FTSE 100 index by 10 percent in any six months within a specified three-year period. This effectively means he would receive them even if GEC's shares outperformed only briefly.</p>
<p>Simpson, former chief executive of Lucas Industries who takes over at GEC from Lord Weinstock, has already been dubbed &quot;the fattest cat of all&quot; by British newspapers.</p>
<p>His three-year contract includes annual pay of up to 1.5 million pounds, including pension contributions, plus a complicated package of share options.</p>
<p>Simpson's controversial deal has turned up the heat in the debate about top executives' pay sparked last year when former British Gas chief executive Cedric Brown was awarded a 75 percent pay rise.</p>
<p>Mounting public anger over fat cat salaries prompted the government to set up a committee to curb boardroom excesses. But despite guidelines set out by the committee, led by Sir Richard Greenbury, chairman of retailer Marks and Spencer Plc, executive salaries continue to rise.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Robert Diamond, new head of global markets at investment bank Barclays de Zoete Wedd, was reported to have signed a two-year contract worth at least 5 million pounds, plus a range of incentive payments.</p>
<p>And British cider-maker Matthew Clark made headlines when it payed nearly 430,000 pounds to its chairman Peter Aikens for moving from Guildford to Bristol, the equivalent of 4,000 pounds a mile. ($1=0.6412 pounds)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
