<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21147" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Soccer-Ivan the Terrible leads invasion of Italy.</title>
<headline>Soccer-Ivan the Terrible leads invasion of Italy.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>&quot;Ivan the Terrible&quot;, a fiery Dutchman and new recruits to French soccer's foreign legion make their Italian league debuts next week, ready to prove that serie A can still buy the best.</p>
<p>Not to forget &quot;The Train&quot;, the &quot;Zola of the Pyramids&quot; and a Brazilian once sold for 40 pairs of boots.</p>
<p>The league kicks off on September 8 with some matches on September 7 to prepare for UEFA Cup ties.</p>
<p>Inter expect great things from Chilean international Ivan &quot;The Terrible&quot; Zamorano, the former Real Madrid striker who joins a formidable line-up at the Milan club.</p>
<p>&quot;If one thing is in my heart it's scoring goals,&quot; he declared recently. &quot;I have goals in my blood.&quot;</p>
<p>The club also have French international Youri Djorkaeff, who joined from Paris St Germain, with new signings Nigerian Nwankwo Kanu from Ajax and Swiss playmaker Ciriaco Sforza.</p>
<p>Djorkaeff has already drawn rapturous comparisons with former Juventus great Michel Platini.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm delighted to be compared to Platini...but I certainly don't claim to be the new Platini,&quot; he cautioned after scoring a lovely goal against Anderlecht in a recent friendly.</p>
<p>Midfielder Paul Ince, the only Englishman in serie A, Dutchman Aron Winter, French international defender Jocelyn Angloma and Argentine midfielder Javier Zanetti are the other foreigners at Inter, who last won the title in 1989.</p>
<p>Englishman Roy Hodgson, who arrived last season, is one of seven foreign coaches in serie A out of 18 clubs.</p>
<p>Champions AC Milan have Dutch midfielder Edgar Davids and defender Michael Reiziger from Ajax and French striker Christophe Dugarry from Bordeaux as their main signings after capturing the &quot;Scudetto&quot; (shield) last season.</p>
<p>The hot-blooded Davids made the headlines at Euro 96 when he went home in disgrace after arguing with his coach. He also had a bust-up in a recent friendly with Juventus.</p>
<p>FIFA's world player of the year George Weah of Liberia remains the main attack force with Montenegrin Dejan Savicevic and French international midfielder Marcel Desailly.</p>
<p>But the big change at the club has been the departure of highly successful coach Fabio Capello for Real Madrid and the arrival of Uruguayan Oscar Tabarez in his place.</p>
<p>European Cup holders Juventus have sold three top players overseas and brought in only one from abroad.</p>
<p>Crowd favourites Gianluca Vialli and Italy striker Fabrizio Ravanelli have left for England while Portuguese international midfielder Paulo Sousa has joined Borussia Dortmund.</p>
<p>Some fans had worried that the Turin club was selling off the family silver but the top-quality arrivals of French midfielder Zinedine Zidane from Bordeaux and Croat striker Alen Boksic from Lazio should dispel that notion.</p>
<p>Lazio, with the two top goalscorers from last season on their books, have lost Italy's Roberto Di Matteo to Chelsea and looked abroad only for the highly-rated South African defender Mark Fish and Australian sweeper Paul Okon.</p>
<p>Parma, with the Milan clubs and Juventus the fourth Italian team with really big money to throw around, have spent the serious cash at home on striker Enrico Chiesa.</p>
<p>Bulgarian striker Hristo Stoichkov -- the big-name arrival last season -- has left while midfielder Daniel Bravo and defender Lilian Thuram have arrived from France.</p>
<p>Argentine attacker Hernan Crespo joins Chiesa, Gianfranco Zola and Alessandro Melli up front.</p>
<p>Udinese, with German international Oliver Bierhoff, also have midfielder Hazem Imam -- dubbed the &quot;Zola of the Pyramids&quot; -- who will be the first Egyptian in serie A.</p>
<p>Napoli, last season beset by financial troubles that threatened to end their stay in serie A, have signed up 21-year-old Brazilian Beto from Botafogo, whose first transfer was from Don Bosque in Mato Grosso for 40 pairs of boots.</p>
<p>The four newly-promoted teams have all signed foreigners, while keeping a tight grip on the cashflow.</p>
<p>Reggiana have the most colourful signing, with their hopes riding on &quot;The Train&quot; -- Colombian Jose Adolfo Valencia of Independiente Santa Fe whose previous incursions into Europe have not been exactly first class.</p>
<p>All will be required to impress immediately.</p>
<p>The recent unprecedented departure of some top Italian players, not just ageing stars cashing in at the end of their serie A careers, has unnerved many in Italy.</p>
<p>&quot;It is significant that champions like Vialli, Ravanelli, Di Matteo, (Ruggiero) Rizzitelli and coaches like Capello and (Giovanni) Trapattoni should have chosen to go abroad,&quot; said former Parma coach Nevio Scala recently.</p>
<p>Scala, himself linked to Germany's Stuttgart, said the danger of Italian soccer being overtaken was real but &quot;serie A will remain the championship that sets the standards in the world for a couple more years at least&quot;.</p>
<p>Although Italy has an impressive seven clubs in European competition, neighbours France have eight. Italy has also failed disappointingly in two major soccer tournaments this summer -- Euro 96 and the Olympics -- and morale needs a lift.</p>
<p>At an institutional level, the Federcalcio federation is also in chaos without an elected president.</p>
<p>The unease made La Stampa newspaper wonder whether Italians would be disappointed when serie A starts.</p>
<p>But Djorkaeff, for one, did not seem concerned after recent friendlies in England and Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;In England they dream of reaching the level of Italian soccer,&quot; the Frenchman said. &quot;We realised that at Inter when we played Manchester United twice and won.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
