<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="211442" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Far East Gold - Producer role in price drop limited.</title>
<headline>Far East Gold - Producer role in price drop limited.</headline>
<byline>Mishi Saran</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>The role of producer hedge sales in gold's sharp drop overnight has been exaggerated, and the extent of physical demand underrated, bullion traders in Hong Kong and Singapore said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at the size of trading that goes on every day in the gold market, then you look at the short positions on COMEX and you look at how much producers are producing, and how much they will actually hedge of all that, the numbers just don't correlate,&quot; one senior Hong Kong dealer said.</p>
<p>Producers are only a small part of the market, he said.  </p>
<p>Gold dived overnight in New York to its lowest level since March 1995 under the weight of producer hedging and fund selling, traders said.</p>
<p>Spot gold  was trading at $376.60/377.10 an ounce in Hong Kong at 0430 GMT on Friday, unchanged from its opening price and slightly above New York's $376.30/80 close on Thursday.</p>
<p>Although producer selling may have exacerbated a weak market, the negative tone had however already been set by significant short selling by hedge funds and professional players, the dealer noted.  </p>
<p>Australian producers were particularly unlikely to sell gold as a hedge after the Australian dollar hit six-year highs and dealers on Friday expected it to hold at around US$0.8050.</p>
<p>Spot gold was quoted at about A$465.50 an ounce on Friday. &quot;The question to ask is why would producers be hedging in a low interest-rate environment,&quot; another bullion dealer said, noting that South Africans and South Americans were more likely to hedge than Australians and Canadians, who were laboring under strong currencies.</p>
<p>But some Hong Kong-based gold dealers said South African producers could stop selling gold now.  </p>
<p>Since the rand had strengthened against the dollar compared with last week, selling gold in rand terms is not as attractive, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect some buying from South Africa at around $375/$376, which would give them some very good returns on their (earlier) sales at $380/$381 an ounce,&quot; said one dealer at an international bank.</p>
<p>Hong Kong and Singapore bullion dealers said a lack of substantial physical demand to offset selling had created much of the problem.  </p>
<p>&quot;I doubt all this would have happened if we'd had good physical demand,&quot; another Hong Kong trader said.</p>
<p>But Asian gold prices could still firm up short-term with most of the selling having already taken place when prices were falling to their current levels, Singapore dealers said.</p>
<p>Traders said demand from Asian giants India and China remained steady, but not spectacular, and buyers from both countries bought when spot gold slipped below $380 an ounce.</p>
<p>Traders said the wider trading band for spot gold would probably be between $375 to $385 an ounce.  </p>
<p>Singapore gold premiums were quoted in a range between 40-50 U.S. cents an ounce over spot London prices, up from last week's 35-45 cents mainly on the back of steady demand.</p>
<p>--Hong Kong News Room (852) 2843 6358</p>
<p>--Rene Pastor in Singapore (65) 870 3174</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
