<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="211973" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss private bank keen on Europe stocks.</title>
<headline>Swiss private bank keen on Europe stocks.</headline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss private bank Pictet &amp; Cie said on Thursday that it favoured a return to European and British stocks, a downsizing of Japanese shares and a reduction in fixed income bonds exposure for asset allocation.</p>
<p>In its latest investment strategy report, the Geneva bank said it favoured a sizeable chunk of its asset allocation -- 25 percent -- in cash and cautioned against low bond yields and the current valuation of stock markets.</p>
<p>In equities, the bank said it was moving away from Japanese shares in favour of European stocks.</p>
<p>Pictet &amp; Cie said Japan had been &quot;desperately disappointing&quot; with domestic investors reluctant to put their money in Tokyo shares and that non-European shares looked expensive in the absence of an upgrading of corporate earnings forecasts.</p>
<p>But it saw sweet pickings in European and British stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;The expected return to economic growth in Europe suggests that corporate profits could register some surprisingly sharp increases,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>&quot;We recommend a smaller proportion than usual in equities, except in Europe where a non-inflationary recovery stands a good chance of taking place next year.&quot;</p>
<p>In emerging markets, Pictet &amp; Cie said an influx of foreign money was behind a surge in Russian stocks since the start of this year. But it said investors were nervous over never-ending reform of tax laws and banks cutting off corporate credit lines.</p>
<p>In Poland, the bank said foreign investors were unsettled by inflation and were taking a wait-and-see appraoch before taking up stock positions for the year-end.</p>
<p>In Latin America, Pictet &amp; Cie predicted a rally on Chile's market from its current rock-bottom levels and favoured interest-rate-sensitive stocks such as utilities and banks.</p>
<p>Pictet &amp; Cie was bullish about Mexico provided that buyers stick to a sectoral approach. In Brazil, it favoured retailing and capital goods companies.</p>
<p>The bank said its current global dollar portfolio with a medium-risk profile allocated roughly 40 percent in equities, 30 percent in bonds, five percent in commodities-related assets and the remaining in cash.</p>
<p>The same portfolio with a low-risk profile had 20 percent in equities, 45 percent in bonds, 32 percent in cash and three percent in commodities-related assets.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Geneva Newsroom 41-22 733 38 31</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
