<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21191" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria would not refuse Commonwealth officials.</title>
<headline>Nigeria would not refuse Commonwealth officials.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigeria would not object to a visit by Commonwealth officials but insists its suspension from the organisation be resolved before any other questions are addressed, Foreign Minister Tom Ikimi said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Ikimi reiterated his position that the Commonwealth had no mandate to send a fact-finding mission.</p>
<p>&quot;The request I have received is for their officials to come and talk to my officials. We cannot object to people wanting to visit Nigeria,&quot; Ikimi told Reuters by telephone from the capital Abuja.</p>
<p>&quot;The fundamental problem we have with the Commonwealth is our unfair suspension. Any discussions we have at ministerial level will be a continuation of what we began in London on that. Before that is accomplished we cannot address anything else.&quot;</p>
<p>Nigeria was suspended from the Commonwealth in November after the execution of Ken Saro-Wiwa and eight other minority rights activists in defiance of international pleas for clemency.</p>
<p>A meeting of Commonwealth ministers in London on Wednesday said it planned to send a team of senior officials to Nigeria as soon as possible to persuade Abuja to accept a fact-finding mission.</p>
<p>The timing of that mission has yet to be determined.</p>
<p>The latest diplomatic row between Nigeria's military government and the club of Britain and its former colonies erupted over the terms of a visit by Commonwealth ministers to discuss Nigeria's suspension.</p>
<p>Nigeria said they would be restricted to a two-day meeting with government officials, but the Commonwealth said it wanted to hold meetings with people outside the government and called off the visit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COMWH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
