<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212065" id="root" date="1996-11-22" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FEATURE - Immigrants inundate Italian island.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Immigrants inundate Italian island.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>LAMPEDUSA, Italy 1996-11-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of the first things illegal immigrants do when they arrive on this windswept island is go to the police station and ask to be arrested.</p>
<p>The police then take them to nearby Sicily and after a brief bureaucratic ritual they are almost always set free to start a new life in wealthy Italy -- or beyond.</p>
<p>&quot;This has to be the easiest stepping stone into Europe and unless the politicians do something now, this problem is going to get much worse,&quot; said Piero Billeci, deputy mayor of this rocky, southern Italian outpost.</p>
<p>A stream of immigrants from northern Africa has poured across the narrow stretch of dazzling blue sea that divides remote Lampedusa from Tunisia.</p>
<p>Since the start of the year nearly 3,200 people have made the 110-km (70-mile) trip in an armada of ramshackle fishing boats, with 1,318 arriving in October alone.</p>
<p>The influx has taken the authorities by surprise and angered some of Italy's European Union partners, but Prime Minister Romano Prodi's centre-left government seems unwilling to introduce tough new immigration laws for fear of appearing racist.</p>
<p>Italy's 4,000-km (2,500-mile) coastline has proved a magnet for illegal immigrants -- called &quot;clandestini&quot; in Italian -- with Albanians and north Africans leading the onslaught.</p>
<p>The barren island of Lampedusa, which lies closer to Africa than it does to Sicily, has become an increasingly popular entry point for Tunisians, Algerians and Moroccans, especially now that Spain has cracked down on illegal immigration.</p>
<p>&quot;There has to be some sort of organisation in Tunisia which is behind all of this,&quot; said Francesco Melis, head of the local finance police which has to register all the new arrivals and send them on to the main administrative offices in Sicily.</p>
<p>Some people believe the Italian Mafia itself might be muscling in on the lucrative trade.</p>
<p>Melis said the clandestini, almost always young men, pay around one million lire ($660) for their passage to Italy. &quot;If you think that the boats carry between 40 to 80 people, someone, somewhere is making a very tidy profit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A small open-air compound next to the police station houses the immigrants until a private ferry company takes them to Sicily at the state's expense. The firm offers a discount: for every group of 10 clandestini, one travels free.</p>
<p>&quot;Only in Italy could a thing like this happen,&quot; sighed Billeci.</p>
<p>Lampedusans have got used to the sight of ragged immigrants wandering across the island in search of the police station and a corner of the tiny port has become a graveyard for the brightly coloured boats that bring them in.</p>
<p>Chastened by the numbers of clandestini to have arrived on the island since the start of the autumn, the government has beefed up its coastal patrols.</p>
<p>A confusing array of marine forces, backed up by helicopters and light aircraft, now watch over the sea, trying to prevent the immigrants from reaching land.</p>
<p>&quot;The trouble is that when we stop them in Italian waters they don't want to turn back,&quot; said Melis.</p>
<p>A group of immigrants caught at sea in October wrecked the engine of their boat, forcing the coastguards to tow them ashore.</p>
<p>Once they get to Sicily, local authorities issue them with expulsion orders which give them two weeks to make their own way out of the country. Some of them do -- but only to Germany or France, not back home.</p>
<p>&quot;They risk their lives coming here in those little boats, which are often unseaworthy,&quot; Melis said. &quot;They are not about to go home because the authorities in Agrigento ask them to.&quot;</p>
<p>Melis said some of the clandestini had turned out to be Algerian fundamentalists looking to cause trouble in France but it was impossible to check their identities when they arrived because virtually none carried documents.</p>
<p>Italy's relaxed immigration policy has angered its European Union partners and thrown into doubt its chances of being admitted to the Schengen pact -- the small club of EU nations operating open borders among themselves.</p>
<p>&quot;Italy has the leakiest borders in Europe,&quot; complained a security source at a western embassy in Rome.</p>
<p>Around 56,015 clandestini were issued with expulsion orders in 1995. Just 7,417 complied.</p>
<p>Some estimates have put the total number of illegal immigrants in Italy at 500,000 and rising.</p>
<p>The head of the national police, Ferdinando Masone, suggested last month that clandestini should be flown back home in a fleet of charter planes. The firebrand leader of the populist Northern League, Umberto Bossi, said cargo ships should be used to save costs.</p>
<p>But any hint of enforced repatriation, of the type seen in France, raises a chorus of protest from civil liberty groups in a country which still remembers the time when millions of its own nationals were forced to emigrate to the Americas earlier this century to escape hardship and poverty.</p>
<p>On Wednesday the government used a vote of confidence to ram through the upper house of parliament a draft law which will allow up to 250,000 immigrants living in Italy without permission to legalise their position.</p>
<p>The hard-right National Alliance party and Bossi's Northern League, demanding compulsory explusions, forced the confidence motion after submerging the bill with amendments. Another do-or-die vote will probably be necessary when the legislation goes to the lower house for further ratification.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not saying that every foreigner who wants to come and live in Italy should be allowed to,&quot; said Interior Minister Giorgio Napolitano, adding that the coalition might soon come up with a new immigration law.</p>
<p>Back on Lampedusa, Billeci said the government decision meant a new army of immigrants would soon be making its way to the island.</p>
<p>&quot;In the end we are going to have to do something to boost the economy over there to make life in Africa more attractive,&quot; he said. &quot;In the meantime we should start to get tough.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-22"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-22"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAMPEDUSA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
