<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21207" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SENEGAL: Malian airport workers protest at &quot;flight of shame&quot;.</title>
<headline>Malian airport workers protest at &quot;flight of shame&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Diadie Ba</byline>
<dateline>DAKAR 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>French troops had to be flown into Mali on Thursday when protesting ground staff refused to service a plane carrying Africans expelled from France, officials said.</p>
<p>The French army Airbus A310 carrying 11 Senegalese arrived in Dakar after a stop in Bamako, where 35 Malians disembarked.</p>
<p>The officials said French soldiers flew to Mali from Senegal to carry out refuelling and pre-flight checks on the plane, dubbed a &quot;flight of shame&quot; like the one that brought home more than 50 illegal immigrants last weekend.</p>
<p>A second plane landed in Tunis and refuelled in Niger without problems before continuing to Zaire. It carried 12 Tunisians and 30 Zaireans -- 10 of them expelled from the Netherlands.</p>
<p>The government of Senegal, in its first comment on expulsions of its nationals from France and Angola, said it was in close contact with the governments of both countries.</p>
<p>&quot;In this (Angolan) affair, as in the case of the Africans without valid documents in Paris, the government of Senegal is acting in close liaison with the other parties to the matter. It is doing so according to the conventions and in line with the rules established for international relations,&quot; a government statement said.</p>
<p>Senegal's opposition and press have attacked the government's lack of criticism of its former colonial ruler.</p>
<p>In Bamako, Sambourou Sow, a member of the High Council of Malians Abroad, said three of the Malians on the plane had been detained in a police raid on protesters at the Saint-Bernard church in Paris on Friday.</p>
<p>One of the three, Mahamadou Niakate from Lambidou in the western Djenne region, said his wife was still in Paris and he did not know whether she would be aboard the next flight.</p>
<p>Sow said about 30 French soldiers had accompanied the deportees.</p>
<p>Last Saturday, France deported 23 Malians, four of them from the church, along with 13 Senegalese, 18 Zaireans and two Gabonese. Another 248 Senegalese have been deported from Angola as part of a crackdown on foreign traders there.</p>
<p>Senegalese traders are found all over Africa and in Europe and North America. Scores more are expected to be affected by tougher rules for migrant workers announced by Sierra Leone on Monday.</p>
<p>Angola has thrown out hundreds of West Africans, Lebanese and Indians since the start two weeks ago of a campaign against foreign traders. President Abdou Diouf sent his minister of state at the presidency, Abdoulaye Wade, to intercede with the Angolan authorities.</p>
<p>French handling of the illegal immigration issue has taken centre stage since the controversial police raid on 300 African protesters, 10 of them on a hunger strike, who had occupied the Saint-Bernard church for two months in a symbolic protest.</p>
<p>Thousands of demonstrators marched through Paris on Wednesday to demand that expulsion orders be repealed and immigration laws reviewed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SENEG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAKAR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SENEGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
