<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212107" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-VIALLI DENIES ZOLA WITH SUBTLEST OF HEADERS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-VIALLI DENIES ZOLA WITH SUBTLEST OF HEADERS.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gianluca Vialli denied fellow-Italian Gianfranco Zola his first premier league goal with the subtlest of glancing headers in Chelsea's eventful 1-1 draw with Newcastle on Saturday.</p>
<p>Zola appeared to have struck on his home debut for the Londoners when he swung a free-kick in from the Chelsea left past Newcastle goalkeeper Pavel Srnicek and into the net.</p>
<p>But Vialli, who lunged at the ball with his head as it flew across the face of goal and then held his arm aloft to claim his seventh goal of the season, confirmed afterwards he had indeed made contact.</p>
<p>&quot;I touched the ball but I don't want to quarrel with anyone about it. I would never take a goal away from Gianfranco, especially on his debut, if it wasn't true.&quot;</p>
<p>Zola did not doubt his friend, saying: &quot;He told me he touched it and I believe him.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I was trying to score. I have scored many goals like that in Italy... But if he says he touched it then I will believe him. That's not a problem for me.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It was important we scored a goal, not who scored it,&quot; said Chelsea player-manager Ruud Gullitt, whose mop of dreadlocks contrasts starkly with Vialli shaven scalp. &quot;Maybe Vialli touched it with the one hair on his head!&quot;</p>
<p>Few at Stamford Bridge cared either way after a bright first quarter dominated by Gullit's side, playing with greater confidence as the season progresses.</p>
<p>But the goal spurred Kevin Keegan's league leaders into action and they had the edge for the rest of the half, snatching a deserved equaliser through Alan Shearer, back in the side after groin surgery which kept him out of the game for 34 days.</p>
<p>Colombian Faustino Asprilla, a former team mate of Zola's at Parma, put the England striker clean through on goal.</p>
<p>Norwegian goalkeeper Frode Grodas saved well at Shearer's feet but the world's costliest player retrieved the ball, danced round a couple of Chelsea defenders and fired a shot high into Grodas's unguarded net for his ninth goal of the season.</p>
<p>As the November gloom encroached on Stamford Bridge, the standard of football deteriorated.</p>
<p>David Ginola was booked for kicking the ball away, Belgium's Philippe Albert was cautioned for a dreadful challenge on Vialli, and David Batty was sent off for elbowing Mark Hughes squarely between the eyes, leaving the Welsh forward with a gash across his forehead.</p>
<p>Chelsea pressed hard for a winner in the closing stages. Dennis Wise struck the crossbar with a thundering drive from 25 metres and Newcastle goalkeeper Pavel Srineck pulled off an astonishing reaction save from a close-range Dan Petrescu header.</p>
<p>But Newcastle clung on for a point which, allied to results from around the country, means they stay a point clear at the top of the premier league.</p>
<p>Liverpool threatened to leap-frog over the Tynesiders for much of the afternoon after Stan Collymore gave them the lead against fourth-placed Wimbledon inside the first minute.</p>
<p>Collymore, starting his first match since October 12 amid widespread speculation he is set to leave Anfield, capitalised on a mistake by defender Dean Blackwell and steered a shot past Neil Sullivan for his fourth goal of the season.</p>
<p>But the Londoners hit back through Norwegian Oyvind Leonhardson in the second half and have now lost only once at Anfield on their last seven visits.</p>
<p>Champions Manchester United had to settle for a single point too after Middlesbrough twice fought back from a goal down to earn a 2-2 draw at the Riverside stadium.</p>
<p>Irish international Roy Keane and defender David May scored for United, who responded to their midweek Champions' League defeat by Juventus by fielding a much-changed side packed with the latest batch of Old Trafford youngsters.</p>
<p>The draws at Chelsea, Liverpool and Middlesbrough meant little changed at the top of the table.</p>
<p>Newcastle stay a point clear of Liverpool and Wimbledon remain fourth, a further three points back. Third-placed Arsenal play Tottenham in the London derby on Sunday.</p>
<p>Chelsea stay fifth while Manchester United slip a place to seventh, one spot behind in-form Everton, who won 2-1 away at Leicester.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
