<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212100" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ALPINE SKIING-KIWI AUSTRIAN CLAUDIA RIEGLER WINS SLALOM.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-KIWI AUSTRIAN CLAUDIA RIEGLER WINS SLALOM.</headline>
<dateline>PARK CITY, Utah 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Claudia Riegler, the latest Austrian skiier to strike it rich under a different country's banner, took another step towards stardom Saturday with a victory in the season's first World Cup slalom.</p>
<p>Riegler, who skis for New Zealand, held off world champion Pernilla Wiberg of Sweden to claim her second career victory with a time of 1:36.50. A strong second run by Wiberg made it close at the finish at 1:36.57.</p>
<p>Austrian veteran Ingrid Salvenmoser took third in 1:37.49, her best result since 1991. Patricia Chauvet of France was fourth and Sabine Egger of Austria fifth, an eyeblink ahead of Deborah Compagnoni of Italy.</p>
<p>Much like countryman Marc Girardelli 15 years earlier, Riegler left the Austrian team three years ago because of frustration over being trapped among the country's masses of fine young racers.</p>
<p>With a New Zealand mother, Riegler claimed dual citizenship and quickly blossomed. Now the 20-year-old looks to have a chance to follow Girardelli, who won five overall World Cup titles and a bushel of medals, as a champion.</p>
<p>She earned her first World Cup victory, also a slalom, midway through last season, then finished fourth -- &quot;the worst place,&quot; she called it -- at the world championships.</p>
<p>&quot;It's great to be back on top of the podium. I take a lot of risks, but I know I can win when I cam make it,&quot; Riegler said.</p>
<p>Her second run typified that attacking style and, for a scary few seconds, nearly cost the race. Flailing wildly through the first few gates, she suddenly settled into solid form and finished strongly.</p>
<p>&quot;I really blew the start and that made me upset. So I attacked some more after that.&quot;</p>
<p>Riegler, who still holds to her Austrian heritage and continues her schooling in her native Salzburg, had a tough challenge her first World Cup season, when, without sponsors or a national team, her parents absorbed more than $50,000 in annual expenses for a coach and travel.</p>
<p>Now she is established among the stars of the sport with a rich future.</p>
<p>Wiberg, in her eighth season with five Olympic and World Championship medals, has quite a different agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;After my bad result in giant slalom two days ago, I just wanted to come through. I skied conservatively, under control both runs.&quot;</p>
<p>The Swedish strategy was a good one on a course still soft and treacherous after the rain the previous day that postponed a men's giant slalom. The course held up well under the circumstances and the way seems clear for Sunday's men's slalom and Monday's makeup men's giant slalom.</p>
<p>Salvenmoser, in her 14th season at age 29, took her success, achieved largely with the fastest second run, as a harbinger of better things to come.</p>
<p>&quot;After so long from the podium, it's a great feeling. I now know what I need to have a victory. This gives me great confidence.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARK CITY, Utah"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
