<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212245" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire refugees leave forests; force in balance.</title>
<headline>Zaire refugees leave forests; force in balance.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rwandan refugees are emerging from the forests of eastern Zaire saying many more are on their way, but just how many appears to be critical with the despatch of a promised international military force still in the balance.</p>
<p>The U.S. army, which has been using surveillance aircraft, put the numbers roaming the region at just over 200,000 -- a third of the U.N. refugee agency's projection.</p>
<p>In Stuttgart, Germany, Western and African military leaders struggled to establish how many refugees needed help in Zaire amid signs interest in the multi-national mission was flagging.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems now as though more people will favour keeping the status quo and not stepping up the commitment since the situation is starting to take care of itself,&quot; one European official there said.</p>
<p>Western aid chiefs and donors ended talks on Saturday to coordinate relief with pledges to help Rwanda resettle its Hutu returnees but no commitment for a military force in east Zaire.</p>
<p>Zairean rebels have agreed to let international relief organisations launch a programme to assess the number of Rwandan refugees still in Zaire and what assistance they need.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed on details of how the (assessment) will work and we expect them to start working on Sunday,&quot; an official for the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) said.</p>
<p>The refugees fled a Tutsi-led rebellion which routed Zairean government troops and the Interahamwe Rwandan Hutu militia which had an iron grip on the vast refugee camps in the region.</p>
<p>Half a million Hutus returned home to Rwanda a week ago after rebels drove Hutu hardliners from the Mugunga Camp, at the time the world's biggest. Estimates of how many remain vary.</p>
<p>&quot;There are so many people in the forest that it is impossible to describe,&quot; said Jeanepo Musivimu, a Rwandan Hutu. &quot;Along the way are many people who are sick... Many... are unaccompanied children whose parents have been killed.&quot;</p>
<p>Musivimu was talking on the outskirts of Mugunga camp, near Goma, after walking for seven days with his family. He was one of an estimated 3,000 who arrived in Mugunga on Saturday.</p>
<p>Residents in Sake, just west of Goma, reported renewed heavy fighting in and around the town overnight on Friday, and said there were now rebel roadblocks on the roads into the town.</p>
<p>&quot;There was very heavy firing last night,&quot; Denis Nduziye, from a hamlet outside Sake, said on Saturday. &quot;The rebels told us it was the Interahamwe who had come down from the Masisi.&quot;</p>
<p>Rebels appeared to be in control of the area along Kivu, a border lake with Rwanda, but local residents said Hutu militants were in the mountains to the west holding many refugees.</p>
<p>Reporters who had their first chance for days to travel along the road from Bukavu and Goma saw traces of what the villagers said were signs of a hasty retreat by Hutu guerrillas after the latest string of battles.</p>
<p>In Goma itself, doctors reported a cholera epidemic, with 15 deaths in the past week.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had 114 confirmed cases of cholera since the refugees left a week ago,&quot; said Jo Lusi, a doctor at the Virunga hospital in the slums of northern Goma. &quot;For us an epidemic would be 40, but this is nearly three times that.&quot;</p>
<p>In Kinshasa, a government spokesman said Zaire radical opposition leader Etienne Tshisekedi will not face arrest on his return from France on Tuesday following government accusations that statements he made verged on treason. &quot;We will not arrest him just like that. The judiciary must first deepen its inquiry,&quot; government spokesman Boguo Makeli told Reuters.</p>
<p>Tshesekedi said after reconciliation talks with President Mobutu Sese Seko, who is recuperating in France from cancer surgery, that dialogue was the only answer to the revolt and rebel leader Laurent Kabila, a veteran Mobutu foe, had a role to play in Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
