<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212329" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's Cardoso hits midway point.</title>
<headline>Brazil's Cardoso hits midway point.</headline>
<byline>Michael Christie</byline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Midway through his four-year term, President Fernando Henrique Cardoso believes he has already achieved the first stage of his Brazilian revolution, opening up the economy to capitalism and trade.</p>
<p>&quot;This we have already won. Economic reform has happened,&quot; Cardoso, an aloof intellectual who has managed to win Brazilian hearts by exorcizing the demon of hyperinflation, said late on Friday in his first interview with the overseas press. &quot;Reforming the state, that is still at play.&quot;</p>
<p>Latin America's largest country, with 160 million people and a topography ranging from the semi-desert of the northeast to the world's largest rainforest, has emerged under Cardoso as an economic and political power to be reckoned with.</p>
<p>The &quot;Real Plan&quot; of economic stability has cut inflation from 5,000 percent a year to an estimated 13 percent in 1996 and has seen the state sell off billions of dollars in assets.</p>
<p>Brazil still lags behind other Latin American nations such as Chile whose economic liberalisation plans were more ambitious. But Cardoso, sitting in his office in the Presidential Palace as aides quietly reminded him a plane to Rio de Janeiro and from there to Africa was ready to leave, said he had laid the foundations for Brazil's future.</p>
<p>&quot;The most important thing I have achieved is the continuity of (economic) stability because it may seem easy but actually is very hard. Now we have started moving in the social area.&quot;</p>
<p>A former sociology professor who went into exile under Brazil's 1964-85 military rule, Cardoso took office pledging to break with the Brazil of the past, where billionaires got richer while 30 million Brazilians languished in the slums.</p>
<p>Critics say he has not done enough and a recent United Nations report showed Brazil was still a wealth-gap leader. But popularity polls put Cardoso way ahead and he claimed the victory against inflation alone had raised 13 million people above the poverty line between 1993 and 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;Stability isn't something to be seen as just benefiting markets, it also benefits society. I think that's the most important thing we've achieved in these two years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Now the Brazilian president wants more time to complete the economic, fiscal and social reforms he has begun. After keeping a dignified silence, Cardoso finally came out of the closet in September and said he would like to seek re-election in 1998, something Brazil has not allowed for fear political continuity could mean a revival of past imperial powers.</p>
<p>Government allies in Congress have set up a committee to draft a constitutional amendment on re-election, following a trend that has swept Latin America in the past five years. And in the intrigue-filled halls of Brasilia, re-election is regarded as the main issue, overshadowing even needed reforms of the distorted pension system and civil service.</p>
<p>But Cardoso denied that re-election dominated his agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;Re-election is not my most ardent desire,&quot; he said. &quot;If re-election doesn't happen, nothing will change. If the other reforms (social security, tax, civil service and land reform) don't take place, then things would change.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he wanted to be remembered for deeper reforms of the state, not just fiscal reforms to counter an operational deficit seen hitting 4.0 percent of gross domestic product this year, but also land reform to even the balance of wealth.</p>
<p>Four percent of Brazil is in the hands of just 307 people while landless groups say 4.8 million families are homeless.</p>
<p>&quot;Agrarian reform is of great symbolic value,&quot; Cardoso said. &quot;It isn't just about raising food production. It's about whether Brazil starts to pay attention to its dispossessed.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
