<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212310" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish peasants keep Pawlak as party leader.</title>
<headline>Polish peasants keep Pawlak as party leader.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish Peasant Party, junior partner in the ruling left-wing coalition, reelected  Waldemar Pawlak as leader on Saturday.</p>
<p>Results announced in the small hours and reported by PAP news agency showed 695 delgates at a party convention voted to give the 37-year old Pawlak four more years in the post.</p>
<p>Agriculture Minister Roman Jagielinski got 402 votes and 120 delegates backed another challenger, Janusz Piechocinski.</p>
<p>&quot;I know I made mistakes, but I also know that I did not betray Poland or the peasants,&quot; Pawlak told delegates before the vote, winning a standing ovation, Gazeta Wyborcza reported.</p>
<p>As prime minister until early last year in coalition with the ex-communist Democratic Left Alliance, Pawlak was accused by critics of braking market reforms and hampering privatisation.</p>
<p>But he remains popular among farmers as the man who led the Peasants to a strong showing in the 1993 elections and whose policies allowed many of the party's members to gain government posts.</p>
<p>Opinion polls have indicated for months that the Peasants, backed by around 15 percent of voters, are likely to hold the balance of power after a general election next year.</p>
<p>The convention also overwhelmingly re-elected parliamentary speaker Jozef Zych as the chairman of the party's council.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
