<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212346" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Christopher calls for N.Korea gesture toward South.</title>
<headline>Christopher calls for N.Korea gesture toward South.</headline>
<byline>Carol Giacomo</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher on Saturday renewed a U.S. call for North Korea to make a &quot;gesture&quot; to the South to acknowledge its submarine incursion last September was a serious mistake.</p>
<p>Christopher did not define what the gesture might be but his remarks were a clear signal to Pyongyang as Washington struggles to restore forward movement in efforts to lower tensions, and ultimately bring stability, to the volatile Korean peninsula.</p>
<p>Washington views the incursion as a &quot;highly provocative incident (and) continues to believe the North Koreans should make a gesture that indicates they have a similar assessment of the seriousness of that action&quot;, Christopher told reporters.</p>
<p>He spoke on the eve of talks between U.S. President Bill Clinton and South Korean President Kim Young-sam that will focus on the submarine incident, a landmark 1994 nuclear accord between Washington and Pyongyang, and a U.S.-South Korean proposal for four-party peace talks with North Korea and China.</p>
<p>Christopher, who met his South Korean counterpart on Friday to prepare for Sunday's summit, said Washington and Seoul were in &quot;total convergence&quot; on dealing with the Stalinist North.</p>
<p>Both governments are committed to the 1994 landmark U.S.-North Korean nuclear deal and both are &quot;fully agreed on the importance of four-party talks&quot; on a new peace accord for the Korean peninsula, Christopher said.</p>
<p>The submarine incident fired up public opinion in South Korea, pushing Kim toward a more hawkish stance and raising questions about how long Washington and Seoul could maintain a united front toward the North.</p>
<p>The closest U.S. ally in Asia, Seoul was not pleased when Christopher's first reaction to the incident was to call for restraint by both sides.</p>
<p>The ministers are in Manila for the annual meeting of the Asia-Pacific Economic forum (APEC). APEC heads of state hold a summit on Monday.</p>
<p>Tense relations between the two Koreas worsened after a North Korean submarine landed 26 agents on a South Korean beach in September. Twenty-four of them were shot dead, one was captured alive and another is still at large.</p>
<p>South Korea had said previously it would suspend all assistance to the North, including financing the nuclear deal, until Pyongyang &quot;clearly apologises&quot; for the submarine incident and guarantees such an incident will not be repeated.</p>
<p>The North insists the incident was an accident.</p>
<p>After the incident, Seoul recently delayed sending technicians to do site work preparation for the reactors in the North and Pyongyang responded by threatening to end its nuclear freeze.</p>
<p>After Christopher met South Korean Foreign Minister Yoo Chong-ha on Friday, his spokesman expressed confidence that the multi-billion dollar landmark nuclear agreement with North Korea would go forward. He said Christopher had been reassured South Korea remains committed to the deal.</p>
<p>Officials said they still believed Seoul required some sort of gesture by Pyongyang to &quot;atone for the sins&quot; of its submarine incursion into the South last September.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns told reporters he expected that gesture would be forthcoming. He did not elaborate, but U.S. officials have been meeting weekly in New York with North Korean counterparts.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Pyongyang pledged to freeze its nuclear programme, in return for two light water nuclear power reactors and alternative energy supliers.</p>
<p>Once estimated at $4.5 billion, the Americans said the South Koreans -- who agreed to pay the lion's share of the costs -- now put the pricetag at $6 billion.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
