<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212350" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Clinton prepares for China talks, APEC.</title>
<headline>Clinton prepares for China talks, APEC.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>PORT DOUGLAS, Australia 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton left Australia on Saturday for the Philippines and the major event of his 12-day Asian trip -- a bilateral meeting with Chinese President Jiang Zemin.</p>
<p>After a relaxing five-day Australian trip highlighted by koala bear-cuddling, reef snorkelling and golf, Clinton must now focus on Washington's major Asian diplomatic headache -- relations with Beijing.</p>
<p>Clinton will meet the Chinese president on Sunday in Manila, before attending a summit of Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum leaders on Monday in Subic Bay.</p>
<p>Clinton will try to persuade the Chinese leader to ease trade barriers viewed as protectionist by the outside world and he plans to raise human rights, an issue that traditionally strains U.S.-China relations.</p>
<p>Clinton has been sending signals to China from Australia that Washington wants a warmer, more stable relationship.</p>
<p>Washington believes China is too big and important to ignore and must be economically and politically engaged, a policy adopted towards the Soviet Union in the Cold War.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States has no interest in containing China. That is a negative strategy,&quot; Clinton said on Wednesday when addressing the Australian parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;What the United States wants is to sustain an engagement with China...in a way that will increase the chances that there will be more liberty and more prosperity,&quot; Clinton said.</p>
<p>To help smooth the waters before Sunday's meeting, U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher held talks in Beijing this week and although there were no official announcements, a blueprint for better relations was drawn up.</p>
<p>A timetable, if not specific dates, for an exchange of summits in each other's capitals is likely to be announced after the bilateral meeting on Sunday.</p>
<p>Clinton's attendance at the 18-member APEC summit on Monday will also give him a chance to demonstrate Washington's renewed commitment to the Asia-Pacific region and engagement with China.</p>
<p>Clinton this week stressed U.S. interest in the region and Washington's determination to be a key economic and political player in a part of the world often neglected by the United States in the past.</p>
<p>&quot;In a global economy and global security challenges, America must look to the East no less than the West,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But senior U.S. officials say the APEC meeting, which Clinton elevated four years ago from ministerial level to heads of governments, is not expected to produce dramatic trade breakthroughs. &quot;We hope to deal with real nuts and bolts issues,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>On Sunday, in addition to talks with the Chinese leader, Clinton plans meetings with Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto and South Korean President Kim Young-sam.</p>
<p>Aides said Clinton intended to explore reviving an idea raised in April for four-way talks between the United States, China and North and South Korea on trying to defuse tensions on the Korean Peninsula.</p>
<p>While in Australia, Clinton leaves behind a reinvigorated U.S.-Australia relationship, based on a theme of united Asian engagement through stronger security ties and trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT DOUGLAS, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
