<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212363" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Suu Kyi speaks briefly, urges discipline, patience.</title>
<headline>Suu Kyi speaks briefly, urges discipline, patience.</headline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burmese democracy leader Aung San Suu Kyi made a brief speech to supporters outside the barricades barring access to her house on Saturday, and urged them to be disciplined, tolerant and patient in their fight for democracy.</p>
<p>&quot;The reason why I came here is to show that we have discipline,&quot; Suu Kyi told about 500 cheering supporters who gathered about three km (1.8 miles) from her house.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not here to cause unrest, we are here to show that we will go on until we reach our intended goal with discipline like this,&quot; she said. &quot;We are not doing this to provoke anyone. Similarly everyone knows that nobody should provoke us either.&quot;</p>
<p>The 1991 Nobel Peace laureate was speaking to her supporters for the first time since her motorcade was attacked by a group of stick-wielding, stone-throwing youths two weeks ago as she drove to make a similar speech.</p>
<p>Suu Kyi, who was unhurt in the the incident which smashed her windshield and the windows of other cars in her motorcade, blamed the government for orchestrating the attack.</p>
<p>The government denied involvement, but diplomats said several men involved in the attack said they were paid money to come in from neighboring townships to cause unrest.</p>
<p>Last weekend Suu Kyi did not come out to meet her supporters, who gather at the same place every Saturday and Sunday with the hope of seeing her.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Suu Kyi told Reuters she stayed home last weekend to avoid a repeat of the attack at the request of other leaders of her National League for Democracy (NLD) party.</p>
<p>The government has been trying for more than two months to stop Suu Kyi from giving regular weekend speeches to supporters from her front gates.</p>
<p>THe speeches, which began spontaneously after Suu Kyi was released from six years of house arrest last July, have become a regular event, drawing thousands of supporters.</p>
<p>The government charged that the gatherings outside her house were illegal, and set up barricades at the entrance to her street barring vehicles and pedestrians from entering. The barricades are usually set up late on Friday night and removed early on Monday morning.</p>
<p>Suu Kyi has vowed to continue the talks, and over the past few weeks had driven in her car outside the barricades to talk to groups of supporters waiting several kilometres (miles) away.</p>
<p>After speaking for about five minutes on Saturday, she asked the crowd to disperse. They went home without incident, and she also arrived back at her residence without any problem, witnesses said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
