<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212439" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>KUWAIT: Ekeus says U.N. concerned about Iraqi weapons.</title>
<headline>Ekeus says U.N. concerned about Iraqi weapons.</headline>
<dateline>KUWAIT 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. official in charge of destroying Iraq's deadliest weapons has expressed concern that Baghdad has not given an acceptable account of its missiles or biological and chemical arms capabilities.</p>
<p>&quot;What we have not achieved is to have a satisfactory account of missiles which Iraq may be keeping or an account of biological and chemical weapon capabilities, so we are still concerned,&quot; the official Kuwait News Agency (KUNA) quoted Rolf Ekeus as saying upon arrival in Kuwait on Friday night.</p>
<p>Ekeus will brief the U.N. Security Council on Iraq's refusal to allow its arms experts to transport missile parts for inspection, KUNA reported.</p>
<p>&quot;The Security Council has already discussed the issue and has agreed that this is a serious matter and asked for an oral report from me after my visit to the region,&quot; Ekeus said.</p>
<p>Ekeus, who is touring Arab Gulf states, said in remarks published on Friday that Baghdad recently obstructed U.N. efforts to study parts of Scud missiles.</p>
<p>A senior U.N. official said this week that the U.N. planned to take the remains of missiles for study outside Iraq to help assess Baghdad's claims that all Scuds have been destroyed.</p>
<p>&quot;It is up to the Iraqi government as it looks now to make up its mind if it wants to cooperate with us or not. We are doing our part,&quot; KUNA quoted Ekeus as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;We are trying to solve this problem. We are depending on a cooperative attitude from Iraq,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Ekeus's deputy, Charles Duelfer, is in Baghdad for talks on the monitoring of weapons of mass destruction in line with terms of the ceasefire that ended the 1991 Gulf War over Kuwait.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KUWAIT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
