<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21242" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: U.N. monitors surrounded by Serb mob, police.</title>
<headline>U.N. monitors surrounded by Serb mob, police.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Six U.N. officials were surrounded in their office by an angry Bosnian Serb mob and a group of Serb policemen on Thursday and one of those trapped said he expected an attack &quot;any minute&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is very, very dangerous,&quot; U.N. police monitor Alexandar Mikulitch told reporters by telephone from Zvornik in eastern Bosnia. &quot;We are expecting an attack any minute. If I survive we will talk again tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>The crowd of some 600 Serbs appeared to be acting in retaliation after NATO troops earlier detained scores of Bosnian Serb policemen, some of them from Zvornik, following a shooting incident with Moslems in the nearby village of Mahala.</p>
<p>In that confrontation Bosnian Serb police beat a group of Moslem refugees who had returned to Mahala to repair homes damaged during the war, the U.N. said.</p>
<p>Gunfire erupted and NATO-led peace forces intervened, corralling 65 Serb policemen inside a cordon of armoured vehicles and combat troops.</p>
<p>NATO officials in Sarajevo said combat troops had been despatched to Zvornik and the Commissioner of the U.N. International Police Task Force (IPTF) in Bosnia, Peter Fitzgerald, was on his way to Zvornik by helicopter.</p>
<p>SRNA reported that Bosnian NATO commander General Sir Michael Walker and Bosnian Serb Minister of Interior Dragan Kijac were also headed for Zvornik, a hard-core Serb nationalist town which expelled its Moslem majority population early in the war.</p>
<p>Those surrounded in Zvornik included five unarmed U.N. police monitors and a U.N. civil affairs officer. Three local staff members who had also been trapped were later allowed to leave.</p>
<p>Alex Ivanko, a U.N. spokesman in Sarajevo, said two of the U.N. monitors had been forced into the office at gunpoint after returning from the nearby village of Mahala where a standoff was under way between Serb police and NATO troops.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the monitors, a Russian, was verbally abused and kicked and shoved into the building at gunpoint. They (U.N. staff) have barricaded themselves inside the building for protection,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The police are doing nothing to control the situation. We believe the Bosnian Serb Minister of Interior is in the area but doing nothing to calm things down. This is beyond belief.&quot;</p>
<p>U.N. sources said three U.N. vehicles in the building's car park had been destroyed.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of those leading the crowd are well-known local thugs,&quot; Ivanko told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.N. is outraged by this attack and we call on officials of the Serb republic to disperse the crowd. We haven't seen anything this outrageous since the Dayton peace agreement was signed last December.&quot;</p>
<p>Mohamed Sacirbey, Bosnia's Ambassador to the United Nations, pointed to the incidents in Mahala and Zvornik as evidence of the deep divisions besetting the country just two weeks before nationwide elections.</p>
<p>&quot;These incidents show that going into elections there are two different philosophies in place,&quot; the ambassador said.</p>
<p>&quot;One, the Serb philosophy, is to divide the country. The other is to reintegrate it. Something needs to be done to reconcile these two philosophies before we can go forward with elections.&quot;</p>
<p>Bosnian elections are scheduled for September 14.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
