<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212427" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAN: Iran hopes tension will not harm ties with Germany.</title>
<headline>Iran hopes tension will not harm ties with Germany.</headline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iranian Foreign Minister Ali Akbar Velayati on Saturday said he hoped strains between Tehran and Bonn would not harm relations between the two countries.</p>
<p>&quot;Iran's official position is what President Rafsanjani said yesterday in Friday sermons. That Iran, too, hopes the disappointing incident would not harm the deep-rooted and long-lasting relations,&quot; he told reporters in Tehran.</p>
<p>Iranian President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani said on Friday the German government was under U.S. and Israeli pressure but said he hoped Bonn would prevent tensions in ties with Tehran from spiralling out of control.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani said Iran hoped to continue its friendship with its biggest trade partner despite strains over the trial of five men for the 1992 killing of three Kurdish dissidents and their translator in Berlin. Prosecutors last week accused Tehran of ordering the murders.</p>
<p>The German prosecutors' accusations against Iranian leaders have provoked outrage in Iran. Protesters have rallied outside the German embassy in Tehran, pelting the compound with eggs and tomatoes and calling for the prosecutors to be &quot;executed&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The governments of Germany and Iran are responsible for preserving the long-lasting bilateral relations. And both have put emphasis on efforts to stop further damage and deterioration of relations,&quot; Velayati said.</p>
<p>German Foreign Minister Klaus Kinkel assured Velayati in a telephone call on Sunday that the German judiciary was independent and that Bonn had no right to interfere in court proceedings.</p>
<p>Velayati on Saturday said Iran recognized the independence of Germany's judiciary, &quot;but at the same time it's not possible for the executive power to say it is not its business if an incident in the country harms relations with other countries.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
