<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212498" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Italian lira set to rejoin Europe's ERM.</title>
<headline>Italian lira set to rejoin Europe's ERM.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy on Saturday was poised to bring its lira currency back in to Europe's exchange rate mechanism (ERM) in a move Rome hopes will let it qualify for the single European currency in 1999.</p>
<p>Senior finance ministry and central bank officials were to meet in Brussels at 1200 GMT to discuss Italy's application to rejoin the currency stabilisation system it was embarrassingly thrown out of four years ago.</p>
<p>The ERM is designed to allow member currencies to trade within bands against each other -- for the most part fluctuating by no more than 15 percent from a central rate.</p>
<p>Eleven of the EU's 15 currencies are currently members, with only Italy, Sweden, Britain and Greece remaining outside. Finland joined the ERM in October.</p>
<p>A stable two year-stint within the ERM currency grid is one of the criteria for countries wishing to join the single currency.</p>
<p>Both Italy and Britain were forced out of the ERM in 1992 after a severe currency crisis nearly brought the system to its knees.</p>
<p>The Italian government does not want the lira to re-enter the grid at too high a level because of the adverse effect on its exports. It has said it would like a rate at between 1,000 to 1,050 lira to the German mark.</p>
<p>Neighbour France, however, wants it in at a less competitive rate because of the impact on its own industry. A figure of 950 lira to the mark has been floated as France's informal goal.</p>
<p>The lira closed around 999 to the mark on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Discussion with the partners on the parity will take into consideration the most recent market rates,&quot; Italian Treasury Minister Carlo Azeglio Ciampi has said.</p>
<p>One EU diplomat on Friday predicted intense negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be a difficult meeting,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But there was &quot;no evidence&quot; that France or Germany had sought a delay to the timing of the currency's re-entry.</p>
<p>German concerns over the future credibility of a single currency have been voiced repeatedly in recent months, punctuated by fears that politics will be the overriding factor in deciding which countries join economic and monetary union (EMU) in 1999.</p>
<p>European countries which want to include their currencies in the planned Euro from 1999 are rushing to meet targets on interest and exchange rates, inflation, budget deficits and public debt in 1997 -- necessary if they are to be at the start.</p>
<p>Most are facing the greatest problems in meeting the fiscal targets, which call for budget deficits to run at a maximum of three percent of gross domestic product and public debt at a maximum of 60 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>Several governments, including Italy, have used controversial one-off budgetary measures to bring their deficits under control.</p>
<p>But some EU monetary officials say that while Italy's turbulent currency history may be a reason to pause, it has nevertheless made enormous strides in the past few years towards becoming a more stable and prosperous economy.</p>
<p>Such an effort cannot be simply brushed aside, they add.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
