<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212589" id="root" date="1996-11-23" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Miss World show to go on, despite protest.</title>
<headline>Miss World show to go on, despite protest.</headline>
<byline>Dev Varam</byline>
<dateline>BANGALORE, India 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian police clashed with protesters and detained more than 1,000 people on Saturday, only hours before the start of the Miss World beauty contest.</p>
<p>But the demonstrators, some carrying banners reading &quot;Long Live Mother India&quot;, and threats by militant women to commit suicide by immolation, failed to deter the pageant organisers.</p>
<p>The nearly 90 contestants were reported to have left their hotel for a heavily guarded cricket stadium in which one of them will be crowned Miss World at around midnight (1830 GMT).</p>
<p>Three separate demonstrations led by right-wing Hindu nationalists left clouds of tear gas over roads leading to the stadium. Police said about 500 people had been detained.</p>
<p>Earlier, police said they had rounded up about 550 people to deter trouble.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot say what the figure (of detained) is. In all it will be over 1,000,&quot; a police official said.</p>
<p>Police said three members of parliament from New Delhi belonging to the Hindu nationalist Bharatiya Janata Party were among those detained.</p>
<p>Also detained was B.S. Yediyurappa, leader of the BJP in the Karnataka state assembly. &quot;I want the resignation of the state government. We are being denied our democratic rights,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Police said up to seven policemen were injured. Casualties among the protesters were unknown.</p>
<p>In one protest, a Reuters reporter saw police with batons and tear gas repel protesters throwing stones and marching on the Chinnaswamy stadium.</p>
<p>The protests blocked traffic for about two hours in Bangalore, the capital of Karnataka -- Indian Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda's home state and India's technology centre.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a police state,&quot; shouted Ananth Kumar, a BJP member of parliament, as police bundled him into a van.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a most bizarre situation,&quot; Julia Morley, the Miss World organiser, said.</p>
<p>Earlier, police held militant Hindu nationalists, communists and other protesters but were still seeking a group of 15 women threatening to burn themselves to protest against the show.</p>
<p>Bangalore police commissioner S.C. Burman said the city, patrolled by more than 10,000 police and paramilitary troopers, had witnessed little response to a strike call.</p>
<p>On Friday, a court ruled the armed forces could be used if needed to keep the peace.</p>
<p>But Miss World organisers remained alarmed by the threat of self-immolation by members of Mahila Jagran Samiti (Forum for Awakening Women), led by Kinay Narayana Shashikala.</p>
<p>Shashikala has been in hiding since Thursday, but members of the BJP say they are in contact with her.</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for her. We will take her into custody when we track her down,&quot; Burman said.</p>
<p>One man has already turned himself into a human torch to protest against the pageant in India. That was last week in a town in Tamil Nadu state, 270 miles (430 km) from Bangalore.</p>
<p>The protesters say the beauty contest demeans women and threatens Indian culture.</p>
<p>Police were also on guard for a hitherto unknown group calling itself the Indian Tigers, which has claimed responsibility for attacks on the Indian organisers of Miss World and two small bomb blasts in which no one was injured.</p>
<p>Among those detained earlier on Saturday were members of a front organisation for the People's War Group, a Naxalite Maoist rebel movement which has killed several policemen in neighbouring Andhra Pradesh state, Burman said.</p>
<p>Shashikala has said her followers will mingle with the 20,000 spectators expected in Chinnaswamy cricket stadium and set fire to themselves after first taking poison.</p>
<p>Large numbers of police armed with guns and tear gas swarmed around the stadium and mobile patrols scoured the city.</p>
<p>Pramila Nesargi, a state legislator, said she planned a &quot;Miss Poverty, Miss Illiteracy&quot; pageant outside the stadium.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-23"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGALORE, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
