<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212653" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: RUGBY UNION-SARFU SAYS PIENAAR MAY FACE DISREPUTE CHARGE.</title>
<headline>RUGBY UNION-SARFU SAYS PIENAAR MAY FACE DISREPUTE CHARGE.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dropped South African rugby skipper Francois Pienaar could face a disrepute charge after he was alleged to have been involved in drunken bout of vandalism at a resort casino.</p>
<p>South African Rugby Football Union chief executive Rian Oberholzer told Reuters on Sunday they would look into the allegations in the South African Sunday Times.</p>
<p>&quot;If it can be proved it would be tantamount to bringing the game into disrepute,&quot; said Oberholzer.</p>
<p>&quot;On that basis Francois Pienaar's World Cup contract could be under threat. But until we can talk to them we cannot verify the allegations.&quot;</p>
<p>Pienaar is understood to be on holdiay in Zimbabwe after being controversially dropped from the Springboks side currently on tour in France.</p>
<p>The newspaper claimed Pienaar and his Transvaal coach Ray Mordt and Springbok and provincial team mate Johan Roux smashed bottles and glasses on the golf course, shattered plates in the restaurant at the Wild Coast Sun and played rugby on the putting greens.</p>
<p>Some members of the party are also alleged to have played golf in their underpants and uprooted banana trees. </p>
<p>Alberto Chiaranda, the Wild Coast's managing director, was quoted as saying: &quot;They must have had a little too much to drink and started horsing around.&quot;</p>
<p>Roux said the trio were at the resort with five Gauteng stockbrokers. He said they had &quot;done nothing bad&quot; although he had apologised for the inconvenience, adding: &quot;I did not have any control over the stockbrokers.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
