<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21264" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: London Club team in Belgrade next month - official.</title>
<headline>London Club team in Belgrade next month - official.</headline>
<byline>Gordana Kukic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yugoslavia expects a delegation of commercial bank creditors to visit Belgrade for debt talks in September, a senior government official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have a meeting with our London Club creditors here in the first half of next month,&quot; said Vuk Ognjanovic, chief Yugoslav negotiator.</p>
<p>&quot;The two delegations will discuss certain elements relevant for the resumption of official talks to be held in mid-October,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In July, Yugoslavia ended a second round of talks with its bank creditors in an attempt to settle the country's $2 billion share of commercial debt left over from former Yugoslavia after its violent break-up five years ago.</p>
<p>Analysts say settling Belgrade's debt is complicated by two law suits and lingering hostility in the aftermath of the Yugoslav conflict.</p>
<p>Belgrade has sued Slovenia and its creditors in London's High Court. Slovenia arranged a debt agreement which excludes paying back any Yugoslav holders of debt, who are reported to have been active buyers of ex-Yugoslav debt on the secondary market.</p>
<p>Ognjanovic said Yugoslavia would pursue its legal battle against Slovenia's rescheduling agreement with London Club creditors.</p>
<p>&quot;Yugoslavia did not and will not withdraw the law suit against the Slovenian deal,&quot; he said. &quot;We are just protecting our own interests.&quot;</p>
<p>Belgrade alleges the deal contravenes the 1988 New Financing Agreement (NFA) that shared out equal responsibility for assets and liabilities between former Yugoslav republics.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia has also prepared a law suit against Croatia, which negotiated a similar agreement with bank creditors. But Belgrade has yet to file the suit and apparently hopes the threat of legal action will give it leverage in debt negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;The law suit is prepared and is on the table as we want a constructive development of the talks with our creditors,&quot; he said. &quot;And it can be filed any time.&quot;</p>
<p>But Belgrade analysts warned the suits could damage Yugoslavia's position by angering the international financial community, which it needs to help finance the country's economic recovery.</p>
<p>Dividing up the assets of the former Yugoslav federation is seen as a key condition for completing individual republic's efforts to settle their share of outstanding debt estimated at about $4.3 billion.</p>
<p>Slovenia has agreed to shoulder 18 percent of the total debt of ex-Yugoslavia, while Croatia took on 29.5 percent.</p>
<p>Macedonia and Bosnia are still in the process of negotiating similar accords. Macedonia is expected to take on five percent and Bosnia about nine percent of the debt.</p>
<p>Belgrade only began negotiating with bank creditors earlier this year due to U.N. sanctions imposed on Yugoslavia for its role in the Bosnian war. The sanctions were suspended last November.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
