<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212760" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Cricket - West Indies collapse as Warne celebrates.</title>
<headline>Cricket - West Indies collapse as Warne celebrates.</headline>
<dateline>BRISBANE, Australia 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>West Indies lost their last seven batsmen for just 28 runs in a dramatic collapse in the first test against Australia on Sunday as wrist spinner Shane Warne celebrated his return from injury with two wickets.</p>
<p>The tourists wasted a disciplined century by number four Carl Hooper to fall three runs short of their follow-on target on the third day at the Gabba.</p>
<p>Australia captain Mark Taylor, who watched from first slip as the home side's fortunes were transformed in the space of 59 eventful minutes after tea, chose not to make West Indies bat again despite a first innings lead of 202 runs.</p>
<p>At close of play, Australia were eight for no wicket, a lead of 210 runs with two days left to play. Taylor was four not out alongside fellow opener Matthew Elliott on two.</p>
<p>Warne claimed the wickets of tail-enders Ian Bishop and Kenneth Benjamin as West Indies were dismissed for 277 in reply to Australia's first innings 479.</p>
<p>Warne was swamped by his team mates after snaring Bishop leg before wicket, one of the seven wickets to fall in the space of 74 balls.</p>
<p>It was a memorable moment for Warne, who is playing his first test match since undergoing surgery to repair ligament damage in the ring finger of his bowling hand in May.</p>
<p>West Indies appeared to be cruising towards safety when Hooper reached his first century against Australia, but his dismissal for 102 after lunch with the total on 249 sparked the collapse.</p>
<p>&quot;We are still confident that we can save the game because it's a good batting wicket,&quot; said Hooper, who endured a lengthy, agonising wait before third umpire Peter Parker turned down Australia's appeals for a run-out after the Guyanese reached three figures with a risky quick single.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not my best century but in terms of what was needed for the team and the fact that I batted for five hours, it was a very important innings for me,&quot; said Hooper, a natural stroke player who tempered his normal aggressive instincts to score his sixth test century.</p>
<p>Hooper's partnership with Shivnarine Chanderpaul added 172 for the fourth wicket after West Indiies had started the day on 61-2.</p>
<p>Chanderpaul contributed an equally patient 82 before he edged a catch a ball from pace bowler Paul Reiffel to Mark Waugh at second slip.</p>
<p>Reiffel ended the innings by dismissing fast bowler Curtly Ambrose for a duck and finished with four for 58 in 24.1 overs while Warne collected two for 88 in 27 overs.</p>
<p>But it was all-rounder Steve Waugh who grabbed Hooper's crucial wicket, inducing the right-hander to edge a delivery on to his pads.</p>
<p>Ricky Ponting raced in from mid-wicket to take an excellent diving catch low to the ground and change the course of the match.</p>
<p>But it was almost the last contribution from  Steve Waugh, who was forced to hobble from the ground shortly afterwards with a groin injury that threatens to rule him out of the second test, starting in Sydney on Friday.</p>
<p>Ponting, a makeshift medium pacer, was summoned by Taylor to complete Waugh's over and immediately justified his captain's faith by removing number six Jimmy Adams for a duck with his fifth ball.</p>
<p>&quot;Australia have the edge at the moment but there is still two days left and all is not lost,&quot; West Indies manager Clive Lloyd said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WEIND">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRISBANE, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
