<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212784" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire marks 31 years of Mobutu rule.</title>
<headline>Zaire marks 31 years of Mobutu rule.</headline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 1,000 supporters of Zaire's ailing president were trucked into the country's parliament on Sunday to celebrate the 31st anniversary of the coup that brought Mobutu Sese Seko to power in 1965.</p>
<p>&quot;When he comes back from France there will be a crowd so large that people will die in the crush,&quot; one enthusiastic supporter at the ceremony said.</p>
<p>Mobutu, Africa's longest serving head of state, has been absent from Zaire for three months, receiving treatment for cancer in Switzerland and resting in France.</p>
<p>He is convalescing in his luxury villa on the French Riviera where he met last week with the leader of Zaire's radical opposition, Etienne Tshisekedi, his chief political foe.</p>
<p>Banza Mukalayi, second to Mobutu in the Mouvement Populaire de la Revolution party hierarchy, told cheering supporters that their leader would be home to resolve the current crisis in Zaire over a Tutsi rebellion in the country's east.</p>
<p>&quot;He will return within the next few days...in political memory President Mobutu remains the only barrier on the path to disorder and the balkanisation of our country,&quot; Banza said.</p>
<p>Mobutu has often claimed that he alone holds together the vast Central African country that is about the size of Western Europe. The 40 million population comprises more than 250 ethnic groups.</p>
<p>During Mobutu's absence, Rwandan backed rebels have routed the ragged Zairean army and captured a swathe of land in the eastern Kivu region.</p>
<p>More than a million Hutu refugees and local Zaireans were displaced by the fighting.</p>
<p>Mobutu's allies say he will soon return to Zaire to pull the pieces back together.</p>
<p>But after numerous similar announcements concerning the president's return, many Zaireans doubt he is in good enough health to manage more than a token visit.</p>
<p>Radical opponents of Mobutu's government have tried to take advantage of the current chaos to try to topple Prime Minister Kengo wa Dondo.</p>
<p>The Rwandan-backed rebel leader, Laurent Kabila, says he is fighting to bring to an end what he calls 31 years of brutal dictatorship under Mobutu.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
