<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212798" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: War-ravaged Angola begins to feel benefit of peace.</title>
<headline>War-ravaged Angola begins to feel benefit of peace.</headline>
<byline>Lesley Wroughton</byline>
<dateline>LUANDA 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two years after Angola's government and rebels halted hostilities, the oil- and mineral-rich country is starting to feel the benefits of peace.</p>
<p>The country is prospering with business deals. In the last six months the capital Luanda has seen a stream of foreign business and government delegations from Europe and Africa.</p>
<p>International Monetary Fund (IMF) economists are in the country planning a comeback after the fund withdrew last year, saying the government was not serious about economic reform.</p>
<p>IMF chief Michel Camdessus changed his mind last month after a visit to Angola and declared he had enough confidence in the peace process to launch an emergency programme to help the economy onto its feet.</p>
<p>Camdessus said the government appeared to be serious this time about a transition to a market-orientated economy.</p>
<p>Angola's first private investment bank opened last month backed by foreign shareholders from South Africa, Portugal, the United States and Britain.</p>
<p>Bigger investments in industry and agriculture however depend on lasting peace.</p>
<p>The MPLA-led government and rebel UNITA movement were parties to the Lusaka Protocol, signed in neighbouring Zambia, that put an end to one of Africa's bloodiest wars which lasted for nearly two decades.</p>
<p>The implementation of the accord has been the focus of attention for the past 24 months overseen by the United Nations and 6,500 peacekeepers.</p>
<p>Troops from Brazil, India, Namibia, Portugal, India, Jordan, Malaysia and Zimbabwe have helped to secure the countryside to allow for the disarming of UNITA rebels before their integration into a single Angolan Armed Forces (FAA).</p>
<p>The process has been long and tedious but the U.N. announced last week it was satisfied that both sides were cooperating enough to begin a gradual pullout from the end of December.</p>
<p>A joint ceasefire commission, overseeing the implementation of a peace timetable, said both sides had completed military task outlined by the Security Council to disarm UNITA rebels and open roads with the lifting of all control posts.</p>
<p>But some Western diplomats feel the U.N. might be pushing ahead too fast.</p>
<p>&quot;We might have seen the end of the military timetable but the most challenging task lies ahead for a political solution. We have here two very determined players who both want political power,&quot; one Western diplomat told Reuters.</p>
<p>Angolan President Jose Eduardo dos Santos and UNITA leader Jonas Savimbi have agreed to form a unity government, but the process still has to see 70 UNITA legislators return to the capital from UNITA-controlled areas to take their seats and an agreement on the future role of Savimbi.</p>
<p>UNITA generals, who have been in Luanda since September, still await integration into a unified Angolan Armed Forces and the selection of UNITA troops for FAA is far from over.</p>
<p>Angolans want peace, but are sceptical about the new efforts to end the war after the collapse of the Bicesse Accord in 1991 when Savimbi rejected U.N. supervised elections and returned to war.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone believed in peace in 1991 and excited. They made plans for businesses and homes but then everything collapsed and the people suffered even more, &quot; Fernando Alonso, a businessman, told Reuters.</p>
<p>But U.N. mediator, Alioune Blondin Beye, has reassured Angolans the peace process is intact and cautioned them against &quot;enemies of peace&quot; who want to see the process fail, pointing a finger at the media and bandits that roam the western corridor of the country attacking civilians.</p>
<p>At a cost of $899,260 a day, the peacekeeping operation is expensive and the U.N. is determined to stand by a full withdrawal of its mission in February.</p>
<p>Next month two infantry companies from Brazil and Romania and two bridge-building companies from Korea and Ukrania will be the first to leave Angola.</p>
<p>&quot;Depending on the political developments we will have packed and paid the bills by June,&quot; a U.N. official in charge of operations told Reuters.</p>
<p>The pull-out will not be simultaneous. Angola is a large country and the roads in bad condition.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been here three times as long as we should have. The process has been very slow. Our tasks have been completed, mainly to secure areas to allow for UNITA troops to quarter. This has now been done and there is no reason to stay. The demobilisaion of the troops is up the the government,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
