<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212725" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Clarke to speak to parliament on Euro row.</title>
<headline>UK's Clarke to speak to parliament on Euro row.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>British finance minister Kenneth Clarke, seeking to defuse a growing row over Europe in his badly divided Conservative party, on Sunday pledged to make a statement to parliament over monetary union.</p>
<p>The chancellor of the exchequer took the highly unusual step of agreeing to speak to the House of Commons on Monday, just one day before presenting his annual budget.</p>
<p>Clarke, whose crucial budget in the runup to a general election has been overshadowed by the Europe row, said he was stung into action by allegations in the Sunday Times that the government withheld vital documents from parliament on monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the highly misleading and inaccurate article in the Sunday Times today about single currency issues, the Chancellor of the Exchequer will make a statement to the House of Commons tomorrow afternoon,&quot; a Treasury spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;He will take the opportunity to correct that and other misleading reports that have emerged over recent days,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The opposition Labour party, opinion poll favourites to win the election that has to be called by next May, accused the Conservatives of a cover-up. &quot;The government is descending into confusion,&quot; said finance spokesman Gordon Brown.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major, whose six years in power have been dogged by party mutinies over Britain's role in the European Union, already faced renewed party revolt over demands for a parliamentary debate on the thorny issue. The Sunday Times added fuel to the political fire by alleging that crucial documents about the preparations for a single European currency had been kept from members of parliament</p>
<p>The paper said that the four documents, including reports from the British Treasury and the European Monetary Institute, revealed that Brussels would interfere in Britain's economic policy even if it opted out of the Euro single currency.</p>
<p>The reports were said to suggest that the pound sterling will need to shadow the Euro even if it does not enter a new exchange rate mechanism.</p>
<p>Leading Conservatives took to the airwaves on Sunday to calm party nerves with Treasury Minister Philip Oppenheimer insisting the press report was misleading.</p>
<p>&quot;The British government will oppose and veto any proposals that will fine us for not joining or shadowing EMU,&quot; he told BBC Television. &quot;Any decision to go into EMU would have to be debated in parliament again. And the British people would have the final say in a referendum,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Scottish Secretary Michael Forsyth repeated an assurance from Clarke that there would be no binding decisions at two meetings of European ministers next month until MPs were satisfied scrutiny had taken place.</p>
<p>Eurosceptics in the deeply divided Conservative Party argue that Brussels is bent on destroying Britain's national sovereignty in a United States of Europe.</p>
<p>The old wounds showed no signs of healing on Sunday with Euro-rebel Richard Shepherd saying the government was &quot;showing a lack of candour.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
