<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212802" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Police hold Zambian election monitors.</title>
<headline>Police hold Zambian election monitors.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambian police on Sunday took into custody the heads of two election watchdog groups which failed to call the southern African country's November 18 general polls as free and fair.</p>
<p>Ngande Mwanajiti -- head of the Committee for a Clean Campaign (CCC), a Zambian umbrella group of 19 non-governmental and civic groups which monitored the ballot -- was picked up by police from his home on Sunday morning.</p>
<p>Alfred Zulu, head of the donor-funded non-governmental organisation Zambia Independent Monitoring Team, was also taken into custody by police.</p>
<p>Earlier police sealed off the offices of the two groups in the capital Lusaka. The two men were being kept in separate offices at the central police station. Neither was charged.</p>
<p>Mwanajiti told Reuters in a brief interview at the police station that he had no idea why he was being held in custody, apparently pending questioning.</p>
<p>&quot;They say they want to search our offices. I don't know why,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Police refused to talk to reporters about the action against the men, which followed sharp government attacks last week on those monitoring groups which failed to declare the presidential and parliamentary elections free and fair.</p>
<p>The CCC had said while the voting itself had been correct, flawed voter registration and abuses of government resources had favoured President Frederick Chiluba's ruling Movement for a Multi-party Democracy (MMD).</p>
<p>Half of Zambia's 4.6 million eligible voters were excluded from the rolls because of flawed registration.</p>
<p>Chiluba was sworn in for a second term on Thursday after a landslide win warned disgruntled opposition parties that the security forces were on alert for any political unrest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
