<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212824" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish BDK bank to open Ukrainian branch.</title>
<headline>Polish BDK bank to open Ukrainian branch.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-11-23</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish Bank Depozytowo -Kredytowy SA (BDK) expects to receive an operating licence from the National Bank of Ukraine for its fully-owned subsidiary in the Ukraine this year, BDK's deputy president said.</p>
<p>Dariusz Blaszczuk told the Rzeczpospolita daily the state-owned BDK would register the subsidiary -- BDK (Ukraina) Ltd -- most likely in November.</p>
<p>BDK has already received permission to set up a bank from the Ukrainian central bank, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;BDK's daughter company in the Ukraine is likely to be registered in November...it is likely to receive an operational licence before the end of the year,&quot; the paper quoted Blaszczuk as saying.</p>
<p>Blaszczuk declined to say what capital BDK's subsidiary would have or what operataions it would concentrate on.</p>
<p>BDK is one of the nine commercial banks created on the basis of former Polish central bank branches when market reform started in 1989.</p>
<p>Together with Pomorski Bank Kredytowy SA and Powszechny Bank Gospodarczy SA it forms a banking group centred around another state-owned bank Pekao SA which is to undergo consolidation and later privatisation.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-23"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
