<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212955" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Canada seen giving visa-free access to HK people.</title>
<headline>Canada seen giving visa-free access to HK people.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Financial Secretary Donald Tsang said on Sunday he was fairly confident Canada would grant Hong Kong people visa-free access after the British colony reverts to Chinese sovereignty next year.</p>
<p>Tsang was speaking after meeting Canadian prime minister Jean Chretien in Manila, where they are attending the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) conference.</p>
<p>He said he again emphasised the government's wish that the territory's residents, particularly those holding passports to be issued by the future Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (SAR) administration, would be given visa-free access.</p>
<p>&quot;I got a very sympathetic hearing from Prime Minister Chretien,&quot; Tsang said in a comment carried on local radio. &quot;I am pretty confident that some good announcement will be made very shortly on this.&quot;</p>
<p>Tsang quoted Canadian officials as saying the signing last week of a pact between Hong Kong and Canada aimed at combatting illegal immigration was a big step forward, government radio reported.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
