<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212912" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Advances rekindle blood substitute debate.</title>
<headline>Advances rekindle blood substitute debate.</headline>
<byline>Richard Jacobsen</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>Advances in the development of human blood substitutes have rekindled the debate over whether the products are a biotechnology goldmine or scientific and investment folly.</p>
<p>The worldwide market for blood substitutes that can safely replace human blood during surgeries, as well as save oxygen-starved organs following heart attacks and strokes, could reach $5 billion by the end of the next decade, industry proponents say.  </p>
<p>They argue that the substitutes will greatly reduce, if not eliminate, the risk of contamination from viruses such as HIV and hepatitis, do away with the need for blood-type matching, and have a longer shelf life than donated blood.</p>
<p>&quot;These products are likely to end up being the largest-selling products in the pharmaceutical industry by some time in the early part of the next century,&quot; said Jim McCamant, editor of the Medical Technology Stock Letter in Berkeley, Calif.</p>
<p>Interest in developing blood substititues surged in the early 1980s, driven by the advent of AIDS and worries over a contaminated blood supply.  </p>
<p>But skeptics say stringent screening of donated blood has reduced the need for artifical blood. In addition, cost-cutting managed care organizations will be unlikley to pay for a more expensive alternative to donated blood, they argue.</p>
<p>The skeptics see the products limited to emergency situtations such as car accidents or gunshot wounds, or in specialized uses such as anti-cancer radiation treatments, rather than widespread use in non-emergency surgeries.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't really see a major market for just the simple use as a blood substitute,&quot; said UBS Securities biotechnology analyst Paul Kelly.  </p>
<p>Kelly caused an uproar among blood substitute makers and industry bulls a year ago when he initiated coverage of two companies in the field, Somatogen Inc and Northfield Laboratories Inc, with recommendations that investors sell the stocks. He maintains the sell ratings.</p>
<p>But on Wednesday shares in Northfield Labs rose 27 percent when the company said it got U.S. Food and Drug Administration approval for its blood substitute PolyHeme at a 10-unit level, equivalent to replacing the total blood volume of an adult, up from the six-unit level.  </p>
<p>On Thursday, Baxter International Inc emerged as the frontrunner in the race to get a blood substitute to market.</p>
<p>Baxter said the FDA had cleared its blood product HemAssist to enter final-stage Phase III testing in patients suffering from blood loss and shock caused by severe trauma. Analysts said the product could be on the market by 1999.</p>
<p>Some saw the news as an FDA verification of the products' safety.</p>
<p>&quot;At this juncture you can be pretty comfortable in knowing the stuff all these commercial manufacterers are making is safe,&quot; said Richard Stover of Stamford, Conn.-based Stover Associates.  </p>
<p>But the true tests of the blood substitutes effectiveness and their potential side-effects will come during the large Phase III trials, critics argue.</p>
<p>The players in the blood substitute drive have taken various approaches.</p>
<p>Products from Baxter and Northfield, and Hemosol Inc are derived from hemoglobin taken from outdated human donor blood, while others, including Enzon Inc, use cow blood as the source for hemoglobin.  </p>
<p>Somatogen's product is genetically engineered, which eliminates its dependence on human blood stocks, potentially allowing it to produce greater quantities.</p>
<p>Punk, Ziegel &amp; Knoell analyst Shekhar Basu said he thinks BioTime Inc's plasma volume expander Hextend could do the job of blood substitutes but at a fraction of the costs. He said the product, which this month entered Phase III trials, could be approved by the end of 1997.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, major players have already lined up in the blood substitutes race. Eli Lilly and Co has partnered with Somatogen. Johnson and Johnson has a deal with Alliance Pharmaceutical Corp and its product Oxygent.</p>
<p>But some have had second thoughts. In July Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn pulled out of a blood-substitute research deal with Biopure Corp, taking a $69 million charge to write off the investment.</p>
<p>Stover said Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn decision's could prove to be a &quot;major strategic mistake.&quot;</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk, 212-859-1733</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25670">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
