<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="212997" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC breakthrough expected in Sino-U.S. ties.</title>
<headline>APEC breakthrough expected in Sino-U.S. ties.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>A breakthrough in Sino-U.S. ties was expected on Sunday when U.S. President Bill Clinton met Chinese President Jiang Zemin on the eve of the Asia-Pacific trade summit.</p>
<p>Clinton and Jiang were due to discuss a series of high-level exchanges culminating in visits to each other's country when they met on the fringes of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) forum in Manila, U.S. officials said.</p>
<p>Detente between the Pacific giants, whose relations hit rock-bottom after the Tiananmen Square killings in 1989 and have never recovered, would boost regional security and APEC's efforts to create a borderless economy on the Pacific Rim by 2020.</p>
<p>A security scare involving Clinton's motorcade after he arrived in Manila on Saturday night highlighted the threat to the summit in Subic Bay from leftist groups, who organised protests involving thousands in the Philippine capital on Sunday.</p>
<p>Clinton's motorcade made a last-minute switch of routes from the airport after two men were reported lurking suspiciously at a traffic light.</p>
<p>U.S. officials have warned that American nationals at the APEC meeting may be targets for terrorist attack.</p>
<p>Protesters packed into Manila's trademark gleaming jeepneys -- minibuses modelled on U.S. World War Two jeeps -- denounced the APEC summit as a ploy by rich nations to prise open Third World markets, set up sweatshops and rape the environment.</p>
<p>Trailing colourful streamers, the vehicles headed for Subic, 80 km (50 miles) north of the capital, but were slowed by police roadblocks.</p>
<p>Leaders from 18 APEC economies embracing nations from Papua New Guinea to Chile and Canada are meeting to put flesh on plans to dismantle trade barriers in developing member nations by 2010 and in developed countries by 2020.</p>
<p>The goal is a free trade and investment zone in a booming region that accounts for 40 percent of global trade and more than half of the world's economic output.</p>
<p>Clinton, relaxed after a five-day working holiday in Australia, pledged continued U.S. commitment to the region.</p>
<p>&quot;America's involvement and influence here helps to provide the stability, to promote the economic progress, to encourage the cooperation on many fronts,&quot; he said in his regular Saturday radio address to the American people.</p>
<p>&quot;With partners and friends like the nations I'm visiting, we're going to enter the 21st century stronger than ever,&quot; he said. Clinton will visit Thailand before heading home.</p>
<p>Aside from the summit at Subic -- a former major U.S. naval base and symbol of America's Pacific power -- Clinton will tackle thorny political and economic issues in bilateral meetings with Jiang and leaders of Japan and South Korea.</p>
<p>A session with South Korean President Kim Young-sam will discuss peace and security on the Korean peninsula following the incursion of a North Korean submarine to the South in September.</p>
<p>The provocation has frozen plans to defuse North Korea's nuclear threat by supplying it with nuclear reactors and threatened a proposal by Clinton and Kim for four-party talks, including China, on a Korean peace deal.</p>
<p>Clinton would be the first U.S. leader to visit China since George Bush in early 1989.</p>
<p>Since then relations have been dogged by disputes over human rights, arms proliferation, Taiwan and trade.</p>
<p>Relations reached a critical point in March when China conducted missile tests during Taiwan's elections and the United States dispatched two aircraft carrier battle groups to the area in response.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher paved the way for Clinton's meeting with Jiang during a visit to Beijing last week by soft-pedalling on human rights and telling Chinese leaders Washington does not want to contain China.</p>
<p>Beijing accuses Washington of trying to block its rise as the superpower of the 21st century.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
