<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213088" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: White House says Greece visit report incorrect.</title>
<headline>White House says Greece visit report incorrect.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>The White House said on Sunday a newspaper report from Athens that President Bill Clinton would visit Greece and Turkey next year was incorrect.</p>
<p>&quot;The story is incorrect. The White House has no plans and has made no announcements concerning any possible visits to Greece or Turkey,&quot; a White House spokesman said.</p>
<p>The daily Kathimerini, quoting White House sources, said Clinton planned to visit Athens and Ankara next June to promote closer relations between Greece and Turkey.</p>
<p>The two countries, despite being NATO allies, almost went to war in January over disputed, uninhabited islets in the Aegean Sea. The United States stepped in to broker a deal which eased the tension but Greek-Turkish relations remain on a tightrope.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Clinton wants to show his personal interest in the eastern Mediterranean and Greek-Turkish relations,&quot; the paper's Washington correspondent Alexis Papahelas said, quoting a White House official.</p>
<p>Greek government officials could not be reached to comment on the report but government spokesman Dimitris Reppas has said Athens awaits a new U.S. initiative.</p>
<p>Athens and Ankara are at odds over territorial rights in the Aegean Sea, dotted with thousands of islands, and over the divided island of Cyprus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
