<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213109" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU ministers hold firm on strong lira.</title>
<headline>EU ministers hold firm on strong lira.</headline>
<byline>Amelia Torres</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union finance ministers and central bank governors held firm against Italy on Sunday, making clear they would not allow Rome to return to the EU's exchange rate mechanism (ERM) with a weak lira.</p>
<p>Officials said Italy had trimmed earlier demands that it re-enter the currency grid at a central rate of 1,010 lira to the German mark.</p>
<p>It was now willing to come in at 1,000 lira to the mark, they said, but the others had not accepted the deal and wanted a far stronger rate for the currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Other countries are seeking 950 to 980,&quot; a Spanish official said.</p>
<p>Sources said Germany, which is adamant that only strong economies should be given a chance to qualify for the EU's planned single currency, was particularly angry with Italy for seeking to re-enter the ERM at a weak rate.</p>
<p>&quot;The Germans are not happy,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>One diplomat said Bundesbank president Hans Tietmeyer wanted a rate of 970 lira to the mark.</p>
<p>Joining the ERM is one step towards qualifying for the single currency.</p>
<p>Europe's top financial policy-makers had to be called in after the EU's monetary committee of central bank and finance ministry officials failed on Saturday to agree a central rate for the lira's return.</p>
<p>Luxembourg Finance Minister Jean-Claude Juncker, who is also the country's prime minister, said he was not surprised that the lower-level body had failed to agree because the issue had far-reaching political consequences.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a political debate,&quot; he told reporters as he entered the meeting. &quot;I don't think the monetary committee was the appropriate body for formulating an answer to a problem which is eminently political.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is whether or not we want to put Italy into a position where it fulfils one of the Maastricht criteria,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Re-joining the ERM, from which the lira was unceremoniously dumped amid a currency crisis in 1992, is seen as crucial for Italy's hopes for being in the first wave of EU countries to adopt the single currency in 1999.</p>
<p>A stable two-year stint within the ERM -- designed to provide exchange rate stability -- is one of the qualifying criteria for the new currency, the Euro.</p>
<p>Officials said other European countries were worried that if they allowed the lira to come in at too weak a level this would give Italy preferential trade terms.</p>
<p>France had been the most vehement in wanting a stronger rate for the lira, having already seen some of its trade battered by a neighbour with a weaker currency.</p>
<p>But if Italy failed to win a seat within the ERM this could put pressure on the lira and send a strong negative signal over the prospect of a joint European currency.</p>
<p>Economists in Italy said the key figure is 1,000 lira, Below that, some industrialists say, Italian business could suffer.</p>
<p>Italy, like other EU countries which want to join the monetary union from the start, has rushed to meet targets on interest and exchange rates, inflation, the budget deficit and public debt.</p>
<p>Seeking to trim their deficits next year to no more than three percent of gross domestic product, however, some states have unveiled controversial one-off budgetary measures.</p>
<p>Italy has proposed a so-called Euro-tax, a one-off revenue raiser ro help it meet the targets.</p>
<p>If Italy is brought into the ERM, only three of the EU's 15 countries will be outside the grid.</p>
<p>Britain and Sweden argue that it is not necessary to be in the grid to qualify for the Euro saying it is enough to have a stable rate with the other countries.</p>
<p>Greece's economy is far weaker that the others and membership of the single currency is far off.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
