<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213144" id="root" date="1996-11-24" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Rhone-Poulenc has 28 pct of CFPI, may seek control.</title>
<headline>Rhone-Poulenc has 28 pct of CFPI, may seek control.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-24</dateline>
<text>
<p>French pharmaceuticals and chemicals group Rhone-Poulenc said on Sunday it had raised its stake in chemicals firm Compagnie Francaise de Produits Industriels (CFPI) to 28.4 percent and may go further.</p>
<p>In a statement, Rhone-Poulenc said it bought 10.1 percent of CFPI's shares from French banking group Paribas.</p>
<p>&quot;The Rhone-Poulenc group is acting independently and reserves every possibility to increase its stake in CFPI and does not totally exclude taking control,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>Rhone-Poulenc said it was primarily interested in CFPI because of its agrochemical activities.</p>
<p>Its stake-building was part of a strategy to strengthen its position on world markets for herbicides and growth regulators.</p>
<p>It was also pursuing its aim of collaborating with CFPI in the production and distribution of the Oxynils herbicides and the plant growth regulator called Ethephon.</p>
<p>Rhone-Poulenc did not give a price for the share purchase.</p>
<p>On October 25, New Zealand firm Fernz Corp said it had bought 11.25 percent of CFPI for NZ$9.5 million.  </p>
<p>It said CFPI had net assets of around 350 million francs and sales of 1.4 billion francs.</p>
<p>Rhone-Poulenc and Paribas both declined comment on Friday on French market speculation that Rhone-Poulenc had built its stake in CFPI from 16.19 percent by buying 10 percent from Paribas.</p>
<p>CFPI stock strongly outpaced a firmer Paris share market on Friday to close up 8.2 percent at 303.0 francs per share.</p>
<p>Rhone-Poulenc shares gained 0.19 percent to 160.7 francs, while the CAC-40 index of leading shares rose nearly one percent to finish at a year-high of 2,255.47 points.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25130">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-24"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-24"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
