<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213346" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bank preferreds tighten, seize US corp debt trade.</title>
<headline>Bank preferreds tighten, seize US corp debt trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Frenzied trade surrounding new banking preferred issuance gripped the U.S. corporate bond market and those spreads tightened dramatically, dealers said.</p>
<p>Issuance of the new type of tax-advantaged preferred security was said to near $1.0 billion on Monday, topped by a $600 million 30-year deal from Chase Manhattan Bank priced at 120 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>The Chase deal, non-callable for 10-years, was priced more than 30 basis points tighter than comparable credit Bank of America's preferred issue last week, a preferreds trader said.</p>
<p>The deals were sold in the 144a private placement market.  </p>
<p>Issuance of the &quot;new&quot; preferred securities should continue to flood the market, adding to to the approximately $5.0 billion that has racked up since last week alone. The debt is issued as first-tier capital, traders said, giving the issuing institutions a fantastic degree of savings.</p>
<p>&quot;You can swap out of publicly traded corporate debt and go into these bonds you can save a ton,&quot; one trader said, adding that &quot;until there's a change in tax laws there's a lot of pent up demand for long quality bonds with good call protection and that's what this product is right now.&quot;  </p>
<p>Other privately placed preferreds tigthened 20 to 25 basis points from original dates of issuance last week, several traders confirmed. Even so, Street opinions said buyers are still getting bargains.</p>
<p>&quot;A Chase Manhattan long bond is not going to trade at 120 over in the public markets,&quot; one trader said. &quot;It would be more like 80 to 90 over, so there's still incremental spread pickup for the 144a -- you're still getting compensated very well.&quot;</p>
<p>By contrast, waning demand for banking and finance corporate debt issues pressured some spreads to widen.  </p>
<p>The preferred securities will begin coming from electric utilities after Thanksgiving, said one trader, as part of an expected $10 billion over the next several months. Chase, Wells Fargo, Citicorp and Bank of America alone have about $8 billion traditional preferreds due by the end of 1998 that could be tendered or called for a refinancing as less-costly tier 1 capital, one source said.</p>
<p>The issuance may come to a sliding halt in the first quarter of next year, however, should Congress change the tax-code as many on the Street expect.  </p>
<p>Separately, an expected recommendation by the National Association of Insurance Commisioners (NAIC) that would require insurance companies to treat the &quot;new&quot; preferreds as debt for risk-based capital purposes is likely to enhance demand for the paper, analysts said.</p>
<p>The NAIC will meet on Tuesday to consider the issue.</p>
<p>Turning to high-yielders, commerce thinned as the day wore on but at least one new issuer tapped the market. Secondary prices were static with the exception of fresh issuance, which popped higher on the break as it often did last week.  </p>
<p>In the day's largest offering, Allied Waste of North America issued $525 million 10.25 percent B3/B-plus 10-year senior subordinated debt at par for a yield spread of about 410 basis points over the Treasury curve.</p>
<p>The debt was quoted at 102 near the close for a yield spread close to 380 over, a trader said.</p>
<p>The rule 144a private placement deal was increased in size by $50 million and was managed via a Goldman Sachs &amp; Co Inc led syndicate. In the Treasury market, the 30-year long bond closed up 6/32 at 100-31/32 to yield 6.43 percent.</p>
<p>--Al Yoon, 212-859-1672</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
