<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213318" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US TV, computer industries reach digital TV accord.</title>
<headline>US TV, computer industries reach digital TV accord.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following weeks of talks, representatives from the television and computer industries reached an agreement in principle Monday on a broadcast standard for a new generation of high-definition digital television.</p>
<p>The accord is aimed at allowing the Federal Communications Commission to finalize a government-prescribed standard for advanced digital TV, which offers cinema-quality pictures and CD-quality sound.  </p>
<p>The agreement between the computer, broadcast and consumer electronics industries calls on the FCC to issue a broadcast transmission standard.</p>
<p>But it would not mandate key aspects, such as the shape of the TV screen and the technology for putting images on to the screen. Those features would be left to the markets to decide.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident that, based on today's announcement, the FCC can act before the end of 1996,&quot; said FCC Commissioner Susan Ness.  </p>
<p>&quot;If the FCC acts this year, it could make high-definition TV a reality for consumers in 1998,&quot; said Gary Shapiro, president of the Consumer Electronics Manufacturers Association, a trade group representing TV makers.</p>
<p>Computer companies, led by Microsoft Corp Chairman Bill Gates, had objected to the broadcast standard the FCC initially proposed in May, saying it would work poorly with computers and stifle the the convergence of TV and computer technologies.</p>
<p>The long-promised convergence would allow consumers to watch TV and surf the Internet via the same &quot;smart box.&quot;  </p>
<p>The latest round of talks, which were held in Washington, also resolved objections raised by Hollywood directors, actors and cinematographers who complained that the proposed screen size would distort images in wide-screen films.</p>
<p>The FCC proposal stalled after the Clinton administration made an election-year reversal in August and warned the plan could be &quot;overly prescriptive&quot; and could &quot;stymie&quot; development of new products and services.</p>
<p>It initially backed the plan, but reversed itself after the objections from the computer industry and Hollywood.  </p>
<p>The talks involved representatives of TV broadcasters, the big networks, TV manufacturers Philips Electronics N.A. Corp. and Thomson Consumer Electronics, plus Microsoft, Intel Corp., Compaq Computer Corp, and Apple Computer Inc.</p>
<p>The FCC proposal stemmed from a recommendation by an advisory panel that included representatives from the entertainment, broadcast, electronic and computer industries. The plan took more than eight years to develop.</p>
<p>The negotiations were initiated after a request last month from Commissioner Ness. She set a Nov. 25 deadline for the negotiators to reach agreement, although the date was not legally binding.</p>
<p>&quot;Our goal has been to trust the market, not government, to define the digital television of the future. Today's agreement is wholly welcome,&quot; FCC Chairman Reed Hundt said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
