<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213436" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends lower on speculative selling.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends lower on speculative selling.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures slumped to three-week lows Monday, as an afternoon round of speculative selling pushed prices through key technical support, traders said.</p>
<p>The break through 108.50 cents a lb support basis the most-active March contract triggered sell-stops, traders said, dragging March to a low of 106.40 cents.</p>
<p>March settled 1.90 cents a lb lower, at 107.60, after rallying to a high of 111.20 earlier in the session. Spot December futures finished 0.50 cent lower at 117.75, while the remaining months closed down 1.85 to 3.75.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is lacking news, but I think it is having trouble now on the upside because of the expectation of more coffee coming in,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Although the flow of coffee from key producing countries is picking up, the analyst said low levels of consumer stocks going into the peak consumption period should continue to provide underlying support.</p>
<p>The analyst also said the latest CFTC Commitment of Traders report released Friday, which showed an increase in non-commercial long positions, could have pressured the market.</p>
<p>Traders await the latest weekly exchange-certified coffee stocks report due after Monday's close.</p>
<p>The CSCE reported last week that U.S. certified coffee stocks fell to just 321 60-kg bags in the latest weekly reporing period, the lowest level since the CSCE began tracking stocks in 1980. There were 1,250 bags pending grading, they said.</p>
<p>Traders are also looking for a private 1997/98 Brazilian coffee estimate by former USDA crop forecaster Leon Yallouz expected sometime this week.</p>
<p>Volume was moderate, at an estimated 7,827 lots.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
