<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213558" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL - SONICS BEAT KNICKS FOR 11TH STRAIGHT WIN.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL - SONICS BEAT KNICKS FOR 11TH STRAIGHT WIN.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Seattle SuperSonics, last year's Western Conference winners, are on a roll again.</p>
<p>Shawn Kemp scored 22 points and the SuperSonics shut down the New York Knicks for much of the second half Sunday in a 102-92 victory, their 11th straight.</p>
<p>Detlef Schrempf scored 17 points, Gary Payton added 16 and Hersey Hawkins had nine of his 15 in the pivotal third quarter for the SuperSonics, who have won eight straight road games.</p>
<p>&quot;We're on a good roll right now,&quot; said Seattle's Sam Perkins, who had 15 points. &quot;We're playing good defence and that doesn't matter where you play.&quot;</p>
<p>Seattle has the longest current winning streak in the NBA. It needs three more wins to match last season's team-record 14-game winning streak.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they are truly a good team,&quot; Knicks coach Jeff Van Gundy said. &quot;They believe in themselves. We haven't earned that belief. It's just like confidence. You aren't given that. You earn it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they're any better a team than we are,&quot; said centre Patrick Ewing, whose team has lost three in a row and dropped to 3-3 at home. &quot;We just fell apart.&quot;</p>
<p>Guards Chris Childs, Allan Houston and John Starks scored 13 points apiece for the Knicks. Ewing was held to a season-low eight points on 2-of-15 shooting.</p>
<p>Ewing was defended most of the night by centre Jim McIlvaine, who had four points, four rebounds and four blocks.</p>
<p>&quot;McIlvaine did a good job for us,&quot; Seattle coach George Karl said. &quot;That was his best game out there for us tonight.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;McIlvaine had nothing to do with it,&quot; Ewing said. &quot;It isn't just one guy. Sometimes, you just have nights like that.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We played good defence in the second half,&quot; Schrempf said. &quot;That was the difference in the game.&quot;</p>
<p>At Los Angeles, Charles Barkley had 23 points and 15 rebounds and sank a key three-pointer with 53 seconds left as the Houston Rockets avenged their only loss of the season with a 90-85 victory over the Lakers, their sixth straight win.</p>
<p>Clyde Drexler scored 10 of his 17 points in the fourth quarter and Kevin Willis added 17 for the Rockets, who overcame the absence of Hakeem Olajuwon and improved to a league-best 6-0 on the road. Olajuwon is sidelined with an irregular heartbeat.</p>
<p>Drexler became the 24th player in NBA history to score 20,000 points. He is the second player this season to surpass the milestone, joining Ewing.</p>
<p>Shaquille O'Neal had 23 points and 12 rebounds and Nick Van Exel added 21 points and 12 assists for the Lakers, who won at Houston in double overtime 12 days earlier. O'Neal was 3-of-11 from the line, including two critical misses with 25 seconds to go.</p>
<p>In Phoenix, the Suns remained winless, losing their 12th straight as former Sun Dan Majerle made a clutch three-pointer with seven seconds to go in an 87-84 Miami Heat victory.</p>
<p>The slide matches the worst in franchise history for the Suns, despite the return of point guard Kevin Johnson. Johnson had 15 points and nine assists in his first game of the season after surgery to remove an abdominal hernia.</p>
<p>The Suns also lost 12 straight in 1977. Phoenix is five losses away from Miami's NBA record of 17 losses to start a season, set in the Heat's inaugural 1988-89 campaign.</p>
<p>In Boston, Dana Barros scored 21 points and Dino Radja added 19 and 11 rebounds as the Celtics cruised past the Dallas Mavericks 105-91, ending a four-game losing streak.</p>
<p>The Celtics, who never trailed, have won 15 of 16 all-time home games against Dallas.</p>
<p>Chris Gatling had 23 points and 11 rebounds and Jim Jackson added 23 and seven for the Mavericks, who have lost five of their last six.</p>
<p>At Cleveland, Tyrone Hill scored seven of his 17 points in an 18-5 run that opened the second half and gave the Cavaliers their third straight win, 103-74 over the Sacramento Kings.</p>
<p>Terrell Brandon scored 21 points for Cleveland, which has led the league in defence the last two seasons and has permitted less than 80 points in half of its 12 games.</p>
<p>Mitch Richmond scored 23 points for the Kings.</p>
<p>In Vancouver, Shareef Abdur-Rahim had 18 points, nine rebounds and nine assists and made two key free throws as the Grizzlies defeated the San Antonio Spurs 96-91 in a matchup of the worst teams in the Midwest Division.</p>
<p>Vancouver snapped a four-game losing streak.</p>
<p>Dominique Wilkins scored 26 points for the injury-crippled Spurs, who lost their fifth straight. San Antonio had won its four previous meetings with Vancouver.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
