<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213535" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: CRICKET-BACHER SEEKS REPORT ON TEST LOSS TO INDIA.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-BACHER SEEKS REPORT ON TEST LOSS TO INDIA.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's cricket supremo Ali Bacher is asking the International Cricket Council for the referee's match report on the first test against India.</p>
<p>The request follows an angry comment from coach Bob Woolmer that they had been &quot;stuffed&quot; before the test because of wickets and practice facilities of a type they did not want.</p>
<p>Bacher, managing director of the United Cricket Board of South Africa, said on Monday: &quot;There were several aspects of the game which were unsatisfactory, but we will wait for John Reid's report before discussing any action.&quot;</p>
<p>The match ended in Ahmedabad on Saturday in 64-run win for India after South Africa were skittled out for 105 on a wearing wicket.</p>
<p>Woolmer  said on Sunday that he was unhappy with the pitch and the practice facilities for his team.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't mind losing, but I don't like losing having been stuffed for three weeks beforehand on wickets and practice facilities which are not conducive to what we want,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Woolmer had complained before the test that although they had won both their warm-up games with ease, the opposition was so weak his batsmen had had no chance to play an innings.</p>
<p>Bacher said on Monday: &quot;Facilities are a worldwide problem which require finance together with motivation from the ICC. Countries must be told that they have a responsibility to provide the best possible practice facilities.</p>
<p>&quot;We requested a certain standard of facilities before the tour and it looks like these have not been forthcoming. But the match referee's report is a lot more wide-ranging now and will include comments on practice facilities.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
