<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213622" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Paper says UK budget documents leaked.</title>
<headline>Paper says UK budget documents leaked.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secret documents revealing tax changes in Tuesday's British budget were passed to the Daily Mirror, the tabloid newspaper said on Monday night.</p>
<p>But the paper said in a statement it realised that premature disclosure of the 36 documents could cause chaos on international stock markets and decided to return them to the government.</p>
<p>Details of the annual budget are one of the most closely guarded secrets in Britain. But a Treasury spokesman said news of the leaks would not force any changes in Finance Minister Kenneth Clarke's budget.</p>
<p>The Daily Mirror, which supports the opposition Labour Party, said the documents had been handed back to Clarke's office.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we wouldn't normally hesitate to embarrass the government with such an amazing scoop, on this occasion we had a public duty to return such sensitive economic documents,&quot; said the paper's editor Piers Morgan.</p>
<p>&quot;Publication of so much detail from the budget before the chancellor's speech could have forced the stock market to close and cause chaos in the international money markets,&quot; he said in the statement.</p>
<p>The paper said Prime Minister John Major's office had confirmed that the documents, which totalled about 100 pages, were genuine. Morgan said he rang Major's office to say the paper had the documents.</p>
<p>Thirty-three of the documents were said to be from the Inland Revenue tax authorities, two from customs and excise and one from the office dealing with Scottish affairs.</p>
<p>Morgan would not say where the documents had come from.</p>
<p>He told BBC Television: &quot;These were in the main press releases which would be issued at the end of the speech on every individual point.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it would be fairly obvious why they chose the Mirror. If you were going to embarrass the government we are a perfect receptacle. And if anybody else out there has sensitive government documents we are in the market.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1947, finance minister Hugh Dalton resigned after leaking parts of his budget to a reporter.</p>
<p>News of tax increases on beer and greyhound racing was printed in newspapers before Dalton told parliament. He resigned the next day. Prime Minister Clement Attlee called him &quot;a perfect ass&quot;.</p>
<p>The budget is considered crucial to the outcome of Britain's general election which must be called by next May.</p>
<p>Clarke, fresh from rescuing the government in a spat with parliamentary supporters over plans for a single EU currency, must score another triumph if Major's Conservative Party is to retain hopes of an election victory.</p>
<p>The Labour Party is currently 20 points ahead of the Conservatives in opinion polls.</p>
<p>The budget Clarke will announce to parliament at 1530 GMT must avoid alarming stockbrokers and foreign exchange dealers. But Conservative members of parliament are desperate for tax cuts which could win voters back to them and save their seats in an election which must be held by May 22.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
