<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213674" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N. Sea crudes hold steady, ignore futures dip.</title>
<headline>N. Sea crudes hold steady, ignore futures dip.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea crude markets were holding steady on Monday afternoon, ignoring Iraqi crude sale-led volatility in IPE Brent futures amid good interest for December cargoes, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was picked clean last week but there still some good buying interest,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;There's good interest for Dec cargoes, I think people are looking to square up early for the Christmas holiday season,&quot; another added.</p>
<p>Dated Brent held steady around Dec Brent -35 cents with the Jan/Feb spread trading firmer at +58 cents.</p>
<p>The Dec/Jan intermonth spread held notionally steady around +70/72 cents.</p>
<p>Three Brent cargoes were nominated from the paper chains on Monday, including one cargo deferred from Friday.</p>
<p>A Gullfaks C loading Dec 12-14 traded on Monday at a stronger Dated Brent +34 cents and a Dec 13 loading Forties cargoe moved at a firm Dated Brent -27 cents to a French refiner.</p>
<p>Balance of first decade December Ekofisk cargoes are now thought cleared with the last cargo sold by a French major at dated Brent +9 cents for Dec 6 loading.</p>
<p>A second decade cargo was heared traded at Dated Brent +23 cents.</p>
<p>Mediterranean refiners were slow to come out to buy crude on Monday following the strong differentials seen traded on Urals on Friday.</p>
<p>Some refiners argued that with only traders buying Urals the levels were too high and would not give &quot;any margin&quot; in their refineries.</p>
<p>&quot;Brent would be better for us than Urals. Brent gives 65 cents more than Urals. Sweet is definitely better than sour and refiners that I have spoken to seem relaxed,&quot; one refiner said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
