<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213752" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian bourse's clearing system ready next year.</title>
<headline>Nigerian bourse's clearing system ready next year.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>All is set for the launch of the Nigerian Stock Exchange's computerised clearing system early next year, an official of the exchange said on Monday.</p>
<p>A team of Canadian experts is in Nigeria installing the system, which is expected to cut costs and transaction time.</p>
<p>&quot;They arrived on Friday, started work on Saturday and have met with officials of brokers' banks,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>The loading of software and other applications had been finished and the experts will now train the users, including officials of the Central Securities and Clearing System (CSCS), the company set up to administer the system.</p>
<p>&quot;They will be meeting with stockbrokers and registrars too,&quot; the official added. They will then conduct a series of test runs before leaving Nigeria.</p>
<p>&quot;Depending on performance during the test runs, the project should be ready for launch in the next quarter,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The project suffered early setbacks when the industry ministry was reluctant to give permission for the exchange to receive a United Nations Development Programme grant to pay for it.</p>
<p>Chilly diplomatic relations between Nigeria and Canada over alleged human rights abuses and lack of democracy in Nigeria also caused problems. Visas for the Canadians took a long time to issue after the closure of the Nigerian High commission in Ottawa in September.</p>
<p>The Nigerian clearing and depository system is modelled after that of the Alberta stock exchange in Canada. The first phase is scheduled to take off next year. The system will be used for clearing, settlement and depository functions.</p>
<p>The system will manage electronic trading under a second phase.</p>
<p>-- Lagos newsroom +234 1 263 03 17</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
