<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213962" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo firms optimistic on econ climate - poll.</title>
<headline>Yugo firms optimistic on econ climate - poll.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Optimism among Yugoslav firms remained high in October despite an unfavourable business climate, the Belgrade Economic Institute said on Monday in its Market Barometer report.</p>
<p>&quot;There were no improvements in the business climate since September,&quot; Miroljub Labus of the institute told Reuters. &quot;But optimism in October about prospects for industrial recovery and overall economic revival was still quite high.&quot;</p>
<p>Of 300 Yugoslav firms polled covering 55 percent of industry, 40 percent expected the business climate to improve over coming months. Only 8.6 percent expected it to worsen.</p>
<p>Despite the optimism and a relativly positive October economic performance -- low inflation and high industrial output -- 27.9 percent firms saw the existing ecnomic climate as unfavourable and only 17.5 percent said it was good.</p>
<p>&quot;This means that business risk is still very high here,&quot; Goran Pitic, an analyst with the institute said.</p>
<p>Business activity in October registered slight decline compared to the previous month with 29.1 percent of firms increasing activity and 5.4 percent firms saying activity fell.</p>
<p>In September business activity was up 9.6 percent over August and 11.3 percent up against the same month in 1995.</p>
<p>Pitic said that high inflationary expectations and lack of working capital and credits remained the main problems for boosting industrial production.</p>
<p>Some 65.1 percent expected input prices to grow and 28.4 percent said they would increase their prices in coming period.</p>
<p>Inflation, on a downward trend since July when it surged to 6.6 percent, stood at 1.4 percent in October after its drop to 2.3 percent in August and to 1.2 percent in September.</p>
<p>For 35.6 percent of firms, lack of credits remained the main obstacle for increasing business with 26.7 percent blaming a lack of imported raw materials and 19.7 percent citing poor demand as the main reason for their low activity.</p>
<p>Regarding the lack of working capital, 25.8 percent were optimistic in expecting investments from local sources and only 10.1 percent believed in foreign capital inflow.</p>
<p>In October use of capacities rose to 60 percent, while employment in real terms continued its downward trend which began in September after relative stability in summer months.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect unemployment to grow even further,&quot; Zoran Popov of the institute said.</p>
<p>Industry output growth of 15.4 percent in October increased stocks, but 57.8 percent of those polled said they consider their stocks of raw and semi-finished goods still to be low and 43.8 percent said their finished products stocks were not enough.</p>
<p>Sales on domestic market remained low, as in September, mostly because of low demand and low purchasing power, Pitic said. But optimism among firms remained as 50.2 percent believed sales would pick up in next three months.</p>
<p>&quot;But prospects on markets abroad are still very gloomy,&quot; Pitic said adding that 46.7 percent planned no exports in the next three months.</p>
<p>&quot;This is worrying consdering high trade deficit which in the first ten months topped $1.7 billion,&quot; he added. -- Gordana Kukic, Belgrade Newsroom ++381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
