<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="213990" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: FEATURE - Russians gearing up for better cars.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Russians gearing up for better cars.</headline>
<byline>Peter Henderson</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian consumers, emerging from recession and decades of shoddy Soviet products, are itching to get their hands on better cars.</p>
<p>Enthusiastic analysts and car makers see millions of new vehicles taking to the roads annually after the turn of the century, but cannot tell when the spending spree will start.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is bottoming out,&quot; said Greg DeYonker, executive vice-president of GM Overseas Corp and GM's executive in charge of the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>DeYonker, like many analysts, sees anywhere from one to two million new car sales a year in Russia by 2000, up from just under 700,000 in 1996, according to DRI/McGraw-Hill's estimate.</p>
<p>General Motors, so far the most aggressive U.S. firm in Russia, will invest $200-250 million in a joint venture plant that will start producting Chevy Blazers in December and have a capacity of 50,000 units.</p>
<p>RUSSIAN CAR ENTHUSIASTS WORLD'S MOST DEPRIVED</p>
<p>Russian car enthusiasts are some of the most deprived in the world after decades of waiting on lists to buy second-rate Soviet products and five years of economic reforms, during which many Russians have had to sell their possessions for food.</p>
<p>But with economic growth predicted for 1997, the first time since the breakup of the Soviet Union in 1991, Russians, whose average car ownership is estimated by MC Securities at only about 15 percent of the U.S. level, are ready to buy.</p>
<p>Choice on the Russian market has not improved much since communist days for the average buyer, and the clumsy Soviet manufacturing and service infrastructure are still in place.</p>
<p>Car output rose two percent on a year ago in the first 10 months of 1996 to 719,000, led by AvtoVAZ with 552,600 cars, continuing an improvement begun in 1994.</p>
<p>But AvtoVAZ, maker of Lada small sedans based on an old Fiat design, is a lumbering industrial dinosaur that is on the government's hit-list, with almost three trillion roubles ($550 million) in tax arrears and more in debts to suppliers.</p>
<p>Its newest Lada is 10 years behind the West, and its three assembly lines, each longer than a kilometre (0.6 miles), cannot be retooled without billions of dollars in new investment, analysts say.</p>
<p>GAZ, in reform-minded Nizhny Novgorod, began production of a light 1.5 tonne truck, the Gazelle, based on its Volga mid-sized sedan's chassis and engine, in 1995, successfully moving from mid-sized truck production to the two hot-selling models.</p>
<p>The Gazelle, which costs $8,000, showed the potential and limits of Russian car makers, said MC Securities analyst Patricia Isaeva. &quot;Right now the quality is not so high, but the ratio of price to quality is excellent.&quot;</p>
<p>Russians, forced to be handy to keep their old Soviet cars running, are used to repairing AvtoVAZ and GAZ models, both of which have huge distribution and repair networks throughout the country, where imports are rare.</p>
<p>FOREIGN COMPETITION LOOMING</p>
<p>But foreign competitors led by South Korean firms are already planning to move in on the Russian market.</p>
<p>Kia Motors Crop announced a five-year, $1 billion investment earlier this year in a plant that would produce parts for and assemble 55,000 cars, in western Russia.</p>
<p>Daewoo is already producing limited volumes at a $650 million, 200,000 capacity joint venture in Uzbekistan.</p>
<p>The low-priced Korean cars do not have the reputations of European and U.S. models but are within reach of Russians, as opposed to GM's high-priced Blazer, aimed at top-level buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;European and American producers are going to lose this market. They take too long to think,&quot; said Isaeva.</p>
<p>Apart from GM, Volkswagen AG's Czech unit Skoda a.s. and Ford each have small-scale assembly plants in the works, Skoda in Russia and Ford in neighbouring Belarus.</p>
<p>But joint ventures have not proven fertile ground for foreign car markers. GM has managerial control of its Blazer plant, and neither AvtoVAZ nor GAZ has succeeded in a joint production agreement.</p>
<p>GAZ, considered the most forward-looking of the two, bought a licence to produce diesel motors from Steyr-Daimler-Puch AG when joint production talks fell through, Isaeva said.</p>
<p>In September, Toyota denied a report quoting GAZ's chief saying the plant would produce Toyota Camrys.</p>
<p>&quot;All the foreign manufacturers have been fairly nervous of Russia,&quot; said DRI/McGraw-Hill automotive analyst Carol Thomas.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone moved in after the fall of the Soviet Union. When they saw how bad the plants and financing were, they held back.&quot;</p>
<p>She said that used car imports, a cheap and trustworthy alternative to new Russian cars, would become less competitive because Russian authorities would increase duties and other trade barriers to keep them out.</p>
<p>Used Japanese cars have swamped the market in the Russian Far East. In the port of Vladivostok the battered right-hand drive cars appear to outnumber Russian vehicles heavily.</p>
<p>Russia's used car imports this year will be about 300,000, Thomas said, but predicted that they would be brought down to about 100,000 by the turn of the century.</p>
<p>The same trend has been seen in Romania and Poland, both formerly large-volume used car importers.</p>
<p>&quot;The governments got tough and killed those markets dead,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But hundreds of thousands may still be able to get through Russia's porous borders, if Russians do not want to buy their own products. Brunswick's Oleg Pavlov said Russian manufacturers were not assured a smooth ride.</p>
<p>&quot;Russian producers already have a bad reputation, even among Russians, and that's hard to shake. They do not have money -- and more importantly time -- to develop and launch a high quality product.&quot; ($1=5,480 roubles)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
