<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214161" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks likely to post moderate gains.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks likely to post moderate gains.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks are expected to get support on Tuesday from the Dow Industrials' record-breaking rise overnight. But gains are likely to be limited, with most participants awaiting key economic indicators to be released later this week, brokers said.</p>
<p>On Monday, the key Nikkei 225 average ended up 77.46 points or 0.37 percent at 21,293.57. Its December futures were up 50 points at 21,300.</p>
<p>&quot;The Nikkei average will eventually head towards 21,500, but today it could hover around 21,300 to 21,400,&quot; said Yasuo Ueki, general manager at Nikko Securities Co Ltd.  </p>
<p>On Monday, the Dow breezed past the 6,500 level for the first time in history, climbing 76 points or 1.17 percent to about 6,548. It was the biggest point rise since August 2.</p>
<p>The bullishness on Wall Street has helped improve market sentiment in Tokyo. But currently, rising stocks on the Tokyo bourse are limited to blue-chip issues, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have to see if the buying becomes cyclical,&quot; Ueki said.</p>
<p>The market is awaiting the Bank of Japan's quarterly &quot;tankan&quot; survey on business sentiment due out on Wednesday and October industrial production due out on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Participants will focus especially on whether Japan's economy will manage to maintain the pace of its recovery, brokers said.</p>
<p>They also said the dollar's rise above 112 yen overnight was likely to have little impact, as it would not fuel fears of foreign investors selling Japanese equities unless the U.S. currency jumps above 115 yen.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Equities Desk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
