<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214201" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares end 2.51 pct up on BNI listing.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares end 2.51 pct up on BNI listing.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The listing of state-owned Bank Negara Indonesia (BNI) coupled with active buying of some blue-chip counters sent the Jakarta index surging on Monday, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Composite Index closed up 15.38 points, or 2.51 percent, at 628.24 points. Advancers led losers by 54 to 46, with 62 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers and analysts said the market was expected to continue to be active on Tuesday with market focus remaining on BNI coupled with additional foreign buying of some banking stocks and fundamentally-sound stocks.  </p>
<p>&quot;What happened today is extraordinary. It (BNI) is such a liquid stock. I believe it will be boosting the Jakarta bourse at least for a week,&quot; a broker from a London-based securities firm said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is for the first time I saw in the Jakarta bourse that one counter can book a trade volume of hundreds of millions of shares,&quot; Harto, a broker in local firm Bhakti Investama said.</p>
<p>BNI closed at 1,250 rupiah from its issue price of 850 rupiah and slightly over 179 million shares were traded of the entire board's volume of 311 million shares.  </p>
<p>Brokers said timber firm Barito Pacific and secondary Asahimas Flat Glass also traded at significant volumes.</p>
<p>They also said local investors dominated trade in BNI.</p>
<p>&quot;Comparing to the total trading volume on BNI stock, foreign participation was small but the total itself is very huge,&quot; a foreign broker said.</p>
<p>Banking stocks including Bank BDNI and Lippo Bank were also actively traded following the spin-off effect from the BNI listing coupled with favourable ratings by Standard &amp; Poor's.  </p>
<p>S&amp;P said it assigned public information ratings to 13 Indonesian banks, including Bank BDNI and Lippo Bank which were both rated BBpi.</p>
<p>The new ratings employ analytical procedures that parallel traditional credit ratings, but differ in that they are based on public disclosure and other sources of information, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>BDNI rose 75 rupiah to 2,200 on 2.5 million shares.</p>
<p>Timber firm Barito Pacific rose 200 rupiah to 1,775 rupiah on a volume of 29.8 million shares following continued market talk of a possible take-over by a prominent group combined with speculation that it might do a private placement.  </p>
<p>Glass manufacturer Asahimas rose 250 rupiah to 1,600 on 18.1 million shares on what brokers said was fresh buying.</p>
<p>Car maker Astra International was also actively traded, rising 600 rupiah to 5,600 on 2.3 million shares on its fundamentals, brokers said.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
