<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214352" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT soy products end lower on late break in wheat.</title>
<headline>CBOT soy products end lower on late break in wheat.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A late and quick drop from the day's highs in the CBOT wheat pit triggered local selling and day-trade profit taking in the soy commplex, traders said.</p>
<p>Soyoil and soymeal closed lower after trading higher much of the day on fresh bullish input from the domestic scene, they said.</p>
<p>Soymeal had found a supportive peg from cattle, specifically from Friday's USDA Seven State Cattle-On-Feed Report, traders said.</p>
<p>USDA said there were 8.544 million head of cattle on feed as of November 1, up one percent from a year ago.</p>
<p>The tally had been expected to drop 0.5 percent. The number of cattle placed on feed during November was 2.531 million, up 11 percent from a year ago, compared with expectations for a 5.7 percent rise.</p>
<p>Technicians cited bull flags from the four- and 20-day moving averages in the soy complex for the nearby December contracts.</p>
<p>Soymeal closed $0.80 to $2.00 per ton lower, with December down $0.80 at $236.90. Soyoil was 0.05 to 0.15 cent per lb lower, with December down 0.11 at 23.31.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
