<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214350" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Massachusetts to ban &quot;Saturday Night specials&quot;.</title>
<headline>Massachusetts to ban &quot;Saturday Night specials&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Massachusetts attorney general Monday unveiled safety and quality standards for handguns he said would effectively ban the sale of the cheap pistols known as &quot;Saturday Night specials&quot; in the state.</p>
<p>The regulations target inexpensive, often defective handguns that fail minimum quality standards and are most often used in violent crimes, Massachusetts Attorney General Scott Harshbarger told a news conference. Most are .22- and .25-calibre guns made in the Los Angeles area, he said.</p>
<p>The regulations would curb the accidental discharge of weapons by children and reduce the number of impulsive suicides and the proliferation of stolen handguns, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Using our consumer protection powers, we regulate the safety of caps for toy guns, fireworks and everything from bicycles to baby rattles. It's time we do everything we can to make sure the handguns offered for legal sale in Massachusetts are as safe as they can be for law-abiding citizens, their families and their children,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The regulations, which would go into effect next year, include childproof features, such as increased trigger pressure or grip safeties, that would prevent the average 6-year-old from discharging a handgun; use-limitation devices, such as a lock or smart-gun technology, to prevent unauthorised use; a load indicator to show if the gun is loaded; and tamper-resistent serial numbers to assist in criminal investigations.</p>
<p>Proposed legislation to ban certain types of automatic weapons failed to pass the Massachusetts legislature this year. With these regulations, Harshbarger bypassed the legislature. He said he was the first attorney general in the United States to use his consumer protection powers to regulate handgun sales.</p>
<p>Stephen Teret, director of the John Hopkins Centre for Gun Policy Research, said he suspected other states would follow Massachusetts' lead and extend handgun regulations.</p>
<p>&quot;It's my guess that the ripple effect will also change the incidence of gun deaths in the United States overall,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Firearms are the second cause of injury-related deaths of children and adolescents in Massachusetts, Susan Gallagher, director of the Children's Safety Network, said.</p>
<p>In the three years from 1992 to 1994, 129 children died in the state from guns, around 30 of them suicides, she said. In 1994, over 160 children were hospitalized for firearms injuries.</p>
<p>James Brady, the former press secretary to President Ronald Reagan who was seriously wounded in a March 1981 assassination attempt on Reagan, will testify at a public hearing in support of the regulations Tuesday.</p>
<p>Smith &amp; Wesson of Springfield, Mass., the world's largest manufacturer of handguns, said it would study the regulations and consider all options, including moving out of the state.</p>
<p>&quot;We are talking to (Harshbarger) about his regulations. We have asked for clarifications,&quot; company spokesman Ken Jorgensen said.</p>
<p>Harshbarger said no Smith &amp; Wesson handguns were targeted for the ban but they would be subject to the regulations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
