<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214318" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco-foe Kessler to leave as FDA commissioner.</title>
<headline>Tobacco-foe Kessler to leave as FDA commissioner.</headline>
<byline>Robert Trautman</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Food and Drug Administration Commissioner David Kessler, leader of the Clinton administration's effort to regulate tobacco, announced on Monday that he would resign once a successor was named.</p>
<p>FDA officials said Clinton had asked Kessler, appointed to the post by President George Bush in 1990, to stay on, but he wanted to return to private life in early 1997.</p>
<p>Kessler, a pediatrician and lawyer, faced heated battles during his final years in office.</p>
<p>When Republicans took over Congress, they joined the pharmaceutical and medical-device industries in fighting to reduce the FDA's regulatory powers over drugs and medical devices.</p>
<p>And the powerful tobacco industry was at his throat immediately after Clinton, at Kessler's urging, proposed regulating the sale of tobacco to young people.</p>
<p>Clinton praised Kessler's &quot;tireless commitment&quot; to public life and said &quot;his contributions to improve the health of our nation are many and their effect will continue to be felt for generations to come.&quot;</p>
<p>Kessler said in a statement he appreciated the opportunity to serve the public, but now believed &quot;it is time to return to private life.&quot;</p>
<p>Donna Shalala, secretary of the Health and Human Services Department, the FDA's parent agency, said Kessler had a profoundly positive effect on the nation's health, particularly its children. She cited him for his &quot;energy, dedication, courage, passion and visionary leadership.&quot;</p>
<p>But the response from industry was muted. The Tobacco Institute, the industry's lobbying arm, said &quot;we are declining to comment.&quot;</p>
<p>The stocks of tobacco companies ended broadly higher Monday on news that Kessler intends to leave his post.</p>
<p>The Health Industry Manufacturers Association, makers of medical devices, said Kessler's resignation was a surprise. It added: &quot;We look forward to working with Dr. Kessler's successor to improve the climate for innovation.&quot;</p>
<p>There was no immediate comment from the Pharmaceutical Manufacturers and Research Association.</p>
<p>Representative Henry Waxman of California, senior Democrat on the Commerce Committee's health subcommittee, praised Kessler as &quot;the finest commissioner the agency has ever had.&quot;</p>
<p>Waxman said in an interview that Kessler should be credited with putting on track the approval of RU486, commonly called the abortion pill, which the congressman said would fundamentally change the abortion debate.</p>
<p>Republicans in Congress had assailed Kessler for what it called FDA over-regulation that stifled innovation, denied new products to the sick and cost jobs in plants making drugs and medical devices.</p>
<p>The FDA over the years had speeded up its approval process and set new records in turning out authorisations for new drugs and medical devices. Efforts to take on the powerful cigarette companies and tobacco growers -- and their allies in Congress -- provoked heated reaction when the issue was first raised.</p>
<p>But Kessler had the legal and medical tools to fight.</p>
<p>He was urged when he took office to regulate tobacco, but waited until he could make the proper legal case that tobacco could be regulated and that tobacco companies had manipulated nicotine to keep smokers smoking.</p>
<p>In 1994 he announced his agency was considering the regulation of the $50 billion tobacco industry. In 1995, he said cigarette companies knew young smokers become addicted adults and the firms were aiming their $5.2 billion marketing budgets at the young.</p>
<p>Kessler declared that 3,000 teens started smoking every day and 1,000 would ultimately die of tobacco-related illnesses, making smoking a pediatric disease.</p>
<p>Clinton proposed wide-ranging rules to curb teen smoking, including tough restrictions on advertising and promoting cigarettes at sporting and entertainment events aimed at children.</p>
<p>The tobacco industry immediately challenged the FDA's authority, filing a lawsuit in a federal court in tobacco-friendly North Carolina.</p>
<p>The case is pending, but Clinton earlier this year made the proposal final, to go into effect next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
