<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214353" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Republicans name nine to U.S. House Ag Committee.</title>
<headline>Republicans name nine to U.S. House Ag Committee.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republicans named nine new members to the U.S. House Agriculture Committee on Monday and gave the panel's new chairman, Bob Smith of Oregon, a seat on the Resources Committee as well.</p>
<p>Smith, who was re-elected to the House after a two-year retirement, has said he wants to work on forestry, property rights and Endangered Species Act reforms. A seat on the Resources Committee would compound his influence.</p>
<p>Democrats have named Charles Stenholm of Texas as their leader on the Agriculture Committee.  </p>
<p>They also named five new Democrats to serve on the Agriculture panel, plus one &quot;future&quot; member, which may signal plans to try to change the party ratio on the committee. Democrats cut into the Republican majority in the House in this month's elections, but, at present, the Agriculture Committee would have 27 Republicans and 22 Democrats in 1997, the same as now.</p>
<p>Named as new Republican members along with Smith were Jo Ann Emerson of Missouri, Jerry Moran of Kansas, Roy Blunt of Missouri, Chip Pickering of Mississippi, Bob Schaffer of Colorado, John Thune of South Dakota, William Jenkins of Tennessee and John Cooksey of Louisiana.  </p>
<p>A congressional staff worker said Smith was listed as 21st in seniority out of 27 Republicans on the Resources Committee. When he left the House in 1994, Smith was fifth in seniority on that committee.</p>
<p>Republicans leaving the Agriculture Committee were Richard Baker of Louisiana, Mike Crapo of Idaho, Ken Calvert of California and Tom Latham of Iowa.</p>
<p>Latham was given a seat on the Appropriations Committee, one of the &quot;exclusive&quot; committees whose members are not allowed to serve on other panels.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
