<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214351" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices up, Calif deal ahead.</title>
<headline>U.S. MUNICIPAL FOCUS - prices up, Calif deal ahead.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. municipal bond prices ended 1/8 to 1/4 point higher Monday as players awaited a $400 million Metropolitan Water District of Southern California deal expected to price via senior manager PaineWebber Inc on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Mets are going to be priced it looks like tomorrow, so we have something to do this holiday-shortened week,&quot; one trader said, adding that the offering should do well. &quot;(The deal) is a double-A stand alone probably coming insured so it will be a good bond. There will be a lot of interest in it.&quot; </p>
<p>Another market source said pricing is expected to be released shortly after 0900 EST Tuesday.</p>
<p>As for Monday's secondary market, the trader described it as &quot;kind of a mixed bag.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In the long end I bought stuff at the same level it traded Friday,&quot; he said. &quot;The intermediate sector, I would say we are up about 1/8 (point), but that's really about it. We didn't really have a big up day here.&quot;</p>
<p>A municipal analyst said high-grade issues improved by two basis points in the intermediate range, while dollar bonds ended 1/8 to 1/4 point higher. </p>
<p>Activity was light, with bid lists totaling about $200 million. The lists contained &quot;a lot of odd couponing and short calls,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A trader also cited lists.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a lot of stuff to bid on today,&quot; he said. &quot;The the good news is at least a lot of it is trading.&quot;</p>
<p>In debt futures, the December municipal contract closed up 7/32 at 117-30/32. The December T-bond contract was up 5/32 at 115-15/32. The MOB spread was 79 ticks.</p>
<p>In the government market, the benchmark 30-year bond closed up 6/32 at 100-31/32 to yield 6.43 percent.</p>
<p>As for Monday's competitive sales, Hutchinson Shockey Erley &amp; Co won the biggest deal, $30 million Unified School District No. 512, Kan., general obligation bonds. The firm won the bonds at a net interest cost of 5.195 percent.</p>
<p>--Kathie O'Donnell, 212-859-1655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
