<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214587" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Jordan urges reconsideration of Libya sanctions.</title>
<headline>Jordan urges reconsideration of Libya sanctions.</headline>
<byline>Marjorie Olster</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan urged a reconsideration on Monday of international sanctions imposed on Libya in connection with airliner bombings, saying such measures hurt ordinary people instead of their leaders.</p>
<p>Jordanian Prime Minister Abdul-Karim al-Kabariti, on a visit to Spain, said the sanctions imposed by the United Nations in 1992 in connection with the 1988 airliner bombing over Lockerbie, Scotland have not solved anything.</p>
<p>Libya was targeted for its refusal to extradite two men accused of planting a bomb aboard Pan Am Flight 103 which exploded over Lockerbie and killed 270 people.</p>
<p>&quot;Libya is now under some sort of a sanction...We would like very much to (re)visit this idea of sanctions,&quot; Kabariti said at a joint news conference with Spanish Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar in Madrid.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very much now needed for the international community to revise and consider the idea of sanctions and see whether they really change the situation in the way that (they are) intended,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The punitive measures against Libya include an air embargo, a ban on arms sales and the downgrading of diplomatic relations. They are reviewed by the U.N. Security Council every 120 days.</p>
<p>They also penalise Libya for not cooperating in an investigation into the 1989 bombing of France's UTA Flight 772 over Niger which killed all 171 aboard.</p>
<p>Because of Tripoli's continued non-compliance, the U.N. Security Council imposed additional sanctions in 1993 including a freeze on some of Libya's assets abroad and a ban on its import of certain types of equipment used in oil transport terminals and refineries.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that sanctions don't affect dictators and don't affect the regimes,&quot; said Kabariti. &quot;In fact what they do is just add to the misery of the people and they don't solve any problems.&quot;</p>
<p>The Arab League, of which Jordan is a member, supports Libya in its offer for the two Lockerbie suspects to be tried by a Scottish judge under Scottish law at the World Court at The Hague. The United States and Britain, which have indicted the two men, insist they stand trial in a Scottish or U.S court.</p>
<p>Kabariti was responding to a Spanish reporter's question about possible Libyan nuclear capabilities following a story in the Spanish daily El Mundo on a secret NATO document pointing to potential future threats to Spain from Tripoli.</p>
<p>El Mundo quoted the secret NATO report on Monday which singles out Russia, Libya, Syria, Iran and Iraq as potential foes of the U.S.-led NATO alliance but sees North Africa as the top source of threats to its territory.</p>
<p>It said Libya could pose a significant threat in 10 years' time if Tripoli successfully develops long-range missiles and warheads which could put Spain within its range.</p>
<p>Al-Kabariti said he does not think Libya has nuclear weapons.</p>
<p>&quot;I doubt very much that Libya really had the time to develop such capabilities,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
