<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214562" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: British Lord Chancellor lobbies Council of Europe.</title>
<headline>British Lord Chancellor lobbies Council of Europe.</headline>
<dateline>STRASBOURG, France 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's top law official urged the Council of Europe on Monday to rein in its enforcement of human rights rules, saying it should not meddle in states' sensitive internal affairs.</p>
<p>The Lord Chancellor, Lord Mackay of Clashfern, said he held talks with officials of the Council of Europe and its two human rights arms -- the European Court of Human Rights and European Commission of Human Rights -- to discuss &quot;matters of mutual concern&quot; about the council's human rights enforcement machinery.</p>
<p>&quot;It is important that the procedures of the court should enable it to give proper weight to laws passed by the parliaments of democratic countries,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;They (national parliaments) are best placed to determine moral and social issues in accordance with regional and national perceptions.&quot;</p>
<p>Britain's Conservative government has criticised the rights court and commission for a series of recent rulings that it says constitute outside meddling in its ability to govern.</p>
<p>Mackay's visit came on a day that the Euro-court, in a rare victory for Britain, issued a ruling upholding a controversial ban on an erotic film about the visions of a 16th-century Spanish nun, rejecting charges that it violated the director's freedom of expression.</p>
<p>The judges ruled by seven to two that Britain's 1989 ban on the 18-minute &quot;Visions of Ecstasy&quot; about the Roman Catholic mystic Saint Teresa of Avila was justified under blasphemy laws to avoid shocking Christians.</p>
<p>But Mackay said he had come to discuss his general concerns rather than &quot;to advance some case which is solely in the interests of the UK&quot;.</p>
<p>He advocated reforms in the way judges are appointed and urged the court and commission to give greater leeway to domestic courts in sensitive matters.</p>
<p>The human rights commission, which screens cases for the court, angered London in September by agreeing to take up the case of a British 12-year-old boy seeking to overturn British laws allowing his parents to smack him.</p>
<p>Last year the court condemned Britain for the killings of three unarmed Irish Republican Army bombers in Gibraltar in 1988.</p>
<p>And this year it condemned Britain's system for jailing minors.</p>
<p>The 40-nation council, headquartered in Strasbourg, northeastern France, was set up following World War Two to foster democracy and human rights across Europe.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STRASBOURG, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
