<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214550" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Middle-aged SPD courts lost German youth vote.</title>
<headline>Middle-aged SPD courts lost German youth vote.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Liffey</byline>
<dateline>COLOGNE, Germany 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Social Democratic Party (SPD) on Monday vowed to slap a training levy on employers if it comes to power in Bonn, in a bid to win back the youth vote the party has lost.</p>
<p>The SPD, once the party of the young under revered chancellor Willy Brandt, has realised after 14 years in opposition that its youthful support has fled in frustration with an organisation nicknamed &quot;Old Auntie&quot;.</p>
<p>On Monday it decked out a one-day party conference on youth issues with graffiti-painted banners reading &quot;Young and Cool&quot;, and used T-shirted roller skaters to show delegates around.</p>
<p>The conference passed a resolution saying that employers who failed to take on their share of young trainees or apprentices would have to pay a special levy into a training fund.</p>
<p>But to many of the predominantly young delegates, the moves rang hollow from a party which has failed to show voters of any age clear alternatives to record unemployment and welfare cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to talk with young people. We don't want to patronise,&quot; party chairman Oskar Lafontaine told the national delegates, surrounded by posters of trendy young SPD members clad in skating gear or straddling mountain bikes.</p>
<p>But 25-year-old Andrea Nahles, eloquent chairwoman of the SPD's youth wing, was not convinced by the leadership's rather stiff efforts to take young people seriously.</p>
<p>&quot;When well-meaning party functionaries go to a techno party, it's about as believable as when Boris Yeltsin, with his heart disease, dances rock and roll at an election rally,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The statistics are damning. The SPD has just six members of parliament under 35 while Kohl's Christian Democrats (CDU), often seen as having their core support among Germany's old-age pensioners, have 20.</p>
<p>The CDU's youth wing, at 153,000, makes up almost a quarter of party membership while the SPD's youth wing, at 128,000, accounts for just a sixth.</p>
<p>Many in the SPD blame a rigid organisation that reflects the historic structures of organised labour.</p>
<p>But others, including Nahles, blame today's leaders -- once the student reform generation of the late 1960s and now often wryly known as &quot;Brandt's grandchildren&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;For years you've been kicking away the ladder for the youngsters coming up behind,&quot; she told them.</p>
<p>A standing policy to cut the voting age to 16 years from 18 has lain dormant for three years, and with time short the conference deferred a motion to reaffirm the policy.</p>
<p>But the SPD's rivals have not been idle. The Greens have stolen many of the SPD's clothes by emphasising social justice combined with a radical approach to environmental issues.</p>
<p>At local elections in Lower Saxony this year, they displaced the SPD as second among young voters, behind the CDU.</p>
<p>&quot;Younger people aged 30 to 45 who we have lost have all gone to the Greens,&quot; said 29-year-old Kerstin Griese, chairwoman of the SPD's youth commission.</p>
<p>That generation of voters and party workers will be tough to get back.</p>
<p>&quot;The SPD has plenty to criticise in Kohl, but I still don't see it giving concrete answers to concrete problems like the hopeless state of education,&quot; said 24-year-old Kai Kullen.</p>
<p>&quot;Young people need a bit more to impress them than brightly-coloured posters.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOGNE, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
