<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214544" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: FOCUS - FinMin slams Skandia bank merger.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - FinMin slams Skandia bank merger.</headline>
<byline>Abigail Schmelz</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swedish insurer Skandia and mortgage bank Stadshypotek on Monday said they would merge to form the Nordic region's biggest financial institution, but the plan was slammed by the bank's largest minority owner, the Swedish government.</p>
<p>The announcement from the two firms, in the wake of a government statement that it would sell its 34 percent Stadshypotek stake through an auction, sparked an uncharacteristically violent reaction from the usually reserved Swedish Finance Minister.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no confidence in the present Board of Directors of Stadshypotek,&quot; Erik Asbrink thundered in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It is remarkable that this happens without them contacting the biggest owner,&quot; Swedish news agency TT quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>The companies said that the new group, Skandia Stadshypotek, would have total assets of about 500 billion crowns ($75.8 billion), net assets of 37.5 billion and a total market capitalisation of about 45 billion as of November 22.</p>
<p>The share market, sensing a bidding war for Stadshypotek, immediately marked the company's share price up seven crowns to 205 crowns when trading started after several hours of suspension. It closed at 203. Skandia dropped 11.5 crowns to 197.</p>
<p>Stadshypotek's board chairman Gosta Renell said it would not resign despite criticism. &quot;The board will be changed at a shareholders' meeting and not by a single shareholder,&quot;he said.</p>
<p>But Asbrink, asked about the possibility of the board resigning, told TT: &quot;You can draw your own conclusions. I have said I have no confidence in the current board of Stadshypotek.&quot;</p>
<p>Asbrink said he planned to pursue the original plan to sell the state's stake to an industrial buyer in a controlled auction. He said expressions of interest had been noted from Sweden and abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;We think this one is not over. This is not a done deal yet, considering the way it has been left open by the government,&quot; BZW analyst Angus Runciman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our feeling is that the government has clearly left the way open for a higher bid for Stadshypotek,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Both companies said the Swedish government had not been willing to discuss the proposed merger. Stadshypotek, Sweden's largest mortgage lender with about 30 percent of the market, said 11 of its shares would buy 10 shares in the new company.</p>
<p>The companies said the merger was expected to improve earnings per share in 1997, generate large savings and enhance returns from international unit linked business.</p>
<p>On the cost side, savings are expected primarily from the integration of SkandiaBanken and Stadshypotek Bank.</p>
<p>The total synergies are estimated at 800 million crowns in 1998 and 1.2 billion in 1999, of which more than half comprises cost savings, the two companies said. Restructuring costs of 500 million crowns over the next three years were forecast.</p>
<p>&quot;We are convinced that the new company will increase value for money for shareholders in Skandia and Stadshypotek,&quot; Skandia's chief executive Bjorn Wolrath said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are creating a strong and competitive Nordic financial services company which has the capital base required to meet the challenges of restructuring within the Nordic finance sector demands,&quot; Wolrath said.</p>
<p>Skandia chairman Sven Soderberg said Skandia's offer was made in the belief that the state would consider the proposal.</p>
<p>Soderberg said in a statement the merger would allow for rapid expansion of AFS (Assurance and Financial Services), Skandia's international life and financial services unit.</p>
<p>He said a 5.0 billion crown cash injection would be needed for AFS over the next five years.</p>
<p>Analysts said the move signalled the start of an industry-wide shake-up in Sweden's financial sector which would end in fewer players in the crowded market.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the beginning of an earthquake,&quot; Swedbank banking and insurance analyst Jonny Sylven told Reuters, saying the finance service sector shake-out could soon spread to major Nordic banks.</p>
<p>($1 =6.597 Swedish Crown)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
