<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="214751" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Big U.S. exporter to pay penalty on Iraqi sales.</title>
<headline>Big U.S. exporter to pay penalty on Iraqi sales.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Continental Grain Co. and a Geneva-based affiliate will pay $35 million to settle a dispute with the U.S. government over use of export credit guarantees on sales to Iraq, the company said Monday.</p>
<p>Continental, one of the world's major exporters of grain, said it would pay $25 million to end the dispute, which involved sales completed before Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>Its affiliate, Arab Finagrain Agri-Business Ltd., pleaded guilty to a one-count criminal charge in a separate settlement and agreed to pay a $10 million fine.</p>
<p>In a statement, New York-based Continental said the settlement would not affect its operations, including its participation in U.S. farm export programmes.</p>
<p>Continental said neither it nor its employees were found in violaton of the law.</p>
<p>The Justice and Agriculture departments said Arab Finagrain pleaded guilty to conspiring to defraud the Agriculture Department on sales of agricultural products to Iraq from 1987 through 1990.</p>
<p>According to the criminal charge, Arab Finagrain used Continental to register for sales of soybean meal and protein concentrate under the Agriculture Department's export credit guarantee programme because Arab Finagrain -- with no office or presence in the United States -- was ineligible.</p>
<p>Agriculture Department Inspector General Roger Viadero said in a statement that Arab Finagrain and some of its affiliated companies voluntarily agreed to no longer take part in any programmes funded, guaranteed or sponsored by the U.S. government.</p>
<p>Continental said it agreed to the settlement to avoid protracted litigation.</p>
<p>At issue was Arab Finagrain's participation in the short-term export credit guarantee programme in order to facilitate sales of U.S. farm products to Iraq.</p>
<p>Continental contended Arab Finagrain was an &quot;intervening purchaser,&quot; or intermediary, in the sales. The Justice Department said it was an unqualified co-exporter and ineligible for the credits.</p>
<p>Continental reportedly made more than $1 billion in sales of soybean meal and protein concentrate to Iraq during the 1980s with the aid of U.S. credit guarantees. The credits assure lenders they will get their money even if the buyer fails to pay.</p>
<p>Arab Finagrain would have participated in all of the sales, a Continental spokesman said.</p>
<p>Following the invasion of Kuwait, Iraq defaulted on hundreds of millions of dollars of purchases made with Agriculture Department credit guarantees.</p>
<p>Arab Finagrain was incorporated in London and had offices in Geneva. It was a joint marketing venture created by three partners -- Finagrain, a European subsidiary of Continental; the Paris bank Banque Arabe et Internationale d'Investissment; and Granflo, a Jordanian transport company.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
