<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215041" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BAHRAIN: New Bahrain bank to offer $80 mln equity next month.</title>
<headline>New Bahrain bank to offer $80 mln equity next month.</headline>
<byline>Abbas Salman</byline>
<dateline>MANAMA 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>A new Bahrain bank will offer $80 million equity to Gulf Arab and global investors in December through private placement, one of its founder shareholders said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will be starting from December...and will be completed by March,&quot; Samuel Belzberg, one of four founder shareholders of the First Gulf Pacific Bank (FGPB), told Reuters in Bahrain.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank is going to have a global concept in investments. Consequently, we have associated ourselves with global people who are going to help us and share our investment decisions,&quot; Belzberg said.</p>
<p>He said the bank would be established in Bahrain before the end of 1996 and would be operational in the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>The Bahrain Monetary Agency, Bahrain's central bank, has licensed the FGPB as an offshore banking unit, raising to 48 the number of international units operating on the island.</p>
<p>Saudi Prince Nawaf bin Abdulaziz, a brother of Saudi King Fahd, is among the founder shareholders, Belzberg said. He said Prince Nawaf, a former Saudi Arabian finance minister, had a &quot;substantial stake&quot; in the bank.</p>
<p>The other investors are C.K. Lau and Geoffrey Lau, members of the family which controls three listed firms in Malaysia, and Robert Lee, chairman of the Canadian investment company Prospero group.</p>
<p>The four had committed to pay $20 million of the bank's $100 million paid-in capital.</p>
<p>Belzberg said the equity would be placed in Gulf Arab states, north America and the Far East &quot;through private placement.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are looking for investors who will be co-investors in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The FGPB would establish offices in New York, Vancouver and Hong Kong, but the head office would be in Bahrain, Belzberg said.</p>
<p>The north American offices would focus on corporate acquisitions and real estate investment and development there. The Hong Kong office would cover the emerging markets of Asia and focus on direct investment, he said</p>
<p>The Bahrain office would be responsible for management of direct investments, investment placement, treasury and liquidity management and financial control, Belzberg said.</p>
<p>Belzberg said the bank had chosen Bahrain, the Gulf's main financial and banking centre, as a location because &quot;we feel it is a good centre, both politically and economically....We are comfortable here with our investment.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BAHRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BAHRAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
