<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215045" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Cairo bourse boom to continue - brokers.</title>
<headline>Cairo bourse boom to continue - brokers.</headline>
<byline>Miral Fahmy</byline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Attractive yields and strong investor interest have catapulted the Cairo stock exchange to the highest level in its history and brokers say the gains are here to stay.</p>
<p>This month's Middle East and North Africa Economic Conference and low price-to-earnings (PE) ratios have also launched Egypt's capital market on the fast track to fame and fortune and sent share prices soaring.</p>
<p>&quot;The take-off has started,&quot; Shireen ElKady, chief financial officer and vice-president of market analysts Arbitrage/Prime Investment, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;People expected the MENA conference to affect other sectors of the economy but its first influence can be seen on the capital market. Foreign investors are buying quantities.&quot;</p>
<p>The Egyptian Capital Market Authority (CMA) all-share index, rising all last week on gains in blue-chip cement and milling firms, closed on Sunday 6.6 points up at 260.54 -- breaking the record of 255.05 set on October 19, 1994.</p>
<p>Brokers say the conference in Egypt revealed the financial delights of the Cairo bourse to hundreds of delegates and now they have come back to do business.</p>
<p>The market's relatively low PE of about 8.5 and a change in local investors' mentality towards long-term investment have also buoyed share prices, brokers say.</p>
<p>They say the market will soon see PEs of about 13 and 14 as foreigners continue to buy in bulk and local investors, eyeing future rises, hang on to their portfolios.</p>
<p>The banking, cement and milling sectors are currently the most attractive, the brokers added.</p>
<p>&quot;It's going to boom for a long while yet,&quot; said Amr Abu el-Magd, managing director of brokers Megavest.</p>
<p>&quot;People now have more knowledge and they aren't selling. There are also a lot of funds wanting to get into the market so prices are definitely going to increase,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Two international funds trade Egyptian equities -- HSBC James Capel's Concord Fund and the Egypt Trust of SBC Warburg and Lazard Freres' Capital Markets. Brokers also say many other securities houses are stocking up on Cairo shares.</p>
<p>But sceptics are questioning the sustainability of the bourse's rapid rise.</p>
<p>They point out that the market usually rises ahead of dividend distribution time and after results are published.</p>
<p>Brokers said the market had enough steam to rise for at least another three weeks. Then it would stabilise, not fall.</p>
<p>&quot;No prices are going down. They will stabilise in about three weeks and then move in a range of two to three percent, not the current five percent or more,&quot; Abu el-Magd said.</p>
<p>Analyst ElKady said that as long as Egypt kept privatising, the bourse would maintain its uptrend and even scale new highs.</p>
<p>&quot;The state can sustain the rise by giving more merchandise (that is) shares. It has to begin with reducing its holding in firms already listed on the bourse,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>ElKady said the state's offer to auction 10 percent of Helwan Portland Cement  was a step in the right direction. The sale of 20 percent in Cairo Pharmaceutical and Chemical Industries  was also encouraging.</p>
<p>The state has also promised to sell 91 firms by the middle of 1998 and officials have repeatedly said privatisation and liberalisation were the two main steps towards economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The Cairo market is on its way to become an excellent market. The market is definitely taking on a new dimension,&quot; said Walid el-Kholy of El Rashad Brokerage and Securities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
