<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215054" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Foreign workers in Israel fewer than believed.</title>
<headline>Foreign workers in Israel fewer than believed.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Central Bureau of Statistics on Monday published for the first time figures on foreign workers in Israel, indicating they number fewer than previously believed.</p>
<p>Foreign workers as of November 1995 totalled close to 110,000, including 61,000 with legal work permits and 47,000 illegal workers.</p>
<p>More recent figures for illegal workers were not available but the number of legal workers, as of August 1, 1996, had increased by 26,000 to 87,000.</p>
<p>Unofficial estimates had put the number of foreign workers at 250,000.</p>
<p>The government has begun considering ways to cut a growing dependence on foreign workers, who do low paying manual labour, particularly in construction and agriculture.</p>
<p>They have gradually been replacing Palestinians barred from the Jewish state for security reasons.</p>
<p>The statistics bureau's data is based on the Interior Ministry's border-crossing figures and information from the National Insurance Institute.</p>
<p>Among the legal workers, more than 70 percent are from Romania and Thailand. STR TCC</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
