<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215326" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Fundamentals to drive Spanish and Sweden bonds.</title>
<headline>Fundamentals to drive Spanish and Sweden bonds.</headline>
<byline>Deepthi Wickremasinghe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Economic fundamentals rather than sentiment on European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) could be the driving force behind further yield spread convergence for Spanish and Swedish bonds, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>Enthusiasm over EMU has helped European peripheral bonds all year, and the trend gained another fillip from Italy's re-entry to the European Exchange Rate Mechanism on Sunday.</p>
<p>Further outperformance may be on the horizon, but first European bond markets could be in for a bout of late 1996 profit taking, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been a great year for convergence,&quot; said Huw Roberts, European bond strategist at NatWest Capital Markets in London.</p>
<p>&quot;I would not be surprised if the temptation to take profits going into year-end grows and grows. Before we get to 100 on Bonos/Bunds we'll probably see a move back to 150.&quot;</p>
<p>The Bonos/Bund 10-year yield spread is currently around 130 basis points having drawn in from 371 basis points at the beginning of January. The Swedish Bond/Bund gap is at 136 basis points versus 241 in January.</p>
<p>David Keeble, bond strategist at CS First Boston in London, said Spanish bonds' recent outperformance of Swedish bonds was based on the idea that Spain was more likely to go into EMU at the start than Sweden was.</p>
<p>&quot;That has probably swung a little bit too far over the past four weeks or so,&quot; he said. &quot;Spain has been one of the biggest ralliers of the year so far, but it is time to start thinking of moving back into Sweden.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Sweden should be outperforming Spain as we look more to fundamentals and less to EMU,&quot; Keeble said.</p>
<p>He said funding costs for putting on bond trades were far cheaper in Sweden than in Spain. One-month Swedish money rates were currently around 4.35 percent, compared with 6.65 in Spain.</p>
<p>&quot;Convergence has not been purely political, it has been justified by economic fundamentals and in Sweden's case that is definitely true because we are pretty much in a deflationary situation,&quot; said Roberts.</p>
<p>He said the Swedish bond spread could come in a little if there was a general move towards further convergence.</p>
<p>&quot;But they have this opt-out senario, so I guess the market will always demand a certain risk premium for that,&quot; said Roberts. &quot;The government in Stockholm may be very pro-EMU but all the evidence we have at the moment is that popular opposition is still quite strong and the government is not yet in a position to take them in (to EMU).&quot;</p>
<p>But Keeble did not expect Swedish yield premiums to move towards levels for gilts. Unlike the case for Britain, which he said was increasingly unlikely to join EMU, the talk for Sweden was rather of delay over entry.</p>
<p>&quot;Sweden is still very much on the EMU track. There is a much higher probability that Sweden will go in,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Juli Collins-Thompson, economist at Yamaichi International in London, said the Swedish/Bund spread might narrow to 100 basis points but not much more.</p>
<p>&quot;Because it is pretty much priced into the market that Sweden and Britain will not be in the first round of EMU, the market will be assessing these markets based on fundamentals similar to the U.S.,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>For Bonos, Collins-Thompson said the spread could narrow to 80 basis points or lower over the next 12 months based on the improving prospects for Spain making the first round of EMU.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if they don't reach the first round there is likely to be the mechanism in place so that they will join EMU one or two years later,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>However Keeble said the swap spreads between Spain and Germany were already looking pretty tight and the market would be reluctant to see the spread going much narrower.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
