<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215364" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Nov 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Financial Times - Nov 25.</headline>
<text>
<p>Prepared by The Broadcast Monitoring Company for Reuters</p>
<p>FINANCIAL TIMES</p>
<p>-- ITALY AGREES RE-ENTRY TO ERM</p>
<p>European Union finance ministers and central bankers have agreed a return to the ranks of the European exchange rate mechanism of the Italian lira. The currency will re-enter the system at a level of 990 to the mark, a tougher parity that had been sought by Italy. A pre-condition to Italian participation in the single currency is two year's membership of the ERM.</p>
<p>-- LLOYDS CHEMISTS DIRECTORS MAY NET 3 MLN STG IN TAKEOVER</p>
<p>It has been revealed that five directors of Lloyds Chemists stand to gain some three million stg between them if the company is taken over by either Gehe or UniChem. The arrangements relating to such payments were put in place after the company received approaches from the two bidders. Allan Lloyd, company founder and chairman, stands to gain at least 1.2 million stg, while managing director Michael Ward would receive 476,000 stg.</p>
<p>-- TORY REVOLT FORCES STATEMENT ON EMU</p>
<p>In the face of tough opposition from Conservative as well as opposition MPs, the government has backed away from a previous refusal to allow a Commons debate on the stance that will be adopted on Emu negotiations to take place at a forthcoming meeting of EU ministers.</p>
<p>-- TAX RELIEF ON PROFIT RELATED PAY MAY GO IN BUDGET</p>
<p>Tuesday's budget is expected to include the abolition of tax relief on profit-related pay, a move that could see the take-home pay fall for some 2.5 million British workers. The government has, however, become increasingly concerned about the cost to the exchequer of the scheme. In 1995 the initiative cost the government 1.5 billion stg in lost revenue. Other budget measures are expected to include a penny cut in the basic rate of tax, as well as a widening of the band at which the lowest rate of 20p is payable.</p>
<p>-- GRANADA MAY KEEP FLAGSHIP HOTEL IF BIDS FAR BELOW 350 MLN</p>
<p>The Granada Group is reported to be considering retaining ownership of the Grosvenor House Hotel, which it acquired as part of its 3.9 billion stg takeover of Forte in January unless it can achieve the 350 million stg price which it is seeking. Observers believe the company may find it difficult to achieve such a sales price, though a successful sale of this asset is essential for the overall success of the disposal of 15 other top international hotels.</p>
<p>-- SIB FEARS MANIPULATION OF WORLD COMMODITIES MARKETS</p>
<p>The Securities and Investments Board, the leading British financial regulator, has expressed concern about the vulnerability of commodities exchanges to manipulation. The SIB has also observed that the situation is likely to deteriorate as more commodity exchanges are opened across the world.</p>
<p>-- OPINION LEADERS DOUBT BLAIR'S PLEDGES ON TAX</p>
<p>A survey of some 100 opinion leaders has found that 66 per cent believe that under a Labour government the overall tax burden will increase, despite claims to the contrary by party leader Tony Blair. Conducted last month by the Financial Times and Opinion Leader Research, the survey also found that just 10 per cent of those asked believed a Labour government would mean lower taxation for the average family.</p>
<p>-- OFT SET TO DELIVER VERDICT ON BASS BID</p>
<p>The Office of Fair Trading is expected this week to announce its decision on a proposed merger between Bass and Carlsberg-Tetley which would give the companies 38% of the UK market. The expectation is that a referral to the Monopolies &amp; Mergers Commission will be recommended to the trade and industry secretary. The decision will now be with Ian Lang as to whether or not to accepted the advice, or to approach Bass with a view to securing revisions of the deal.</p>
<p>-- PRIVATE FINANCE INITIATIVE WELCOMED</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund in an assessment of the government's Private Finance Initiative has welcomed the scheme, though warned that new accounting methods would be required so that such projects could be properly monitored over their lifetimes. The IMF has noted that the PFI has the potential to improve efficiency in the delivery of public services, though would not create additional investment.</p>
<p>For a full range of news monitoring services, phone BMC +44-171-377-1742</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
