<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215499" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK newspaper headlines - Nov 25.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK newspaper headlines - Nov 25.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- APPLE DAILY -- Some members of the Selection Committee went to Beijing to accuse other members of involving themselves in behind-the-scenes deals over the appointment of the provisional legislature. It said some supporters of the Chief Executive hopefuls had started allocating seats in the future Special Administrative Region (SAR) government.</p>
<p>-- WEN WEI PO -- Chinese President Jiang Zemin and U.S. President Bill Clinton held a &quot;friendly, positive and constructive&quot; meeting in Manila. Both agreed on visits in the next two years.</p>
<p>-- Research in China showed that 70 percent of Chinese supported economic reforms and believed that Hong Kong's prosperity depended on whether the &quot;one country two systems&quot; principle could be carried out. Singapore topped the list of most popular countries while Japan was at the bottom.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO DAILY NEWS -- Financial Secretary Donald Tsang said he was confident that Canada would grant Hong Kong SAR passport holders visa-free access.</p>
<p>-- Newly re-elected Democratic Party leader Martin Lee said the party would unite all democratic forces to avoid being isolated.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG ECONOMIC TIMES -- The financial problems of Top Firm International and Pam and Frank International Holdings were further exposed when big losses were reported in the two businesses in the first six months of the year.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- New World Development will invest about three billion yuan in a toll road project and a large-scale housing development as part of an investment push into Hebei province.</p>
<p>-- Beijing's Justice Bureau has put foreign law firms in a dilemma by asking them to provide information about their clients and the work they do for them.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG STANDARD -- Strong economic growth in some of China's main regions was encouraging investors to seek exposure to the areas through the initial public offering market in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
