<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215555" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK'S MTRC launches HK$3.5 bln revolving credit.</title>
<headline>HK'S MTRC launches HK$3.5 bln revolving credit.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's Mass Transit Railway Corp (MTRC) said on Monday it had launched syndication of a HK$3.5 billion revolving credit facility.</p>
<p>Chase Manhattan Asia, Hang Seng Finance and the Industrial Bank of Japan Hong Kong branch are joint bookrunners.</p>
<p>The facility will have a five-year tenor and will be available for drawings on a revolving basis during the life of the facility. The interest margin will be set at 36.5 basis points over the Hong Kong Interbank Offered Rate.  </p>
<p>Proceeds will be used for general corporate funding requirements, including refinancing of maturity debts and financing of new capital expenditure, the MTRC said.</p>
<p>The facility will constitute the only major fundraising exercise undertaken by the MTRC this year, it said.</p>
<p>Twelve banks have joined as arrangers and underwriters.</p>
<p>The group includes BA Asia, Bank of Tokyo-Mitsubishi, Bayerische Landesbank Girozentrale Hong Kong branch, Chase Manhattan Asia, Deutsche Bank AG Hong Kong branch, Fuji Bank, Hang Seng Bank, Industrial Bank of Japan Hong Kong branch, JP Morgan Securities, Paribas Asia, Sanwa Bank Hong Kong branch and Union Bank of Switzerland.</p>
<p>Details on fees were not immediately available.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
