<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215513" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore jet fuel soars on short covering.</title>
<headline>Singapore jet fuel soars on short covering.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore jet fuel prices soared on Monday on short covering by traders who had earlier sold into Japan, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Traders said the market was also boosted by talks of tight regional supplies as a result of the recent purchases by Japan, South Korea and China.</p>
<p>As a result of the short covering, premiums to North Asia rose with one 30,000-tonne cargo traded on Friday at a premium of close to $2.00 a barrel over spot Singapore quotes on a cost-and-freight basis to Japan, up about 20 cents from the previous deal, traders said.  </p>
<p>In the Singapore physical market, a trader was offering a 100,000-barrel jet fuel cargo at $33.40 a barrel fob, up about $1.00 from Friday's bid level.</p>
<p>The December jet fuel/gas oil spread (regrade) rose substantially and was last quoted at $2.60/$2.80 a barrel, up from Friday's $1.80 bid level, brokers said. December jet fuel swaps traded at $33.00 a barrel.</p>
<p>Gas oil also firmed despite bearish news of India's January purchase of a low 255,000-tonnes, due to strong demand from China which is paying up to $249.00 per tonne for barge lots on an ex-terminal Hong Kong basis.  </p>
<p>Gasoline was dull as the market prepared for the Taiwan buy tender for Jan 1-15 for unleaded reformate which closes today.</p>
<p>Traders said offers were above $27.00 a barrel c-and-f Taiwan, much higher than the last two cargoes purchased for Dec 16-31 delivery at slightly above $25.50. Only talk was heard on paper - an offer at $25.80 for December.</p>
<p>Naphtha swaps were largely uncchanged with December talked at $23.50/$23.70, compared to $23.55/$23.70 on Friday.</p>
<p>Fuel oil rose on healthy buying interest with two 20,000-tonne cargoes traded at $124.50 and $125.00 a tonne fob Singapore. --Singapore Newsroom (+65-870-3093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
