<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215554" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Futures exchanges in China to give additional data.</title>
<headline>Futures exchanges in China to give additional data.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's futures exchanges will announce the 20 most active trading companies and top 20 position holders at the end of each day's trading session, starting from Monday, analysts and officials said.</p>
<p>The daily announcement has been ordered by the China Securities Regulatory Commission (CSRC) as one of a series of measures to restrain excessive speculation in the futures market, analysts said.</p>
<p>The exchanges will publish the 20 most active members and their trading volumes. They also will publish the 20 members who hold the largest long and short positions and the amount each holds after the day's trading, exchange officials said.</p>
<p>But the CSRC did not say how the lists will be prepared, such as whether they will be based on the combined volume of each exchange or on individual contracts, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Exchanges may have a different understanding of the CSRC requirements and the daily report will not be helpful for the market unless the data of different exchanges is announced using the same standard,&quot; said an official for the Shanghai Commodity Exchange.  </p>
<p>&quot;Some small exchanges with a lower trading volume, usually dominated by a handful of speculators, would be hurt by making everything public,&quot; a local broker said.</p>
<p>China's exchanges were also ordered to announce registered warehouse stocks for every contract and the amount of each contract for which members have applied for physical delivery after the close each Friday, exchange officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
