<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="215928" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: S&amp;P assigns new ratings to 14 Philippines banks.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P assigns new ratings to 14 Philippines banks.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard and Poor's Corp said on Monday it has assigned public information ratings to 14 Philippine banks.</p>
<p>The new ratings employ analytical procedures that parallel traditional credit ratings, but differ in that they are based on public disclosure and other sources of information, S&amp;P said.  </p>
<p>The following banks have been rated:</p>
<p>    Bank of the Philippine Islands	     BBBpi</p>
<p>    Development Bank of the Philippines		   BBBpi</p>
<p>    Far East Bank and Trust			BBBpi</p>
<p>Philippine Commercial International Bank BBBpi</p>
<p>    Allied Banking Corp			     BBpi</p>
<p>    China Banking Corp			     BBpi</p>
<p>    Equitable Banking Corp				     BBpi</p>
<p>    Metropolitan Bank and Trust		   BBpi</p>
<p>    Philippine National Bank			BBpi</p>
<p>    Rizal Commercial Bank			   BBpi</p>
<p>    Security Bank Corp			     BBpi</p>
<p>    Solidbank					   BBpi</p>
<p>    Union Bank of the Philippines		 BBpi</p>
<p>    United Coconut Planters Bank			     BBpi</p>
<p>Aggressive lending growth by Philippine banks, including a disproportionate increase in real estate loans combined with skyrocketing real estate prices, raises concerns that the commercial banking sector, as well as individual banks, will experience asset quality difficulties, especially if the economy declines, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>Commercial banks' total assets grew 28.9 percent in fiscal 1995, while total loans grew an astonishing 40.4 percent, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>The reported percentage of commercial bank outstanding loans for finance, real estate and business services lending has increased to 27.2 percent of all lending in fiscal 1995, more than double the level of 1992, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>&quot;In combination with a strong surge in domestic property prices in the Philippines over the last three years, S&amp;P has concerns that some banks are increasingly vulnerable to a downturn in the property market,&quot; S&amp;P said.  </p>
<p>The banks that are most vulnerable to a deterioration of asset quality in an economic downturn are those that have relaxed credit standards in their traditional markets to compete vigorously for increased market share, moved into new markets and aggressively expanded real estate lending, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>In spite of these problems, S&amp;P said that the major banks are sound in the context of the local climate.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite the high economic risk levels of the Philippines, as indicated by the Republic's BB foreign currency rating, which is commensurate with an emerging market economy, the major local banks are sound in the context of the domestic environment,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6371</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
