<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216061" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian bonds becalmed waiting monthly auction.</title>
<headline>Belgian bonds becalmed waiting monthly auction.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian linear bonds were becalmed in early business on Monday waiting for the monthly OLO auction and with most players already winding down towards the end of the year, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is very, very quiet. What is important in Belgium is the auction of the March 2001 and March 2007 OLO. That is weighting on the market,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;End investors are already long in short-maturity paper and they are hesitant to buy more so the focus is shifting towards the longer end,&quot; another trader said. &quot;But even there they are hesitant.&quot;  </p>
<p>Traders said the wrangling over the weekend as the lira was grudgingly readmitted to the European Union's Exchange Rate Mechanism had little immediate impact on the bond markets.</p>
<p>However, traders said the two days of arguments that forced EU's monetary officials to call in their finance ministers to settle the reentry rate did give a signal to money markets that there would be no soft options for countries bidding to join the bloc's future single currency.</p>
<p>&quot;That is a very important signal. It shows that countries that have tried to manipulate their figures will not be allowed to get away with it,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>Traders said the short-term impact of this would be limited, but they warned that it could effect longer-maturity bonds as the 1998 deadline for qualifying to join the single currency in 1999 neared.</p>
<p>&quot;There could be pressure on the long end,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Traders said there was otherwise little on the horizon to produce a change in the underlying bullish trend of bond markets, with a light correction possible before new buying emerged in the New Year.</p>
<p>The benchmark 2006 OLO was at six percent against Friday's 5.97. The spread over bunds was an unchanged 17 basis points.  </p>
<p>The December futures contract was 15 basis points lower at 120.22.</p>
<p>-- Jeremy Lovell, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
