<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216095" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Adare Printing says optimistic for future.</title>
<headline>Adare Printing says optimistic for future.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ireland's Adare Printing Group said on Monday it was confident in the UK economy and optimistic about the future.</p>
<p>&quot;While the climate for acquisitions is becoming less favourable due to comparatively high ratings in the market, nevertheless, the group still sees some opportunities to add shareholder value in attractive sectors,&quot; Adare said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Board is confident in the UK economy and optimistic about the future,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The group said in a statement that it had continued the growth of recent years.  </p>
<p>Earlier, Adare recorded a 28 percent rise in pre-tax profits for the six months to October 31, 1996, to 5.2 million Irish pounds.</p>
<p>The group said turnover had increased by 60 percent to 54.9 million Irish pounds in the same period.</p>
<p>Adare said the acquisition of Prontaprint Group, Lexicon and Pillings since the interim results of 1995 had combined with strong organic growth in higher margin products and services, and a benign business environment, to deliver significantly increased breadth to the Group's activities and earnings.</p>
<p>&quot;The acquisitions made since the last interim statement are performing well, up to expectations and in line with budget,&quot; Adare said.</p>
<p>Adare said it was developing its strategy of migration to higher value added niche printing and the manufacture or provision of branded products and services.</p>
<p>The company said it was significantly cash generative and had substantial unutilised facilities. -- Dublin Newsroom +353 1 6603377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
