<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216148" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: APEC summit hammering out area's economic future.</title>
<headline>APEC summit hammering out area's economic future.</headline>
<byline>Bill Tarrant</byline>
<dateline>SUBIC BAY, Philippines 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leaders of 18 Asia-Pacific economies, seeking to translate lofty goals for the world's biggest free trade into concrete action, met on Monday to hammer out the economic future of half of humanity.</p>
<p>Against the backdrop of Subic Bay, a former major American naval base, U.S. President Bill Clinton pitched into a lobbying battle to get full APEC backing for a plan to rip away all barriers to trade in information technology by 2000.</p>
<p>The ministers of the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum had earlier given lukewarm endorsement to the plan, but Clinton was looking for &quot;a little more oomph&quot;, according to White House press spokesman Mike McCurry.</p>
<p>Already APEC has scored a triumph with an agreement between Clinton and Chinese President Jiang Zemin to swap visits to each other's capitals, ending an almost decade-long chill.</p>
<p>Now leaders are working on a Manila Action Plan for APEC (MAPA) piecing together a raft of free-trade initiatives by the 18 members to create a single Pacific Rim economy without customs barriers, visa requirements or red tape.</p>
<p>Leaders from Indonesian President Suharto to Papua New Guinea Prime Minister Sir Julius Chan arrived at the summit site in what was once a U.S. officer's club dressed in traditional Filipino Barong shirts woven from silk and pineapple fibre.</p>
<p>Clinton expected the summit to strongly endorse a U.S. plan for a global agreement on free trade in computers, memory chips and telecommunications equipment, a U.S. spokesman said.</p>
<p>An advance copy of a joint declaration to be issued by the summit said leaders called for an accord on information technology to be concluded at the first ministerial meeting of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) in Singapore next month.</p>
<p>Such an agreement &quot;should substantially eliminate tariffs by the year 2000&quot;, the declaration said. But it recognised the need for flexibility in the negotiations.</p>
<p>The copy of the declaration obtained by reporters in advance did not give any more detail. It was not clear whether the statement was still open to further changes.</p>
<p>Washington says information technology trade is worth $500 billion a year, 80 percent of that in the booming Asia-Pacific.</p>
<p>Leftwing activists who had threatened to disrupt the summit with a motorcade of 500 jeepneys -- minibus copies of World War Two U.S. jeeps -- gave up the effort. Leaders retreated from a confrontation with riot police.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the large number of our enemy, we will not sacrifice our bodies, we will not sacrifice our force because that will be suicide,&quot; leftist leader Nathaniel Santiago said.</p>
<p>Opponents of the APEC forum say developing countries are not ready for the rigours of free trade that APEC advocates, and they fear rising unemployment.</p>
<p>The Manila People's Forum on APEC called on APEC leaders to &quot;wake up to the reality that our legacy, our dignity, our culture and our natural world are being drained away instead into the offshore accounts of global robber barons&quot;.</p>
<p>APEC has pledged to abolish all obstacles to trade in developed countries by 2010 and in developing nations by 2020 to create a borderless economy embracing two billion people with 40 percent of global trade and more than half of economic output.</p>
<p>Not all the leaders agreed on how to do it. The United States wants to fling all markets open in a trade free-for-all.</p>
<p>Some of the heads of developing Asian countries, such as Malaysia's Mahathir Mohamad, want to move ahead more gingerly and are chafing at the pressure.</p>
<p>A four-page draft of the declaration called for &quot;freer and non-discriminatory trade in goods and services&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We call on WTO members to build on the process of progressive liberalisation and enhanced transparency we have initiated at APEC,&quot; the draft declaration said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are determined that our efforts at APEC should serve as a catalyst to the liberalisation of the multilateral trading system.&quot;</p>
<p>As well as freeing trade and investment flows, APEC aims to promote technical cooperation in areas like transport, energy, telecommunications and infrastructure development. It also intends to make life easier for businessmen by streamlining regulations on customs, standards and testing.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SUBIC BAY, Philippines"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
