<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216145" id="root" date="1996-11-25" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FEATURE - Axe falls on South Africa farm control boards.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Axe falls on South Africa farm control boards.</headline>
<byline>Nicole Mordant</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sixty years of white control of South Africa's farming sector is ending, leaving it to fend for itself in a world of free market forces.</p>
<p>Milestone legislation passed in parliament last month outlaws statutory agricultural market controls and accepts that market supply and demand is the best method to ensure the efficient allocation of resources.</p>
<p>The Marketing of Agricultural Products Act signals the demise of commodity control boards which have long held powerful sway over the marketing of agricultural products and, at the same time, entrenched white domination over commercial farming.</p>
<p>Established by the state in the 1930s, the all-white boards set out to modernise and strengthen farming after the 1929 Depression hit many farmers, pushing them from their land or forcing them to sub-divide their holdings.</p>
<p>Black farmers, who had already been chased off large tracts of land by the 1913 Land Act, became further marginalised under the boards, forcing most into a subsistence existence.</p>
<p>LITTLE CHANGE FOR BLACK FARMERS</p>
<p>Despite the dismantling of apartheid white-minority rule and 1994 elections which ended 300 years of white domination, little has changed for black farmers most of whom still grow crops just to feed their families.</p>
<p>However, some agricultural sectors, including sugar, are encouraging black smallholders to grow crops for sale.</p>
<p>Boards were given monopoly powers over the distribution of farm products and were funded by statutory levies paid by farmers. Although not directly funded by the state, boards were at times helped out of financial difficulties by the government.</p>
<p>At the peak of control, 21 boards existed.</p>
<p>Since the middle of the 1980s, control boards have begun to feel the heat amid rumblings about market deregulation and as the state increasingly came to their financial rescue.</p>
<p>SOME BOARDS PRE-EMPTED CHANGE</p>
<p>Faced with deregulation pressures, several boards took the initiative to transform themselves before laws compelled them.</p>
<p>The Banana and Chicory Boards were dismantled a few years ago, while the Milk and Meat Boards have mutated into non-interventionist bodies, focusing on research and information dissemination.</p>
<p>According to Johan Willemse, an independent agricultural economist, deregulation has been a slow evolutionary process.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of this started a few years ago...This new act is really the cherry on the cake to formalise what a lot of people were doing,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>OTHER BOARDS WAITING AS LONG AS POSSIBLE</p>
<p>But some boards are holding on until the last minute, taking advantage of the 13-month window the new act gives them before they will be forced to dismantle.</p>
<p>Louis van Staden, general manager of the Wheat Board, one of the bodies with the highest degree of market intervention, said the board will continue to run a single channel market next year.</p>
<p>&quot;At this stage we still have a year's leeway, (and) in that context we do not have formal decisions we can give to the outside world,&quot; van Staden said.</p>
<p>This season's wheat price, which is set by the board, has been criticised by farmers who say they can get more for their product on the open market.</p>
<p>FRUIT BOARD STAYING UNTIL END OF 1997 SEASON</p>
<p>Another strong market interventionist, the Deciduous Fruit Board, said it will remain in existence until the end of the current season in September next year.</p>
<p>The board still runs a monopoly on fruit exports contracting to a sole marketing agent Unifruco.</p>
<p>&quot;We are insisting on a transitional period,&quot; Bokkie Strauss, the board's chief executive told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;It's crucial for the industry so that they can use the transitional period to gear themselves for a freer market environment.&quot;</p>
<p>The Maize Board, which still plays a role in the export of South Africa's biggest commodity is as yet unsure of its continued existence in the new season which starts in May.</p>
<p>MAIZE BOARD SEEKING BLUEPRINT FOR CHANGE</p>
<p>Leon du Plessis, the board's general manager said it will be dismantled before the new season if the industry is able to agree on a blueprint for a future marketing system by then.</p>
<p>Du Plessis, however, cautioned: &quot;I must stress that there is no finality...There are still a lot of discussions between all the role players.&quot;</p>
<p>South Africa's domestic maize market was deregulated in 1995 and the export market partially freed this year when private traders were invited in for the first time. The dual presence of traders and the board has led to confusion and wranglings among industry players.</p>
<p>Like maize, the tobacco industry remains in the dark about its future. The Tobacco Board, which runs a domestic monopoly, last month announced it had dissolved itself but said it was uncertain what the effect of its demise would be.</p>
<p>MEAT BOARD RESHAPING ITSELF</p>
<p>In contrast, the Meat Board has been quick off the mark, last month announcing plans to reshape into a non-profit association. It will continue the board's current functions of controlling industry standards, promotions and an information service.</p>
<p>Pieter Kempen, general manager of the board which left the market in 1993 said: &quot;We have changed over time. When the act came in we were already in line.&quot;</p>
<p>Similarly the Milk Board will have little to change than its organisational structure, as the dairy market has been fully deregulated since 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;The bottom-line is that the new act allows exactly the same services that we offer right now,&quot; said general manager Bertus de Jongh, adding that its main activities were controlling illegal dairy imports and funding research.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-25"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
