<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216546" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: TENNIS-WIMBLEDON NUMBER ONE COURT DUG UP.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-WIMBLEDON NUMBER ONE COURT DUG UP.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Work began on  Tuesday on digging up the turf of Wimbledon's Number One Court in preparation for the demolition of the arena to make way for a new 11,500-capacity stadium.</p>
<p>But although the arena has reached the end of its life after 72 years, the grass will continue to play host to top-class tennis.</p>
<p>On Thursday it is due to be bundled up and taken by lorry to Eastbourne, where it will be laid on Devonshire Park international tennis centre's Number One Court.</p>
<p>A Wimbledon spokesman said: &quot;We wanted the turf to remain in Britain and if it had been sold at auction, then it could have gone to a private bidder from abroad.&quot;</p>
<p>Christopher Gorringe, the All England Lawn Tennis Club's chief executive, added: &quot;We are naturally pleased that this favourite surface will continue to make a lasting contribution to tennis in this country.&quot;</p>
<p>The 100,000 pounds ($165,000) cost of buying and moving the turf, as well as the purchase of some seats and memorabilia from the court, is being met by the Lawn Tennis Association, an insurance company and the Eastbourne local council.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
