<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216530" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-ITALY'S REGGIANA NAME ODDO AS NEW COACH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ITALY'S REGGIANA NAME ODDO AS NEW COACH.</headline>
<dateline>REGGIO EMILIA, Italy 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Francesco Oddo, a Sicilian coach who has never worked with a serie A side before, took over at bottom-of-the-table Reggiana on Tuesday after Romanian Mircea Lucescu was sacked by the Italians.</p>
<p>The club said Oddo, a former coach of serie B sides Avellino, Modena and Pescara, had signed a two-year contract and would lead his first training session on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reggiana were promoted from serie B at the end of last season when current Parma coach Carlo Ancelotti was at the helm. They decided to replace Lucescu on Monday.</p>
<p>The provincial northern club stands out as the only serie A team yet to win a match this season despite having several international stars such as Colombia's Adolfo &quot;The Train&quot; Valencia and Romanian Ioan Sabau.</p>
<p>They have just four points from 10 games and are firmly embedded in the floor of the division with only nine goals to their credit -- the lowest tally in serie A.</p>
<p>Lucescu, who arrived in Italy from Dinamo Bucharest in 1990 when he took over as coach of Pisa, has been dismissed three times in seven years in Italian soccer.</p>
<p>Pisa fired him in 1991 and he moved to Brescia, where he stayed in charge until 1995.</p>
<p>He was the second serie A coach to lose his job this season after Cagliari's Uruguayan Gregorio Perez in October.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="REGGIO EMILIA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
