<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216618" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Winter oil market shrugs off Iraqi crude.</title>
<headline>Winter oil market shrugs off Iraqi crude.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices held steady on Tuesday and recovered from earlier losses as the market took the view that it could absorb Iraqi crude at least during a tight winter supply quarter.</p>
<p>World benchmark Brent crude for January delivery on the International Petroleum Exchange fell to an intra-day low of $22.49 a barrel before bouncing back to trade 21 cents higher at $22.83 a barrel in the afternoon session. It later eased to $22.79.</p>
<p>&quot;January Brent is basically back to where it was 24 hours ago,&quot; a futures broker said, adding that the upward move was a correction driven by concern over heating oil stocks.</p>
<p>January Brent futures fell sharply on Monday after Iraq said it had agreed all conditions of the U.N. limited oil sales deal allowing it to sell $2.0 billion worth of oil over six months to buy food and medicines.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not a big thing any more. It will not make a whole lot of different to global supply and demand,&quot; an oil industry source said, adding that Iraq's return to the market had been factored in for some time.</p>
<p>He said the market had underestimated demand and that was why prices recently rose to a five-year high in October after the Iraq-U.N. oil-for-food deal was postponed in September.</p>
<p>&quot;Demand has been underestimated for the last year or so, and the only reason prices are where they are is because of that,&quot; the industry source said.</p>
<p>Cold weather and low inventories of both crude and heating fuels in consumer countries have made for a tight oil market, allowing OPEC producers to reap the benefit of higher oil prices and turn a blind eye to quota-busters among the 11-member cartel.</p>
<p>Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) oil ministers meet in Vienna on Wednesday to set their production ceiling for the first six months of 1997 amid calls by several members for a rollover.</p>
<p>OPEC raised its ceiling by 800,000 barrels per day (bpd) in June to 25.03 million bpd to absorb the Iraqi crude which was expected to appear in September.</p>
<p>The delay and the subsequent rise in prices has eroded the volume Iraq is likely to export under the price formula agreed with the United Nations for its sales contracts.</p>
<p>The formula prices Iraq's Kirkuk grade at a $1.5 a barrel discount to physical Brent, which on Tuesday was valued at just under $23 a barrel.</p>
<p>An oil industry source said Iraqi crude exported via pipeline to Turkey's Ceyhan terminal would compete with Russian Urals and with Iranian light crudes in the Mediterranean and European markets.</p>
<p>The absence of Iraqi crude from the fourth quarter, coupled with low stocks in consumer countries, led prices to a five-year high in October. The average price for the year for front-month Brent has been $20 a barrel.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					    Nov 26	Nov 25</p>
<p>					   1621 GMT	close</p>
<p>  Dated Brent			   22.89	 22.99</p>
<p> IPE London Brent futures (Jan)   22.79	 22.61</p>
<p> NYMEX light crude futures (Jan)  23.70	 23.45</p>
<p>-- Kate Dourian, London newsroom +44 171 542 4088</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
