<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216709" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dlr eases in late Europe as mark/yen ticks higher.</title>
<headline>Dlr eases in late Europe as mark/yen ticks higher.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar eased from earlier highs in late European trade, pressured by mark gains against the yen and to slipping U.S. asset markets.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark retreated over half a pfennig from an afternoon high of 1.53 marks after being boosted earlier by a weak Swiss franc and softer French franc.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/mark couldn't get through the 1.53 level and when mark/yen turned higher, it became easy to take profits,&quot; said a UK bank dealer. &quot;This late sell-off in the Dow and to a lesser extent in the bonds has also cooled dollar bulls for the moment.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S. stocks reversed an early sharp gain to a 50-point loss in the Dow industrials. Although slightly firmer in late European trade, dealers said the slide helped prompt profit-taking in dollar.</p>
<p>Mark gains against the lira, rising briefly above the 994 lire level in late trade, were also seen adding some pressure to dollar/mark.</p>
<p>Dealers cited renewed political concerns in Italy for the mark's late fillip, particularly talk of a possible general election if Prime Minister Romano Prodi gets embroiled deeper into allegations of abuse of office when on the board of IRI.</p>
<p>The dollar stood at 1.5241/46 marks at 1711 GMT, below a session high of 1.53 marks and above 1.5215/25 late Monday.</p>
<p>Sterling's strength was also seen weighing on the dollar. The pound was steady in late Europe after choppy trade during the UK annual budget statement for 1997/98.</p>
<p>Analysts said the budget measures gave little to add to sterling's current strength but at the same time did not offer much to push it lower by late trade.</p>
<p>Cable was steady in late Europe, trading at $1.6728/38, off a session high of $1.6756 but above $1.6690/00 late Monday.</p>
<p>Sterling/mark was also firm at 2.5525/30 but off an earlier 32-month high of 2.5586 marks and well above late Monday's 2.5385/96 marks.</p>
<p>The dollar was boosted in early trade by a fresh 21-month high against the Swiss franc, touching 1.2964 amid jitters over the Swiss banking sector.</p>
<p>Worries surfaced today after Union Bank of Switzerland planned to take a 3.0 billion Swiss franc special charge to cover domestic credit risk. UBS's addition to Standard and Poor's CreditWatch list also highlighted the depressed Swiss economy.</p>
<p>The dollar against the Swiss franc stood at 1.2920/30 in late Europe against 1.2855/65 on Monday.</p>
<p>The Swiss franc also touched 20-month lows against the mark of 84.84 centimes earlier but settled back to 84.62/64 centimes per mark in late trade from 84.48/54 Monday.</p>
<p>Klaus Baader, senior economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, said aside from the UBS news, there were other factors contributing to the Swiss franc's weakness against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;There is talk that Swiss pension funds are looking to allocate a great deal more of their assets in foreign assets,&quot; Baader said.</p>
<p>The dollar shed some of its gains against the French franc after being boosted earlier by comments from Bank of France monetary policy council member Paul Marchelli calling for French rate cuts as soon as possible. He also said the dollar was overvalued against European currencies.</p>
<p>Eyes now are on the Japanese fourth quarter Tankan survey of business sentiment, due at 2350 GMT today.</p>
<p>The average forecast ranges from minus three to minus two against minus seven in August when the previous survey was done.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen stood at 112.57/62 against 112.68/74 late Monday.</p>
<p>-- Andrew Reierson, London Newsroom +44 171 542 6745</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
