<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216938" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian supreme court rejects opposition appeal.</title>
<headline>Serbian supreme court rejects opposition appeal.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia's supreme court on Tuesday upheld rulings cancelling results of a local election in the capital Belgrade which opposition parties said they had won, state media reported.</p>
<p>The three-party Zajedno coalition slammed the decision as further evidence that the country was controlled solely by the interests of the ruling Socialist party led by President Slobodan Milosevic.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not surprised that the supreme court has again been placed in the service of the ruling party, but we are surprised that Milosevic's regime is in this way causing new conflicts,&quot; Zajedno said in a statement.</p>
<p>The opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition had appealed a decision from a municipal court which annulled the opposition victory in Belgrade.</p>
<p>Local electoral authorities originally confirmed the opposition victory in the Belgrade city council race -- the first opposition victory in the capital since World War Two.</p>
<p>Zajedno lawyers had charged the annulment was illegal and had asked for the supreme court to declare invalid another round of voting scheduled for Wednesday and Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of the above-stated ruling and the decision of the city electoral commission, the third round of voting for certain seats for the city council will take place on Wednesday, November 27,&quot; said a supreme court statement quoted by state news agency Tanjug.</p>
<p>Zajedno commented: &quot;The citizens are rightfully bitter that their will has been annulled and therefore the coalition Zajedno will continue protests in all major towns in Serbia.&quot;</p>
<p>Local courts and electoral commissions have annulled opposition victories in other major towns since the run-off municipal elections were held on November 17.</p>
<p>The annulment has set off a wave of street demonstrations across the country and prompted international criticism of Milosevic's government.</p>
<p>The opposition has announced a boycott of the third round of voting, calling the poll a farce.</p>
<p>Serbian authorities declared a 48-hour campaign blackout before the third round and issued a warning on Tuesday to opposition parties and independent media.</p>
<p>The city electoral commission said opposition protests and media coverage of them were in clear violation of the campaign blackout, which went into effect on Sunday at midnight, Tanjug reported.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
