<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216986" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Ban lifted on Bosnian refugees returning home.</title>
<headline>Ban lifted on Bosnian refugees returning home.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A ban on refugees returning to their homes in a NATO-patrolled, demilitarised zone in Bosnia was lifted on Tuesday, two weeks after it was imposed following gun battles between Moslem refugees and Serb police.</p>
<p>The fighting around the village of Gajevi, northeast of Tuzla, was the most serious in Bosnia since the Dayton peace agreement ended 43 months of war a year ago.</p>
<p>The office of the international community's High Representative for Bosnia, Carl Bildt, lifted the resettlement ban in a letter to Bosnian authorities.</p>
<p>The letter reinstituted a U.N.-approved procedure for returns in what is known as the &quot;Zone of Separation&quot;, (ZOS) a narrow band of former front-line territory stretching more than 600 miles across Bosnia, within which NATO has supreme powers.</p>
<p>NATO said the Moslem refugees had violated this procedure in Gajevi by going into the village before their applications to return had been approved and because they were armed.</p>
<p>The North Atlantic Treaty Organisation has also said that the incident provoked a disproportionate response on the part of Bosnian Serb police, who also brought illegal weapons into the zone and used them.</p>
<p>While tempers may have cooled around Gajevi over the past two weeks, observers say nothing has changed to give Moslem refugees, keen to go their homes on Serb territory in the ZOS and beyond, any reason for optimism.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
