<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="216962" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria delays choosing telecom sale advisor.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria delays choosing telecom sale advisor.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria said on Tuesday it will delay issuing a shortlist of financial houses who bid to advise the cabinet in the sale of 25 percent of the state telecoms company as it is seeking more information on the bidders.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to collect additional information for all of the 18 contenders as they all have obvious qualities and experience and are solid investment institutions,&quot; Deputy Prime Minister Doncho Konakchiev told a news conference.</p>
<p>He said the cabinet could not take a decision on the basis of the available data and needed more time to gather detailed information and to analyse it.</p>
<p>Konakchiev said he had written to the contenders on Friday asking them to provide additional information to the cabinet within a week.</p>
<p>&quot;The procedure has been delayed as the cabinet wants to take its decision on the grounds of maximum information clarity as the partial privatisation of BTC is a very important and strategically sensitive deal,&quot; Konakchiev added.</p>
<p>The cabinet is expected to shortlist the top six banks among the 18 bidders. The World Bank, which is funding part of the BTC sale procedure, must then approve them.</p>
<p>The list includes Investment Bank Austria, Union Bank of Switzerland, and Vienna's Creditanstalt Investment Bank AG together with Sofia's Creditanstalt Bulinvest EOOD.</p>
<p>A consortium of Bankers Trust, Charterhouse Bank, KPMG and Squire Sanders &amp; Dempsey is also bidding. Another consortium is Raiffeisen Investment AG and Lazard Houses.</p>
<p>Other bidders are Deloitte &amp; Touche, Salomon Brothers, Swiss Bank Corp, Merill Lynch International, Warburg, Nat West Markets, Schroders, Deutsche Morgan Grenfell, BZW, Daiwa Europe Ltd, Societe Generale Finance Developpement, Goldman Sachs International and Freshfields.</p>
<p>Officials have said the tender for the BTC partial sale would be called at the end of May or at the beginning of June.</p>
<p>-- Galina Sabeva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
