<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217062" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Nov 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Nov 26.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Prime Minister Zhan Videnov said the cabinet and the central bank had accepted an International Monetary Fund proposal for a currency board as the only way to stabilise Bulgaria's financial system.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Centre for Mass Privatisation will open on Tuesday the 400 000 individual bids for the first tender for voucher privatisation, a senior official said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's court is expected to decide in December on an insolvency suit filed by the central bank against four of the commercial banks placed in receivership on September 23, a court official said.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- Shareholders of state-owned Biochim bank are expected to vote a 14.871 billion lev capital increase at a meeting on Tuesday. The bank's capital now is 1.885 billion levs.</p>
<p>-- The Confederation of Independent Trade Unions expects inflation of 300 percent for 1996, a senior union official said.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's leading financial experts and bankers said they supported the introduction of a currency board at a meeting with Prime Minister Zhan Videnov.</p>
<p>The cabinet should also seek a reduction of Bulgaria's foreign debt from its government creditors in the Paris Club, an expert said.</p>
<p>-- A further fall of the lev against the dollar is not needed for introduction of a currency board, an IMF official said.</p>
<p>-- The Bulgarian Telecommunication Company (BTC) plans to raise its rates by 40 percent effective from December 1, to compensate for losses from the fall of the lev against the dollar in the last two weeks, a BTC senior official said.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's presidential-elect Petar Stoyanov said he would use his powers to investigate the murder of Bulgarian writer Georgi Markov in 1978 in London.</p>
<p>-- Domestic debt figures in Bulgaria's 1996 budget need to be revised, Finance Minister Dimitar Kostov said. The budget has already been updated twice this year.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom +3592 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
