<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217073" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Nov 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Nov 26.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 2440 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Free Democrat President Ivan Peto addressed an open letter to Prime Minister Gyula Horn on Monday, in response to Horn's letter of congratulations to Peto on Sunday. In the letter he said proposals linked to governing should be made public following consultations betweenn the two governing coalition parties.</p>
<p>- Parliament began a general debate on amendments to the bill on social administration and care.</p>
<p>- Government spokesman Elemer Kiss said that Welfare Minister Gyorgy Szabo is to quit his post at the end of November.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- The parliamentary group of the Socialists decided Monday that the bill on MPs' possible conflicts of interest should cover business interests acquired since the 1994 elections.</p>
<p>- Jozsef Meruk, the Socialist Party's candidate for the vacant post of general director of the Hungarian News Agency MTI, declined his nomination.</p>
<p>- According to reports, two ministerial posts were offered Monday to the Democratic Federation of Hungarians in Romania.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- A new system of electricity prices will be introduced from July 1997, the Energetics Advocacy Council decided yesterday. Separate prices will be paid for consumption in the two peak periods.</p>
<p>- The Budapest Stock Exchange council yesterday suspended trading in the shares of the refrigeration company Goldsun.</p>
<p>NEPSZABADSAG</p>
<p>- Foreign Minister Laszlo Kovacs met Saudi Arabian Oil Minister Ali bin Ibrahim an-Naimi in Riyadh on Monday to discuss questions of cooperation in the oil and mining industries.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Hungarian exports to Britain have increased dynamically to over $400 million in the first nine months of this year, said Hungarian trade councilor in London Jeno Hamori.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- The new act on customs tariffs, introduced in April, will pour additional revenues of HUF 50 billion into the state budget this year.</p>
<p>- Hungary's revenues from tourism are forecast to come to $2.1-2.2 billion this year, 25-30 per cent more than in 1995.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Investment consultants Merrill Lynch have recommended the plastics manufacturer Pannonplast Rt. to long-term investors. ING Barings opts for the chemicals firm BorsodChem.</p>
<p>- After a capital increase by open share issue, the</p>
<p>securities company Questor Rt. plans to have its shares listed</p>
<p>on the Budapest Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- US Ambassador to Hungary Donald Blinken met the mayors of Taszar and Kaposujlak on Monday at the air base of US peacekeeping forces near Taszar.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Port Rt., the owner of the brokerage firm Co-Nexus Ertekhaz, whose operations were suspended following allegations of mishandling state funds, has declared itself bankrupt.</p>
<p>- Leaders of Graboplast suspect a conspiracy aimed at giving the firm a bad name, said company representatives after authorities found toxic materials in a Graboplast truck.</p>
<p>- Primagaz and the gas trading firms Total and Shell have been putting up to 20 percent less gas in household cylinders sold to the public than advertised on the containers, the Consumer Protection Authorities has established.</p>
<p>@</p>
<p>- Former Turkish prime minister Mesut Yilmaz was struck in the face by an unidentified, possibly foreign man in the lounge of the Budapest Hilton Hotel on Sunday.</p>
<p>			  -- Budapest newsroom (36-1) 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
