<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217179" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Mexico City to raise '97 property tax up to 23 pct.</title>
<headline>Mexico City to raise '97 property tax up to 23 pct.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico City authorities are planning to raise property taxes by a maximum OF 23 percent in 1997, the city's Finance Minister said Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The upper limit will be 23 percent, but we are still working on bringing that level down,&quot; Javier Beristain told radio network Radio Red. He went on to stress it would be &quot;around 20 percent.&quot;</p>
<p>Property taxes for homes or businesses are the number one form of income for the city government, followed by income taxes coming from salaries. Water payments are the third largest income source for the city.  </p>
<p>The increases could have an impact Mexico's inflation rate in 1997, given that owners could pass on much or all of tax increments to people renting properties, which would show up in the national consumer price index.</p>
<p>Beristain said reports that property taxes would rise in scales, from 12 to 75 percent, depending on the value of the home or business, were not true.</p>
<p>&quot;That option has been completely and totally thrown out,&quot; he said, explaining it had been an alternative under discussion by city authorities, but had been discarded in favor of the single percentage increase for all properties.  </p>
<p>Inflation over the past 12-month-period thorugh October was about 29 percent.</p>
<p>The Mexico City media reported Tuesday that plans were to implement increments scaled to the value of houses, with the middle class worse hit by the proposal.</p>
<p>City legislator Dolores Padierna told Radio Red Tuesday that plans were to increase property taxes by 75 percent for those homes worth between 200,000 and 380,000 pesos.</p>
<p>Padierna said lower class home owners would see property taxes increase 12 percent for homes valued around 70,000 pesos. For weathly residents, Padierna said property taxes would rise less drastically, saying a house valued at 8,000,000 pesos would see taxes rise 22 percent.</p>
<p>--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom +525 7289530.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
