<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217237" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea sends home N.Korean sailor, seeks talks.</title>
<headline>S.Korea sends home N.Korean sailor, seeks talks.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea sent home a rescued North Korean sailor on Tuesday and awaited a response from the communist state to a renewed call for peace talks.</p>
<p>Military officials said the sailor, Chung Kwang-son, private first class in North Korea's navy, was escorted by United Nations Command representatives and handed over to North Korean officers at the border village of Panmunjom.</p>
<p>Once on North Korean soil, Chung raised his arms and shouted &quot;Hooray, Hooray&quot; several times before bursting into tears as he was embraced by senior communist officers and his colleagues who travelled to the border to meet him, witnesses said.</p>
<p>North Korean Colonel Park Im-su decorated Chung with a badge of North Korean leader Kim Jong-il on his lapel, they said.</p>
<p>Park also thanked his U.N. Command counterpart Colonel Ashton Ormes for sending Chung home on humanitarian grounds.</p>
<p>Chung, 19, was picked up by a South Korean maritime police vessel and taken to the western port city of Inchon on Saturday after his boat drifted into Southern waters in a storm.</p>
<p>Chung's return was the first goodwill gesture by Seoul towards Pyongyang since already-tense relations between the two Koreas worsened after a Northern submarine landed 26 agents on the South Korean coast in September.</p>
<p>All but two of the 26 are known to be dead. One has been captured and another is still at large.</p>
<p>Pyongyang's official Korea Central News Agency (KCNA) said Seoul had tried to persuade Chung to defect to the South.</p>
<p>&quot;Though I was alone in the enemy's area, I fought with revolutionary faith and indomitable will with belief only in the respected general Kim Jong-il and therefore was able to come back to the socialist fatherland,&quot; KCNA quoted Chung as saying.</p>
<p>Two days earlier, U.S. President Bill Clinton and South Korean leader Kim Young-sam urged the North &quot;to take acceptable steps to resolve the submarine incident, reduce tension and avoid such provocations in the future&quot;.</p>
<p>At a meeting of Asia-Pacific leaders in the Philippines, Clinton and Kim also renewed an invitation to North Korea to join four-nation peace talks, which would also involve China.</p>
<p>The two leaders jointly proposed the peace talks in April to discuss replacing the truce that ended the 1950-53 Korean War with a lasting peace.</p>
<p>Seoul officials said South Korea's Kim had told Clinton that once the North agreed to talks, the next task would be to seek an apology from Pyongyang over the submarine incursion and assurances that such an incident would not be repeated.</p>
<p>South Korea had previously said it would freeze all contacts and assistance to North Korea until it apologises for the submarine incursion.</p>
<p>North Korea says the submarine incident was accident and demands the return of the captured man and the bodies of killed crewmembers.</p>
<p>South Korean analysts said Pyongyang was expected to explain its stand, particularly on the four-nation peace talks and its willingness to seek detente with the South, to U.S. Congressman Bill Richardson.</p>
<p>Richardson flew from Tokyo to Pyongyang on Monday in hopes of securing the release of American detainee Evan Carl Hunziker, who was arrested on August 24 after crossing the Yalu River from China into North Korea.</p>
<p>Richardson, a Democrat from New Mexico close to the Clinton administration, postponed his planned Tuesday departure by one day without giving a reason, U.S. officials said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
