<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217280" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Low risk seen as HK stocks soar on low volatility.</title>
<headline>Low risk seen as HK stocks soar on low volatility.</headline>
<byline>Kathleen Kearney</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The current bull run of Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index has been less volatile than previous rallies, offering investors a lower risk investment environment, brokers and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen a fairly steady uptrend in the index and as a result average volatility is below what we saw one year ago,&quot; said Ted Chen, technical analyst at Technical Data Inc.</p>
<p>Comparing the daily changes in the closing level of the Hang Seng Index, the Hong Kong market's historical volatility was at a three-month low, Chen said.</p>
<p>Volatility falls when the market is trending -- moving at a steady rate up, down or sideways. Rapid movements in any direction over a short period of time raises volatility and the risk to investors.</p>
<p>Volatility is a historical analysis and cannot be used to forecast the direction of the index, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;By volatility we are measuring or looking for the expected daily move of the index or a stock,&quot; said Richard Chow, head of derivatives trading at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatility of 16 percent, for example, would be equivalent to a one percent per day move in the index,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Many technical analysts use a 200-day year, roughly equivalent to 16 days of trading a month, when making their calculations.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index has risen from 10,073.39 at the end of December 1995 to 13,485.33 at Tuesday's close, a gain of 33.9 percent. It has gained 18.9 percent in the last three months.</p>
<p>But despite the index's recent record-breaking run, the climb has been steady and that means low volatility.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatility in Hong Kong has fallen steadily from 34 percent in January 1995 to less than 13 percent now, except for a jump up to 24 percent during the market's mini-slump in March,&quot; said Calvin Chan, quantitative analyst at NAVA SC Securities.</p>
<p>The story was quite different during the market's sharp advance in late 1993. From April to October that year, just prior to the index's leap, historical volatility ranged from 18 to 20 percent, said NAVA's Chan.</p>
<p>&quot;But then the index jumped 64 percent in about three months, and volatility surged to 34 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>One reason for low volatility now might be the increase in the supply of derivative products, including covered warrants, stock options and index futures, analysts said.</p>
<p>These instruments allow investors to hedge against an adverse move in the underlying asset, rather than sell the stock or a portfolio of stocks.</p>
<p>Chow pointed out that the volume of futures contracts now traded is about five times what it was throughout 1993.</p>
<p>Hong Kong is not the only market to see a decline in volatility, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been a phenomenon of the past 18 months. Whatever asset category you are looking at, volatility has imploded,&quot; said Joost Pielage, director of Amstel Securities.</p>
<p>The volatility of Tokyo's Nikkei stock average has fallen to 12-13 percent from the mid-20s, and that of the Amsterdam index was at single digits, said Pielage.</p>
<p>&quot;Volatility in many currency markets has also fallen to about five percent to six percent in 1996 compared with the double digits in 1995,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The general decline in volatility might be due to the greater synchronisation of world economies, said analysts.</p>
<p>Higher price levels do not necessarily lead to higher volatility, they said.</p>
<p>But as the Hang Seng Index heads further into unexplored territory, analysts are unsure whether the decline in volatility is permanent, and many are warily expecting a return to previous trends in market fluctuations.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6933</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
