<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217332" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai new PM to name Amnuay finance minister.</title>
<headline>Thai new PM to name Amnuay finance minister.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Newly-appointed Thai Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh said on Tuesday he would name former banker Amnuay Viravan finance minister and deputy premier in charge of economic affairs.</p>
<p>Chavalit told foreign journalists in his first interview since his appointment that he would give top priority to boosting Thailand's slowing economy.  </p>
<p>&quot;My top priority is the economy. I see my role as providing leadership ... to accomplish this I shall bring together the best talents in the country,&quot; Chavalit said.</p>
<p>During his election campaign Chavalit had pledged to appoint an economic team made up of several non-elected experts to help reverse the economic slowdown. Private economists project that the Thai economy will expand at a 10-year low of six to seven percent this year.</p>
<p>Chavalit said Narongchai Akrasanee, chairman of General Finance and Securities Plc, will take over the commerce portfolio, and Somphob Amatayakul, president of Saha Union Plc, will be named deputy industry minister.</p>
<p>Chavalit said he and his New Aspiration Party had solved all the major problems with the second-biggest coalition member, the Chart Pattana Party, regarding the sharing of cabinet positions. Chavalit and his cabinet should be sworn in on December 1, one of his top aides said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
