<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217322" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China dissidents on trial for counter-revolution.</title>
<headline>China dissidents on trial for counter-revolution.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A court in central China began a trial on Tuesday of three pro-democracy activists on charges of counter-revolutionary propaganda and incitement, court officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;The trial began this morning,&quot; an official of the Intermediate People's Court in Hefei, capital of Anhui province, said by telephone.</p>
<p>The official declined to say if the trial of Shen Liangqing, Ma Lianggang and Huang Xiuming had been adjourned or had ended or when the court would deliver its verdict.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a fairly unusual case,&quot; the official said. He declined to give further details.</p>
<p>The New York-based watchdog Human Rights in China said on Monday the trial of the Anhui dissidents was the latest step in an official crackdown that has seen many key figures in China's tiny pro-democracy movement vanish into prison or detention.</p>
<p>There was little doubt about the likely result of the proceedings against Shen, Ma and Huang, all of whom had been detained at least once since they took part in an ill-fated campaign for more democracy in 1989, the group said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although they must go for trial... it has already been decided that they are guilty and must be punished,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>All three dissidents were currently unemployed, the group said. Shen was formerly a government official, Huang is a company manager and Ma used to be a student.</p>
<p>The evidence against the three stemmed from articles written and distributed in 1991, and for which all had already been detained for more than a year, Human Rights in China said.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, a Beijing court took just 10 minutes to reject the appeal of leading dissident Wang Dan and uphold his 11-year prison sentence for subversion.</p>
<p>The trial and failed appeal of the former student leader were part of a series of crushing blows delivered by authorities to China's small band of political dissenters.</p>
<p>China dismisses foreign criticism of its human rights record as interference in its internal affairs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
