<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217315" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: U.S. firms unimpressed by Thai tax treaty.</title>
<headline>U.S. firms unimpressed by Thai tax treaty.</headline>
<byline>James Mclean</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. and Thai leaders hailed a bilateral treaty to avoid double taxation signed on Tuesday but American company executives expected to reap few immediate benefits from the long awaited agreement.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton, in Thailand for a 27-hour visit, and caretaker Thai Prime Minister Banharn Silpa-archa witnessed the signing of the treaty, which received a lukewarm welcome by some American executives.</p>
<p>The agreement will spare U.S. and Thai companies being taxed twice on profits earned in both countries.</p>
<p>Clinton said the treaty, which took the two countries more than a decade to negotiate, &quot;opens a new era of trade and investment between Thailand the United States... today the doors of opportunity have been opened a little wider.&quot;</p>
<p>Banharn said the agreement would cut the operating costs of American firms doing business in Thailand.</p>
<p>American executives, however, said they did not expect their firms to pay substantially lower taxes due to the treaty although it might help them save some administrative costs.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see it making a vast difference to American companies though it will relieve some of the administrative burden,&quot; said Michael Perine, Chase Manhattan Bank's Asian tax manager.</p>
<p>He said the treaty's tax benefits were limited as many American multinational firms doing business in Thailand have operated for years through subsidiaries in third countries which already had double tax avoidance treaties with Thailand.</p>
<p>U.S. embassy officials said the agreement was similar in scope to Thai treaties with other countries that reduced, but did not remove, witholding taxes on revenues earned from royalties, dividends and services.</p>
<p>They expected the treaty to boost bilateral trade, which was worth about $18 billion in 1995. The United States is Thailand's largest export market.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't expect to see a surge of U.S. activity in Thailand. There are other more tax-friendly sites in the region, such as Singapore, though it's good news if you're here,&quot; said the head of an American machinery manufacturer.</p>
<p>The treaty signed on Tuesday will not go into effect until U.S. and Thai legislators ratify it.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to wait another one and a half years for it to come into affect, so we are not exactly jumping up and down with joy yet, though it will benefit us when it does,&quot; said George Simpson, finance director at Du Pont's Conoco Thailand Ltd unit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
