<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217302" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea seen posting drop in electronics exports.</title>
<headline>S.Korea seen posting drop in electronics exports.</headline>
<byline>Yoo Choon-sik</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's electronics industry is expected to post its first drop in exports in 14 years due to a plunge in international memory chip prices, industry officials and analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They predicted the slump would continue well into next year when chip prices might start to pick up.</p>
<p>&quot;I see a recovery in the chip business starting in around the second quarter of next year,&quot; said Namuh Rhee, head of research at Dongbang Peregrine Securities.</p>
<p>The Electronics Industries Association of Korea predicted this year's electronics exports would fall 4.4 percent to $41.67 billion from $43.59 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Electronics exports, the engine of the nation's rapid growth over the past several decades, posted average annual growth of 27.6 percent between 1982 and 1995, the association said.</p>
<p>&quot;The slump in DRAM exports was the direct and the biggest cause for the poor electronics exports,&quot; said Chung Jin-woo, head of the association's trade department.</p>
<p>The international spot price for a 16-megabit dynamic random access memory (DRAM) chip, the most widely used memory chip, has fallen to between $7 and $8 from around $50 late last year.</p>
<p>Analysts predicted memory chip exports, which make up 30 percent of the nation's electronics exports, would fall to around $9.3 billion this year from $12.6 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>The slump would directly affect overall exports, analysts said. More than a third of South Korea's exports come from the electronics industry.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy heavily relies on exports and the weak DRAM price is the biggest factor behind slowing exports. So we can easily say the whole economy depends on the DRAM business,&quot; said Jeon Woo-jong, an analyst at Dongwon Securities.</p>
<p>The trade ministry forecast this year's export growth would slow to around four percent from a 30.3 percent rise in 1995, also citing the slump in memory chip sales.</p>
<p>&quot;Earlier we forecast this year's exports at $142 billion but now the figures are seen at around $130 billion,&quot; said an official at the ministry's export department.</p>
<p>Last year, South Korea's customs-cleared exports totalled $125.06 billion.</p>
<p>A Federation of Korean Industries survey showed exports by the 30 largest conglomerates were expected to grow a mere nine percent this year against a 36.4 percent rise in 1995.</p>
<p>The government has said the sluggish exports would directly lead to a slowdown in gross domestic product growth. It has predicted real GDP growth will slow to around seven percent this year from nine percent in 1995.</p>
<p>The association said electronics exports fell more than 18 percent to $3.55 billion in October from $4.34 billion in the same month of 1995.</p>
<p>For the first 10 months of this year, electronics exports were down two percent to $34.22 billion from $34.9 billion in the year-earlier period.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
