<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217479" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Simpson says he was battered by Nicole.</title>
<headline>Simpson says he was battered by Nicole.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA MONICA, Calif. 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are excerpts from Tuesday's testimony by O.J. Simpson, his third day on the witness stand.</p>
<p>Questioning the former football star in his civil wrongful death trial were plantiffs' attorneys Michael Brewer and John Kelly.</p>
<p>On why he pleaded no contest to a spousal abuse charge stemming from an altercation with ex-wife Nicole Brown Simpson in 1989:</p>
<p>&quot;The totality of my intent was that Nicole was not going to testify. Nicole, as you may have seen on national television from her mother, she was just as much responsible as I was, and I didn't think we should be in a courtroom testifying what went on, so I took full responsibility.&quot;</p>
<p>On whether he considered himself a battered husband, as he said in the suicide note read by his friend Bob Kardashian on June 17, the day of the slow-speed Bronco chase:</p>
<p>&quot;I meant to convey that, at the time, I felt battered.&quot;</p>
<p>On whether there were other times he considered himself a battered husband or boyfriend on other occasions:</p>
<p>&quot;Numerous times after this (the 1989 incident), and I kept a log of it.&quot;</p>
<p>(During therapy) &quot;We both (he and Nicole) came to the conclusion we were both abusive ... sometimes it was only verbal.&quot;</p>
<p>And:</p>
<p>&quot;The physical side of it was initiated by Nicole. I felt I should still reacted differently than I did ... I was wrong in the way I reacted. At the time I felt like a battered husband, yes.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked who the &quot;real O.J.&quot; referred to in his suicide note was:</p>
<p>&quot;I like to think I was the guy who everyone who had a problem, including Nicole -- when Nicole had real serious issues she was the person she could come to ... my philosophy was treating everybody ... do unto others. I always had time for people, when Nicole, family and friends had problems, they came to me.&quot;</p>
<p>On why he didn't mention outrage against the killers of Nicole Brown Simpson and Ron Goldman in his suicide note:</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't know who was responsible. I knew it wasn't me.&quot;</p>
<p>On whether he hit Nicole while she was on the phone with a 911 operator during the 1989 incident:</p>
<p>&quot;I was very, very physical in getting her out of the bedroom and I got her out of the bedroom, but I was very physical.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I did not hit her, but I certainly was very physical with her.&quot;</p>
<p>On how often he called Nicole Brown Simpson's mother, Juditha Brown, during the couple's break-up:</p>
<p>&quot;Vitually daily. I talked to her for hours and hours.&quot;</p>
<p>On his conversations with Juditha Brown:</p>
<p>&quot;Judy was continually telling me about her concerns for Nicole, just like Nicole's friends were.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked by Kelly if he murdered Nicole Brown Simpson:</p>
<p>&quot;That's absolutely false.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked by Kelly if he murdered Ron Goldman:</p>
<p>&quot;That's absolutely wrong.&quot;</p>
<p>On whether he noticed cuts on the fingers of his left hand while on a flight to Chicago just hours after the murders:</p>
<p>&quot;It's not anything I had on my mind.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA MONICA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
