<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217461" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Mid-West power prices ease in quiet trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. Mid-West power prices ease in quiet trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wholesale spot electricity prices for the U.S. Mid-West were mostly lower Tuesday in quiet trade ahead of some warmer weather and weakening holiday demand, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Tough winter cold was expected to ease in northern states, reaching highs above the freezing level Wednesday. Winter cold was again forecast to move into the area however from December 1 to 5.</p>
<p>Spot trade was said to be fairly thin through the Mid-West, with many traders planning to take Wednesday off ahead of the U.S. Thanksgiving Day holiday.</p>
<p>In the Mid-Continent Area Power Pool (MAPP), peak non-firm next day power deals for Wednesday delivery were pegged lower with talk at $25.00-27.00 from $27.50-29.50 per megawatt hour (MWh) on Monday, the brokers and marketers said.</p>
<p>Many traders were sewing up deals through to the end of the holiday weekend at $15.00-18.00 per MWh.</p>
<p>Off-peak non-firm MAPP power deals were notionally pegged steady in the $12.00-14.00 range, the sources said.</p>
<p>In the Mid-American Interpool Network (MAIN) peak, non-firm power for Wednesday delivery was pegged higher at $27.00-31.00 from $25.00-27.00 on Monday, again with few 16-hour deals being done.</p>
<p>MAIN power through to the end of the weekend was also trading at $15.00-16.00 per MWh.</p>
<p>MAIN off peak power was said to be steady at $12.00-14.00.</p>
<p>Peak, non-firm electricity prices in the East Central Area Reliability Coordination Agreement (ECAR) for Wednesday delivery were assessed at $25.00-27.00 from $27.00-28.00 on Monday, the sources said.</p>
<p>Off-peak next-day ECAR power was notionally assessed steady at $13.00-15.00.</p>
<p>December peak ECAR was talked steady at $22.00-23.00, with January/February ECAR also assessed steady at $23.00-24.00 per MWh.</p>
<p>Peak non-firm power prices in the Southwest Power Pool (SPP) for Wednesday delivery were talked higher at $27.00-29.00, the sources said.</p>
<p>Off-peak prices throughout SPP were notionally said to be steady in the $13.00-15.00 area.</p>
<p>December SPP was assessed lower at $24.00-26.50 from $25.00-27.00 on Monday, while January/February was pegged at $27.00-27.50 per MWh.</p>
<p>--Chris Reese, New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1627</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
