<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217462" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Disney film could hurt China expansion. [CORRECTED 00:10 GMT 27/11]</title>
<headline>Disney film could hurt China expansion. [CORRECTED 00:10 GMT 27/11]</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>(Corrects the spelling of the Dalai Lama from 'Dali Lama' throughout the text.)</p>
<p>By Jerry Dubrowski</p>
<p>Walt Disney Co., faced with the difficult task of balancing its wholesome image as home to Mickey Mouse against the changing tastes of the commercial world, is certainly no stranger to controversy.</p>
<p>But a new film about the life of the Dalai Lama could prove to be more than a headache for Disney Chairman Michael Eisner.</p>
<p>According to published reports, the Burbank, Calif.-based entertainment giant, which operates television stations, movie studios and theme parks around the world, has come under fire from Chinese officials for producing a Martin Scorsese film called &quot;Kundun&quot; about the life of the Dalai Lama, the religious leader of Tibet. Chinese officials have accused the Dalai Lama of stirring up separtist sentiment in the Himalayan region.</p>
<p>The New York Times Tuesday said China has told Disney executives it would be unhappy if the film was made, indicating Disney's other business plans could be affected by the film.</p>
<p>Disney officials declined to comment on the controversy but industry analysts said a Disney decision to release the film could have major implications.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think they make a lot of money in China now, but China could turn into an enormous market for them in the future,&quot; said Wertheim Schroder analyst David Londoner. &quot;Do they want to jeopardise that?&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, like most Hollywood studios, Disney wants to expand into Asia, particularly China, where demand for U.S. products is high.</p>
<p>Disney's new president, Michael Ovitz, has travelled extensively to Asia in an effort to boost Disney's profile there and discuss plans for a possible theme park.</p>
<p>But such plans could easily disintegrate if officials in China are angered over Disney's involvement in the film.</p>
<p>Industry experts said Disney could opt to withdraw from the project, and suffer a modest loss on it, but such a move could anger many free speech advocates in Hollywood's creative community.</p>
<p>The uproar over &quot;Kundun&quot; is not the first time Disney has run into trouble with one of its films. Last summer, a number of religious groups launched a boycott against Disney to protest the release of the controversial film &quot;The Priest&quot;, which chronicles the struggles of a gay cleric. The film was released by Disney's Miramax unit.</p>
<p>In 1994, the company was forced to abandon a proposed &quot;Disney's America&quot; theme park in northern Virginia after historians and environmentalists opposed the project.</p>
<p>Even something as innocent as &quot;The Lion King&quot;, an animated blockbuster that has generated more than $1 billion in profits for Disney, has come under fire from some viewers who claim to see the word &quot;sex&quot; spelled out in a dust cloud.</p>
<p>Analysts said Disney may ultimately try to reach a compromise that would not jeopardise its expansion plans.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that this is a picture that Michael Eisner will go to the wall over,&quot; one expert said. &quot;This is not McCarthyism. This is a business decision.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
