<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217681" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German public broadcasters plan digital offensive.</title>
<headline>German public broadcasters plan digital offensive.</headline>
<byline>William Boston</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>German public broadcasters on Tuesday outlined plans to offer digital television programming next year using open decoder technology that could put a dent in the pay TV ambitions of their commercial television rivals.</p>
<p>Germany's huge public TV networks, ARD and ZDF, squeezed into a corner by media giants Bertelsmann AG and Bavarian mogul Leo Kirch, will offer viewers all of the technical wizardry of digital television, but at no extra charge.</p>
<p>Tired of waiting for Germany's media titans to settle their bitter dispute over the basic technology, public broadcasters have won the support of the electronics industry to get digital TV out to the public soon and open the market.</p>
<p>Officials from both networks told a conference on digital television in Cologne that a group of companies including Sony, Grundig and Panasonic plan to market open decoders that would make free digital television possible.</p>
<p>The main difference between the open decoder and the one used by Kirch's DF1 will be that it will only decode TV signals, but not include a so-called conditional access system that restricts access to programming for paying customers only.</p>
<p>&quot;The box will offer all of the aspects of digital programming but it will not contain a conditional access system,&quot; said Christian Blankenburg, ARD programme director.</p>
<p>The open box will probably cost no more than 500 marks ($328) and could even be included as part of TV sets to be unveiled by the industry at the Berlin broadcasting exhibition in August.</p>
<p>It will also be made in such a way as to allow pay TV operators later to plug a conditional access component into the main box, the way it is now possible to install a CD-Rom drive into a standard PC, allowing pay TV without an extra decoder.</p>
<p>The new development is a blow to Kirch's DF1 digital pay TV channel. DF1 says it has over 10,000 subscribers, far short of its goal of 200,000 by the end of the year.</p>
<p>But it could be a major breakthrough for so-called free TV, advertising-financed networks like RTL, SAT1 and Pro7, who could now consider adding digital features to their programme.</p>
<p>This would come as a boon to Bertelsmann, whose TV merger with Cie. Luxembourgeoise de Telediffusion (CLT) makes it Europe's largest advertising-based television broadcaster.</p>
<p>Blankenburg dismissed press reports that ARD was planning to offer pay TV. While the Bavarian Broadcasting Company was in favour of doing this, most of the other ten companies that make up the ARD network have blocked such plans.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no consensus within ARD for pay TV,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Carl-Eugen Eberle, ZDF's legal adviser, said if the public broadcasters wanted to offer pay TV they would first need to get the blessing of Germany's 16 state legislatures, who must approve new national programming for ARD and ZDF.</p>
<p>&quot;It also creates a problem because it makes it difficult for us to justify the mandatory fees to the public,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ARD alone rakes in nearly 10 billion marks a year from monthly fees it charges the public to finance its programming, making it one of the largest media organisations in the world.</p>
<p>Public broadcasters plan to migrate their entire programme onto separate digital platforms on the Astra satellite network and include on-screen electronic programme guides.</p>
<p>With ARD's system, viewers will be able to place electronic &quot;bookmarks&quot; on news stories during the evening news programme that will launch a menu with background information about that subject to be viewed later.</p>
<p>It will also offer near-video-on-demand, making it possible for viewers to choose to see a film nearly whenever they want.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom, 49 228 26097150 ($ = 1.526 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I9741102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
