<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217625" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Russia settles with France on tsarist debt.</title>
<headline>Russia settles with France on tsarist debt.</headline>
<byline>Irwin Arieff</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia agreed on Tuesday to pay off French holders of tsarist debt issued before 1917, settling a dispute that had blocked trade in a new Russian bond in France.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe told a news conference that the accord, reached in talks in Paris with visiting Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, required Moscow to pay $400 million to some 400,000 investors who have held onto the bonds.</p>
<p>He said the money would be paid out over a period of years. Asked how many years, Juppe responded, &quot;several&quot;.</p>
<p>He and Chernomyrdin added that it would be a complex and time-consuming task to determine who was eligible for the money and how much each would be paid.</p>
<p>The amount is a tiny fraction of the 140 to 160 billion francs ($27 to $31 billion) claimed by holders of the tsarist bonds, mostly in unpaid interest built up over nearly 80 years.</p>
<p>The association of Russian debt holders in France promptly issued a statement denouncing the accord as &quot;merely symbolic&quot;.</p>
<p>But Juppe insisted it was &quot;the best I felt we could reach.&quot;</p>
<p>Moscow had earlier settled smaller debt disputes with investors in Britain, the United States, Canada and Switzerland.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin, on a two-day visit to France, had said before leaving Moscow that Russia would pay the debt run up by its tsarist government before and during World War One and repudiated by the Soviet Union after the communist revolution of 1917.</p>
<p>The row over the debt had marred Russia's return to international capital markets last week with a $1.0 billion Eurobond, its first debt offering since the 1917 revolution.</p>
<p>France banned trading in the Eurobond pending settlement of the compensation issue.</p>
<p>The dispute was also seen as an obstacle to Russia joining the powerful Paris Club of government creditors, which France chairs, a move that would allow it to negotiate the return of Soviet-era debts owed to Moscow, mainly by developing countries.</p>
<p>Following the signing of the tsarist debt accord, both Juppe and Chernomyrdin said they hoped for success soon in talks allowing Moscow to participate in the Paris Club.</p>
<p>Some 1.2 million French investors bought Russian bonds prior to 1917 to fund projects like the Trans-Siberian railway.</p>
<p>The Soviet refusal to meet the obligations of its tsarist predecessor left savers holding virtually worthless, if attractively printed, paper.</p>
<p>Russia has argued that any liability for Tsarist-era debt must be offset against the seizure in the West of Russian assets, which were used to help fight the Communists.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin, who has been virtually running Russia while President Boris Yeltsin convalesces from heart bypass surgery on November 5, also held talks on Tuesday with conservative French President Jacques Chirac.</p>
<p>Chernomyrdin said afterwards he had been &quot;very happy&quot; with the talks though he had reiterated Moscow's opposition to NATO's eastward expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;We are against the enlargement because we have no right to destabilise Europe,&quot; the Russian premier told reporters. &quot;We should instead put it on a stable and viable path&quot;.</p>
<p>Chirac spokeswoman Catherine Colonna said Chirac reiterated his desire for a summit including NATO states, eastern European nations who wish to join it and former Soviet republics, including Russia, as a preliminary step toward an agreement between NATO and Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;We understand that Russia remains worried and convinced that enlargement would constitute a threat to Russia's security,&quot; Colonna said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
