<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217644" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Buba officials want strict Maastricht guidelines.</title>
<headline>Buba officials want strict Maastricht guidelines.</headline>
<byline>Clifford Coonan</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key to success for Europe's planned single currency is economic stability and strict interpretation of the guidelines for adopting the Euro is vital, Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>European Union member states hope to meld their currencies into a single currency to be launched in 1999, but must meet certain economic targets before that date to qualify.</p>
<p>Many, including Germany, one of the chief driving forces behind economic and monetary union (EMU), are facing problems attaining these goals, triggering talk about possible delay.</p>
<p>&quot;The criteria for European monetary union membership require strict and narrow interpretation,&quot; Issing said at a conference in Munich, adding that there was no room for &quot;creative accounting&quot; by EU member states seeking to join currency union.</p>
<p>Issing's colleague on the Bundesbank council, Hans-Juergen Krupp, said earlier in Hamburg punctuality was important for developing currency stability and any delay in EMU could result in sharp revaluation of the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;Any delay would bring a new revaluation wave. Anyone who demands a delay in the start of the project is clearly not aware of the consequences,&quot; Krupp said.</p>
<p>Germany's economy took an unexpected downturn late last year due in part to the strength of the German currency on foreign exchange markets.</p>
<p>Krupp said that the introduction of a single European currency would create greater economic stability in Europe. He added that this was particularly important for German companies because they have a high export quota.</p>
<p>Another Bundesbank directorate member, Peter Schmidhuber, also struck home the importance of currency stability at a meeting in Frankfurt. He said sustainable conditions for the stability of the Euro were essential.</p>
<p>Lasting currency stability would not only allow for the proper administration of the currency through the European Central Bank, but would also help to introduce a culture of stability, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes little sense to start currency union with only two or three countries,&quot; Schmidhuber said, adding that uncertainty about the start date for currency union at the start of 1999 could not be totally dismissed.</p>
<p>Schmidhuber said the decision as to which countries will take part in the crucial third stage of European economic and monetary union on January 1, 1999, would be taken after a complicated process during 1997. --Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
