<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217668" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission persists over car spare parts.</title>
<headline>Commission persists over car spare parts.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission's drive to force large car manufacturers to allow smaller ones to copy their spare parts gained a reprieve on Tuesday at the Internal Market Council.</p>
<p>The Irish presidency was unable to secure a qualified majority for its plan for a common position which would rub out the so-called &quot;repairs clause&quot; of the directive and continue the current system used to protect industrial designs and models rather than introduce harmonisation at EU level.</p>
<p>If the presidency proposal had been adopted a hotch potch of national rules for spare parts would have continued.</p>
<p>Internal Market Commissioner Mario Monti told a news conference after the Council that he hoped the draft directive would be discussed again in several months time.</p>
<p>On this issue, unless the Council secured unanimity, which it was unable to do in the absence of agreement by Austria, the Commission's opinion counted. So the Commission was able to prevent the Council from agreeing to keep the status quo.</p>
<p>Monti told the news conference he was unable to agree to something which would go so clearly against EU citizens' interests. He had originally amended his proposal to take into account European Parliament amendments.</p>
<p>By allowing smaller manufacturers to copy, under licence and for a reasonable and equitable fee, spare parts, the Commission believes that more competition and investment will be promoted.</p>
<p>&quot;I am aware of the difficulties of adaptation that the achievement of the single market can sometimes cause and I was ready to accept a transitional period for the application of this regime,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can nevertheless not forget the advantages that the opening of the markets and strengthening of competition brings for the overall economy, in terms of increasing competitivity and lowering prices for consumers.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the current system, larger car manufacturers are able to protect spare parts from copying by independent manufacturers.</p>
<p>The Commission had proposed modifying the so-called &quot;repairs clause&quot; of the draft directive to mean that smaller manufacturers could copy so-called &quot;visible&quot; parts like doors and headlights under a licence system, as long as they paid the original manufacturer an equitable and reasonable fee.</p>
<p>So-called &quot;non-visible&quot; parts would not be protected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
