<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217781" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish share index hits new all-time closing high.</title>
<headline>Danish share index hits new all-time closing high.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Danish top-20 KFX share index closed on Tuesday at a new all-time closing high for the second consecutive day, boosted by the strong dollar and Wall Street but dealers foresaw profit-taking ahead and modest falls in the days ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar's advance and a bullish U.S. market helped us along today but I scent profit-taking ahead so tomorrow could end in moderate falls,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The KFX top-20 index gained 1.30 point to reach a new all-time closing high of 131.49, while the KFX December future rose 1.20 point to 131.20 with 615 contracts traded.  </p>
<p>Shares which did particularly well on a positive day included Novo Nordisk, Den Danske Bank and Tele Danmark.</p>
<p>Novo Nordisk continued to surge ahead, putting on 30 crowns to end at 1095, while Den Danske Bank rose four to 450.</p>
<p>Tele Danmark was the most traded KFX paper, finishing seven crowns higher at 296 with 266,000 shares changing hands.</p>
<p>Carlsberg closed untraded at 375 after announcing record 1995/96 profits but an uncertain forecast on Monday.</p>
<p>--Chris Follett, Copenhagen newsroom, 45-33-969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
