<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217812" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: Bangladesh, India in water-sharing talks.</title>
<headline>Bangladesh, India in water-sharing talks.</headline>
<dateline>DHAKA 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief minister of India's West Bengal state arrives in Dhaka on Wednesday for talks on the thorny issue of sharing water from the Ganges river.</p>
<p>&quot;The visit has been long awaited and seen as very crucial,&quot; one official said on Tuesday. &quot;The success of the talks holds the key to life and death for millions of people in this country,&quot; said the official, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The Ganges, which flows into Bangladesh through West Bengal, has been a major irritant in relations between the two countries since 1974 when India built its Farakka barrage about 18 km (11 miles) from Bangladesh's northern border.</p>
<p>Dhaka says the dam obstructs the river flow during the dry season (December-May), depriving the country of its fair share of water. During monsoons, the barrage releases excess water, flooding much of this downstream country, local officials say.</p>
<p>The five-day visit by West Bengal's chief minister, Jyoti Basu, is at the invitation of Bangladesh Foreign Minister Abdus Samad Azad, who has often expressed &quot;full confidence&quot; the neighbours can reach a permanent agreement on the water-sharing dispute before the end of 1996.</p>
<p>Bangladeshi officials privately said Dhaka had high hopes for a positive outcome, noting that Basu may have a special sympathy for Bangladesh, his native home.</p>
<p>Basu's ancestral home in Barodi village near Dhaka is being given a facelift because the West Bengal chief minister will spend a few hours there, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;If everything goes well at the Dhaka meeting, it will be followed by a summit meeting between prime ministers of the two countries in New Delhi next month, where the agreement may be formally signed,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>Officials in Dhaka say more than 40 million people in north and northwest Bangladesh have faced gradual desertification of their land because of the Farakka dam which they say is drying up rivers fed by the Ganges.</p>
<p>The last agreement between the two neighbours, under which Bangladesh was receiving 35,000 cubic metres per second of Ganges water during the dry season, expired in 1988 and attempts to renew it have since failed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DHAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
