<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217903" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bell Atlantic to manage Iusacell.</title>
<headline>Bell Atlantic to manage Iusacell.</headline>
<dateline>PHILADELPHIA 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bell Atlantic Corp. will take over management of Mexican cellular phone company Grupo Iusacell SA de CV, in a deal worth at least $200 million, Bell Atlantic and Grupo Iusacell's parent company, Grupo Iusa SA de CV, announced Tuesday.</p>
<p>The announcement prompted a $2 rise in Iusacell stock to $9, making it the biggest percentage gainer on the New York Stock Exchange in early afternoon trading. Bell Atlantic was unchanged at $62.875 on NYSE.</p>
<p>The deal was signed by Bell Atlantic, which owns 42 percent of Iusacell common stock, and Mexico's Peralta family, which owns 48 percent, the companies said.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic Vice Chairman Lawrence Babbio Jr. will become vice chairman of Iusacell, replacing Carlos Peralta, and Philadelphia-based Bell Atlantic will take a majority of seats on Iusacell's board. Peralta will remain on the board.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the Mexican telecommunications market presents tremendous opportunities, and this agreement demonstrates our continuing commitment to Mexico,&quot; Babbio said in a statement.</p>
<p>Mexico City-based Iusacell has 220,000 subscribers in Mexico, according to Bell Atlantic.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic Nynex Mobile, Bell Atlantic's joint venture with Nynex Corp., has more than 4 million subscribers in the United States. Bell Atlantic also has interests in cellular phone ventures in Italy, the Czech Republic and Slovakia.</p>
<p>Grupo Iusa, an industrial conglomerate with interests in construction, automotive equipment and financial services, said its manufacturing portfolio was expanding rapidly and demanding significantly more time and effort.</p>
<p>&quot;With competition a reality in Mexican telecommunications, we think now is the right time for our partner, Bell Atlantic, to take the lead at Grupo Iusacell,&quot; Peralta said in the statement.</p>
<p>The companies said the agreement would better position Iusacell for opportunities in Mexican telecommunications, including cellular and long-distance services resulting from deregulation, the opening of markets and improving economic conditions.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Bell Atlantic will pay $50 million and transfer certain shares in Iusacell in exchange for a controlling interest in the Peralta group's shares.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic will make a $150 million loan to Iusacell which can be repaid or converted into Iusacell stock at a price of $7 per U.S. share.</p>
<p>Bell Atlantic and the Peralta group will also convert certain outstanding debt and provide interim funding convertible into additional Isuacell stock.</p>
<p>The agreement gives the Peralta group the option to sell one-third of its interest in Iusacell to Bell Atlantic at the end of each of the next three years at prices of $8.50, $9.60 and $10.70 per U.S. share, respectively.</p>
<p>The companies said they want to close the deal within the next 30 days. The companies need to reach a final agreement and gain the approval of Bell Atlantic's board and Iusacell's stockholders.</p>
<p>The deal must also be approved by Mexico's secretary of communications and transportation, the Foreign Investment Commission and other Mexican agencies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHILADELPHIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
