<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="217914" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French rail unions call 24-hr strike in Rouen.</title>
<headline>French rail unions call 24-hr strike in Rouen.</headline>
<dateline>ROUEN 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three unions with members working for France's SNCF railway network called for a 24-hour strike from 1900 GMT on Tuesday at the Sotteville-Les-Rouen depot.</p>
<p>Patrice Lamare, secretary-general of the CGT branch at the depot, said some 50 workers voted unanimously at a meeting to strike. The strike could affect rail traffic between Rouen and Paris, Le Havre, Dieppe and Caen, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not so much an act of solidarity with the truckers' strike, although there is common ground between our struggles, as it is to demand higher wages and more hiring,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The SNCF regional office said it had heard of a strike call but had not been notified. It said it expected &quot;normal traffic.&quot;</p>
<p>The SNCF unions, which spearheaded a hugely disruptive three week transport strike in France late last year, have profited from a nine-day truckers' strike to highlight their demands.</p>
<p>The CGT railway workers' division said in a separate statement on Tuesday that it had written to the government and to the SNCF management to demand negotiations to end layoffs and restructuring plans at the state-owned railway, discuss working conditions and the maintenance of routes and stations.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom, +33 1 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROUEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
