<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218025" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Deere sees higher '97 worldwide sales to dealers.</title>
<headline>Deere sees higher '97 worldwide sales to dealers.</headline>
<dateline>MOLINE, Ill. 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deere &amp; Co said Tuesday it expects its worldwide physical volume of sales to dealers on a comparable basis to increase by about five percent in 1997 compared with 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;First quarter physical volumes are also projected to be six percent higher than the comparable levels in the first quarter of 1996,&quot; Hans Becherer, chairman and chief executive officer, said in a statement.  </p>
<p>He added that Deere expects another strong operating performance next year, based on a favorable market outlook for its businesses and better operating margins for the company.</p>
<p>&quot;We are continuing to invest in new growth initiatives throughout the world which should promote the sale of new as well as existing products in new markets such as China, the republics of the former Soviet Union and India,&quot; Becherer sad.</p>
<p>Worldwide demand for John Deere agricultural equipment remains very strong, he added.  </p>
<p>&quot;Favorable weather conditions in the major producing areas in North America, combined with the removal of all annual acreage reduction programs in the United States, resulted in significant increases in production of wheat, corn and soybeans in 1996,&quot; Becherer said.</p>
<p>Grain prices remain at reasonably good levels overall, despite recent declines, he added.</p>
<p>Deere said it expects strong North American demand for agricultural equipment, due in part to a new U.S. government payment program and U.S. Department of Agriculture projections for tight supplies of grains and oilseeds during the next year.  </p>
<p>Overseas agricultural equipment sales, which were strong during 1996, are expected to continue to increase in 1997 due to sales in the Ukraine and Kazakhstan.</p>
<p>&quot;Industrial equipment markets also remained strong in 1996,&quot; Becherer said.</p>
<p>Housing demand is expected to remain at approximately the same levels in 1997. That, coupled with general expectations for moderate domestic economic growth, should promote continued good industrial equipment demand in 1997, he added.  </p>
<p>Commercial and consumer equipment industry sales were hurt this year by a cold, wet spring and a cool and dry summer, resulting in retail sales about equal to 1995 levels.</p>
<p>&quot;However, the first Sabre by John Deere (lawn care) products were introduced during 1996, opening a new market segment to the company,&quot; Becherer said. &quot;Retail sales volumes in 1997 are currently expected to increase moderately over 1996 levels, assuming more normal weather patterns, growth of the Sabre brand and a continuing strong economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Financial services operations also are expected to continue their profitable growth next year, partially offset by planned lower gains on note sales and higher expenditures for key growth initiatives.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOLINE, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
