<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218076" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: DUTCH CLOSING SHARE MARKET REPORT.</title>
<headline>DUTCH CLOSING SHARE MARKET REPORT.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares, sluggish after a firm start, surged in the last half hour, setting a new intraday peak moments before backing down to a new closing high.</p>
<p>The AEX index closed up 3.83 points, or 0.61 percent, at 627.10, just off a new intra-day peak of 627.57.</p>
<p>Traders said some shorts were forced to cover while others just went along with the late bullish sentiment.</p>
<p>After the opening, the Dutch market had spent some time in the shadow of other bourses.</p>
<p>Traders said profit-taking after Monday's jump of over one percent had left Dutch shares lagging.  </p>
<p>&quot;The market has been leaving others behind, so it was bound to have a relative off-day,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The late rally was largely the result of strength of a individual stocks, rather than a common push.</p>
<p>&quot;A couple of stocks have really raced ahead of the market,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The heaviest trading was in Philips, which gained 3.30 guilders to 69.20. The buying came after Morgan Stanley raised its rating for the company to strong buy from outperform.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course, Philips has been one of the worst performers so far this year,&quot; one trader commented.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
