<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218358" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Austrian stocks add on as AMS surges.</title>
<headline>Austrian stocks add on as AMS surges.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Austrian shares ended moderately higher on Tuesday with buying encouraged by buoyant international bourses, traders said.</p>
<p>The ATX index gained 1.54 points, or 0.14 percent, to 1,102.39 after initially powering up to 1,107.67. Of its constituents, 10 gained, 10 fell and one was unchanged.</p>
<p>Some traders are doubtful the ATX index of 21 blue chips has finally left the 1,100 mark behind, saying they could not rule out a relapse to 1,085 points.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think we're going to be able to hang above 1,100 points for long,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>But another disagreed, pointing out that although Vienna has lagged behind its international peers, customers were gradually moving more to the buy side and &quot;the number of customers is increasing&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It's becoming a more and more difficult game for the bears,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The day's best performer was microchip maker AMS. It gained 5.68 percent to end at 800 schillings, boosted by gains in U.S. semiconductor shares and the belief the worst is behind for the firm's two loss-making subsidiaries.</p>
<p>&quot;AMS has become a restructuring story. You can either believe in it or not. If you do, it's time to buy and have a good look at it,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Traders said buy orders above all came from abroad, and that the share price had room up to 840 over the short term.</p>
<p>The leading decliner was Flughafen, down two percent at 486, as it continued to suffer foreign selling after its half-year results. One trader sees further downside to 440 schillings.</p>
<p>The broad-based Vienna bourse index climbed 0.13 percent to 419.37.</p>
<p>The December ATX future rose 1.4 points to 1,106.4 with 529 contracts traded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
