<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218304" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Sweden's Riksbank cuts key rate, more expected.</title>
<headline>Sweden's Riksbank cuts key rate, more expected.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's central bank, the Riksbank, Tuesday surprised financial markets with a larger-than-expected 0.25 percentage point cut in a key interest rate, and analysts forecast more cuts before the year's end.</p>
<p>The Riksbank trimmed its repo rate to 4.35 percent, exceeding most analysts' expectations, which ranged between 0.05 and 0.25 points, saying inflation remained on target.</p>
<p>Riksbank governor Urban Backstrom on Monday said he was satisfied with inflationary data over the past month, with Swedish consumer prices unchanged in October and producing a year-on-year rate of minus 0.1 percent. It was the first time since 1959 that Sweden has seen prices fall.</p>
<p>With all signs pointing to inflation staying under control in the near future, analysts said the Riksbank could cut its repo rate at least one more time in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be new speculation about further repo rate cuts because fundamentals show there's still potential for further monetary easing,&quot; Unibank Markets analyst Bjorn Englund said.</p>
<p>The Riksbank said the cut to the repo rate, the bank's key tool for controlling money market liquidity, was permissible because inflation was in line with its target of 2 percent with a one percentage point variance in either direction.</p>
<p>&quot;The Riksbank judges that the outlook for inflation continues to be in line with the inflation target,&quot; the bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>The deposit and lending rates currently stand at 4.25 percent and 5.75 percent. They were last lowered by 0.50 percentage points on Oct. 24.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
