<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218407" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy pensions review to start in 1997 - Treu.</title>
<headline>Italy pensions review to start in 1997 - Treu.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Labour Minister Tiziano Treu confirmed on Tuesday that Italy's centre-left government intends to begin a review of last year's pension reform deal in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;The review will begin at the start of 1997,&quot; Treu told reporters, confirming similar comments by Prime Minister Romano Prodi last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The commitment is to get a grip on the system in 1998, but we'll see how the review goes,&quot; Treu said.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the original deal, the review was not due to begin until 1998. Trade union leaders, backed by the hard left Communist Refoundation party that ensures the government's majority in parliament, have fiercely rejected suggestions that the revision should be brought forward.</p>
<p>Analysts have criticised the 1995 pension reform, enacted by then prime minister Lamberto Dini, for being too slow in moving to eradicate generous early retirement packages.</p>
<p>Commentators have said Italy needs to restructure pensions spending to balance its books and get the ratio between the state deficit and gross domestic product below the three-percent level needed to join Europe's planned single currency.</p>
<p>Treu acknowledged that full data on the effects of the Dini reform would be available only late next year but said that &quot;at the start of 1997, we will certainly have some significant data&quot;. -- Rome newsroom +396 6782501</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
