<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218521" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Paper says it was leaked British budget secrets.</title>
<headline>Paper says it was leaked British budget secrets.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Daily Mirror said on Tuesday it had been leaked secrets of tax changes in Britain's annual budget in what the tabloid called &quot;the shambles of the decade.&quot;</p>
<p>The paper said it decided not to publish the documents because of the chaos it would cause on financial markets.</p>
<p>Editor Piers Morgan said the documents had been handed over to the office of Chancellor of the Exchequer Kenneth Clarke, whose last budget before a general election is crucial to the hopes of the ruling Conservatives of staying in power.</p>
<p>Budget details are one of the most closely guarded secrets in British government circles. A previous finance minister had to resign in 1947 after leaking tax details to a journalist.</p>
<p>But markets played down the importance of the Mirror scoop, saying many of the changes had been widely expected in advance. Sterling was unaffected and dealers took a sanguine view of what is more of a political than a financial embarrassment.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it would have been pretty irresponsible for us to have published them because the ramifications for the financial markets around the world are pretty obvious and pretty serious and I didn't want to be held responsible for ultimately perhaps damaging the purses of our readers,&quot; Morgan told BBC Radio on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Morgan, hailing the story as &quot;the scoop of a lifetime,&quot; said Prime Minister John Major's office acted with amazement when told of the leak.</p>
<p>&quot;There was a long silence and then they decided they would start by threatening us with legal action and we pointed out that actually we were going to return (the budget) anyway,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We eventually handed it over at No 10 (Downing Street) with one of our reporters, who shook hands warmly with one of their policemen and handed over the Budget back to Ken, who I assume was in there having a late night cocoa.&quot;</p>
<p>The paper, without going into details, said in a five-page spread in its later editions that the leaks revealed details of income, inheritance, capital gains, road and company tax.</p>
<p>Major's office refused to comment on the tabloid story but a Treasury spokesman said the contents of the budget would not be affected by the revelations.</p>
<p>The Daily Miror is a supporter of the opposition Labour Party, which has a 20 point lead over the Conservatives in opinion polls in the lead-up to the election, due by next May.</p>
<p>Morgan said: &quot;Although we wouldn't normally hesitate to embarrass the Government with such an amazing scoop, on this occasion we had a public duty to return such sensitive economic documents.&quot;</p>
<p>The Sun, an arch rival of the  Mirror, claimed in what it termed as an exclusive that Clarke will cut income tax by one penny in the pound as well as lowering corporation tax and raising the starting point for inheritance tax.</p>
<p>Clarke, fresh from rescuing the government in a spat with parliamentary supporters over plans for a single EU currency, must score another triumph if Major's Conservative Party is to retain hopes of an election victory.</p>
<p>The budget Clarke will announce to parliament at 1530 GMT must avoid alarming stockbrokers and foreign exchange dealers. But Conservative members of parliament are desperate for tax cuts which could win voters back to them and save their seats.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
