<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218600" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Survey shows NZers want portable numbers - Clear.</title>
<headline>Survey shows NZers want portable numbers - Clear.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Clear Communications said a survey it released on Tuesday showed there was strong public support for portability of phone numbers.</p>
<p>CEO Andrew Makin said 46 percent of residential customers and 45 percent of businesses said they would change telephone suppliers if they could retain their number.</p>
<p>&quot;It shows there is considerable demand for choice,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>Clear has been battling rival phone company Telecom Corp over the issue.  </p>
<p>Makin said the issue was a consumer one, not a competition issue and a very large impediment to choice that was not related to service or pricing issues.</p>
<p>Telecom sees it as a competition issue.</p>
<p>Makin said that without portability of numbers Clear would not enter the residential market.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the biggest single barrier to competition in the residential market and it is easy to fix.&quot;</p>
<p>He said in every other country telephone numbers were owned by the government like radio spectrum.  </p>
<p>Phone companies had been talking about the issue for four years and making little progress. Clear was calling on the government to regulate on the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are after is a set of ground rules for implementing portability.&quot;</p>
<p>He rejected legal redress as a remedy. It was too slow, he said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
