<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218686" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Singapore's future is digital, minister says.</title>
<headline>Singapore's future is digital, minister says.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Digital information holds the key to Singapore's economic future, Environment Minister Teo Chee Hean said on Tuesday as he launched four new initiatives, two of them Internet-based.</p>
<p>&quot;The digital economy is the way to Singapore's future growth,&quot; he said in a speech at Singapore's National IT (information technology) Forum 1996.</p>
<p>Teo, who is also chairman of Singapore's National IT Committee, said Singapore aimed to be the IT mega-hub of the Asia-Pacific region in the next five years.</p>
<p>Teo said the four new initiatives include the launch of the information service TIARA, which provides users with a one-stop access to multiple library and other electronic databases and which, he said, was the first of its kind in the world.</p>
<p>Singapore Connect is an Internet-based information service for small and medium enterprises whose website, when fully operational, will carry a comprehensive business directory to help businesses to find partners.</p>
<p>Some 80,000 businesses are already listed on the website, or Internet location, and there are plans to lift this to 200,000 in two years.</p>
<p>To help establish electronic commerce on the Internet in Singapore, Teo also announced the availabilty of an Electronic Commerce (EC) Home Page and the Infrastructure for Electronic Identification (IEI).</p>
<p>The EC Home Page (http://www.ech.ncb.gov.sg) is an electronic shop front on which 30 applications are currently available covering merchandise from clothes, cakes and flowers to computer parts, music CDs and hotel and resort reservations.</p>
<p>The number of applications on which users can order items or make payments online will rise to a 100 by the end of next year.</p>
<p>IEI is a nationwide system for authenticating users on a network via electronic identification, Teo said.</p>
<p>The new services are aimed at schools, libraries, home users, small and medium sized businesses, said Teo.</p>
<p>Teo said the United States and Europe had already announced initiatives to develop IT applications, networks and legal frameworks to support a digital economy.</p>
<p>&quot;The positioning of Singapore as the IT mega-hub of the Asia-Pacific will enable us to provide value-added services to the region and generate new business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Addresses for the other websites were not immediately available.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703011)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
