<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218629" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ First, National in &quot;informal&quot; talks.</title>
<headline>NZ First, National in &quot;informal&quot; talks.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Representatives from New Zealand First and National went into a round of top level &quot;informal&quot; coalition talks on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Only hours after he returned from the APEC summit in the Philippines Prime Minister Jim Bolger, with Finance Minister Bill Birch, met NZ First leader Winston Peters and other party negotiators in the room in parliament set aside for the talks.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe this is an informal session,&quot; Bolger said, clarifying the status of the meeting.  </p>
<p>He said National would have a meeting of its MPs on Wednesday and the National Party organisation would meet on Thursday.</p>
<p>He would not comment on whether a deal would be on the table at Wednesday's caucus.</p>
<p>Nationalist NZ First holds the balance of power after the October 12 election and is negotiating separately with both National and Labour over the shape of the next government.</p>
<p>NZ First leader Winston Peters told journalists as he went into the meeting there would be coalition meetings throughout the week, into the weekend, and possibly into next week.  </p>
<p>He said Tuesday's meeting was informal &quot;with fewer people and more specialists in the field...of those areas for discussion&quot; than at formal sessions.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Labour leader Helen Clark said talks with NZ First were scheduled for later on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Peters said a paper on superannuation his party had released on Monday, which had been interpreted as changing its position, was a clarification which answered concerns expressed by the Council of Trade Unions.  </p>
<p>He said it did not amount to a shift in NZ First's position. &quot;This was a reply...to the CTU and therefore does not have to address all the detail going before Labour and National,&quot; Peters said.</p>
<p>&quot;It addressed the ten issues or mistakes which they had sought by a programme of disinformation to put around the community of this country.</p>
<p>&quot;A fuller and more definitive policy statement has been there for some time.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;A national savings strategy is a key point of NZ First's economic policy and the only hope long term for this country's economic sovereignty and we are very much committed to it,&quot; Peters said.</p>
<p>He said a public function planned for his Tauranga electorate at the weekend was the normal annual function.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing should be read into it other than that it is the normal annual function we have to wrap up the year.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
