<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218711" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia current account deficit widens 20.6 pct.</title>
<headline>Indonesia current account deficit widens 20.6 pct.</headline>
<byline>Muklis Ali</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia's current account deficit widened 20.6 percent in the first half of fiscal 1996/97, the government said on Tuesday, adding that cooling the overheating economy was top priority.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Mar'ie Muhammad said the deficit widened to $4.521 billion in the April-September period from $3.749 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>In a report to the parlimentary budget commission, he said exports in the first half of the fiscal year amounted to $25.203 billion and imports $23.069 billion. The services deficit was $6.655 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will always maintain...prudent macroeconomic policies,&quot; Mar'ie said in the report.</p>
<p>&quot;The government is also making efforts that domestic interest rates remain at a reasonable level, which can boost investment and production...(and) prevent capital outflow and excessive capital inflow, especially in the short term.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Indonesia's economic growth of 8.1 percent in 1995 signalled overheating.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation is reflected by high inflation and the pressure of the current account deficit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Rapid economic growth has prompted money supply (M2) growth to exceed targets. High M2 growth is because of high credit expansion.</p>
<p>&quot;To reduce overheating is top of the agenda in the government's economic policy -- among other ways, by reducing credit growth as the main cause of money supply expansion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The central bank, Bank Indonesia, had called on private banks to provide credit only to productive sectors of the economy, he said.</p>
<p>Private banks had given 169.33 trillion rupiah credit in the first half of fiscal 1996/97, an increase of 22.53 trillion over the year earlier, he said.</p>
<p>Indonesia had estimated its current account deficit would widen to $8.7 billion in fiscal 1996/97, or about four percent of gross domestic product, from $7.0 billion, or about 3.2 percent of GDP, in 1995/96.</p>
<p>Central bank governor Sudradjad Djiwandono said in May the growth of M2 money supply needed to be curbed. Growth in aggregate M1 had shown signs of slowing since the third quarter of 1995 but broad M2 remain high.</p>
<p>Indonesia had forecast credit expansion of 16.0 percent in fiscal 1996/97. The broad M2 money supply was forecast to rise 17 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
