<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218891" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Two more E.Timorese held over attack on journalist.</title>
<headline>Two more E.Timorese held over attack on journalist.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two East Timorese have been arrested in connection with the beating of a local journalist earlier this month, police said on Tuesday, bringing to four the number so far detained over the incident.</p>
<p>&quot;We have arrested two more people,&quot; East Timor deputy police chief Colonel Atok Rismanto told Reuters by telephone from Dili.</p>
<p>Last week, two youths were arrested in connection with the beating of Gaudensius Mau, an East Timor correspondent for the Jakarta-based magazine Tiras. The two are still being held.</p>
<p>Mau, who is still being treated in hospital, said he was attacked by eight youths who mistook him for an Indonesian security agent.</p>
<p>Many East Timorese do not accept Indonesia's rule of the province. Jakarta invaded the former Portuguese colony in 1975 before annexing it the following year in a move still not recognised by the United Nations.</p>
<p>Police in East Timor said it was too early to speculate on a motive for the attack.</p>
<p>Separately, the Jakarta Post newspaper reported on Tuesday that state prosecutors had refused to accept police evidence in the killing of a Yogyakarta-based reporter.</p>
<p>The reporter, known for his critical reporting of local government affairs, was beaten to death in August by an unidentified attacker.</p>
<p>The prosecutors said the evidence against the man suspected of killing the Bernas daily reporter was incomplete.</p>
<p>The National Commission on Human Rights and officials of the Indonesian Journalists' Association have questioned whether the police conducted a proper investigation.</p>
<p>They have said evidence suggests the man arrested by the police was not the attacker.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
