<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="218931" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Chemical fibre maker Meilun to float staff shares.</title>
<headline>Chemical fibre maker Meilun to float staff shares.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chemical fibre producer Tianjin Meilun Co Ltd said on Tuesday it had been granted approval by the Shenzhen bourse to list 23.64 million staff shares there on November 28.</p>
<p>The staff shares, which were issued at 2.80 yuan per share in 1992, would become class A stock after being listed, Meilun said in a statement published in the Shenzhen-based Securities Times.</p>
<p>CITIC Securities and Anshan Securities have been appointed Meilun's listing promoters, it said.</p>
<p>After the listing, Meilun's total share capital of 69.378 million shares would consist of 27.238 million state shares, 14.452 million legal person shares, 23.640 million A shares and 4.048 million staff shares.</p>
<p>Meilun, based in China's eastern port city of Tianjin, has forecast net earnings of 10.40 million yuan for 1996, compared with 9.40 million yuan in 1995 and 10.10 million yuan the previous year.</p>
<p>It said it had after-tax profits of 1.69 million yuan in the first five months of 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25140">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I26000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
