<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21896" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Sicilian Mafia turncoat held in murder probe.</title>
<headline>Sicilian Mafia turncoat held in murder probe.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Sicilian Mafia turncoat was detained on Thursday for allegedly ordering killings, including those of a young widow and a 14-year-old boy, while under a protection programme, state television reported.</p>
<p>RAI television said turncoat Giuseppe Ferone, 41, was one of five people held in connection with the shootings of Santa Puglisi, 22, and Salvatore Botta in a cemetery in the Sicilian city of Catania on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Puglisi, 22, was shot as she knelt praying by the tomb of her husband, who died last year in a Mafia ambush.</p>
<p>Botta, who had accompanied Puglisi to the cemetery, tried to flee from the lone gunman but was caught and killed.</p>
<p>Police sources said that Ferone was detained with others at a safe house in Anzio, on the Mediterranean coast south of Rome, and questioned by magistrates for nearly five hours.</p>
<p>Police in Catania meanwhile said they had seized an arsenal, including 20 rifles, sub-machine guns, plastic explosives, ammunition and electronic detonators.</p>
<p>The haul also included police uniforms, blank driving licences and radios tuned in to police frequencies.</p>
<p>The reports fuelled an already heated debate in Italy over whether former Mafia killers can be trusted and should benefit from a generous protection programme that includes reduced sentences, a salary and a new identity.</p>
<p>The issue has returned to the headlines after jailed Mafia boss Giovanni Brusca, accused of a string of murders, was reported to be collaborating with police.</p>
<p>Magistrates have said they will treat Brusca cautiously, in case his &quot;repentance&quot; proves to be an attempt to mislead investigators and win favourable treatment.</p>
<p>Giuseppe Ayala, an undersecretary at the justice ministry, told RAI's TG1 news that the &quot;pentito&quot; (turncoat) programme could not be discredited by one person.</p>
<p>&quot;You cannot wipe out an overall contribution that is of exceptional importance just because one criminal, after becoming a &quot;pentito&quot;, becomes a criminal again,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Enzo Guarnera, a lawyer who has defended turncoats, told Sicilian regional television that if the reports were true then Ferone had clearly deceived a lot of people.</p>
<p>RAI said Ferone, a Catania boss who began cooperating with investigators after his son and father died in 1994 in a bloody power struggle between Mafia families, was believed to have ordered the cemetery killings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
