<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219066" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-French central banker questions strong franc.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-French central banker questions strong franc.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>A member of the Bank of France's monetary policy council was quoted on Tuesday as saying a decade-old French policy linking the franc to the mark was sterile and that interest rates should be cut to boost growth.</p>
<p>Daily Liberation quoted Paul Marchelli, one of a minority camp in the council believed to favour an easier monetary policy, as criticising Germany's attachment to a strong mark, saying it was dictated &quot;largely by sentimental reasons&quot;.</p>
<p>His comments were likely to stoke a debate on France's strong franc policy started last week after former president Valery Giscard d'Estaing broke a taboo on questioning the franc-mark link by calling for a sharp franc depreciation.</p>
<p>Giscard d'Estaing reiterated his call on Tuesday.</p>
<p>He told French radio Europe 1 the currency should be trading at around 5.50 francs per dollar. It was at 5.16 francs to the dollar at 0955 GMT. He said his call for a weaker currency involved the relationship of the franc to the dollar, not the decade-old link between the franc and the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;If we had a dollar worth 5.50 francs, the situation of most of our (economic) sectors would improve rapidly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Marchelli said he believed most European currencies were overvalued against the dollar and that the franc was overvalued &quot;by about 10 percent&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We should do everything possible to lower our interest rates as quickly as possible which would allow an acceleration of growth and (the franc) to find a suitable level against the dollar,&quot; Liberation quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>Liberation quoted Marchelli as saying &quot;the franc-mark link is sterile because we are forced to wait until the Bundesbank cuts its rates before we cut ours.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;If we cut our rates quickly, even if it means going below German rates, the markets will understand our strategy very well because the franc is in good shape,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Bank has traditionally kept its intervention rate, now at 3.20 percent, slightly above the German repo rate, now at 3.00 percent, to maintain a cushion to protect the franc and hold it stable against the mark.</p>
<p>Liberation said that out of the nine members of the monetary policy council, set up when the Bank of France became independent in 1994, six supported the current policy of holding the franc-mark exchange rate stable.</p>
<p>Two of these see their mandates expire at the end of the year, although officials have declined all comment on who might replace them.</p>
<p>Marchelli's comments mark the first time a member of the secretive monetary policy council has criticised the Bank's policies publicly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
