<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21900" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: One dead as wind, rains batter Belgium.</title>
<headline>One dead as wind, rains batter Belgium.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>One man died after being swept off a yacht as torrential rains and galeforce winds battered Belgium on Thursday, causing widespread damage, police said.</p>
<p>The 45-year-old man fell overboard in the Channel off the coastal town of Nieuwpoort.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said it was not immediately clear whether the man had drowned or died from injuries. The yacht, which had four other people on board, was driven onto the beach.</p>
<p>Some areas had more rainfall in 24 hours than they normally get in a month, the meteorological office said.</p>
<p>Cellars, houses and streets were flooded throughout the country, trees were uprooted and roofs and cars damaged.</p>
<p>Some trains were delayed as fallen trees blocked lines.</p>
<p>Brussels received 5.6 cm (2.24 inches) of water in the past 24 hours -- compared to an average 7.4 cm (2.96 inches) per month -- but in several districts in the south of the country up to eight cm (3.2 inches) fell, the Royal Meteorological Institute said.</p>
<p>An Institute spokesman said that near the eastern town of Turnhout, a group of boy scouts camping in a low-lying meadow had to be evacuated after water flooded their tents.</p>
<p>The rain also severely hindered Belgian investigators' excavations in the southern village of Jumet, where they are looking for bodies in one of the houses of the main character in a paedophile sex-and-murder scandal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
