<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219132" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Nov 26.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Germany - Nov 26.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-25</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Tuesday morning's German newspapers:</p>
<p>FRANKFURTER ALLGEMEINE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- The SPD makes pitch for youths, large majority at party congress backs proposal to slap a training levy on employers. Party also urges cutting minimum voting age to 16 from 18.</p>
<p>- Truck drivers block border crossings into France.</p>
<p>- Joy surrounds lira's return to EMS. But banks warn it is not an early preliminary decision for currency union.</p>
<p>- Consumer prices in west Germany declined 0.1 percent in November from October and were up 1.4 percent from a year earlier.</p>
<p>- Hans-Olaf Henkel remains president of BDI German industry federation</p>
<p>- Difficult negotiations for metalworkers in North Rhine-Westphalia. Employers want an agreement with steady costs.</p>
<p>- CDU wants big tax reform at start of 1999. FDP wants earlier start.</p>
<p>HANDELSBLATT</p>
<p>- CDU to raise pressure on the SPD in the debate over the 1997 tax law, says CDU general secretary Peter Hintze. CDU will not coproise on taxes.</p>
<p>- SPD party conference agrees on training levy for employers.</p>
<p>- Talk about taxes has cut into consumer spending of many Germans.</p>
<p>SUEDDEUTSCHE ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- SPD wants to make up lost ground with youth.</p>
<p>- Europe welcomes return of lira to EMS.</p>
<p>- Another new record on German bourses. DAX rises 1.3 percent to 2,799</p>
<p>DIE WELT</p>
<p>- SPD wants training levy on employers.</p>
<p>- Truck drivers strike in France expands</p>
<p>- Not enough fuel to fly: Foreign airlines to be controlled more closely in Germany.</p>
<p>-- Bonn Newsroom +49 228 26097160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-25"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
