<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219154" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FEATURE - Libya's Gaddafi put remote Italian island on map.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Libya's Gaddafi put remote Italian island on map.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>LAMPEDUSA, Italy 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi tried to blow this tiny island out of the Mediterranean. Instead, he put it on the tourist map.</p>
<p>In April 1986, Libya fired two missiles at Lampedusa, Italy's southernmost outpost, in retaliation against the West for a U.S. bombing raid on Tripoli. Both missiles fell short but Lampedusa found itself at the centre of world attention.</p>
<p>When the reporters left, the tourists started to arrive on the then little-known island, drawn by television images of dazzling blue seas and picturesque sandy beaches.</p>
<p>&quot;At the beginning we just weren't prepared for the tourist invasion. We were submerged,&quot; remembers Lombardo Giandamiano, head of 35th Parallel, the local hoteliers' association.</p>
<p>&quot;Economically it was great but it created a lot of bad feeling among the locals. Now things have become much better organised,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>However, many on the windswept island, which lies closer to Tunisia than it does to Italy, resent the growing number of tourists and say Lampedusa cannot cope with the annual influx.</p>
<p>&quot;The missles missed the island but ended up doing much more damage than if they had actually hit,&quot; said Giovanni Fragapone, Lampedusa's long-serving mayor until two years ago and a teacher in the local high school.</p>
<p>Lampedusa has a population of around 5,000, most of whom live in the island's one small port town.</p>
<p>This past summer season, local authorities estimate that around 150,000 tourists, virtually all Italians, visited the narrow finger of land, packing the 10 small beaches which dot the rocky island and pushing the infrastructure to its limits.</p>
<p>&quot;It has become a nightmare. Prices rocket with the start of the season and unless you are actually involved in the tourist trade you can't afford to live here,&quot; said Fragapone.</p>
<p>&quot;I have to go to Sicily to buy shirts and soon I'm going to have to start growing my own onions.&quot;</p>
<p>Recently Lampedusa has been hit by a different type of invasion -- from illegal immigrants.</p>
<p>Well over 3,000 have arrived from nearby Tunisia this year alone in an armada of small boats, lured by Italy's lax immigration laws and the dream of a job in affluent Europe.</p>
<p>Although they are swiftly taken to Sicily, Italy's largest island, deputy mayor Piero Billeci is worried that television pictures of the army of bedraggled immigrants arriving in Lampedusa might make some tourists stay away.</p>
<p>While Billeci agreed that tourism had brought its ills, it had also prevented the community from disintegrating, he said.</p>
<p>Ten years ago fishing was Lampedusa's lone industry, now tourism is the main money earner. It is generating enough cash to keep many of the community's young people from having to leave their families and find work on the mainland.</p>
<p>&quot;The big boats are destroying the fishing trade here. They come using large drift nets which are just on the right side of the law and take away everything,&quot; Billeci complained. &quot;Tourism has been something of a godsend.&quot;</p>
<p>The impact of new-found tourist wealth is clear for all to see. The once shabby town of flat-roofed buildings has been given a lick of paint, a chic designer bar dominates the main street and a rash of hotels and restaurants has sprung up.</p>
<p>The enthusiastic council has also sought to bring a bit of green to an otherwise barren island by planting a forest of palm trees around the town.</p>
<p>But behind the facelift, Lampedusa is not yet fully equipped to handle the tourist onslaught. There is still no sewage plant and all the island's raw sewage spews out into the sea close to the harbour.</p>
<p>Some 13 years ago, the local council sought permission from the regional authorities based on Sicily to extend the sewage outlets for more than a kilometre into the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still waiting for a reply,&quot; hotelier Giandamiano said, adding that planning permission was a constant problem, with schemes to build tennis courts and swimming pools on the island all awaiting clearance from Sicily.</p>
<p>An official in the Sicilian town of Agrigento, which handles town planning, said the requests were still under examination.</p>
<p>Lampedusans said such bureaucracy was emblematic of the problems they faced across a wide range of issues.</p>
<p>To obtain most official documents, of which an enormous number are needed in Italy, islanders have to make a 400 km (250 mile) round trip to Sicily. People also have to go to Sicily for hospital treatment -- including childbirth.</p>
<p>&quot;What with the cost of flying to Sicily and then the hotel costs, having a baby sets you back 10 million lire ($6,700),&quot; Billeci said. &quot;Most people can only afford small families.&quot;</p>
<p>The state offers no financial assistance.</p>
<p>And when the hoteliers' association asked Sicily to help it advertise the island as a tourist attraction, they were told that thanks to the Libyan missiles, they did not warrant any extra publicity, Giandamiano said.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been targeted by Gaddafi and now by immigrants but still the government does nothing to help us,&quot; Giandamiano added. &quot;What have we done to deserve this?&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAMPEDUSA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
