<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219168" id="root" date="1996-11-26" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan says to donate rice to cut overgrown stocks.</title>
<headline>Japan says to donate rice to cut overgrown stocks.</headline>
<byline>Eiichiro Tokumoto</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan said on Tuesday it would donate more than 60,000 tonnes of rice to poor countries in Africa, Asia and Central America, a move it said was also to reduce swollen grain stocks.</p>
<p>In announcing the plan, Agriculture Minister Takao Fujimoto told reporters it had not yet been decided whether the rice would come from Japan's stocks of domestic or foreign rice.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Fujimoto's predecessor, Ichizo Ohara, angered foreign rice exporters when he proposed sending foreign rice Japan is obliged to import under world trade accords back overseas as aid.</p>
<p>Rice exporters, such as Australia, said this would be against the spirit of the 1993 GATT Uruguay Round agreements under which Japan agreed to gradually open its long-closed rice market.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the price gap between domestic and foreign rice, it makes more sense to send imported rice as an aid. But this can anger rice exporters like the United States and Australia,&quot; a rice trader at a major trade house in Tokyo said.</p>
<p>Despite Japan's commitment to opening its rice market, exporters complain that very little foreign rice actually reaches shop shelves to offer a choice from Japan's home-grown short-grain &quot;sticky&quot; rice.</p>
<p>Fujimoto said Japan had decided to send the more than 60,000 tonnes of rice to Laos and Haiti and to seven African countries -- Senegal, Tanzania, Togo, Benin, Madagascar, Mauritania and Mozambique.</p>
<p>Another 40,000 tonnes of rice aid was likely to be announced soon, government officials said.</p>
<p>Fujimoto said the purpose was to cut excessive domestic grain stocks.</p>
<p>Japan's Agriculture Ministry has estimated that domestic rice stocks at the end of October stood at three million tonnes, almost double the 1.61 million tonnes of a year ago.</p>
<p>Good harvests in the past two years have swollen stocks in grain warehouses across the country. A stock level of 1.5 million tonnes is considered desirable throughout the year.</p>
<p>Under the Uruguay round accords, Japan agreed to import 511,000 tonnes of rice this fiscal year to the end of next March. It has so far bought only 155,300 tonnes, mainly from Thailand, the United States and Australia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-26"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
