<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219282" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: New York begins revision of state energy plan.</title>
<headline>New York begins revision of state energy plan.</headline>
<dateline>ALBANY, N.Y. 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New York State Energy Planning Board has voted to start a new energy planning proceeding leading to the adoption of a revised and streamlined state energy plan, Chairman F. William Valentino said Wednesday.</p>
<p>Citing the significant changes that have taken place in the energy industry during the last two years, Valentino said &quot;The board views the revision and streamlining of the state energy plan as essential at this time.</p>
<p>He noted in particular changes occurring with respect to competition in both the natural gas and electric sectors.  </p>
<p>The state energy law provides that the board shall adopt a state energy plan &quot;every four years following the adoption of the most recent plan...provided, however, the board may adopt such a plan more frequently for good cause shown.&quot;</p>
<p>The last state energy planning proceeding was initiated in 1993 and the last plan adopted in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a number of important issues and considerations related to the move toward competition in the electric and gas sector,&quot; said Chairman of the Public Service Commission John O'Mara, a member of the board.  </p>
<p>&quot;Preliminary discussions with industry, environmental and consumer groups have indicated that a revision of the existing state energy plan would be very useful and appropriate to deal with the impending changes.&quot;</p>
<p>Some of the issues to be addressed in the plan include:</p>
<p>-- outlining the appropriate role of government in a more competitive economy with respect to promoting fairness and equity to all market participants;</p>
<p>-- looking at the effect that competitive forces will have on New York's energy industries and how state government can use the forces of competition to promote economic growth;</p>
<p>-- examining the factors that influence New York's energy prices and rates;</p>
<p>-- analyzing the interaction between energy and environmental issues, particularly in terms of how restructuring the electricity and natural gas industries influences and affects New York's compliance with the Clean Air Act; and</p>
<p>-- determining how the macro-economic implications of New York's energy situation affect its competitive position vis-a-vis other states and regions of the nation.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALBANY, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
