<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219205" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Allelix Biopharm CEO sees Q1 loss.</title>
<headline>Allelix Biopharm CEO sees Q1 loss.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Biotechnology firm Allelix Biopharmaceuticals Inc will post a loss in its first quarter after an unexpected profit in its fourth quarter, chief executive Graham Strachan said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not show a profit in the first quarter,&quot; Strachan told Reuters in an interview. &quot;We'll show the losses you see in a development company.&quot;</p>
<p>Toronto-based Allelix earned C$0.29 a share in its fourth quarter ended August 31, versus a year earlier loss of C$0.64. The profit was due partly to a supplier's decision to delay an expensive shipment of a hormone for research.  </p>
<p>The supplier delayed the shipment until Allelix's new fiscal year ending August 31, 1997. Allelix also received a C$6.8 million payment from partner Astra AB as part of its agreement with the Swedish drug firm. Astra bought exclusive worldwide rights to a possible osteoporosis treatment from Allelix in one of Canada's largest drug deals.</p>
<p>Strachan said he did not know how deep the loss would be. &quot;It's hard to say at this point,&quot; he said, adding the quarter had not ended.</p>
<p>In its fiscal 1996 first quarter, which ended November 30, 1995, Allelix lost C$0.35 a share or C$3.9 million.  </p>
<p>Linda Willis, Allelix's vice-president of finance, said &quot;The fact that we had income last quarter was an anomaly because of a larger payment.&quot;</p>
<p>Allelix's osteoporosis product, called PTH (Human Parathyroid Hormone), was in advanced clinical trials called Phase II trials, Strachan said. The hormone rebuilds brittle bone eaten away by osteoporosis, a disease afflicting about 200 million people around the world.</p>
<p>Allelix was also developing a treatment to attack the Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV), which causes Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS). The potential product ALX40-4C was also in Phase I/II combined clinical trials, Willis said.</p>
<p>Allelix shares rose 0.15 to 15.75 in light trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange, below the year high of 26, but above the year low of 10.625.</p>
<p>-- Lydia Zajc, Reuters Toronto Bureau (416) 941-8109</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
