<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219495" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: HUNGARY BCE PLANS ELECTRONIC, FUTURES OPTIONS TRADE.</title>
<headline>HUNGARY BCE PLANS ELECTRONIC, FUTURES OPTIONS TRADE.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Budapest Commodity Exchange (BCE) is to introduce electronic trade and futures options trade in the second half of 1997, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Futures options trade will become operational in September or October 1997,&quot; BCE council member Katalin Visky told Reuters following the bourse's annual general meeting.</p>
<p>She added that after technical matters are sorted out, currency futures options trade could start at any time, but the introduction of grain futures options might be linked to timing of the new harvest.</p>
<p>Pre-qualifying tenders for an electronic trading system are under preparation and the system will probably be operational in the second half of 1997, another BCE official said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have invited 22 foreign and domestic companies for the pre-qualifying round,&quot; said Andrea Varga Pongracz, President and CEO of the BCE.</p>
<p>The Budapest Commodity Exchange has a currency futures section, trading seven currencies and Budapest Inter-Bank Offered Rate (BUBOR) futures, with an average daily turnover of 2.7 billion forints for the first 11 months of 1996.</p>
<p>The grain section trades black seed, maize, barley and wheat contracts, and has had an average daily turnover of 400 million forints this year.</p>
<p>Grain trading would be extended to every working day form January 1, 1997, from the current Tuesday to Thursday trade, officials said.</p>
<p>The livestock section has the smallest turnover of between 50 to 60 million forints per month.</p>
<p>Total turnover of the BCE for the January-November period was 675 billion forints.</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
