<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219442" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-VICENZA DUMP AC MILAN OUT OF ITALIAN CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-VICENZA DUMP AC MILAN OUT OF ITALIAN CUP.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roberto Baggio made an emotional return to his soccer roots on Wednesday but could not stave off defeat as league leaders Vicenza dumped AC Milan out of the Italian Cup to reach the semifinals for the first time.</p>
<p>In the night's other quarter-final, Napoli held Lazio to a 1-1 draw at the Olympic Stadium in Rome to record a 2-1 aggregate win, despite playing most of the second half with nine men.</p>
<p>Napoli now play Inter or Juventus while Vicenza take on Bologna in the other semifinal.</p>
<p>Vicenza, the current &quot;miracle team&quot; of Italian soccer,  held the league champions to a 0-0 draw at their Romeo Menti stadium, and went through on away goals having drawn 1-1 at the San Siro in the first leg of the quarter-finals.</p>
<p>Coach Francesco Guidolin, however, was not on the bench to celebrate -- he picked up a one match ban from the previous encounter for &quot;verbal intemperance&quot; and watched the match from the stands while Ernesto Galli took his place.</p>
<p>Vicenza, who went one point clear at the top of serie A for the first time in their history at the weekend, were reduced to 10 men two minutes from time when midfielder Fabio Bellotti was sent off for his second bookable offence.</p>
<p>Before that Uruguayan striker Marcelo Otero had a second half goal ruled offside for the home team in a game which Milan dominated for most of the first half.</p>
<p>Baggio, who played three seasons at Vicenza from 1982 to 1985, had begged Milan's Uruguayan coach Oscar Washington Tabarez to allow him to play against his former club in Vicenza for the first time in his career.</p>
<p>&quot;He said he had never played against Vicenza in his home town and so wanted to play. If I could, I would have saved him because the strain could affect him,&quot; said Tabarez.</p>
<p>Napoli had defender Francesco Baldini and attacker Alfredo Aglietti sent off in the 45th and 49th minutes.</p>
<p>Baldini walked on the stroke of halftime for a foul on Pierluigi Casiraghi while Aglietti was shown the red card for two fouls -- first protesting against the referee and then kicking the ball away while play was stopped.</p>
<p>Lazio had Czech Pavel Nedved sent off in the 83rd minute for a double booking -- faking a foul and then protesting.</p>
<p>Lazio's goal came from Casiraghi in the 21st minute. Napoli equalised five minutes later through Brazilian Caio.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
