<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219462" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER SHOWCASE-STUTTGART FACE TEST OF PEDIGREE AGAINST BAYERN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-STUTTGART FACE TEST OF PEDIGREE AGAINST BAYERN.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>When former coach Christoph Daum made the notorious blunder of sending one foreigner too many on to the pitch in a European Cup tie against Leeds United in 1992, VfB Stuttgart became the butt of many a joke.</p>
<p>The club has taken a long time to get over the embarrassment.</p>
<p>As 1992 champions, Stuttgart were forced to replay the match and lost, letting millions of dollars of income slip through their fingers. Daum later left and the club has not finished higher than seventh for the last four years. Last season they were just 10th.</p>
<p>Now, boosted by some intelligent signings, Stuttgart are finally making a serious challenge for the German championship again. Sunday night's southern German derby with rivals Bayern Munich is a test of their pedigree.</p>
<p>Second-placed Stuttgart, two points behind leaders Bayern, do not have anyway near the Bavarians' record of success.</p>
<p>Former European Cup winners Bayern have won the title a record 13 times while VfB have been German champions just four times and only twice since the Bundesliga was formed in 1963 -- in 1984 and 1992.</p>
<p>But the club, which was very successful in the 1950s, winning both the championship and the Cup twice, has always had aspirations to higher things and has come close to international success.</p>
<p>In 1989, with a rising young striker called Juergen Klinsmann in their ranks, Stuttgart reached the final of the UEFA Cup where they were beaten by a Napoli team inspired by Diego Maradona.</p>
<p>The club has always been able to boast major internationals like Klinsmann, 1990 World Cup-winning defender Guido Buchwald, Euro 96 striker Fredi Bobic and talented Brazilian forward Giovane Elber.</p>
<p>The two clubs have a great deal in common. Both are run by major figures in international football with contrasting profiles.</p>
<p>Bayern's chairman Franz Beckenbauer, the former World Cup winning coach and captain, is a household name everywhere in the footballing world.</p>
<p>While Stuttgart's Gerhard Mayer-Vorfelder may not be known to many fans outside Germany, the Baden-Wuerttemberg state finance minister plays a major role in the international game.</p>
<p>Vice-president of the German soccer federation and chairman of the Bundesliga committee, Mayer-Vorfelder is a member of FIFA's executive committee. Like Beckenbauer, his views on any new development in the game are always in demand.</p>
<p>Like Munich, Stuttgart has a major profile in international sport. Its stadium was rebuilt for the 1993 world athletics championships and is now one of the most attractive grounds in the country.</p>
<p>This season's game is by far the most fascinating for years between the two clubs. Last season Bayern won the corresponding match 1-0 and also won 2-0 in the 1994-95 season.</p>
<p>Bayern will need to play exceptionally well to repeat those results against a Stuttgart side who have been playing some of their best football for years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
