<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219460" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-PSG TURN ATTENTION FROM ATTACK TO DEFENCE.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-PSG TURN ATTENTION FROM ATTACK TO DEFENCE.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Paris Saint-Germain, who went nine league matches without conceding a goal at the start of the season, look set to strengthen their defence before the December 31 deadline.</p>
<p>French clubs are allowed to sign a &quot;joker&quot; between the end of the pre-season transfer deadline and the end of the year.</p>
<p>PSG have their eye on Guingamp's France defender Vincent Candela who has played well in his three outings with Aime Jacquet's national team this season.</p>
<p>Defender Jose Cobos may go to Espanyol of Barcelona and Portugual's Daniel Kenedy is injured.</p>
<p>The only problem with Candela is that he is cup  tied, having played in the UEFA Cup for Guingamp this season. He is not able to appear for PSG in the European Cup Winners' Cup when they resume their defence of the title in the quarter-finals in March.</p>
<p>The first division pacesetters appeared early on to be looking for a replacement for their erratic Panamanian striker Julio Cesar Dely Valdes.</p>
<p>PSG had a superb defence which went nine league matches without being breached and a brilliant midfield in which Brazil's Leonardo stood out also for his goal poaching qualities.</p>
<p>But PSG tended to win by small scores and then fell into crisis when they were hammered 4-2 away by Galatasaray in the second round of the Cup Winners' Cup last month. They had their 13-match unbeaten league record ended at Rennes.</p>
<p>But the recovery was equally remarkable with Dely Valdes scoring four goals in f7ive games, including two in the 4-0 home leg victory over the Turks.</p>
<p>When PSG crashed to their second league defeat 5-3 at Bordeaux 11 days ago they were level until late in the second half but conceded nearly as many goals as they had in all their previous matches.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
