<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219596" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: BA/American Airlines deal faces more delay.</title>
<headline>BA/American Airlines deal faces more delay.</headline>
<byline>Greg Mahlich</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways and American Airlines are facing further delay in getting their controversial alliance approved and now will not get Britain's ruling until next year, industry sources said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They said because trade and industry minister Ian Lang has found it impossible to resolve the competition issues he has referred the matter back to his Office of Fair Trading (OFT).</p>
<p>&quot;There is now not going to be anything (a decision) before the new year,&quot; said one source on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lang's ruling was due in September after he received the results of a three-month investigation into the deal by the OFT.</p>
<p>But it was confirmed on Wednesday that Lang has now referred the matter back to the OFT.</p>
<p>&quot;By agreement with the Secretary of State for Trade and Industry the Director General (of the OFT) is continuing discussions with BA and American Airlines and will be giving further advice to the Secretary fo State in due course,&quot; a spokesman for the OFT said.</p>
<p>He declined to give details. &quot;The discussions are on a confidential basis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Industry sources say it is believed that Lang has asked the OFT's director general John Bridgeman to seek concessions from BA and American on giving up some runway slots at London Heathrow to make way for more competition.</p>
<p>BA has refused to give up slots, saying other carriers have a bigger share of slots at their home hubs and airlines should find their own slots through the normal processes of trading and allocation at Heathrow.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in a related move, British and U.S. negotiators are expected to run into heavy lobbying by rival airlines when they meet in London next week to try and break a five-year deadlock in open skies talks aimed at freeing up the market.</p>
<p>BA and American argue their deal will lead to greater competition on transatlantic routes because it will only go ahead if Britain and the U.S. get an open skies agreement.</p>
<p>But talks broke down in August and although the two sides agreed last month to try again with next week's meeting the negotiators remain obliged to try and reconcile the conflicting interests of all their airlines.</p>
<p>&quot;The talks next week may make a little bit of progress but there will need to be another round,&quot; said an industry source on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think a lot of U.S. heavyweights are going to be in London for this one and we are going to try and keep the heat under the negotiators to make sure they don't give the shop away,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Under the current pact which was last modified in March 1991, only four carriers can use Heathrow for transatlantic services -- American Airlines, United Airlines, British Airways and Virgin Atlantic.</p>
<p>Industry sources say the main sticking points remain that American's U.S. rivals want to be given space to compete at London Heathrow as the most popular, but congested landfall for transatlantic travellers. They also want &quot;fifth freedom&quot; rights to fly from Britain to third countries.</p>
<p>On the British side BA says it should not have to give up any of its own 38 percent share of runway slots at Heathrow.</p>
<p>In addition BA's arch rival Virgin Atlantic Airways says it wants British government negotiatiors to press for &quot;cabotage&quot; rights which would allow British airlines to fly domestic routes within the United States.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
