<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219549" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: N.Sea crude firms on good demand in and out of reg.</title>
<headline>N.Sea crude firms on good demand in and out of reg.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The North Sea wet Brent market held onto early gains on Wednesday after a strong morning deal was followed up by others at the same level.</p>
<p>A Dec 11-13 Brent traded early between refiners at Jan Brent +30 cents, 20 cents up on Tuesday's traded level.</p>
<p>Confirming the hike in prices, a 10-12 loader was traded at Jan +30 cents and resold at a 33 cent premium. A Dec 11-13 was traded at Jan Brent +35 cents, while a 7-9 cargo changed hands at a Dated related price.</p>
<p>&quot;There was talk that the market was being pushed around, but it's pretty clear that the demand is there,&quot; a trader said.  </p>
<p>Healthy buying interest was seen not only from local refiners, but also from the Mediterranean, traders said.</p>
<p>Jan Brent was trading steady at around IPE screen levels of $22.75/$22.80 a barrel at 1840 GMT. The Dec/Jan spread was talked at +66/75 cents late in the day, while Jan/Feb was discussed slightly softer at +54/61 and Feb/March at +53/56.</p>
<p>Despite an apparently booming Brent market, the two Brent dates turning wet today were both clocked. Suko was clocked with one of the Dec 12-14 loaders by Cargill, while Nova was clocked with another by Morgan Stanley.  </p>
<p>Brisk buying was also seen for other North Sea grades which are now mostly sold out until the third decade of December.</p>
<p>A Gullfaks A, loading Dec 21-23, traded at Dated Brent +28 cents and a Gullfaks C with Dec 27-29 dates fetched Dated Brent +44 cents. An end-Dec Norwegian Statfjord traded at a p+c price, while a Danish DUC, loading Dec 26-28, changed hands at a firmer Dated Brent +12 cent</p>
<p>The West African crude market was looking tidy in the short term, traders said, with most early December cargoes placed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
