<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219564" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain backs Spain in row with Cuba.</title>
<headline>Britain backs Spain in row with Cuba.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister John Major on Wednesday gave his backing to Spain in the diplomatic row between Madrid and Cuba.</p>
<p>Seeking to improve relations strained by disputes over Spanish fishing vessels in British waters and the British colony of Gibraltar, Major criticised Cuba for withdrawing its acceptance of a new Spanish ambassador.</p>
<p>Major, flanked by visiting Spanish Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar, told reporters: &quot;We wholeheartedly support the Spanish position. We don't think the way the Cubans treated the Spanish ambassador was a tolerable way to behave.&quot;</p>
<p>The diplomatic tension came about after repeated criticism of Cuba's communist system by Aznar, who has called for democratic reforms on the Caribbean island.</p>
<p>Angered by these criticisms and by Spanish moves to urge European Union partners to take a tougher stance against Cuba in line with U.S. policy, Havana revoked its earlier approval for Ambassador Jose Coderch, who was due to arrive in Havana in December.</p>
<p>Aznar, speaking during an official visit to London, thanked Major for his support and said the common European position was to demand respect for human rights and democracy.</p>
<p>In their talks, Major and Aznar said they discussed moves to overhaul the European Union in the Intergovernmental Conference now going on, as well as efforts to resolve the two countries' differences over Gibraltar.</p>
<p>They also discussed a dispute about Spanish fishermen buying up British fishing quotas, a major issue in Britain where fishermen complain their livelihoods are being threatened.</p>
<p>Several of the fishing areas are in constituencies now represented by ruling Conservative members of parliament but facing strong opposition, posing a problem for Major who lags the opposition Labour party in polls and has a majority of just one seat in parliament.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
