<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219634" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian cases pose dilemma on status of unborn.</title>
<headline>Canadian cases pose dilemma on status of unborn.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>SMITHS FALLS, Ont. 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two Canadian court cases, one of which opened here on Wednesday, have posed a tricky judicial dilemma: if foetuses are legally not humans, can they be injured at will?</p>
<p>The cases have potentially far-reaching ramifications for the issue of abortion, on which Canada has had no restrictions since 1988. &quot;The irony is that women may be free to terminate unborn life but they're not free to risk damaging it when born alive. That's the issue the court has to grapple with,&quot; University of Toronto medical law expert Bernard Dickens said.</p>
<p>In the first case, which opened in provincial court in this town 50 miles (80 km) southwest of Ottawa, Brenda Drummond was charged with attempted murder for allegedly shooting her unborn boy in the womb shortly before birth.</p>
<p>In the second, which the federal Supreme Court has agreed to hear, a Winnipeg child protection agency is seeking to force a pregnant glue-sniffer into treatment so her baby will not be born handicapped or addicted.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court overturned Canada's abortion law in 1988, making it legal to have an abortion up to the time of delivery. It asked Parliament to enact a replacement but a Conservative government was blocked from doing so in 1991 by the Liberal majority in the unelected Senate and no Canadian government has tried again.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court has also ruled that a foetus is not a person or a human being, even if his or her head has already emerged from the mother.</p>
<p>Drummond, her head bowed as she listened to the charges, did not contest a tentatively agreed joint statement of facts: that she inserted a rifle into her vagina and pumped a lead pellet into the brain of her foetus, who was born as Johnathan shortly thereafter.</p>
<p>But her lawyer, Lawrence Greenspon, asked for the case to be dismissed since a foetus is not human under the law. &quot;If she attempted to kill a foetus, what crime is that?&quot; he asked reporters during a break. &quot;A foetus in law, distasteful as that may be to some, is not a human being.&quot;</p>
<p>Drummond is now confined to a psychiatric hospital.</p>
<p>Government prosecutor John Waugh said he would rely to a large extent, during hearings that could last several days, on a provision in Canada's Criminal Code that has not been struck down by the Supreme Court. It states that &quot;a person commits homicide when he causes injury to a child before or during birth as a result of which the child dies&quot; after birth.</p>
<p>Greenspon says the law refers to homicide, not attempted homicide. Baby Johnathan survived.</p>
<p>The Winnipeg woman, two of whose three other children were born with a chemical addiction and were developmentally handicapped, is due to deliver in December. The court is not likely to hear her case until early next year but it will proceed, even if it no longer affects her, in order to rule on the status of an unborn child and whether a mother is obligated to care for her foetus.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SMITHS FALLS, Ont."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
