<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219674" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Mandela, forced to choose, dumps Taiwan for Beijing.</title>
<headline>Mandela, forced to choose, dumps Taiwan for Beijing.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Hamilton</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa on Wednesday abandonned a vain attempt to have diplomatic relations with two Chinas and announced it would ditch ties with Taiwan in favour of the more powerful Beijing.</p>
<p>The move grasped a diplomatic nettle that President Nelson Mandela's government -- to the detriment of a coherent foreign policy, according to some critics -- had long sought to avoid.</p>
<p>&quot;We have now granted diplomatic recognition to the Peoples Republic of China. We will cancel our diplomatic relations with Taiwan with effect from December 1997,&quot; Mandela told a news conference at his home in Johannesburg.</p>
<p>Taiwan lost the biggest of its 30 diplomatic allies.</p>
<p>Mandela expressed his regret, praising Taiwan for its economic contribution to South Africa and its support for the country's transition to democracy over the past two years.</p>
<p>He said South Africa wanted continuing &quot;constructive relations with Taiwan&quot;, but made clear that by the end of 1997 it would have ties with the communist People's Republic only.</p>
<p>Mandela said he met representatives of both Chinas on Tuesday and expressed the hope that &quot;within the next twelve months it would be possible to achieve a smooth transition&quot; allowing South Africa to remain friends with Taiwan.</p>
<p>Asked what had happened to his goal of ties with both Chinas, Mandela said: &quot;Beijing made it clear they would not tolerate that. And it is impossible to move forward on the basis of dual recognition.&quot;</p>
<p>Enumerating reasons for the shift, he said China had the world's biggest population, an economy growing at 10 percent per year, a permanent seat on the United Nations Security Council, and was recognised by almost every country in the world.</p>
<p>The new South Africa's active participation in the Organisation of African Unity and the Non-Aligned Movement, whose members recognise Beijing, also influenced the decision.</p>
<p>&quot;A permanent continuation of diplomatic recognition of...Taiwan is inconsistent with South Africa's role in international affairs,&quot; he said. &quot;We regret this very much.&quot;</p>
<p>The China decision was only one of several prickly issues on South Africa's diplomatic plate.</p>
<p>The government has been criticized for what some western critics see as over-friendly ties to Cuba, Libya and Iran. But Mandela has vowed not to ditch allies who aided his African National Congress when it was an outlawed black liberation movement.</p>
<p>Mandela said Pretoria's ties with Taiwan were inherited from South Africa's former whites-only government, but Taiwan had proved a valuable business partner to the new South Africa which took shape after his election to the presidency in April 1994.</p>
<p>Taiwan's embassy would go but &quot;all other relations besides diplomatic relations will be maintained,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mandela, who said three months ago it would be &quot;immoral&quot; to dump Taiwan, expressed his readiness to meet Taiwan's president Lee Teng-hui to discuss the issue, declaring &quot;I've got an open door.&quot;</p>
<p>But he left no doubt the decision was irrevocable.</p>
<p>In a bid to preserve its position in South Africa, Taiwan forecast recently that bilateral trade, totalling $1.9 billion in 1995, would grow by 10 percent a year.</p>
<p>Taipei also dangled the prospect of a $3.5 billion dollar petrochemical complex before South Africa's investment hungry eyes. But political imperatives proved stronger.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
