<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219635" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada govt pressured to help Canadian Air.</title>
<headline>Canada govt pressured to help Canadian Air.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pressure mounted on Canada's federal government on Wednesday to announce financial aid for troubled Canadian Airlines Corp as a deadline loomed for Canada's second biggest carrier to conclude a rescue plan.</p>
<p>Two of the biggest unions remained defiant in their opposition to company and government demands for wage concessions. Their opposition has blocked a restructuring plan agreed to by four unions and the company.</p>
<p>That plan would involve average wage cuts of about five percent and C$35 million in assistance from Ottawa and the provinces of Alberta and British Columbia, officials said.  </p>
<p>Canadian would save a total of C$70 million.</p>
<p>The company has set a deadline of midnight Wednesday for agreement on the restructuring plan.</p>
<p>Canadian president Kevin Benson told reporters that the deadline was firm and his focus today would be convincing the two holdout unions and federal government to agree to the restructuring. &quot;We have the best plan we can get. It's right here...waiting and ready to happen,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Canadian Union of Public Employees and the Canadian Auto Workers, who represent 6,300 of Canadian's 16,400 workers, have refused to consider wage concessions.  </p>
<p>They are calling for the federal government to help rescue the airline and re-regulate the industry.</p>
<p>Federal Transport Minister David Anderson has been in Vancouver all week in a bid to resolve the crisis, but he has refused to commit to any assistance until all the airline's unions agreed to wage cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;We need you to say you will put money into this airline and show some leadership,&quot; CUPE president Judy Darcy urged Ottawa in a speech to a labor convention in Vancouver on Wednesday.  Added CAW president Buzz Hargrove: &quot;The government has to step in.&quot;  </p>
<p>They said creditors, including major lender Royal Bank of Canada and AMR Corp, parent of American Airlines and 33 percent owner of Canadian, must make sacrifices.</p>
<p>The International Association of Machinists, which has agreed to the restructuring plan, said swift help from Ottawa was vital to get the rescue operation off the ground. &quot;One of the main players still has not come to the plate -- the federal government,&quot; said IAM president Dave Ritchie.</p>
<p>Alberta Premier Ralph Klein agreed Tuesday to measures including fuel tax breaks and an easing of loan terms. British Columbia Premier Glen Clark also expressed willingness to help.  </p>
<p>Clark was in Dallas on Wednesday to meet with AMR officials, union officials said.</p>
<p>Canadian has been seeking a C$48 million reduction in the fees it pays to AMR and a Vancouver television station reported that Clark would also explore AMR's interest in raising its stake in Canadian. The federal government has expressed reservations about that idea.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Vancouver Bureau (604) 664-7314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
