<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219657" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria's Abacha wants development masterplan.</title>
<headline>Nigeria's Abacha wants development masterplan.</headline>
<byline>Felix Onuah</byline>
<dateline>ABUJA 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigerian military ruler General Sani Abacha called on Wednesday for a blueprint to develop the resource-rich African nation.</p>
<p>Abacha told the 172-member body appointed to plan the country's future under his &quot;Vision 2010&quot; programme that it had until September 1997 to submit a report which would become the &quot;masterplan for the nation's economic development&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is high time we put the interest of the nation first and now work out a clear vision to open new horizons and tap all our potentials for our future prosperity,&quot; he said as he inagurated the committee.</p>
<p>Headed by former head of state Ernest Shonekan, a staunch advocate of economic deregulation from whom Abacha seized power in 1993, the committee includes traditional rulers, newspaper editors, prominent bankers and businessmen and chief executives of major multinational oil firms in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Vision 2010 is for now an idea. We are to fashion out the vision, that is our mandate,&quot; said Shonekan, adding &quot;Vision 2010 will guide us to realise our dreams as a properous nation in the 21st century.&quot;</p>
<p>Abacha launched the idea &quot;Vision 2010&quot;, which is modelled on plans in other countries such as Malaysia, at an economic conference in Abuja in September.</p>
<p>He said at the time its aim was to raise Nigeria's gross domestic product through agriculture and industrialisation as well as to improve literacy levels, healthcare and employment.</p>
<p>Although among the 10 leading producers of crude oil in the world, Nigeria is among the poorest nations on the basis of per capita income, due mainly to corruption and political instability.</p>
<p>Africa's most populous nation of 100 million plunged into turmoil in June 1993 when the army annulled an election that would have restored democracy.</p>
<p>Abacha seized power in the chaos that ensued and has pledged to hand over to a democratically-elected president in 1998.</p>
<p>His critics doubt that he will and say programmes like Vision 2010 suggest he wants to hang on to power well into the next century.</p>
<p>But apparently to counter this, Abacha told the committee that the aim  of his government was to launch a foundation for economic prosperity.</p>
<p>&quot;This administration does not pretend to have sufficient time to finish the Vision 2010 assignment,&quot; he said, adding &quot;If it is completed by subsequent administrations, we would feel fulfilled to have pioneered this effort.&quot;</p>
<p>Alleged human right abuses culminating in last year's hanging of nine minority rights activists including author Ken Saro-Wiwa turned Nigeria into an international pariah.</p>
<p>But since then the government has implemented pragmatic economic policies that have won praise locally and abroad.</p>
<p>Expectations are high that the economy, now stabilised, could notch up growth of up to seven percent by next year.</p>
<p>Among key measures being awaited and known to be favoured by Shonekan and other prominent members of the Vision 2010 committee is privatisation of Nigeria's oil industry.</p>
<p>--Lagos newsroom +234 1 2630317</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABUJA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
