<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="21961" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Weather may impair German crop quality, Bonn says.</title>
<headline>Weather may impair German crop quality, Bonn says.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German farm ministry on Thursday said changeable weather during harvesting could impair the quality of this year's grain crop.</p>
<p>Agriculture minister Jochen Borchert said, &quot;Quality this year will probably not reach that of last year's harvest although there are wide regional differences.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Weather patterns have been harassing farmers this year and in some parts lost them the fruits of their labour.&quot;</p>
<p>If harvests kept being disrupted by bad weather, rye and triticale, but also wheat, could suffer.</p>
<p>But malting barley should have both higher yield and quality.</p>
<p>In a preliminary estimate, Borchert put the grain harvest three percent up at 41 million tonnes, adding this was due to a 2.7 percent area increase to 6.7 million hectares.</p>
<p>Pan-German yields of 6.1 tonnes a hectare should be unchanged but those in eastern Germany, where the winter was extremely harsh, should be 10 percent below last year's average in the region of 6.0 tph.</p>
<p>Borchert said a period of warm and dry weather was now needed to ensure grain still in the field -- roughly one third of the total crop -- reached a reasonable quality.</p>
<p>Eastern German farmers should suffer 7.6 percent volume losses at 13 million tonnes, because large parts of the winter barley area needed to be resown, the ministry said.</p>
<p>Farmers in the West may be luckier and raise their crop by 8.7 percent to 28 million tonnes.</p>
<p>The harvest is currently two to three weeks behind schedule as a result of a cold and dry winter and a cool and wet spring.</p>
<p>Sporadic, but heavy, rainfall in July and August caused some hail damage and lodging. --Vera Eckert, Bonn newsroom, +49-228-26097146</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
