<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219681" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe share index leaps to new record high.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe share index leaps to new record high.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean industrial shares traded predictably bullish on Wednesday, and the main industrial index surged over 52 points to a new record high of 8,179.86, for the second day running.</p>
<p>Brokers said both local and foreign investors -- individuals and corporates -- continued to trade on current forecasts that the southern African state's economy will grow by 5-7 percent next year from an estimated five percent in 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the same trend. The market remains generally bullish although we can expect to get some hiccups and volatility here and there in response to news from specific companies,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investor interest is broad but I think it will soon narrow to the heavyweights and the conglomerates. For now, price offers and bids remain high and balanced...and should stay that way for a while,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, the 57-counter industrial index jumped 52.03 points to its record level on broad support, but some brokers said 10-cent gains in transport group Clan at 330, banking group Finhold at 850 Cnd sugar producer Hippo Valley at 930 had added the most weight.</p>
<p>Gold producer Rio Tinto's 350 cents drop to 3,300 on minings ploughed the secondary seven-share mining index 24.86 points down to 1,176.21.</p>
<p>----Cris Chinaka, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
