<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="219887" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>LITHUANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Lithuania - Nov 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Lithuania - Nov 27.</headline>
<dateline>VILNIUS 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lithuanian newspapers carried the following reports in their Wednesday editions. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>LIETUVOS RYTAS</p>
<p>- The prosecutor's office thinks the main reason for the banking crisis which broke last December was a lack of control and supervision by the central bank and intends to start a criminal case against former central bank chief Kazys Ratkevicius and another official.</p>
<p>- Police officers have discovered a machinegun which belonged to one of the policeman murdered at the Medininkai checkpoint in July 1991.</p>
<p>- The presidents of three Baltic countries at a summit in Riga declared their wish once again to be accepted into NATO in a first round of expansion.</p>
<p>- Parliament formed its leadership and 12 parliament committees. The chairman of parliament, Vytautas Landsbergis, will have four deputies.</p>
<p>- Hermis Bank's shares reached a record 146 litas price.</p>
<p>- The demand for three-month T-bills exceeded supply nearly three times and the average yield was 10.42 percent.</p>
<p>- Mobile telecommunications company Omnitel intends to invest 80 million litas next year and expects that the number of its customers will reach 25,000.</p>
<p>RESPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- Nine party factions were formed in parliament.</p>
<p>- The Homeland Union party, the largest in parliament, suggested a reduction in the number of ministries from 19 to 17.</p>
<p>- The results of a Baltic Surveys opinion poll showed that in November peoples' trust in parliament rose seven percent to 22 percent but most people trusted the mass media at 72 percent, up three percent.</p>
<p>LIETUVOS AIDAS</p>
<p>- The Homeland Union wants to merge the economy and trade and industry ministries into one new economy ministry.</p>
<p>- The first vice-chairman of parliament, Andrius Kubilius of the Homeland Union, promised to modernise the political system.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LITH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VILNIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LITHUANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
