<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220196" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Buy long-term care insurance for Christmas?.</title>
<headline>Buy long-term care insurance for Christmas?.</headline>
<byline>Linda Stern</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>Have you been thinking of buying a long-term care policy? If so, you might want to pick one up before year end, according to some financial advisors.</p>
<p>They suggest that this year's health legislation, while making the premiums and benefits deductible, may have set standards that could make those policies worse by next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The federal government wasn't too concerned that first-rate or 'Cadillac-coverage,' policies be available,&quot; writes retirement advisor Bob Carlson in his newsletter.</p>
<p>&quot;I've heard that insurers might drop some benefit options from their policies beginning next year in order to issue policies that meet both the federal qualification requirements and don't carry premiums that exceed the annual deduction limits,&quot; he writes.</p>
<p>The issue won't come to light until years and decades later when policyholders try to collect, according to Art Stein, a McLean, Va., planner who studies (and sells) long-term care insurance.</p>
<p>Specifically, the rules that concern Stein relate to when a policy holder can qualify for benefits.</p>
<p>There are two ways: They must either have a cognitive impairment or need assistance to perform certain &quot;activities for daily living,&quot; such as bathing, eating, using the toilet or dressing.</p>
<p>In codifying these standards, the new law adds some qualifiers that concern Stein: they require the policyholder to need &quot;substantial&quot; assistance and have &quot;severe&quot; cognitive impairment. They also mandate a 90-day waiting period before the daily activities tests can trigger benefits.</p>
<p>&quot;There's bound to be some level of impairment that's not severe and some assistance that's not substantial,&quot; says Stein. He worries that insurers will blithely sell the policies without worrying about those words.</p>
<p>Decades later, policyholders who have been paying for years may find themselves in court trying to prove their situations are severe enough to fulfil the small print.</p>
<p>He is telling his customers to buy their policies now, while more broad wording remains.</p>
<p>&quot;They will still be able to take all the tax benefits,&quot; he says. Consumers should note, however, that the law requires pre-1997 policies to be &quot;issued&quot; before the new year to be eligible for those tax breaks, so make sure your company can guarantee pre-1997 issue before signing on the dotted line.</p>
<p>Manhattan attorney and long-term care expert Walter Feldesman, a consultant to consumer group United Seniors Health Cooperative, concedes that a good policy bought today might be better and cheaper than one bought in 1997, but he shies away from the &quot;hurry up and buy approach.&quot;</p>
<p>Feldesman points out that it's not so easy to find a good policy that includes all the broader wording without adding separate and overly restrictive limits.</p>
<p>For example, the policies that require only &quot;stand by assistance&quot; for daily activities also include medical requirements that could doom coverage. Some states, notably California, limit the restrictions which policies can put on coverage; residents of those states might be happiest to shop before year end, says Feldesman.</p>
<p>Feldesman further notes that future arguments over words like &quot;substantial&quot; and &quot;severe&quot; may not be all that, well, substantial.</p>
<p>&quot;Realistically, it will be such an infinitesimal percentile of people who have these impairments but don't need substantial assistance&quot; that the word may not matter.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Feldesman also believes if you're a candidate for one of these policies, and careful about your shopping, you may want to find one before the new year.</p>
<p>&quot;If you can latch on to one of the better policies, then what you have gained by doing it now instead of later may be a better premium,&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Of course, these's no point rushing into any long-term care policy if you don't need one. You don't need one if you have so much money you can easily pay for nursing home care that currently runs from $30,000 to $70,000 a year, according to Ernst &amp; Young.</p>
<p>You don't need a long-term care policy if you don't have any money: You'll qualify for Medicaid benefits should you need nursing home or at-home round the clock care.</p>
<p>If you have enough money that you'd like to protect it for your heirs, or assure yourself of the budget to afford a quality nursing home, you may want to purchase long-term care insurance before the language shifts. Find a reputable broker who will sift through many policies to find a safe and affordable policy for you.</p>
<p>But avoid the following: policies that require &quot;medical necessity&quot; or minimum hospital stays before coverage kicks in; policies that don't pay enough to cover nursing homes; and policies that don't have built in inflation adjustments.</p>
<p>Before you buy, you can educate yourself about long-term care insurance from a consumerist viewpoint by reading &quot;Long Term Care Planning: A Dollars and Sense Guide,&quot; a book published by United Seniors Health Cooperative, available for $15 from USHC, 1331 H Street, NW, Suite 500, Washington, DC 20005.</p>
<p>You can Email Linda Stern at 72160.1546(at)compuserve.com or write to her in care of Reuters, Suite 410, 1333 H St., NW, Washington, DC 20005.  She regrets that she cannot answer each letter individually, but will cover your questions in upcoming columns.</p>
<p>(EDITORS: Linda Stern is a freelance writer who covers personal finance issues for Reuters. Any opinions in the column are solely those of Ms. Stern.)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
