<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220297" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Southeast power eases ahead of holiday weekend.</title>
<headline>US Southeast power eases ahead of holiday weekend.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot bulk electricity prices in the southeastern U.S. were mostly lower Wednesday due to anticipated lower industrial loads for the long holiday weekend and softer natural gas prices, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Firm, peak power in the northern part of Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) territory for Friday delivery traded mostly in the $21.00-23.00 per megawatt hour (MWh) range, with offers heard as high as $25.00. This compares with Tuesday's late trading range of $25.00-27.00.</p>
<p>Sources attributed the softening to mild temperatures in the southern part of Southeastern Electric Reliability Council (SERC), a drop in holiday demand and lower natural gas prices.</p>
<p>Natural gas prices on most of the Gulf Coast pipes for the remainder of November fell at least 10 cents today into the $3.75-3.80 per million British thermal units range.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak electricity in northern TVA was assessed around $15.50, which is mostly unchanged.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, prices for firm, peak electricity in 16 hour blocks dropped to about $22.00, as compared to Tuesday's 26.00-27.00 trading range.</p>
<p>Peak prices for Monday delivery at the border were talked around $24.50 per MWh.</p>
<p>Florida sources said demand for power was weak due to the mild weather and the greater usage of coal.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak power for the weekend at the Ga./Fla. border was quoted in the $16.00-17.00 range.</p>
<p>Among Florida utilities, 12-hour block power for the weekend was talked in the low-$20s, but trading was very limited.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the Southeast are expected to average five to 10 degrees Fahrenheit below-normal through Saturday, according to the National Weather Service. However, more seasonable temperatures are forecast to return during the first few days of December.</p>
<p>Separately, Entergy Corp's 1,173 MW Grand Gulf 1 nuclear unit is expected to return to the grid Thursday morning following scheduled maintenance and refueling.</p>
<p>Also, Duke Power's 1,129 MW McGuire nuclear power unit in Cornelius, N.C., was cut to 20 percent power early Thursday. The company was not available for further details.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
