<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220393" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: EPA clears New York emissions testing plan.</title>
<headline>EPA clears New York emissions testing plan.</headline>
<dateline>ALBANY, N.Y. 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. government granted interim approval of a plan proposed by New York Gov. Pataki for emissions testing at participating downstate local stations, State Senator Carl L. Marcellino said.</p>
<p>U.S. Environmental Protection Agency granted interim approval for the plan with final approval possible after an 18 month trial period, said Senator Marcellino, who heads the State Senate Environmental Conservation Committee.</p>
<p>The Syosset Republican said the state's new downstate (Long Island, New York City, Westchester County) emission testing program is expected to begin in November, 1997.  </p>
<p>Under an earlier plan put forward by the previous administration, motorists would have had to get emission testing done at a limited number of centralized testing centers, Marcellino noted.</p>
<p>Due to the large volume of vehicles in the downstate region, motorists would have faced long delays at those centers. Centralized testing centers were tried and rejected by such states as Texas, Maine and Pennsylvania.</p>
<p>It is expected the new plan will see about 2,000 downstate testing centers, Marcellion said.</p>
<p>Participating businesses will test emission levels for a fee of $25. Two dollars of the emissions fee will be deposited in the State Clean Air Fund to finance quality control, consumer protection and enforcement programs, he said.</p>
<p>There is no change to the annual $10 safety inspection fee which is separate from the emission testing fee, he noted. New cars will be exempt from emissions testing during their first two years of operation.</p>
<p>--New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALBANY, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
