<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220428" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French customs agent shot, wounded, in car chase.</title>
<headline>French customs agent shot, wounded, in car chase.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>A gunman shot and seriously wounded a French customs agent after a car chase in southwest France on Wednesday, officials said.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the budget ministry, which is in charge of the customs service, said the 34-year-old agent, Michel Icart, underwent surgery for liver and lung wounds.</p>
<p>Local officials said the gunman had made a U-turn to avoid a customs checkpoint between the towns of Agen and Auch.</p>
<p>He stopped when two customs officers on motorcycles caught up with his car, fired several bullets at them and escaped.</p>
<p>The spokesman said police were hunting for the gunman who had not been identified. He could not confirm reports that he might belong to the ETA (Basque Homeland and Freedom) guerrilla movement.</p>
<p>The shooting occured a day after French police in the nearby Landes region captured Juan Luis Aguirre Lete, a suspected ETA leader, who also tried to evade customs controls. Lete was armed but did not shoot.</p>
<p>Lete, also known as Isuntza, has been accused by Madrid of ordering an attempt to assassinate Spanish King Juan Carlos at his holiday home on Palma de Majorca in August 1995. Spanish police foiled the attempt.</p>
<p>ETA has killed nearly 800 people in a campaign that began in 1968 for independence for the Basque region, which includes part of northern Spain and extends into France.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
