<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220421" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Russian PM, IMF head hold informal talks.</title>
<headline>Russian PM, IMF head hold informal talks.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>International Monetary Fund managing director Michel Camdessus held a &quot;working meeting&quot; late Wednesday with Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin to discuss matters of &quot;mutual interest,&quot; a Russian embassy spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The meeting has taken place,&quot; the Russian spokesman said, declining to confirm a Tass news agency report that the talks involved unblocking the latest tranche of Russia's $10 billion IMF loan.</p>
<p>&quot;The contents (of the talks) are not for public release,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>There was no comment by the IMF on the meeting held at the Russian embassy between Camdessus and Chernomyrdin who was in Paris on a two-day official visit.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Russian Central Bank Chairman Sergei Dubinin said the IMF would base a decision on whether to pay out the next tranche of Russia's $10 billion IMF loan on Russian economic data for November.</p>
<p>That information would be available December 1.</p>
<p>An IMF mission left Moscow on Tuesday for the second time in two months without deciding whether to recommend payment of the tranche. Russian and IMF officials said the IMF team would return next month.</p>
<p>The mission last month did not recommend disbursing the money because it was concerned about tax shortfalls.</p>
<p>Russian officials say revenues have picked up in the past few months but the Fund wants evidence that the recovery in tax collection is sustainable and not a one-off event.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
