<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220511" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Report prompts Dutch review of euthanasia laws.</title>
<headline>Report prompts Dutch review of euthanasia laws.</headline>
<byline>Lien van der Leij</byline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Netherlands signalled on Wednesday it was prepared to further decriminalise euthanasia after an official inquiry revealed almost six in 10 mercy killings went unreported by doctors who feared prosecution.</p>
<p>The inquiry report will form the basis for a review of euthanasia legislation promised by the current government -- the first coalition to exclude the anti-euthanasia Christian Democrats in living memory -- when it came to power in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;It has repeatedly been suggested we look to other ways of monitoring (euthanasia cases) than through the coroner's office or public prosecutor,&quot; Justice Minister Winnie Sorgdrager told a news conference on the long-awaited report.</p>
<p>Although technically illegal, euthanasia is tolerated under Dutch law as long as certain guidelines are followed.</p>
<p>Doctors are virtually assured freedom from prosecution if the patient was of sound mind, in unbearable physical or mental pain and had repeatedly asked for death.</p>
<p>Last year doctors reported 1,466 cases of euthanasia under special disclosure procedures introduced in 1993, the inquiry, commissioned by the justice and health ministries, found.</p>
<p>However, such disclosures represented only 41 percent of a total 3,200 mercy killings, the report said.</p>
<p>Many euthanising doctors interviewed in confidence said they failed to report mercy killings because they feared prosecution and wished to spare the deceased's family from legal action.</p>
<p>Public acceptance of euthanasia is widespread in the Netherlands, with a poll earlier this year showing 84 percent of the Dutch supported the practice to relieve unbearable and irremediable suffering.</p>
<p>According to statistics gathered by the inquiry, patients' requests for help to die have grown 37 percent in the last five years to 34,500. Requests for immediate euthanasia rose by nine percent to 9,700.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for the country's powerful right-to-die lobby said the outcome of the inquiry supported its demands for legal mercy killing on request.</p>
<p>&quot;We see this report as confirmation of what we have been saying for so long...we need clear criteria as to what constitutes medically careful treatment,&quot; said Jonne Boesjes of the Dutch Voluntary Euthanasia Society (DVES).</p>
<p>The society argues that current procedures do not give doctors sufficient legal protection, pointing to a series of cases brought to court in 1993 after the government changed its interpretation of existing guidelines.</p>
<p>Only a law which clearly stipulates under what circumstance euthanasia is permissible can change this, the society argues.</p>
<p>&quot;It remains to be seen if this is the way the government is going,&quot; Boesjes said. &quot;In our view amending the reporting procedures will not solve the problem.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
