<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220846" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: GREEK PAST BUDGETS SHOW TARGET-OUTCOME DIVERGENCE.</title>
<headline>GREEK PAST BUDGETS SHOW TARGET-OUTCOME DIVERGENCE.</headline>
<byline>Dimitris Kontogiannis</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece will unveil its 1997 budget</p>
<p>on Friday, coined the toughest in 15 years by National Economy</p>
<p>Minister Yannos Papandoniou, in a bid to near the fiscal</p>
<p>Maastricht target and make it to the EMU in 2000 or 2001.</p>
<p>Greece wants to reduce its general government budget deficit</p>
<p>to 4.2 percent of GDP in 1997 from an expected 7.6 percent in</p>
<p>1996 and the central government budget deficit to 6.2 percent of</p>
<p>GDP from an expected 9.3 percent.</p>
<p>The budget deficit reduction package relies on a combination</p>
<p>of new, heavier taxes, the closing of existing tax loopholes and</p>
<p>reigning in planned spending to about 1997 average inflation --</p>
<p>projected at 6.5 percent from an anticipated 8.5 percent in</p>
<p>1996.</p>
<p>The GDP growth is forecast to speed up to 3.3 percent from</p>
<p>an expected 2.6 percent in 1996 and 2.0 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>But a closer look at Greece's 1994-1996 budget performance</p>
<p>reveals that the central government budget deficit target</p>
<p>diverged from the actual deficit by a large margin. In fact,</p>
<p>targets were below actual budget deficit outcomes.</p>
<p>Final central government primary surplus figures were close</p>
<p>to target in 1994 and exceeded it in 1995.</p>
<p>The contrasting behaviour of the overall central budget</p>
<p>deficit and the primary surpluses points to the accounting</p>
<p>treatment of interest payments on public debt as a likely</p>
<p>explanatory variable in the budget equation.</p>
<p>The general government budget deficit targets also diverged</p>
<p>but target deficits ended higher than final outcomes.</p>
<p>This can be largely explained by unrecorded operating</p>
<p>surlpuses of state entities mainly due to the 1992 social</p>
<p>insurance reform that was incorporated in budget figures in</p>
<p>1995.</p>
<p>But the central government budget and primary surplus</p>
<p>figures are calculated on an administrative basis and the</p>
<p>general government budget figures on a national accounts basis</p>
<p>which means that the comparison of the two is incorrect.</p>
<p>The central government budget figures do not include accrued</p>
<p>and capitalised interest as well as the non-cash coverage of</p>
<p>state guarantees to public sector utilities.</p>
<p>Another interesting development that has worked towards</p>
<p>reducing budget deficits as a percent of GDP is the better-than-</p>
<p>projected performance of the GDP which reflects upward revisions</p>
<p>as well as a higher volume of goods and services in the economy.</p>
<p>						 BUDGET  1996</p>
<p>					TARGET    ESTIMATES	 FINAL</p>
<p>Central govt budget deficit    8.4%	  9.3%	     --</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>Primary surplus (central govt) 5.1%	  4.0%	     --</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>General govt budget deficit    7.4%	  7.6%		--</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>						BUDGET  1995</p>
<p>				    TARGET	ESTIMATES	  FINAL</p>
<p>Central govt budget deficit   9.8%	  10.2%	    10.7%</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>Primary surplus(central govt) 3.4%	   2.6%	     4.4%</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>General govt budget deficit  10.2%	   9.2%	     9.1%</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>						BUDGET  1994</p>
<p>				    TARGET	ESTIMATES	 FINAL</p>
<p>Central govt budget deficit  10.5%	   10.0%	   12.4%</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>Primary surplus(central govt) 1.9%	    2.0%	    2.0%</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>General govt budget deficit  13.1%				12.1%</p>
<p>(% of GDP)</p>
<p>--Dimitris Kontogiannis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
