<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220874" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Capital Intl Perspective details MSCI Russia index.</title>
<headline>Capital Intl Perspective details MSCI Russia index.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Capital International Perspective SA on Wednesday announced the constituents of the MSCI Russia Index, adding that to reflect the market properly large energy firms and utilities predominated.</p>
<p>Capital International Perspective, the Geneva-based manager and calculator of the Morgan Stanley Capital International (MSCI) indices, said in a statement released in London that the MSCI Russia Index included the following firms:</p>
<p>Lukoil Holding (Common), Lukoil Holding (Preferred), Unified Energy (Common), Gazprom ADR (market capitalisation factor of 5.0 percent), Surgutneftegaz (Common), Surgutneftegaz (Preferred), Rostelecom (Common), Rostelecom (Preferred) Irkutskenergo, Norlisk Nickel (Common), Norlisk Nickel (Preferred), Kamaz, Trade House Gum, and Gaz Auto Plant (Common).</p>
<p>&quot;The 14 securities included reach a market capitalisation of $19.5 million and cover approximately 50 percent of the market capitalisation of Russia,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The MSCI indices are used as benchmarks against which investors measure the performance of funds.</p>
<p>&quot;As an accurate reflection of the whole market, large energy sources companies such as Lukoil, Surgutneftegaz and Gazprom, or utility companies such as Unified Energy in electric power, and Rostelecom in telecommunications, dominate the MSCI Russia index,&quot; the statement added.</p>
<p>Gazprom ADRs were included in the index under a special scheme using the dollar-denominated ADR price listed in London, and a market capitalisation of 0.05. This was due in part to the firm's size and the disparity between the price of its ADRs and its shares listed locally in Russia.</p>
<p>It was included in the index at 5.0 percent of its market capitalisation, yet still represents some 11 percent of the MSCI Russia Index, the statement said.</p>
<p>While the index will initially be a standalone index, it will be considered for inclusion in the MSCI Emerging Markets Free index in the next few months.</p>
<p>&quot;Its potential inclusion in MSCI EMF will be considered in the coming months, but at the earliest for structural changes effective at the close of May 30, 1997,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>The MSCI Russia index has performed 75.8 percent from its inception date on January 1, 1995 to November 20, 1996,&quot; it added. &quot;Year to date (to November 20, 1996) the performance has been 144.2 percent.&quot; --Caroline Brothers, London Newsroom +44 171 542 2734; fax +44 171 583 7239</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
