<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220973" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: More than 30 dead in Turkey's rebel Kurd conflict.</title>
<headline>More than 30 dead in Turkey's rebel Kurd conflict.</headline>
<dateline>TUNCELI, Turkey 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish troops have killed 27 Kurdish rebels in the east of the country in fighting over the last two days in which about six soldiers also died, military officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Military officials in the eastern province of Tunceli said seven soldiers and six Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) guerrillas had died in clashes there but an armed forces spokesman said only four soldiers had been killed in Tunceli.</p>
<p>&quot;Twenty-seven PKK terrorists have been killed in eastern Anatolia since yesterday,&quot; the spokesman told Reuters in Ankara. &quot;Four soldiers were killed in Tunceli and two others elsewhere,&quot; he said, without giving further details.</p>
<p>The PKK abducted an engineer and the manager of Tunceli's only intercity bus company from a lonely road in the province on Sunday, the officials said.</p>
<p>More than 21,000 people have been killed in the conflict between troops and the PKK, fighting for autonomy or independence in the mainly Kurdish southeast.</p>
<p>Security officials said they were not expecting any particular increase in rebel attacks on Wednesday, the 18th anniversary of the PKK's foundation. The group began its armed campaign proper in 1984.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNCELI, Turkey"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
