<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="220903" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Croatia, Yugoslavia troubles pose problem for West.</title>
<headline>Croatia, Yugoslavia troubles pose problem for West.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Nicholas Doughty, Diplomatic Correspondent</p>
<p>Western governments have been taken aback by a wave of popular discontent in the two nations holding the key to peace in Bosnia and now face potentially difficult questions about the future of the Balkans.</p>
<p>Diplomats say demonstrations in Croatia and Yugoslavia, one year after the end of Europe's worst war in half a century, do not mean that Croatia's ailing Franjo Tudjman and Yugoslavia's Slobodan Milosevic are about to be ousted.</p>
<p>But the extent of the protests has forced major powers which finally brokered an end to the Bosnian conflict to think about how they will manage the Balkan region if the two leaders are seriously weakened or eventually ousted.</p>
<p>&quot;This has certainly come as a surprise and it opens up a possibility that none of us had really contemplated until now -- that we might have to deal with a different political situation in Belgrade or Zagreb,&quot; said one senior European diplomat.</p>
<p>The United States and its European allies have supported both Tudjman and Milosevic, despite widespread questions about their record on human rights and commitment to democracy, because both men were needed to end the war.</p>
<p>Croatia and Serbia are the biggest powers in the region and have important ties with their ethnic kin in Bosnia. The major powers say they had little choice but to enlist their support, while critics argue they indulged in cynical &quot;realpolitik.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We needed them to deliver on the peace agreement,&quot; said Chris Cviic, an expert on former Yugoslavia who works for the Royal Institute of International Affairs (RIIA) in London.</p>
<p>&quot;We have relied on these people and no alternative policy has been developed.&quot;</p>
<p>The Washington Post wrote in an editorial on Tuesday that the United States and its allies had &quot;paid too little heed to the loathsome irony of cooperating with and therefore strenghtening undemocratic regimes&quot; in Croatia and Serbia.</p>
<p>European Union foreign ministers discussed the protests in both countries, which have brought hundreds of thousands onto the streets, at a meeting in Brussels on Monday.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, international peace coordinator Carl Bildt said in Bonn he was &quot;extremely concerned&quot; by what was happening in Belgrade and urged greater moves to democracy in the region.</p>
<p>Since Milosevic and Tudjman are effectively guarantors of the Bosnian peace deal, there are questions about what happens if either or both of them is forced to go.</p>
<p>NATO is planning to keep troops in Bosnia next year as part of an international deal to secure the fragile peace there -- issues which will be discussed at a European security summit in Lisbon and a meeting in London next week.</p>
<p>Diplomats caution against comparing the murky intricacies of Balkan politics with what happened in Eastern Europe in 1989 and 1990, when popular discontent forced out communist governments.</p>
<p>For a start, they say, there are no clear successors to take over in either Croatia or Serbia.</p>
<p>Milosevic is still widely considered to have a firm grip on power, despite the biggest mass protests in five years over the president's refusal to accept local election results in which the opposition did well.</p>
<p>&quot;Our concern is that if Milosevic is eventually on his way out, he may not be replaced by democrats who will continue to support the Bosnian peace process,&quot; said another diplomat.</p>
<p>Among the opposition are ultra-nationalists like Vojislav Seselj who think Milosevic, after stoking the passions that led to war, then sold out the Bosnian Serbs by reinventing himself as a peacemaker when it suited him.</p>
<p>As for Croatia, U.S. officials say Tudjman is suffering from cancer and has no more than a year to live, with opposition to his right-wing government growing. Protests in Zagreb were sparked by an attempt to shut down an independent radio station.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Zagreb has its eyes firmly fixed on joining the European Union and is widely regarded as reasonably stable. Any transfer of power, diplomats say, would be smoother than in Belgrade -- but would not necessarily be good news for Bosnia.</p>
<p>Tudjman's right-hand man, Defence Minister Gojko Susak, has his main power base in a sensitive area of western Bosnian peopled by nationalist Croats and under Zagreb's effective control, in defiance of the peace agreement.</p>
<p>Efforts to resolve problems there could be under threat if Susak emerges as Tudjman's successor.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
