<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221097" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Nov 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Nov 27.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-26</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carries the following stories on its front page on Nov. 27:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>CHICAGO - Major league baseball's team owners approved an agreement with players, ending the longest, costliest and most bitter labour dispute in professional sports history.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGKOK - First Lady Hillary Rodham Clinton is sending mixed signals on what her role will be during the next four years of the Clinton administration.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A military investigation into management of the Navy's giant PX shopping mall in Norfolk has found a pattern of inappropriate discounts and other preferential treatment given senior officers and their spouses.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - Some of America's biggest industrial giants are fighting the Environmental Protection Agency's plan to tighten regulation of air quality.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>NEWARK - Facing prison, a flamboyant former prosecutor from New Jersey Tuesday killed himself with a gunshot to the head after federal marshalls caught up with him in Nevada.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-26"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
