<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221036" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel's Koor Industries Q3 EPS $0.41.</title>
<headline>Israel's Koor Industries Q3 EPS $0.41.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's Koor Industries Ltd.</p>
<p>			   (in millions of dollars except EPS)</p>
<p>			   Q3 96	Q3 95     9-MTH 96    9-MTH 95</p>
<p>Revenue		  844.0	817.3	2,650.0     2,590.0</p>
<p>Operating Income	54.9	 64.5	  256.7	 246.5</p>
<p>Net Income		31.3	 34.7	  154.3	 141.1</p>
<p>Earnings per ADS	0.41	 0.50	   2.04	  2.05</p>
<p>Benjamin Gaon, Koor's president and chief executive officer, attributed the decline in third-quarter operating and net profit to a deterioration in Israel's economic and political climate this year.</p>
<p>&quot;Our economy is still affected by high interest rates and the increasing gap between the inflation rate and the exchange rate of the Israeli shekel against the U.S. dollar,&quot; he said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time uncertainties in the peace process dominate the political environment. Given this setting, we are pleased to report a modest increase in revenues.&quot;</p>
<p>Koor's revenues were up just 3.3 percent in the third quarter from a year earlier to $844.0 million, while operating income declined 14.9 percent to $54.9 million and net profit 9.6 percent to $31.3 million.</p>
<p>Earnings per American depository share (ADS) fell more sharply than net because of an increase in the number of shares outstanding.</p>
<p>Nine-month results, which showed a 9.4 percent increase in net, were helped by a $21 million gain from the initial public offering in Tadiran Telecommunications Ltd.</p>
<p>Despite an unfavourable exchange rate environment, Koor said it increased group exports in the nine months by 10.7 percent in dollar terms. Because of the real appreciation of the Israeli shekel, however, exports in shekel terms rose only 7.1 percent.</p>
<p>Koor estimated the difference represented lost revenues of 100 million shekels.</p>
<p>Koor said its telecommunications businesses, centred on Tadiran Ltd and Telrad Telecommunications and Electronic Industries Ltd had a &quot;very productive quarter and experienced growth reflecting the structural improvements made last year.&quot;</p>
<p>The agro-chemicals business, which comprises Makhteshim Chemical Works and Agan Chemical Manufacturers, also experienced strong sales growth, Koor said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our building materials business was obviously the most affected by the current economic and political condtions,&quot; Koor said. &quot;Nevertheless, cement production increased.&quot;</p>
<p>Koor's board approved an interim 1996 dividend of 1.5 shekel per ordinary share.</p>
<p>($1=3.24 shekels)</p>
<p>- Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34430">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
