<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221172" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Parliament probe might finish Olivetti -MD.</title>
<headline>Parliament probe might finish Olivetti -MD.</headline>
<byline>Giselda Vagnoni</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief executive of troubled Olivetti Spa warned the Italian parliament on Wednesday against opening an inquiry into the company's affairs, saying the prospect of such a probe could finish the group off.</p>
<p>Olivetti's Roberto Colaninno, addressing a parliamentary industry committee hearing, appealed for the lower house not to start an investigation as proposed by some members.</p>
<p>&quot;If an inquiry committee -- the most important judicial process -- was to be started, Olivetti would lose all its clients the next day,&quot; he told the lower house committee.</p>
<p>In that case, he feared the information technology group would be forced to close.</p>
<p>Loss-making Olivetti is already the subject of judicial investigations in the northwestern city of Turin and nearby Ivrea where it has its headquarters.</p>
<p>Italian bourse regulator Consob opened its own investigation after a manager resigned saying he did not agree with all the figures published in Olivetti's first half accounts for 1996.</p>
<p>Parliamentary deputies have asked for an inquiry following the accounting disagreement and in the wake of suggestions of insider trading in Olivetti shares on the Italian stock market.</p>
<p>Colaninno said as Consob and Italian tax police were both in the process of investigating the company, &quot;an inquiry committee would just be a duplication.&quot;</p>
<p>He stressed his optimism that the company could turn itself around, notwithstanding its current financial situation and provided no &quot;non-financial&quot; upsets occurred.</p>
<p>Olivetti, which has not turned a profit since 1990, had net debt at the end of October this year of 3.028 trillion lire ($2 billion), after 3.016 trillion lire at the end of September.</p>
<p>The company, which underwent dramatic changes in its top management in September, has lost much investor confidence due to financial and management problems and now wants to focus on computer systems and telecommunications while selling off its loss-making personal computer division.</p>
<p>Colaninno, who took up his post in September, told the committee: &quot;I have been able to ascertain in this working period that the various areas of activity are well placed in the market, but that the repeated attacks on the company's credibility and seriousness are damaging clients' confidence.&quot;</p>
<p>He repeated Olivetti's intention to face up to the challenge of turning itself around without state help.</p>
<p>But he said the group did feel penalised compared with its competitors in global information and telecoms markets, partly by the slow liberalisation of Italy's telecommunications sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Olivetti finds itself operating in a national market and planning important investments in conditions of huge uncertainty,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We therefore ask the country to move with the same speed and the same force as other European countries in the process of developing the information market,&quot; he added. ($1=1,510 lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
