<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221385" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Eurobourses down, strike hits french markets.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Eurobourses down, strike hits french markets.</headline>
<byline>Leonard Santorelli</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>European bourses fell on Wednesday with Paris stocks hit by the French truckers strike, although the franc recovered slightly on signs of progress in the 10-day-old dispute.</p>
<p>The dollar, meanwhile, strengthened over half a yen after a Bank of Japan report on manufacturing pointed to no increases in interest rates, helping to support the American currency.</p>
<p>French shares slipped on profit-taking after recent peaks and with investors worried about the nationwide truckers protest. The blue-chip CAC-40 index was down 0.25 percent.</p>
<p>The mood was depressed by anxieties over the impact of the strike on the French economy with petrol supplies interrupted and airline unions joining.</p>
<p>The dispute also hit the franc, which weakened to 3.3926 to the mark in early trading but picked up slightly amid indications of progress on two key points in the strike.</p>
<p>The government mediator chairing marathon talks between the drivers and employers said agreement had been reached on their two main demands, early retirement and shorter working hours. The franc perked up to 3.3882 to the mark by late morning.</p>
<p>London, Europe's biggest bourse, lost early gains to show a loss of 0.3 percent after figures showed British exports were doing well despite strong sterling, raising concerns over inflationary pressures.</p>
<p>Investors had largely shrugged off rising interest rate expectations following Tuesday's budget but the latest trade data saw inflation fears creep back.</p>
<p>&quot;Inflation is definitely in the back of people's minds,&quot; said one dealer. &quot;But the market is so short of stock that any downside will probably be limited.&quot;</p>
<p>Strategists said that finance minister Kenneth Clarke's budget was conservative but not tight enough to allay pressure for further higher intererest rates.</p>
<p>European investors were also depressed by events in New York where the Dow Jones industrial Average finished 20 points down in the wake of its record-breaking run of recent days.</p>
<p>Frankfurt was the worst performer of the day. The bourse fell 0.5 percent after its record close on Tuesday. Carmaker Volkswagen AG tumbled almost six percent after a U.S. judge denied VW's motion to dismiss racketeering claims by rival Opel.</p>
<p>The dollar climbed against the yen as the Bank of Japan's quarterly tankan report showed only a modest economic recovery and pointed to no change in interest rates.</p>
<p>&quot;There is enough in this survey to confirm that the recovery continues...But it is perhaps less positive than I would have liked with interest rates on hold for the foreseeable future,&quot; said Daiwa Europe economist Julian Fisher.</p>
<p>On bullion markets, platinum was fixed at $377.75 an ounce, the lowest since December 8, 1993, amid bearish market sentiment across the precious metals complex.</p>
<p>Its sister metal palladium was also set lower, fixing at $114.75 an ounce, the lowest since April 20, 1993.</p>
<p>CURRENCIES AT 1245 GMT</p>
<p>The dollar was quoted at 113.07 yen and 1.5240 marks against 112.65 yen and 1.5251 marks late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>STOCK MARKETS AT 1245 GMT</p>
<p>The FTSE 100 index of leading British shares down 12.7 points at 4,055.7.</p>
<p>In Paris, the CAC-40 share index was down 6.02 points at 2,269.06.</p>
<p>The 30-share DAX index in Frankfurt was down 13.61 at 2797.03.</p>
<p>PRECIOUS METALS</p>
<p>Gold fixed slightly higher at $373.95 an ounce vs $373.50 on Tuesday afternoon and London's close of $373.75. Silver was up one cent at $4.76.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
