<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221486" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH - Budget bills update for Nov 27 - Details.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH - Budget bills update for Nov 27 - Details.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is an update on the status of each of the Australian government's contentious budget bills.</p>
<p>The analysis focuses only on measures that will or might be opposed by both the Labor opposition and Australian Democrats minority party, which would leave the government depending on the doubtful support of the two Greens or two Independents to obtain its legislation.</p>
<p>Scores of other budget measures not mentioned here will pass the Senate because they will gain the support of Labor, the Democrats or both.</p>
<p>The list has been expanded today to include five social security measures, in two bills, whose future now appears doubtful.</p>
<p>Here are the relevant bills, their status in the parliamentary process, descriptions of the contentious measures and their value to the budget in 1997/98, when most have a significant impact, and 1999/00, when all should be fully implemented:</p>
<p>---LOSSES TO DATE---</p>
<p>SOCIAL SECURITY (NEWLY ARRIVED RESIDENTS' WAITING PERIODS) BILL, 1996.</p>
<p>The Senate amended this bill on Tuesday. Its measure was:</p>
<p>-- Migrants' social security waiting period. The government wanted to generally exclude migrants from social security for two years after their arrival. The remainder of the Senate voted down the waiting period for some social security, but not unemployment benefits. Value before amendment: A$140 million in 1997/98, A$194 million in 1999/00. Treasurer Peter Costello says the amendments cost A$200 million over the period to 1999/00.</p>
<p>---UPCOMING BILLS---</p>
<p>HIGHER EDUCATION LEGISLATION AMENDMENT BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill will probably be dealt with next, perhaps on Thursday.</p>
<p>It includes:</p>
<p>-- Student charges. The government wants to hike the charges for some university courses for new students. Value to the budget: A$66 million in 1997/98, A$123 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Student charges repayments. Students can defer payment of their charges until their income reaches a certain threshold. The government wants to drop that threshold, initiating faster repayments. Value: A$230 million in 1997/98, A$318 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>NATIONAL HEALTH (BUDGET MEASURES) BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill is also listed for debate in the Senate by the end of the week. Its contentious measure is:</p>
<p>-- Pharmaceutical benefit scheme changes. The government wants people to pay more for each prescription. Value: A$134 million in 1997/98, A$147 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>CHILDCARE LEGISLATION AMENDMENT BILL, 1996</p>
<p>The House of Representatives has passed this bill and it has been introduced into the Senate. However, it is not listed for early debate and appears to be well down the queue. Its contentious measure is:</p>
<p>-- Childcare subsidies. The government wants to tighten eligibility. Value: A$147 million in 1997/98, A$170 million in 1999/00. </p>
<p>TAXATION LAWS AMENDMENT BILL (NO.3), 1996</p>
<p>This bill has passed the House of Representatives and has been introduced into the Senate. By Senate convention, it has arrived too late to be dealt with this year, unless the chamber chooses to change the rules to suit it.</p>
<p>It includes:</p>
<p>-- Research and development tax break legislation. Companies can deduct 150 percent of R&amp;D spending from taxable income. The government wants to cut this to 125 percent. Value: A$430 million in 1997/98, A$440 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Research and development syndication. The government says the syndication rules encourage exploitation of its tax break with false R&amp;D projects, so it wants to abolish the syndication. Value: A$288 million in 1997/98, $400 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Medical expenses rebate. People whose medical expenses exceed A$1,000 a year get a tax rebate, depending on their income. The government wants to raise the income threshold. Value: A$26 million in 1997/98, A$24 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Co-operatives financing tax break. The government wants to end this small tax break, mostly affecting primary producers. Value: A$2 million in 1997/98, A$6 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>SOCIAL SECURITY LEGISLATION AMENDMENT (BUDGET AND OTHER MEASURES) BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill should be dealt with next week or the week after.</p>
<p>-- Activity tests. The government wants to impose several new requirements on people receiving unemployment benefits, such as a tighter definition of the sort of job they can reject and still receive money. Value: A$106 million in 1997/98, A$116 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Social security advances. In some circumstances, the Social Security Department will pay in advance. The government wants to restrict this. Value: A$28 million in 1997/98, minus A$2.5 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Earnings credits. Social security beneficiaries can sometimes spread out income they earn to reduce the effect on their entitlements. The government wants to end this. Value: A$76 million in 1997/98, A$83 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>SOCIAL SECURITY LEGISLATION AMENDMENT (FURTHER BUDGET AND OTHER MEASURES) BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill should be dealt with next week or the week after.</p>
<p>-- Superannuation means testing. The government wants to count retirement savings in means testing for social security beneficiaries aged between 55 and retirement age. Value: A$93 million in 1997/98, A$65 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Rent assistance. The government wants to reduce social security for some single people in share accommodation. Value: A$33 million in 1997/98, A$41 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>STUDENT AND YOUTH ASSISTANCE (WAITING PERIOD) BILL, 1996.</p>
<p>This bill is expected in the Senate next week. It contains:</p>
<p>-- Student income support (&quot;Austudy&quot;). The government wants to tighten eligibility, in part by excluding younger people. Value: A$63 million in 1997/98, A$78 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>BOUNTY LEGISLATION AMENDMENT BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill has made no progress in the House of Representatives since its introduction in September. But the Senate, which has not actually received the bill yet, has referred it to a committee which is to report on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Bounties abolition. The government wants to abolish, or bring forward the abolition of, bounties on computers, shipbuilding, machine tools and books. Value: A$36 million in 1997/98, A$49 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>OTHER MEASURES</p>
<p>The government's aged care legislation has not been introduced into the lower house and is unlikely to be introduced this year, so there is no bill yet.</p>
<p>The legislation will include contentious nursing home changes. The government wants residents to pay more, as they do in other forms of accommodation for the aged. Value: A$125 million in 1997/98, A$194 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>Also, changes to court fees were effected by regulation, not legislation.</p>
<p>The Senate, using its power to alter any regulation, imposed some minor amendments in early October.</p>
<p>Before amendment, the measure was expected to raise less than A$27 million in 1997/98 and something under A$31 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
