<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221493" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FEATURE - Australian tourism showing signs of slowing.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Australian tourism showing signs of slowing.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's fast-growing tourism industry is showing signs of slowing, with the biggest visitor group, the Japanese, looking elsewhere for holidays.</p>
<p>The recent race row that has engulfed Australia has also softened demand in the short-term with some Asian tour groups cancelling their trips, while the stronger Australian dollar is also making a holiday &quot;Down Under&quot; more expensive.</p>
<p>And plans by the government to cut 25 percent of the Australian Tourism Commission's (ATC) annual A$80 million (US$64 million) budget will see fewer overseas promotions.</p>
<p>&quot;With a reduction in the ATC funding and with the strengthening in the Australian dollar and with more vigorous competition from other nations...(it) is a pretty tough game at the moment,&quot; said Len Taylor, managing director of Inbound Tourism of Australia.</p>
<p>The A$14 billion a year Australian tourism industry is also worried about the slowing growth rate in the number of Japanese visiting Australia.</p>
<p>Of the estimated 4.17 million overseas visitors expected to holiday in Australia in 1996, 20 percent will come from Japan, according to government figures, compared with 21 percent in 1995 and the peak of 24 percent in 1992.</p>
<p>Australia's share of the Japanese outbound market has fallen by half a percent to 4.9 percent between the 1993/94 and 1995/96 fiscal years, even though more Japanese are taking overseas holidays.</p>
<p>Australia is losing ground to Europe and the United States in the battle for Japanese tourists, with high air fares, visa problems and hotel shortages blamed for the decline, said tour operators.</p>
<p>&quot;What we are saying is you can't treat Japan as something special as you did in the past where it was quite easy to make large profits,&quot; said Jon Hutchinson, managing director of the Australian Tourism Commission.</p>
<p>Increased competition through more aggressive advertising campaigns in Japan from markets such as the west coast of the United States, Hawaii, Canada, Thailand and Indonesia, is also putting pressure on Australia's tourist industry.</p>
<p>&quot;All countries are realising that tourism has good potential for foreign exchange earnings and employment,&quot; said Bob Cain, director of tourism forecaster and consultant, Tourism Futures.</p>
<p>The recent strong rise in the Australian dollar is not welcomed by the local tourism industry. Tourism analysts said the local market had been mainly built on a lower dollar value.</p>
<p>&quot;During a lot of the time that we have had these high growths, we have had a low dollar and it meant we were not portrayed as a expensive place,&quot; Cain told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;If we look like having a high dollar for a long period of time, then it's more critical how we present ourselves. Clearly, we are going to be perceived as a long-haul expensive place to travel,&quot; Cain said.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar has risen about 11 percent to stand at US$0.81 currently from a 1996 low in January of US$0.73.</p>
<p>The recent race debate, sparked by independent politician Pauline Hanson's maiden parliamentary speech in March, is also seen as potentially damaging.</p>
<p>Hanson called for a halt to Asian immigration, arguing that Australia was being swamped by Asians.</p>
<p>Asians make up less than five percent of Australia's 18 million people.</p>
<p>&quot;It is creating false images for Australia, so it is a bit off-putting for our industry because if other countries are worried about safety they won't send their people here,&quot; said Hutchinson at the Australian Tourism Commission.</p>
<p>However, tourism leaders said the Australian tourism sector is in good shape despite the toughening conditions, thanks to its traditional attractions of the Outback, beaches and the Great Barrier Reef.</p>
<p>Tourism leaders said although the Japanese market might be slowing, the rest of Asia is growing strongly, particularly South Korea and Taiwan. The number of vistors from South Korea jumped 36 percent in the nine months to September 30.</p>
<p>The latest figures from the Australian Bureau of Statistics show there were 2.97 million arrivals between January and September, with short-term visitors up 13 percent on last year.</p>
<p>Overseas holidaymakers are projected to top the six million mark in the year 2000, up from the 3.73 million that visited last year and the 4.17 million expected this year, according to the Australian Tourism Forecasting Council.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
