<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221580" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Nov 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malaysia - Nov 27.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Wednesday's Malaysian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>NEW STRAITS TIMES</p>
<p>- Indah Water Konsortium has written off 290 million ringgit in sewerage charges following the government's directive to cancel all sewerage bills issued before Jan. 1.</p>
<p>- Malaysia on Tuesday became the first country to enter into partnership with an internationally-renowned motor racing team in the 17-leg 1997 Formula One World Championship.</p>
<p>- Police are investigating two reports lodged by applicants of Fumakilla (M) Bhd shares, after their applications were rejected on November 18 and 19, ahead of the public balloting orignally scheduled for Wednesday.</p>
<p>BUSINESS TIMES</p>
<p>- Rashid Hussain Bhd on Tuesday unveiled a massive 5.84 billion ringgit restructuring exercise which includes a 2.16 billion ringgit cash acquisition of 75 percent of Kwong Yik Bank Bhd.</p>
<p>- Malayan Banking Bhd will utilise proceeds from the 2.16 billion ringgit sale of its 75 percent stake in Kwong Yik Bank to finance future business expansion, locally and overseas.</p>
<p>- Malaysian Airline System Bhd has turned in a 155.28 million ringgit group pre-tax profit for the six months ended September 30, 1996, a marginal 3.7 percent increase from 149.72 million ringgit posted in the previous corresponding period.</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- The Education Ministry will consider reducing the number of tests for primary school pupils following complaints of excessive pressure on the young minds.</p>
<p>- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-230 8911)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
