<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221674" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SingTel 6-mth net seen up 8-9 percent.</title>
<headline>SingTel 6-mth net seen up 8-9 percent.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slower growth in international direct dialing (IDD) and cuts in telephone charges are likely to restrain half-year profit growth at Singapore Telecommunications Ltd (SingTel), analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A Reuters survey of industry analysts found SingTel's net average profit for the six months to September 30, due to be announced on Friday, would show an increase of eight to nine percent to around Singapore $805 million (US$575 million), from S$742.5 million in the previous first-half.</p>
<p>But estimates varied widely from an increase of only six percent to S$787 million to a rise of 13 percent to S$839 million. SingTel registered a 9.5 percent year-on-year rise in net profit in its previous first-half.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this set of results may disappoint,&quot; said Winston Lim, telecoms analyst at DBS Securities in Singapore. &quot;The fastest growing area for SingTel has been IDD but that is directly correlated with economic growth, which has been lower over the last few months.&quot;</p>
<p>SingTel, Southeast Asia's biggest listed telecoms group with market capitalisation of more than S$40 billion, has benefited over the past five years from Singapore's position as a regional business centre.</p>
<p>But the city-state has been hit this year by a slowdown in the electronic sector, on which it relies for about half its industrial output and almost 60 percent of its non-oil exports.</p>
<p>As a result, its gross domestic product (GDP) is expected to grow by about six percent this year after 8.8 percent in 1995 and 10.2 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>DBS Securities expects revenue growth in IDD, which accounts for about 40 percent of SingTel's turnover, to slow to under seven percent in 1997, from almost nine percent in 1996.</p>
<p>SingTel has also cut its IDD rates on three occasions this year, in some cases by more than 40 percent. This should be balanced in part by higher contributions from the company's investments in overseas associates.</p>
<p>In the six months to September 30, 1995, associates turned in a loss of S$31.1 million. But analysts expect a positive return this time round with some estimates of associate profits as high as S$50 million.</p>
<p>A wholly state-owned monopoly until 1993, SingTel is due to lose its control of the local mobile telephone market next year and of basic telecoms services in April 2000.</p>
<p>In response, the company has invested an estimated S$2.2 billion in foreign and regional ventures.</p>
<p>One of the biggest investments was in Belgium, where SingTel joined U.S. group Ameritech Corp and Tele Danmark A/S in December 1995 to spend US$2.47 billion on almost 50 percent of national telephone operator Belgacom.</p>
<p>&quot;But it will be two to three years before associates really begin to contribute,&quot; said John Chester, regional telecoms analyst at Schroders.</p>
<p>Chester said SingTel's half-year results were unlikely move its share price dramatically unless they were well outside the market's forecast range.</p>
<p>&quot;If prices do move on the results, it will more likely be a reaction to any statements the company makes about prospects for the industry,&quot; he said. &quot;I'll be looking for what it has to say on changes in industry competition and rates.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
