<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221613" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Police warn tourists of being drugged during sex.</title>
<headline>Police warn tourists of being drugged during sex.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Police in the Thai resort of Pattaya, known for its sex industry as much as its beaches, are warning foreigners to be wary of gangsters robbing and killing tourists after they are drugged during sex.</p>
<p>Police said on Wednesday the warning was issued following a recent sharp rise in the number cases of tourists who had died of heart failure after apparently being drugged.</p>
<p>A 40-year-old American tourist, who did not want to be identified, filed a complaint with police late on Tuesday that he had collapsed unconscious before having sex with a prostitute and later woke up in a hospital bed.</p>
<p>Police quoted the victim, who lost more than 200,000 baht ($8,000) in cash and valuables, as saying that he passed out after having licked the woman's nipples.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that gangsters are rampant (in Pattaya) but we can do nothing as most victims refuse to cooperate with investigators,&quot; a police officer told Reuters.</p>
<p>Police and medical sources said gangsters mostly drugged foreign tourists with a heavy dosage of sleeping pills mixed in drinks taken by victims. But some prostitutes apparently coat their nipples with a drug.</p>
<p>Police and hospital statistics said at least 45 American, European and Asian tourists had died of suspicious drug overdoses in Pattaya this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
