<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="221929" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: INSTANT VIEW - Bank of Japan's &quot;tankan&quot; survey.</title>
<headline>INSTANT VIEW - Bank of Japan's &quot;tankan&quot; survey.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following is a selection of economists' and analysts' reactions to the Bank of Japan's short-term corporate survey in November, released on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The survey showed that manufacturers' diffusion index -- a key gauge of corporate sentiment -- rose to minus three from minus seven in the previous survey in August.</p>
<p>PETER MORGAN, SENIOR ECONOMIST, JAMES CAPEL PACIFIC:</p>
<p>&quot;It looks overall pretty much in line with expectations, both the sentiment indices and the capital spending plans. The forecasts look pretty cautious, probably reflecting the anticipation of the consumption tax rise.&quot;  </p>
<p>&quot;Interest rate policy will be on hold for some time,&quot; Morgan added.  </p>
<p>ROBERT FELDMAN, DIRECTOR OF ECONOMIC ANAYSIS, SALOMON BROTHERS:</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers are pretty much in line with most people's expectations and I would not expect the BOJ to change its monetary policy on the basis of this.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if we had a much weaker tankan, it's unlikely that the BOJ would ease further given the low level of interest rates right now. And we would have required a much, much stronger tankan to get any hike of rates. This basically says to me that the BOJ will remain essentially stable in its policy.&quot;  </p>
<p>(Regarding forecasts for March,) if we are seeing expectations of continued improvement of the economy...that would be taken as saying the modest recovery of the economy is continuing. There is hope that would be true but there is an important fiscal policy debate coming up in the month of December...we still have a lot of decisions to be made (on fiscal policy).&quot;  </p>
<p>MINEKO SASAKI-SMITH, CHIEF ECONOMIST, CS FIRST BOSTON:</p>
<p>&quot;It's very much as expected. I think that everything is fine...until next March. That's when I have a problem&quot; because of fiscal drag from the consumption tax rise and the end of special income tax cuts.</p>
<p>&quot;Monetary policy remains unchanged until about next summer at the earliest. Policy will remain unchanged not because of the real economy per se but because of financial sector weakness.&quot;  </p>
<p>JANE BERRYMAN, SENIOR ANALYST, FIXED INCOME, TECHNICAL DATA, TOKYO:</p>
<p>&quot;Until I saw the tankan today, I would have thought the earliest...you might have another tightening of rates was late in Q2. You can remove any risk of that -- maybe we're looking for late in the second half of 1997, but if the pace of economic growth doesn't accelerate...I have a lot of time for the argument that there may not be a hike in 1997 at all.</p>
<p>&quot;One thing that's definite, there is no hike coming in the first half of next year.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
