<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222049" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: VW hit by French strike, may work short-time.</title>
<headline>VW hit by French strike, may work short-time.</headline>
<dateline>WOLFSBURG, Germany 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>German carmaker Volkswagen AG will decide on Monday whether to introduce short-time working at its main plant in Wolfburg because the supply of car parts has been affected by the French truckers' strike, VW's employee council said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Striking French truckers have set up almost 200 truck blockades on major routes and blocked refineries and fuel depots around France, forcing some factories to close.  </p>
<p>VW's plant in Brussels may also be affected, the chairman of VW's group works council, Klaus Volkert, said.</p>
<p>VW imports heating and air conditioning systems for its Golf and Polo models from plants in central France and gets metal parts for the Polo from Spain.</p>
<p>The transport of car components to VW's plants posed considerable problems, Volkert said.</p>
<p>VW was also having difficulties delivering axles and engines from its Wolfsburg plant to its subsidiary Seat in Spain, Volkert said.</p>
<p>In order to be able to react quickly to delivery bottlenecks, VW had already asked to be exempted from the legal requirement of having to give 14 days notice before introducing short-time working, Volkert said.</p>
<p>French truckdrivers have been striking for the past 10 days to back demands for higher pay, shorter hours and retirement at 55 instead of 60. Trucker leaders and employers were locked in new marathon talks on Wednesday as truckers kept up barricades.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WOLFSBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
