<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222061" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asian tanker outlook bright - Osprey.</title>
<headline>Asian tanker outlook bright - Osprey.</headline>
<byline>Marguerita Choy</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>The outlook is bright for tanker owners in Asia due to high oil demand, but deciding what size vessel to buy could be difficult, a shipping industry expert said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential for further oil consumption growth in Asia is large, offering significant opportunities for both crude oil and product tanker owners,&quot; Tim Cottew, chairman of tanker charter company Osprey Maritime Ltd, said in an interview.</p>
<p>Speaking on the sidelines of the World Tanker Outlook Conference in Singapore, he said that by 2005, Asian oil consumption was expected to rise by one-third to about 22.5 million barrels per day (bpd). Even excluding Japan's consumption it will equal North American demand.</p>
<p>The most remarkable development in the Asian crude oil trades over the past few years has been the greater use of VLCCs (Very Large Crude Carriers), with a 60 percent increase in east-bound fixtures from the Middle East, the region's largest source of oil. VLCCs carry at least 160,000 tons of cargo.</p>
<p>&quot;There are limited growth prospects for Asian oil production,&quot; Cottew said. &quot;We envisage the Far East becoming increasingly dependent on the Middle East for its oil.</p>
<p>&quot;By 2005, the Middle East will account for about 58 percent of oil consumed in Asia compared to 52 percent at present.&quot;</p>
<p>But one question for tanker owners is whether to buy large tankers for crude oil or smaller ones for refined petroleum products. The key to this is the extent to which new oil refining capacity will be built in Asia.</p>
<p>Refinery production in Asia, currently at 16 million bpd, will have committed additions of 1.9 million bpd by 1997 and various additions of 1.35 million bpd are planned by 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;There are dozens of other proposals that may, or may not, materialise and which make forecasting tanker requirements fraught with difficulties,&quot; Cottew said.</p>
<p>He said Osprey Maritime was focusing on tankers for refined petroleum products as he expects these imports to grow strongly. Most of its current fleet comprises tankers of 40,000 to 45,000 deadweight tons (dwt).</p>
<p>Cottew said the tanker market for refined products has suffered to some extent in 1996 from an increase in new refinery capacity in Asia, especially in South Korea.</p>
<p>But intra-Asian seaborne trade in refined products was on the rise, doubling to 1.7 million bpd between 1990 and 1995.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect South Korea's and possibly Japan's emergence as export refinery centres to split the Far East into two main trading areas, namely northeast and southeast Asia,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Although the polarisation will lead to a reduction in average haul lengths, this should be offset by an increase in the volume of coastal and short-haul movements within each area in terms of tonnage carried per mile.</p>
<p>He said approximately two-thirds of intra-Asian clean tanker fixtures involved cargoes of 30,000 to 40,000 dwt and around a third of deep-sea product tankers currently are in the 40,000 to 50,000 dwt bracket.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
