<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222041" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - Nov 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Switzerland - Nov 27.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are the highlights from Swiss newspapers on Wednesday:</p>
<p>NEUE ZUERCHER ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- Union Bank of Switzerland (UBS) said Tuesday that it will restucture its domestic operations. Some 800 employees will be laid off. UBS also announced that it will take a three billion Swiss franc one-time charge next year to cover credit risks. It expects to report a loss of 500 million francs for 1996.</p>
<p>TAGES ANZEIGER</p>
<p>- The Swiss Canton of St Gallen plans to axe its inheritance tax scheme. A number of wealthy people moved to neighbouring Canton Schwyz to avoid having their heirs pay estate duties. - Swiss-Swedish technology group ABB received an $270 million order to build an combined power plant in South Humber (U.K.). - Swissair ground staff rejected new work regulations proposed by management which would have included salary cuts.</p>
<p>- Scientists at the Federal Insitute of Technology said that</p>
<p>about 86 of a total of 230 Swiss winter sport resorts would have to close down due to lack of snow within the next 50 year, if global warming scenarios prove correct.</p>
<p>JOURNAL DE GENEVE</p>
<p>- The Swiss upper house of parliament voted against the government's plan to kill 230,000 cows in a bid to eradicate mad cow disease in Switzerland. Instead, it proposed slaughter of only 1,000 cows. The chamber proposed allocating some 25 million Swiss francs to support the Swiss meat market.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
