<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222081" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian stocks end weaker but off lows.</title>
<headline>Australian stocks end weaker but off lows.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian shares closed weaker on Wednesday but were lifted off the midsession lows by bargain hunting in the afternoon session.</p>
<p>By the close, the All Ordinaries index lost 5.3 points to 2,376.7.</p>
<p>The leaders saw a choppy day's trading with few obvious trends. Most swung to and fro around square, but all closed off their lows as traders spotted value around the day's lows.</p>
<p>&quot;You started to see some buying come back into it,&quot; said a Sydney-based dealer.</p>
<p>Activity was mixed with the day generally one of small losses or small gains and with the single figure end result widely expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Banks were stronger and the gold index was slightly better. Most losses were in the transport, media and insurance,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>Best performers among the leaders were major miners CRA and WMC, which both ended firmer at A$20.15 (US$16.33) and A$7.85 respectively.</p>
<p>Outside the leaders, though, the pace was frenetic in the small miners, particularly those prospecting in the Gawler Craton region in South Australia.</p>
<p>Helix Resources shares doubled in value to A$3.70 from A$1.85 after a drilling report early in the day that confirmed additional significant gold mineralisation at its Lake Everard Project in the Gawler Craton region.</p>
<p>Other miners with exploration interests in the area also rocketed as players punted on the region as a gold play.</p>
<p>Rises just shaded falls, while 30 percent of stocks traded remained steady.</p>
<p>(A$1=US$0.8105)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
