<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222037" id="root" date="1996-11-27" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Nov 27.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Nov 27.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- The Finance Ministry's opposition to a proposed merger between Skandia and Stadshypotek stems from its ambition to use its minority 34 percent stake in the mortgage bank to engineer a rival tie-up with state-controlled Nordbanken, according to Anne-Marie Palsson, a board member of Stadshypotek.</p>
<p>- Industry &amp; Commerce Minister Anders Sundstrom says he will not force the closure of any nuclear power reactor before the next election in 1998. The Centre, Greens and Leftist Parties have demanded the closure of at least one reactor by that year, in line with a parliamentary decision to phase out nuclear power by the year 2010.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Goran Persson is in for a hard winter of discontent because public trust in politicians has sunk to a low ebb and people are ready to mobilise and protest against the Social Democratic government's inability to bring down the rate of unemployment.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- The planned Skandia/Stadshypotek merger is still on the cards, according to the mortgage bank's chairman Gosta Renell, who said he was surprised at the vehemence of Finance Minister Erik Asbrink's outburst against the idea. Skandia managing director Bjorn Wolrath said the fall in Skandia's share price since the announcement on Monday was &quot;normal&quot;.</p>
<p>- Centralised bargaining between Swedish trade unions and employers, in practice for about 100 years, should give way to agreements without binding figures, according to Heinrich Blauert, managing director of the manufacturing industry organisation VI. This is the only way to reconcile wage growth with other important goals - low unemployment, stable prices and economic expansion.</p>
<p>- Therese Rajaniemi, the unemployed mother who led a protest march in Stockholm on Tuesday, said trade union leaders should call a general strike if the government did not back down over a plan to curtail employment rights. &quot;It is the last weapon at our disposal. But if they won't listen, we will take it up,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- Investment bankers Merrill Lynch are advising the government on the disposal of its 34 percent shareholding in Stadshypotek. The handful of potential bidders will be asked to name their bids within the next week. The interested parties include GE Capital, S-E-Banken, Handelsbanken and Nordbanken.</p>
<p>- A direct ferry between Riga and Stockholm starts operating today, using the Polish-made roll-on roll-off vessel Russ chartered by ScanSov and the Latvian shipper RS Redereja. The two capitals have been without a direct ferry link for one year.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-27"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
