<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222115" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: New Canada tobacco policy &quot;extreme&quot; says Imperial.</title>
<headline>New Canada tobacco policy &quot;extreme&quot; says Imperial.</headline>
<dateline>MONTREAL 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's tough new measures to restrict tobacco advertising are extreme, said a spokesman for Imasco Ltd unit Imperial Tobacco, the country's biggest cigaret maker.</p>
<p>&quot;The government appears to be proposing a regime that is extreme, will probably be ineffective, will have its economic impacts, and possibly be illegal. And all of that without consultation with the industry,&quot; Imperial spokesman Michel Descoteaux told Reuters.</p>
<p>Canadian Health Minister David Dingwall announced the sweeping new tobacco restrictions earlier Thursday.  </p>
<p>Descoteaux said Imperial, which has a 66 percent share of the Canadian cigarette market, was disappointed with Dingwall's proposals, particularly those limiting the way Canada's tobacco companies can advertise their products.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the Supreme Court decision of 14 months ago, we have worked quite hard to develop a set of reasonable rules on advertising and other issues that would reflect the spirit and intent of the Supreme Court decision,&quot; Descoteaux said.</p>
<p>&quot;The minister seems to be heading in a direction that the Supreme Court never envisaged,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Descoteaux was referring to a Supreme Court of Canada decision in September 1995 that struck down a government ban on tobacco ads. Dingwall's new proposals call for banning tobacco advertising on radio, television or billboards.</p>
<p>The new measures also would restrict the use of tobacco brand names in community, cultural, sporting and other events sponsored by tobacco companies.</p>
<p>&quot;The Supreme Court dealt with the content of advertising, not the placement. And now the government is going to ban many forms of advertising which the Supreme Court specicifally upheld,&quot; Descoteaux said.  </p>
<p>It is too early, ahead of the final regulations, to determine how the minister's proposals will affect the tobacco companies' ability to do business, but the restrictions could put at risk such sponsorship, Descoteaux said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know whether he has left enough room for the continuation of the sponsorships,&quot; Descoteaux said said.</p>
<p>&quot;If we find that have to drop some of them because they don't make sense anymore, then the government will have only itself to blame for that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Descoteaux said Imperial will wait for more details on the proposed legislation before deciding on a response, and whether that would include another legal challenge.</p>
<p>Imperial is one of the three major players in the Canadian tobacco industry. Parent company Imasco is 40 percent owned by B.A.T Industries Plc, of Britain.</p>
<p>The other two big Canadian tobacco companies are Rothmans, Benson and Hedges Inc, owned 60 percent by Rothmans International, a unit of Rothmans International Plc, and 40 percent by Philip Morris Cos Inc, and RJR MacDonald, wholly owned by RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp unit R.J. Reynolds Tobacco International. -- Reuters Montreal bureau (514) 985-2434</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTREAL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
