<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222562" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czechs may decide on gas supplies in Jan - ministeR.</title>
<headline>Czechs may decide on gas supplies in Jan - ministeR.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech government may decide in January on how to diversify natural gas supplies, now coming solely from Russia, Industry and Trade Minister Vladimir Dlouhy said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Dlouhy, who recently called the diversification issue one of the most difficult decisions faced by Czech officials, told a news conference that the government was still discussing the matter.</p>
<p>&quot;We will search for diversification to ensure to have other sources at our disposition and not just one. Toward this, we are still searching for a decision on partners,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dlouhy declined to say which partners the government was considering, though government representatives have held talks on limited deliveries from Norway, which according to a preliminary agreement could start in January next year.</p>
<p>The state Norwegian energy company Statoil said on Thursday no agreement it had not reached any agreement with Prague but an early decision on who should meet the country's gas needs was expected.</p>
<p>The Czech news agency CTK reported earlier on Thursday that Prime Minister Vaclav Klaus had met several ministers to discuss the topic. It did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Dlouhy has said he would submit four options for securing gas supplies, but has given no details. He has said that Russia will remain the dominant supplier.</p>
<p>Ministry sources, however, recently told Reuters four options are being considered:</p>
<p>* Purchasing all natural gas from Gazprom, using two different shipping routes, with a long-term agreement until 2016, with price guarantees until 1998.</p>
<p>* Purchasing some Russian gas indirectly through Dutch company Nederlandse Gasunie NV, and Germany's Wintershall, a subsidiary of BASF. Gasunie would start supplies in 1998, delivering up to two billion cubic metres in 2005, with the agreement lasting until 2014.</p>
<p>In case of a fall in Russian supplies, it would deliver its own gas through Wingas, a joint venture of Wintershall (65 percent) and Gazprom (35 percent). Wintershall offers a similar scheme, with deliveries starting on January 1 next year, rising to one billion cubic metres in 2000, under a deal until 2016.</p>
<p>Negotiations with these firms are in the stage of initiating an supply contract.</p>
<p>* Finalising and maintaining the agreement for Norwegian gas, which has already been preliminarily approved this year, until 2017.</p>
<p>* A limited purchase from Mobil Europe Gas Inc, Germany's Brigitta Erdgas und Erdoel (BEB) and British Gas Plc.</p>
<p>The Czechs have ended their dependance on Russian crude oil by building a new pipeline to Germany, but are still completely dependant on supplies provided by Russia's Gazprom.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic consumes around eight to nine billion cubic metres of natural gas per year, but volumes are expected to rise to some 12-13 billion cubic metres by the turn of the century.</p>
<p>According to the preliminary agreement, which was initiated by Czech state-owned importer Transgas with Norway's GFU gas negotiating alliance in summer, expects eventual growing of the potential supplies to three billion cubic metres per year in 2002.</p>
<p>-- Alan Crosby, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
