<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222604" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Bosnian Serb general Mladic quits - report.</title>
<headline>Bosnian Serb general Mladic quits - report.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The man who led the Bosnian Serb Army through the 1992-95 war, General Ratko Mladic, has agreed to resign, the independent Yugoslav VIP news agency reported on Thursday, ending a power struggle with his political masters.</p>
<p>The agency said Mladic wrote to the civilian leadership in the self-proclaimed Bosnian Serb capital Pale to confirm that he had handed authority to his deputy, General Manojlo Milovanovic.</p>
<p>VIP said one of Milovanovic's first tasks would be to attend a ceremony on Thursday in Pale where he would transfer his hours-old command to General Pero Colic, who has the support of the civilian leadership.</p>
<p>The move ended a battle for control of the Bosnian Serb Army which flared earlier this month when President Biljana Plavsic ordered the retirement of Mladic and most of his senior commanders.</p>
<p>Plavsic replaced Mladic with the relatively unknown Colic, but Mladic and his old guard refused to recognise the new command and occupied the military headquarters in Han Pijesak.</p>
<p>The ensuing struggle between the war-time military leaders and Colic's staff threatened to erupt into a fratricidal conflict.</p>
<p>VIP said Mladic had set a number of conditions that were aimed at protecting staff who had remained loyal to him.</p>
<p>Mladic asked for written guarantees that &quot;the continuity of the Bosnian Serb Army will be ensured&quot;, that serving soldiers would be able to chose their futures and that their families would be taken care of.</p>
<p>He also demanded guarantees no inquiry would be launched against any soldier who acted on his orders and that no action would be taken against any of them.</p>
<p>Along with former Bosnian Serb president Radovan Karadzic, Mladic heads a list of people wanted for trial at the U.N. international war crimes tribunal in The Hague.</p>
<p>Mladic has been charged with genocide and crimes against humanity for his role in the siege of Sarajevo and the massacre of some 8,000 unarmed Moslems who had been sheltering in the town of Srebrenica.</p>
<p>Under the Dayton peace accord which ended Bosnia's 3-1/2 year war, any person indicted for war crimes was barred from holding an official post.</p>
<p>Mladic's continued presence at the head of the Bosnian Serb Army was a constant irritation to international mediators working to build a united Bosnia.</p>
<p>Although Mladic has quit, analysts say the Bosnian Serbs are unlikely to agree to him being extradited to The Hague.</p>
<p>He is revered as a folk hero among the Serbs and any extradition move could prove politicaly dangerous.</p>
<p>Mladic is expected to stay in Bosnia because analysts say no neighbouring state, including rump Yugoslavia, is likely to be willing to pay the international political cost of harbouring one of the world's most wanted men.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
