<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222714" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: Venezuela's Caldera plans no cabinet change-report.</title>
<headline>Venezuela's Caldera plans no cabinet change-report.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela's President Rafael Caldera said he does not plan to change his cabinet of ministers for the time being although a shuffle could occur before the end of his term.</p>
<p>&quot;At the moment I am not thinking about any change in the cabinet,&quot; Caldera said in a rare interview with leading daily El Universal published Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;But this does not mean, in my opinion, that all the ministers must stay until the end of the constitutional period,&quot; in February 1999, he added.  </p>
<p>Caldera singled out Finance Minister Luis Raul Matos Azocar, Planning Minister Teodoro Petkoff and Trade and Industry Minister Freddy Rojas Parra for special praise.</p>
<p>The three ministers have been the main proponents of an economic reform package launched with the backing of the International Monetary Fund in April.</p>
<p>Caldera said that despite the harsh effects of the program -- which has pushed inflation to over 115 percent and sent the economy into recession -- there were signs that recovery was around the corner.  </p>
<p>&quot;I dare to think that the hope of a better life is beginning to reach Venezuelans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have shown that we are on the road to overcoming a tremendous crisis.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
