<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222730" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>NICARAGUA: Faction splits from Nicaragua Liberal coalition.</title>
<headline>Faction splits from Nicaragua Liberal coalition.</headline>
<dateline>MANAGUA 1996-11-27</dateline>
<text>
<p>President-elect Arnoldo Aleman's Liberal Alliance coalition showed signs of fracturing on Wednesday when a dissident far-right faction vowed to chart an independent course in the National Assembly.</p>
<p>Enrique &quot;Cuco&quot; Sanchez of the Nationalist Liberal Party (PLN) said he will seek the powerful post of president of the National Assembly, breaking away from the Liberal bloc and looking for support from across party lines, including from the left-wing Sandinista Front.</p>
<p>Sanchez said he has enough support to get elected.</p>
<p>The far-right PLN bears the name of the party of former dictator Anastasio Somoza, who was toppled by the 1979 Sandinista revolution.</p>
<p>Aleman's Liberal Alliance is a coalition of four Liberal parties that had been divided until the campaign for this year's Oct. 20 election. A fifth Liberal party, the Independent Liberal Party, never joined the alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;The alliance ended on Oct. 20 ... The PLN is going to vote in an independent fashion,&quot; Sanchez, a founder and commander of the former right-wing Contra rebels that fought the Sandinista government in the 1980s, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not forming an alliance with the Sandinistas, but I'm looking for their votes,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NICG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-27"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NICARAGUA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
