<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="222983" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India SBI net up on higher yields, lower provisions.</title>
<headline>India SBI net up on higher yields, lower provisions.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reduced provisions and improved yields on advances and investments helped the State Bank of India (SBI) post a sharp jump in net profit for the fist half of 1996/97 (April-March), its chairman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>India's largest commercial bank, SBI reported a net profit of 6.41 billion rupees for the six months ended September 30, 1996 against 2.3 billion in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>SBI chairman Pandurang Kakodkar said the bank had benefited from an increase in the average yield on advances to 14.25 percent in the first half of the current year against 12.17 percent during the year-ago period.</p>
<p>Yields on government securities rose to 11.78 percent from 11.55 percent while yield on other securities climbed to 13.54 percent from 13.48 percent, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have also had to make less provisions for depreciation on securities this year as compared to last year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year we provided more than eight billion rupees in the first half for depreciaiton on securities.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This year the bank is saved of this burden thanks to the softening of interest rates,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bank had marked to market 65 percent of its securities portfolio as of March 1996 and planned to increase this to 75 percent by March 1997, the SBI chairman said.</p>
<p>&quot;Towards this end, we have made total provisions of 3.34 billion rupees towards depreciation on securities,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bank held about 110 billion rupees of securities in excess of statutory requirements, he said.</p>
<p>Kakodkar said a reduction in bad loans (non-performing asssets) had also helped SBI improve its showing.</p>
<p>&quot;As of March 31, 1996, the gross non-performing assets formed 16 percent of our advances portfolio. We are committed to reduce this to 11 percent by the end of March 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kakodkar said the bank had reduced the number of loss-making branches to 1,394 by the end of September from 2,261 at the end of March 1996.</p>
<p>Loss-making branches reported losses of 380 million rupees against the earlier 1.2 billion, he said.</p>
<p>The bank reported a 9.65 percent increase in domestic deposits, excluding certificates of deposit, to 955.73 billion rupees between April and September.</p>
<p>Advances of the bank, however declined by 4.13 percent to 496.72 billion rupees on account of poor demand for credit, Kakodkar said.</p>
<p>&quot;But this trend is being reversed...In October and November, our disbursals went up by 17 billion rupees after registering negative growth between April and September.&quot;</p>
<p>Kakodkar said the bank had brought only $100 million out of almost $400 million it had raised recently through an issue of global depositary receipts.</p>
<p>&quot;We will bring in the funds only as and when they are required,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The bank was also in the process of finalising the launch of its credit card, Kakodkar said. &quot;The project is likley to be finalised within the next six months.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
