<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223106" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Cemig maintained as hold.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Cemig maintained as hold.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Robert Fleming Inc said it is maintaining its hold recommendation on Minas Gerais state-owned power firm Cemig.</p>
<p>-- The brokerage cited the company shows little near-term upside potential for the stock based on fundamentals.</p>
<p>-- Cemig is run like a public company and &quot;squandered an excellent opportunity this year to maximize its operating margin,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>-- But the situation could change once Cemig takes on a new strategic partner, Fleming said.</p>
<p>-- &quot;We see the presence of a new partner as very favorable interms of managerial discipline, better preparing Cemig for a more competative scenario in which it hopes to be a net exporter of electricity to otherstates,&quot; the brokerage said.</p>
<p>-- Fleming said it is maintaining its hold rating until it sees more concrete signs of improvement in fundamentals or a shift in the firm's managerial style relating to cost containment.</p>
<p>-- Cemig's preferred was up 2.17 percent to 33.00 reais while its common voting share was trading 2.89 percent higher at 54.50 reais at 1127 local/1327 gmt on the Sao Paulo Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>-- James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 248-5413</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
