<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22310" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Huntsman denies seeking Eastman Chem unit.</title>
<headline>Huntsman denies seeking Eastman Chem unit.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Privately-held Huntsman Corp, which is set to announce two acquisitions in the next 30 days, denied that is seeking to buy the polyethylene business of Eastman Chemical Co.</p>
<p>&quot;To the best of my knowledge, we are not speaking to Eastman about this,&quot; said Huntsman spokesman Don Olsen.</p>
<p>Rumors that a transaction may be forthcoming boosted shares of Eastmam Chemical by 3/4 to 56-3/4 at midday. The gain came amid broad market losses.  </p>
<p>In a note to clients issued Thursday, PaineWebber analyst Paul Raman said Eastman Chemical may be seeking to sell the polyethylene unit to Huntsman. He estimated the value of the business to be $400 million.</p>
<p>In an interview with Reuters last week, Huntsman chief exeucitve officer Jon Huntsman said the company expected to announce two acquisitions in the next 30 days. He said one of the transactions would be the purchase of a major polymers unit of a publicly-held company.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not the business Jon was referring to,&quot; Olsen said of the Eastman Chemical unit.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Eastman Chemical could not be reached for comment. The PaineWebber report said Eastman Chemical did not comment on the speculation.</p>
<p>--Robin Sidel, 212/859-1723</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25120">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
