<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223221" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain urges fresh look at Africa.</title>
<headline>Britain urges fresh look at Africa.</headline>
<byline>Lyndsay Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said on Thursday it was time the world saw the positive side to Africa rather than dwell on coups, crises and famine.</p>
<p>He also urged Africa to take the lead in tackling its political problems and cooperating on economic growth or risk falling still further behind Asia and Latin America.</p>
<p>&quot;The truth about Africa is a great deal more positive than it was even a few years ago,&quot; Rifkind said in prepared remarks. &quot;Across Africa, the ballot box and the free market are seen by more and more people as the guarantors of stability and growth.&quot;</p>
<p>Rifkind was due to deliver his speech -- &quot;Africa: time to take another look&quot; -- to foreign-policy experts at the Royal Institute of International Affairs later on Thursday.</p>
<p>On the plus side, he said, inflation was down, democracy spreading and corruption on the wane. Warring factions have made peace, state economic power has diminished and the disenfranchised have embraced their newly won right to vote.</p>
<p>&quot;It is high time our views of Africa caught up with Africa's realities,&quot; said Rifkind, who lived in Africa during the 1960s.</p>
<p>While singling out success stories from South Africa to Tanzania to Mauritius, he admonished those countries that have not embraced democracy, free markets or human rights.</p>
<p>Nigeria had repeatedly stalled in switching to democracy, Zambia must demonstrate a commitment to economic reform and good government while Britain would only resume cooperating with the Gambia if forthcoming elections proved fair, said Rifkind.</p>
<p>As for the refugee crisis in eastern Zaire, Rifkind said Britain stood ready to intervene should help prove necessary but said the world must not get caught up in quick fixes. A long-term political solution was vital to ease ethnic tensions in the region and it was not Britain's role to provide one.</p>
<p>&quot;We should look to African countries to take the lead in tackling African problems,&quot; said Rifkind.</p>
<p>The Organisation of African Unity had made progress in resolving regional conflicts but did not yet have the capacity to deal quickly with such crises. Absent greater cooperation, he said, Africa would lag behind competing geographical blocs.</p>
<p>Nor did Rifkind contain his criticism to Africa, accusing some rich nations of stalling on trade and economic help.</p>
<p>&quot;In the case of South Africa we are committed to negotiating a free trade agreement. But the (European Union) Commission has been given a mandate which, despite the vigorous efforts of Britain, Sweden and others, is depressingly protectionist.&quot;</p>
<p>Rifkind expressed hope that forthcoming negotiations would yield &quot;a more generous approach&quot; and urged members of the World Trade Organisation to back plans for the developed world to grant tariff-free access to the exports of the least developed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFRICA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GAMB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
