<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223314" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Jesus painting said to shed tears in Bethlehem.</title>
<headline>Jesus painting said to shed tears in Bethlehem.</headline>
<byline>David Silverman</byline>
<dateline>BETHLEHEM, West Bank 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pilgrims at Bethlehem's Church of the Nativity say a centuries-old painting of Jesus has begun to weep just above the grotto where tradition holds that Christ was born.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a miracle and a sign that Jesus sent us to strengthen our belief,&quot; Father Anastasios, Bethlehem representative of Jerusalem's Greek Orthodox Archbishop Diodoros, said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He dismissed sceptics' belief that the weeping Jesus was a ploy to bring pilgrims and holiday cheer to Bethlehem this Christmas, the second under Palestinian President Yasser Arafat's rule.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know what this means for tourism, this is a religious matter,&quot; Father Anastasios insisted, saying: &quot;I saw him closing and opening his eyes.&quot;</p>
<p>Eli Udwin, a tour guide familiar with Christian sites in the Holy Land, said the painting likely dated back to the 12th Century, when Crusaders renovated the Byzantine church. Priests dated the painting to between the fourth and sixth centuries.</p>
<p>&quot;These reports of tears generally occur in the wintertime when there is condensation, especially in closed places,&quot; Udwin told Reuters.</p>
<p>Sadika Hamida said she was the first to see Jesus weep.</p>
<p>&quot;About four weeks ago, a light came from the column and the picture of the messiah Jesus, peace be upon him, began to cry.</p>
<p>&quot;It was beautiful, beautiful, beautiful. He opened and closed his eye and later tears fell, red tears,&quot; she said, pointing to red streaks at the base of the marble column on which the icon is painted.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been coming to this church for 22 years and it is the first time in history I have seen such a sight,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>Greek Cypriot pilgrims in the church on Thursday fell to their knees and wept before the painting after saying Jesus had winked at them.</p>
<p>Disbelievers dismissed the winking Jesus as an optical trick. They said one of Christ's eyes was brighter than the other, creating an illusion that the dark eye opened and closed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BETHLEHEM, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
