<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223363" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan eyes Iraq's U.N. deal to expand trade.</title>
<headline>Jordan eyes Iraq's U.N. deal to expand trade.</headline>
<byline>Suleiman al-Khalidi</byline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordan's business community is looking to expand links with its major trading partner Iraq under the United Nations deal for Baghdad to sell $2 billion of oil over six months, officials and businessmen said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Industrialists say they have their eyes set on the oil-for-food deal, approved in May but not yet activated, to boost private sector trade for a wide range of U.N. approved humanitarian goods the Jordanian industry exports.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope this deal will be an opportunity to expand our trade with Iraq and have a share in the oil-for-food deals...we are capable of competing on the basis of prices and quality,&quot; Walid al-Khatib, general manager of the Amman Chamber of Commerce told Reuters.</p>
<p>Jordanian industrialists hope the deal will allow them to substantially increase trade above a $220 million annual protocol that barters Iraqi oil for U.N.-approved humanitarian goods.</p>
<p>Jordan's Red Sea port of Aqaba has also been positioning itself for months to handle a sizeable portion of Iraq's import needs beyond the capacity of the Gulf port of Umm Qasr, officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq will depend on Umm Qasr for goods coming from the Far East, but cargo that is coming from Europe will go through Aqaba along will goods from the Far East that Umm Qasr will not be able to handle because of congestion,&quot; said Mohammed Dalabeeh, general manager of Jordan's Port Authority told Reuters.</p>
<p>The oil-for-food deal moved closer to being activated when Iraq earlier this month unconditionally accepted terms of the May 20 U.N. accord.</p>
<p>Jordan had also recently cut Aqaba port's handling fees for transhipments -- a move to benefit mostly Iraq-bound trade -- and has expanded land transport capacity on the 1,000 km (625) highway linking Jordan and Iraq.</p>
<p>Dalabeeh said that his team gained assurances in recent high-level talks with Iraqi officials that Aqaba was designated by Iraqi authorities as &quot;the main twin port of Iraqi ports.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is the first port after the Iraqi ports,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Business at Aqaba, which in the 1980s during the Iraq-Iran war became Iraq's main sea conduit, has dropped sharply since the United Nations imposed sanctions on Iraq after its August 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Dalabeeh estimated that Jordan's Aqaba port could handle at least one million tonnes of a total of 2.8 million tonnes of cargo that he said would be generated every six months by the $2 billion oil-for-food deal.</p>
<p>Jordan's 7,500 strong trucking fleet has also pinned hopes on handling a substantial share of Iraqi imports, truckers said. Extra cargo handling in the port could triple daily truck traffic to around 700-800 trucks daily from an average of 250 trucks that now includes oil tankers.</p>
<p>Despite a cooling in once close political ties with Baghdad, businessmen say they have neutralised its impact on trade ties by maintaining strong links with their Iraqi counterparts.</p>
<p>Jordan's industrial lobby see Iraq as a natural market that should not be jeopardised by efforts to win political favour of Gulf states as Jordan seeks to normalise ties damaged by its pro-Iraq stance during the Iraqi invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>A 24-strong delegation of Jordan's Exporters Association are heading to Baghdad on Friday to lobby for deals from pharmaceuticals to paints, businessmen said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
