<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223443" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily sugar report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>SUGAR: World market for November 27, 1996</p>
<p>White sugar futures in London held their established ranges at the close after profit-taking on the spot March contract offset earlier mixed buying, traders said. Outright trade and commission house buyers provided most of the overall volume. March and May both closed down $0.20 at $303.70 and $304.40 per tonne respectively. Dealers said the nearby contango could easily continue for some time as heavy supply weight down on the spot month. Raw sugar futures in New York finished at the session lows, pressured by speculative selling and a dearth of buyers, traders said. The spot month contract ended down 0.09 cent at 10.66 cents/lb after trading from 10.74 to 10.66 cents. The back months settled unchanged to 0.06 lower. Support was seen at current levels and then at a gap in the charts between 10.50 and 10.48 for March delivery. Traders pegged resistance from 10.75. The CSCE will be closed on Thursday and Friday in observance of the Thanksgiving holiday.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>BRAZIL - Striking Brazilian port workers returned to work on November 27 after controversial labor rules were removed from a shipping bill approved by Brazil's lower house, a union official said. According to union sources, the decision to end the two day old strike had been taken after lawmakers agreed to drop from the bill a clause which would have allowed members of foreign crews carry out tasks currently reserved for Brazilian port workers. The strike brought loading activities at key Brazilian ports such as Santos and Paranagua to a virtual standstill.</p>
<p>FRANCE - The beet campaign 1996 benefitted from favourable weather conditions up to the start of November. Then rains returned which slowed down harvesting operations in many growing regions. 95 per cent of the beet crop have been harvested by November 20 and 77 per cent have already been delivered to factories. These figures are near to the long term mean. Average beet yield per ha amounted to 55 tonnes and sugar content reached 18.9 per cent according to French Growers Association CGB. This compares to a yield of 58.2 tonnes per ha and a sugar content of 17.5 per cent in 1995.</p>
<p>MAURITIUS - Sugar production in September 1996 amounted to 142,843 tonnes, raw value, up from 139,360 tonnes. This brought cumulative production in the first four months of 1996/97 (June/September) up to 420,145 tonnes against 351,348 tonnes the like period the previous year. Total production in 1995/96 reached 571,515 tonnes against 529,671 tonnes in 1994/95. Sugar exports in September 1996 amounted to 78,954 tonnes, up from 73,220 tonnes in September 1995. This brought cumulative exports in June/September 1996 up to 282,912 tonnes against 237,632 tonnes in the corresponding period the previous year. Total exports in 1995/96 amounted to 565,608 tonnes against 525,697 tonnes in 1994/95. Major countries of destination in June/September 1996 were the United Kingdom with 200,440 tonnes raws against 208,067 tonnes, Portugal with 50,880 tonnes compared to 19,080 tonnes and the United States with 22,249 tonnes compared to 1,451 tonnes.</p>
<p>TENDERS</p>
<p>The European Union awarded 88,250 tonnes of white sugar at a maximum refund of ECU 46.704 per 100 kg at its weekly tender on Wednesday. Cumulative awards so far made under the 1996/97 series of tenders for the period up to November 27 reached 1,152,750 tonnes, which compares to 1,308,225 tonnes last year. El Salvador tendered on Wednesday to sell 6,250 tonnes of US quota raw sugar for shipment in January/February, traders said. Bids would be accepted on an executable order basis against New York's March No.14 contract, they said. No more details were immediately available.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
