<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223425" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Jewish congress extends Nazi loot hunt to Sweden.</title>
<headline>Jewish congress extends Nazi loot hunt to Sweden.</headline>
<byline>Tony Austin</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The World Jewish Congress (WJC) said on Thursday the Swedish government would help it look for evidence of unclaimed Jewish assets, possibly including looted gold, dating from World War Two.</p>
<p>Israel Singer, secretary-general of the WJC and chairman of the World Jewish Restitution Organization, said he had received assurances of this from Swedish Foreign Minister Lena Hjelm-Wallen whom he met in Stockholm on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If I didn't think there was something left here I would not have come. Yes, we do believe there is money, even gold here,&quot; Singer told a news conference on Thursday.</p>
<p>WJC president Edgar Bronfman said during a meeting in Oslo this week that &quot;a lot of money&quot; had been deposited in banks in neutral Sweden by victims of the Holocaust.</p>
<p>Foreign Ministry spokesman Staffan Bjorck said: &quot;We were welcoming and positive and said we would help. The WJC has made no demands on Sweden, but we will meet them at the beginning of December to set the task and decide how it should be done.&quot;</p>
<p>Singer said the task of winning moral and material restitution to victims of the Holocaust was urgent, not least because the average age of survivors of Nazi German concentration camps in World War II was now 78.</p>
<p>&quot;This was a war not only about killing people but also about taking their possessions,&quot; Singer said.</p>
<p>&quot;There were neutral countries which benefited from our deaths,&quot; Singer said, adding that Norway's response to WJC fact-finding had been &quot;remarkable&quot; and Sweden's &quot;satisfactory.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The response of Switzerland leaves much to be desired,&quot; Singer said.</p>
<p>Former U.S. Federal Reserve Board Chairman Paul Volcker, who heads a commission probing Swiss banks' cooperation with the Nazis in World War Two, briefed the WJC meeting in Oslo on the strategy of the commission.</p>
<p>He is starting an 18-month investigative audit with the help of accounting firms Arthur Andersen, KPMG Peat Marwick and Price Waterhouse, which were named last week by the commission.</p>
<p>Neutral Sweden's economic relations with Nazi Germany included substantial shipments of ore and business links involving a branch of the Wallenberg industrial dynasty.</p>
<p>Raoul Wallenberg, a Swedish diplomat and member of the same family, became a folk hero in Sweden and abroad for having rescued thousands of Hungarian Jews from deportation by issuing them with false passports.</p>
<p>The Riksbank, Sweden's central bank, examined the origins of the 188 tonnes of gold in its vaults this autumn and found no evidence that any of it came from Nazi Germany, the daily Dagens Nyheter quoted the head of its legal department as saying.</p>
<p>Asked whether Hjelm-Wallen had guaranteed to lift Sweden's secrecy laws to permit the probe, Singer said: &quot;The only guarantees we have are that everybody will eventually die, and that we are in a hurry.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We knew what we were asking for and we heard what she replied. I have to take the minister at face value,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Singer said the minister had agreed to appoint a number of officials to help the WJC investigators, who wished to follow up accounts of the war years describing the deposit of assets by Holocaust victims and certain looted metals.</p>
<p>&quot;There is guilt,&quot; Dagens Nyheter said in a leading article on Thursday, urging the Swedish government to cooperate from the start &quot;and learn by Switzerland's mistakes. They delayed until the last minute in admitting there was a problem.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
