<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223406" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French truckers vote to extend strike.</title>
<headline>French truckers vote to extend strike.</headline>
<byline>Christian Curtenelle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Striking truck drivers voted to keep up their 11-day stranglehold on the French economy Thursday, defying government calls to return to work after talks with bosses collapsed over pay demands.</p>
<p>Truckers maintained almost 250 barricades on main roads and tightened a blockade of the oil industry after talks broke down around midnight. The strike has brought petrol rationing in some areas, closed factories and stranded hundreds of foreign trucks.</p>
<p>Unions said grassroots truckers consulted about the outcome of marathon government-brokered talks with employers were voting to stay on strike despite repeated calls by Transport Minister Bernard Pons to go back to work.</p>
<p>Pons said most truckers' demands had been met and that the government mediator had successfully ended his mission.</p>
<p>&quot;We've got the result of the votes from the barricades in 15 to 20 sectors -- about a fifth of France -- and it's 100 percent for continuing the action,&quot; said Michel Fleurot, strike coordinator for France's biggest union, the pro-Socialist CFDT.</p>
<p>Other unions, noting a gulf with employers over demands for pay rises, said the trend among their members was the same.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps the truckers don't have a good perception of reality,&quot; Pons told a news conference. &quot;In a compromise, you can't get everything you want. Very positive results were obtained.&quot;</p>
<p>Pons said the two sides had agreed to cut the retirement age to 55 from 60 and reached accords on working time and sick pay, even though there was still discord over pay.</p>
<p>He ruled out using force to clear the truckers' roadblocks on highways, at ports, borders, refineries and fuel depots.</p>
<p>Pons said that despite the break in negotiations, a group made up of representatives of unions and employers would try to tackle the controversial issue of what could be defined -- and consequently paid -- as working time for drivers.</p>
<p>Some firms pay drivers differently according to whether they are actually driving on the road or waiting to load or unload.</p>
<p>There is also confusion as to what rates of pay apply to long-distance drivers during rest time they enjoy after unloading and before returning home or loading again.</p>
<p>Pons warned that &quot;if this working group does not agree quickly, I will propose to the government that we settle the issue by decree.&quot;</p>
<p>Leaders of main unions -- the CFDT, the Communist-led CGT and the non-partisan Force Ouvriere -- all told workers to stick to their roadblocks.</p>
<p>The state traffic information centre counted 240 blockades on major highways around midday Thursday, slightly down from 247 Wednesday. Snow and sleet fell overnight in some areas.</p>
<p>Strikers completed a blockade of oil refineries with barricades outside the only one of 13 that had escaped the strike so far, an industry ministry official said. About half the country's 400 fuel depots were blocked.</p>
<p>Force Ouvriere leader Marc Blondel appealed to the government to make one more mediation attempt. &quot;Talks must continue,&quot; he told Europe 1 radio. &quot;The big problem is wages.&quot;</p>
<p>The CGT said &quot;the government is alone in considering the talks ended in a success allowing it to withdraw its mediator.&quot; A CGT statement said the move effectively blessed the employers' refusal to grant bigger wage hikes.</p>
<p>Secretary of State for Transport Anne-Marie Idrac said unions and employers could hold wage talks without mediator Robert Cros. &quot;The dialogue is not broken,&quot; she told France 2 television. &quot;The mediation has been successful...Most demands have been satisfied even though the question of wages remains.&quot;</p>
<p>Haulage firms were offering a 1 percent raise and a one-off bonus of 1,500 francs ($300). Unions are demanding pay increases that amount to an average 23 percent.</p>
<p>The roadblocks have forced closure of some factories and cut supplies of perishable goods ranging from fish to fruit. Farmers reported shortages of animal feed as grain shipments were hit. The strike was also disrupting mail deliveries.</p>
<p>The strike and a parallel one in Denmark caused problems in other European countries, clogging highways and ports and disrupting commerce. Ports in neighbouring Belgium were clogged by trucks seeking an alternative ferry crossing to Britain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
