<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223451" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian bonds/futures closing report.</title>
<headline>Italian bonds/futures closing report.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian debt intruments closed lower but made up a bit of ground after an easier start in a dull session of range-trading, lacking direction from the U.S. with markets there closed for Thanksgiving Day, traders said.</p>
<p>Btp futures, feeling the weight of a 10-year Btp auction this morning, recovered a touch on the rise of Bund futures which set a new record high on Liffe but were unable to benefit fully despite the lira firming to a new historic high against the mark of 986.65.</p>
<p>&quot;Btps continued to stay in range, perhaps consolidating on recent highs,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>The December Liffe Btp slipped through support at 127.50 this morning but moved up again only to meet resistance around 128.00. December rolls over into March on Wednesday. March ended 8 bps off at 126.90. &quot;The roll-over's going pretty smoothly after some volatility Wednesday,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Traders noted there was no great enthusiasm over the Btp and Cct auctions. The Btps were assigned at a price of 104.05 against a previous 104.60 and the Ccts at 100.95 from 101.35.</p>
<p>On the interbank market. the overnight rate was at an average 8.02 percent against 8.13 but tom/next rose to an average 8.22 from 8.13 percent.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
