<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223432" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU formally warns Volkswagen over Italian market.</title>
<headline>EU formally warns Volkswagen over Italian market.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission on Thursday formally warned Volkswagen and its subsidiary Audi over distribution restrictions in the Italian market.</p>
<p>The warning, a statement of objections, follows inspections carried out a year ago at the companies' premises in Germany and at their common Italian distributor called Autogerma.</p>
<p>Volkswagen, which is already embroiled in another EU dispute over subsidies promised by the German state of Saxony, has until mid-January to reply.</p>
<p>At stake in the present dispute is the alledged refusal by the distributors of Volkswagen and Audi car makes in Italy to sell to Austrian as well as German and French consumers.</p>
<p>The Commission has received &quot;many complaints from consumers alledging that Volkswagen and Audi have developed a strategy, with the complicity of their Italian partners, to prevent consumers...to buy cheaper cars in Italy,&quot; the Commission said in a statement.</p>
<p>Commission surveys on car prices in the 15-nation European Union have shown that Italy is one of the cheapest places to buy a car due to a large extent to the depreciation of the lira in the years that followed its ejection from the EU's monetary grid in 1992.</p>
<p>Austria, Germany and France, on the other hand, are among the most expensive markets.</p>
<p>Under EU legislation which exempts cars distribution from competition rules, carmakers are allowed to conclude exclusive dealership agreements, but consumers must be able to buy the car they want wherever it is the cheapest.</p>
<p>The Commission warned Volkswagen it may loose the benefit of a so-called block exemption on car distribution for the whole European Union if it persists with its restrictive practices in Italy. It could also ultimately be fined.</p>
<p>The Commission had already made it known, first in October 1995 and this summer, that it would not tolerate VW's selling restrictions in Italy.</p>
<p>Italy's price advantage, however, is slowly shrinking due to the recent appreciation of the lira, now likely to be accentuated by its return to the EU's Exchange Rate Mechanism.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
