<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223544" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greek capital mkt commission sets trading rules.</title>
<headline>Greek capital mkt commission sets trading rules.</headline>
<byline>George Georgiopoulos</byline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's capital markets commission set a series of new rules for all 65 members of the Athens stock exchange placing limits to the daily trading volume of orders brokers will be allowed to execute.</p>
<p>In a unanimous decision, the commission ruled that brokers will be allowed to execute orders daily for amounts up to their equity capital. Trading volumes exceeding their equity capital will have to be covered by letters of guarantee, cash or securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The amount of daily trades is defined as the total of all buy and sell orders during the session. Prearranged block trades are excluded as they will be settled separately,&quot; the commission said.</p>
<p>The commission will apply the rule based on brokers' equity capital on December 31, 1995.</p>
<p>When daily trades exceed this limit, the amount over the brokers equity capital will need to be covered 100 percent as follows:</p>
<p>1. With a letter of guarantee from a bank which must be submitted before the opening of the trading session.</p>
<p>2. With cash, letter of guarantee or listed company shares which must be submitted to the clearing house by 9:00 a.m. the next day.</p>
<p>3. If the amount of trades is twice the amount of a firm's equity capital, its trading terminal will be automatically switched off unless coverage of the amount in excess has been secured in advance with a letter of guarantee.</p>
<p>4. All submitted cover for trades will be kept by the clearing house until settlement is completed.</p>
<p>5. For those Athens stock exchange members that were incorporated after December 31, 1995 and have not yet completed their first fiscal year, the commission will consider as equity capital their paid-in share capital.</p>
<p>When a member fails to provide the required coverage for trades exceeding the equity capital limit, it will be barred from trading in the following session.</p>
<p>Delays in providing coverage will mean administrative sanctions on the member, the commission said in a letter to the Athens stock exchange members' association (SMEHA).</p>
<p>--Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
