<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223574" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Thursday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Thursday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Thursday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Nicolaas Wegter said the Commission would host a conference on the role of the media in the peace process in Ex-Yugoslavia. He said participants would include journalists from Croatia, Serbia, Montenegro and Bosnia-Herzegovina. He said the conference was of great political importance and that the conclusions would be transmitted to the conference on civilian aspects of the peace implementation to be held on December 4-5 in London.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, spokesman Willy Helin said the Commission had sent Audi and Volkswagen a statement of objections warning them over distribution restrictions in Italy.</p>
<p>Asked about the Commission's policy on tobacco, spokesman Nikolaus van der Pas said its two main objectives were to adapt markets towards common organisation and to fight addiction to smoking. He said the main problem was to guarantee employment and health at the same time.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/96/1095: Consumers complaints in car sector: Commission sends communication to Audi and Volkswagen.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1096: The Commission lifts the TACA parties' immunity from fines in respect of inland rate fixing.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1097: Commissioner Christos Papoutsis welcomes EASDAQ market.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1098: Conference on the role of the media in the peace process in Ex-Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1099: 793 new transnational vocational training projects under the Leonardo da Vinci programme in 1996.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1100: Commission challenges U.S. origin rules on textile.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1101: High level meeting of the social dialogue in Dublin on 29 November.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/306: Speech by Commissioner Marcelino Oreja on European Fund for Culture.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/307: Speech by Commission President Jacques Santer on employment.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/308: Statement by Commissioner Neil Kinnock on &quot;continuing dispute in the road haulage sector in France&quot;.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/309: Speech by Commissioner Ritt Bjerregaard on EU budget reform and environment policy.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/311: Speech by Commissioner Emma Bonino on fisheries management in the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/312: Speech by Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan responding to Sir James Goldsmith.</p>
<p>- Press release of the high level group on the free movement of persons.</p>
<p>- Report of the high level group on the free movement of persons on supplementary pensions.</p>
<p>- Partnership, information bulletin from the centre for the development of industry No 27.</p>
<p>- ME96/28.11: Midday express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
