<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223540" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: SNB's Rich sees Swiss GDP under 1.0 pct in 1997.</title>
<headline>SNB's Rich sees Swiss GDP under 1.0 pct in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss National Bank chief economist Georg Rich said the central bank believed real Swiss economic growth next year would be less than one percent.</p>
<p>Asked for a forecast for Gross Domestic product (GDP) in 1996 and 1997, Rich noted that the International Monetary Fund had recently forecast 1997 Swiss growth of 1.0 percent</p>
<p>&quot;We would even say it will be less than one percent,&quot; Rich told reporters.</p>
<p>Rich also said the SNB was pleased by the reaction of the Swiss franc exchange rate to its monetary policy.  </p>
<p>Asked how he viewed the recent decline of the Swiss franc on foreign exchange markets, Rich said:</p>
<p>&quot;We are certainly pleased with the reaction of the exchange rate to our monetary policy.&quot;</p>
<p>The SNB has taken a gradually more expansive stance since 1995, especially since August when it began pumping extra liquidity into the money market. The Swiss franc has eased since about September.</p>
<p>Rich said he believed the SNB had laid down a good basis for growth through interest rate cuts since early 1995.</p>
<p>However, he said that it generally could take from one to two years before monetary policy changes made themselves felt in terms of real growth and up to three years to have an impact on price levels.</p>
<p>-- Zurich Newsroom, +41-1-6431 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
