<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223548" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French exporters renew air charter enquiry.</title>
<headline>French exporters renew air charter enquiry.</headline>
<byline>Stuart Todd</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shippers are renewing their enquiries on chartering aircraft to beat the lorry drivers barricades since the breakdown of talks earlier Thursday on ending the dispute, airlines, shippers and forwarders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Shippers were waiting to see if an agreement would be reached overnight, Wednesday/Thursday, before seriously considering the transfer of time-sensitive freight from road to air, &quot; a French charter airline official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Over the past week or so, there had been strong demand for ex-France air cargo charters to the UK and Germany with aircraft mainly carying automotive components.</p>
<p>&quot;If the dispute continues until the end of the week, some shippers wanting to despatch normally road-borne perishable goods will be faced with the choice of consigning them to the dust-bin or chartering an aircraft,&quot; the charter airline official said.</p>
<p>However, shippers continued to hesitate as long as possible because the price difference between road and airfreight was significant.</p>
<p>&quot;We had a request for information, for example,  for a consignment of apples which by road probably cost 25 centimes a kilo by road whereas by air you're talking six to eight francs per kilo,&quot; the official added.</p>
<p>Charter airlines would find it difficult to satisfy a further surge in demand from shippers.</p>
<p>&quot;We are at the busiest time of the year for the sector with every aircraft in the air.&quot;</p>
<p>Meanwhile, airlines continue to maintain some trucking services for airfreight despite these being prone to delays.</p>
<p>&quot;For freight originating in or destined for France we have experienced few problems but we do admit to having some difficulties in getting shipments from Paris to Frankfurt because of the road blocks,&quot; a Japan Airlines (JAL), cargo official said.</p>
<p>JAL had felt the impact of a 48-hour strike by Air France Europe staff more than the lorry drivers action, the official added.</p>
<p>&quot;We use Air France Europe's domestic network for the pre-forwarding and on-forwarding of small-volume shipments and the fact there are fewer flights to and from provincial cities, such as Lyon, Marseille and Toulouse has caused some disruption.&quot;</p>
<p>Road Flight Systems  (RFS), a road haulage company specialising in freight under air way bill said it was running a greatly-reduced service because of the road blocks.</p>
<p>&quot;While we are managing to maintain one of our main routes, Paris-Amsterdam, overall, we are only operating at between 25 to 30 percent our normal level of activity,&quot; an RFS official told Reuters.</p>
<p>DHL Worldwide Express said it was maintaining Boeing 727F &quot;contingency&quot; flights between Paris and Brussels, a route it normally services by road until further notice.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, DHL's air cargo services from Brussels to French provincial cities - Nantes, Bordeaux, Toulouse, Marseille, Nice and Lyon, were operating as normal, an official said.</p>
<p>Despite a growing shortage of fuel in France because many distribution depots are blocked , DHL had not had any trouble refuelling planes at French airports.</p>
<p>&quot;If the situation worsened, we would have to fill up to a maximum at Brussels and operate with reduced payloads but we are not at this stage yet,&quot; the DHL offical added. -- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
