<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223528" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Villeroy says loss in full-year 1996 inevitable.</title>
<headline>Villeroy says loss in full-year 1996 inevitable.</headline>
<dateline>METTLACH, Germany 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>German bathroom fittings and tableware maker Villeroy &amp; Boch said on Thursday that a loss for 1996 was unavoidable but that it expects to post positive results in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Profit-boosting and other necessary measures introduced by the company are combined with extraordinary charges and mean that a loss in full-year 1996 looks inevitable,&quot; the company said in a compulsory statement.</p>
<p>The company said it was confident that the measures it had taken would lead to a clearly higher result in 1997 and would secure satisfactory earnings capabilities in 1998.  </p>
<p>Villeroy says loss in full-year 1996 inevitable=2</p>
<p>Villeroy reported a pre-tax loss of 10.4 million marks ($6.8 million) in the first nine months of the year, compared to a pre-tax profit of 50.2 million marks in the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The unsatisfactory development in earnings is primarily due to a fall in sales in the high-earning bathroom fittings sector, and a successful programme of cost reduction was not enough to compensate in the period,&quot; the group said.</p>
<p>In the nine month period, total sales fell by 3.1 percent to 1.08 billion marks, with the group's bathroom division registering a 12.4 percent fall in turnover to 353.1 million marks.</p>
<p>&quot;Rationalisation programmes will take place in all areas of activity, to improve the earnings capability of Villeroy &amp; Boch. The sale of the Bamberg unit and the capacity reduction at Torgau are real steps in this direction,&quot; the company said.</p>
<p>--Clifford Coonan, Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($ = 1.532 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I24800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="METTLACH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
