<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223884" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Wallis raises Australia mega-regulator option.</title>
<headline>Wallis raises Australia mega-regulator option.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Wallis Inquiry into Australia's financial system has put forward several options for who might regulate the system in the future, including the option of a mega-regulator for banks, insurers, pension funds and other institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;There are four broad models for the prudential framework,&quot; the Inquiry said in its interim discussion paper released on Wednesday. The options include:</p>
<p>* keeping the existing regulatory structure,  </p>
<p>* having a single national regulator of deposit taking institutions (DTIs) such as banks, and a separate regulator for insurance companies and superannuation funds, or</p>
<p>* a single regulator covering both DTIs, insurance companies and superannuation groups, or,</p>
<p>* a mega-regulator that combines responsibilities for prudential regulation of all financial institutions with consumer and market regulation.</p>
<p>Currently the Reserve Bank of Australia is responsible for the prudential regulation of the banks and the payments system.  </p>
<p>The Australian Securities Commission regulates companies generally and the Insurance and Superannuation Commission regulates insurers and superannuation companies.</p>
<p>The Australian Financial Institutions Commission and the State Supervisory Authorities regulate building soceties and credit unions.</p>
<p>The Wallis Inquiry, headed by prominent businessman Stan Wallis, said it would not give any indication of which option it favoured, but that it would make recommendations on these areas in its report to the government by the end of March 1997.  </p>
<p>Treasurer Peter Costello has said he is interested in the option of a mega-regulator, but that he would like to see the report from the Wallis Inquiry before taking a firm position.</p>
<p>The idea of a mega-regulator is supported by some of the superannuation and insurance groups, but is opposed by the major banks and the Reserve Bank.</p>
<p>-- Bernard Hickey Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1812</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
