<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="223930" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Chronology of Taipei-Beijing diplomatic war.</title>
<headline>Chronology of Taipei-Beijing diplomatic war.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan suffered its biggest diplomatic loss since 1992 when South Africa announced on Wednesday it would switch formal recognition to Beijing from Taipei by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>The following is a chronology of the long-running contest between Taiwan and China for international recognition since a civil war split them in 1949.</p>
<p>-- 1949 - The Republic of China government retreats to Taiwan after losing civil war in mainland China to communists. Battle for international legitimacy begins.</p>
<p>-- 1949-1971 - Government in Taiwan holds onto United Nations seat and support of most non-communist countries.</p>
<p>But China, seeing relations with former Soviet Union collapsing after period of cooperation in 1950s, begins courting international support in late 1960s.</p>
<p>-- July 1971 - First clear sign of Beijing gaining clout as U.S. President Richard Nixon announces plan to visit China in 1972.</p>
<p>-- October 1971 - United Nations forces Taipei out of China's U.N. seat and awards it to Beijing.</p>
<p>-- February 1972 - Nixon visits China. Days later U.S. signs Shanghai Communique declaring that &quot;there is but one China and that Taiwan is a part of China&quot;.</p>
<p>-- September 1972 - Japan severs ties with Taiwan and establishes diplomatic relations with China. Deluge of others follow: former West Germany in October 1972, New Zealand in December 1972, Australia in January 1973, Spain in March 1973 and Malaysia in May 1974.</p>
<p>By end 1974, Taiwan maintains formal ties with only 32 countries, down from 65 in 1969.</p>
<p>-- January 1979 - United States seals cross-Pacific rapprochement by recognising Beijing as government of China, but retains close military and economic ties with Taiwan.</p>
<p>-- July 1990 - Saudi Arabia and China establish diplomatic relations after Riyadh switches recognition from Taiwan.</p>
<p>-- August 1990 - Indonesia re-establishes diplomatic relations with China that were frozen in 1967 after Jakarta accused Beijing of backing an abortive coup two years earlier.</p>
<p>-- October 1990 - Singapore establishes diplomatic relations with Beijing. China agrees to allow Singaporean troops to continue training in Taiwan.</p>
<p>-- August 1992 - South Korea abruptly breaks off diplomatic ties with Taiwan and switches recognition to Beijing, a Cold War enemy for more than 40 years.</p>
<p>-- July 1992 - Niger drops China to establish diplomatic relations with Taiwan, prompting parliamentary protests and student demonstrations in the Saharan republic.</p>
<p>-- July 1995 - Western African nation of Gambia switches recognition to Taiwan from China.</p>
<p>-- March 1996 - During visit to Beijing by South African Foreign Minister Alfred Nzo, China warns Pretoria it must cut off diplomatic ties with Taiwan.</p>
<p>-- August 1996 - Beijing coaxes Niger back into diplomatic fold, four years after the Saharan republic switched loyalties to Taipei.</p>
<p>-- August 1996 - South African President Nelson Mandela says only a man without morality would take money from Taiwan, as he had, and then cancel diplomatic relations.</p>
<p>-- October 1996 - Fiji follows precedent of other Pacific island nations Vanuatu and Papua New Guinea and signs mutual recognition pact with Taiwan despite ties with Beijing. China warns Fiji not to be deceived by Taipei's political plots.</p>
<p>-- November 27, 1996 - South Africa announces plan to ditch ties with Taipei in favour of Beijing, but says will take more than a year and that non-diplomatic ties with Taiwan should not be harmed.</p>
<p>Loss of South Africa would drop number of diplomatic allies for Taipei to 29.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
