<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22394" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA sues America Online over scores.</title>
<headline>NBA sues America Online over scores.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The National Basketball Association has sued America Online Inc, alleging that the United States' No 1 on-line service is delivering real-time information about league games without its permission, The Wall Street Journal reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>The suit was filed on Wednesday in federal court in Manhattan and is another legal skirmish over what constitutes a &quot;broadcast&quot; in the computer age.</p>
<p>The suit contends America Online was misappropriating NBA property by providing a site containing continually updated scores and statistics of NBA games in progress.</p>
<p>America Online chairman and chief executive Steve Case said, &quot;We believe the new online medium should have the same right to report on real-time events and news as television and radio.&quot;</p>
<p>America Online said its dispute with the NBA began three weeks ago, when the online company filed suit against the league in Virginia.</p>
<p>The earlier lawsuit seeks to have a court declare that American Online is within its rights in using the real-time NBA scores and statistics and that the NBA may not legally bar the company from doing so.</p>
<p>The cases are related to a suit that the NBA filed earlier this year against Sports Team Analysis and Tracking Systems Inc. The company provides data to America Online and is also a defendant in the case.</p>
<p>-- New York newsroom, (212) 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
