<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224014" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines to cut bank reserve requirements.</title>
<headline>Philippines to cut bank reserve requirements.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines' Monetary Board had approved a resolution cutting the reserve requirements on banks' deposits by two percentage points to 13 percent, board chairman and Central Bank governor Gabriel Singson said on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said the reduction will be executed in two tranches, with the first percentage point to be cut on January 3 next year and the next percentage point on July 4.</p>
<p>Singson also said the board had approved an increase in the minimum capitalisation of expanded commercial banks to 4.5 billion pesos from the present 2.5 billion pesos.  </p>
<p>Expanded commercial banks, locally known as universal banks, are banks which are allowed to invest in non-allied undertakings such as real estate and manufacturing ventures.</p>
<p>The minimum capital for commercial banks would also be increased to 2.0 billion pesos from the present 1.25 billion pesos.</p>
<p>Banks will have until two years to meet the requirements, provided that universal banks increase their capital to 3.5 billion pesos, while commercial banks, 1.625 billion pesos, after one year.</p>
<p>&quot;The new minimum capitalisation requirement was arrived at after thorough consultations and discussions by the Monetary Board, taking into consideration the increased trade and financial demands of the economy and, on the other hand, the need to ensure prudential standards,&quot; Singson said in a statement.  </p>
<p>Listed banks are given an additional six months to comply with the new minimum capital base.</p>
<p>On the reserve requirement, Singson said the move would free up 13.4 billion pesos worth of investible funds to the market.</p>
<p>Reserve requirements for thrift banks would be reduced to 11 percent from 13 percent, for rural banks, to 5.0 percent from 7.0 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;With the notable slowdown in the inflation rate in recent months, this is an appropriate time to further reduce the reseve requirements to levels comparable with Asian countries,&quot; Singson said. - Ramoncito dela Cruz (632) 8418938 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
