<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224186" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK's Hang Seng charges to a new high in early trade.</title>
<headline>HK's Hang Seng charges to a new high in early trade.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index charged further into record territory in early Thursday trade, in a drive which traders linked to the expiration of November Hang Seng Index futures.</p>
<p>The index was up 175 points at a new all-time high of 13,706 in the first few minutes of trade.</p>
<p>&quot;This big jump is definitely futures-related buying,&quot; said Chris Roberts, regional technical strategist at HSBC James Capel.</p>
<p>Turnover was HK$1.63 billion in the first 15 minutes of trade. Brokers said the buying interest was chiefly coming from market professionals and the retail sector including large regional players.</p>
<p>Trading in Hang Seng Index futures was also active. Brokers said open interest in the December contract was quite high for this stage of its trading, suggesting that those out of the money were rolling over their November contracts.</p>
<p>Technical analysts said the market has surpassed more than one target forecast for 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;For sometime we have recommended institutional investors exercise extreme vigilance and reduce their overweighting in Hong Kong, then watch for any sign of a crack in the index,&quot; Roberts said.</p>
<p>&quot;But we have seen no signs of a crack yet,&quot; Roberts added.</p>
<p>Analysts using fundamental criteria are also surprised at the record-breaking performance of the Hang Seng in the past few weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;The index has gone way beyond what any fundamental justification suggests it should,&quot; said Peter Rice, head of research at Nomura Research Institute Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Many stocks, including several heavy-weight index constituents, bounded to new records at the open then fell back.</p>
<p>HSBS Holding leaped to HK$168.50, a new record high then tumbled back to HK$163.00, down HK$0.50.</p>
<p>Sun Hung Kai Properties touched a new record of HK$101.50 then retreated to trade HK$1.50 up at HK$99.50. Its previous high was HK$98.00.</p>
<p>CITIC Pacific bounded to a record HK$42.50, then fell back to HK$40.50, down HK$0.50.</p>
<p>-- Kathleen Kearney (852) 2843 6933</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
