<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224270" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Nov 28.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Turkey - Nov 28.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Turkish press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>SABAH</p>
<p>- A draft law to cut the period of police detention in line with Europe is presented to parliament.</p>
<p>- Main opposition leader Mesut Yilmaz says his office is being bugged by the state.</p>
<p>MILLIYET</p>
<p>- A Turk resident in Hungary, Veysel Ozerdem, says he attacked Yilmaz in a Budapest hotel at the weekend because of the politician's criticism of a far-right gangster.</p>
<p>HURRIYET</p>
<p>- Ozerdem says Turkey has organisation of &quot;secret civilians&quot; working for it.</p>
<p>YENI YUZYIL</p>
<p>- International Monetary Fund report rings alarm bells for Turkish economy.</p>
<p>CUMHURIYET</p>
<p>- Experts split on whether the health ministry decision to treat drug addicts by giving them methadon is the right approach.</p>
<p>DUNYA</p>
<p>- Government preparing to reduce import tax on South Korean make of cars from 30 percent to ten percent.</p>
<p>RADIKAL</p>
<p>- Deputy Prime Minister Tansu Ciller sentenced to pay four billion Turkish lira compensation for slandering current coalition partner Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan during election campaign.</p>
<p>ZAMAN</p>
<p>- Parliament is to meet to extend emergency rule for another four months in southeast Turkey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
