<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224246" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia Bakun dam works to start on Dec 1 - paper.</title>
<headline>Malaysia Bakun dam works to start on Dec 1 - paper.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>Construction work on the $5.5 billion Bakun hydroelectric dam in Sarawak state will begin on December 1, one month ahead of schedule, the Star newspaper reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>Quoting Ting Pek Khiing, executive chairman of the dam's main contractor Ekran Bhd, the newspaper said the earlier start on construction would save millions of ringgit in overhead costs.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything (at the project site) is already ready for work to start. This will be a big incentive for the contractors to complete the dam's construction much earlier,&quot; Ting told a news conference.</p>
<p>The dam is to be built in eastern Malaysia's Sarawak state on Borneo island.</p>
<p>Ting also said that the investment arm of Malaysia's Ministry of Finance, Khazanah Holdings, would take up Malaysia Mining Corp Bhd's five percent stake in Bakun Hydro-Electric Corp, the holding company for the dam.</p>
<p>In October local newspapers reported said that Malaysia Mining was reconsidering its planned investment in Bakun, but the company issued a statement earlier this month saying it had not pulled out of the project.  </p>
<p>Ting did not say why Malaysia Mining had turned down the equity stake, the newspaper reported. Officials at Malaysia Mining were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Other shareholders in the Bakun dam company, whose shares are due to be listed on the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange, include Ekran (32 percent), electric utility Tenaga Nasional Bhd (five percent) and Malaysia's national pension fund (five percent).</p>
<p>The dam will be built by a consortium led by ABB Asea Brown Boveri and Brazil's Companhia Braseileira de Projectos e Obras.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603 201 4813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020011">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
