<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224390" id="root" date="1996-11-28" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French economy winces as trucker strike continues.</title>
<headline>French economy winces as trucker strike continues.</headline>
<byline>Christian Curtenelle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French economy was in a tightening stranglehold on Thursday after talks between truckers and employers to try to end an 11-day strike over pay broke down without agreement.</p>
<p>Roger Politti, secretary-general of the Force Ouvriere union, told reporters as he came out of the talks that negotiations had stopped and government mediation had ended.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Roger Cros (the government mediator) decided to put an end to his mediation mission,&quot; Politti said.</p>
<p>Talks broke down over pay, he said. Union sources said truckers asked for an up to 23 percent pay rise but employers were offering one percentage point.</p>
<p>Truckers would keep up roadblocks around the country which have started to strangle the French economy, Politti said. He added that employers and unions would meet on Friday to sign an agreement on some issues, mostly about pension rights, which had been agreed earlier in the day.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe's centre-right government had worked overtime to broker a deal between employers and truck drivers, who have set up more than 250 roadblocks across France.</p>
<p>The Force Ouvriere union led a 24-day wave of anti-government strikes with the Communist-led CGT union that virtually paralysed France in late 1995.</p>
<p>Sudden snow and sleet in several areas of north and eastern France, including some greater Paris suburbs, brought new misery to motorists trying to snake their way between barricades.</p>
<p>Adverse weather was the latest blow as more petrol stations were forced to close after supplies dried up.</p>
<p>Barricades around petrol depots and 12 of 13 refineries across France closed up to 2,000 of the country's 18,000 petrol stations and petrol rationing was imposed in some areas so that supplies could be maintained for fire engines and ambulances.</p>
<p>Tempers flared as frustrated motorists saw official cars drive up to petrol stations and receive precious fuel while they were denied supplies, eyewitnesses said.</p>
<p>Police were called to several stations where irate motorists refused to allow vehicles to jump queues, including those for doctors given high priority for supplies.</p>
<p>Roadblocks have forced fuel rationing in some areas, closed some factories and cut supplies of perishable goods ranging from fish to fruit.</p>
<p>School buses stopped running in the southeastern Drome department because of a lack of petrol. Factories closed their doors in several areas as they could not obtain raw materials.</p>
<p>Farmers reported shortages of animal feed as grain shipments were hit. The strike was disrupting mail and grain imports.</p>
<p>In a 20-hour overnight session which ended earlier on Wednesday, union and government officials said they made progress on two of the truckers' key demands, retirement at 55 instead of 60 and shorter working hours.</p>
<p>The strike and a parallel one in Denmark sent waves of agitation throughout other European countries, clogging highways and ports and disrupting commerce.</p>
<p>In neighbouring Germany, strikes threatened to disrupt production at Volkswagen AG, Europe's largest carmaker, and hampered delivery of fresh fruit, vegetables, fish, spirits and gourmet foods from France, Scandinavia, Spain and elsewhere.</p>
<p>Thousands of drivers from Britain, Spain, Germany and other countries were trapped by the blockades without enough food or money. Growing tension led to some violent confrontations with French truckers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-28"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
