<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22448" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain calls Israeli West Bank homes illegal.</title>
<headline>Britain calls Israeli West Bank homes illegal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain sharply criticised Israel on Thursday for approving plans to extend Jewish settlements in the West Bank and warned that it could jeopardise the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>The Foreign Office said it was concerned by an escalation of tension in Jerusalem and the Occupied Territories following Israel's demolition of a Palestinian community hall and its decision to build more Jewish homes in the West Bank.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that settlements are illegal and an obstacle to peace. We call on both sides to implement the Interim (peace) Agreement and to avoid taking precipitate actions which could throw the peace process into a downward spiral,&quot; the ministry said in a statement.</p>
<p>Palestinian shops and businesses shut on Thursday for four hours across the West Bank and Gaza, as well as Israeli-annexed Arab East Jerusalem, in response to a strike call by Palestinian President Yasser Arafat to protest against Israel's plans.</p>
<p>Arafat also condemned the government of right-wing Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu for its insistence that East Jerusalem will remain forever under Israeli control.</p>
<p>The PLO wants East Jerusalem as the capital of a future Palestinian state.</p>
<p>The Foreign Office said it regarded it as particularly important that the status quo in Jerusalem be respected pending resolution of its status.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
