<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224695" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Goldman Sachs committed to base metal trading.</title>
<headline>Goldman Sachs committed to base metal trading.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major investment house Goldman Sachs dismissed earlier talk swirling around the London Metal Exchange (LME) that it was considering downgrading its role in base metals trading.</p>
<p>Reinforcing this view a source at Goldman said a managing director of Goldman Sachs, Chris Carrera, had taken over market operations in London. He was recently based in the U.S.</p>
<p>&quot;The move of Carrera is the strongest indication that Goldman is totally committed to base metals trading,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Carrera will head all activities in London concerning base metals trading.</p>
<p>&quot;Goldman Sachs refutes in the strongest terms that they are running down their base metals activities,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Earlier on the LME floor some senior traders had voiced concern over the position of Goldman Sachs in the market.</p>
<p>The copper market has been unpredictable and volatile all year, particularly since the Sumitomo Corp copper scandal in June.</p>
<p>Sumitomo fired its head trader Yasuo Hamanaka, alleging he admitted running up losses of $2.6 billion in unauthorised copper trading.</p>
<p>&quot;The move of Carrera has no repeat no reflection on the Sumitomo affair,&quot; the source commented.</p>
<p>Copper prices slumped from above $2,700 in April, down to $1,745 in June, then rising strongly to $2,313.</p>
<p>Copper's backwardation was erased in September, only to flare up during the autumn months.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, Lehman Brothers Commodities quit the LME floor, although traders said their departure did not reflect losses, as Lehman's metals business this year had been profitable.</p>
<p>Other LME ring-dealing companies have also shed staff, but some LME member firms, both on and off the floor, are still expanding.</p>
<p>Paul Shannon, London Newsroom, =171 542 8080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I63000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
