<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224795" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: China syndrome shows meltdown in Mandela diplomacy.</title>
<headline>China syndrome shows meltdown in Mandela diplomacy.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Hamilton</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's decision to drop Taiwan and open ties with mainland China was hardly a bombshell but the way it came about dismayed political analysts exasperated by the Mandela government's foreign policy muddle.</p>
<p>Taiwan's ambassador got only 24 hours' notice of the move and lodged &quot;the strongest protest&quot;. South Africa's man in Taipei reportedly got a phone call 10 minutes before the announcement.</p>
<p>The foreign ministry's statement, read out by President Nelson Mandela on Wednesday, was so convoluted, apologetic and hedged with reassurances and time delays that reporters were not sure they understood its meaning.</p>
<p>South Africa said it would switch diplomatic relations from Taiwan to Beijing by December 31, 1997, an unusually long notice period that some analysts saw as a vain attempt to soften the blow. In fact, it may just prolong the agony for Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;These things are normally done immediately. It's the cold shower principle of diplomacy,&quot; said South African Institute of International Affairs director Greg Mills.</p>
<p>&quot;The pill was always going to be bitter whenever it was delivered but frankly this was pretty mind-boggling,&quot; said Mills, who has long advocated dropping ties with Taiwan in favour of relations with Beijing, as a matter of realpolitik.</p>
<p>Taiwan's ambassador Loh I-Cheng said the decision had taken him totally by surprise. Loh is dean of the diplomatic corps in Pretoria, a 45-year veteran of the foreign service who speaks perfect English and knows Mandela personally.</p>
<p>He said he had been led to believe that Taiwan ties would stay at least until Mandela stepped down in April 1999, and given his experience he is unlikely to have misinterpreted.</p>
<p>&quot;The Taiwanese could justifiably argue they've been misled,&quot; Mills told Reuters. &quot;Why now? This smacks of a presidential decision being handed down rather than going through the foreign policy making process.&quot;</p>
<p>Quite absent from critical dissection of the biggest foreign policy move made by Mandela's 31-month-old government was the name of the foreign minister himself, Alfred Nzo.</p>
<p>Nzo is frequently caricatured by the addition of ZZZZZ's to his name. The government's critics say Mandela and his heir apparent Thabo Mbeki really run foreign policy themselves.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the sort of ad hoc foreign policy we've unfortunately become notorious for,&quot; Mills commented.</p>
<p>&quot;It sends the wrong signals to Taiwan. They could see this 12 months as a window of opportunity that turns out to be false. They could waste a lot of effort trying to woo us away from a decision that can't be reversed.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan's foreign minister, John Chang, on Friday advanced his plans to visit South Africa in January and said he would be here next week to talk about maintaining &quot;maximum contacts&quot;.</p>
<p>South Africans were also asking why did Mandela -- who has said it would be &quot;immoral&quot; to ditch Taiwan -- change his mind?</p>
<p>Analysts said the prospect of &quot;losing&quot; Hong Kong when it joins mainland China next year had added pressure on South Africa to make a choice that loomed, anyway, as unavoidable.</p>
<p>Mandela may have also been swayed by the fear that his country's influence on the part of Africa at the United Nations could be hurt by a vengeful Beijing.</p>
<p>Whatever the reasons, commentators lamented the manner.</p>
<p>&quot;The government badly botched the way it went about reaching what seemed, from the start, an inevitable decision,&quot; Johannesburg's Star said in its lead editorial on Friday.</p>
<p>It had &quot;over-estimated the Mandela factor&quot; and tried to achieve the impossible -- dual recognition of both Chinas.</p>
<p>In view of their heavy investment and South Africa's assurance of continuing loyalty &quot;the Taiwanese could be forgiven for suspecting they have been used and then dumped&quot;, it said.</p>
<p>The political commentator for Business Day newspaper called the decision &quot;surprising and even bewildering, because it constitutes such a marked departure from almost everything (Mandela) has said before on the subject&quot;.</p>
<p>Mandela looked guilty of making empty promises, although he made clear his choice was made in a spirit of resignation, mixed with resentment at mainland China's &quot;blackmail&quot;.</p>
<p>Amid the damage assessment came a touching plea from the Taiwanese community in South Africa, which took out newspaper advertisements beseeching &quot;Dear President Nelson Mandela...The Taiwan people in South Africa love you...please do not cut our country off.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
