<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224765" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ETHIOPIA: Sacked Ethiopian deputy PM expected to face trial.</title>
<headline>Sacked Ethiopian deputy PM expected to face trial.</headline>
<byline>Jean MacFarlane</byline>
<dateline>ADDIS ABABA 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ethiopian Prime Minister Meles Zenawi said his sacked deputy Tamirat Layne would probably face trial for corruptly helping businessmen win contracts.</p>
<p>Meles told Reuters in a television interview that the Ethiopian authorities had arrested three or four other people in a subsequent crackdown on high-level corruption.</p>
<p>Tamirat, who was also defence minister, was sacked on October 24 and Meles told parliament at the time that he had &quot;fallen prey to the corrupting comfort of city life&quot;.</p>
<p>In the interview, which was due to be broadcast later on Friday, Meles said Tamirat was under &quot;government protection&quot; rather than imprisonment and unable to leave the country while investigations continued.</p>
<p>&quot;He was involved in unethical behaviour that facilitated inappropriate attempts by some businessmen to get contracts and so on and so forth. The details should be made available when the case is brought to the courts,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked whether charges woulld definitely be brought, he said: &quot;The indications so far are that there may be enough reason for us to go beyond a mere disciplinary move. The decision will have to be made by the attorney general but I'm told that the evidence so far seems to lead in that direction.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Many people do seem to feel betrayed and if there are any punishments, we want them to be done by the courts...He requested and we agreed that he should not be imprisoned but he should be protected from possible problems,&quot; Meles added.</p>
<p>The prime minister said the anti-corruption campaign was concentrating for the moment on the higher ranks of government.</p>
<p>He said: &quot;We know there is a lot of petty corruption. Our focus now is not on petty corruption, it is on what is called grand corruption. Once we clean that up I think it's easier to sort out the petty corruption at the lower reaches.</p>
<p>&quot;The real issue is how high up the ladder it reaches. And clearly in this instance it really did reach a very high level. (But) it's not as widespread as the rumours seem to indicate.&quot;</p>
<p>The prime minister said he was unable to give details of what charges Tamirat might face or the sums of money involved.</p>
<p>He said the affair could have &quot;short-term negative consequences&quot; on investment in Ethiopia but he was confident that in the long term it would be beneficial for the shift from a command economy to a free market.</p>
<p>&quot;The fly-by-night vultures who come in the guise of investors will be frightened away and I hope they get frightened away. The real investors...should be very encouraged because the steps we have taken in that regard have, I think, indicated to people that no matter what the consequences might be, we will not tolerate thieves in our midst,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said he was personally very upset by the affair. During the 17-year struggle to overthrow Ethiopia's Marxist rulers, he and Tamirat fought side by side and formed a close friendship.</p>
<p>He denied rumours that the sacking was the result of a power struggle within his government.</p>
<p>&quot;This particular incident was a case of one rotten apple among many fresh and healthy ones,&quot; Meles said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADDIS ABABA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ETHIOPIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
