<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224873" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia to announce Surgut probe results soon.</title>
<headline>Russia to announce Surgut probe results soon.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia's Federal Commission for the Securities Market will announce the results of its probe into a share issue by oil firm AO Surgutneftegaz in the coming days, a commission official said on Friday.</p>
<p>The official said the commission had completed its work in the western Siberian oil town of Surgut and had returned to Moscow.</p>
<p>The commission, which is Russia's main securities industry watchdog, said earlier this month it was examining whether investors' rights had been violated with the issue.</p>
<p>It said it had made a proposal to the finance ministry to suspend the issue and not to register it pending the checks.</p>
<p>The oil company's parent Surgut Holding (NK Surgutneftegaz) said late last month it had acquired an entire new issue of 500 million ordinary shares and 34.02 million preferred shares in Surgutneftegaz, raising its stake to 43.5 percent from 38 percent.</p>
<p>A senior official of Surgut Holidng said the shares would not reach the secondary market but some analysts said the issue was still a dilution of other shareholders' stakes.</p>
<p>Surgut Holding said the issue was made in accordance with the company's charter, approved by shareholders in June, and was intended to strengthen control over the subsidiary.</p>
<p>The uncertainty contributed to a fall in Surgutneftegaz shares, though they have since recovered somewhat.</p>
<p>The ordinary shares closed at $0.421 on the Russian Trading System, compared with $0.420 at Thursday's close. The preference shares stood at $0.294, after $0.292 on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Olga Popova, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
