<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="224961" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Romania press - Nov 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Romania press - Nov 29.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories in Romania's press on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy:</p>
<p>Business:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- The Romanian Development Agency endorsed the creation of the  Daewoo Romania SA bank, which will have a capital of 75 billion lei.</p>
<p>- Total direct foreign investment in Romania exceeded $2.0 billion at end-October, when foreign investors had reinvested some 3.0 trillion lei worth of profits.</p>
<p>TINERETUL LIBER</p>
<p>- The price of milk is expected to rise by 15 percent starting December 1. The rise is expected to trigger a jump in the prices of dairy products.</p>
<p>- Refinery  Petromidia SA, now working at 60 percent of its capacity, is running out of fuel.</p>
<p>AZI</p>
<p>- A new company,  Uztel SA oilfield equipment maker, has joined the bourse, bringing to 16 the number of traded stocks.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>-  Banca Agricola SA eyes privatisation through restructuring programme.</p>
<p>-  Radet thermal power authority has managed to upgrade heating plants in Bucharest on 45 billion lei investment.</p>
<p>- The leu is about to break the threshold of 5,000 to the dollar at retail currency shops.</p>
<p>LIBERTATEA</p>
<p>- The high interest rates on leu credits encourage illicit businesses and balloon financial bottlenecks, Razvan Temesan, president of  Banca Romana de Comert Exterior Bancorex SA, says in an interview.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- The present political moment is favourable for foreign investment, but what really counts is the quality of economic policies, says central bank chief economist Daniel Daianu.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- Romania's sugar beet output this year will only meet half of the country's sugar consumption requirements.</p>
<p>- The National Oil Company said a rise in the prices of oil products had not been discussed for this year. It said the government alone could decide on such a rise.</p>
<p>General:</p>
<p>ROMANIA LIBERA</p>
<p>- The Party of Social Democracy (PDSR) walked out during lower Chamber of Deputies debates protesting over the way in which posts on the leading board had been distributed.</p>
<p>ADEVARUL</p>
<p>- The &quot;constructive&quot; opposition promised by the former ruling PDSR, the National Unity Party (PUNR) and the Greater Romania Party (PRM) starts by boycoting the creation of a lower chamber leading board, a front-page report says.</p>
<p>- President-elect Emil Constantrinescu said Romania could join NATO as a full member by the year 2001. Otherwise the country's future &quot;would be in question&quot;, he added.</p>
<p>EVENIMENTUL ZILEI</p>
<p>- Outgoing Prime Minister Nicolae Vacaroiu will head the upper Senate's privatisation commission.</p>
<p>- Constantinescu lodged an application to leave the National Peasant Party (PNT-CD). Under the constitution the President cannot be a member of any party.</p>
<p>- PUNR and PRM deputies will not attend the ceremony for the President's inauguration on Friday.</p>
<p>- After the inauguration ceremony, Constantinescu will meet the leaders of parliamentary parties to consult with them over the designation of a prime minister.</p>
<p>CRONICA ROMANA</p>
<p>- PNT-CD sources said Virgil Magureanu might stay the head of the Romanian Intelligence Service.</p>
<p>ZIUA</p>
<p>- The newspaper prints the schedule of Constantinescu's visit to Alba Iulia on December 1 to attend National Day ceremonies.</p>
<p>CURIERUL NATIONAL</p>
<p>- The Social Democratic Union (USD), the second largest alliance in the coalition government, will get up to 13 posts of local prefects and the deputy minister portfolios in the ministries headed by the PNT-CD.</p>
<p>($=3,591 lei) -- Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
