<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225134" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Abortion clinic killer dead, suicide suspected.</title>
<headline>Abortion clinic killer dead, suicide suspected.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>An anti-abortion crusader who murdered two receptionists at abortion clinics in 1994 was found dead in his cell at a high-security prison on Friday after an apparent suicide, Massachusetts correction officials said.</p>
<p>John Salvi, 24, was convicted in March of the shootings of Lee Ann Nichols, 38, and Shannon Lowney, 25, in Brookline on Dec. 30, 1994. Five other people were wounded in the shootings.</p>
<p>Salvi was found in his cell shortly after 6 a.m. EST (1100 GMT) and taken to a medical clinic where personnel tried to revive him, said Nina Flaherty of the Norfolk County District Attorney's Office.</p>
<p>He was officially pronounced dead at 6:55 a.m. (1155 GMT)</p>
<p>&quot;It was reported to us as an apparent suicide and from initial reports it does appear to be a suicide,&quot; Flaherty said.</p>
<p>Salvi's attorney, J. W. Carney, had conceded in the opening statements at his trial that his client committed the abortion clinic killings but argued Salvi should be found not guilty by reason of insanity.</p>
<p>&quot;It was not unexpected, given that he was a seriously ill young man suffering from mental illness that was not being treated and was not being medicated,&quot; Carney said of Salvi's apparent suicide.</p>
<p>His conviction was being appealed, Carney told reporters at a news conference in a Boston hotel. Carney said Salvi had tried once before to commit suicide in prison and was recently beaten by fellow prisoners.</p>
<p>Witnesses at Salvi's trial said he believed he was defending the world's Catholics against an evil conspiracy that included the Ku Klux Klan and the Freemasons.</p>
<p>Officials at Walpole prison did not immediately return calls seeking comment.</p>
<p>Carney had argued in court that his client should have been sentenced to a mental facility where he could have received treatment, rather than the state's maximum security prison at Walpole.</p>
<p>But Ruth Ann Nichols, the mother of one of Salvi's victims, told reporters in telephone interviews on Friday that Salvi belonged in a prison.</p>
<p>&quot;Absolutely, he was where he should be after all the killing he did,&quot; Nichols said. &quot;If in case he was insane, something should have been done about it years ago, and then there wouldn't be all this killing and shooting.&quot;</p>
<p>Salvi was sentenced to serve two consecutive life terms for the killings and five additional terms, which would have meant 18 to 20 years in prison after the life terms, for attempted murder in the wounding of five people in what was the worst violence at abortion clinics in the nation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
