<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225256" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Lufthansa Cargo plans express, general cargo services.</title>
<headline>Lufthansa Cargo plans express, general cargo services.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo AG (LCAG) said it will split global air cargo transport services into express and general cargo from 1998.</p>
<p>The cargo airline will develop an &quot;A&quot; product with time guarantees and a &quot;B&quot; product for other cargo, LCAG Chairman Wilhelm Althen told a news conference.</p>
<p>The two services, a central element of the new logistics strategy, will be charged at different rates, he said.</p>
<p>Althen said test projects have been launched in Chicago, Tokyo, Hong Kong and London, and the logistics strategy will be extended to key markets next year before going global in 1998.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo had to cover the 70-80 world industrial production centres with time-definite guarantees, Althen explained.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can guarantee the client the good comes on time, then it does not matter how it gets there,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>These centres should be served by five flights a week operating out of four or five international cargo hubs.</p>
<p>The air network would be provided together with four or five partner cargo airlines to gain the market leadership on cargo trunk routes.</p>
<p>Handling at Frankfurt airport would be split at some point into separate local handling and transit cargo centres to simplify ground processes, Althen said.</p>
<p>Lufthansa would select certain freight forwarders as &quot;system partners&quot; to build up the planned logistics chains.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to concentrate on a few so-called system partners. They are not necessarily the biggest forwarders, medium-sized forwarders have the highest growth with us and they are the ones who can profit from our network,&quot; Althen said.</p>
<p>&quot;A system partner is someone who can go in our direction, whether it is a partner airline or a forwarder,&quot; he explained.</p>
<p>&quot;He must bring added-value for us and for the client, and that makes him an alliance partner.&quot;</p>
<p>Althen stressed: &quot;We do not want to become a forwarder. We do not plan to carry out these prior and onward transport services ourselves.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
