<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225203" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton briefly returns to White House, gets poems.</title>
<headline>Clinton briefly returns to White House, gets poems.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Clinton briefly interrupted his Thanksgiving weekend to return to the White House to work on his inauguration, picking up poetry books to take back to Camp David, the White House said.</p>
<p>Clinton returned to Washington by helicopter with his wife, Hillary, and daughter, Chelsea, spending less than two hours at the White House before returning alone to the presidential retreat in western Maryland.</p>
<p>The two women remained in Washington where Chelsea, 16, has dance rehearsals for a ballet performance, White House spokesman Mike McCurry told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;He came back with the first lady and Chelsea to do some work on the inaugural,&quot; McCurry said. &quot;He's got some work he wants to do on just the programme itself -- who's going to speak and what poetry will be delivered.&quot;</p>
<p>McCurry said that during the brief stop at the White House Clinton worked with Harry Thomason, a television producer and family friend whom the White House consults on major events. The two read poems and discussed which poet may be invited to speak at the Jan. 20 inauguration as well as what the event's theme may be, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Clinton was expected to remain at Camp David until Sunday, as previously scheduled. McCurry said it was not clear whether Mrs. Clinton and Chelsea would return to the retreat later in the weekend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
