<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225239" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Ex-Belgian minister defends child rapist's release.</title>
<headline>Ex-Belgian minister defends child rapist's release.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former Belgian justice minister vilified for releasing convicted child rapist Marc Dutroux from prison on parole in 1992 on Friday defended his &quot;difficult&quot; decision and said he had been aware of the risks.</p>
<p>Dutroux is the chief suspect in a paedophile and murder scandal which erupted in mid-August when two sexually abused girls were rescued from one of his houses and the macabre discovery of four girls' bodies swiftly followed.</p>
<p>&quot;I didn't sign his release papers with my eyes closed,&quot; former Justice Minister Melchior Wathelet told a parliamentary commission looking at apparent police and judicial incompetence in the cases of the girls' disappearances and Dutroux.</p>
<p>&quot;Many conditional release cases are serious...there are no simple cases...or ones where there are no risks. There are negative and positive elements, and at a given moment you have to come down on one side or the other,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Wathelet, a judge at the European Court of Justice since 1995, bore the brunt of public outrage over the girls' deaths for releasing Dutroux 10 years early from a 13-year sentence.</p>
<p>After Dutroux led police to the bodies of eight-year-olds Melissa Russo and Julie Lejeune buried in his garden, their distraught parents posted a notice on their front door asking bitterly of Wathelet: &quot;Has he a clear conscience?&quot;</p>
<p>The minister released Dutroux after considering opinions of concerned parties including the original prosecuter, social workers, psychiatrists and prison staff.</p>
<p>Two, including the prosecutor, came out against Dutroux's release and four, including the prison, were in favour.</p>
<p>Speaking under oath during a three hour hearing, Wathelet said Dutroux had been prepared for release by a special treatment unit in prison, and it gave positive reports on him.</p>
<p>But Wathelet said he recognised that in the reports there were contradictions, indicating the complexity of such cases.</p>
<p>Once Dutroux had been released social service reports showed he had formally fulfilled the conditions of release, presenting himself regularly and punctually to his social worker.</p>
<p>But Wathelet said a social worker could not keep tabs on every area of a prisoner on parole's life. Judicial, local and police authorities also played a role.</p>
<p>Parents of the dead girls were present in the public gallery at the hearing. &quot;I see a man who prevents me celebrating the tenth birthday of my daughter today,&quot; Jean-Denis Lejeune, father of Julie, told Belgian RTL-TVI television.</p>
<p>To head off a growing public confidence crisis in the weeks after August the Belgian government quickly approved tougher new rules proposed by the present Justice Minister Stefaan De Clerck on the early release from jail of convicted paedophiles.</p>
<p>These included setting up a special tribunal of magistrates to vet requests for early release -- taking the decision out of the justice minister's hands -- which would work on the basis of unanimity for paedophiles and in other serious cases.</p>
<p>It has also promised more special treatment centres, and an independent examinations of all 8,000 prisoners now on release.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
