<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225248" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bankgesellschaftacts to counter bad debts.</title>
<headline>Bankgesellschaftacts to counter bad debts.</headline>
<dateline>BERLIN 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bankgesellschaft Berlin AG, Germany's sixth largest bank, said on Friday that bad debt worries had forced it into huge provisions for 1996 and that its two chief excecutives had resigned as a result.</p>
<p>The bank, which had warned this month that it might need to raise its debt provisions this year, said it would set aside 2.2 billion marks ($1.43 billion) of provisions in its 1996 balance sheet.</p>
<p>Commenting on the decision to make the provisions, Bankgesellschaft said, &quot;This is to take account of the continued difficult economic situation in Germany, particularly ...the risk position in east Germany and Berlin.&quot;</p>
<p>It added that the decision to make the provisions was in line with the bank's conservative credit policy.</p>
<p>The banks two chief executives, Hubertus Moser and Wolfgang Steinriede, would be leaving the bank on December 31, Bankgesellschaft said. Wolfgang Rupf, currently a board member, would take over as chief executive from January 1, it added.</p>
<p>Bankgesellschaft, formed in 1994 through the fusion of three Berlin banking groups, has been constantly dogged by problems due to high risk provisions and costs linked to internal restructuring measures.</p>
<p>The bank reported a 32.4 percent slide in operating profit for the first nine months to 465 million marks. Its debt provisions for that period were already well above the 1995 level, at 612 million marks compared with 542 million.</p>
<p>In its statement, the bank said that it still expected to post a breakeven result for 1996 and planned to maintain its dividend at the 1995 level of 11 marks. It predicted a sharp improvement in profits in 1997 and the years beyond.</p>
<p>&quot;Against this background and on the basis of the group's solid structure, the management board is convinced that the group will register notably better orders for 1997 and the following years,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>Moser and Steinriede had tendered their resignations &quot;in the interests of continuity of the bank's development and in pursuit of continued clear leadership responsibility at the bank,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The supervisory board had accepted the resignations.</p>
<p>Speculation on the losses swept through German stock exchanges today after various media reports warned of troubles at the bank.</p>
<p>Bankgesellschaft shares ended down 75 pfennigs at 24.50 marks. The announcement came after trading had closed</p>
<p>A German newspaper had reported on Friday that the bank could face losses of up to a billion marks following the collapse of a number of companies owing it money.</p>
<p>($1=1.5362 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
