<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225343" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian soymeal export affected by moisture content.</title>
<headline>Indian soymeal export affected by moisture content.</headline>
<dateline>INDORE, India 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian soymeal shipments were affected this week as buyers waited for some consignments with high moisture content to dry out before loading, traders said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;Around 100,000 tonnes of soymeal, for November shipments, are lying at the ports,&quot; said Sunil Saboo, a leading oilmeal broker.</p>
<p>&quot;Overseas buyers are waiting for the consignments to dry out before loading for shipments,&quot; said another oilmeal trader.</p>
<p>Traders said heavy rains during the last fortnight of November had damaged a part of the soybean crop and disrupted harvesting.</p>
<p>High moisture in the soymeal reduced the protein content.</p>
<p>Overseas buyers have asked Indian exporters to load the consignments for shipment only after the moisture content was reduced.</p>
<p>&quot;But this is not a big problem and we will sort it out. We are not cancelling any contracts,&quot; said Neal Sahni, a foreign buyer, who had come to India to discuss the problems.</p>
<p>Traders said Indian exporters had so far signed contracts to export around 1.4 million tonnes of soymeal in 1996/97 (November-October).</p>
<p>Indian soymeal was currently quoted at $275 per tonne fas compared to around $218 at the same time last year.</p>
<p>In plant delivery conditions, soybean was quoted at around 10,300 rupees per tonne against 8,500-8,700 in the markets of central India, the hub of India's soybean processing industry.</p>
<p>-- Mohan Narvaria, New Delhi newsroom +91-11-301 2024</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="INDORE, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
