<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225407" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - Nov 29.</title>
<headline>INDIAN HEADLINE STOCKS - factors to watch - Nov 29.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors affecting Indian stock markets on Friday morning:</p>
<p>NEWS OUTLOOK:</p>
<p>**  Foreign institutional investors (FIIs) have slowed down their purchases of Indian stocks significantly this month, the Economic Times reports</p>
<p>According to figures provided by the Securities &amp; Exchange Board of India, the net monthly investents made by FII's upto November 22 stand at $86 million, compared to $233 million made in October this year, the paper says.</p>
<p>**  State Bank of India, the country's largest commercial bank announced a 179 percent rise in net profit to 6.41 billion rupees in the six months ending September 30, 1996 (April-March)</p>
<p>The stock rallied to 220/221.50 rupees in kerb deals after the results were announced. SBI closed at 216.25 rupees at the Bombay Stock Exchange on Thursday.</p>
<p>MARKETS:</p>
<p>**  Indian shares across major stock exchanges finished lower in dull trade on Thursday, with market attention focussed on major companies announcing six month earnings.</p>
<p>The BSE's  benchmark 30-share index fell 12.55 points, or 0.44 percent, to end at 2,871.02.</p>
<p>The National index  eased 7.02 points, or 0.55 pecent at 1,278.21.</p>
<p>The 50-stock National Stock Exchange index  dropped 3.61 points, or 0.43 percent, at 825.47.</p>
<p>The Delhi share index lost 4.22 points, or 0.64 percent, to 652.85.</p>
<p>The Calcutta share index  surrendered 1.68 points, or 0.42 percent to 396.81.</p>
<p>The Madras share index  was down 9.08 points, or 0.31 percent to 2,951.38.  </p>
<p>STOCKS TO WATCH:</p>
<p>**  Power firm, BSES announced a 11 percent rise in its first half 1996/97 (April-March) net profit to 941.9 million rupees against 850.2 million in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>**  State-run and India's largest steel producer, Steel Authority of India Ltd (SAIL) said its net profit for the six months ending September 30, 1996 fell 17 percent to 3.61 billion rupees from 4.3 billion rupees.</p>
<p>**  Textile and petrochemicals major, Bombay Dyeing &amp; Manufacturing Co. Ltd reported a 78 percent drop in net profit to 2.23 million rupees compared to 1.03 billion rupees.</p>
<p>**  Tata Power said its net profit shrunk 29 percent to 858.6 million rupees from 1.20 billion in the previous year.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I43000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
