<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225411" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Atlantic group backs ban on tuna from three nations.</title>
<headline>Atlantic group backs ban on tuna from three nations.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Commission for the Conservation of Atlantic Tunas (ICCAT) cleared the way for its members to ban imports of bluefin tuna from Belize, Honduras, and Panama, a U.S. official said Friday.</p>
<p>The three countries, which do not belong to the group, were warned last year that fishing of the giant tuna on their ships was undermining efforts to save the fish.</p>
<p>The commission, which met in San Sebastian, Spain this week, also warned Trinidad and Tobago, another non-member, that it could be subject to sanctions in the future if it did not curb its swordfish catches, and established penalties to punish members which flouted their annual fishing quotas.</p>
<p>The commission gave Belize and Honduras six months to prove they had taken steps to clamp down on bluefin tuna fishing before sanctions would be imposed, said Will Martin, ICCAT's U.S. commissioner.</p>
<p>The Panamanian government, which has told Panamian-flagged ships that their registry would be canceled if they were caught fishing bluefin tuna, was given up to January 1, 1998 to show that its measures had worked before a ban could begin.</p>
<p>&quot;Sufficient evidence was not put on the table that Panama had taken charge of the problem,&quot; Martin said in a telephone interview from Spain.</p>
<p>Most of the exports from the three countries go to Japan, which consumes up to 70 percent of the world's catch.</p>
<p>Japan, which had earlier questioned whether tuna import bans to promote conservation would be in line with World Trade Organization rules, was fully in support of the potential sanctions, according to Martin.</p>
<p>By notifying the countries of the trade ban threat, giving them time to respond, and reaching a joint decision in the commission to impose sanctions, ICCAT had met WTO requirements, he said.</p>
<p>Within the commission, members who exceeded their tuna and swordfish quotas would be forced to reduce their catches by the amount they overharvested the previous year. Repeat offenders could be hit with an additional cut of at least 25 percent of their allowed catch and eventually a trade ban.</p>
<p>Martin said enforcing compliance, as proposed by the United States, would not be easy. &quot;It's the first time that we've really put teeth into ICCAT....These are baby teeth at least,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Shunning calls from environmentalists for sharp cuts in U.S. tuna catches, the commission voted to increase tuna quotas in the western Atlantic by 150 metric tons to 2,354 tons, with the U.S. share up 33 tons to 1,344 tons for 1997 and 1998. The quota was calculated to yield a catch of 2,500 tons, which the commission's science body said was enough to allow for a slow rebuilding of the population.</p>
<p>North Atlantic swordfish catches were set at 11,300 tons for 1997, 11,000 tons for 1998, and 10,700 tons for 1999, the second consecutive cut to help stem the decline of the swordfish stock.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
