<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225414" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia names firms that traded with drug fronts.</title>
<headline>Colombia names firms that traded with drug fronts.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's government on Friday published a list of more than 70 international firms that it said had done business with local companies blacklisted by Washington because of their alleged links to drug cartels.</p>
<p>The list published by the Foreign Trade Ministry included U.S. firms Warner Lambert and B.F. Goodrich.</p>
<p>In all, companies in more than 15 countries -- including Germany, Switzerland, Spain, the Netherlands, Denmark and Italy -- did business with firms listed by the United States as suspected shell companies or fronts for Colombia's top drug lords in 1994 and 1995, the ministry said.</p>
<p>The U.S. list of Colombian firms with links to drug lords was made public by President Bill Clinton in an address to the U.N. General Assembly in New York last year. The Foreign Trade Ministry said it had compiled its own list of companies with past business ties to the suspected front organisations by auditing import records and other statistics.</p>
<p>The ministry also published a separate list of 50 companies operating in Colombia that it said had been involved in money laundering operations this year through the import of contraband goods.</p>
<p>It was not immediately clear if the ministry published its list at the request of the U.S. government or if Washington would seek to take reprisals against the international companies that appear on it. A ministry spokesman said the list had been turned over to the office of Colombia's chief prosecutor for further investigation.</p>
<p>Most of the foreign firms on the list were found to have served as suppliers or exporters to Laboratorios Kressfor de Colombia, a local drug company said by judicial sources to have served as a leading supplier to Drogas La Rebaja.</p>
<p>Drogas La Rebaja, a nationwide chain of discount pharmacies, is owned and operated by family members of the brothers Miguel and Gilberto Rodriguez Orejuela, the jailed leaders of Colombia's infamous Cali drug cartel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
