<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225532" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: U.S. data to rouse markets from slumber.</title>
<headline>U.S. data to rouse markets from slumber.</headline>
<byline>Adam Cox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A stream of heavyweight U.S. economic numbers will dominate the week ahead as markets return from a sleepy holiday period, analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>The U.S. is not the only hotspot. A number of European centres will feature, with German statistics in the lead.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an important time for the markets. We get a first reading on the November U.S. data. That'll determine direction on the bond market and expectations on Fed policy,&quot; said Ian Amstad, senior economist at Bankers Trust in London.</p>
<p>&quot;The employment report is obviously the big enchilada.&quot;</p>
<p>The November report on U.S. non-farm payrolls, often seen as the most crucial set of data each month, is due on Friday.</p>
<p>Before that, the U.S. has the National Association of Purchasing Management report and auto sales on Monday, October new home sales on Tuesday, housing completions and the &quot;Beige Book&quot; on economic conditions on Wednesday, and jobless claims and non-farm production figures on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. market is going to be formed from those numbers.&quot; said Graham McDevitt, senior analyst at Paribas Capital Markets in London.</p>
<p>He said the U.S. debt market had struggled in the past week to sustain its rally so the data would need to be fairly weak to get Treasuries moving again.</p>
<p>Germany will also be key.</p>
<p>Gross domestic product (GDP) for the third quarter is slated for Wednesday, with economists surveyed by Reuters predicting a 1.5 percent increase year-on-year.</p>
<p>German unemployment data are on Thursday, industrial production is expected from Monday onwards, and manufacturing orders are expected from Wednesday.</p>
<p>Amstad said the GDP figures would highlight a recovery in Germany. &quot;The overall feeling is that the economy is on a fairly solid recovery track and that should be underlined by the GDP figures,&quot; Amstad said.</p>
<p>But Stuart Thomson, chief international economist at Nikko Europe in London, said the jobless numbers on the following day would show how sluggish conditions remain.</p>
<p>He expected a rise of 20,000 in German unemployment, bringing the cumulative rise in joblessness to around 170,000 in the year. That, he said, would show the domestic economy was not strong enough to create employment.</p>
<p>&quot;That is going to hold back the consumer and hold back the recovery. The next move in German interest rates is more likely to be down than up,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As far as the bond markets are concerned, McDevitt said German debt was well placed to handle the data after shooting higher in a &quot;ballistic&quot; rally this week.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, there will be some attention on France, where markets have been watching for any gyrations in the franc, and on Britain, where interest rate uncertainty lingers after Tuesday's 1997/98 budget presentation.</p>
<p>&quot;Does the budget change the view that the BOE (Bank of England) will continue to argue for a rate hike in January?&quot; said McDevitt. &quot;It's quite clear the government is going for growth.&quot;</p>
<p>In France, where two Bank of France council members spoke out, arguing that the dollar is undervalued against the franc, markets will be on watch for any further comments from the central bank, analysts said.</p>
<p>French unemployment figures for October are due on Monday.</p>
<p>In Italy, where markets are still testing the water after the lira's recent return to the European Exchange Rate Mechanism, consumer price numbers are scheduled for Thursday.</p>
<p>Markets are speculating about an Italian interest rate cut soon, although analysts think the authorities will want to see a fall in inflation first.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6784</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
