<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225640" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq's dinar falls on fears of currency change.</title>
<headline>Iraq's dinar falls on fears of currency change.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The value of the Iraqi dinar, which soared on this week's oil-for-food deal, had slumped again by Friday on fears that the government planned changes to the currency.</p>
<p>Iraq's acceptance of U.N. terms for implementing a limited oil sale to buy food and medicine had more than doubled the value of the dinar, moving from 1,650 to the dollar on Monday to a high of 700 on Wednesday.</p>
<p>But the volatile currency, which has plummetted in value under the U.N. trade embargo imposed for Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait, slipped back on Friday to 900 dinars to the dollar.</p>
<p>Prices of essential commodities, which private importers must buy with dollars, also firmed following a dramatic plunge on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The dinar's slip began when Baghdad traders sniffed rumours the government had plans to withdraw high denomination bills and issue lower ones as part of a fight against inflation.</p>
<p>Despite government denials, traders for two days crammed Baghdad's al-Kifah district, where most illegal money-changing takes place, trying to dump their 250 and 100 dinar notes for dollars.</p>
<p>&quot;They gobbled up all the hard cash in Kifah. Demand for the greenback surged and the dinar fell again,&quot; said a shopkeer in the area.</p>
<p>Iraq's state television and Shebab television, a private channel run by President Saddam Hussein's eldest son Uday, interrupted programmes on Thursday night with a central bank statement that it had no plans to change the currency.</p>
<p>&quot;Such sick rumours circulated by foreign currency speculators...surface whenever there is an improvement in Iraq's economy and an increase in the value of the Iraqi dinar,&quot; the central bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Iraqi currency will not be changed and none of its denominations will be withdrawn.&quot;</p>
<p>The trade ministry also tried to help the dinar and push down prices. Newspapers, quoting a source at the ministry, said on Friday the government would increase the supply of food at prices below the local markets.</p>
<p>Iraq has four denominations in use. Traders mainly deal in 250 and 100 dinar bills. Lower denominations of 50 and 25 notes are mostly reserved for retail trading.</p>
<p>Bills of 10, five and one dinar and its fractions, though still legal tender, have been swept away by Iraq's runaway inflation.</p>
<p>The official exchange rate before Iraq invaded Kuwait in August 1990 valued a dinar at $3.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
