<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225711" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Helicopter crashes in Gulf of Mexico, two dead.</title>
<headline>Helicopter crashes in Gulf of Mexico, two dead.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-11-28</dateline>
<text>
<p>A helicopter ferrying workers to an offshore oil rig crashed in the Gulf of Mexico on Thursday while trying to make an emergency landing, killing at least two of the three people on board, officials said.</p>
<p>The helicopter crashed as it approached a Forest Oil Corp natural gas platform about 27 miles (43 km) southeast of Galveston, Texas, after making a distress call at 1708 EST, officials said. The third person on board was feared dead.</p>
<p>&quot;It was trying to make an emergency landing on a rig and smashed into the rig,&quot; U.S. Coast Guard Petty Officer Howard Brittain said.</p>
<p>The Aerospatiale 350, a five-passenger helicopter, was owned by Petroleum Helicopters Inc., a New Orleans company that operates 300 helicopters used to ferry workers to offshore oil and natural gas platforms.</p>
<p>A company spokesman said divers would be sent to the scene on Friday to join the search in waters about 50 feet (15 metres) deep. Seas at the time of the crash were choppy.</p>
<p>&quot;Weather I believe not to be a factor&quot; in the accident, said company spokesman Ed Gatza. &quot;Apparently there was a distress call, but we're not sure yet what the problem was.&quot;</p>
<p>The accident did not cause a fire on the offshore platform, Brittain said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-28"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
