<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22575" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: July new-home sales rate highest in five months.</title>
<headline>July new-home sales rate highest in five months.</headline>
<byline>Glenn Somerville</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sales of new homes jumped unexpectedly in July to the briskest rate in five months, the Commerce Department said Thursday, driving prices up in a strong housing market.</p>
<p>Sales shot up 7.9 percent last month to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 783,000 units -- the strongest since February, when new homes were selling at rate of 784,000 a year.</p>
<p>It was the largest increase in monthly sales since an 8.8 percent rise in January and was sharply contrary to Wall Street economists' forecasts of a drop in sales to a rate of 734,000.</p>
<p>Sales have been expected to level off or decline because mortgage rates have climbed significantly since the beginning of the year, but so far show little sign of doing so.</p>
<p>The Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp. said rates for a 30-year mortgage loan averaged 8.25 percent in July, down from 8.32 percent in June. But that was well above the average 7.03 percent rate available last January.</p>
<p>Analysts said beforehand that the availability of adjustable-rate mortgages, together with rising employment and incomes, have bolstered the housing industry.</p>
<p>Separately, the Mortgage Bankers Association of America said the volume of total U.S. mortgage applications fell 5.1 percent in the week ended Aug. 23.</p>
<p>The volume of applications to refinance mortgages fell 6.1 percent in the latest survey week, while applications to purchase mortgages fell 4.8 percent, the trade group said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the National Association of Realtors said sales of existing, or used, homes eased 0.5 percent in July to a seasonally adjusted annual rate of 4.14 million -- a second straight monthly drop, but still a higher rate than that recorded for any month in 1995.</p>
<p>The department said June sales of new homes fell a revised 1.8 percent to 726,000 a year instead of declining 5.3 percent to 734,000 as it reported a month ago.</p>
<p>Prices for new homes climbed strongly in July, with the median sales price jumping to a record $143,000 from $140,000 in June. The median marks the midway point for prices, with half of all new homes selling above this price and half selling below.</p>
<p>The average sales price gained to $169,800 in July from $165,300 in June.</p>
<p>Sales of new homes picked up during July in every region of the country except the Northeast, where they decreased 1.4 percent to an annual rate of 72,000.</p>
<p>In the Midwest, sales soared 12.5 percent to 144,000 a year and in the West they were up 8.8 percent to an annual rate of 223,000.</p>
<p>Sales in the South, the nation's largest regional market, rose strongly, by 7.5 percent to an annual rate of 344,000.</p>
<p>The department noted that the sales rate for new homes has exceeded 700,000 a year in each of the first seven months of this year. That is the longest string of sales at such a brisk rate in a decade, since an eight-month period from November 1985 through June 1986.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8500031">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
