<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225775" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Lufthansa cargo plans 7 pct rate rise in 1997.</title>
<headline>Lufthansa cargo plans 7 pct rate rise in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo AG (LCAG) said it plans two rounds of rates rises in 1997 to try to improve profitability and stop the fall in air cargo market rates.</p>
<p>LCAG chairman Wilhelm Althen said an early spring rise of up to seven percent would be followed by a second round of rises by September 1997.</p>
<p>The Deutsche Lufthansa AG cargo subsidiary raised rates to selected destinations by up to 10 percent and on certain types of goods from October 1 this year.</p>
<p>Althen told a Frankfurt news conference: &quot;As the market leader we must seize the initiative. We will increase prices next year.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;I think it will be about seven percent. There will be routes where we have to increase by up to 10 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The rates increase was likely to come into effect from March 1 and would be differentiated by routes and countries.</p>
<p>&quot;There will have to be a second round of increases in the autumn, in mid-August to September,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Air cargo market rates have fallen steadily in 1995 and 1996 due to over-capacity and weak demand in some markets, observers said.</p>
<p>Althen warned: &quot;If we do not increase prices then this industry will not be in the position to provide capacity and we would have to quit part of the market,&quot; he warned.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo made a loss of 66 million marks in the first three quarters of 1996 and does not expect to break even until 1998.</p>
<p>Althen said Lufthansa Cargo lost &quot;a lot of business&quot; to airlines which delayed introducing a cargo fuel surcharge until November 15.</p>
<p>Lufthansa Cargo added a global 10 US cents surcharge with effect from November 1, a move since followed by virtually all airlines in the freight business.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
