<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225749" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Dutch closing share market report.</title>
<headline>Dutch closing share market report.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch shares finished Friday at their third closing high this week, boosted by a strongly higher bond market which was surging in response to a record high German bund future.</p>
<p>Dealers said the continuing strength of the dollar was proving a strong incentive for international shares, while the higher Wall Street opening after investors returned from Thursday's Thanksgiving holiday gave prices an afternoon boost.</p>
<p>The AEX share index closed 6.83 points, or 1.09 percent higher at 631.06, above the previous 627.10 record high set on Tuesday but just below today's new intra day high of 631.21.  </p>
<p>Bond prices in Amsterdam were showing gains of as much as 1.35 points at the long end late on Friday, driven by a leap in the German bund future to fresh record highs.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything is looking good for the stock market with bonds up big-time, the dollar up a couple of cents in the last few days and Wall Street up,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>He said volumes were brisk, with strong retail interest evident. &quot;But I get the feeling that some of this is a bit panicky, a bit nervous. People don't want to feel that they've missed out, which is why every time there's a bit of a dip you get buyers coming back in.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dealers said institutions were piling cash into shares as bond markets around the region jumped. &quot;This cash has got to enter the markets one way or another,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>Dealers said the buying spree seemed set to continue as investors distributed their cash around the share market, seeking better yields than in bond and money markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors don't want to put their money on short term deposit at rates of 2-1/2 to three percent and they don't want to lock into the bond market for 10 years at 5-1/2 percent. They still think they can make more money in stocks,&quot; said a dealer.  </p>
<p>Dealers said buyers seemed intent on picking out stocks which had been seen as underperforming. &quot;A lot of people seem to have certain targets for stocks and they're buying them up to those levels -- it's a bit speculative,&quot; said another dealer.</p>
<p>Royal Dutch moved ahead on the back of the firm dollar, closing 5.30 guilders higher at 290.80, while Unilever put on 4.80 guilders to 298.40 for the same reason.</p>
<p>ABN AMRO added 1.50 guilders to 111.70, boosted by positive analysts' comment on its proposed takeover of Standard Federal in the United States. Fortis climbed a guilder to 57.50 on yesterday's nine months results and improved profit estimate.  </p>
<p>Philips was up 1.10 guilders 69.50, boosted by yesterday's news that its plans to restructure its Sound and Vision unit were on course.</p>
<p>Chemicals firm Akzo gained 90 cents to 229.50 while in the same sector DSM was up 1.40 guilders to 167.00. -- Keiron Henderson, Amsterdam Newsroom +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
