<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225826" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Bonn confident on EMU as parliament passes budget.</title>
<headline>Bonn confident on EMU as parliament passes budget.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's Bundestag lower house of parliament on Friday passed Finance Minister Theo Waigel's 1997 federal budget into law, putting Germany on course to qualify for European economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>Deputies voted by 336 to 313 in favour of the budget, which plans to cut the federal deficit to 53.3 billion marks ($34.77 billion) from an expected 73 billion marks this year.</p>
<p>Taken together with states and municipalities, the total public deficit is on course for 2.5 percent of gross domestic product, below Maastricht's three percent limit, Waigel said.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers show that Germany will qualify for monetary union,&quot; he told the fourth and final day of the budget debate.</p>
<p>Waigel's 1997 budget, first presented in July, has gone through a rocky path of borrowing overshoots, coalition rows and emergency spending cuts to cover likely revenue shortfalls.</p>
<p>The opposition Social Democrats (SPD) kept up their attack on Waigel's credibility, saying that after missing borrowing targets this year the same would happen again in 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;None of the country's problems will be resolved by this budget,&quot; SPD finance spokeswoman Ingrid Mattaeus-Maier said.</p>
<p>Matthaeus-Maier accused Waigel of using the sort of creative accounting which Germany has criticised in other European countries seeking to join the first wave of EMU.</p>
<p>Waigel hit back by saying that his budget would cut back spending by 2.5 percent to 440 billion marks next year. He said the government was on track to reduce spending -- burdened by the costs of unification in 1990 and high unemployment -- back to levels last seen in the late 1980s by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Waigel also rejected criticism of his position on EMU by Bank of France member Jean-Pierre Gerard, who said devaluation of the French currency against the mark could become necessary because of Germany's hardline position on a EMU stability pact.</p>
<p>Germany insists European Union members agree on a stability pact that would punish EMU participants who ease fiscal discipline after EMU's start in 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;A European stability pact ensures the stability of the euro. Only a stable monetary union can create economic growth and jobs in Germany and Europe,&quot; he said. &quot;Growth and jobs cannot be created through targeted exchange policies.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition to defeat on the budget, the SPD had to concede that its bid to block Waigel's 1997 tax bill with its majority in the Bundesrat upper house of parliament had failed.</p>
<p>The SPD has been battling to preven the abolition of wealth taxes -- which had been ruled illegal by the constitutional court and would be scrapped automatically next year.</p>
<p>Waigel defended the abolition of the tax, saying it would be offset by increases in inheritance taxes.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact is, that with the end of the wealth tax there will be no tax giveaway for the rich,&quot; Waigel told deputies.</p>
<p>Waigel's tax bill has gone into parliament's mediation process, and negotiators on Thursday reported progress towards offsetting the resulting nine billion mark shortfall in funding which would hit Germany's 16 states.</p>
<p>Talks will continue next Wednesday on drafting a compromise measure which would be put to a final vote in the Bundesrat.</p>
<p>($1=1.5330 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
