<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225888" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Past casts shadow over European security summit.</title>
<headline>Past casts shadow over European security summit.</headline>
<byline>Richard Waddington</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A European summit sets out on Monday to lay the foundations of peace for the 21st century but with divisions and animosities of the past casting long shadows.</p>
<p>The 54-nation Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) aims to agree at a meeting in Lisbon on a blueprint -- a security model -- for closer cooperation between countries that were on different sides of the Cold War.</p>
<p>Encouraged by the OSCE's recent success in organising elections in Bosnia, government leaders from North America and all of Europe will look at ways of strengthening the organisation and boosting its effectiveness.</p>
<p>Since its birth in 1975 in Helsinki as an East-West forum for discussing issues from democracy to economics, the security body has played a key role in bringing about arms reductions, organising ballots and giving early warning of looming ethnic conflicts in the former Soviet empire.</p>
<p>But the challenge facing the 54 member states -- there were 55 but Yugoslavia was suspended in 1992 -- is to decide where the organisation should go from here.</p>
<p>Russia, deeply suspicious of NATO plans to expand up to its borders, wants an ever greater role for OSCE as a counterbalance to the U.S.-led military alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not want (OSCE) to become some sort of commander-in-chief of European organisations,&quot; Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin, who heads the Russian delegation to Lisbon, told Portuguese newspaper Publico in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;(But) it should have a coordinating role. It has all the necessary characteristics,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Washington rejects any link between the expansion of NATO, with Poland, Hungary and the Czech Republic expected to join before the end of the century, and the development of OSCE.</p>
<p>Others are also reluctant to agree to Russia's proposals for strengthening the European security forum -- even though diplomats say a failure to address Russian concerns could mean more opposition from Moscow as NATO takes in new members.</p>
<p>As closed-door sessions continued on a draft document, there were signs of disagreement between the U.S. and some of its European allies over how to handle Moscow.</p>
<p>&quot;Some feel that we should move towards Russia, extend it a hand, while the Americans see no need,&quot; said one OSCE official.</p>
<p>The last OSCE summit in Budapest in 1994 was wrecked by a row over the Bosnian war and warnings from Russian President Boris Yeltsin that NATO risked plunging Europe into a &quot;Cold Peace&quot;.</p>
<p>Yeltsin will not be in Lisbon because of his recent heart surgery. President Bill Clinton will also not attend and the U.S. delegation is to be headed by Vice President Al Gore.</p>
<p>OSCE officials and diplomats do not see any repeat of the public bickering that marred the previous summit, even if there is still some hard bargaining to be done before the planned Lisbon Declaration is ready.</p>
<p>&quot;We are confident that there will be a document that all delegations can sign,&quot; said one diplomat.</p>
<p>Russian concerns over NATO remain, but the overall European mood has improved since Budapest when the bloody fighting in Bosnia was deepening a sense of international impotence.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not in the same situation at all. The atmosphere is a lot calmer,&quot; said one European diplomat.</p>
<p>But the expected presence of President Alexander Lukashenko of Belarus, who recently won a highly controversial referendum extending his personal powers, will be a reminder of the multiple problems still to be resolved.</p>
<p>Lithuania has suggested to fellow neighbours Poland and Ukraine that they hold a regional presidents' meeting in Lisbon to discuss Belarus' constitutional turmoil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
