<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225804" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: UN seeks $544 million for former Yugoslavia.</title>
<headline>UN seeks $544 million for former Yugoslavia.</headline>
<byline>Stephanie Nebehay</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations appealed on Friday for $544.7 million for former Yugoslavia, mainly to rebuild homes and ease the return of two million people still displaced a year after the signing of the Dayton peace accord.</p>
<p>But the returnees face major hurdles, including landmines, lack of homes and jobs, as well as the refusal of local authorities to allow them to resettle in ethnic minority areas.</p>
<p>Only 250,000 have returned to their homes, mostly to areas where their groups constitute an ethnic majority, according to the U.N. refugee agency.</p>
<p>The appeal, launched by 11 U.N. agencies, covers humanitarian activities during 1997 in Bosnia, Croatia, the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, and Macedonia. Bosnia, where roughly two million people now receive aid, is in line to receive $372 million.</p>
<p>&quot;The main obstacles for returning home continue to be obstruction, lack of confidence and the destruction of homes,&quot; U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees Sadako Ogata and Yasushi Akashi, under secretary-general for humanitarian affairs, said in a joint statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The international community must continue to assist with the rebuilding of homes, and with the building of bridges between the people,&quot; they added.</p>
<p>Ogata, in a separate statement appealing for funds, added: &quot;1997 is the second year of peace in Bosnia. UNHCR wants to make it the year of return and organised repatriation.&quot;</p>
<p>Ethnic tensions and evictions continue in Bosnia, and complete freedom of movement has not been achieved, according to the agency. Some 60 per cent of housing was damaged in the war.</p>
<p>&quot;The first year of the peace process has not yielded the number of refugee returns to Bosnia and Herzegovina that were anticipated,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>UNHCR -- which was the leading humanitarian agency in Bosnia during the three-and-a-half-year war and ran the Western airlift of supplies, -- is seeking $236 million under the appeal.</p>
<p>The agency said it would continue to encourage returns to 22 &quot;target areas&quot; in Bosnia, where considerable progress had been made in rebuilding houses and water supply systems. It also planned to increase the number of such areas next year.</p>
<p>UNHCR said it would increase its efforts to protect returnees and would monitor and report on their treatment.</p>
<p>&quot;In cooperation with countries of asylum, UNHCR will facilitate the return of refugees from abroad,&quot; it said, adding that half of its $125 million budget for Bosnia would be focused on persons returning from abroad.</p>
<p>The Rome-based World Food Programme, which is resuming overall responsibility for food aid and distribution, is seeking $116 million.</p>
<p>The overall appeal represents a drop of nearly 33 per cent of the amount requested last year.</p>
<p>The World Bank and the European Union estimate that $5.8 billion in foreign aid is needed for Bosnia for the three-year period 1996-98. As of the end of last October, rehabilitation and reconstruction projects worth $1 billion were underway.</p>
<p>&quot;Although significant, this work funded by donors represents repair of only about five per cent of the damage to infrastructure caused during the war,&quot; the appeal document said.</p>
<p>The International Organisation for Migration, which arranges the movement of refugees and migrants to new homes, is in line to receive $25 million. The Geneva-based IOM aims to help 1,000 qualified experts residing abroad to return to jobs in Bosnia.</p>
<p>UNICEF, the U.N. Children's Fund, said it needed $18.9 million to pay for immunising 900,000 children and providing psycho-social servcies to young trauma victims.</p>
<p>The appeal also covers deploying 2,000 deminers to remove landmines during the winter months. The United Nations needs $62 million for its mine clearance and awareness campaign.</p>
<p>Other agencies taking part include the World Health Organisation, the Food and Agriculture Organisation, the U.N. Development Programme and the International Labour Organisation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCDNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
