<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="225817" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Friday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Friday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Friday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Jean Christophe Filori said Commissioner Neil Kinnock had expressed his concern for the freedom of people and goods in Europe since the start of the French hauliers' strike and had asked French authorities in a letter sent on Thursday night to take necessary measures to allow non-French truckers caught in the strikers' barricades to go home.</p>
<p>Spokesman Patrick Child briefed on Monday's ECOFIN Council. He said discussions would focus on Economic and Monetary Union, proposals for a stability pact, preparation of the Dutch presidency, VAT and SEM 2000.</p>
<p>Spokesman Josep Coll i Carbo said Commissioner Manuel Marin would be on an official visit in Algeria on Sunday and Monday in the framework of the Euro-Mediterranean partnership. He said Marin would meet Algerian President Liamine Zeroual, Foreign Minister Ahmed Attaf, Industry Minister Abdessalam Bouchouareb and Finance Minister Abdelkrim Harchaoui. He said Marin would hold a news conference at 1700/1600 GMT on Monday.</p>
<p>Spokesman Gerry Kiely said he was not aware of discussions on a possible lifting of the ban on beef products from Northern Ireland as suggested in recent news reports.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/96/1090: Cooperation between the European Union candidate countries in the field of customs.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1094: The Commission adopts ecological criteria for refrigerators.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1102: Ecological recovery: the Commission grants 243.000 ecus to the United Kingdom.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1103: Conference on Company-consumer relations.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1104: The Commission appeals to the French road haulage unions to relieve the problems of non-French truckers blocked by the current dispute in France.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1105: French hauliers' strike.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/313: Speech by Commissioner Yves-Thibault de Silguy at annual congress of European movement.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/314: Address by Commissioner Hans van den Broek on the role of the media in support of the peace process in Ex-Yugoslavia.</p>
<p>- Memo/96/114: Calendar of Commission activities from December 2-8, 1996.</p>
<p>- Eurostat news release No 78/96: Annual inflation up to 2.4%.</p>
<p>- Eurostat, statistics in focus; agriculture, forestry anf fisheries No 1996-14: May-June 1996 cattle population survey.</p>
<p>- ME96/29.11: Midday express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
