<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226086" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan envoy on damage-control trip to S.Africa.</title>
<headline>Taiwan envoy on damage-control trip to S.Africa.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's foreign minister said on Friday he would leave soon for South Africa to try to limit the political damage from Pretoria's decision to sever diplomatic ties with Taiwan in favour of Beijing.</p>
<p>But an opinion poll on Friday urged him not to use financial aid to try to change Pretoria's mind.</p>
<p>&quot;I originally planned to go to South Africa in January, but now I am advancing my schedule. The South African side is aware of my decision,&quot; Foreign Minister John Chang told state radio.</p>
<p>&quot;I plan to leave for South Africa within a very short period of time, probably within one week,&quot; Chang said.</p>
<p>He said he planned to open negotiations with senior officials there. &quot;I hope we can maintain maximum contacts between the two countries.&quot;</p>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela said on Wednesday that Pretoria, a longtime diplomatic ally of Taiwan, would switch ties to Beijing by the end of 1997 in a move that shocked people in increasingly isolated Taiwan.</p>
<p>But according to the opinion poll, most Taiwanese do not believe the carrot of aid should be used to reverse one of biggest diplomatic setbacks for the island in recent years.</p>
<p>Some 53 percent of the 775 people interviewed by the United Daily News said Taiwan should not use aid to save ties with South Africa, while 21 percent said Taiwan should provide money.</p>
<p>On the question of investment projects in South Africa, 35 percent said they should continue, while 28 percent said such investments should stop.</p>
<p>Seventy-four percent said China would continue its repression of Taiwan internationally and only four percent said China would not.</p>
<p>Taiwan and China have been rivals since 1949 when the Nationalists fled to the island after losing a civil war to the Communists. Both governments say they want reunification but disagree on the terms.</p>
<p>China sees Taiwan as a renegade province not entitled to foreign ties, while Taiwan insists its 21 million people have a right to international representation.</p>
<p>About a dozen Taiwanese on Friday staged a brief, peaceful demonstration at the South African embassy in Taipei, a gesture that stood in sharp contrast to the sometimes violent protests that followed the severing of ties by the United States in 1979 and South Korea in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;Two people entered the embassy to deliver a protest letter. It lasted only about 15 minutes,&quot; an eyewitness said.</p>
<p>Lawmakers warned of a possible &quot;domino effect&quot; following South Africa's move.</p>
<p>&quot;After South Africa severs ties with us, there may be a domino effect followed by other smaller African countries,&quot; said Su Chen-chang of opposition Democratic Progressive Party. &quot;What should we do with our future foreign policy?&quot;</p>
<p>The opinion poll showed 48 percent remained optimistic about Taiwan's future international status while 29 percent were pessimistic.</p>
<p>South Africa is the biggest of 30 countries -- most of them in central America and Africa -- that recognise Taiwan's Republic of China government rather than the People's Republic of China on the mainland.</p>
<p>South African ex-President F.W. de Klerk criticised Mandela's decision, saying the government had betrayed a good friend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
