<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226046" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-BRL OK with analysts' profit forecast.</title>
<headline>RTRS-BRL OK with analysts' profit forecast.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's second largest wine producer BRL Hardy Ltd said on Friday it was not uncomfortable with analysts' forecast for a 20 percent rise in net profit before abnormals for calendar 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not uncomfortable with those projections,&quot; said managing director Stephen Millar told reporters after a Securities Institute of Australia briefing.  </p>
<p>BRL reported a 21 percent rise in operating profit to A$13.33 million for the six months to June 30 and said it was targetting similar growth in the second half of 1996.</p>
<p>Millar said the company was set next year to launch a new premium Chilean wine brand on the United Kingdom in a 50 percent joint venture with a Chilean producer.</p>
<p>BRL Europe managing director Christopher Carson said he expected the new venture to become a &quot;500,000 case a year&quot; brand, with sales to the U.K. of more than 150,000 cases in the second full year.  </p>
<p>Millar said French winery L'Occitane, a substantial co-operative winery group in the Midi region of france, could move to 20 percent of equity in BRL's French winery Domaine de la Baume if it chose to.</p>
<p>However, BRL did not give up its majority position.</p>
<p>BRL earlier announced that L'Occitane had acquired an initial equity interest of 10 percent in La Baume SA, BRL's French holding company, as part of a long term strategic alliance.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
