<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226060" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Howard says he and Costello agree on Senate.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Howard says he and Costello agree on Senate.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard said on Friday he and Treasurer Peter Costello had agreed that a substantially amended welfare bill should be returned to the upper house of parliament, the Senate, for reconsideration.</p>
<p>&quot;I'll just take the opportunity of saying that reports in this morning's papers that I, in some way, overruled the treasurer in what he said is not true,&quot; Howard told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew he was going to make that statement. We agreed that he should make it.&quot;</p>
<p>But Howard said returning the bill to the Senate did not mean the government was angling for an early election.  </p>
<p>The government can call a double dissolution election if the Senate rejects a bill twice.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't want an early election ... but we will do what we can to get our legislation through,&quot; Howard said.</p>
<p>&quot;It was just a simple statement of what we're going to do and I say again don't start reading early elections into it.&quot;</p>
<p>The Senate substantially amended the social security bill on Tuesday, in a move which Costello has said will cost the budget A$400 million over the next four years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
