<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226021" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH-Budget bills update for Nov 29 - overview.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH-Budget bills update for Nov 29 - overview.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bradley Perrett</p>
<p>The outlook for the budget bills has ended the week much brighter than expected just two days ago.</p>
<p>Only one major bill was dealt with during the week and it was virtually demolished. However, two smaller bills on Friday showed the two key Independents siding with the government.</p>
<p>Since there is no reason to think the Independents personally approved of these small measures, we may have seen the first signs of the Independents backing the government for the sake of its mandate alone.</p>
<p>The heavily amended bill, as is now well publicised, sought to exclude immigrants from social security for two years.</p>
<p>But every non-government senator thought otherwise, and it eventually excluded immigrants only from unemployment benefits -- and even then the Senate gave a close substitute for the dole.</p>
<p>In the end, the government lost A$130 million of the A$140 million saving that it had budgeted for.</p>
<p>Of the two bills on Friday, one effectively redirected schools funding away from the public education system and towards the private system.</p>
<p>This is hardly the sort of warm fuzzy measure that attracts Independent support -- especially from two ex-Laborites such as the two Independents. But both Brian Harradine and Mal Colston voted for the measure and against attempts to amend it.</p>
<p>The second bill had similar implications. It aimed to end a subsidy on seafarers' wages that effectively made them tax exempt, saving about A$20 million a year.</p>
<p>The subsidy was a piece of good old fashioned industry intervention, which one might have expected Colston and Harradine to like. </p>
<p>There was even a rational argument for it: many other countries similarly subsidise their maritime industry.</p>
<p>But again, Colston and Harradine backed the government.</p>
<p>As a matter of pure speculation, one wonders whether Treasurer Peter Costello's threats this week of higher tax and an early election has made a difference to the Independents.</p>
<p>NEXT ...</p>
<p>The next major budget bill for consideration raises student charges for university courses and makes the students pay off their charges sooner.</p>
<p>The latest word is that it will be dealt with late on Monday.</p>
<p>We have two full weeks of Senate sittings to go and they are supposed to deal with contentious budget measures worth more than A$1 billion a year, compared with the total fiscal tightening of A$7.2 billion in 1997/96.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
