<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226178" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK maintains 1996 GDP growth forecast at 4.7 pct.</title>
<headline>HK maintains 1996 GDP growth forecast at 4.7 pct.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hong Kong government said on Friday it was maintaining its forecast of full-year gross domestic product (GDP) growth at 4.7 percent, and was cutting its forecast of full-year consumer price inflation to 6.0 percent from 6.8 percent.</p>
<p>The government also said GDP grew a tentative estimate of 5.0 to 5.5 percent in the third quarter of 1996 against 4.3 percent in the second quarter and 3.3 percent in the first.  </p>
<p>&quot;Overall economic conditions in Hong Kong improved in the third quarter from the setback in the latter part of last year and early this year,&quot; the government said in a statement.</p>
<p>Consumer demand continued to revive as seen by a steady pickup in retail sales. Investment demand also continued growing, although at a less rapid rate than the preceeding two quarters as the Airport Core Programme had already reached its peak. Inventory accumulation also fell to a more normal level.</p>
<p>The growth in exports of goods so far this year was considerably slower than last year, but the dampening effect on overall GDP was offset by a slow-down in imports of goods for local use, further narrowing the visible trade deficit.</p>
<p>Domestic demand was underpinned by better labour market conditions, with unemployment and underemployment moving down, lower inflation, and the bullish stock and property markets.</p>
<p>There has been little price pressure from imported inflation, given the relative strength of the U.S. dollar and continued low inflation in the major supplier economies such as China, Japan and the United States, the statement said.</p>
<p>Domestic inflationary pressures have also been subdued, given a more balanced situation in the local labour market and generally more stable rentals in the property market,it said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843-6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
