<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226214" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Iraq sets Dec crude price formula--traders.</title>
<headline>Iraq sets Dec crude price formula--traders.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq's state oil firm SOMO has set the price of Kirkuk Blend crude for December loading to European customers at a discount of $1.55 per barrel, oil industry sources in Tokyo said on Friday.  </p>
<p>The discount of $1.55 is to dated Brent quotations.</p>
<p>Basrah Light crude for December loading to Asian customers has been set at a premium of 20 cents to the average of Oman and Dubai quotations, oil industry sources said.</p>
<p>For customers in the U.S., Kirkuk crude will be priced at a discount of $3.00 to West Texas Intermediate (WTI) crude quotations, and Basrah Light at WTI minus $3.75, they said.</p>
<p>The sources said they received a facsimile from SOMO, sent overnight, stating the price formulas for December loading Iraqi crude. SOMO asked the potential buyers to give specific dates when the two sides could meet in Baghdad to negotiate contract terms, they said.  </p>
<p>In the facsimile, SOMO says the price formula to Europe will use the average of dated Brent quotations during the five-day period following the issue date of the bill of lading (B/L), oil industry sources said.</p>
<p>The price formula for Asian customers will take the average of Oman and Dubai quotations during the 10-day period following the issue date of the B/L, they said.</p>
<p>The U.S. formula will use the average of WTI quotations for the five-day period, starting 15 days after the B/L has been issued, they said.  </p>
<p>Kirkuk crude exports will be from Turkey's Ceyhan terminal, while exports of Basrah Light crude will be from the Gulf port of Mina al-Bakr.</p>
<p>The price formula for pending sales of Iraq crude oil under the United Nations oil-for-food deal was accepted by the United Nations Council sanctions committee on Iraq on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The United States had blocked adoption of pricing formulas in August and September.</p>
<p>U.S. protests were eliminated on Monday after Iraq unconditionally accepted all U.N. terms for the May 20 accord, which set out the oil-for-food deal.  </p>
<p>The plan was delayed by differences over implementation, including Iraqi insistence on controlling the number, makeup and movement of U.N. observers who would monitor it.</p>
<p>The U.S. acceptance removed a key obstacle to allow Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months to buy food and aid for civilians suffering from sanctions imposed since Iraq's invasion of Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Osama al-Hiti, head of the Iraqi delegation at an OPEC meeting in Vienna, said renewed Iraqi oil exports could resume by mid-December.</p>
<p>On the same day, Turkish State Minister Lutfi Esengun said Iraqi oil would start flowing through a trans-Turkey pipeline by December 15 at the latest.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
