<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226306" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: SIA to raise fares mid-December - source.</title>
<headline>SIA to raise fares mid-December - source.</headline>
<byline>Raj Rajendran</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Singapore Airlines Ltd (SIA) is expected to raise international passenger air fares sometime in mid-December, a company source said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are in the process of making an application for the fare increase to the CAAS (Civil Aviation Authority of Singapore),&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said no specific date had been set for the fare increase but it would be sometime in mid-December.  </p>
<p>The source said the rise would be close to the three percent recommendation made by the International Air Transport Association (IATA) on November 15.</p>
<p>On November 20, SIA said in a statement:</p>
<p>&quot;Owing to the rise in fuel prices and the attendant cost burden experienced by the airline industry, SIA will soon be announcing fare increase in line with other carriers.&quot;</p>
<p>Several Asian airlines have already made applications to their respective governments for permission to raise fares.  </p>
<p>Three major Japanese carriers, Japan Airlines Co Ltd, All Nippon Airways Co Ltd and Japan Air System Co Ltd said earlier this week they had applied to Japan's Ministry of Transportation for permission to raise international airfares by three percent.</p>
<p>Malaysia's national carrier Malaysian Airline Systems Bhd (MAS) said on Thursday it had made a proposal to the government to raise fares by three percent.</p>
<p>Malaysia's Transport Minister Ling Liong Sik said on Wednesday MAS was free to raise its international fares.  </p>
<p>Hong Kong flag carrier Cathay Pacific Airways Ltd said on Thursday it would also soon apply to the Civil Aviation Department (CAD) to raise fares by three percent.</p>
<p>The 251-member IATA proposed a global three percent fare increase to make up for a rise of over 40 percent in fuel costs this year.</p>
<p>Fuel represents around 10 percent of most airlines' costs.</p>
<p>In Asia, as measured by benchmark Singapore prices, jet fuel prices have risen by about 22 percent over 1995 to an average of around $28.00 per barrel so far this year.  </p>
<p>Jet fuel prices have recently soared on the onset of peak winter demand with trade done last week at a post winter high of $32.30 a barrel, free-on-board Singapore.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom (65 8703093)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
