<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226309" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Yuan closes slightly down against US dollar.</title>
<headline>Yuan closes slightly down against US dollar.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chinese yuan moved in a narrow range just below the key 8.30 level on Friday, with no reaction seen to the announcement that the yuan would be fully convertible on the current account from Sunday, traders said.</p>
<p>The currency ended at 8.3009 against the U.S. dollar on the Shanghai-based interbank foreign exchange market, down slightly from Thursday's 8.3007, the traders said.</p>
<p>Dai Xianglong, governer of the People's Bank of China, said on Thursday that China would make the yuan convertible on the current account as from Sunday.  </p>
<p>It opened higher at an intra-day high of 8.3000 and moved down to consolidate around 8.3010 for most of the session, hitting a low of 8.3025.</p>
<p>Trading was active, with most done at 8.3012, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The announcement had little impact on the yuan's movement because the market had known about it for some time,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>Dealers said that while the market was little affected by Dai's announcement, it was still an important step on the way to making the yuan completely convertible.  </p>
<p>Dealers expect the yuan to move around 8.3010 early next week.</p>
<p>The yuan closed up at 7.2943 from 7.3285 against 100 Japanese yen and slightly up at 1.0741 from 1.0745 against the Hong Kong dollar.</p>
<p>-- Shanghai newsroom (86-21) 6279-7004</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
