<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226380" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan jobless rate edges up to near record level.</title>
<headline>Japan jobless rate edges up to near record level.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's jobless rate edged up close to record levels last month, but the government said on Friday that the number of the unemployed had been pushed up by people seeking to change jobs as the economy picks up.</p>
<p>The nation's unemployment rate rose to 3.4 percent in October compared with 3.3 percent in September, a shade below the record 3.5 percent seen in the summer, according to official data released on Friday.</p>
<p>Although Japan does not have the double-digit jobless rates of some Western countries, the climb in the rate seen over the past year has caused concern in a nation which has had minimal unemployment for most of the post-war era.</p>
<p>&quot;Data showed that the employment situation remains severe...but there are more people who decided to leave their current jobs and look for better ones as the economy is picking up,&quot; a senior government official told reporters.</p>
<p>The government said that although the rate stayed stubbornly high, there was a silver lining in the statistics that suggested growing economic confidence and job mobility.</p>
<p>The figures showed that a record number of workers had voluntarily quit their job in October -- a total of 960,000 people, up 100,000 from a year earlier.</p>
<p>Another encouraging figure was an increase in the employed. The number increased 0.8 percent from a year earlier to 65.45 million.</p>
<p>Unemployment among young female workers is on a rising trend as they are voluntarily leaving their jobs amid a recovering economy.</p>
<p>However, unemployment among middle-aged or older workers was still increasing as companies continue to streamline operations and cut wage costs.</p>
<p>The economy has been struggling to recover from a slump which set in after the collapse of the 1980s economic &quot;bubble&quot; of inflated asset prices, forcing companies to cut costs and restructure their operations to maintain profits.</p>
<p>Many economists predict that the economic recovery will slow in early 1997, especially after a planned rise in the sales tax in April to five percent from three percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
