<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226488" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks rally to year high in early trade.</title>
<headline>French stocks rally to year high in early trade.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>French stocks surged on Friday to their highest levels of the year on big gains in European bond prices, a strong dollar and signs that striking truckers could be about to call an end to a damaging 12-day strike.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an ideal scenario,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The blue-chip CAC-40 index was up 17.30 points, or 0.76 percent, at 2,307.61 at 1000 GMT after sailing through the psychological 2,300 barrier in the first few minutes of trading.</p>
<p>Traders say the path is clear up until a resistance level at 2,320. &quot;If we break past 2,320, we're on the way to 2,400-2,450,&quot; another trader predicted.</p>
<p>The index's all-time high, set in February 1994, is 2,360.98 points.</p>
<p>The bourse is only now catching up with other European markets that have risen from one record to another this year. Analysts say equities investors have taken heart from a recent public debate about the franc-mark exchange rate and hope it will lead to both a weaker franc and lower interest rates.</p>
<p>Investors also heaved a great sigh of relief on Friday after truck drivers' unions said they were eager to negotiate an end to the strike that was threatening thousands of businesses.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of investors are buying on the expectation of a year-end rally fuelled by window-dressing,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Activity centred on shares that have underperformed the market this year. Publishing group Havas, one of the biggest laggards, climbed for the second day in a row.</p>
<p>After rallying on Thursday on reports that shareholder Alcatel Alsthom was pushing it to boost shareholder value, Havas rose a further 3.19 percent to 378 francs on Friday.</p>
<p>The CAC-40 November futures contract was 18 points higher at 2,310.</p>
<p>Early volume was a heavy 760 million francs, swollen by activity linked to the expiry of monthly futures and options contracts.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
