<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226436" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Nov 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Nov 29.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- The ruling Social Democrats increased their popularity in an opinion poll, despite what was feared as negative fallout from a controversial remark about China by Prime Minister Goran Persson. The Social Democrats gained two percentage points to 31.5 percent, followed by the Conservatives up one to 28.0 percent. The Leftists dipped one point to 13.5 percent and the Centre by the same amount to 6.0 percent. The next general election is not until September, 1998.</p>
<p>- Insurer Skandia's new managing director Lars-Eric Petersson has not yet taken office but is already sure of achieving a merger with Stadshypotek, announced by the two boards on Monday.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- State-owned telecoms company Telia could be hit by costs ranging from 1.2 to 3.6 billion crowns to adjust its computer systems to the year 2000. Ylva Hambraeus-Bjorling, project leader of the Telia 2000 programme, said Swedish companies are generally ill-equipped to deal with the millennium switch.</p>
<p>- A local authority official recommends making centrally-negotiated wage deals valid for two years instead of one, in order to bring Swedish wages into line with European nations. Gunnar Wetterberg, director of the federation of local authorities, says the pattern of large nominal increases will not otherwise be broken.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- Former Volvo managing director Christer Zetterberg has returned to Sweden from Britain and is more actively involved in Swedish business life. One of his first tasks as chairman of the trading company Ekman in Gothenburg is to seek a bourse listing. He is also on the boards of the Lundberg property group, mortgage lender Siab and forestry group MoDo.</p>
<p>- Swedish top businessmen have a good reputation abroad, according to Rolf Borjesson, managing director of Rexam (formerly Bowater) in Britain. &quot;This is because we have worked slightly differently over the last 20 years,&quot; he said. &quot;We have worked in teams and have a greater knowledge of vertical communication. We know how to anchor decisions in the organisation. But we are also known for being tough and tenacious when necessary.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
