<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226490" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: FEATURE - Coke and Pepsi start battle for Ukraine market.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Coke and Pepsi start battle for Ukraine market.</headline>
<byline>Irene Marushko</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coca-Cola Amatil (CCA) laid the first brick for what it says is Europe's largest bottling plant in November and Pepsi-Cola International announced its new plant would be running by the end of the month -- hailing the start of cola wars in Ukraine.</p>
<p>&quot;The big Pepsi-Coke war is coming,&quot; Justin Melvin, Pepsi's general manager, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that competition is healthy,&quot; Muhtar Kent, CCA European managing director, told a news conference announcing the construction of the $120 million plant outside Kiev.</p>
<p>The struggle for the Ukrainian soft drinks market has become evident with Coca-Cola's Australian arm CCA plastering Kiev with advertisements and sponsoring contests.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola, which holds about 25 percent of market share compared to Pepsi's 22 percent, has also declared itself the single largest foreign investor in Ukraine with an expected $200 million in investment once the new plant opens.</p>
<p>With a population of 52 million people, Ukraine has managed to attract only $1.2 billion in foreign investment in five years since independence.</p>
<p>UPHILL BATTLE</p>
<p>But the battle for supremacy is uphill for both companies.</p>
<p>Despite growing sales they are banking on the future to turn a profit and hesitate to say when that day might come.</p>
<p>Both companies admit consumption per person is one of the lowest in Eastern Europe for either cola, which sell for about 50 cents a can and just over one dollar for a two-litre bottle. The average monthly salary is $70-$80.</p>
<p>Pepsi has taken the role of venerable old-timer in the fight, looking back to 1979 when it started selling its product here after the company struck a deal with the Soviet Union to market Stolichnaya vodka abroad.</p>
<p>&quot;By being here 25 years we've established the cola market,&quot; said Melvin. &quot;In the old days it was a Western product, one of the only Western products available.&quot;</p>
<p>Pepsi will begin bottling at its new $6 million plant in Chernivtsi in western Ukraine, Pepsi's largest investment to date. Until now bottling and canning has taken place in 10 locations -- mostly breweries -- inherited from Soviet days.</p>
<p>&quot;Coke came in almost brand-new. It's easier to do if you have an open playing field,&quot; Melvin said.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola is expected to gain a big advantage when the U.S. fast food outlet McDonald's, which sells only Coke, opens seven planned restaurants next year.</p>
<p>Melvin said consumption dropped from 1989-90, when Ukraine was a large cola consumer.</p>
<p>Post-independence economic problems like hyperinflation and rapid currency devaluation took their toll on the soft drinks market, and Pepsi also watched traditional distribution systems and some of its bottling plants collapse in the aftermath.</p>
<p>Undaunted, Melvin predicted rapid growth in the industry driven by the cola giants. He said the market stood at 90 million cases in 1996, with one case equalling 24, eight-ounce (227 millilitre) bottles.</p>
<p>&quot;I would expect the soft-drink industry to be around 200 million cases by 2000,&quot; Melvin said, adding that Pepsi expected to sell 22 million cases in 1996. &quot;We had 36 percent growth in sales from last year, and 1995 was up 25 percent from 1994,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Coke's corporate affairs director Barry Blufer said the company expected to triple or even quadruple sales in 1997, after selling more than seven million cases in 1995 and more than one million cases in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect the current market to grow in the next few years,&quot; said Kent. &quot;For the next five to 10 years we see significant growth coming out of the Ukrainian marketplace.&quot;</p>
<p>Coke's new plant will produce 800 million eight-ounce cans and bottles a year, and Kent said that was intended solely for the Ukrainian market.</p>
<p>Coca-Cola has also announced plans to construct a third plant near the eastern city of Dnipropetrovsk in two to five years, in addition to its Lviv plant in western Ukraine which began operating at the beginning of 1995.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
