<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226434" id="root" date="1996-11-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Nov 29.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Norway - Nov 29.</headline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Follwing are some of the leading stories in Norwegian papers this morning:</p>
<p>AFTENPOSTEN</p>
<p>- Shipping company Bergesen ASA is negotiating with Esso Societe Anonyme Francaise to buy two supertankers.</p>
<p>- Former Planning Minister Terje Roed-Larsen says he is convinced the tax authorities will clear him of allegations that he back dated a share-options contract in 1986. Roed-Larsen resigned on Wednesday.</p>
<p>- Documents concerning former Planning Minister Terje Roed-Larsen are inexplicably missing from tax authorities' files. Bjarne Hope, head of the tax department, says it is very serious if the documents really have disappeared. The authorities are making a great effort to search for the documents, he says.</p>
<p>DAGENS NAERINGSLIV</p>
<p>- The Norwegian crown has advanced 0.7 percent against ECU since Wednesday. Operators in the market say that foreigners now find the crown to be so cheap that it is a good buy.</p>
<p>- Kvaerner ASA is negotiating on the sale of the company's fleet of refrigerated ships. The deal will probably be finalised next week. Market sources expect the fleet to be sold for about one billion crowns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
