<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226614" id="root" date="1996-11-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-MILAN OWNER BERLUSCONI DEFENDS EMBATTLED WEAH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MILAN OWNER BERLUSCONI DEFENDS EMBATTLED WEAH.</headline>
<dateline>TURIN, Italy 1996-11-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>AC Milan owner Silvio Berlusconi jumped to George Weah's defence on Saturday, saying the Liberian's head-butting of Jorge Costa was understandable given the Porto captain's racist taunts and rough play.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe his reaction is understandable,&quot; former Italian prime minister Berlusconi said of the striker, who has admitted he butted Costa in the players' tunnel after their European Cup Champions' League match in Portugal on November 20.</p>
<p>UEFA has suspended Weah for Milan's vital final Champions' League clash against Rosenborg next week and said it would conduct a full investigation later.</p>
<p>&quot;He was provoked throughout the match, he suffered a foul to his knee that could have jeopardised his soccer career and he is perennially the subject of insults due to the colour of his skin,&quot; Bersluconi told reporters in this northern city.</p>
<p>&quot;Even in the tunnel the Porto players tried to insult (Weah). He reacted, but I think the result was much worse than he intended,&quot; Berlusconi added.</p>
<p>Weah said on Friday he was ready to apologise to Costa for his &quot;stupid&quot; reaction if the Portuguese defender would admit he had provoked him.</p>
<p>Weah, due to be awarded FIFA's 1996 Fair Play award at a ceremony in Lisbon in January, suggested he and Costa should play in a friendly in the Portuguese capital scheduled for January 29 between African and European players as a goodwill gesture.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="LIBER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TURIN, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
