<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226791" id="root" date="1996-11-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SAUDI ARABIA: Saudi monarch, Perry discuss U.S. troop security.</title>
<headline>Saudi monarch, Perry discuss U.S. troop security.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>RIYADH 1996-11-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Defence Secretary William Perry held talks on Saturday with Saudi Arabia's King Fahd on the protection of American servicemen in the kingdom where two attacks have killed 24 U.S. troops in the past year.</p>
<p>&quot;They met for about forty minutes. The focus of the discussion was force protection measures,&quot; a senior defence official told reporters travelling with Perry.</p>
<p>Taking part in the discussion was U.S. army general Binford Peay, Commander of the U.S. Military Central Command.</p>
<p>The official said the King and the Secretary noted during the meeting, which began at about 2.00 a.m local time at the king's palace, that a joint U.S.-Saudi investigation on the second bombing in June that killed 19 Americans &quot;reached no conclusion yet and was still continuing&quot;.</p>
<p>Perry later visited Eskan village, about 18 miles (30 kms) south east of Riyadh, where more than 1,000 U.S. troops were moved after the attack.</p>
<p>&quot;We uprooted a lot of you, we did it to protect you,&quot; Perry told the troops at the secure facility. &quot;You can feel quite safe I believe.&quot;</p>
<p>Eskan village, originally built by the Saudis for bedouins, has about 800 air conditioned villas surrounded by a 12 foot (three metre) high wall topped by barbed wire and a 400 foot &quot;exclusion zone&quot; between the highway and outer perimeter.</p>
<p>Three checkpoints guarded by soldiers with automatic weapons and guard dogs control access.</p>
<p>The Saudi government executed four Saudis after the first bombing attack. Saudi authorities and the U.S. FBI were cooperating in investigating the two bombings.</p>
<p>The second bombing attack killed 19 Americans and unconfirmed reports says the Saudis have arrested as many as 40 persons in connection with the investigations.</p>
<p>U.S. officials earlier expressed their dissatisfaction with Saudi Arabia's cooperation with the FBI. But the FBI said this week it was now satisfied.</p>
<p>&quot;The Secretary and the King had a very good meeting in the wee hours of the morning as is normal. The King was very active and engaged. He obviously had prepared himself for the discussion,&quot; the senior U.S. official said.</p>
<p>He said the King &quot;re-affirmed the kingdom's commitment to do all it could to help assist in the relocation and to ensure that American forces are secure and comfortable.&quot;</p>
<p>Since an attack in Riyadh in November of last year that killed five U.S. troops, and another in Dharan on June 25 that killed 19 Americans, the U.S. miltary has moved 4,000 airforce personnel to a remote Prince Sultan airbase in the desert 60 miles (100 km) southeast of the Saudi capital.</p>
<p>Another 1,000 U.S. military personnel involved in security and cooperating in the investigations were moved to Eskan.</p>
<p>Nearly 100 U.S. F-15 and other attack and fighter jets were moved to Sultan airbase at al-Kharj in the past two months.</p>
<p>&quot;They also reviewed the security situation in the region, including Iran and Iraq,&quot; said the official.</p>
<p>Some 200 U.S., British and French warplanes based in Saudi Arabia and Kuwait continue to fly missions over Iraq to enforce a warning to president Saddam Hussein against again attacking Kuwait or Shi'ite Moslems in southern Iraq.</p>
<p>Perry announced in Kuwait earlier that eight radar-avoiding F-117A Stealth fighter bombers would remain in Kuwait to challenge any threats from Iraq and Iran.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIYADH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SAUDI ARABIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
