<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226798" id="root" date="1996-11-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Nov 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Egypt - Nov 30.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-11-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Egyptian press on Saturday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>AL-AHRAM</p>
<p>- President Mubarak and Italian President Scalfaro will discuss developments in the peace process, strengthening Egypt's ties with Italy and European-Arab coordination. The Italian president began his visit to Egypt with a trip to the Battle of Alamein memorial.</p>
<p>- Mubarak sends a letter to the Palestinian Human Rights Committee in the United Nations, warns that current deadlock in peace process and Jewish settlements will throw the region into a cycle of violence.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Kamal Ganzouri says Egypt will set up a free zone in the Gulf of Suez and that the project will provide 140,000 job opportunities.</p>
<p>- Three Egyptian labourers killed and 13 wounded after a wall collapses on top of them in Mecca, Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>AL-AKHBAR</p>
<p>- International evaluation of Egypt's economy. Global institutions place Egypt's economy in the same category as the &quot;Asian Tigers&quot;. Ganzouri will meet envoys of these institutions that will rate the economy and provide $200 million in investment annually.</p>
<p>- Ministerial committee to take several investment projects discussed in the Middle East and North Africa Economic Conference to Saudi Arabia.</p>
<p>AL-GOMHURIYA</p>
<p>- Mubarak in a letter to the Palestinian Committee in the United Nations: Israel is pushing the region towards a cycle of violence. We are committed to peace.</p>
<p>- Italian President says Egypt has special status.</p>
<p>- Six Egyptians killed and wounded after a wall collapses in Mecca.</p>
<p>- Israeli official says Egypt has decided to half its oil exports to Israel, adds decision is commercially -- not politically -- motivated.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
