<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226873" id="root" date="1996-11-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sunken tanker may pose threat to U.S. marine reserve.</title>
<headline>Sunken tanker may pose threat to U.S. marine reserve.</headline>
<dateline>MONTEREY, Calif. 1996-11-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. oil tanker sunk in 1941 has been found off the California coast, apparently still full of oil and posing a potential environmental threat to a marine sanctuary, officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Researchers using a small submarine found the wreck of the Montebello this month 900 feet (270 metres) down on the sea floor about six miles (10 kms) off the central California coast near the town of Cambria, according to the Monterey Bay National Marine Sanctuary.</p>
<p>The Montebello was carrying 75,346 barrels (3.1 million gallons) of crude oil when it was sunk by a Japanese submarine on Dec. 23, 1941 -- just 16 days after the attack on Pearl Harbor -- and could still be carrying several million gallons of oil, marine sanctuary spokesman John Robinson said.</p>
<p>The tanker lies about a mile (1.6 km) outside the boundary of the marine sanctuary, and sanctuary officials are worried that the tanks could one day break, causing a major oil spill that could damage the reserve's fragile environment.</p>
<p>&quot;We are very concerned,&quot; said Terry Jackson, manager of the Monterey Bay National Marine Sanctuary. &quot;This is a large amount of oil sitting in an aging tanker on the bottom of the sea.&quot;</p>
<p>The marine sanctuary, founded in 1992, protects an area of more than 5,000 square miles off the central California coast. Hundreds of species of fish and birds as well as whales, sharks, seals, sea otters and sea lions can be found in the sanctuary, the oceanic equivalent of a national park.</p>
<p>Because of the very deep water around the wreck, it would be very difficult and costly to try to salvage the ship or remove the oil, Jackson said. &quot;We will have to evaluate the condition of the ship, the threat of a spill and what our options are,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The threat of a spill depends partly on what type of petroleum product the tanker was carrying. Due to the cold temperature of the sea at that depth, heavy crude oil would become very dense and flow slowly, if at all, from any hull breach. A lighter crude, or refined product, would surface much more quickly and pose a greater threat, officials said.</p>
<p>A team led by archaeologist Jack Hunter found the wreck earlier this month using the Delta, a 16-foot (five metre) submarine previously used to explore the shipwrecks of the Lusitania in the Atlantic Ocean and the Edmund Fitzgerald in Lake Superior.</p>
<p>The researchers, who surveyed and filmed the wreck, found the ghostly vessel sitting upright, teeming with sea life and littered with webs of snagged fishing lines and nets.</p>
<p>According to researchers, two of the Montebello's 10 onboard storage tanks were ruptured when it sank. The remaining eight tanks appear undamaged. Although the ship has been submerged for 55 years, it shows little sign of hull deterioration, the marine sanctuary said. No leakage from the remaining storage tanks was seen.</p>
<p>The Montebello, built in 1921, was loaded with crude oil at Port San Luis, California and set sail for Vancouver, British Columbia early on Dec. 23, 1941.</p>
<p>The tanker was a few miles off Cambria when a lookout spotted a Japanese submarine surfacing nearby. The Montebello sank after being hit by a torpedo. All 38 crew members reached shore safely. Although the general location of the sinking had been known, the wreck had never before been precisely located or examined.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MONTEREY, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
