<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226890" id="root" date="1996-11-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEPAL: South Asian nations agree to reduce tariffs.</title>
<headline>South Asian nations agree to reduce tariffs.</headline>
<byline>Gopal Sharma</byline>
<dateline>KATHMANDU 1996-11-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Seven countries of South Asia on Saturday agreed to reduce tariffs on more than 1,500 products as a move towards increased trade and economic cooperation in the region, officials said.</p>
<p>They said many consumer goods, industrial products and raw materials would be entitled to 10 to 50 percent tariff cuts when the second round of the South Asian Preferential Trading Arrangement (SAPTA) comes into force.</p>
<p>A statement by the secretariat of the SAARC regional grouping said negotiators had recommended that the second round of SAPTA should become effective by March 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a very encouraging development because all have worked in a spirit of cooperation and everybody realises that our future is in economic integration,&quot; said Ujjal Singh Bhatia, India's chief negotiator.</p>
<p>SAARC was formed in December 1985 to improve the economies of the more than one-fifth of the world's population that lives in South Asia. It groups Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, Pakistan and Sri Lanka.</p>
<p>SAPTA, whose member countries provide tariff concessions for imports from within the region, was incorporated within the SAARC framework in 1993 and came into force in December 1995.</p>
<p>At the end of the first round of talks, member countries had agreed to give tariff cuts for 226 items.</p>
<p>Negotiators said India and Pakistan, two traditional rivals in the grouping, were moving ahead positively with India alone offering tariff cuts on about 900 items.</p>
<p>They said the the consolidated list of items agreed on Saturday will be transmitted to the committee on economic cooperation consisting of commerce secretaries of the member nations, which is the supervising body for SAPTA.</p>
<p>Negotiators said the report will then be forwarded to the SAARC Council of Ministers, comprising foreign ministers and scheduled to meet on December 19 in New Delhi, for implemention.</p>
<p>They said the move would be a major step forward towards realising the goal set by SAARC for launching the South Asian Free Trade Area (SAFTA) preferably by 2002 but before 2005.</p>
<p>Officials said SAPTA would help &quot;significantly&quot; increase the trade between the seven South Asian nations which currently represents only 3.4 percent of the global share.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BHUTAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NEPAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-11-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KATHMANDU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEPAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
