<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226990" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-TAYLOR GAMBLES IN SEARCH OF AUSTRALIAN RUNS.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-TAYLOR GAMBLES IN SEARCH OF AUSTRALIAN RUNS.</headline>
<byline>Robert Galvin</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mark Taylor was only partially rewarded for his positive captaincy as Australia fought to assert their control in the second test match against West Indies on Sunday.</p>
<p>Determined to build on his side's first innings lead of 27 runs, Taylor declined an offer from the umpires to leave the field for bad light after tea.</p>
<p>At close of play on the third day at the Sydney Cricket Ground, Australia were 77 for two, an overall lead of 104 runs, with eight wickets in hand.</p>
<p>With two days left to play, the match is evenly balanced.</p>
<p>Although the home side used the extra time in the middle to score valuable runs, they also lost Taylor and number three Ricky Ponting to give the tourists some encouragement.</p>
<p>Ironically, Taylor may have saved his own wicket if he had walked off when the conditions deteriorated sharply after tea.</p>
<p>Shortly after making his decision, the left-handed opener edged a ball from fast bowler Ian Bishop to first slip, where Brian Lara took the catch at the second attempt.</p>
<p>Taylor, who scored 16 to prolong a run of indifferent form this season, added 51 runs for the first wicket with fellow opener Matthew Elliott.</p>
<p>Elliott, playing in only his second test, grew in confidence as the innings progressed to remain unbeaten on 45. Mark Waugh was the other not out batsman on two.</p>
<p>Bishop claimed his second wicket of the innings to complete a memorable day when Ponting edged a catch to wicketkeeper Courtney Browne with his score on four.</p>
<p>West Indies, who lost the first test in Brisbane by 123 runs, started the day on 156 for three in reply to Australia's first innings total of 331.</p>
<p>The tourists were eventually dismissed for 304 after losing their last six wickets for 75 runs during the afternoon session.</p>
<p>Middle order batsman Shivnarine Chanderpaul and Bishop both scored 48 before falling victim to wrist spinner Shane Warne.</p>
<p>Bishop attempted to bring up his maiden test half-century with a boundary but only succeeded in giving Elliott a catch at deep mid-wicket to end the West Indies innings just before tea.</p>
<p>Australia fast bowler Glenn McGrath triggered the collapse by removing left-hander Jimmy Adams for 30 and wicketkeeper Browne for a duck in the fourth over after lunch with the total on 229.</p>
<p>McGrath finished with figures of four for 82 from 31 overs.</p>
<p>Fellow paceman Jason Gillespie took two wickets on his test debut by bowling tail-enders Curtly Ambrose and Kenneth Benjamin in quick succession.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
