<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="226967" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-RANGERS FIVE POINTS CLEAR AFTER BEATING ABERDEEN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-RANGERS FIVE POINTS CLEAR AFTER BEATING ABERDEEN.</headline>
<dateline>ABERDEEN, Scotland 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ruthless Rangers streaked five points clear at the top of the Scottish premier division on Sunday in pursuit of their ninth successive championship.</p>
<p>David Robertson, Brian Laudrup and Charlie Miller grabbed the goals as they crushed Aberdeen 3-0 at Pittodrie to take full advantage of Celtic's slip against Hearts - a 2-2 draw - 24 hours earlier.</p>
<p>Robertson's first goal of the season silenced the fans at the club he left in 1991, but he was upstaged by Man of the Match Laudrup, who scored a brilliant second after 77 minutes before substitute Miller wrapped it up.</p>
<p>It leaves Roy Aitken's Aberdeen without a premier win against Rangers for almost two years as they try in vain to bridge the gap on the Rangers-Celtic Old Firm.</p>
<p>Four players, three for Rangers, were booked but for Rangers manager Walter Smith the only blot were injuries to Jorg Albertz and Joachim Bjorklund ahead of Wednesday's Champions' League match in Auxerre.</p>
<p>It was the first of an 11-match schedule in the next 35 days for Smith's side.</p>
<p>Paul Gascoigne created the opening goal when he released Laudrup down the left and after the Dane beat Stewart McKimmie he crossed and Robertson netted at the near post.</p>
<p>Robertson has missed much of the current campaign through injury and has been the subject of abuse for Aberdeen fans ever since leaving his home-town club so it must have been a special moment.</p>
<p>In the 77th minute Miller's pass released Laudrup through the middle and the Dane brilliantly chipped home from 35 yards.</p>
<p>Miller sidefooted in the third with four minutes left.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABERDEEN, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
