<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227084" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: What's happened in Bosnia since Dayton peace deal.</title>
<headline>What's happened in Bosnia since Dayton peace deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here is a chronology of the main events since the signing of the Dayton peace deal which ended the war in Bosnia in which some 200,000 people were killed and two million others displaced:</p>
<p>1995</p>
<p>Nov 21 - Warring sides in Bosnia agree to a peace plan at U.S.-sponsored talks in Dayton, Ohio. Deal calls for Bosnia to be made up of two states, Bosnian-Croat and Bosnian Serb, Sarajevo will remain united and parliament and president will be democratically elected</p>
<p>Nov 22 - The United Nations suspends economic sanctions against Serbia</p>
<p>Nov 24 - Two hundred Bosnian soldiers loot a U.N. base in northwest Bosnia, firing machineguns and stealing nine vehicles</p>
<p>Dec 2 - Bosnian Serb army commander General Ratko Mladic rejects Dayton peace agreement</p>
<p>Dec 9 - Two-day international conference on rebuilding Bosnia ends in London</p>
<p>Dec 12 - Bosnian Serbs release French pilots Frederic Chiffot and Jose Souvignet, shot down on August 30</p>
<p>Dec 14 - Balkan leaders sign Bosnian peace treaty in Paris, formally ending Europe's worst conflict since World War Two</p>
<p>Dec 20 - The U.N.'s 3-1/2-year mission in Bosnia comes to an end when NATO forces officially take over</p>
<p>Dec 22 - Bosnian government ends the formal state of war that has existed since June 1992</p>
<p>Dec 24 - Bosnia's rival Serb and Moslem armies exchange over 200 prisoners of war</p>
<p>Dec 31 - U.S. engineers beat wintry storms to finish an epic pontoon bridge over the river Sava, allowing tank-led NATO peacekeeping columns to roll into Bosnia</p>
<p>1996</p>
<p>Jan 5 - NATO fires its first shots in anger in Bosnia after a gunman wounds an Italian soldier</p>
<p>Jan 9 - Sarajevo airlift ends after 43 months of Serb siege</p>
<p>Feb 5 - The Bosnian government arrests Serb officers over alleged war crimes. The next day, separatist Serb leaders suspend contacts with the Bosnian government over the arrests</p>
<p>Feb 7 - Croat demonstrators attack European Union representative Hans Koschnick in Mostar for trying to reunify the Bosnian town's Croat and Moslem communities</p>
<p>Feb 8 - Mladic says he is breaking off all contact with NATO</p>
<p>Feb 10 - Bosnian government releases the four Bosnian Serbs</p>
<p>Feb 12 - Two Bosnian Serb officers, Djordje Djukic and Aleksa Krsmanovic, are deported to the Netherlands to face the U.N. war crimes tribunal</p>
<p>Mar 19 - Sarajevo becomes a united city again after four years when Moslem-Croat authorities take control of the last Serb-held district</p>
<p>Mar 22 - U.N. war crimes tribunal charges three Bosnian Moslems and one Bosnian Croat with war crimes, the first indictments for crimes against Serb victims</p>
<p>Apr 13 - Representatives of 80 countries and organisations pledge $1.23 billion to rebuild Bosnia</p>
<p>May 7 - The first international war crimes trial for 50 years opens with a Bosnian Serb accused of taking part in &quot;events of unspeakable horror&quot;</p>
<p>June 14 - The Florence conference reviewing Dayton demands Bosnian Serb leader Radovan Karadzic be removed and sets September 14 as date for post-war national elections in Bosnia</p>
<p>June 30 - Karadzic relinquishes all power to his deputy Biljana Plavsic but keeps his title as head of state</p>
<p>July 11 - U.N. criminal tribunal on former Yugoslavia issues arrest warrants against Karadzic and Mladic</p>
<p>July 19 - Karadzic resigns to clear way for Bosnia elections</p>
<p>Aug 6 - Bosnian Moslems and Croats agree to an EU-mediated deal to form a local government in Mostar</p>
<p>Aug 15 - Senior Bosnian officials sign an agreement to fully form the country's Moslem-Croat Federation and dismantle the self-styled Bosnian Croat republic of Herceg-Bosna</p>
<p>Sept 18 - Results from the Sept 14 election show Bosnia's Moslem President Alija Izetbegovic narrowly defeated Bosnian Serb rival Momcilo Krajisnik</p>
<p>Nov 9 - Bosnian Serb president sacks Mladic</p>
<p>Nov 12 - One Moslem killed in clash with Serbs over disputed northeastern Bosnian village in worst conflict since Dayton</p>
<p>Nov 14 - Bosnia's three co-presidents, meeting world leaders in Paris, agree plan to stabilise peace in former Yugoslavia as condition for continuing international aid</p>
<p>Nov 27 - NATO agrees to send follow-on force to Bosnia to replace IFOR and stipulates it should stay in country for no more than 18 months</p>
<p>Nov 28 - Mladic gives up leadership of Bosnian Serb Army</p>
<p>Nov 29 - U.N. warcrimes tribunal sentences a Croat who confessed to taking part in the Bosnian Serb Army massacre of over 1,200 unarmed Moslems at Srebrenica to 10 years in jail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
