<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227003" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA-JORDAN BECOMES SECOND FASTEST TO SCORE 25,000.</title>
<headline>NBA-JORDAN BECOMES SECOND FASTEST TO SCORE 25,000.</headline>
<dateline>SAN ANTONIO, Texas 1996-11-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Michael Jordan scored 35 points to become the second-fastest player in NBA history to reach 25,000 as the Chicago Bulls defeated the San Antonio Spurs 97-88 Saturday.</p>
<p>Jordan, who needed all 35 to reach the 25,000 plateau, hit an 18-footer from the right baseline with 29.4 seconds left in the fourth quarter to attain the milestone. Jordan reached the mark in 782 games, 91 more than it took Wilt Chamberlain.</p>
<p>&quot;It feels pretty good,&quot; Jordan said.  &quot;I kind of hoped I would do it in Milwaukee so my wife could see it. But I'll take it.&quot;</p>
<p>Other than Jordan's achievement, it was business as usual for the Bulls. At 15-1, they are ahead of last season's record 72-win pace by one game.</p>
<p>Chicago improved to 9-1 on the road.</p>
<p>Scottie Pippen finished with 20 points and Bill Wennington, in the absence of injured centre Luc Longley, scored 18 for Chicago.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew I was going to play a lot more with Luc gone,&quot; said Wennington, who was 8-of-11 from the field in 32 minutes. &quot;I don't think I've played this many minutes in three years. Anyway, I've got to do what I have to do to help this team win.&quot;</p>
<p>Dominique Wilkins scored 25 points and Avery Johnson 23 for the Spurs, who have lost eight straight and fell to 1-7 at home, despite an Alamodome record crowd of 37,058.</p>
<p>In Los Angeles,  Robert Pack scored 11 of his 24 points in overtime and Jayson Williams had 28 points and 24 rebounds as the New Jersey Nets held on for their first road win of the season, 106-95 over the Clippers.</p>
<p>Kendall Gill scored 29 points to lead New Jersey, which snapped a three-game losing streak.</p>
<p>Los Angeles suffered its sixth straight loss.</p>
<p>The Nets set team records with 49 free throws made and 60 attempted.</p>
<p>In Miami, Alonzo Mourning's dunk with 1:41 remaining capped a 9-0 run as the Heat nipped the Boston Celtics 78-77 for their seventh straight victory to tie a franchise record.</p>
<p>Tim Hardaway scored 19 points and Mourning had 17 points, 16 rebounds and four blocks for Miami.</p>
<p>At Washington, Hakeem Olajuwon scored 34 points and grabbed a season-high 17 rebounds as the Houston Rockets used a 15-4 fourth-quarter run to win their ninth straight, 103-99 over the Bullets.</p>
<p>Charles Barkley added 27 points, 10 rebounds and six assists for Houston (15-1), which matched the 1993-94 team for the best start in franchise history. The Rockets are the only undefeated road team in the NBA (8-0).</p>
<p>Chris Webber scored 24 points for the Bullets, who have lost consecutive games following a three-game winning streak.</p>
<p>In New York, Patrick Ewing recorded 29 points and 14 rebounds and John Starks scored all 13 of his points in the fourth quarter as the Knicks snapped a three-game skid, 115-101 over the Sacramento Kings.</p>
<p>Buck Williams contributed a season-high 16 points and eight rebounds off the bench, while Charles Oakley had 13, 10 and seven assists for New York, which posted a season high in points scored.</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Allen Iverson scored five of his 23 points in a 7-0 fourth-quarter run and Jerry Stackhouse had 31 points as the 76ers turned back the Vancouver Grizzlies 96-90.</p>
<p>Iverson also had nine assists for Philadelphia, which has won three of its last four games.</p>
<p>Vancouver fell to 0-9 on the road. </p>
<p>At Minnesota, Tom Gugliotta scored 25 points as the Timberwolves set a franchise record for fewest points allowed in a 79-70 victory over the Toronto Raptors.</p>
<p>The Timberwolves' previous best was 71, set against Dallas in 1993.</p>
<p>Damon Stoudamire scored 20 points for the Raptors, who were held to a franchise-low in scoring. The previous low was 75 in a loss at Sacramento last January.</p>
<p>In Milwaukee, Glen Rice scored 23 points, including seven during a 9-0 fourth-quarter run as the Charlotte Hornets defeated the Bucks 94-87.</p>
<p>Anthony Mason, who shut down All-Star forward Vin Baker, had 18 points, nine rebounds and nine assists and Dell Curry added 22 points for Charlotte.</p>
<p>Glenn Robinson scored 27 points for the Bucks, who have lost six of their last nine games.</p>
<p>In Cleveland, former Cavalier Gerald Wilkins scored 18 points including a crucial three-pointer with 3:25 as the Orlando Magic held on for an 86-82 victory.</p>
<p>Orlando held off a late Cleveland rally by hitting five of six free throws in the final 90 seconds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-11-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN ANTONIO, Texas"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
