<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227083" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British students sue schools for poor education.</title>
<headline>British students sue schools for poor education.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former students at two British schools, judged by government inspectors as failing their pupils, are suing them for their poor education in a case that has shocked education officials.</p>
<p>Jack Rabinowicz, the London-based lawyer representing the 17-year-old boy and girl, refused to identity his clients, but said the schools and the local education authority could both be held responsible.</p>
<p>&quot;If you have a child who is locked into what is effectively a dumping ground, because he can't get in anywhere else, but would otherwise be of a reasonable academic standard, and the child has failed as a consequence, then the school may have to pick up the tab,&quot; he told The Sunday Times newspaper.</p>
<p>Both students, who have been granted legal aid, are seeking compensation for tuition, maintenance and loss of earnings while they retake exams which they failed the first time around.</p>
<p>If the students are successful in their case it could open up a floodgate of similar legal proceedings against primary and secondary schools.</p>
<p>The Sunday Times said up to 300 schools are expected to fail the new education inspection system, which was introduced by the government and provides pupils with evidence of teachers' failings, by 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;This concerns us very much. We have just had an instance where a kid has sued a school over bullying and the insurance company settled for 30,000 pounds ($50,390),&quot; Bill Heron, assistant general secretary of teaching union NASUWT, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Schools are very vulnerable. If this becomes something which develops in a significant way, schools would have to think about ways in which they can protect themselves, and I have no doubt that in that case money would be spent on insurance that could otherwise be spent on educating children.&quot; ($1=.5953 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
