<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227108" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Volcano erupts in eastern Zaire.</title>
<headline>Volcano erupts in eastern Zaire.</headline>
<dateline>RUMANGABE, Zaire 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eastern Zaire's Nyamulagira volcano erupted on Sunday close to camps abandoned by Rwandan Hutu refugees, spewing jets of lava high into the air and forming a lava trail 10 km (six miles) long through forests.</p>
<p>A Reuters correspondent who travelled to Rumangabe, north of the deserted refugee camps of Kahindo and Katale, saw about 10 km of burning forest in the Virunga national park left by boiling lava as it moved northwestwards.  </p>
<p>A U.N. refugee agency spokesman in the Rwandan capital Kigali told Reuters the eruption posed no threat to the human population as the area was abandoned weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It probably does not pose any hazard to people. We checked and the Katale and Kahindo camps are completely empty,&quot; said UNHCR spokesman Paul Stromberg.</p>
<p>The crater of the volcano was hidden by thick cloud.</p>
<p>The slopes of the volcano and surrounding areas are home to tropical rain forest and rare mountain gorillas.</p>
<p>The volcano, 40 km (25 miles) northwest of the Zairean border town of Goma, is one of seven in the area of the Virunga National Park as well as on the Rwanda-Zaire-Uganda border.</p>
<p>Only two are active, Nyamulagira and Nyaragongo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RUMANGABE, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
