<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227134" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Opposition say Belgrade police detain official.</title>
<headline>Opposition say Belgrade police detain official.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbian police arrested an opposition official on Sunday in Belgrade after two weeks of street protests against President Slobodan Milosevic, the opposition coalition said on Sunday. Zelko Ozegovic, a candidate for the district council in Belgrade, was arrested in the morning for the second time in two days, the Zajedno (Together) coalition alleged in a statement.</p>
<p>Zajedno said they had no further details of the arrest and also said a 19-year-old opposition supporter had been detained in the town of Novi Sad.</p>
<p>Serbian authorities were not immediately available for comment. Zajedno officials expressed concern over the arrests and warned President Milosevic that these detentions could provoke &quot;incidents&quot;.</p>
<p>The Zajedno statement coincided with the arrest of four demonstrators, who were charged with vandalism and a British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) report that two student protesters were mistreated during a police interrogation.</p>
<p>Yugoslavia's state media reported earlier that Serbian authorities had charged four demonstrators with vandalism in street protests in which some opposition supporters threw stones at the state television building and newspaper offices.</p>
<p>The Belgrade public prosecutor said police had arrested four men on suspicion of causing major damage to property in the Serbian capital, state television reported.</p>
<p>Two of the suspects were 18 years old and one was 20, authorities said.</p>
<p>Belgrade has been rocked by unprecedented street protests over the past two weeks after authorities annulled the results of an oppositon victory in local elections.</p>
<p>Demonstrators have focused their anger on two symbols of President Milosevic's power -- the state television station and state newspaper offices.</p>
<p>Opposition supporters have pelted the buildings with eggs and some have thrown stones, shattering plate glass windows.</p>
<p>Opposition stewards put a stop to the stone-throwing a few days ago and the protests have remained peaceful.</p>
<p>Milosevic's state media has portrayed the protesters as outlaws trying to stir up violent conflict.</p>
<p>University student leaders, who have launched their protests in support of the opposition, expressed concern over a report that two student demonstrators were abused by police.</p>
<p>Britain's BBC reported that two students, one woman and one man, alleged they were mistreated in an eight-hour interrogation on Saturday.</p>
<p>The students, who asked not to be identified and were not among those named by the prosecutor's office, say they were arrested on Saturday. They said police repeatedly slapped them and accused them of throwing stones at state media buildings.</p>
<p>The two students strongly deny throwing stones or committing acts of vandalism and said they were interrogated at length about their involvement in street protests, which have drawn thousands of students.</p>
<p>Authorities were not immediately available for comment on the allegations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
