<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22711" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German austerity plan passes key lower house vote.</title>
<headline>German austerity plan passes key lower house vote.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>The lower house of the German parliament voted again on Thursday to back the government's austerity plan, allowing the package to proceed on schedule for enactment in mid-September.</p>
<p>In a special session, Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christian Democrats and their allies the Christian Social Union and Free Democrats cast aside objections decided on Monday by an arbitration committee of both houses of parliament.</p>
<p>The government unveiled its Programme for More Growth and Jobs in April, aiming to cut 50 billion marks from public spending and 20 billion marks from health, social security and pension funds in 1997.</p>
<p>The upper house, dominated by the opposition Social Democrats, is expected to vote against the package of bills on September 12, but its approval is not required for the bills to become law.</p>
<p>Most of the bills are likely to be passed into law by the lower house the following day.</p>
<p>That vote, however, will face a higher hurdle, requiring an absolute majority of the lower house, instead of the simple majority of those present needed in Thursday's vote.</p>
<p>In Thursday's debate, economics minister Guenter Rexrodt stressed that the aim of the package was to reduce joblessness by slimming the state, easing the burden on corporations and encouraging competition.</p>
<p>-- Terence Gallagher, Bonn newsroom, 49 228 26097150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
