<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227164" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: Cuba sees AIDS rise linked to tourism growth.</title>
<headline>Cuba sees AIDS rise linked to tourism growth.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cuba, where anti-AIDS measures have kept the number of cases relatively low, is likely to see the virus start to spread in 1997 because of an expected increase in tourism and sexually-transmitted diseases, a report published on Sunday said.</p>
<p>The Cuban news agency Prensa Latina quoted health officials as saying the number of HIV-positive cases registered so far in Cuba rose to 1,408 in November. Of these, 524 had developed AIDS and 373 had died.</p>
<p>This compared with 1,196 HIV-positive cases reported at the end of 1995 on the communist-ruled Caribbean island.</p>
<p>&quot;Existing estimates point to an expected increased incidence of the disease in the country in 1997 due, among other causes, to the growth of tourism and the increase of sexually-transmitted diseases,&quot; Prensa Latina said.</p>
<p>In general, the occurrence of AIDS among Cuba's 11 million population has remained low because of a combination of widespread AIDS testing and a policy of isolating patients in special sanatoriums.</p>
<p>Prensa Latina quoted Manuel Hernandez of Cuba's National Centre for Health Education as saying the Cuban adult population had a low perception of risk from AIDS and there was a widespread unwillingness to use condoms.</p>
<p>Tourism has become Cuba's fastest growing economic sector, but the increased arrival of foreign visitors has led to a visible rise in prostitution over the last few years.</p>
<p>Concerned by this, Cuban authorities have moved to try to halt the increase in prostitution, which they link to the faster spread of AIDS and other sexually transmitted diseases. There have been periodic crackdowns on pimps and prostitutes.</p>
<p>The Cuban policy of isolating AIDS patients in special sanatoriums was originally applied to all HIV cases, but this has been relaxed. Half of the island's HIV carriers are now allowed to live normally in society, receiving regular medical treatment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
