<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227221" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-News Corp says Fairfax off agenda.</title>
<headline>RTRS-News Corp says Fairfax off agenda.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The head of The News Corp Ltd's Australian operations said on Sunday that a takeover of newspaper publisher John Fairfax Holdings Ltd was no longer on the agenda for the global media group.</p>
<p>Ken Cowley, executive chairman of Sydney-based News Ltd, said News Corp chairman and chief executive Rupert Murdoch had ambitions to take over Fairfax about a year ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It was serious a year ago, but it's gone away...,&quot; he said in an interview of Channel Nine's Business Sunday programme.</p>
<p>&quot;I mean it's no secret that Mr Murdoch may have romanced with the idea, but that's gone away and I think in all seriousness, it was never more than a strategic investment.&quot;</p>
<p>News Corp confirmed earlier this month that it sold almost all its five percent stake in Fairfax.</p>
<p>Cowley, who said foreigners should be allowed to invest more in Australian media assets, said he now hoped that Canadian Conrad Black would end up with control of Fairfax in preference to Australian media mogul and Murdoch rival Kerry Packer.  </p>
<p>Black, who holds about 25 percent of Fairfax, has said he wants to build his stake to at least 50 percent. Packer's interests hold a 15 percent stake in the newspaper group.</p>
<p>Black is prevented from boosting his stake under rules limiting foreign ownership while Packer's ambitions are thwarted by regulations which restrict cross-media ownership.</p>
<p>Packer controls the market-leading Nine Network through his control of Publishing and Broadcasting Ltd.</p>
<p>Australian Communications Minister Richard Alston said in another interview on Sunday that the federal government would probably reconsider foreign ownership restrictions in the media industry but not as a part of its current cross-media inquiry.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's fair to say that in due course, we will have to contemplate an ongoing approach to foreign ownership,&quot; Alston said later on Channel Nine's Sunday programme.</p>
<p>&quot;But this inquiry is principally about cross media,&quot; he said. &quot;That was what we said prior to the election, that is what we have criticised consistently, that's what we want to improve.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
