<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227247" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia launches quest for world recognition in autos.</title>
<headline>Malaysia launches quest for world recognition in autos.</headline>
<byline>Maryanne Masilamany</byline>
<dateline>LANGKAWI, Malaysia 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia on Sunday launched its quest for recognition in the world automotive industry at the 1996 Langkawi International Motor Show (LIMOS), led by its newest acquisition, British sports car maker Lotus.</p>
<p>&quot;Malaysians have developed a greater interest in automobiles since we began to produce our own cars. This exhibition ... is an expression of that keenness,&quot; Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said in a speech after opening LIMOS '96.</p>
<p>LIMOS '96, the second international automobile show on Langkawi island, is to become an annual event, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have always encouraged the growth of the motor industry and would do anything to ensure technology transfer in the advancement of the industry,&quot; he said in separate message to LIMOS.</p>
<p>&quot;We would also like Malaysia to be the centre for international car manufacturers to showcase their latest design and technology in the Asia-Pacific region,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In a new 10-year industrial master plan unveiled last week, Malaysia announced that the automotive sector would be one of eight industry groups targetted for development from assembly operations stage to full-scale manufacturing.</p>
<p>Under the plan, Malaysia hopes to develop an automotive industry capable of producing one million cars annually without any external technological dependance.</p>
<p>At present, Malaysia's national car maker, Proton, manufactures designs licensed from Mitsubishi Motor Corp of Japan and Citroen of France.</p>
<p>Many other European, Japanese and U.S. made cars are assembled by various Malaysian companies.</p>
<p>In October, Proton and its chairman Yahaya Ahmad acquired 80 percent of British firm Lotus Group International Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;This acquisition will enable us to learn more about automotive engineering,&quot; Mahathir said in his speech.</p>
<p>After his speech, the prime minister drove out to the exhibition in an 1886-built Mercedes three-wheel car, but he was clear about who would steal the show at LIMOS.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course, the stars of the show are the Lotus cars, the unique and limited cars which should draw much attention,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said Lotus cars were not easily available in the East, but Proton would soon begin marketing them in the region.</p>
<p>Apart from the big international brand names displaying their latest wares, LIMOS has also attracted a concept car, the Xanae, developed by Citroen, and a locally-designed sports car.</p>
<p>The Prime Minister launched the sports car, the Delfino, developed and designed by a Malaysian, Arjunaidy Ariffin, who said manufacture of the model would begin next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LANGKAWI, Malaysia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
