<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227356" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tobacco firms to battle Massachusetts law in court.</title>
<headline>Tobacco firms to battle Massachusetts law in court.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>On Halloween last year, the five-year-old son of Massachusetts state Sen. Warren Tolman was going trick-or-treating dressed up as a cowboy when he looked up at his father and said, &quot;Dad, all cowboys smoke, right?&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It really hits you when your five-year-old son asks you about smoking,&quot; Tolman told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Tolman said his son's question led him to sponsor legislation that would make Massachusetts the first state in the country to require tobacco companies to disclose their ingredients.</p>
<p>The legislation, signed into law last August and scheduled to go into effect next July, would also set tougher tests to measure the nicotine intake from cigarettes, snuff and chewing tobacco.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, four major tobacco companies will challenge the law in a federal court in Boston. The law violates federal trade statutes and constitutional rights and would disclose valuable trade secrets, said David Remes, a lawyer for the tobacco companies.</p>
<p>The four companies -- Philip Morris Cos Inc, R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co, a unit of RJR Nabisco Holdings Corp, Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp, a unit of B.A.T Industries Plc and Lorillard Tobacco Co, a unit of Loews Corp -- account for more than 90 percent of the cigarettes sold in the state.</p>
<p>The Massachusetts law, if successful in court, could spur other states to pass similar laws and force the tobacco companies to change their ingredients, Tolman said.</p>
<p>Legislators and health officials in Illinois, Florida, New York, Texas, Minnesota, Michigan and other states have contacted Massachusetts officials about the law, Tolman and other officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the hope is that other states will follow our lead,&quot; Massachusetts Attorney General Scott Harshbarger told Reuters. &quot;This law is really asking the tobacco companies to play by the same rules as every other company in this state ... so the consumers can make choices and judgments.&quot;</p>
<p>Massachusetts would use the information on the ingredients and nicotine levels in its $12 million advertising campaign to alert the more than one million smokers in the state of the dangers of tobacco, health officials said.</p>
<p>The tobacco companies said in court papers they might stop selling tobacco in Massachusetts, where annual sales top $1.2 billion, if the law goes into effect.</p>
<p>Tolman said the tobacco companies would more likely stop selling in Massachusetts long enough to change their ingredients, as R.J. Reynolds did in 1989 when Canada passed a similiar law.</p>
<p>The four tobacco companies said in court papers that disclosing their trade secrets would &quot;destroy the value of that property ... not only in Massachusetts but in every other state and throughout the world.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This law sets a very, very dangerous precedent for all businesses,&quot; Remes said. &quot;What the Commonwealth (of Massachusetts) does today for tobacco companies, it can do tomorrow to other industries.&quot;</p>
<p>Remes said food manufacturers use generic terms such as &quot;spices&quot; or &quot;flavorings&quot; on ingredient lists on packages in order to keep their trade secrets.</p>
<p>&quot;This is like telling Coca-Cola to tell Pepsi what makes Coke different. Companies can't compete if they have no trade secret protection,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Tolman said the tobacco companies are keeping secret such ingredients as amino acids, plant extracts and toxic compounds that can cause organ damage when burned.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the only product in which you can not find out the ingredients,&quot; Tolman said. &quot;It is the only product which, when used as the manufacturer recommends, will kill you.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
