<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227470" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stock rally seen cooling, Tokyo to drift.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stock rally seen cooling, Tokyo to drift.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian stock markets are mainly set for a week of consolidation or mild losses, analysts in the region said.</p>
<p>Appetite for Hong Kong shares is likely to taper off after the market's record-shattering rally last week while Tokyo's main index is expected to remain trapped in a range, although foreign buyers are likely to return to the market after last Thursday's U.S. Thanksgiving holiday. Elsewhere in the region, brokers predict generally lacklustre conditions due to an absence of fresh factors and the approach of the December holiday season.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Stocks are expected to cool off this week after a buying frenzy pushed the blue chip Hang Seng index to an all-time high last week, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the market may cool down a little bit,&quot; said Frederick Tsang, head of research at PrimeEast Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;This last upleg has been very strong and we have not had a sizeable correction so the market is probably likely to consolidate a bit,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index rose 277.14 points, or 2.11 percent, last week to close at 13,393.93 on Friday. The index surged to a new all-time high during the week of 13,744.30 points.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TOKYO - Tokyo's benchmark Nikkei 225 index is likely to hug the 21,000 level this week, searching for a chance to break out of its current range, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The floor is firming, as interest rates are not likely to be raised soon and pension funds are eager to buy on dips,&quot; said Haruo Nakaharu, strategist at Toyo Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;But unless the index can keep its head up above the end-March level of 21,406, it may not have the strength to break out of that box,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The blue-chip rally should resume this week when foreign investors return after the U.S. Thanksgiving Day holiday, Harushige Kobayashi, Yamaichi Securities deputy general manager said.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Nikkei settled 15.18 points or 0.07 percent lower at 21,020.36. It closed at 21,216.11 the week before.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SINGAPORE - Singapore blue chip stocks are expected to consolidate over the week, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Blue chips are going into hibernation as a lot of fund managers are going on holiday in December,&quot; said a dealer.</p>
<p>However, dealers said window-dressing could give blue chips a boost later in December. The key Straits Times Industrials Index closed down 11.58 points at 2,188.09 on Friday, compared to 2,194.75 the week before.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BANGKOK - The Stock Exchange of Thailand (SET) index is expected to decline slightly this week due to a lack of fresh positive news and jitters over the economy, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The only good news seen next week is that major local commercial banks will start cutting their prime lending rates by 25 basis points. But this news is discounted by investors already,&quot; said Thanadech Mahapokai of Book Club Finance and Securities.</p>
<p>The market will be closed on Thursday for the King's birthday. The SET index closed down 12.45 points at 925.97 points on Friday, compared with 970.30 the previous Friday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MANILA - Analysts were mixed on the outlook for this week as some saw GNP data at the weekend as the key factor, while others said banking rule changes would turn the focus to bank stocks.</p>
<p>The government said on Saturday that nine-month GNP rose 7.1 percent against a 5.3 percent gain in the year-ago period.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be buying interest on GNP-sensitive stocks which include property, construction and food issues,&quot; Cilette Liboro, research head at Citisecurities Inc said.</p>
<p>But Felix Barrientos, trader at ING Barings, said the market would move sideways with interest focused on bank stocks, following the Central Bank's decision this week to cut reserve requirements by two percentage points to 13 percent.</p>
<p>The main index ended Friday at 3,090.16, 12.2 points lower, or 0.39 percent, from the previous Friday's close of 3,102.36.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TAIPEI - Taiwan share prices may have little room to rise in the coming week amid worries that the government might take action to cool the over-heated stock market after November's sharp gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;November's rally was mainly driven by the government's supportive policies, people will turn cautious once the government shows signs of backing off,&quot; said Lin Long-hsien of United Securities.</p>
<p>On Friday, the index ended at 6,765.93, compared with last Friday's 6,761.39. Bargain hunting helped the weighted index recover 60.13 points to 6,826.06 on Saturday, but was not seen by analysts as a shift in sentiment.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA - Analysts said the market was likely to be mixed this week with possible bargain-hunting in some medium and big-capitalised stocks, and selective foreign buying.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment will be mixed. I don't expect any surprises which can boost sentiment, like the listing of BNI last Monday which pushed the index to a new year high,&quot; a foreign broker said.</p>
<p>Bank Negara Indonesia's debut was well received by investors, who boosted the index to 628.24 points.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Jakarta Composite Index closed at 613.01 points, against last week's 612.86 points.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>WELLINGTON - New Zealand shares ended Friday on another lacklustre note as the market awaited clues from New Zealand First Party leader Winston Peters about who would form the next government.</p>
<p>&quot;We're just going to have a continuation of the trend of a sideways market until we see resolution of the political situation,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 Capital Index ended at 2,348.42, barely changed from last Friday's close of 2,352.13.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SEOUL - Seoul shares are expected to continue to consolidate this week as poor economic indicators and stock oversupply act as a drag on sentiment, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;I see further consolidation for the market for the time being,&quot; said a Dongsuh Securities broker. &quot;The downside risk is limited but the upside is also slim.&quot;</p>
<p>Investors, disappointed that rumoured market boosting measures did not materialise this week, might dump shares early next week, brokers cautioned.</p>
<p>On Friday, the composite index closed at 733.50, up 2.06 points, or 0.28 percent, from the previous Friday's close of 731.44.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The Australian stock market was seen drifting in directionless trade in the near term with little in the way of corporate news to inspire local players.</p>
<p>The benchmark All Ordinaries index ended at 2,388.6 on Friday, a gain of 5.2 points over the week.</p>
<p>After a meandering week's trade, brokers said the local market looked like settling into its pre-Christmas torpor with only major moves on Wall Street likely to change things.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KUALA LUMPUR - Stock prices should remain in a consolidation phase early this week, but the trend could be affected by requotation of banking shares Rashid Hussain, Maybank and DCB Holdings on Monday, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is waiting to see what happens after the relisting of Maybank and Rashid Hussain and the other banking stocks,&quot; said Simon Maughan, head of research at W.I. Carr in Kuala Lumpur.</p>
<p>&quot;But, if the Dow drops say 200 points the Index will fall. The market is sentiment driven at the moment,&quot; Maughan said.</p>
<p>Week-on-week, the Composite Index rose 8.56 points to 1,226.52 from 1,217.96 at last Friday's close.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
