<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227466" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: S.Africa's Manuel says rand set to strengthen.</title>
<headline>S.Africa's Manuel says rand set to strengthen.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African rand is set to strengthen against major currencies in the near term, having been oversold during recent bouts of weakness, Finance Minister Trevor Manuel said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a fair amount of room for strengthening. I think generally it's been accepted that there's been an overshoot in the last period,&quot; he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;There's likely to be some strengthening over the next while,&quot; Manuel said when asked if he saw some strengthening in the rand over the next year or so.</p>
<p>Manuel, who is in Australia for a trade conference, said the currency was backed by a commitment by South Africa's central bank to support it over the long term.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a constitutionally entrenched independent reserve bank that has a constitutional mandate to protect the long-term value of the currency,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Manuel did not give a precise forecast for the rand.</p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Reuters last week forecast an exchange rate for the rand of 4.92 against the dollar by the end of 1997, and 5.17 by the end of the following year.</p>
<p>The rand, which has plummeted 30 percent against the dollar this year, was last traded at around 4.6130/4.6180.</p>
<p>Manuel declined to give a timeframe for the removal of foreign exchange controls, despite Reserve Bank Governor Chris Stals' comments to Reuters last month that it was linked to the implementation of the government's macroeconomic strategy, a four to five-year process.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know why he said four to five years. The view I've held...is that it's a process shaped by circumstances rather than by some date pulled from a hat,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>But he said the removal of exchange controls was tied to reserve levels which remain low.</p>
<p>&quot;I think your reserve level is going to be key to that entire situation,&quot; Manuel said.</p>
<p>South Africa's official reserves rose slightly to 10.28 billion rand in October from 10.04 billion in September.</p>
<p>-- Melbourne Bureau 61-3 9286-1435</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
