<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227402" id="root" date="1996-12-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German Greens end congress aiming for government.</title>
<headline>German Greens end congress aiming for government.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Gray</byline>
<dateline>SUHL, Germany 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's opposition Greens ended a three-day party congress on Sunday, buoyed by the choice of a new co-leader to spearhead their next general election campaign with the aim of ousting Chancellor Helmut Kohl.</p>
<p>The Greens, who have grown from the peace movement and student demonstrations of the 1960s and 1970s to become Germany's third political force, hope to form a coalition with the main opposition Social Democrats (SPD) after the 1998 poll.</p>
<p>The fiercely egalitarian party elected Gunda Roestel, a 34-year old east German schoolteacher, for a two-year term in the leadership post it reserves for a female candidate.</p>
<p>&quot;People under 30 have known no other chancellor than Helmut Kohl in their entire polical lives,&quot; Roestel told around 750 delegates in the eastern town of Suhl. &quot;People expect a signal from politics and it is up to us to give that signal here.&quot;</p>
<p>Opinion polls show the Greens attracting around 12 percent of the national vote and indicate that, if they maintain current levels of support together with the SPD, they could topple Kohl's centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>&quot;This party conference must herald the start of our campaign to bring about a change of government in 1998,&quot; said Rezzo Schlauch, a Green member of parliament who narrowly failed to become mayor of Stuttgart in an election earlier this year.</p>
<p>Roestel replaced Krista Sager, who quit the top job to concentrate on local elections next year in her home city of Hamburg. The party also re-elected Juergen Trittin to its male co-leadership post.</p>
<p>The Greens devoted much of the congress to economic policy in a bid to show they can be not just Germany's environmental conscience but also a professional party of government.</p>
<p>Signs of the party's ecological roots were still evident -- stalls outside the conference hall sold hemp products and health foods while a slogan on the platform proclaimed: &quot;We have only borrowed the earth from our children&quot; -- but largely subdued.</p>
<p>In a sign of increasing discipline, delegates voted against discussing the concept of military force as a last resort to stop violent conflicts, an issue which provoked a bitter debate in the traditionally pacifist party at a congress last year.</p>
<p>The Greens' increasing acceptance by the political mainstream was demonstrated by the fact that the leader of Germany's trade unionists gave a speech to open the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We have more in common these days than the belief that an incompetent government is in charge in Bonn,&quot; said Dieter Schulte, whose movement has close ties to the SPD and has been suspicious of Green anti-industrial rhetoric in the past.</p>
<p>Numerous delegates urged the party to do more to attract support in eastern Germany. The Greens are widely perceived in the former communist region as having no concrete solutions to problems of industrial decline and high unemployment.</p>
<p>Officials said they hoped holding the conference in Suhl -- a popular East German winter sports resort -- and electing Roestel, the director of a school for handicapped children in the state of Saxony, would give them a boost in the east.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps the difficulty of reaching this idyllic town also shows the difficulty we have in getting across in the east,&quot; Roestel said. Many delegates struggled to get to the conference as public transport ground to halt in heavy snow.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's make Suhl a good sign for the recovery of our party in the east,&quot; Roestel urged.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SUHL, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
