<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227552" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. corporate market off to a slow start.</title>
<headline>U.S. corporate market off to a slow start.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Primary and secondary market activity among U.S. corporate bonds was subdued on the Monday following the Thanksgiving vacation, traders said.</p>
<p>Traders said prices on high-grade bonds were unchanged relative to Treasuries, while junk bonds ended the day unchanged to marginally higher.</p>
<p>Volume in both markets was low, they added.  </p>
<p>TCI Communications Inc bonds tightened several basis points on Monday as the market digested news of a $500 million shelf offering of preferred stock by the company.</p>
<p>TCI said in a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission last Wednesday that it would use proceeds from the offering to pay down existing commerical paper.</p>
<p>Some market players said the move could help the company avoid a downgrade of its debt rating, which is currently under review by Standard &amp; Poor's.</p>
<p>But Marion Boucher Soper, a media analyst at Bear Stearns &amp; Co Inc, said the move was unlikely to affect S&amp;P's decision.  </p>
<p>&quot;This may help their balance sheet but there are bigger issues which S&amp;P is dealing with, such as whether the company will hit its debt-to-cash flow projections,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The S&amp;P analyst covering TCI debt could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Among high-yield credits, bids for MobileMedia 9-3/8 percent bonds fell two to three points as the company failed to make interst payments by the end of a grace period.</p>
<p>In the primary market, while no investment-grade corporate deals priced on Monday, syndicate officials expected total new issuance for the week to come in at $4 billion to $5 billion.  </p>
<p>One sydnicate official predicted new issuance would increase substantially from these levels if the yield on the on-the-run ten-year Treasury dropped below six percent or if the yield on the benchmark 30-year dropped below 6-1/4 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If the long bond dips below 6-1/4 that would allow a single-A issuer to finance inside seven percent and that's pretty attractive. You could see a slew of new bank and finance paper and a marginal pickup in industrial issuance at those rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The on-the-run ten-year closed at 103-7/32 to yield 6.06 percent. The benchmark long-bond closed at 101-27/32 to yield 6.36 percent.  </p>
<p>Despite a heavy forward calendar of well over $1 billion in new high-yield deals, syndicate officials said new issuance could be light this week as many dealers were conducting roadshows.</p>
<p>In what may be an indication that investor appetite for new high-yield paper remains strong, AES China Generating Co increased the size of its upcoming junk deal to $180 million from $150 million, according to a source familiar with the situation.</p>
<p>The deal, which will be underwritten by Morgan Stanley &amp; Co Inc, will be priced next week, the source said.</p>
<p>-Douglas Brown, 212-859-1662</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
