<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22753" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swissair ground staff reject wage cuts.</title>
<headline>Swissair ground staff reject wage cuts.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Worker councils representing ground staff at Swissair AG on Thursday said they unequivocally rejected management proposal to cut salaries by five percent across the board.</p>
<p>A statement from three personnel unions and worker councils representing 7,700 Swissair ground staff said shorter working hours, which would improve employment, was preferred.</p>
<p>Union representatives and Swissair management, led by chief operating officer Philippe Bruggisser, met earlier today and unions will consider their response next Monday.</p>
<p>At the meeting Bruggisser modified Swissair's position and told the worker representatives that a five percent cut was not mandatory, but managment would insist on carrying out savings of 30 million Swiss francs.</p>
<p>A Swissair spokesman confirmed Bruggisser's views.</p>
<p>On July 30 Bruggisser told Swissair's staff magazine that he would beging talks with worker councils with the aim of lowering personnel costs by five percent in 1997.</p>
<p>The savings are part of Swissair's overall target of cutting personnel costs by five percent, or some 100 million francs.</p>
<p>Swissair is working on improving its bottom line by 500 million francs by 1998, including 100 million in personnel cost that also will be achieved by reducing jobs.</p>
<p>The protest over management's proposal reflects the growing dissatisfaction among ground staff, which has seen productivity increase dramatically, unions said.</p>
<p>The unions noted staffing had been cut by 18 percent since 1991 while revenue tonne-kilometres -- a measure of an airlines production -- had risen more than 40 percent.</p>
<p>-- Peter Nielsen, Zurich Editorial +41 1 631 7340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
