<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227522" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US not happy with NAFTA rule on Canada ag tariffs.</title>
<headline>US not happy with NAFTA rule on Canada ag tariffs.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. government and agricultural industry officials said Monday they were deeply disappointed with a final ruling by a NAFTA panel that Canadian tariffs on imports of U.S. poultry and dairy products are legal under the North American Free Trade Agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;We are deeply disappointed that the panel supported Canada's view that it could apply extremely high tariff rates to imports of dairy, poultry, egg, barley and margarine products from the United States,&quot; said a joint statement from Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman and Acting U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky.  </p>
<p>The two cabinet officials said that the panel's ruling &quot;has no basis&quot; and &quot;is inconsistent with the commitment in the NAFTA and the U.S.-Canada Free Trade Agreement (CFTA) that all duties be eliminated by January 1, 1998.&quot;</p>
<p>Glickman and Barshefsky said, &quot;The United States will do everything possible, consistent with our trade laws, to seek the ultimate elimination of these duties...&quot;</p>
<p>Washington will continue to reveiw Canada's dairy industry support programs, according to the statement, and will carefully review the panel's report and &quot;consult closely&quot; with Congress and the U.S. industry on the findings.  </p>
<p>The U.S. poultry and dairy industry also reacted angrily to the final ruling, which had been fairly well anticipated.</p>
<p>&quot;The panel's decision was wrong and disappointing,&quot; said the National Broiler Council. &quot;We are dismayed, but we expect our government to pursue this matter with the Canadian government.&quot;</p>
<p>The U.S. Dairy Export Council said the panel's decision &quot;flies in the face of all logic and reason, running counter to the letter and spirit of free trade ... it's report is completely unacceptable.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The battle is far from over,&quot; said the dairy group. The association said it would continue to press Washington to bring Canada back to the negotiating table.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
