<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227651" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends broadly lower as speculators sell.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends broadly lower as speculators sell.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended lower across-the-board Monday in technically driven trade, pressured by speculative selling, floor sources said.</p>
<p>But a round of light trade buying and local short covering lifted prices off session lows, they said.</p>
<p>Commission house selling at the open touched off sell-stops below 106.50 cents a lb basis March, spurring fund selling, which took arabica prices to their lowest levels in over a month.</p>
<p>Traders and analysts said the sharp decline in London last Thursday set today's weak tone. LIFFE futures tumbled through key support levels to end at 31-month lows Thursday on speculative long liquidation. CSCE was closed Thursday and Friday for the Thanksgiving holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;The fall in London over the long weekend caused the lower opening,&quot; one analyst said.</p>
<p>Benchmark March coffee settled 1.70 cents a lb lower, at 106.05, after ranging between 107.40 and 104.50. Spot December futures finished down 1.45 cents, to 114.80, while the remaining months closed 1.00 to 1.85 weaker.</p>
<p>Technically, traders said March support was seen near 103.50 cents, while resistance was pegged at 107.50 cents.</p>
<p>The CSCE will release its weekly certified stock report after the close Monday. As of Wednesday, the CSCE said 2,500 bags of coffee were pending grading.</p>
<p>Last week, the CSCE reported that U.S. certified coffee stocks were unchanged at 321 60-kg bags in the week ended Nov. 22, the lowest level since the CSCE began tracking stocks in 1980.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, open interest in the December contract, which entered its month-long notice period Nov. 19, fell by 143 lots on Wednesday, to 1,336 lots, the equivalent of more than 300,000 bags of coffee. As of Monday, no delivery notices had been issued.</p>
<p>Turnover reached an estimated 8,514 lots.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
