<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227738" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-AC MILAN CONFIRM SACCHI BACK AS COACH.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-AC MILAN CONFIRM SACCHI BACK AS COACH.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy coach Arrigo Sacchi, increasingly seen as a lame duck even by his team, has ended months of debate about his future by resigning and returning to AC Milan, the club where he made his name.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that we have made the right choice by turning to Arrigo Sacchi,&quot; billionaire media mogul Silvio Berlusconi, owner of the Italian champions, said on Monday.</p>
<p>Sacchi had called the Italian soccer federation (FIGC) special commissioner Raffaele Pagnozzi shortly before midnight on Sunday to advise him of his decision.</p>
<p>&quot;I can't say no to Berlusconi. Milan calls me, I can only resign. Try to understand,&quot; the Corriere dello Sport newspaper quoted the 50-year-old Sacchi as saying.</p>
<p>FIFA vice-president Antonio Matarrese, the former FIGC chairman who appointed Sacchi in 1991, said the coach had called him also at midnight to break the news.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's just say it was in the air,&quot; Matarrese said of the move. &quot;And it's what so many Italians wanted.&quot;</p>
<p>Sacchi, who spent five glorious years at Milan until his appointment to the national side in 1991, replaces Oscar Washington Tabarez who has had a bleak six months with the club that lost 3-2 at lowly Piacenza on Sunday.</p>
<p>That defeat dropped Milan, who have a key European Champions' League match against Norway's Rosenborg on Wednesday, to ninth in the league.</p>
<p>&quot;This morning they told me they had accepted my resignation,&quot; Tabarez said on Monday. He was the third serie A coach to leave clubs this season and the second Uruguayan casualty.</p>
<p>It was not yet clear who would succeed Sacchi in the most criticised job in Italian soccer but two men have emerged as clear favourites for the nomination, expected after the FIGC elects a new chairman on December 14.</p>
<p>Italy's next match is away to England in February in a key qualifier for the 1998 World Cup.</p>
<p>Former World Cup-winning goalkeeper Dino Zoff, now chairman of Lazio, has been heavily tipped as a likely replacement despite a nondescript coaching record. Under-21 coach Cesare Maldini has been seen as a possible stop-gap.</p>
<p>Former Parma coach Nevio Scala is immediately available having left his club at the end of last season.</p>
<p>Other candidates, seemingly coming more from the realms of fantasy football than reality, include Bayern Munich coach Giovanni Trappatoni and Real Madrid coach Fabio Capello -- the man who took over from Sacchi as Milan coach in 1991.</p>
<p>At that time, the national team was held to have rescued Milan from a difficult position by relieving them of Sacchi at a time when several players were openly in revolt.</p>
<p>On Monday, the boot was on the other foot with Milan relieving the FIGC of the need to dismiss a coach whose contract ran to 1998 and who had seemed determined to hang on.</p>
<p>Sacchi took Italy to the 1994 World Cup final in Los Angeles, where they lost on penalties to Brazil, but has been under intense pressure since the side crashed out of Euro 96 in the first phase.</p>
<p>His last match in charge was a friendly against Bosnia in Sarajevo last month that Italy lost 2-1.</p>
<p>Sacchi has a record of 34 wins, 10 draws and nine defeats in the 53 matches he has conducted since November 1991.</p>
<p>He has been criticised for frequent change -- trying out almost 100 players in five years -- and falling out with key men, most notably Gianluca Vialli of Chelsea.</p>
<p>Soft-spoken, reserved and with his sunglasses almost permanently perched on his forehead, Sacchi divided Italy. Some disliked him so much that they formed an anti-Sacchi club. Sacchi said he was willing to join too.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
