<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227881" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Copper reverses after its blistering rally.</title>
<headline>Copper reverses after its blistering rally.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Copper prices turned sharply lower on Monday on a belief that a draw on stocks that fuelled a recent rally may be ending.</p>
<p>But traders said that conditions on the London Metal Exchange (LME) are seen remaining volatile, and prices may easily whip higher again.</p>
<p>&quot;It would not take much to get (the market) up...&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Last afternoon kerb business was at $2,187 a tonne, down $55 on Friday and compared with last week's 6-month peak of $2,313.</p>
<p>LME warehouse stocks on Tuesday are expected to register an increase of 2,000-4,000 tonnes. But even though inventories will have risen for two successive reports, if the forecasts prove accurate, the market remains critically short of metal.</p>
<p>Copper's late losses knocked the rest of the metals complex, and nearly all other LME markets turned lower.</p>
<p>Aluminium finished at $1,518 per tonne, down $11 from Friday, but is still looking to consolidate after last week's advances to six-month highs. Stocks are seen lower tomorrow.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in the commodity sector, gold remained weak, fixing in London at $370.50 per ounce before a very modest rebound, and hovering around 20-month lows.</p>
<p>Selling by South African and Australian gold miners as they became increasingly anxious to protect income against falling prices was cited as a major factor eroding the value of gold.</p>
<p>Dealers and analysts also cited a string of clues to the presence of a central bank as a seller in the market including isolated big offerings on the fixings.</p>
<p>&quot;The pressure at the moment is from central banks' selling and speculators who believe that central banks could sell,&quot; Fedsure Asset Management analyst Nick Goodwin in Johannesburg said.</p>
<p>U.S. grains prices eased.</p>
<p>Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) soybean futures were lower early on nearly ideal soy crop weather in South America.</p>
<p>Maize was lower on the drop in soybeans and wheat eased on news that Pakistan bought 225,000 tonnes of wheat from Australia and none from the United States.</p>
<p>Early Chicago trading saw January soybeans down 12-3/4 cents at $7.00 a bushel. December wheat was down 2-1/2 cents at $3.93-1/2 per bushel.</p>
<p>Coffee steadied after a dramatic fall last week.</p>
<p>London robusta coffee futures were mostly easier but the January contract managed to end $1 per tonne up on the day at $1,337. Other forward contracts lost up to $17.</p>
<p>Speculative funds continued to sell coffee and the trade and roasters bought on the dips. Values had fallen to 31-month lows on Friday as Januaryslipped through key support at $1,340.</p>
<p>Cocoa eased and sugar was little changed.</p>
<p>World oil prices also traded little changed even as Iraq said it signed export agreements with foreign companies under a delayed oil-for-food agreement with the United Nations.</p>
<p>World benchmark Brent Blend for January delivery was trading above $22.75 a barrel late in London's day.</p>
<p>Some key commodity prices at 1730 GMT on Monday</p>
<p>						Monday	     Friday</p>
<p>    Gold ($/ounce)			371.15	     371.35</p>
<p>    IPE Brent ($/barrel) (Jan)	 22.87		22.68</p>
<p>(London Metal Exchange)</p>
<p>    COPPER (three months/tonne)   2,187.00	    2,242.00</p>
<p>    ALUMINIUM			   1,518.00	    1,529.00</p>
<p>Ldn futures)</p>
<p>    COFFEE ($/tonne) (Jan)	  1,337.00	    1,336.00</p>
<p>    COCOA (sterling/tonne) (Mar)    921.00		949.00</p>
<p>    WHITE SUGAR ($/tonne) (Mar)     304.50		303.90</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
