<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227813" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: TENNIS-GRIPPING DAVIS CUP FINAL SILENCES CRITICS.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-GRIPPING DAVIS CUP FINAL SILENCES CRITICS.</headline>
<byline>Clare Lovell</byline>
<dateline>MALMO, Sweden 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A gripping Davis Cup final won for the first time in the final set of the final match by France over Sweden was just what the competition needed to counter critics who accuse it of crowding the tennis schedule.</p>
<p>Leading American players including Andre Agassi have suggested the Cup should be played at most every other year and maybe once every four years.</p>
<p>But nobody in Malmo at the weekend would have agreed.</p>
<p>Sweden's Stefan Edberg, who retired after the tie, said the Cup had to be played annually.</p>
<p>&quot;It was probably the best tennis that can ever happen,&quot; Edberg said. &quot;It is one of the world's biggest competitions in any sport and it involves so many countries.</p>
<p>&quot;It must be played every year.&quot;</p>
<p>Yannick Noah, who has now captained France twice to victory in the final, concurred..</p>
<p>&quot;What I love about the Davis Cup is it is not about contracts, schedules and business. It's different,&quot; Noah said.</p>
<p>&quot;You have to sacrifice things for others, for the team. If you don't want to give up four weeks of your schedule, that's tough. You don't have to play.&quot;</p>
<p>International Tennis Federation president Brian Tobin said he worked hard to find suitable dates that fitted into the players' schedules.</p>
<p>&quot;The main element that sets it apart from other tournaments is the home and away format which allows teams to generate great national interest and pride,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Frenchman Arnaud Boetsch clinched an emotional tie for the French when he held off Nicholas Kulti 7-6 2-6 4-6 7-6 10-8 in the second reverse singles.</p>
<p>&quot;It was my dream to win a Davis Cup final, it's just an unbelievable day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A devastated Kulti commented: &quot;I would have done anything to have won out there today.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MALMO, Sweden"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
