<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227831" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: OUTGOING BULGARIAN PRESIDENT FOUNDS POLITICAL PARTY.</title>
<headline>OUTGOING BULGARIAN PRESIDENT FOUNDS POLITICAL PARTY.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's President Zhelyu Zhelev, who leaves office in January, has set up a new political party which will seek an increase in the president's constitutional powers.</p>
<p>Around 200 intellectuals, some of whom entered politics when Bulgaria started its tortuous transition to democracy and market economy seven years ago, met over the weekend in Sofia to found the Liberal Democratic Alternative (LDA).</p>
<p>&quot;President Zhelyu Zhelev is a member of the party's founding committee and he is expected to join the party as its leader after he relinquishes presidential powers to his successor,&quot; LDA deputy-chairman Georgi Spasov told a news conference on Monday.</p>
<p>Under Bulgaria's post-communist constitution, the president's powers are largely ceremonial but that has never stopped Zhelev from wading into the political fray.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulgaria's political model of transition, the parliamentary republic, has proved ineffective,&quot; said LDA chairman Boris Galabov.</p>
<p>The party says it wants a change to a presidential republic, where the president and government share reponsibility.</p>
<p>&quot;Without quick and bold changes we risk becoming the first post-communist state which has failed in its transition to democracy and a modern market economy,&quot; said a party statement.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Zhelev upset Bulgarians across the political spectrum with calls for a strong Russian-style presidency to avert economic collapse.</p>
<p>He has used his presidential veto frequently, using the Constitutional Court to help him block what he saw as the current government's attempts to curb media freedom and restrict private ownership of land.</p>
<p>Zhelev, the first freely elected head of state in Bulgaria's post-communist history, withdrew from this year's presidential contest after losing a U.S.-style primary election in June to lawyer Petar Stoyanov.</p>
<p>Discontent with the ruling Socialists, who still hold the majority in parliament, swept Stoyanov to victory in the second round of presidential elections last month. He is due to take office in January.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's post-communist parliament chose Zhelev as president in 1990 and two years later he won a five-year mandate in a nationwide election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
