<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="227825" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - DEC 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - CZECH REPUBLIC - DEC 2.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Wages increased by 18.4 percent to 9,214 crowns a month in the third quarter of 1996 as compared to the same period a year earlier when average gross wages amounted to 7,784 crowns a month.</p>
<p>- The Civic Democratic Alliance (ODA) will support the proposed 1997 state budget on condition that reforms are pushed through on liberalisation of rents and energy prices, and cuts in taxation.</p>
<p>- Vladimir Stehlik, the general manager of the Poldi steelmill who has been in prison since last Wednesday with his son Marek, has sent his employees home for a one-month holiday.</p>
<p>- Value-added tax (VAT) should be decreased in the not too distant future, according to Finance Minister Ivan Kocarnik. VAT will make up more than a fifth of state income next year.</p>
<p>- An analysis of Czech Railways' financial situation, which will be used as the basis for its restructuralisation, must include more information on tariffs, state grants and proposals for the development of train routes, said Transport Minster Martin Riman. The proposal should be ready by December 20.</p>
<p>- Aero Vodochody shareholders failed to approve a proposed debt removal plan during their general meeting on Friday, according to the chairman of the board of directors, Jaroslav Borak.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES -  Motoinvest intends to leave the capital market by the end of March, 1997, according to Motoinvest's general manager Pavel Tykac. Tykac stated that the capital market is to risky.</p>
<p>- More and more Czechs are investing their money elsewhere than in traditional bank accounts, including construction savings banks, pension funds and insurance companies.</p>
<p>PRAVO - President Vaclav Havel voiced his support for Petr Pithart to lead the newly-formed Senate. Pithart was the chairman of the federal parliament in the two years following 1989.</p>
<p>- Pragobanka is currently raising its basic capital by 500 million crowns. The bank's basic capital is currently 1.86 billion crowns, according to Pragobanka spokesman, Dusan Michelfeit.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
