<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228023" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: FEATURE - Diamond rush threatens Angola peace.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Diamond rush threatens Angola peace.</headline>
<byline>Lesley Wroughton</byline>
<dateline>LUCAPA, Angola 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>One of the major threats to lasting peace in Angola is wrangling over control of the country's diamond fields, some of the richest on earth.</p>
<p>The government is in charge of the oil riches, but anarchy rules in the diamond-studded northeast, site of rich kimberlite pipes and good quality alluvial gemstones.</p>
<p>Among those wanting a piece of the action are top government officials, military officers, UNITA former rebels, clandestine diggers or &quot;garimpeiros&quot; and illicit diamond buyers who drive expensive off-road vehicles with darkened windows.</p>
<p>A peace pact was signed in Zambia's capital two years ago and fighting stopped between the government and the rebels after nearly two decades of civil war.</p>
<p>This month, the United Nations said it would start to wind down its 6,500-man peackeeping operation, since the Angolan government and UNITA were making good progress in implementing the terms of the Lusaka accord.</p>
<p>By February next year, the U.N. mission could be gone.</p>
<p>But there are still problems between Angola's former civil war foes. Both sides still hold on tightly to their diamond patches and private mining companies are caught in the middle.</p>
<p>UNITA controls the gem-rich Cuango river valley in the west of Lunda Norte province as well as river banks to the east. Its diamond areas bring in an estimated $470 million each year and helped to pay the bills for their 20-year guerrilla war.</p>
<p>Government revenue from diamonds is not half of that.</p>
<p>Talks between UNITA and the state Endiama diamond company have failed to find a settlement and the U.N. has refused to become involved, even though it is overseeing implementation of the 1994 peace accord which ended the war.</p>
<p>CONFLICT WILL NOT BE OVER UNTIL DIAMOND PROBLEM IS RESOLVED</p>
<p>A formal contract with Endiama for a concession, worth millions of dollars, is the first step.</p>
<p>Next is taking control of the site -- evicting hundreds of heavily armed illegal diggers and keeping them out.</p>
<p>&quot;This war will never be over until the government has resolved the problem with UNITA over the diamonds and then the problem still remains in keeping out illegal diggers,&quot; a mining official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Alluvial diamonds are plentiful and excellent in quality, selling for between $280 and $450 per carat.</p>
<p>An illegal diamond digger can make $15,000 per month, in a country where the average person takes home around $40 monthly.</p>
<p>The penalty if caught is up to two years in jail.</p>
<p>Government troops who previously kept order are now confined to barracks in keeping with the terms of the peace accord, so mining companies are using private firms to secure their concessions.</p>
<p>Angolan and South African security companies spent the past year securing concessions for the state-owned Sociedade Mineira do Lucapa Ltd (SML) and British-based ITM mining company.</p>
<p>Among the hazards are ambushes by illegal diggers and landmines left over from two decades of war.</p>
<p>Armed guards patrol on foot for hundreds of kilometres (miles) around the concession.</p>
<p>UNITA miners are busy on terraces on the banks of the Chicapa river just a few hundred metres from ITM's operation and the company has asked the U.N. to help arrange a meeting with former rebel commanders to discuss security.</p>
<p>UNITA divers fetching diamonds from the river bed are guarded by well-armed gunmen.</p>
<p>DIAMOND FIRMS RECRUIT SECURITY GUARDS TO SAFEGUARD MINING</p>
<p>Further east, on the Luo River, security guards watch over a concession for Tricorp and its Canadian-based partner Diamond Works Ltd, formerly known as Carsons Gold, who are to begin mining there soon.</p>
<p>Illegal diamond diggers have threatened to take over the concession, one of the richest in Lunda Norte.</p>
<p>&quot;Our mission is to safeguard the area to ensure that mining activities can be conducted. In a year we have managed to stabilise the area and our clients have doubled their production,&quot; Gray Security's Andre Diedrichs said.</p>
<p>His company recruits Angolan guards with military training to survive the tough working conditions and thick bush.</p>
<p>The settlement of Lucapa was intended to house just 20,000 people, but now over 100,000 live there. Around 19,000 are people displaced during the civil war. Tens of thousands more are illegal immigrants, mainly from Zaire and Senegal.</p>
<p>Lucapa resembles a squatter camp except for neat rows of homes for mining officials, but roads to the town are still not safe enough, so companies have to fly in food and equipment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I23000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUCAPA, Angola"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
