<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228048" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Croat-Serb customs to open in Serb enclave.</title>
<headline>Croat-Serb customs to open in Serb enclave.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Croatian and Serb customs officers have agreed to open a joint customs service at six border crossings in the last Serb-held enclave in Croatia, a U.N. spokesman said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;A transitional customs service...will establish their checkpoints at six different crossings on Tuesday,&quot; Yuri Chizik, spokesman for the U.N. Transitional Administration in Eastern Slavonia (UNTAES) told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Five checkpoints will be at Eastern Slavonia's border with Yugoslavia and one with Hungary. Each will employ Croatian and Serb officers, working closely with UNTAES border monitors, he said.</p>
<p>The officials will wear neutral dark uniforms but will be applying Croatian customs regulations, Chizik said.</p>
<p>The deal followed a Memorandum of understanding signed by UNTAES and the Croatian government on Saturday.</p>
<p>UNTAES's 5,000 peacekeepers are overseeing the gradual return of fertile Eastern Slavonia to Zagreb's rule.</p>
<p>The region split from Croatian authority in a bloody war in 1991 when Zagreb declared independence from the former Yugoslav federation.</p>
<p>The issue of reintegration has been frought with lingering antagonism and suspicion between the Serbs who fear persecution under Croatian rule, and Croat's desire to reclaim lost property.</p>
<p>The process is to be completed next year. Croatia recaptured other Serb enclaves in military action last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
