<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228267" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia's net foreign reserves at year high.</title>
<headline>Colombia's net foreign reserves at year high.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's net foreign reserves stood at $8.32 billion as of November 15, the most recent date for which officials figures are available, the central bank said.</p>
<p>The reserve figure was the highest reported by the central bank, or Banco de la Republica, since Oct 28 of last year when net reserves stood at $8.38 billion.</p>
<p>A recent increase in foreign investment flows, coupled with a surge in dollar-denominated loans and flagging demand for U.S. currency have contributed to the increase in the country's overall foreign reserves.  </p>
<p>The bank has been forced to intervene in Colombia's foreign exchange market by buying dollars in recent weeks to halt the peso's strengthening against the dollar.</p>
<p>The peso, which was trading at more than 1,070 to the dollar in June, closed at 994.19 Friday.  Its rise has put a strain on exporters, who have seen their revenues in real peso terms shrink steadily in recent months despite an increase in production costs stemming from inflation totalling 20.76 percent so far this year.</p>
<p>-- Javier Mozzo, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E513">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
