<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228297" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>Australia: RTRS - PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News-Dec 3.</title>
<headline>RTRS - PRESS DIGEST - Australian Business News-Dec 3.</headline>
<text>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Serving a three-year jail sentence following his conviction in August in the La Promenade case, Perth businessman Alan Bond is expected to plead guilty in the Perth Supreme Court tomorrow to participating in Australia's biggest corporate fraud, involving the alleged transfer of more than A$1 billion from Bell Resources to Bond Corp. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Leaving nothing to chance in its bid to secure rival Sydney-based regional Advance Bank, St George Bank is offering to pay stockbrokers a fee for each proxy vote gathered from Advance shareholders and has started calling Advance shareholders to ask them which way they will vote at the first of two ballots on December 23. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Seeking to recover funds used in two allegedly sham foreign exchange deals in 1988 with companies associated with New Zealand entrepreneur Allan Hawkins, via the Bank of New Zealand, mediation talks are set to begin today in Foster's A$66.5 million civil laim against the Bank of New Zealand and former Foster's executives, including John Elliott. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Dutch-owned financial services group Mercantile Mutual Holdings Ltd posted a total group premium increase of A$1.51 billion in the year to September 30 and an 18 per cent rise in annual net profit to A$71.1 million. Managing director Rod Atfield said the result reflected a higher level of business being written by the intermediaries through which the company distributed its products. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>UK-based Premier Oil has won support from Discovery Petroleum's major shareholders after raising its takeover offer by just one cent. The new offer valued Discovery at A$107 million and prompted Oil Search Ltd, which had been considering a rival offer, to immediately sell its 10.1 per cent holding, as did RGC Ltd, which held eight per cent. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Trading in Highlands Gold Ltd shares yesterday reflected the company's assertion that the Placer Dome Inc A$423 million bid for Highlands undervalues its undeveloped base-metals deposits in Papua New Guinea. At 75 cents a share, Highlands believes the Freda/Nena copper gold and Ramu nickel cobalt deposits are undervalued. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank is under increasing pressure from leading economists to cut interest rates as they claim the surging Australian dollar - which yesterday broke through US82 cents for the first time in six years - will have a crippling effect on already suffering exporters and is further evidence of a flat economy. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Ansett Australia, general manger sales and marketing, Rick Ellis unveiled plans yesterday for the airline to drop its three-class cabin system for domestic flights in March, replacing the first and business class with a single premium class which Ansett hpes will generate higher revenue yields. Qantas is yet to decide whether it will mirror the move on domestic services. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Standard Chartered Bank Australia Ltd managing director Thomas Dunton told a commodity markets conference in Sydney yesterday Australia is running a poor third to Hong Kong and Singapore as an Asia Pacific financial centre and must improve its competitiveess if it is to seriously compete with its regional rivals. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The A$66.5 million lawsuit brought by Foster's Brewing Group Ltd against the company's former chairman John Elliott and his former Elders IXL colleagues Peter Scanlon, Ken Biggins and Ken Jarrett, edged closer to settlement yesterday, with Victorian Supree Court Justice Allan McDonald adjourning the case until December 20 to enable the parties to continue negotiations. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Representing an annualised return on shareholders' funds of almost 21 per cent, Macquarie Bank Ltd  MBL.AX, which listed on the Australian Stock Exchange in July, yesterday lifted net profit 20 per cent to a record A$46 million in the half year to September 30 an predicted a strong start to the second half. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Canadian miner Aber Resources Ltd, RTZ-CRA's partner in the Diavik diamond project, has upgraded the value of the discovery by five per cent. Diavik is located just south of BHP's diamond bonanza, the Diamet mine at Lac de Gras in Canada's frozen Northwest Territories Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>As the High Court made a ruling on the Adelaide Steamship case, news emerged that an end to Foster's long-running civil action against former Elders IXL directors John Elliott, Peter Scanlon, Ken Biggins and Ken Jarrett to recover some A$66.5 million lost in allegedly sham foreign exchange deals in the late 1980s appears imminent. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Australian dollar shot past US82 cents yesterday for the first time since the week of October 8, 1990, when it touched US83.80 cents, ending at US81.94 cents as foreign investors pursued better interest rates. However, the boost is not a good sign for exporters, for whom a strong dollar represents a threat to profits and the broad economy. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>National Mutual Funds Management chief economist Michael Bargholz said yesterday, based on his analysis of the &quot;deep causes&quot; of inflation (the exchange rate and economic growth), Australia's inflation rate is on course to fall below one per cent in the net year and is not likely to be threatened by a wages outbreak. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Thanks to favourable market conditions - in terms of both high volumes and price gains - Macquarie Bank  MBL.AX has come up with the goods in its first profit since listing this year, posting a 21 per cent increase to a record A$46 million in the six months to December, with the bank's equities division lifting its overall contribution from nine per cent to 17 per cent. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The surprisingly strong results of the Bureau of Statistics survey of private sector stocks and manufacturers sales in the September quarter have prompted forecasts of a stronger growth outcome and a sharp upwards revision in estimates of growth in GDP fo the September quarter, while a survey of manufacturers shows they are more optimistic of recording solid sales growth this year. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Any plan National Australia Bank has to scuttle St George Bank's takeover of Advance Bank will depend on NAB's ability to disrupt Advance's second meeting in January to pass the merger, as the takeover will not proceed unless Advance can get shareholder aproval for it on December 23 and change the articles on January 13. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>A Supreme Court judge suggested yesterday that Foster's Brewing Group was close to reaching &quot;a satisfactory outcome&quot; to its civil action brought against former Elders IXL directors John Elliott, Peter Scanlon, Ken Biggins and Ken Jarrett over allegedly shm foreign exchange deals. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Qin Xiao, the president of China International Trust and Investment Corporation, or CITIC, is one of the keynote speakers at the National Trade and Investment Outlook Conference, opened by Deputy Prime Minister Tim Fischer last night. While Qin sees great potential for trade between Australian and China to expand, he rejects arguments for further processing of resources here, saying labor and transport costs are too high and Australia is essentially a source of raw materials. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>At the first meeting of world trade ministers since the Uruguay Round ended in April 1994, trade ministers from 120 nations, including Australia, will meet next week in Singapore to set in motion new global work programs aimed at reducing Asian barriers to trade in manufactured goods. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After posting a maiden net profit of A$8.2 million in 1995-96, compared with a A$4.2 million loss in the previous year, coal miner CIM Resources Ltd yesterday forecast profits and sales would double in the current financial year, despite tough trading conitions under a strengthening dollar. Page C2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although the share prices of Gawler Craton explorers saw a general decline yesterday following spectacular rises last week, Perth miner General Gold Resources NL  GGC.AX announced it would explore the South Australian gold rush region under a farm-in deal with RM Services Pty Ltd. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>According to the business stress index, prepared by chartered accountants Ernst &amp; Young, there were 228 forced business sales in the 12 months to September - the highest figure since 247 in 1994 and 70 per cent higher than at the same time last year. The hardest hit sectors were agriculture, forestry and fishing, property and business services and wholesale trade. Page C3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
