<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228445" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco inaugurates $1.4 bln gas pipeline section.</title>
<headline>Morocco inaugurates $1.4 bln gas pipeline section.</headline>
<byline>Jamal Amiar</byline>
<dateline>TANGIER, Morocco 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Morocco on Monday inaugurated a $1.4 billion section of an Algeria-Europe pipeline and said it would tender next year for a 300 megawatt electricity station to be powered by gas from the pipeline.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a historical event which brought together our colleagues and neighbours, ministers of Algeria, Spain and Portugal, to inaugurate this station,&quot; said Moroccan Energy Minister Abdellatif Guerraoui.</p>
<p>Officials and reporters from the four countries attended the symbolic inauguration of a gas pumping station located on the Atlantic coast 10 km (six miles) south of the northern city of Tangier.</p>
<p>Last month, Algeria inaugurated the first section of the Maghreb-Europe gas pipeline built at an estimated total cost of $2.4 billion over 30 months, officials said. The pipeline has an annual capacity of 9.5 billion cubic metres of natural gas, coming from Algeria's Hassi R'mel field to Spain, via northern Morocco.</p>
<p>The pipeline, first envisaged in an agreement signed in 1991, runs from the Algerian gas field over a distance of 1,385 km (865 miles), across Morocco, under the Strait of Gibraltar, to the Spanish city of Cordoba, and is to link up with a gas distribution network for Portugal.</p>
<p>Algeria hopes to double its present annual gas exports to 60 billion cubic metres by the year 2,000, when one Algerian official said its oil and gas exports should earn $16 billion.</p>
<p>Morocco later will use gas from Hassi R'mel, including for electricity generation, when it has created the necessary infrastructure. Until then it will take royalties as a share of the income generated, a Moroccan official said.</p>
<p>&quot;Morocco plans in 1997 to launch an international tender for building a 300 megawatt power station generated by gas near Tangier pumping station,&quot; Guerraoui told a joint news conference held by the four energy ministers.</p>
<p>He said the project would be operational by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Spanish Energy Minister Jose Pique with his Algerian counterpart underlined &quot;the political role of the pipeline as a whole.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Despite difficulties, the Maghreb-Europe gas pipeline has been achieved...It shows the will of all parties (including Rabat and Algiers) to strengthen economic cooperation,&quot; Pique said.</p>
<p>In September 1994, the border between Morocco and Algeria was closed after attacks blamed on &quot;terrorists&quot; in the southern Moroccan city of Marrakesh, where two Spanish tourists were killed.</p>
<p>Morocco blamed the attack on a group of Algerian nationals who were arrested and jailed for life in Morocco.</p>
<p>&quot;To be noted, the stability of Morocco and Algeria is very important for stability of Spain and Europe,&quot; Pique added.</p>
<p>A third inauguration ceremony is expected to take place in the Spanish city of Cordoba next week.</p>
<p>The pipeline section in Portugal is expected to be operational in January 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020043">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TANGIER, Morocco"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
