<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228465" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Healthsouth to buy Health Images for $270 million.</title>
<headline>Healthsouth to buy Health Images for $270 million.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthsouth Corp., the nation's largest provider of outpatient surgery and rehabilitative care, said Monday it agreed to buy Health Images Inc., a diagnostic X-ray and radiology services company, for about $270 million in stock.</p>
<p>The merger is the latest among health care providers seeking to build their own low-cost networks for managed care organisations, insurers and big corporations.</p>
<p>Birmingham, Ala.-based Healthsouth has been growing rapidly by acquisition. It also said that it completed its $70 million purchase of Readicare Inc., a chain of 37 occupational health centres, which was announced on Sept. 11.</p>
<p>Under the deal announced Monday, Healthsouth will acquire Health Image's 55 radiology centres, including six in Britain, to add to its chain of 1,000 centres across the country that provide physical therapy, rehabilitation and outpatient surgery to about 55,000 patients a day.</p>
<p>&quot;Many of of our patients are hurt on the job or need orthopedic treatment, so they need MRIs as well as traditional X-rays and other tests,&quot; Healthsouth Chairman Richard Scrushy said by telephone.</p>
<p>He noted the companies fit well together geographically and that since Healthsouth currently has only 16 diagnostic X-ray and imaging centres, it would not close any facilities after the merger was completed.</p>
<p>He said the company planned to open at least 15 new imaging centres in the United States next year, and that Health Images' outlets in Britain presented an opportunity for overseas expansion.</p>
<p>He said the stock-swap merger would add to Healthsouth's earnings right away.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Health Images stockholders will receive 0.446 of a share of Healthsouth common stock for each Health Images share.</p>
<p>&quot;In an increasingly competitive health care market, the ability to offer multiple services to managed care payers and networks represents increased opportunity,&quot; Robert Carl III, chairman of Atlanta-based Health Images, said in a statement.</p>
<p>He said the merger will allow Health Images' stockholders to &quot;participate in the growth&quot; of Healthsouth.</p>
<p>The agreement does not provide for termination based on fluctuations in Healthsouth's stock price. It does call for payment of a $10 million break-up fee if Health Images ends the deal and is acquired by another company within a year.</p>
<p>The transaction has been approved by the boards of both companies. It is subject to approval by regulators and stockholders of Health Images and is expected to be completed in early 1997, the companies said.</p>
<p>Health Images stock rose 37.5 cents to $16, and Healthsouth stock fell 75 cents to $36.875 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
