<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228442" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>Iran: Iran accuses Germany of blackmail over Berlin trial.</title>
<headline>Iran accuses Germany of blackmail over Berlin trial.</headline>
<byline>Sharif Imam-Jomeh</byline>
<dateline>TEHRAN 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iran's intelligence minister accused Germany of trying to blackmail Tehran into helping find a missing Israeli airman in exchange for resolving a Berlin murder trial that has strained Tehran-Bonn ties.</p>
<p>&quot;The Germans had given in to Israeli and American pressure and told us somehow to free (Ron) Arad so that we would resolve this trial,&quot; Intelligence Minister Ali Fallahiyan said in remarks published in the Kayhan newspaper on Monday.</p>
<p>Iran has said it has no information on Israeli airman Ron Arad, shot down over south Lebanon in 1986.</p>
<p>&quot;They wanted to blackmail us. We did not give in to Israeli, American and German pressure and therefore they insulted the Islamic republic's top officials,&quot; Fallahiyan added.</p>
<p>Four Lebanese men and an Iranian are on trial in Berlin for the killing of three Iranian Kurdish dissident leaders and their translator in the city's Mykonos restaurant in 1992.</p>
<p>A prosecutor at the trial last month accused Iran's leadership, including spiritual leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei and President Akbar Hashemi Rafsanjani, of ordering the killings.</p>
<p>Tehran has denied involvement in the killings. The accusations against the Iranian leadership triggered demonstrations at the German embassy in Tehran.</p>
<p>Rafsanjani and other Iranian government officials have been trying to ease tensions with Germany, the Islamic republic's main trade partner.</p>
<p>The head of Iran's judiciary, Ayatollah Mohammad Yazdi, was quoted by Iran's official news agency IRNA on Monday as saying the German prosecutor had &quot;ignored most evident legal principles&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Ayatollah Yazdi said that based on investigations and legal surveys made by legal experts, there were some mistakes made by the German prosecutor that showed he was under the influence of others,&quot; IRNA said.</p>
<p>Fallahiyan, who is a Moslem cleric, reiterated Tehran's position that the Berlin killings were the result of infighting among Kurdish groups.</p>
<p>&quot;So attributing it to us is ridiculous,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>German prosecutors in March issued a warrant for the arrest of Fallahiyan in connection with the killings.</p>
<p>The accusations against the Iranian leadership touched off a wave of attacks against Germany in Iranian media.</p>
<p>Ettelaat newspaper on Monday quoted the head of a support group for Iranian victims of poison gas attacks in the 1980-88 Iran-Iraq as accusing German firms of helping Baghdad build up its arsenal of chemical weapons during the conflict.</p>
<p>&quot;Eighty-four German government-affiliated companies helped mobilise Iraq's chemical arsenal,&quot; it quoted Abdullah Mazandarani as saying.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEHRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
