<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228452" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Moroccan bourse ends two-hour session lower.</title>
<headline>Moroccan bourse ends two-hour session lower.</headline>
<dateline>CASABLANCA 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Casablanca bourse on Monday closed its two-hour session 0.22 percent lower compared with the previous session, traders said.</p>
<p>The all-share index closed at 432.28 points from 433.24 points over the previous session.</p>
<p>&quot;The drop in largest capitalisation firms, including Societe Nationale d'Investissement (SNI), was mainly behind the bourse index decline,&quot; a Casablanca-based stockbroker said.</p>
<p>SNI, which has diversified stakes in more than 40 companies, lost 10 dirhams in one session to close at 540 dirhams.</p>
<p>SNI is Morocco's second largest private conglomerate with a market capitalisation of more than 5.5 billion dirhams.</p>
<p>ONA Group, the country's largest private group, was traded on Monday below the 500-dirham line for the first time since October, a broker said. It lost three dirhams to close at 475 dirhams.</p>
<p>Banque Marocaine du Commerce Exterieur, one of the liquid stocks, lost one dirham, to close at 395 dirhams.</p>
<p>Traded volume on the official market was 15.5 million dirhams, down from 22.5 million dirhams last Friday.</p>
<p>($1= 8.6 dirhams)</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom +212-7 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CASABLANCA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
