<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228460" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey and U.S. in talks on Iraq air patrols.</title>
<headline>Turkey and U.S. in talks on Iraq air patrols.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey and NATO ally the United States are discussing the mandate of allied air patrols over northern Iraq that runs out at the end of the year, a Turkish official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We all know that the circumstances have changed in northern Iraq, so our studies are continuing to determine the future of that joint operation,&quot; foreign ministry spokesman Sermet Atacanli said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have also been in contact with the American side to look into these issues,&quot; he told a news briefing.</p>
<p>U.S., British and French planes, in a overflights known as Operation Provide Comfort, has been patrolling the skies of northern Iraq to protect the Kurds from any attack by Baghdad since the end of the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>But its usefulness was brought into question when one Iraqi Kurdish militia joined Iraqi government forces in August in fighting with a rival Kurdish group.</p>
<p>The allies have since evacuated Provide Comfort ground personnel from Iraq in fear of Baghdad's increased influence in the region.</p>
<p>The Turkish parliament is to vote by December 31 on whether to allow the planes to continue flying from a base in southern Turkey.</p>
<p>Islamist Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan has gone back on promises to throw the planes out of Turkey but Western diplomats say Turkey wants a greater say in the running of the force.</p>
<p>Successive governments have heeded advice from Turkey's powerful National Security Council to extend the force's mandate. The council discussed Provide Comfort last week but delayed making any recommendation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
