<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228601" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYC and new authority could sell up to $40 bln.</title>
<headline>NYC and new authority could sell up to $40 bln.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York City could sell an additional $9 billion of debt if a new city bonding authority is created, boosting its total issuance to $40 billion, city Comptroller Alan Hevesi said Monday.</p>
<p>Hevesi, speaking at a Bond Buyer Conference on New York Public Finance here, said the new authority would help solve the city's capital needs over the next several needs.</p>
<p>The new authority would allow the city to sell more debt for education and transportation projects without hitting the state constitutional debt limit on city bonds.  </p>
<p>The comptroller added that, although the city is nearing its limit, he saw no immediate problems for the city under current debt ceiling.</p>
<p>While an expected reduction in the property tax base could reduce the debt ceiling below $31 billion in the next couple of months, the city could still sell debt because it has the flexibility of diverting $1 billion in potential contracts to bond sales, Hevesi said.</p>
<p>&quot;That can buy us a couple of months,&quot; Hevesi said.</p>
<p>Mayor Rudolph Giuliani said earlier on Monday at the conference that he expects the authority to be approved by the state legislature because it has general support from the governor and leaders of the state Senate and Assembly.</p>
<p>Giuliani said he hoped lawmakers would take up the authority legislation in a special session in December.</p>
<p>--Joan Gralla, 212-859-1654</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
