<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228658" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME to trade Taiwan Stock Index contracts on Jan 8.</title>
<headline>CME to trade Taiwan Stock Index contracts on Jan 8.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chicago Mercantile Exchange received U.S. regulatory approval to trade Dow Jones Taiwan Stock Index futures and options, and will list the contracts on Wednesday, January 8, the exchange said.</p>
<p>A CME spokeswoman said the CME's decision to list the contract in January 1997, instead of November 1996 as originally proposed, was based on CME logistics and was not a concession to the Taiwan Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>Taiwanese regulators had expressed concern that the CME's contracts could increase volatility in Taiwan's stock market.  </p>
<p>The exchange offered to delay the start of the products to January 15 if the Taiwan Stock Exchange would sign an information-sharing agreement.</p>
<p>&quot;We did not get it (agreement),&quot; she said. &quot;We are proceeding with the January 8 launch because we believe that is the best day for us.&quot;</p>
<p>The CME contracts are based on an index of 117 of the largest and most liquid stocks on the Taiwan Stock Exchange. They will trade exclusively on the GLOBEX after-hours electronic trading system.  </p>
<p>&quot;We've talked in the past about using the after-hours system as an incubator of sorts for new products,&quot; a CME spokeswoman said. The contracts may eventually trade in open outcry if there is enough interest on GLOBEX, she said.</p>
<p>The contracts will begin trading at 1900 CST January 8 (0100 GMT January 9), but will be regularly offered during GLOBEX hours of 1430 CST to 1030 CST (2030/1630 GMT) on Monday through Thursday.</p>
<p>On Sunday evening, GLOBEX hours are 1730 CST to 1030 CST Monday (2330 GMT to 1630 GMT).</p>
<p>Dow Jones Taiwan Stock index futures will also trade on GLOBEX on Friday evenings to correspond with the Saturday morning sessions on the Taiwan Stock Exchange. The contracts will trade from 1830 to 2100 CST on Fridays (0030 to 0300 GMT Saturday).</p>
<p>The CME, Reuters Holdings Plc and the Marche a Terme International de France (MATIF) are partners in GLOBEX. ((Derivatives desk 312-408-8750;E-mail derivatives@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83954">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
