<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228796" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italian opposition leader predicts government downfall.</title>
<headline>Italian opposition leader predicts government downfall.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian opposition leader Silvio Berlusconi said on Monday he believed the government of Prime Minister Romano Prodi would fall next spring.</p>
<p>Speaking at a convention of his Forza Italia party, Berlusconi said he thought Prodi's centre-left coalition would crumble when it became clear the 1997 budget would not allow Italy to meet tough criteria for European monetary union.</p>
<p>Berlusconi said he believed Prodi would be forced next spring to add a mini-budget for 1997 to cut public debt even more, angering coalition partners and the Communist Refoundation on whose support he depends in the Chamber of Deputies.</p>
<p>&quot;The government would not be able to survive these hypotheses,&quot; said Berlusconi, who served as prime minister for eight months in 1994 and who leads the centre-right Freedom Alliance opposition of which his Forza Italia party is a member.</p>
<p>In the event the government fell, Berlusconi said he would offer to lead a broad coalition government to oversee constitutional and institutional reform in Italy for a set period of time.</p>
<p>Prodi's 1997 budget aims to slash 62.5 trillion lire ($41.2 billion) off next year's deficit. A key element of the package is an unpopular &quot;Euro-tax&quot; to raise some 12.5 trillion lire to help Italy be a founder member of a European single currency.</p>
<p>The package has been approved by the lower Chamber of Deputies and is now working its way through the Senate, where amendments will mean it must return to the lower house for a further reading.</p>
<p>Labour Minister Tiziano Treu, speaking to reporters before Berlusconi's comments, said Prodi's coalition was stable despite some dissension from Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini and his small centrist Italian Renewal party over the &quot;Euro-tax&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;What's important is that the coalition finds a common result,&quot; Treu said in Venice. &quot;I believe that is the spirit in which Dini is working.&quot; ($1=1516 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
