<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228777" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France asks Zaire lift envoy's immunity over crash.</title>
<headline>France asks Zaire lift envoy's immunity over crash.</headline>
<byline>Alister Doyle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>France asked Zaire on Monday to lift the diplomatic immunity of Zaire's ambassador to Paris after his car killed two French schoolboys on a pedestrian crossing in an accident last month.</p>
<p>&quot;The French government has asked the Zairean government to lift the diplomatic immunity of the Zairean ambassador,&quot; Foreign Minister Herve de Charette said of envoy Ramazani Baya.</p>
<p>&quot;It's shocking that diplomatic immunity might mean that the person who caused this accident...might escape responsibility,&quot; he said, adding he was not making a judgment about the crash.</p>
<p>He said Paris would review workings of the Vienna Convention that protects diplomats from prosecution, saying it was not intended to shield foreign envoys in such cases.</p>
<p>Zaire said it was recalling Baya at Paris's request on Sunday after the accident in the Riviera resort of Menton on November 23. Police say the ambassador was driving at 100 km an hour (62 mph) in a 45 kph (30 mph) zone.</p>
<p>The families of the two schoolboys want Baya, who wrote a letter to them to express remorse, put on trial over the killings. The newspaper France-Soir dubbed him the &quot;crusher-ambassador&quot;.</p>
<p>An official at the Zairean embassy in Paris said on Monday that Baya had not yet left France. &quot;He's going to leave. He's still in France,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>One of the boys, Raphael Lenoir, 13, died instantly. The other, 12-year-old Ronald Lehartel, died on Saturday. He had been in a coma in hospital since the accident.</p>
<p>Baya was driving through Menton on his way to visit Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, convalescing at a luxury mansion in nearby Roquebrune Cap Martin. Mobutu underwent cancer surgery in Switzerland in August.</p>
<p>In a letter to the mayor of Menton, de Charette pledged to work for the families. &quot;They can count on me,&quot; he wrote. De Charette also sent letters to the two families.</p>
<p>On Saturday, 4,000 people -- about a sixth of the town's population -- marched through Menton in a silent but angry tribute hours before Lehartel's death. Mourners carried white carnations and laid a wreath at the seafront pedestrian crossing where the accident took place.</p>
<p>Asking a country to recall a diplomat is a frequent sanction for envoys suspected of crimes. Lifting immunity to enable legal action is extremely rare.</p>
<p>France in 1978, for instance, sent home Iraqi diplomats without prosecution after they were accused of shooting dead a French policeman. Britain cut off relations with Libya after the killing of a policewoman in 1984 by shots apparently from the Libyan embassy.</p>
<p>Patrick Lenoir, the father of Raphael, has rejected an offer of talks with de Charette. &quot;This is an attempt to find a compromise,&quot; he told the newspaper Le Monde. &quot;Accepting this type of compromise would be to kill my son a second time.&quot;</p>
<p>The accident has embarrassed France by putting the focus on the presence of Mobutu, a pariah banned from much of Europe and the United States, in a palatial Riviera mansion during a crisis over hundreds of thousands of refugees in eastern Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
