<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228865" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: OAU chief urges African nominees for top U.N. post.</title>
<headline>OAU chief urges African nominees for top U.N. post.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Organisation of African Unity chairman has urged African leaders to propose candidates for the post of U.N. secretary-general to ensure Boutros Boutros-Ghali is succeeded by another African if he remains blocked from a second term.</p>
<p>Cameroonian President Paul Biya's letter to African heads of state appeared to break a deadlock that followed the U.S. veto of Boutros-Ghali on Nov. 19, when Africans remained reluctant to submit alternative candidates while the Egyptian diplomat's name was still in play.  </p>
<p>In the letter, obtained by Reuters, Biya said it seemed time, in order to preserve Africa's chances for a second term as U.N. secretary-general, for African states to present the names of other qualified candidates jointly with that of Boutros-Ghali.</p>
<p>Urging swift action, he said countries could inform the president of the U.N. Security Council directly of their nominations, while also keeping him informed.</p>
<p>A number of African diplomats have been mentioned as possible candidates for the post of secretary-general when Boutros-Ghali's current five-year term expires on Dec. 31.</p>
<p>But none has been officially submitted since Boutros-Ghali's candidacy has not been withdrawn, although the United States has vowed to keep blocking him on the grounds that the United Nations needs new leadership to carry out reforms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CAMER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OAU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
