<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228805" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Olivetti sees plan ready in December.</title>
<headline>Olivetti sees plan ready in December.</headline>
<dateline>MANTUA, Italy 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Troubled information technology group Olivetti will have its recovery plan ready sometime in December, Olivetti managing director Roberto Colaninno said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;For a company like Olivetti, you don't build an industrial plan in a week or even in two months,&quot; Colaninno, who only took over his post in September, said at a meeting in Mantua.</p>
<p>Olivetti said in early October it wanted to sell off a string of businesses, including its loss-making personal computer division, and focus on computer systems and telecoms to nurse itself back to health.</p>
<p>But Italian Industry Minister Pierluigi Bersani noted recently in a parliamentary committee that no industrial plan was as yet forthcoming from the loss-making group.</p>
<p>Colaninno, addressing the parliamentary committee last week, also warned that plans to sell off the personal computer unit by the end of the year may be delayed.</p>
<p>Speaking in Mantua, the chief executive said: &quot;To create (a recovery plan), it is necessary to understand the reality, prospects for a market and above all there's the need to put certain restructuring work into action...we are working on the plan and I believe we'll have it within the month of December.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the plan would be &quot;substantial&quot; in parts and would also &quot;as expected bring back balance to the company's accounts without affecting the work force.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;A plan with these characteristics is not an exercise that you can do in a week,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He stressed that getting Olivetti back on its feet was top priority among his and shareholders' concerns and he added when the plan was presented &quot;I will be very glad to discuss it, when it can be made public, with Minister Bersani and everyone else.&quot;</p>
<p>Olivetti, which has not turned a profit since 1990, has made some progress in addressing its problems. It sold part of its stake in mobile telephone consortium Omnitel in October for 432.5 billion lire ($285 million).</p>
<p>But Colaninno said last week plans to sell off the PC division by the end of the year had been delayed and the intended sale of profitable specialty computer unit Tecnost could be reviewed. $1=1520 lire</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3302003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANTUA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
