<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228880" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian shares end down, auto stocks take a beating.</title>
<headline>Indian shares end down, auto stocks take a beating.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares suffered fresh losses across major Indian stock exchanges on Monday, a day lacking any major action, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said new rules on short-sales announced by market regulator the Securities &amp; Exchange Board of India(SEBI) limited trading volumes and kept major players to the sidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a pretty bad day. Overall, sentiment continues to be bearish,&quot; said Dheeraj Agarwal, trader at SS Kantilal Ishwarlal Securities, a Bombay-based brokerage.</p>
<p>The key Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) 30-share index lost 39.07 points or 1.35 percent to close at 2,851.43, off 2,906.15.  </p>
<p>Issued by SEBI last Thursday, the rules to be effective this week require all exchanges to ask member-brokers to submit their scrip-wise net short sales positions at the end of the day.</p>
<p>&quot;Volumes will come down because of the new restrictions,&quot; trader Ramnik Parikh said.</p>
<p>Market players said the latest move by the regulator will not do much to revive the sagging bourses, with volumes cited as the first casualty of the short-selling rules.</p>
<p>&quot;It'll lead to lower volumes...Whenever the government has made any restrictions, the market has gone down,&quot; said dealer Zubin Tampal at brokers Motilal Oswal said.  </p>
<p>Traders said foreign funds and speculators were sellers in auto stocks on fears of a prolonged economic slowdown.</p>
<p>Bajaj Auto lost 51.10 rupees to 793.0 rupees, M&amp;M 13.70 to 275.50, TELCO 22.0 to 294.50, SBI 1.75 to 216.50, TISCO 0.50 to 152.75, ITC 4.50 to 275.25, ACC 36.20 to 966.50 and Reliance 0.25 to 180.50.</p>
<p>&quot;The bearish phase gathered momentum as purchases by domestic institutions failed to arrest the declining trend,&quot; said Sumit Gandhi of Delhi brokers Rare Financial Services.</p>
<p>-- ANSHUMAN DAGA, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
