<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228807" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Council agrees burden of proof rules.</title>
<headline>Council agrees burden of proof rules.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Social Affairs Council agreed in principle on Monday on a draft directive on the burden of proof in sex discrimination cases, EU officials said.</p>
<p>It cannot formally adopt the draft directive, COM(96)93, until the European Parliament has given its opinion.</p>
<p>The text, adopted under the Social Protocol excluding Britain, aims to make it easier for workers to win sex discrimination cases by asking employers to share the burden of proof when they are sued.</p>
<p>It says that workers must first establish before a court or other competent authority facts &quot;from which it can be presumed that there has been direct or indirect discrimination.&quot;</p>
<p>The employer must then prove that it has not violated the &quot;principle of equal treatment&quot;.</p>
<p>The text sets out a definition of &quot;indirect discrimination&quot;, saying it exists when a practice &quot;disadvantages a substantially higher proportion of the members of one sex&quot; and cannot be justified objectively.</p>
<p>Social Affairs Commissioner Padraig Flynn said he was not sure the European Commission could support the Council's decision to exclude EU directives on social security and the self-employed from a provision outlining which issues were covered by the text.</p>
<p>&quot;As you know, most rulings in indirect discrimination concern social security, and the European Parliament might have specific views on that,&quot; he said according to a speaking note.</p>
<p>He said he could accept new wording, however, that excluded voluntary out-of-court procedures such as conciliation or mediation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
