<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="22889" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: World congress raps media for making children sexy.</title>
<headline>World congress raps media for making children sexy.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global media came under fire at the first world congress on commercial sexual exploitation of children on Thursday for using youngsters' sexuality to sell products.</p>
<p>British actor Roger Moore, a goodwill ambassador for the United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), told the third day of the five day conference that the so-called Lolita syndrome, when the media portrays young girls as sexy, was irresponsible.</p>
<p>&quot;Increasingly we see images of young children whose sexuality is used to sell products in the advertising market and to titillate and to tease,&quot; Moore told a conference panel.</p>
<p>&quot;Even non-child models are increasingly chosen for their childlike bodies. The line between sexually ready and way too young is being lowered.&quot;</p>
<p>Moore told the conference, attended by over 1,000 delegates from 130 countries, that when the film &quot;Lolita&quot; first appeared in 1962, depicting a 12-year-old girl seducing an elderly lodger in her family home, it was scandalous.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we see Lolitas everywhere, not only in films but also on advertising boards, in glossy magazines, and in music videos on TV ... but to hardly a murmur,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But with the conference held in the shadow of a horrifying child sex-abuse scandal unfolding in Belgium, Moore said he was glad to see that a remake of &quot;Lolita,&quot; based on Vladimir Nabokov's novel, was yet to find a distributor.</p>
<p>Some U.S. and British critics have savaged Adrian Lyne, director of steamy &quot;9 1/2 Weeks&quot; and &quot;Fatal Attraction&quot;, after reports of sex scenes between actor Jeremy Irons and an adult stand-in for co-star Dominique Swain, 14.</p>
<p>Britain's Daily Mail said: &quot;Let us be sure that the new, authentic, honest, fearless and explicit film version of this dreary and poisonous tract in our misbegotten times gets its just reward -- critical obloquy.&quot;</p>
<p>The Belgian case has triggered a Europe-wide search to detail a paedophile ring in which young girls were abducted, sexually abused and filmed. Some were even left to die.</p>
<p>The conference was told the media has to look at its role in combating a multi-billion dollar child sex industry.</p>
<p>UNICEF estimates one million children a year are forced into either child prostitution, sold for sexual purposes or used in child pornography.</p>
<p>Aidan White, secretary general of the International Federation of Journalists (IFJ), said the media needed to review the way it portrayed children.</p>
<p>&quot;(Children) should not be portrayed as hopeless, helpless, vulnerable, faceless individuals,&quot; he told the media panel.</p>
<p>He said the Stockholm conference should produce &quot;concrete ideas for helping journalists to raise this issue, to report on this issue, and to make it part and parcel of the democratic discussion for which we're responsible&quot;.</p>
<p>The conference has heard repeated calls for unified action globally to tackle the sexual exploitation of children, discussing ways different industries can take action.</p>
<p>Ray Wyre from Britain's Lucy Faithful Foundation said a global approach was vital as was more monitoring of people dealing with children on a day-to-day basis.</p>
<p>&quot;Why is it that three male teachers suspended from a school in England are now teaching in Bangkok?&quot; Wyre asked the conference. &quot;Why was a teacher in the UK who died of AIDS nicknamed Mr Feeler for 15 years and no-one did anything?</p>
<p>&quot;We have got to have a coordinated response and become more global in the way we deal with this problem.&quot;</p>
<p>The conference is organised by the Swedish government, UNICEF, pressure group End Child Prostitution in Asia Tourism and a non-governmental organisation on the rights of the child.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
