<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228989" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AOL to upgrade network to meet demand surge.</title>
<headline>AOL to upgrade network to meet demand surge.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>America Online Inc. said Monday it was starting a major expansion of its online network and planned to spend $250 million through the end of its fiscal year in June to build capacity and improve service.</p>
<p>The nation's largest online service provider said it was upgrading its network to meet the surge in demand generated by its new pricing and recent marketing initiatives. As of Sunday, AOL began offering a new flat-rate pricing plan to its 7 million subscribers.</p>
<p>AOL said it will double its system hardware over the next six months, which would grow large enough to cover nearly two football fields.</p>
<p>Since September, AOL has doubled its electronic mail capacity and its capability to connect users to the Internet's popular World Wide Web.</p>
<p>An America Online spokesman said that despite heavy usage over the Thanksgiving holiday weekend, there were no serious problems with its online network.</p>
<p>The Dulles, Va.-based company said that since July 1, it has added tens of thousands of new modems to AOLnet, which it said was the world's largest dial-in network. The expansion is to accelerate through the spring with tens of thousands of new modems being installed monthly, it added.</p>
<p>Last month, AOL said it had received inquiries from attorneys general in 15 states expressing concern with how it was implementing and disclosing the new pricing plans to members. A spokesman said at the time that its plan and the implementation was &quot;fair in every sense.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
