<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228900" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: PRESS DIGEST - Sri Lanka Newspapers - December 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sri Lanka Newspapers - December 2.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sri Lankan press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>VEERAKESARI</p>
<p>Left-wing Sri Lanka Progressive Front expells member of parliament Nihal Galappaththi.</p>
<p>Army launches operation to capture deserters after amnesty for their return expires.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THINAKARAN</p>
<p>Students in LTTE-held Wanni region demonstrate against human rights abuses by security forces.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>DAILY NEWS</p>
<p>Sri Lanka calls for global action on sexual exploitation of children during meeting of United Nations committee on social and humanitarian affairs.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE ISLAND</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Lakshman Kadirgamar to discuss fight against LTTE during talks with his Indian counterpart Inder Kumar Gujral in New Delhi later this month.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>LANKADEEPA</p>
<p>Security forces arrest six Tamil Tiger rebels planning to bomb General Hospital in Colombo. Among those detained were four female Tiger suicide bombers who were to enter hospital disguised as nurses.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>DIVAINA</p>
<p>More than 13,000 army deserters return during amnesty offer.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>DINAMINA</p>
<p>Army captures 90 Tamil Tiger rebel infiltrators during search operations in northern Jaffna peninsula.</p>
<p>-- Colombo newsroom 941-434319 REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
