<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="228994" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Healthsouth to buy Health Images for $270 million.</title>
<headline>Healthsouth to buy Health Images for $270 million.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA</dateline>
<text>
<p>Healthsouth Corp., the nation's largest provider of outpatient surgery and rehabilitative care, said Monday it agreed to buy Health Images Inc., a diagnostic X-ray and radiology services company, for about $270 million in stock.</p>
<p>The merger is the latest among health care providers seeking to build their own low-cost networks for managed care organisations, insurers and big corporations.</p>
<p>Birmingham, Ala.-based Healthsouth operates 1,000 centres across the country providing physical therapy, rehabilitation and outpatient surgery. It will acquire Atlanta-based Health Image's 55 radiology centres, including six in Britain.</p>
<p>&quot;Health Images represents a natural fit with Healthsouth, since 96 percent of the Health Images facilities overlap with our rehabilitation and surgery locations,&quot; Healthsouth Chairman Richard Scrushy said in a statement.</p>
<p>Almost all Healthsouth patients require some form of diagnostics, Scrushy noted, adding that the stock-swap merger would add to Healthsouth's earnings right away.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, Health Images stockholders will receive 0.446 of a share of Healthsouth common stock for each Health Images share.</p>
<p>Health Images Chairman Robert Carl III said, &quot;In an increasingly competitive health care market, the ability to offer multiple services to managed care payers and networks represents increased opportunity.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the merger will allow Health Images' stockholders to &quot;participate in the growth&quot; of Healthsouth.</p>
<p>The agreement does not provide for termination based on fluctuations in Healthsouth's stock price. It does call for payment of a $10 million break-up fee if Health Images ends the deal and is acquired by another company within a year.</p>
<p>The transaction has been approved by the boards of both companies. It is subject to approval by regulators and stockholders of Health Images, but does not require a vote of Healthsouth's stockholders, the companies said.</p>
<p>Health Images stock rose 25 cents to $15.875, and Healthsouth's stock fell 75 cents to $36.875 at midday on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
