<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229083" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Emerson to take controlling stake in Sport.</title>
<headline>Emerson to take controlling stake in Sport.</headline>
<dateline>PARSIPPANY, N.J. 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Emerson Radio Corp said it reached an agreement to acquire a controlling stake in Sport Supply Group Inc and will spend $12 million to buy 1.6 million newly issued Sport shares.</p>
<p>Combined with Emerson's original investment in Sport Supply, the total transaction is valued at about $18.2 million, Emerson said.  </p>
<p>Emerson said it is also acquiring five-year warrants to buy one million more shares of Sport Supply common stock at an exercise price of $7.50 per share under the deal. The company said it also will arrange for supplemental foreign trade credit financing for Sport Supply.</p>
<p>Emerson said the purchase is part of its strategy to diversify from its core business of consumer electronics distribution to other types of distribution businesses.</p>
<p>The company said the deal should be completed immediately after the 10-day notice period required by the Securities and Exchange Commission expires.  </p>
<p>As part of the deal, Emerson will make up a majority of Sport Supply's board until a shareholder vote at the next annual meeting, Emerson said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I49420">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARSIPPANY, N.J."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
