<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229121" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GalaGen Sporidin-G results favorable.</title>
<headline>GalaGen Sporidin-G results favorable.</headline>
<dateline>ARDEN HILLS, Minn. 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>GalaGen Inc said Monday use of its Sporidin-G showed favorable clinical results and an acceptable safety profile in the treatment of diarrhea caused by Cryptosporidium parvum in patients with AIDS.</p>
<p>GalaGen said the results are from a Phase I/II study in 24 patients and are published today in the December 1996 issue of The Journal of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome and Human Retrovirology.</p>
<p>Based on these positive results, GalaGen said it is conducting a Phase II/III double-blind placebo-controlled study using an advanced, more potent formulation of Sporidin-G.  </p>
<p>The company said it expects the Phase II/III trial, being conducted at multiple sites throughout the United States, will be fully enrolled in early 1997.</p>
<p>If the trial demonstrated efficacy of the drug, GalaGen said the data might support the filing of a product licensing application with the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, and with regulatory authorities in Europe and Latin America.</p>
<p>In the Phase I/II study, was conducted by researchers at the University of California, San Francisco.</p>
<p>&quot;The current oral formulation of Sporidin-G that is being studied in the ongoing trial has a nearly four-fold greater concentration of antibodies specific for C. parvum than the product used in this initial clinical study,&quot;  Robert Hoerr, president of GalaGen, said.  &quot;Based on the results of this initial study, we have great confidence in the new formulation of our product as a clinically attractive, safe and viable treatment for cryptosporidiosis.&quot;</p>
<p>C. parvum, the parasite responsible for cryptosporidiosis, is an infection in AIDS patients that can cause intractable diarrhea, profound weight loss, malnutrition, dehydration and, in some cases, death, GalaGen said.</p>
<p>Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ARDEN HILLS, Minn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
