<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229293" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Jordan shares buttressed by institutional demand.</title>
<headline>Jordan shares buttressed by institutional demand.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Jordanian stock rose on Monday with prices buttressed by renewed institutional and portfolio buying focused mainly on firms that would gain from revived trade with Iraq, dealers said.</p>
<p>The Amman Financial Market 60-share index rose 0.34 percent to 152.47 points with select demand underpinning healthy turnover of 830,159 dinars ($1.2 million).</p>
<p>Monday's rise lifted share prices close to Saturday's nine month high after a fall on Sunday sparked by doubts over the extent of Jordan's gains from the near implementation of the $2 billion U.N. oil for-food-deal with Iraq.</p>
<p>Investors said the main players, the state pension fund, individual investors and firms associated with Jordan's Islamic Bank, are pinning hopes on select industrials that could perform well in 1997 from Iraqi exports.</p>
<p>&quot;Institutional investors helped activate the market, when you have a number of investors moving in, they activate trade,&quot; said one brokers.</p>
<p>Brokers said the state pension fund stepped up its purchases on Monday, focusing on Jordan Cement Factories and drug firms while most of the outside buying by large investors appeared to favour leading drug firms.</p>
<p>Jordan, a traditional trading partner of Iraq and a transit route for many of its imports, has suffered from the six-year U.N. sanctions on its neighbour. Jordanian industry lost a major export market and business at Aqaba port plummeted.</p>
<p>Gaining shares outnumbered losers on Sunday by 18 to 13, with another nine trading but closing unchanged.</p>
<p>Arab Bank, Jordan Electric Power, Arab Pharmaceutical Manufacturing and Jordan Cement Factory were the busiest stocks closing at 258.50 dinar (1.50 dinar higher), 1.76 dinar (0.06 dinar up), 3.45 dinar (0.09 dinar up) and 3.41 dinar (0.03 dinar higher) respectively.</p>
<p>The private Pearl Index of 45 best-traded shares rose 0.29 percent to 81.84, 14.31 percent down on last year.</p>
<p>-- Amman newsroom, 962 6 623 776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
