<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229282" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shares end mixed in thin trading.</title>
<headline>Israeli shares end mixed in thin trading.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli shares closed mixed to lower on Monday in thin trading, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark Mishtanim index of the top 100 shares lost 0.33 percent, or 0.66 points, to 198.79 on a low all-share turnover of 68 million shekels against 55 million shekels on Sunday.</p>
<p>The Maof 25 blue chip index fell 0.25 percent to 208.84.</p>
<p>&quot;The market continues to show strength,&quot; said Eli Nahum, head of trading at Zannex Securities. &quot;Despite some profit taking, it remained stable closing with only a mild decline.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Today's decline is meaningless and the number of shares that rose and fell was divided fifty-fifty,&quot; said a trader at Bank Leumi.</p>
<p>&quot;Volume was low because investors are waiting for the opening of trading in the Israeli shares traded in New York,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Even the relatively disappointing earning reports published on Sunday had no real impact on trading. Investors realize that the Bank of Israel will have to lower the interest rate soon because inflation is falling,&quot; Nahum said.</p>
<p>Elbit Ltd again declined sharply, falling 6.5 percent to 2,456. Traders said the share was trading with volatility in the wake of the split with its sister companies, which began trading separately on the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange on Thursday.</p>
<p>One of the other two, Elbit Systems, was the second most active share of the day and fell 1.25 percent to 2,357 on turnover of 2.3 million shekels.</p>
<p>The other most active shares were Koor Industries, which fell 1.5 percent to 27,878 on volume of 4.7 million shekels, and Bezeq Israel Telecom, which lost 1.75 percent to 771 on volume 2.1 million shekels.</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
