<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229367" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Kansas City Southern unit buys railway.</title>
<headline>Kansas City Southern unit buys railway.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kansas City Southern Industries Inc said Monday its KCS Transportation Co unit plans to acquire the outstanding stock of Gateway Western Railway Co.</p>
<p>Gateway Western is a class II, or second tier, rail carrier with operations between Kansas City and East St. Louis and Springfield, Ill., as well as haulage rights between Springfield and Chicago.</p>
<p>Kansas City Southern said the purchase price for Gateway Western was not material.  </p>
<p>The stock acquired by KCS Transportation will be held in an independent voting trust pending a decision by the U.S. Surface Transportation Board approving the deal.</p>
<p>Kansas City Southern said the acquisition would expand its rail network from East St. Louis and Springfield to Laredo, Texas, via the Texas Mexican Railway.</p>
<p>Kansas City Southern owns 49 percent of MexRail Inc, the parent of the Texas Mexican Railway. The Texas Mexican Railway recently gained trackage rights between Corpus Christi and Beaumont, Texas, where it connects with Kansas City Southern Railway.</p>
<p>&quot;Gateway Western has established itself as an important rail transportation link between Kansas City and East St. Louis,&quot; Landon Rowland, president of Kansas City Southern, said in a statement. &quot;Its network will be a good complement to its sister company, Kansas City Southern Railway.&quot;</p>
<p>Kansas City Southern said review and possible approval by the Surface Transportation Board is expected to take about four months.</p>
<p>((Reuters Chicago Newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
