<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229433" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Russia, Belarus jar start of European summit.</title>
<headline>Russia, Belarus jar start of European summit.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Nicholas Doughty, Diplomatic Correspondent</p>
<p>Russia attacked NATO's plans for enlargement and Belarus came under fire at the start of a security summit on Monday, sounding a jarring note as some 50 nations met to try and build lasting peace in Europe.</p>
<p>Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin told the assembled leaders that NATO would create new dividing lines in Europe if it goes ahead with plans to take in countries from Eastern Europe as new members.</p>
<p>&quot;We have declared clearly, and declare clearly now, our firm opposition to the North Atlantic alliance's plans to move itself and its military infrastructure towards our territory,&quot; Chernomyrdin told the opening session of the two-day summit.</p>
<p>&quot;Is it not clear that the appearance of new dividing lines would lead to a worsening of the whole geopolitical situation in the world?&quot;</p>
<p>The last OSCE summit two years ago in Budapest was wrecked by a row over the same issue and by differences over Bosnia.</p>
<p>Belarus President Alexander Lukashenko, attending the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) summit, was forced to listen to criticism of his autocratic rule from countries around the table.</p>
<p>Swiss Foreign Minister Flavio Cotti, currently OSCE chairman in office, said he was &quot;deeply concerned&quot; by developments in the former Soviet republic and told Lukashenko he should resolve his problems through political dialogue.</p>
<p>Irish Prime Minister John Bruton, speaking for the 15-nation European Union, said Belarus should return to &quot;respect for democratic principles&quot;.</p>
<p>Despite the jarring notes, countries attending the summit agreed on Monday that a new round of conventional arms talks for Europe would start early next year. The negotiations will adapt and extend a 1990 Cold War-era treaty that reduces military hardware across the continent.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a major achievement which, by itself, will justify this summit,&quot; Portuguese Prime Minister Antonio Guterres told the assembled leaders.</p>
<p>The summit will agree a final document laying out plans for European security in the 21st century and measures to help shore up peace in Bosnia, one year after the war ended there.</p>
<p>The leaders will also hold a series of bilateral meetings on the fringes of the summit -- more than 170 in total. Chernomyrdin was scheduled to meet U.S. Vice President Al Gore, German Chancellor Helmut Kohl and French President Jacques Chirac.</p>
<p>Representatives from Algeria, Egypt, Morocco, Tunisia, Japan and South Korea are attending the summit as observers, as well as Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</p>
<p>Russia has little chance of winning support at the summit for its proposals to give the OSCE a more powerful role in European security and have it act as a counterbalance to NATO.</p>
<p>Officials worked through the night to reach final agreement on the summit documents on issues ranging from ethnic conflicts and human rights to arms control. Diplomats said some issues remained unresolved as the summit opened.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
