<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229533" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France asks Zaire to lift ambassador's immunity.</title>
<headline>France asks Zaire to lift ambassador's immunity.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>France asked Zaire on Monday to lift the diplomatic immunity of Zaire's ambassador to Paris who was driving a car that killed two French youths in an accident last month in southern France.</p>
<p>&quot;We are asking Zaire to lift the immunity of its ambassador (Ramazani Baya) so that he may present himself to French justice as he has himself has suggested,&quot; French Foreign Ministry spokesman Yves Doutriaux told reporters.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's up to the Zairean authorities to make a decision about lifting his immunity,&quot; Doutriaux said.</p>
<p>Zaire recalled Baya at Paris's request on Sunday after the car he was driving hit the two youths on a pedestrian crossing in the Riviera resort of Menton last Wednesday. Police say he was speeding.</p>
<p>One of the boys, Raphael Lenoir, 13, died instantly. The other, 12-year-old Ronald Lehartel, died on Saturday. He had been in a coma in hospital since the accident.</p>
<p>Baya had travelled to Menton to visit Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, convalescing in nearby Roquebrune Cap Martin from cancer surgery in August. The accident has embarrassed France by putting the focus on Mobutu's presence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
