<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229522" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Commission says beef markets returning to normal.</title>
<headline>Commission says beef markets returning to normal.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Beef markets in the European Union are getting back to normal and intervention weight levels are to be reduced, European Commission offcials said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are warning that weight levels will be coming down because the market is about where it was foreseen to be at the time of the 1992 reform of the Common Agriculture Policy,&quot; a senior official told Reuters.</p>
<p>Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler had expected beef intervention to reach 600,000 tonnes this year but it now looks as though intervention purchases to support the market will not exceed 500,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Buying in of beef as an emergency measure because of the mad cow crisis has seen a steady rise in weight limits of animals bought in. From 340 kilograms the limit rose progressively to 420 and at one point the Commission ceased to operate a weight limit at all.</p>
<p>&quot;The limit will now be reduced progressively since markets are getting back to normal levels,&quot; an official said.</p>
<p>The Commission is highlighting that on Friday the EU beef management committee bought in only 7,918 tonnes of beef compared with an average of around 25,000 tonnes since the spring.</p>
<p>They say that French fears that their markets for broutards, young cattle, would collapse have not been realised. On Friday only 229 tonnes of broutards were bought into intervention.</p>
<p>&quot;The anxiety about the market for French broutards amounts to crying wolf. There has been no significant collapse of the market as Friday's intervention figures show,&quot; an official told Reuters. -- Brussels Newsroom 32 2 287 6800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100105">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41220">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
