<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229540" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Russia wins backing for new arms talks at summit.</title>
<headline>Russia wins backing for new arms talks at summit.</headline>
<byline>Steve Pagani</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A European security summit agreed on Monday to a new round of talks to reduce conventional arms across the continent, adapting a Cold War-era pact to meet Russian concerns over the military balance in Europe.</p>
<p>Russian leaders have pushed for changes to the 1990 Conventional Forces in Europe (CFE) treaty ever since the breakup of the Soviet Union the following year.</p>
<p>Portuguese Prime Minister Antonio Guterres announced at the opening session of a two-day summit of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) that agreement had been reached on the fresh arms talks.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a major achievement which, by itself, will justify this summit,&quot; Guterres told national leaders from the 54-member OSCE, grouping the United States and Canada with all European states.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the fresh negotiations would start in January in Vienna, where the OSCE is based.</p>
<p>The CFE treaty was negotiated under the auspices of the OSCE to try to strike a balance between the military hardware held by the NATO military alliance and the now-defunct Soviet-led Warsaw Pact. Thirty countries are now signatories to the treaty and diplomats said more could join in the new talks.</p>
<p>Addressing the summit, Russian Prime Minister Viktor Chernomyrdin said: &quot;A key question here is the adaptation of the agreement on conventional forces in Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;This work must be aimed at limiting the military potential of alliances, not building up the military potential on foreign territories, limiting more broadly than now the circle of categories of military equipment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>U.S. Vice President Al Gore described the CFE treaty as &quot;an important step&quot; in European security,</p>
<p>&quot;Not all our (OSCE) members are CFE states but all share in the increased stability and security that will be provided by a successful outcome,&quot; Gore told the assembled leaders.</p>
<p>Western nations hope that the agreement will go some way to easing Moscow's opposition to NATO plans to expand eastwards, taking in former Soviet satellites such as Poland and Hungary.</p>
<p>Signatory states destroyed more than 50,000 pieces of military equipment within a November 17, 1995 deadline set down in the treaty. The total included nearly 19,000 battle tanks, 18,000 armoured vehicles and thousands of pieces of artillery, combat aircraft and attack helicopters.</p>
<p>But just before the 1995 date, Moscow announced it could not meet its treaty obligations because it feared that reduced military might on its frontiers would ruin its defence capabilities. It was particularly concerned about its southern flank near the troubled Caucasus region, where Russian troops were fighting Chechen rebels.</p>
<p>By missing the deadline Russia was in technical violation of the pact, but Moscow argued that CFE limits on military equipment allowed on a state's borders had to be altered because Russia's frontiers were not the same as the Soviet Union's.</p>
<p>The United States accepted Moscow's argument and put pressure on its NATO allies to agree to adapt the CFE pact, despite concern from Norway and Turkey over any increase in Russian military equipment near their borders.</p>
<p>The CFE states agreed in Vienna on June 1 to extend the CFE deadline, giving Russia until May 31, 1999 to meet its arms cuts quotas.</p>
<p>Referring to the new arms talks agreement in his address to the summit, French President Jacques Chirac said: &quot;This is a major decision which will allow negotiations to open in Vienna in January.&quot; Chirac said it was clear the CFE pact needed to be adapted and the decision should allow other states to join in the arms control limits.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
