<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229622" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: NTT may be broken up under giant holding company.</title>
<headline>NTT may be broken up under giant holding company.</headline>
<byline>Yuko Inoue</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>An agreement could be reached soon in the long-running debate over whether to break up Japanese telecommunications giant Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp., the company and the government said Monday.</p>
<p>A possible breakup of NTT, which at present enjoys a monopoly over Japan's local telephone networks, has been mulled for more than a decade.</p>
<p>The government argues that a breakup is needed before letting NTT enter global telecommunications markets.</p>
<p>Industry sources said that discussions between NTT and the Posts and Telecommunications Ministry, held since this summer behind closed doors, are focusing on the possible establishment of a holding company by NTT.</p>
<p>Under the new structure, NTT's domestic long-distance and local phone operations would be broken up into three or four different businesses but united under an umbrella company, the sources said.</p>
<p>But NTT said there are still many hurdles to overcome.</p>
<p>Agreement on the future shape of NTT, the biggest telecoms company in the world in terms of sales and the third-biggest in profits, would mark the end of a decade-long battle between its management and the government.</p>
<p>Asked about the talks with the government, an NTT spokesman said: &quot;There is still a large gap, even if we are to talk about a holding company scheme.&quot;</p>
<p>Sources in NTT referred in particular to tax issues, which NTT says could jeopardise its shareholders' assets.</p>
<p>A split NTT would be liable to large taxes on latent assets transferred from the parent company. NTT earlier this year calculated the tax burden stemming from realignment at as much as 1.8 trillion yen ($15.7 billion).</p>
<p>NTT also wants the government to introduce a group-based tax payment system to reduce its tax burden and narrow a possible financial gap between local phone companies.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been no discussion on such issues that would have a detrimental impact on NTT,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>A Posts Ministry official said early this year that beneficial tax treatment would be given to NTT if it was split by government order.</p>
<p>If an agreement is reached on a holding company scheme, a new NTT unit operating long-distance networks would be allowed to enter international business.</p>
<p>Current NTT shareholders would get shares in a holding firm. But for the plan to take effect, the government must clear another major hurdle by lifting a nearly 50-year-old ban on the setting up of holding companies.</p>
<p>Vice Posts and Telecommunications Minister Mitsuo Igarashi said Monday that an agreement had not been reached with NTT. But he said a bill on NTT's management status would be submitted to a regular parliament session starting in January.</p>
<p>Analysts were divided on whether smaller NTTs under a holding company would enhance competition in Japan's telecommunications market.</p>
<p>&quot;It is hard to judge for the moment whether that could cause a real shakeup in the Japanese market,&quot; said Hironobu Sawake, an analyst at Nikko Research Centre.</p>
<p>A ministry panel proposed in February that NTT, which holds 80 percent of Japan's domestic telecommunications market, be broken up into three different companies. But the government, which owns 65 percent of NTT, postponed a decision on whether to split it up until next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
