<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229621" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Bre-X, Indonesian partner in Busang talks.</title>
<headline>Bre-X, Indonesian partner in Busang talks.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA, Indonesia</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Indonesian partner of Canadian mining company Bre-X Minerals Ltd. said Monday he had put off a $1.9 billion lawsuit against Bre-X because it was willing to discuss the ownership dispute over the Busang gold find.</p>
<p>Businessman Jusuf Merukh, who claims to own 40 percent of the spectacular find in East Kalimantan, said Bre-X had been in touch with his lawyers in opening negotiations over their dispute.</p>
<p>He had given Bre-X, which has estimated Busang contains at least 47 million ounces of gold, until Wednesday to start serious negotiations.</p>
<p>&quot;I am delaying the legal action because Bre-X has been in touch with my lawyers,&quot; he told Reuters.</p>
<p>Merukh, who declined to give further details, had been locked in an ownership dispute with Bre-X, which led to the Indonesian government delaying issuing a contract of work Bre-X until their dispute was resolved.</p>
<p>The government has since advised Bre-X to team up with Barrick Gold Corp. to develop Busang, with Bre-X taking a 25 percent stake and Barrick 75 percent.</p>
<p>It has given both parties until Wednesday to strike a deal, and also said it wanted a 10 percent stake, to be allocated by Bre-X and Barrick.</p>
<p>Bre-X has a partnership deal with PT Panutan Duta of the Panutan Group, run by President Suharto's eldest son, Sigit Harjojudanto.</p>
<p>Panutan would receive $40 million over 40 months plus a 10 percent stake in Busang's richest areas under the deal.</p>
<p>Barrick has teamed up with a construction company in the Citra Group of Suharto's eldest daughter, Siti Hardianti Rukmana.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA, Indonesia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
