<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229733" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: HK's Lee sees China fear in Australian refusal.</title>
<headline>HK's Lee sees China fear in Australian refusal.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong democracy campaigner Martin Lee said on Monday that diplomatic fears of offending China may have led Australia's Prime Minister John Howard to refuse a formal meeting with him.</p>
<p>&quot;People in the foreign office (may have) thought a meeting with me would upset China tremendously,&quot; Lee, chairman of Hong Kong's Democratic Party, told reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;I am not saying this is Mr Howard's view, but I can certainly see this might be the foreign office's view.&quot;</p>
<p>Lee, who is lobbying Canberra to apply diplomatic pressure on Beijing over its treatment of Hong Kong, said he had been invited to meet Howard only at a cocktail party that he would have trouble attending.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Howard said the prime minister's schedule was too busy to accommodate a private meeting.</p>
<p>China, which will resume sovereignty of the British colony at midnight on June 30 next year, is setting up an interim replacement for Hong Kong's democratic Legislative Council.</p>
<p>Lee says the new assembly is intended to merely rubber stamp Beijing's wishes.</p>
<p>He will meet Foreign Affairs Minister Alexander Downer on Tuesday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
