<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229769" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AWB Report-Australia wheat exports on track.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AWB Report-Australia wheat exports on track.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia and Canada shared the bulk of a Saudi Arabian purchase of 500,000 tonnes of wheat last week at prices reported at A$163.00 a tonne, the Australian Wheat Board (AWB) said in its weekly grain market report.</p>
<p>AWB sales to Sri Lanka and Turkey in the last week had been at prices very supportive of pool returns, it said.</p>
<p>Australia sold 50,000 tonnes of soft wheat to Sri Lanka at A$212.50 a tonne c and f for December shipment, it said.</p>
<p>Shipments to Turkey during October and November totalled 190,000 tonnes with an additional 60,000 tonnes due to be shipped in December, it said.  </p>
<p>By the end of November, the AWB had shipped 1.7 million tonnes of wheat, the best start to a shipping season since market deregulation in 1989, it said.</p>
<p>The European Commission last week boosted wheat and barley subsidy prices slightly, with the wheat subsidy up to A$27.00 a tonne and the barley subsidy to A$47.00 a tonne, it said.</p>
<p>Argentine producers rejected trade claims last week that the total crop could reach 17.0 million tonnes, the AWB said.</p>
<p>The harvest was gathering pace around Australia with early deliveries made in Victoria last week, the board said.  </p>
<p>Indications continued than usual quantities of small grains in this season's sample, the AWB said.</p>
<p>Bids for Prime Hard wheat fell by A$8.00-A$9.00 a tonne in New South Wales (NSW) and Queensland while in Victoria bids for the premium grades rose by A$4.00 a tonne.</p>
<p>Feed grain prices were particularly buoyant, it said.</p>
<p>Feeders anticipating ample supplies of feed wheat in Queensland had been disappointed and were now buying Australian Standard White, it said. Feed barley prices firmed by A$2.00 a tonne in Queensland and remained firm in NSW, the report said.  </p>
<p>New crop sorghum in Queensland was trading well above export parity with bids up by A$2.00 a tonne, while in Victoria there has been a A$6.00 a tonne rise in triticale prices and a A$2.00 a tonne increase in winter wheat prices.</p>
<p>Canola continued to be volatile during the week with prices A$6.00 a tonne down to A$350.00 a tonne delivered Melbourne.</p>
<p>The AWB has replaced its indicator price with cash bids at all sites.</p>
<p>The estimated wheat crop remains at 21.0 million tonnes.  </p>
<p>Wheat Shipping:</p>
<p>		  Latest Week     Year to Date     Previous Year</p>
<p>    (tonnes)   89,033	   1,691,524	  1,286,241</p>
<p>NOTE: Shipping year starts October 1.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
