<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229702" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Scottish &amp; Newcastle gives positive outlook.</title>
<headline>Scottish &amp; Newcastle gives positive outlook.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's largest brewer Scottish and Newcastle Plc announced a 26 percent increase in half-year profits to 195.1 million pounds ($328 million) on Monday and said the second half of the year had started positively.</p>
<p>Its acquisition of Courage from Australian brewer Fosters last year helped the company turn in a 67 percent rise in trading profit to 89.9 million pounds. But profits from its Center Parcs holiday resorts were down 11 percent at about 44 million due to weak consumer spending in Benelux countries.  </p>
<p>Profits from the company's retail business grew 8.2 percent to 87 million pounds ($146.1 million), driven by its managed pub estate where S&amp;N's redevelopment programme paid off and like-for-like food sales across the estate grew by 13 percent.</p>
<p>The company said it planned to open more than 30 so-called Chef &amp; Brewer pub restaurants by the end of the year.</p>
<p>The beer market fell by just over one percent compared to the first half of 1995 which was bolstered by outstanding summer weather, said the company. Despite this, S&amp;N said sales of John Smith's, the country's leading ale, were up 17 percent and sales of Foster's lager grew 6.5 percent to its highest ever volume.</p>
<p>However, chief executive Brian Stewart bemoaned the failure of Chancellor Kenneth Clarke to reduce excise duty on beer in his Budget last week. &quot;It was disappointing that the Chancellor refused to recognise the industry's well reasoned case for a reduction,&quot; he said. ($1=.5953 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
