<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229772" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ's Cullen says exchange rate top priority.</title>
<headline>NZ's Cullen says exchange rate top priority.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand Labour party finance spokesman Michael Cullen said on Monday that the high exchange rate would be his first priority as finance minister if Labour leads the next government.</p>
<p>Cullen was commenting on Treasury's December Economic and Fiscal Update, released earlier.  </p>
<p>Cullen said the slight deterioration in the Treasury forecasts since September showed &quot;the effects of the high-flying kiwi dollar are coming home to roost&quot;.</p>
<p>He said the latest figures suggested &quot;neither Treasury nor the caretaker National Party government have grasped the nature or the urgency of, or the action needed to deal with, the issues facing the New Zealand economy&quot;.</p>
<p>Cullen added: &quot;The answer is not, as vested interests continue to claim, to punish the poor or to bankrupt health and education services. The answer has to be to attack directly the cause of the present problems. And that is the high exchange  </p>
<p>rate.&quot;</p>
<p>Cullen has consistently argued the New Zealand dollar is overvalued.</p>
<p>Labour has said it will insist on Cullen as finance minister if it forms a government with nationalist New Zealand First. The latter is also negotiating with the caretaker National government in drawn-out talks following the inconclusive October 12 general election.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
