<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229871" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Outline of U.S.-Japan agreement on Okinawa.</title>
<headline>Outline of U.S.-Japan agreement on Okinawa.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are details of an agreement the United States and Japan signed on Monday to streamline U.S. military bases on Okinawa, cut back on training and address aircraft noise and other problems.</p>
<p>BASES AND FACILITIES:</p>
<p>Eleven facilities will be returned, totalling 12,000 acres (4,900 hectares) or about a fifth of the 58,000 acres (23,500 hectares) the U.S. military occupies on Okinawa.</p>
<p>They are:</p>
<p>-- Futenma Air Station - The U.S. Marine Corps air base in an urban part of southern Okinawa. The base, to be replaced in several years' time by a floating helicopter facility off the east coast of the island, was the biggest issue because its relocation was announced by U.S. President Bill Clinton and Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto in April.</p>
<p>-- Northern Training Area, Aha Training Area, Gimbaru Training Area - Huge 4,000-hectare (10,000 acre) area of training ground in the north, and two other smaller training areas in the centre of the island, will be returned.</p>
<p>-- Sobe Communications Site - U.S. Navy antenna facility in southern Okinawa to be relocated to a nearby U.S. Marine Corps base. The so-called &quot;Elephant Cage&quot; at Sobe, a large circular array of antennas, had become a symbol for the anti-bases movement in Okinawa.</p>
<p>-- Yomitan Auxiliary Airfield - To be returned, with parachute exercises currently held here to be conducted at the Ie Jima Auxiliary Airfield, on an outlying island.</p>
<p>-- Camp Kuwae - Navy hospital in Camp Kuwae, adjacent to Futenma Air Station, will be relocated to a nearby U.S. Marine Corps base at Zukeran.</p>
<p>-- Senaha Communications Station - The antenna complex on the picturesque west coast of the island will be relocated.</p>
<p>-- Makiminato Service Area - Stretch of land adjacent to a national highway will be returned so the road can be widened.</p>
<p>-- Naha Port - Dock and wharf area at the port of Naha, Okinawa's provincial capital, will be returned.</p>
<p>-- Housing at Camps Kuwae and Zukeran - Land used for single-storey houses will be returned when high-rise apartment blocks are built.</p>
<p>TRAINING:</p>
<p>1. Artillery - Live-fire artillery training over National Highway 104 in central Okinawa will be terminated, pending relocation to an artillery range elsewhere in Japan. Live-fire exercises stopped all traffic on the highway and was bitterly resented by Okinawans.</p>
<p>2. Parachute - Parachute drops will be conducted on the outlying Ie Jima island.</p>
<p>3. Forced marches - Forced-march training on Okinawan public roads will be terminated.</p>
<p>AIRCRAFT NOISE REDUCTION:</p>
<p>1. Aircraft noise reduction barriers to be built at Kadena Air Force Base and Futenma Air Station.</p>
<p>2. KC-130 in-flight refuelling aircraft stationed at Futenma will be relocated to Iwakuni in western Japan. AV-8 Harrier jump-jets have been moved back to the United States.</p>
<p>3. Navy aircraft at Kadena Air Force base will be moved to the other side of the base, away from the built-up area.</p>
<p>4. Night-flight training at Futenma Air Station will be curtailed.</p>
<p>STATUS OF FORCES AGREEMENT</p>
<p>1. Aircraft accidents - Provide detailed reports to local Japanese authorities in the event of U.S. military aircraft accidents.</p>
<p>2. Traffic accidents - All U.S. military personnel are now required to obtain Japanese car accident insurance. All official U.S. vehicles will be accurately marked. Claims procedures against U.S. servicemen will be improved.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
