<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229852" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan central banker cautiously bullish on economy.</title>
<headline>Japan central banker cautiously bullish on economy.</headline>
<byline>Yoko Kobayashi</byline>
<dateline>OSAKA, Japan 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's central bank governor struck a cautiously bullish stance on the nation's economy on Monday but signalled that interest rates will be kept low so as to maintain the momentum of recovery.</p>
<p>His remarks boosted the yen against the dollar.</p>
<p>Governor Yasuo Matsushita told a news conference that Japanese companies were still cautious about the future as they were continuing to adjust their business structures to get out of a prolonged slump.</p>
<p>&quot;The economy is continuing to recover gradually. The strength of the economic recovery appears to be becoming more solid,&quot; he said on a trip to western Japan.</p>
<p>Japan's industrial output was rising more rapidly, he said.</p>
<p>Leading the increasing production was brisk sales of cars in Japan. The Japan Automobile Dealers' Association said on Monday that domestic vehicle sales in November rose 14 percent from a year earlier to 507,548 units.</p>
<p>Financial markets took Matsushita's remarks as indicating that Japan's economy may be stronger than expected, which could lead to a credit-tightening some time in the future.</p>
<p>The comments prompted selling of the dollar against the yen, pushing down the U.S. currency. The dollar was hovering around 113.80 yen in late Tokyo trading on Monday.</p>
<p>Matsushita was not entirely upbeat, however.</p>
<p>&quot;We can well expect a favourable economic cycle of production creating income and then consumption to strengthen further. However, we still need to make sure this is on track,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Asked about the Bank of Japan's monetary policy, Matsushita said:  &quot;We will put emphasis on ensuring a basis for economic recovery while keeping close watch on economic conditions.&quot; This was taken as a signal that no change in interest rate policy is imminent.</p>
<p>The central bank has kept its official discount rate, which it charges on lending to commercial banks, at a historic low of 0.5 percent since September last year.</p>
<p>The BOJ declared in February that the nation's economy had finally come out of the slump that followed the collapse in the early 1990s of the &quot;bubble&quot; economy of inflated asset prices.</p>
<p>But economic indicators have shown the pace of recovery has not been picking up, and many economists suspected that the economy actually came to a halt in the summer.</p>
<p>Pressures from structural adjustments and an expected fall in public works spending are still keeping Japanese companies cautious about their future prospects, he added.</p>
<p>Many economists predict the economic recovery will slow in the coming months, with a fall in public works spending, and especially after a planned rise in the consumption tax next April to five percent from the current three percent.</p>
<p>Matsushita said the central bank's easy money policy was intended to prevent a deflationary spiral, to strengthen corporate confidence and to put the economy back on a self-sustainable recovery track.</p>
<p>The first two aims had &quot;just about been achieved&quot;, he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSAKA, Japan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
