<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229837" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber ends mixed on weak interest.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber ends mixed on weak interest.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices ended mixed due to little interest from overseas consumer markets already showing signs of year-end holiday lethargy, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I guess it's going to be like this the whole month,&quot; said a trader with a sigh after failing to note any business for the first trading day of December.</p>
<p>Dealers said apart from uncertainties usually associated with the start of a new week, Monday's trading was notably gloomier with the virtual absence of U.S. and European dealers.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. dealers are still not through the lethargy of the long Thanksgiving weekend,&quot; said a Kuala Lumpur-based trader.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Europeans are already holidaying.&quot;</p>
<p>At the close, the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board quoted December RSS1 buyer at 317 cents ($) a kg, down half cent from Friday's close. December SMR 20 was a cent higher at 306.50.</p>
<p>Traders offered the SMR CV at 366 cents, SMR L at 346, SMR 5 at 322, SMR 10 at 314, SMR 20 at 311 and drum latex at 237.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day moving average fell to 241.95 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on Nov 29 from 242.14 on Nov 28. The daily indicator price dipped to 242.71 from 243.05.</p>
<p>-- Barani Krishnaan (603-230-7509) ($1=2.5270 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
