<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="229926" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shangdong Pharm seen in HK$200-300 mln IPO - sources.</title>
<headline>Shangdong Pharm seen in HK$200-300 mln IPO - sources.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>China state-owned medicine manufacturer Shangdong Xinhua Pharmaceutical Co is expected to raise HK$200-HK$300 million through an H-share listing in Hong Kong, market sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>Sources said the company is expected to issue about 145 million H-shares at a price of about eight times its prospective price to earnings multiple. Proceeds raised are expected to be used to repay debt and to expand production capacity.</p>
<p>H-shares are Hong Kong-listed shares issued by China incorporated companies.</p>
<p>One market source noted Shangdong Xinhua has a long term contract to supply products to Coca-Cola Co's production lines in China.</p>
<p>&quot;Shangdong Xinhua is one of the approved caffeine suppliers (of Coca-Cola) in China,&quot; B.C. Lo, vice president and director of external affairs of Coca-Cola China Ltd, told Reuters on Monday. Lo declined to give further comment.</p>
<p>Sources said Coca-Cola has less than 10 caffeine suppliers in China.</p>
<p>Shangdong Xinhua is expected to arrange a trip for analysts to visit its manufacturing facilities in China by the end of this week, sources said.  </p>
<p>The listing promotion is expected to kick off in mid-December, and dealing in shares is expected later in the month, they said.</p>
<p>Sources said Nomura International is expected to be the sponsor of the issue. Nomura officials declined to comment.</p>
<p>Shangdong Xinhua is expected to be the last Chinese enterprise to seek a H-share listing in Hong Kong in 1996.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
