<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230049" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Asia defence spending up despite low war chances.</title>
<headline>Asia defence spending up despite low war chances.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian military spending is soaring despite remote possiblities of a full-scale war in the region, the Political &amp; Economic Risk Consultancy Ltd (PERC) said in its latest &quot;Asian Intelligence&quot; report.</p>
<p>It said while some northern Asia countries have a good excuse for their heavy spending, reasons for Southeast Asia's huge appetite for military hardware are less obvious.</p>
<p>At more than $9 billion, southeast Asia arms spending in 1995 was 22 percent of world sales, making the region overtake the Middle East as the world's third largest weapons market after the United States and Europe, PERC said in its fortnightly report.</p>
<p>It &quot;is nothing short of amazing that military spending in Asia is growing as fast as it is,&quot; PERC said. It said Singapore puts 21 percent of total goverment expenditure towards defence, Thailand 17 percent and Malaysia 12 percent.</p>
<p>PERC discounted the possibility of full-scale war even in the region's two hot spots -- the Korean peninsula and Taiwan.</p>
<p>Due to mounting economic problems in North Korea it is much more likely the North will undertake economic reforms that would bring it closer to the global economy, the report said.</p>
<p>Also North Korea &quot;cannot count on the support of either Russia or China&quot; for any military attacks, it said.</p>
<p>Turning to Taiwan, PERC said &quot;it is probably only a matter of months before Taipei and Beijing move decisively in the direction of of closer commercial relations...&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What's more, those in Taiwan who believe the U.S. can be counted on to throw its support behind Taiwan autonomy under any circumstances are likely to receive a rude awakening when President Clinton adopts a policy in the coming years of less confrontation and more positive engagement.&quot;</p>
<p>Among the reasons offered for southeast Asia's huge expenditure are U.S. withdrawal from the Philippines in 1992, the need for defence spending to be in line with overall economic growth, and modernisation of the military, PERC said.</p>
<p>Southeast Asian nations are also beefing up their arms because &quot;a country may be a friend of its neighbour today, but circumstances could change tomorrow&quot;, the report said.</p>
<p>But it expressed doubts about those and some other responses to queries on the need for high defence spending. &quot;Unfortunately, the answers given usually are made more to score debating points than to communicate a truth,&quot; PERC said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
