<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230107" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: PRESS DIGEST - United Arab Emirates - Dec 2.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - United Arab Emirates - Dec 2.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the United Arab Emirates press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>GULF NEWS</p>
<p>- President Sheikh Zaid bin Sultan al-Nahayan issued a decree raising salaries, wages and bonuses of federal government employees by 15 to 30 percent.</p>
<p>KHALEEJ TIMES</p>
<p>- The UAE said it would sell more shipments of liquefied natural gas to the United States and Spain in deals that will allow it to dispose of capacity surpluses.</p>
<p>- A UAE trade team is to go to Iraq next month.</p>
<p>AL KHALEEJ</p>
<p>- The UAE on Monday celebrates its silver jubilee and the 30th anniversary of the accession of Sheikh Zaid.</p>
<p>- Abu Dhabi National Oil Company (ADNOC) said it was implementing programmes to fulfil the growing gas needs of the domestic market until 2005.</p>
<p>- ADGAS has signed a deal with U.S. company Cabot Oil and Gas Corp and a Spanish company to increase its shipments of liquefied natural gas in November and December to 37,000 tonnes and 57,000 tonnes respectively.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
