<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230132" id="root" date="1996-12-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Dini says Italy govt must consult to survive.</title>
<headline>Dini says Italy govt must consult to survive.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Foreign Minister Lamberto Dini was quoted by La Stampa newspaper on Monday as saying that he would consider pulling his centrist Italian Renewal party out of the government if he felt it was not being properly consulted.</p>
<p>Dini told La Stampa that Prime Minister Romano Prodi's office had failed to consult the cabinet formally on plans to raise 12.5 trillion lire ($8.3 billion) as part of the 1997 budget through a special &quot;Euro-tax&quot; provision.</p>
<p>Tensions over the issue were resolved last week in a compromise reducing the proposed burden of the tax on self-employed Italians after pressure from Dini's party.</p>
<p>&quot;Up until last Thursday the Euro-tax had never been discussed in the cabinet. I said it clearly: another discourtesy of this sort and the break between us and the government will become inevitable,&quot; Dini was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>He said the loyalty to the government of his party, one of the smaller forces in Prodi's centre-left coalition, was not in question.</p>
<p>But the minister, who has frequently voiced dismay at the government's dependence on support from the hardline Communist Refoundation party, said the coalition's centrist component had to be strengthened.</p>
<p>The Euro-tax has been drawn up to help reduce Italy's 1997 deficit sufficiently to give the country a chance of meeting the conditions for membership of Europe's planned single currency due to be launched in 1999.</p>
<p>Asked whether Prodi would still be prime minister when the single currency decision is due to be taken in early 1998, Dini said:</p>
<p>&quot;The Prodi government has some very demanding stages ahead. It must confront them decisively and in a balanced manner.</p>
<p>&quot;Given that he (Prodi) likes cycling, he should remember that we must all make the running together and that Italian Renewal is not a spare wheel. If he does that, the government will last. (If he doesn't) the bicycle will break.&quot;</p>
<p>--Rome newsroom +39 6 678 2505  ($1=1514 Lire)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
