<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230588" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Papers show Duke of Windsor was royal loose cannon.</title>
<headline>Papers show Duke of Windsor was royal loose cannon.</headline>
<byline>Giles Elgood</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Duke of Windsor, who gave up the English throne 60 years ago this month to wed American divorcee Wallis Simpson, was reprimanded by World War Two leader Winston Churchill for &quot;defeatist and pro-Nazi&quot; views.</p>
<p>And a secret service informant reported that the Germans wanted the former king to resume his throne under German occupation if they won the war, according to official papers released by Britain's Public Record Office on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Germans expect assistance from the Duke and Duchess of Windsor, the latter desiring at any price to become queen,&quot; said a terse note in one file.</p>
<p>The Germans had asked Charles Bedaux, a naturalised American, to ask the Duke if he would be king of England in the event of a German victory, but Bedaux had declined because he was no longer friendly with the Windsors.</p>
<p>Thousands of pages of secret documents throw new light on official attitudes to the Duke's often embarrassing views and the whiff of pro-German intrigue that surrounded him.</p>
<p>An interview he gave while he was colonial governor of the Bahamas in 1941 drew a frosty telegram from Churchill, who feared the Duke's remarks would be seen as backing the isolationist aim of keeping the United States out of the war.</p>
<p>&quot;I could wish indeed that your Royal Highness would seek advice before making public statements of this kind,&quot; wrote the prime minister to the man who until his abdication in 1936 had been King Edward VIII of England.</p>
<p>In another paper, Churchill said the Duke had become an embarrassment to the goverment, and although his loyalties were &quot;unimpeachable&quot;, he was dogged by &quot;a backwash of Nazi intrigue which seeks to make trouble for him&quot;.</p>
<p>While in Lisbon before moving to the Bahamas in 1940, the Duke fuelled speculation about his loyalties by staying in the house of a Portuguese bank manager said by the British secret service to be in close touch with the German embassy.</p>
<p>One British diplomat, after a conversation with the Windsors about the surrender of France, described them as &quot;practically Fifth Column&quot;.</p>
<p>The papers released by the Public Record Office range from secret service memos to letters between members of the public &quot;intercepted&quot; by the security forces.</p>
<p>One such letter made clear just how enraged some sections of British opinion had been by the Duke's decision to give up the throne in order to marry the twice-divorced Wallis Simpson.</p>
<p>Miss F. Davidson, of Northern Ireland, angered by the Duke's appointment to the Bahamas, wrote that Canada and the United States were &quot;fizzing with disgust&quot; to see &quot;a rat and a bitch in their cherished government home.&quot;</p>
<p>The Windsors also got into trouble soon after arriving in the Bahamas in 1940, when the Duke asked for large sums of money to refurbish his official residence.</p>
<p>It was pointed out to him by London that such requests were open to criticism during wartime, when &quot;the money could have been used to buy a fighter&quot;.</p>
<p>The British government also struggled unsuccessfully to prevent the luxury-loving Windsors from leaving the Bahamas and visiting the U.S., where it was feared they would attract unwelcome publicity.</p>
<p>At one point, in the face of hostile news reports, the Duke was forced to defend himself against claims that he was behaving frivolously while men were dying in the war.</p>
<p>&quot;The Duchess and I have not darkened the door of any night club in New York,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
