<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230522" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Dollar just shy of 23-month peaks at midday Europe.</title>
<headline>Dollar just shy of 23-month peaks at midday Europe.</headline>
<byline>Julia Meehan</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar was just shy of 23-month peaks touched against Europe's heavyweight currencies at midday but Germany's shaky economic recovery and Europe's encroaching monetary union will keep the greenback a favourite with investors, traders and analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The general trend of the dollar continuing to strengthen is in place...But we are going to have some further hiccups on the road to monetary union and at those times we may see the deutschemark strengthen,&quot; said David Brickman, European analyst at Yamaichi International.</p>
<p>	     The dollar shot to 23-month highs against the mighty</p>
<p>deutschemark, French franc and Swiss franc in overnight dealings after comments by German and U.S. officials on the dollar's status as a reserve currency ahead of European Monetary and Economic Union (EMU).</p>
<p>But profittaking later knocked the dollar off 23-month peaks against European currencies. At 1128 GMT dollar/mark was at 1.5651/58 marks, after powering to 23-month peaks of 1.5735, but still well up from 1.5445/50 marks in late Europe on Monday.</p>
<p>Dollar/Swiss franc was at 1.3256/66 after a fresh 23-month high of 1.3320 and well up against 1.3143/53 in late Europe.</p>
<p>Against the French franc, the dollar stood at 5.2975/85 at 1137 GMT after rallying to 23-month highs at 5.3233 in overnight dealings. Traders said there had been hefty buying of dollars on Tuesday for French francs and analysts said much of the dollar's gains in Europe had been led by French-franc weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;This is mainly a function of what has happened within Europe, particularly given the amount of pressure for a French devaluation, which is clearly not on the cards,&quot; said Yamaichi's Brickman.</p>
<p>&quot;For France to devalue now would actually put the whole EMU process into question,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Comments by Bundesbank chief economist Otmar Issing and New York Federal Reserve Bank President William McDonough on the dollar becoming more important in the run-up to EMU and Issing forecasting a possible shift from deutschemarks into dollars also provided a key spark, said analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;There are strong reasons why the deutsche mark will suffer and the dollar will benefit ahead of monetary union. I see the dollar easily heading to 1.70 against the deutschemark,&quot; said Lyons.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe the euro, if it ever happens, will be a soft currency anyway,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>While the dollar as a reserve currency in the run-up to EMU is and will be an ongoing issue, analysts said its alternative to the mark is being voiced at this key moment because the Germans are worried about the state of their economy.</p>
<p>Pan-German October industrial output, for instance, fell to 1.8 percent month-on-month in November, its second consecutive month of weakness, and much weaker than expected.</p>
<p>&quot;In Germany, we are looking at what can be termed a bumpy recovery at best,&quot; said Jeremy Stretch, currency strategist at NatWest Markets in London. &quot;The economic outlook should keep the mark soft against the dollar and its European crosses.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The Germans are clearly worried about their domestic economy...The Bundesbank wants a weaker deutschemark,&quot; said DKB International Chief Economist Gerard Lyons.</p>
<p>Some dealers had also been speculating about a further cut in German interest rates after the Bundesbank eased the securities repurchase rate to 3.0 percent last August.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Germans will cut official rates. I think they will first cut the repo rate and then they will cut the discount rate,&quot; said DKB's Lyons.</p>
<p>The Bundesbank on Tuesday declined to comment directly on the bout of market speculation about rate cuts in Germany.</p>
<p>But in response to a Reuter query on rates, chief Bundesbank spokesman Manfred Koerber said while the central bank had no direct comment on the talk: &quot;I would draw your attention to recent comments by Mr. Tietmeyer in Spiegel magazine, when he observed - I see no short-term reason for another interest rate change.&quot;</p>
<p>--Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 6701</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
