<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230587" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices flat despite looming Iraqi oil sales.</title>
<headline>Oil prices flat despite looming Iraqi oil sales.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil prices were unchanged on Tuesday as the prospect of Iraqi oil hitting world markets for the first time in six years began to exert downward pressure.</p>
<p>Iraqi oil exports have been banned under a U.N. embargo imposed since Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990. But the last hurdle in an oil-for-food deal worth $2 billion over six months was cleared last week between Iraq and the U.N.</p>
<p>OPEC Secretary-General Rilwanu Lukman on Tuesday said he was confident the oil market would manage to absorb Iraqi crude when it returns to the market and forecast there would be little impact on prices. &quot;The market is always nervous,&quot; Lukman told reporters in Vienna.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks as though the market has largely discounted any impact from the re-introduction of Iraqi oil...We are only talking about another 700,000 or so barrels per day,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But prices dipped before recovering on news that Iraqi state-owned oil company SOMO had already signed contracts with some foreign companies to sell oil under the delayed U.N. &quot;oil-for-food&quot; plan.</p>
<p>Brent blend, the world benchmark, for January delivery was up one cent at $23.63 a barrel at 1608 GMT.</p>
<p>An Iraqi oil official said on Tuesday the first Iraqi oil since the Gulf War could be shipped to world markets next week.</p>
<p>&quot;No problem remains...The story is over...Loading is supposed to start next week,&quot; Taha Hmud Mosa, senior under-secretary at Iraq's oil ministry, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Mosa said Iraq had signed &quot;initial contracts&quot; with 50 international firms for the oil sales, putting Iraqi crude onto world markets for the first time since sanctions were imposed for invading Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;We have deals with 50 firms from Europe, South East Asia and South America...These are initial but binding international contracts. They do not include prices as prices have to be determined at the time of shipping,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mosa said the deals could be completed &quot;in several days as the companies are ready waiting for the signal to start loading.&quot;</p>
<p>On Monday the United nations said an inspection of oil metering equipment by Dutch firm Saybolt was the last step before the oil-for-food plan could start running. Two experts from the firm arrived in Baghdad on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, traders of refined oil products said there was good demand in the West for winter heating fuels. Stocks are at low levels and oil companies are scrambling to refill near empty storage tanks.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem of working with low stocks is beginning to have an effect. Buyers are having to pay big numbers when they need the oi,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					    Dec 3	Dec 2</p>
<p>					   1608 GMT     close</p>
<p> Dated Brent			    23.97	 23.97</p>
<p> IPE London Brent futures (Jan)   23.63	 23.62</p>
<p> NYMEX light crude futures (Jan)  24.68	 24.80</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
