<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230694" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Foreign demand boosts activity at Nairobi bourse.</title>
<headline>Foreign demand boosts activity at Nairobi bourse.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Activity at the Nairobi Stock Exchange was up by about six million shillings boosted by foreign demand, brokers and bourse officials said.</p>
<p>Turnover was posted at 13.583 million shillings traded on 402,576 from 7.816 million shillings traded on 216,430 shares.</p>
<p>The index gained 10.57 points to stand at 3052.68.</p>
<p>Kenya Commercial Bank, Firestone East Africa and Kenya Breweries were the most active shares in the market on Tuesday. Brokers said their sustained price increase was supported by unmatched demand, mainly from foreign investors.</p>
<p>Firestone closed at 30 from 28.50, while Kenya Commercial Bank gained a shilling to close at 63.50. Kenya Breweries was unchanged at 52, while power monopoly Kenya Power &amp; Lighting jumped to 141 from 136.</p>
<p>During the latest share offer by Kenya Commercial bank, there were rumours in the market that the share price was undervalued at 50, and would soon reach the 70 shillings level.</p>
<p>&quot;Well, I definitely think that if demand continues at this level, it will most probably hit the 65 mark before Christmas,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a lot of excitement in the market because it looks like prices are picking up,&quot; a bourse official said.</p>
<p>&quot;The interest shown by foreign investors in our market is something every emerging market, hopes for. A lot of demand from foreigners projects our market positively, and says that many of our shares are undervalued,&quot; a senior broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact you watch the market now, everybody is going to jump in. Nobody likes to be a market leader, but many don't mind joining the bandwagon once they're sure things have improved,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee gained a shilling to close at 58.50, while Total Kenya closed at 63 from 62.50.</p>
<p>--Wambui Chege, Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
