<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230661" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UGANDA: Multinational force for Zaire bides time in Uganda.</title>
<headline>Multinational force for Zaire bides time in Uganda.</headline>
<byline>Manoah Esipisu</byline>
<dateline>ENTEBBE, Uganda 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Over two weeks after the United Nations launched a multinational force to save refugees in Zaire, only a few hundred troops have reached the region and they are still hundreds of miles from where food may be needed.</p>
<p>At Entebbe airport command on the shores of Lake Victoria in Uganda, the troops are biding their time while the politicians try to clear the obstacles to deploying the force.</p>
<p>One army officer, from European Command in Stuttgart, Germany, said he spent his time playing with the local monkeys. &quot;All I want is this thing to be over. I have a pregnant wife and child who need me back home,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Captain Kent Stewart, a Canadian officer with the Civil Military Operations Centre, said he had no idea when the force would spring into action, either with airdrops of food or by deploying forces on the ground in Zaire, or possibly both.</p>
<p>He said Entebbe had about 300 Canadians, as well as some British, Italian and U.S. troops. Some Dutch soldiers had come and then gone home, he added.</p>
<p>The forces include a command centre, a surgical team and a detachment of transport planes which could drop food for the hundreds of thousands of refugees believed to be roaming the countryside in eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Captain John Robinson, spokesman for 300 U.S. troops based at Entebbe outside the framework of the multinational force, said he expected the force to start work within two days.</p>
<p>It would focus on between 165,000 and 200,000 people who can be repatriated to Rwanda, leaving aside 100,000 Rwandans thought to have trekked westwards away from the Rwandan border.</p>
<p>The second group includes soldiers of the Rwandan government ousted in 1994, members of the hardline Hutu militia the Interahamwe and their families. Some of these people were responsible for the genocide in which a million Rwandans were killed in 1994 and they may not want to go home.</p>
<p>Major Rod Babuik, spokesman for the force's liaison unit in the Rwandan capital Kigali, said 49 more personnel were on standby at Stuttgart in Germany, the force's rear headquarters, and 424 more were on 24 hours' notice to deploy to Uganda from Ontario and Alberta in Canada.</p>
<p>But the force is yet to start reconnaisance flights over eastern Zaire and the foot patrols announced by force commander Lieutenant-General Maurice Baril last week have been delayed.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't got all the approvals necessary to conduct the reconnaisance into Zaire and we are meeting with Rwandan officials today,&quot; Babiuk said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's frustrating, but to avoid a dangerous situation it is important to make sure you have all the necessary approvals before going in,&quot; Babiuk said.</p>
<p>U.N. Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali said on Monday that hundreds of thousands of men, women and children were still facing hunger, disease and violent death, most of them scattered in inaccessible and inhospitable areas of eastern Zaire.</p>
<p>Independently, U.S. and British reconnaisance planes have made sorties over eastern Zaire in search of the refugees.</p>
<p>British defence sources said they believed it unlikely that a large-scale multinational force would be needed because a reconnaissance mission found far fewer refugees than expected.</p>
<p>The British aerial mission over eastern Zaire located only around 200,000 refugees and displaced people, compared with the 700,000 estimated by the United Nations' refugee agency.</p>
<p>Rwanda refuses to let the force use its territory as a base, arguing that most refugees have gone back home. The force has failed to obtain permission to overfly or enter Zaire.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ENTEBBE, Uganda"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UGANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
