<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230602" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain upholds veto power ahead of EU summit.</title>
<headline>Britain upholds veto power ahead of EU summit.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain on Tuesday raised the temperature ahead of next week's European Union summit in Dublin by reaffirming its determination to block any proposals for EU treaty changes that would weaken its power of veto.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not accept any undermining or dilution of the veto in any circumstances,&quot; David Davis, Foreign Office minister for European affairs, told a parliamentary committee.</p>
<p>Ireland, which holds the rotating EU presidency, will unveil in Brussels on Friday an outline of the formula for changes to the 1991 Maastricht treaty on monetary and political union.</p>
<p>The aim of the treaty changes is to streamline the EU's institutions so that decision-making does not become impossibly unwieldy when the 15-nation bloc expands to include the eastern European countries, probably in the next decade.</p>
<p>Davis reiterated the British government's objection to the proposition that fewer decisions should require unanimity.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not under any circumstances going to give up the veto in that respect,&quot; the minister said.</p>
<p>The initial draft for changes, the result of months of negotiating by ministers and officials in a running Inter-Governmental Conference (IGC), will be scrutinised at the Dublin summit.</p>
<p>Davis, Britain's lead negotiator at the IGC, told the Select Committee on European Legislation that he expected a &quot;centralist, integrationist document&quot; that would be unacceptable to Prime Minister John Major's government.</p>
<p>He said Britain was happy to make the EU's common security and foreign policy work better -- for instance by developing the notion of &quot;constructive abstention&quot; from collective decisions -- as long as it did not impinge on national sovereignty.</p>
<p>He said Britain was still far apart from France and Germany on their demands to allow a group of EU members to override the objections of a minority.</p>
<p>Davis said Britain was concerned this could lead to the veto being removed &quot;by the back door&quot;.</p>
<p>He said Britain was as keen as other countries to wrap up the IGC on schedule next June at a summit in Amsterdam, but its partners would first have to respond to Britain's concerns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
