<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230868" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russian domestic grain buying for army very low.</title>
<headline>Russian domestic grain buying for army very low.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russia has a slightly bigger harvest this year but is behind schedule in purchasing grain from domestic farmers, an Agriculture Ministry official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Ivan Gridasov, head of the ministry's crop-growing department, told Interfax news agency that state reserves for the army and far-flung towns had only 400,000 tonnes out of a targeted 4.5 million tonnes.</p>
<p>But he said the government had bought 8.2 million tonnes of domestic grain for other uses by the end of November, below last year's 8.7 million tonnes.</p>
<p>Russia's net harvest is expected to weigh in officially at a gross 70 million tonnes or so, above last year's 63.4 million tonnes.</p>
<p>But both figures have probably under-reported actual output by several million tonnes.</p>
<p>Gridasov said the government had bought 4.7 million tonnes of wheat, almost one million tonnes less than a year earlier.</p>
<p>Government rye purchases were up to 1.55 million tonnes against 1.06 million tonnes at this time last year.</p>
<p>Gridasov said elevators held more than three million tonnes of grain, half of which was bread-making wheat, on behalf of farmers who were reluctant to sell at low state prices.</p>
<p>--Peter Henderson, Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
