<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230809" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Shares in Czech CEZ rated hold - analysis.</title>
<headline>Shares in Czech CEZ rated hold - analysis.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Czech power utility CEZ a.s. are properly valued at the current market price of 961 crowns and shareholders are advised to hold, a report to investors from Patria Finance investment bank said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the fair value of the stock is between CZK 900 and CZK 1,000. At the current price...we advise to hold the stock and we see little short-term upside potential. A price level of below CZK 900 would deserve a second look,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Patria said the company's nine month net profits of 8.4 billion crowns, calculated according to international accounting standards (IAS), were better than expected and that it had revised upwards its full year 1996 profit forecasts.</p>
<p>&quot;We slightly raised our full-year estimate for IAS net profit to CZK 9.0 billion from the previous CZK 8.8 billion,&quot; the Patria report stated.</p>
<p>Shares in CEZ have been particularly hard hit by the downturn in the Prague Stock Exchange's PX50 index which began in earnest in early September.</p>
<p>CEZ shares gained 11 crowns to 961 on Tuesday but were still nearly 26 percent below their 12-month high of 1,310.</p>
<p>Patria said CEZ's improved financial results had been built on the back of a 5.5 percent rise in electricity consumption in the Czech Republic combined with lower income taxes.</p>
<p>In view of the company's performance, Patria said it belived CEZ could afford to push through its plan to pay its first ever dividend on 1996 profits.</p>
<p>&quot;From the cash flow point of view, we believe that CZK 35 per share would be affordable. This represents a 3.7 percent dividend yield.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Robin Shepherd, Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
