<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="230850" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian opposition unites against Milosevic.</title>
<headline>Serbian opposition unites against Milosevic.</headline>
<byline>Donald Forbes</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Serbia's President Slobodan Milosevic may prove again to be the houdini of Balkan politics, but the fierce reaction over accusations of socialist election rigging could this time have damaged his image beyond repair.</p>
<p>Never a man to be underestimated, the 55-year-old former communist lawyer and banker has been on the ropes before and bounced back stronger than ever.</p>
<p>But the embattled Milosevic has united a broad spectrum of opposition to his nine years in power since the ruling socialists tore up opposition election victories in Belgrade and other cities last month.</p>
<p>Students and the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition are fielding up to 100,000 protesters a day at demonstrations in Belgrade while the United States and its allies have warned Milosevic not to defend himself with force.</p>
<p>Supreme court judges are protesting at being made a party to the cheating and Zajedno is taunting the president as &quot;the last Stalin&quot; and &quot;the last Tyrannosaurus.&quot;</p>
<p>Its leaders' claim that by proving the election fraud they have long suspected, they have changed the political landscape and prised open the first chinks in Milosevic's invincibility.</p>
<p>The president, rarely seen or heard in public, has remained characteristcally aloof during his biggest test since 1993.</p>
<p>His only appearance was during the rerun of the vote in Belgrade when television showed him grimly casting one of the ballots that preserved socialist control of the capital.</p>
<p>The socialists and the state-controlled media have been working overtime however in a battle with the Zajedno for the support of Serbia's &quot;silent majority&quot;.</p>
<p>The government media accused the opposition of fomenting violence, after one of its leader called for terrorism, although Zajedno and the students have deployed heavy security to keep their hotheads under control.</p>
<p>A threat by Milosevic to use the police to quell the unrest turned out to be another blunder when the United States said it would react with outrage. Britain and France called for respect for the right to demonstrate peacefully.</p>
<p>The socialists' mishandling of the crisis has been a puzzle from the start, given that they organised the elections and dominated the counting of votes.</p>
<p>Opposition monitors quickly sniffed out fraud by socialist officials in Nis, Serbia's second city, as Zajedno sensed that it was winning there and in other towns including Belgrade.</p>
<p>In most places the rigging was covert but in Belgrade it was breathtakingly blatant.</p>
<p>The socialists at first recognised the opposition had won an overwhelming victory for the first time in modern Serbian history. Then, as unfavourable results were annulled in provincial towns, they claimed to find unexplained &quot;irregularities&quot; in the capital as well and called a fresh vote that restored socialist control.</p>
<p>Milosevic has seen his claim to electoral legitimacy destroyed amid charges that multi-party democracy in Serbia is a sham that cloaks effective one-party rule.</p>
<p>Western countries have pressed the point with their ambassadors stressing the seriousness of the situation personally to the president and Serbian officials.</p>
<p>Some Western envoys say privately that economic sanctions should be restored unless the socialists recognise Zajedno's triumph.</p>
<p>The United States is not yet considering restoring sanctions that have been lifted but said on Monday it would maintain those still in place which deny Milosevic access to foreign credits he desperately needs.</p>
<p>Political sources believe sanctions could in any case prove a doubled edged sword that Milosevic would exploit in the state media as renewed international persecution of Serbs.</p>
<p>Serbia's economy -- and the living standards of ordinary people -- are still sunk under the effects of 3-1/2 years of U.N. trade and oil sanctions imposed during the Bosnian war.</p>
<p>With the weather deteriorating, Milosevic is counting on the demonstrations withering as protesters become cold and bored with little prospect of him yielding.</p>
<p>But even if it loses, the united opposition which in the past has been fragmented and quarrelsome has shown that it probably commands a majority in Serbia's main cities.</p>
<p>With his electoral credibility in tatters, that may be Milosevic's biggest challenge in republican elections next year which he intended to seal him in power for a decade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
