<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231081" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan says &quot;very delighted&quot; by U.S. missile deal.</title>
<headline>Taiwan says &quot;very delighted&quot; by U.S. missile deal.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan said on Tuesday it welcomed a U.S. move to award a missile contract to the island, hailing the deal as part of Washington's efforts to maintain peace between the island and its giant neighbour, China.</p>
<p>&quot;The foreign ministry is very delighted about the contract,&quot; state-run Central News Agency quoted foreign ministry spokesman Peter Cheng as saying.</p>
<p>The U.S. Army announced without elaboration that it had awarded the US$63 million contract to Boeing Defence and Space Group, Missiles and Space Division, in Huntsville, Alabama, to produce 74 Avenger fire units for Taiwan.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe the United States wants to maintain the stability across the Taiwan Strait, so it provided us with defensive weapons,&quot; Cheng said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's military has kept a low-profile over the deal in an apparent attempt to prevent feared protests from rival China.</p>
<p>&quot;It is inappropriate to discuss any aspects of military deployment, such as the use of military personnel or artillery,&quot; spokesman Kung Fan-ting told reporters.</p>
<p>Taiwan and China have been rivals since the Nationalist government lost the Chinese civil war to the communists and fled into exile to Taiwan in 1949.</p>
<p>Since then, Beijing has regarded Taiwan as a renegade province not entitled to foreign ties and vows to retake the island by force if Taipei opts for independence.</p>
<p>The Army's announcement on the weapons came just days before a relations-mending trip to Washington by a delegation headed by Chinese Defence Minister Chi Haotian.</p>
<p>General Chi and a 20-member senior delegation from China's defence and foreign ministries is due to arrive in the United States on Thursday for a two-week visit at the invitation of Defence Secretary William Perry.</p>
<p>The Avenger is a mobile anti-aircraft defence missile system that can launch eight Stinger missiles from two reloadable pods.</p>
<p>The U.S. Defence Department approved the Taiwan sale last summer, despite a warning from China's foreign ministry that it would cause &quot;new damage&quot; to improving U.S.-China relations.</p>
<p>On August 25, the Defence Department notified Congress of plans to sell Taiwan 1,299 Stinger missiles, launchers and other equipment, despite China's protest.</p>
<p>Despite switching diplomatic recognition to Beijing from Taipei in 1979, Washington reserves the right to provide Taiwan with defensive weapons.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Beijing carried out a series of war games in waters off Taiwan intended to intimidate voters in the run-up to Taiwan's first-ever direct presidential election.</p>
<p>Taiwan also planned to buy 68 batteries of French Mistral missiles, but the deal has not yet been finalised, state-funded television reported.</p>
<p>Officials here said the Mistrals could theoretically work with the Avenger units with a small modification.</p>
<p>China strongly objects to military links between the island and foreign countries.</p>
<p>Taiwan has said the Avenger units and the Patriot anti-missile system, bought from U.S. defence giant Raytheon Co, would enter service in 1999, boosting the island's defences against China.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I3640026">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C331">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
