<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231118" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Burmese exiles predict more student protests.</title>
<headline>Burmese exiles predict more student protests.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Exiled Burmese students called on the country's military rulers on Tuesday to respect human rights and introduce democratic reform or face further demonstrations.</p>
<p>The All Burma Students' Democratic Front (ABSDF), formed in Thailand in 1988 after pro-democracy protesters fled a military crackdown, was commenting on student demonstrations in Rangoon which broke out on Monday.</p>
<p>The ruling State Law and Order Restoration Council (SLORC) said it had briefly detained 300 students on Tuesday but released them after checking their identification.</p>
<p>&quot;If the SLORC refuses to respect democratic rights and solve underlying problems correctly, they will be damaging themselves as this will result in further demonstrations rather than the aim of peaceful and stable education of the students,&quot; the ABSDF said in a statement.</p>
<p>It was not clear whether the ABSDF had links to the student protesters in Rangoon.</p>
<p>Students from the Yangon (Rangoon) Institute of Technology had been protesting against what they termed unfair police handling of a brawl between their colleagues and some restaurant owners on October 20.</p>
<p>The ABSDF also called on the SLORC to open talks with pro-democracy leader and Nobel Peace laureate Aung Sang Suu Kyi and Burmese ethnic groups to solve the country's social, political and economic problems.</p>
<p>&quot;The ABSDF strongly supports the movement of the students and demands that the military regime...enter tripartite dialogue with democratic forces led by Daw Aung San Suu Kyi and ethnic nationalities as a very first step,&quot; said the group.</p>
<p>The United States and some other Western countries have accused the SLORC of widespread human rights abuses, attacked a recent crackdown on the pro-democracy movement and accused it of involvement in the heroin trade.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
