<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231191" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Three ex-ADM executives charged with price-fixing.</title>
<headline>Three ex-ADM executives charged with price-fixing.</headline>
<byline>James Vicini</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal grand jury in Chicago Tuesday indicted three former top Archer Daniels Midland Co. executives for conspiring to fix prices of the feed additive lysine, the Justice Department announced.</p>
<p>It said the indictment named Michael Andreas, the former executive vice president and son of ADM's powerful chairman, Dwayne Andreas; former Vice President Terrance Wilson, who headed the corn-processing unit; and Mark Whitacre, a fired ADM executive who had been an FBI informant in the case.</p>
<p>ADM, a Decatur, Ill.-based agricultural products giant, issued a terse statement, &quot;Respecting that the issues will now, finally, be aired in a court of law, we will continue to refrain from comment until the judicial process is complete.&quot;</p>
<p>Whitacre, who acted as an informant for three years and secretly taped company meetings as part of the price-fixing investigation, said he no longer was cooperating.</p>
<p>&quot;I have decided not to participate in the government's cover-up any longer,&quot; said Whitacre, who had been president of ADM's BioProducts division.</p>
<p>Asked to comment on the indictment against him, Whitacre said, &quot;I have no comment other than when all the evidence comes out in this case, the only people that will have questions yet to answer will be the Justice Department and the FBI itself.&quot;</p>
<p>Whitacre was fired by ADM in August 1995 after being accused of stealing $9 million from the company. He has denied the charges and recently filed a wrongful dismissal lawsuit against ADM.</p>
<p>The Justice Department also said Cheil Jedang Ltd., based in Seoul, South Korea, agreed to plead guilty and pay a $1.25 million fine for participating in the worldwide conspiracy to fix prices of lysine, a feed additive for livestock.</p>
<p>Besides the three former ADM executives, the Justice Department said the grand jury also indicted Kazutoshi Yamada, a managing director of Ajinomoto Co. Inc. The Japanese company previously entered a guilty plea in the case.</p>
<p>In October, Archer Daniels Midland pleaded guilty to two counts of federal charges of price-fixing in the sale of agricultural products and was sentenced to pay a record $100 million fine.</p>
<p>The indictment of ADM's former executives had been expected since then, when Andreas took a leave of absence and Wilson retired.</p>
<p>The Justice Department said its antitrust investigation into the lysine, citric acid and high-fructose corn syrup markets continues.</p>
<p>&quot;These charges should signal to business executives, both at home and abroad, that we will vigorously pursue individuals involved in international cartels, wherever they are,&quot; Acting Assistant Attorney General Joel Klein said in a statement.</p>
<p>The indictment charged that the defendants conspired with ADM, three previously charged companies and other unnamed corporate and individual co-conspirators to suppress competition in the worldwide lysine market, a $600 million-a-year industry.</p>
<p>The indictment charged the defendants with fixing prices and allocating sales volumes for three years, starting in June 1992.</p>
<p>The Justice Department said the indictment specifically charged the defendants and co-conspirators:</p>
<p>-- agreed to charge lysine prices at agreed-upon levels and to increase those prices accordingly.</p>
<p>-- agreed to allocate among the companies the volume of lysine to be sold by each firm.</p>
<p>-- issued price announcements and price quotations in accordance with the agreements.</p>
<p>-- participated in meetings and conversations for the purpose of monitoring and enforcing adherence to the agreed-upon prices and sales volumes.</p>
<p>Besides ADM, Ajinomoto and Cheil Jedang, other companies that agreed to plead guilty and cooperate in the probe have been Kyowa Hakko Kogyo Co. Ltd. and Sewon America, a unit of the South Korean-based Sewon Co. Ltd.</p>
<p>The individuals who were indicted Tuesday face a maximum prison term of three years if convicted. In addition, they face possible fines. The next step in the case will be an arraignment in federal court in Chicago.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
