<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231131" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia clears Belo's trip to accept Nobel prize.</title>
<headline>Indonesia clears Belo's trip to accept Nobel prize.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian Foreign Minister Ali Alatas said on Tuesday that East Timorese Nobel Peace laureate Bishop Carlos Belo was free to travel to Norway next week to receive his award.</p>
<p>The official Antara news agency quoted Alatas as saying the government would not raise any objections to Belo's travels.</p>
<p>Alatas said Belo would also visit the Vatican to call on the Pope and meet German Chancellor Helmut Kohl in Bonn after the award ceremony in Oslo.</p>
<p>Belo was jointly awarded the 1996 Nobel Peace Prize with self-exiled East Timorese resistance leader Jose Ramos-Horta.</p>
<p>&quot;Bishop Belo has sent a letter to me as foreign minister to tell of his plans to travel to Oslo, Stockholm and the Vatican, including his meeting with Chancellor Kohl in Bonn,&quot; Alatas was quoted by Antara as saying.</p>
<p>He said the government had no objections.</p>
<p>Last month, Alatas warned the sometimes outspoken Belo against meddling in politics after controversy over an interview in which he reportedly said Indonesian troops treated East Timorese like &quot;scabby dogs&quot; and &quot;slaves&quot;.</p>
<p>Belo later gave a news conference in the East Timor capital Dili where he denied using the word &quot;scabby&quot; in the interview with the Der Spiegel magazine, which was published in October after his peace prize was announced.</p>
<p>The correspondent who conducted the interview has stood by his story.</p>
<p>The bishop is highly regarded by East Timorese, who gathered in their thousands to show their support when he returned to the territory after facing demonstrations against his comments in Der Spiegel while visiting Jakarta last month.</p>
<p>Indonesia still faces opposition to its rule in the former Portuguese colony of East Timor which it invaded almost 21 years ago this week and unilaterally annexed in July 1976.</p>
<p>Jakarta's declaration of East Timor as its 27th province has never been recognised by the United Nations, which still regards Portugal as the administering power.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
