<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231268" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. junk corporates rise on new issue lull.</title>
<headline>U.S. junk corporates rise on new issue lull.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prices across the high-yield market rose 1/2 to one point on Tuesday, as a lull in the pace of junk bond issuance forced investors with large cash positions to look to the secondary market as a place for investments, traders said.</p>
<p>In the investment-grade market, International Business Machines Corp made a splash by selling $850 million in 100-year debentures in a deal that caught the market by surprise.  </p>
<p>The deal, which was underwritten by Salomon Brothers Inc, was increased from $500 million as a result of strong investor demand, sydnicate officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;IBM has been very prudent in their debt issuance in recent years. They seem to have knack for selling bonds as rates near their historic lows,&quot; said Edward Oppedisano, research analyst at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>Oppedisano noted IBM last hit the U.S. market with a large debt deal last October when rates were also relatively low. The offering consisted of $750 million of 30- and 50-year bonds, he said.  </p>
<p>In the junk market, despite strong demand by investors which drove up bids, traders said relatively few bondholders were willing to sell and volume remained low.</p>
<p>Traders said expectations for strong Christmas sales created particular demand for Kmart Corp bonds which have risen a total of three points over the past several days.</p>
<p>Kmart is often used as proxy for junk investors to express their sentiment about the retail sector becuase of the large size and liquidity of the company's $1 billion in outstanding high-yield bonds, traders noted.  </p>
<p>Prices on Penn Traffic's senior subordinated notes ended the day unchanged, after trading down four points in the morning. Earlier the company reported a third quarter net loss greater than a year ago.</p>
<p>The supermarket company's bonds recovered from its losses because the earnings had been largely anticipated, one trader said.</p>
<p>Overall, the junk market gave back about 1/8 of a point by the end of the day as a result of a late-day sell-off among stocks.  </p>
<p>In the high-grade market, Mellon Bank, which sold $500 million in preferred stock through a special business trust, was the only other issuer to hit the market with a large deal on Tuesday. Goldman Sachs &amp; Co lead-managed the transaction.</p>
<p>While issuance of trust preferred stock has hammered bank and finance sector bonds primarily, the new securities have also widened spreads among similarly-structured callable utility paper in recent weeks, traders said.</p>
<p>In fact, callable utility bonds were the only high-grade sector to end the day wider, traders noted. Prices in the rest of the high-grade market were unchanged relative to Treasuries on light trading volume, they said.</p>
<p>The sector was also hurt on Tuesday as investors swapped into more postively convex instruments in the face of a Treasury rally earlier in the day, traders said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury closed 101-25/32 to yield 6.37 percent, down 2/32 from yesterday's close.</p>
<p>Douglas Brown, 212-859-1662</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
