<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231354" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn ends mixed, new lows set in most months.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn ends mixed, new lows set in most months.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures closed mixed with nearby months lower on a slide in wheat futures and new contract lows were set in nearly all but the nearby December, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Wheat just pulled everything down today. We tried to rally but with the weakness in wheat we couldn't go anywhere,&quot; said Vic Lespinasse of Dean Witter Reynolds.</p>
<p>The new low for March is $2.62-1/4 a bushel, down from the previous low of $2.62-3/4 set on November 5.</p>
<p>Pressure also came from nearly ideal crop weather in South America, they said.</p>
<p>Lespinasse and others said the market Monday was hit by reports of excellent crop prospects in South America and spillover selling was in the market Tuesday.</p>
<p>The market especially took note of Argentine corn prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;The South American crop is coming along well, especially Argentine corn,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>Corn futures were underpinned by slow farmer selling and steady to firm cash basis markets.</p>
<p>Corn closed 2-3/4 cents per bushel lower to one cent higher, with December down 1-1/2 at $2.65 a bushel.  </p>
<p>Commercial buying underpinned the market with Cargill Inc, ADM Investor Services and Term Commodities each buying three million bushels of March, traders said.</p>
<p>But commercial bear spreading weighed on the nearbys and propped the back months.</p>
<p>Cargill Inc did two million March/December, ADM did 1.5 million March/December and Term Commodities did one million March/December, the traders said.</p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated at 65,000, below the 74,846 traded Monday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In corn options, Refco Inc sold 400 March $2.70 calls at 6-1/2 cents and Farmers Commodities Corp bought 400 March $3.00 calls at 1-1/4 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 18,000, above the 17,160 traded Monday.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
