<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231457" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Pause in dlr/mark rally seen refreshing.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Pause in dlr/mark rally seen refreshing.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A pause in the dollar's rally versus the mark will likely prove an opportunity for the U.S. currency to gather strength for fresh attacks on upside targets, chartists said.</p>
<p>After surging to 1.5590 marks on Monday in New York, the dollar hit a fresh 23-month high of 1.5735 marks overnight in Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;We've extended yesterday's rally already,&quot; said Scott Siller, a senior technical analyst at MCM CurrencyWatch. &quot;Usually when you get that second extension, you know it's time to cool off a little bit.&quot;  </p>
<p>The dollar lost steam Tuesday in New York, slipping to 1.5575/85 marks at 1400 EST/1900 GMT from 1.5635/45 at the open.</p>
<p>The U.S. currency, nevertheless, is expected to battle its way higher again.</p>
<p>MMS International technical analyst Ken Boyer said he expects the dollar over the next few weeks to reach 1.5830 marks, a high from December 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;We're definitely bullish and the target that is on the upside is 1.5830,&quot; Boyer said.  </p>
<p>For his part, Siller contended the dollar could test in the next week or two 1.5950 to 1.60 marks, which he termed a 19-month bull channel projection area.</p>
<p>Yet he warned the dollar might get a &quot;little toppy&quot; and pull back after reaching that area.</p>
<p>The U.S. unit also retreated Tuesday after its latest trek higher versus the Japanese unit. It traded at 113.25/35 yen at 1400 EST/1900 GMT, down from 114.08/18 at the open.</p>
<p>Boyer of MMS pegged dollar support at 113 yen and predicted the dollar may retest its 1996 high at 114.92 yen in the next few days.  </p>
<p>On Tuesday, the mark also weakened versus the Japanese currency, falling to about 72.60/70 yen in afternoon trade from 72.91/94 in early dealings.</p>
<p>Siller noted the weekly indicators show a lot of downside potential for mark/yen.</p>
<p>Siller sketched initial downside targets at 72.40 and 71.15 yen and warned that realizing these targets could mean a setback for dollar/yen also to 112.75 and 112.25, which he deemed respectively 50 percent and 62 percent retracements of the dollar move from 110.65 yen to 114.80.</p>
<p>-- Donna Sells 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
