<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231688" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Madrid stocks rocket amid rate cut, EMU hopes.</title>
<headline>Madrid stocks rocket amid rate cut, EMU hopes.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Madrid stocks rocketed to new highs in busy trade on Tuesday, fuelled by a heavy inflow of domestic funds from the bond market in a euphoric climate, dealers said.</p>
<p>The general index rose 5.70 points, 1.40 percent, to 411.42 and the Ibex added 73.68 points, 1.57 percent, to 4,757.18.</p>
<p>Spain's expected entry into EMU and an influx of funds from the debt market were supporting the rise, according to analysts.</p>
<p>They added that forecast lower money rates also helped, hence investors were focusing on motorways and some utilities.</p>
<p>Iberdrola rose 70 pesetas to 1,605 and Fenosa added 55 pesetas to 1,055. Motorways Acesa and Aumar were also up strongly.</p>
<p>Gas Natural was of the few to end lower after the government fixed a 26,000 peseta price for its oversubscribed 3.8 percent stake. The stock shed 120 pesetas to 26,380.</p>
<p>So far any chance of a correction was being ruled out by an overwhelming appetite for stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;One key factor is the reallocation of money from debt funds to equities,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>This may well sustain gains until the end of the year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
