<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231661" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Nagorno-Karabakh row almost wrecks Lisbon summit.</title>
<headline>Nagorno-Karabakh row almost wrecks Lisbon summit.</headline>
<byline>Timothy Heritage</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bitterness over a conflict in a remote corner of Europe almost wrecked the Lisbon security summit on Tuesday, forcing diplomats to revert to an unusual last-minute manoeuvre to avoid a major embarassment.</p>
<p>Disaster loomed as negotiations between Azerbaijan and Armenia over the disputed enclave of Nagorno-Karabakh hit a brick wall with no hint of a breakthrough in sight.</p>
<p>Forced into action by the threat of Azerbaijan vetoing the entire final summit declaration, international mediators agreed to drop all reference to the dispute from the closing document and issued a separate statement on it instead.</p>
<p>Armenian President Levon Ter-Petrosyan sat stony-faced at the final session of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) meeting. Azeri President Heydar Aliyev, who dropped his veto threat, hailed his success.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very satisfied,&quot; Aliyev told a news conference.</p>
<p>Ter-Petrosyan, by contrast, cancelled a planned news conference.</p>
<p>The conflict over Nagorno-Karabakh, a disputed enclave with an Armenian majority which is surrounded by Azeri territory, flared in the Cold War era.</p>
<p>It is also a reminder of the instability and security problems that still haunt many parts of the former Soviet Union and could threaten European security.</p>
<p>About 10,000 people were killed in fighting which flared in Nagorno-Karabakh in 1988. The clashes ended under a ceasefire signed in 1994 but up to one million refugees still live in tent camps.</p>
<p>Azerbaijan wanted its territorial integrity reaffirmed in the final summit statement. It also sought support for demands to define Nagorno-Karabakh's legal status clearly, based on the right to self-determination, and guarantees over its security.</p>
<p>Armenia blocked Azerbaijan's demands, earning the wrath of other states at the closing session, including Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;I regret that one delegation could not accept this. These principles have the support of all other participating states,&quot; said Swiss Foreign Minister Flavio Cotti, chairman in office of the OSCE.</p>
<p>Azerbaijan's demands were included in the separate statement drawn up to the indignation of Ter-Petrosyan.</p>
<p>He rejected Cotti's remarks, saying they did not correspond with the views of a group of 11 countries in the so-called Minsk Group set up to mediate over Nagorno-Karabakh. He has said &quot;unilateral solutions&quot; must not be imposed over the enclave.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to express concern in connection with this statement. In our view it does not reflect the spirit and the letter of the Minsk Group,&quot; Ter-Petrosyan said.</p>
<p>His comments made clear the leaders left Lisbon as far apart on Nagorno-Karabakh as when they arrived.</p>
<p>The OSCE agreed at its last summit, in Budapest in 1994, to prepare a multinational peacekeeping force for Nagorno-Karabakh but deployment cannot go ahead until the two sides agree full terms for peace.</p>
<p>&quot;You all know that no progress has been achieved in the last two years to resolve the Nagorno-Karabkah conflict,&quot; Cotti said.</p>
<p>Matters have been further complicated by tension over an election in Nagorno-Karabakh last month which Armenia acclaimed and Azerbaijan condemned.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARMEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="AZERB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
