<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231639" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-Elf, unions to negotiate on refinery strike.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Elf, unions to negotiate on refinery strike.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Tim  Hepher</p>
<p>France's biggest oil company was hit by a refinery strike for a sixth day on Tuesday amid signs that trade unions, bolstered by the triumph of truck drivers last week, were willing to spread conflict to other oil firms.</p>
<p>Managers and unions at oil giant Elf Aquitaine agreed to start negotiations from Thursday on a conflict over job cuts which has shut down all three Elf refineries in France. But it was unclear if the firm was willing to bend to increasing union demands.</p>
<p>Unions raised the stakes beyond demands for job security by calling on Monday for shorter hours and the right to retire at 55, saying they deserved the same benefits conceded to truck drivers to end a bitter 12-day strike last week.</p>
<p>It was the first sign of the knock-on effect from the truck strike and unions also warned of action, and possibly strikes, over planned lay-offs at Esso France, the country's fourth biggest refiner.</p>
<p>Prices for some grades of oil including gasoline (petrol) rose in Europe on Tuesday in response to the Elf strike, which affects three quarters of the company's European production. The strike has also budged gasoline prices as far away as New York.</p>
<p>Elf plans up to 300 layoffs at its French refineries and around 330 jobs are on the line at Esso, amounting to about 10 percent of local refinery staff at both companies.</p>
<p>An Elf company spokesman said the company had agreed in talks about talks with unions on Tuesday to hold concrete negotiations over pay and working conditions from Thursday.</p>
<p>But an agenda drawn up for Thursday made no mention of a key union demand that the plan to axe jobs should be cancelled.</p>
<p>Industry sources said Elf would be reluctant to talk about cancelling a plan which it believed necessary to knock its fragile refining operation into shape.</p>
<p>At Esso, a representative of the Socialist CFDT union, the country's largest, said protests had been slated for December 11-12 and could turn into a strike. Esso France, a subsidiary of Exxon Corp, announced its job cut plans last week.</p>
<p>The union said there were also tentative plans for protests over cost cuts at Shell France on December 6 but that these had yet to win the backing of all unions.</p>
<p>Separately, electricity and gas utility workers staged their own 24-hour strike on Tuesday over feared job losses. The strike was designed to coincide with talks in Brussels between European Union energy ministers.</p>
<p>Similar, if far more local, conflicts surfaced on Tuesday as well. Bus services in the Normandy city of Rouen and in Toulouse in the south were disrupted by transport workers pushing for shorter hours and a cut in the retirement age to 55.</p>
<p>Analysts doubt oil, power and transport workers have the power to strangle the economy as effectively as the truckers, who threw up strategic blockades at oil depots and on highways across the country.</p>
<p>In the wake of the truck drivers' victory last week, some economists said they would be watching closely for any knock-on effect on early retirement demands which could strain government finances further in the run-up to a single currency in 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
