<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231616" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Reform seen key to jobs, not Spain business tax cut.</title>
<headline>Reform seen key to jobs, not Spain business tax cut.</headline>
<byline>Sharman Esarey</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's plans to cut tax rates for small firms will hardly dent Europe's highest unemployment rate, and the government will still have to undertake unpopular labour market reform to create jobs, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>On Monday, Spain's minority Popular Party government said it would present an amendment to the budget that would cut the tax rate on businesses with receipts of less than 250 million pesetas a year at a cost of 20 billion pesetas to the Exchequer.</p>
<p>As of January, the firms will pay a 30-percent, rather than a 35-percent, tax rate on their initial 15 million pesetas of profit. The remainder will continue to be taxed at 35 percent.</p>
<p>In Spain, as elsewhere, small- and medium-sized business create the most jobs, and the six-month-old government has pledged it would bring down Spain's 22-percent unemployment rate next year, termed &quot;The Year of the Job.&quot;</p>
<p>The Association of Small- and Medium-sized businesses welcomed the tax cut, but analysts said it was too small to chip away at the mountain of jobless.</p>
<p>&quot;It looks good on paper,&quot; said Henrik Lumholdt, chief economist at Bank of America in Spain. &quot;But it's not a very big fiscal thing.&quot;</p>
<p>And the government will still have to tackle the political minefield of labour market reform, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The ugly truth is that the labour market reform is what will kick off job growth...It's very necessary but very unpopular with the electorate,&quot; Lumholdt said.</p>
<p>The government has so far given signs that it is eager to take up labour reform.</p>
<p>Reform talks between unions and employers are due to begin in the first few weeks of 1997, but Prime Minister Jose Maria Aznar has already said the government would intervene if the outcome was unsatisfactory.</p>
<p>Ros Lifton, senior HSBC international economist, also said the lower tax burden would only relieve pressure on profits. It would not ease pressure on labour-intensive companies like a reform of Spain's high cost of dismissals would.</p>
<p>Many companies have been reluctant to hire new workers because of high punitive costs of dismissing them if necessary.</p>
<p>As a result, employers have turned to temporary contracts. Nearly a third of the labour force works under such contracts, and the employment insecurity is considered a brake to consumer consumption and growth.</p>
<p>&quot;(The tax changes) don't get around labour reform,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
