<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231703" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy rates seen steady to mid-Dec despite lira.</title>
<headline>Italy rates seen steady to mid-Dec despite lira.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bank of Italy is mostly seen waiting until at least mid-December before trimming its official discount rate by 50 basis points, despite the lira's sharp rise against the mark, economists said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In a Reuter survey of 11 economists, five said they expected the key discount rate to fall before the year's end and three expected the central bank to wait until preliminary inflation data for December were released.</p>
<p>But several said a rate move at any moment would not be a surprise given the lira's recent strength following its return to Europe's exchange rate mechanism (ERM) just over a week ago.</p>
<p>Bond traders watching BTP futures and the lira soar to new highs on Tuesday also noted growing speculation the lira's strength versus the mark would prompt an easing soon.</p>
<p>The lira climbed to its firmest level against the mark since June 1994, peaking at 977.65, above its 990 ERM central parity.</p>
<p>The minimum rate at a Bank of Italy repurchase agreement (repo) operation earlier also fell to 7.35 percent, below the 7.50-percent discount rate and the 8.01 level seen at last week's operation.</p>
<p>However, analysts said the repo rate has not previously been used as a direct signal for a rate cut and doubted it was more than a medium-term indication.</p>
<p>Martino Dolfini at Chase Manhattan here expected the central bank to wait for December inflation data, which should be published by the 10 sample Italian cities around December 19.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank of Italy is prudent and is waiting to have a little more information behind it as far as the lira exchange rate in the ERM is concerned,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The lira has gone well recently, and I think the upward pressure will continue. But the Bank of Italy remains cautious and is waiting so that it doesn't extinguish the rise.&quot;</p>
<p>Marcello Pericoli at San Paolo bank in London said because the central bank did not cut after preliminary November price data last month, which indicated 2.6 percent inflation, there was no reason why it should do so with the final November figure due on Thursday.</p>
<p>In addition, &quot;the Bank of Italy won't want to cut before a metalworkers' contract,&quot; he said, referring to talks over renewal of engineering workers' contracts. Labour Minister Tiziano Treu has called a meeting with unions and employers on Thursday.</p>
<p>Instead, Pericoli said the central bank might also wait for approval of the 1997 budget. Voting on the measures is due to start in the full Senate upper house on December 10.</p>
<p>But Darren Williams at UBS in London said Italy's rates could drop any time from Thursday, after final November CPI.</p>
<p>&quot;Both previous cuts have come after the cities' CPI, but they have been linked to inflation. You could argue the ERM entry actually stopped them cutting rates after the last cities' CPI and now, it's far enough removed from ERM entry for them to cut,&quot; Williams said.</p>
<p>Bruno Rovelli at Bank of America here said an easing now was needed.</p>
<p>&quot;A reduction of the discount rate would serve to counterbalance the restrictive monetary policy of recent weeks, given that inflation has fallen and the lira has risen a lot in the last two weeks,&quot; Rovelli said.</p>
<p>Following are the results of the survey:</p>
<p>1 - When will the Bank of Italy next cut the discount rate?</p>
<p>    In first 10 days Dec			 3</p>
<p>    After prelim Dec CPI			 3</p>
<p>    By year end				    5</p>
<p>2 - By how much?</p>
<p>    50 bps					   7</p>
<p>    50-75 bps					2</p>
<p>    75 bps					   2</p>
<p>The following institutions took part in the survey: Banca di Roma, BCI, Banco di Sardegna, Bank of America, Credito Italiano, Chase Manhattan, Banque Indosuez, San Paolo, UBS, Paribas and HSBC.</p>
<p>--Milan bureau +392 66129507</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
