<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="231828" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka eyes wind to boost power supply.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka eyes wind to boost power supply.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka is planning to build wind power stations to increase electricity supply after drought caused a severe power shortage earlier this year, a senior state power utility official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We see potential to generate up to to 200 megawatts through wind power,&quot; Shavi Fernando, deputy general manager, generation planning at the Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) told Reuters.</p>
<p>Tenders for a three MW pilot wind power plant to be built in the southern Hambantota district with World Bank aid by mid-1997 will be called by year's end, he said.</p>
<p>The CEB has said it plans to invest up to $2 billion to build new power plants in the next decade and will rely heavily on coal for future energy needs. It is not known how much of that investment would be spent on wind power.</p>
<p>The wind power plants will be concentrated in the southeastern part of this Indian Ocean island to take advantage of the northeast and southwest monsoon.</p>
<p>A Tamil separatist rebellion in the island's northeast precludes setting up power stations in that region, CEB officials said.  </p>
<p>The island, which relies heavily on hydroelectricity, suffered severe power shortages this year after monsoon rains failed.</p>
<p>The government's 10-year plan will virtually double the present power generating capacity of about 1,250 MW -- 84 percent from hydroelectric plants and the balance from thermal plants.</p>
<p>The power crunch was attributed to delays in building new power plants to meet rising demand.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
