<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232115" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Former British minister to be Gibraltar governor.</title>
<headline>Former British minister to be Gibraltar governor.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>A former British Foreign Office minister was named on Tuesday as the next governor of Gibraltar, the tiny British colony on the south coast of Spain.</p>
<p>Sir Richard Luce will take up the job in February in succession to Sir Hugo White, who has been in the post for a year, the Foreign Office announced.</p>
<p>Britain and Spain have for years been at diplomatic loggerheads over Gibraltar, with Madrid claiming sovereignty over the rocky outcrop, but Britain insisting it can be handed over only with the consent of the pro-British population.</p>
<p>Luce was a junior Foreign Office minister between 1979 and 1985, and held other ministerial posts until 1990. He retired from parliament at the last general election in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;Sir Richard has a considerable amount of political and wider experience which he will be able to put to good use on behalf of the people of Gibraltar,&quot; a Foreign Office spokesman said.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources said White, a retired Vice-Admiral in Britain's Navy, was leaving Gibraltar for family reasons.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GIB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
