<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23217" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Seoul shares end higher on foreign ceiling hopes.</title>
<headline>Seoul shares end higher on foreign ceiling hopes.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares rose in the afternoon on the hope that there will soon be an announcement on the raising of the foreign shareholding limit, brokers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing on the market changed, but there was talk that the finance ministry would announce a higher ceiling after a meeting between the new finance minister and the president,&quot; said Ha Yong-hyun of Hyundai Securities.</p>
<p>Brokers said Finance Minister Han Seung-soo would meet with President Kim Young-sam later this afternoon to brief the president on new economic policies.</p>
<p>The composite stock index closed up 12.83 points to 766.18  </p>
<p>The Blue House and ministry spokesmen denied the minister was meeting with the president.</p>
<p>The foreign ownership ceiling is currently at 18 percent. The government has said it plans to allow foreign investors to buy up to 20 percent by the end of the year.</p>
<p>Advancing shares outpaced decliners 507 to 320, with blue chips and large-cap shares leading the way. Dacom climbed 6,500 won to a limit high of 122,500. POSCO gained 1,100 won to 47,900.</p>
<p>Brokers said the expectation of the ceiling boost outweighed any concerns about economic figures released this afternoon.  </p>
<p>August's consumer price index rose 5.3 percent against last year's 3.5 percent. The producer price index climbed 2.3 percent versus 4.6 percent, while July's industrial output was up eight percent against 15 percent last year.</p>
<p>Brokers said Friday's index movement would depend on whether an announcement about the foreign ceiling is made.</p>
<p>&quot;If there is good news, the index should climb. But if not, the index will probably head back down,&quot; Ha said.</p>
<p>The September futures contract climbed 1.50 points to 84.50, while the KOSPI 200 index gained 1.59 points to 82.50.</p>
<p>The index was later revised to 766.16, up 12.81.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
