<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232244" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Regional uncertainty to cut Lebanon growth - report.</title>
<headline>Regional uncertainty to cut Lebanon growth - report.</headline>
<byline>Haitham Haddadin</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lebanon's economic growth is expected to fall to four percent for 1996, half its 1995 level, partly due to a slowdown in capital inflows induced by regional political uncertainty, a leading Beirut bank said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This unfavourable development stems from several growth-restricting factors...namely, the slowdown in capital inflow induced by the existing unfavourable political uncertainty in the region....&quot; Fransabank said in its report for the third quarter.</p>
<p>Regional tension has risen since right-wing Israeli leader Benjamin Netanyahu ousted the moderate Shimon Peres as prime minister in May on a platform rejecting the principle of trading occupied Arab land for peace, the basis of stalled peace talks.</p>
<p>Central bank officials have said gross domestic product growth would fall to between four and 4.5 percent in 1996 from a forecast 7.5 percent, partly due to a 17-day Israeli blitz in April against pro-Iranian Hizbollah guerrillas based in Lebanon. Officials estimate the blitz caused $500 million in damage.</p>
<p>Fransabank cited other factors including relatively high Lebanese pound interest rates discouraging private sector borrowers, shrinking consumer spending due to high inflation -- 10 percent per annum -- and increased use of deferred payments in daily transactions.</p>
<p>&quot;Lower consumption spending, higher public indebtedness, higher unemployment, and the shortage in domestic financing needed for reconstruction could well contribute to this slower growth rate,&quot; Fransabank added.</p>
<p>But it said the economic cycle recovered during the third quarter after slowing in the first and second quarters.</p>
<p>&quot;Aggregate economic activity was better off during Q3, 1996 owing to the fact that all influential economic sectors have revived their recovery and growth. Industry, construction, trade, banking, tourism, and transportation all recorded a better performance during the said quarter,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>It said capital inflows recovered in the third quarter, with eurobonds by several Lebanese banks contributing to this rise.</p>
<p>Lebanon posted a trade deficit of $1.694 billion in the third quarter, bringing the January-September total to $4.715 billion, but capital inflows offset the deficit and led to a balance of payments surplus of $287 million.</p>
<p>The bank said that despite the Israeli blitz, tourist activity recovered in the third quarter and the number of tourists exceeded 330,000 during that period.</p>
<p>Net public debt rose 10 percent to $9.585 billion in that quarter from $8.705 billion in the second quarter, it said.</p>
<p>This was due to a rise in debt interest payments and the fiscal deficit to 50.2 percent for the first nine months from a forecast deficit of 37.6 percent for the whole of 1996.</p>
<p>Fransabank said the &quot;ambitious&quot; shortfall of revenue to expenditure of 35.9 percent noted in the 1997 state budget could not be realised if public spending remained uncontrolled as in 1996 and previous years.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, the presumed cutdown in public spending for several major sectors...during 1997 could induce a further slowdown in aggregate economic activity,&quot; it added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
