<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232212" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: In Nazareth, Bible the best guide.</title>
<headline>In Nazareth, Bible the best guide.</headline>
<dateline>NAZARETH, Israel 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>For pilgrims, the Bible is the best tourbook to Nazareth.</p>
<p>&quot;Nazareth speaks to everyone whether or not they've been here and so does the Biblical landscape,&quot; said Miriam Feinberg-Vamosh, senior editor of Eretz, Israel's geographic magazine.</p>
<p>Here is a summary of key citations and the holy sites as they appear today:</p>
<p>-- THE ANNUNCIATION. The angel Gabriel, sent by God to Nazareth, tells the Virgin Mary she will bear the son of God (Luke 1:26-38).</p>
<p>This event, known to Christians as the Annunciation, is said to have taken place at one of two sites.</p>
<p>The Basilica of the Annunciation, completed in 1966, was built over a cave where according to Roman Catholic tradition the Annunciation occurred. It is erected on the remains of earlier churches.</p>
<p>The St Gabriel Greek Orthodox Church of the Annunciation is built over a well that according to apocryphal sources and another tradition Mary was drawing water when she received the word from Gabriel.</p>
<p>Spring water flows into a well at this church where pilgrims can still draw water.</p>
<p>-- THE PRECIPICE. The people of Nazareth, angry at Jesus, thrust him out of the city and lead him to the brow of a hill but he went his way (Luke 4:28-30).</p>
<p>According to legend, the hill is two kms (1.5 miles) outside of Nazareth. It is known also as the Mount of the Fright or in Hebrew as Har Hakfitza (the Mount of the Jump).</p>
<p>Nazareth plans to make this a major tourist site.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be a forest on the Mount of the Fright in the name of the Pope,&quot; said Sharif Sharif, head of antiquities and conservation for the Nazareth municipality.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAZARETH, Israel"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
