<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232374" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Belarus told by European leaders to clean up act.</title>
<headline>Belarus told by European leaders to clean up act.</headline>
<byline>Paul Mylrea</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Europe's biggest security organisation told Belarus President Alexander Lukashenko on Tuesday to bring back democracy without delay in the former Soviet republic and to respect his country's constitution.</p>
<p>In a rare and public rebuke to a participating member, the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) told Lukashenko to ensure the freedom of the media, re-establish full democratic procedures and start talking to the opposition.</p>
<p>&quot;(The OSCE) remains deeply concerned about the constitutional situation in Belarus,&quot; it said in a statement issued at a European security summit in Lisbon.</p>
<p>&quot;(It) urges the government of Belarus to take action without delay to respect its commitment to OSCE norms and principles.&quot;</p>
<p>The statement was issued by the foreign ministers of Hungary, Switzerland and Denmark -- the so-called &quot;troika&quot; which currently guides OSCE policy. The OSCE monitors human rights and democracy throughout Europe.</p>
<p>It said last month's referendum which Lukashenko used to give himself sweeping powers over parliament and the courts &quot;was conducted in contradiction with constitutional procedures and cannot be considered as legitimate&quot;.</p>
<p>Lukashenko, a former collective farm manager said by his foes to have dictatorial tendencies, has been trying to shut down parliament following his resounding referendum victory.</p>
<p>Tuesday's rebuke came after U.S. Vice President Al Gore, British Prime Minister John Major, Irish premier John Bruton, speaking for the European Union, and other leaders lined up to condemn what they see as an unconstitutional bid for power.</p>
<p>Poland, a neighbour of Belarus, added its voice to the chorus of criticism on Tuesday, saying that any country that wanted to be part of Europe had to respect democratic rules.</p>
<p>&quot;Human rights and fundamental freedoms have to be observed in Belarus...since common values are the prerequisite of a united Europe,&quot; Polish President Aleksander Kwasniewski said.</p>
<p>Western leaders are worried at the prospect of conflict in Belarus, a country at the strategic heart of Eastern Europe which inherited long-range nuclear missiles after the break-up of the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>But the Belarus leader shrugged off the barrage of criticism, bluntly telling the OSCE summit on Monday: &quot;It would be counterproductive to try to exert pressure on us or try to interfere in our internal affairs.&quot;</p>
<p>Lukashenko also denied there was a political crisis in Belarus, accusing the United States of double standards and telling the OSCE and neighbouring states not to meddle.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States is, of course, a great power but this does not give it the right to interfere in the affairs of another state,&quot; Lukashenko told a news conference.</p>
<p>Describing the referendum as totally legitimate, he said he was flattered by the attention of the leaders of Ukraine, Lithuania and Poland, who have been critical of his recent actions, but added sarcastically: &quot;I think there are enough problems in their own countries to deal with.&quot;</p>
<p>Belarus's only remaining major ally is Russia, with which the economically struggling country of 10 million is seeking closer integration five years after the Soviet Union's collapse.</p>
<p>So far the OSCE has not threatened to suspend Belarus from the security forum as it did with Yugoslavia in 1992 in punishment for its role in the Balkan War.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
