<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232342" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Convicted S&amp;L chief Keating to get new trial.</title>
<headline>Convicted S&amp;L chief Keating to get new trial.</headline>
<byline>Andrea Orr</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-12-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>A federal judge on Monday ordered a new trial for Charles Keating, the bank chief whose name became synonymous with America's savings and loan collapse of the 1980s.</p>
<p>Judge Mariana Pfaelzer's ruling came after Keating's lawyers argued some jurors who found him guilty of fraud and racketeering three years ago had been aware of a previous state court conviction and as such their verdict was tainted.</p>
<p>She did not set a date for a new federal trial but scheduled a Jan. 16 status hearing to decide on a trial date.</p>
<p>Keating became a symbol of the Reagan-era savings and loan crisis when his Lincoln Savings and Loan declared bankruptcy in 1989. The collapse had a domino effect on America's savings industry, as hundreds of other institutions went bankrupt.</p>
<p>Lincoln's collapse cost U.S. taxpayers $2.6 billion, making it one of the costliest in U.S. history.</p>
<p>Prosecutors portrayed him and his son Charles Keating III as greedy men who arranged phony land deals and bilked elderly investors out of millions of dollars in savings.</p>
<p>Judge Pfaelzer will rule later this week on whether Keating's son will get a new trial.</p>
<p>The elder Keating was freed on $300,000 bail in October from a prison in Tucson, Arizona, where he was serving a 12-year sentence for 73 counts of federal securities and wire fraud from his 1993 conviction.</p>
<p>Two years earlier he had been convicted in California state court on 17 counts of defrauding investors. That state conviction has also been tossed out and a new trial ordered after the judge -- O.J. Simpson criminal trial judge Lance Ito -- was ruled to have given improper instructions.</p>
<p>Keating, who remains free on bail, looked relieved when the ruling was announced. Asked outside the court by reporters if he was happy, Keating grinned and said: &quot;Do I look sad.?&quot;</p>
<p>During arguments on Monday, Keating's lawyer Stephen Neal said at least four jurors and two alternate jurors at the 1993 federal trial were aware of the prior state court conviction and another juror learned about it from news reports.</p>
<p>That amounted, he said, to &quot;indisputable, incurable prejudice.&quot;</p>
<p>Outside the courthouse, Neal was asked about the thousands of people who lost money investing in Lincoln. They were irrelevant to the case, he said. &quot;The notoriety of the defendant and public venom toward him should not be an occasion to ignore applicable legal standards,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
