<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232431" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Health workers march against cuts in Bonn.</title>
<headline>Health workers march against cuts in Bonn.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Around 10,000 banner-waving health workers marched on Bonn's health ministry on Tuesday to protest against cuts in Germany's insurance system which they said would cost up to 100,000 jobs.</p>
<p>Physiotherapists, masseurs and home nurses were objecting to a government bill which would leave it to health insurers to decide if they would pay for a range of &quot;optional&quot; treatments, mostly involving home care and rehabilitation.</p>
<p>The bill, the so-called third stage health reform, also provides for patients to pay a higher share of their own health costs in a bid to stem abuse and cut the spiralling costs of the German system, one of the world's most comprehensive.</p>
<p>&quot;The level of health care in Germany can only be maintained by higher patient contributions to medicines and treatments, at a level which is compatible with social welfare,&quot; Health Minister Horst Seehofer told a conference in Koenigswinter near Bonn.</p>
<p>He also said claims for treatments and therapies were rising at a rate that bore no relation to medical needs.</p>
<p>&quot;We can no longer afford to have the health system pay for everything from help with marital crises to school problems,&quot; he said. &quot;It's time patients stopped expecting so much of the health system and started taking more responsibility for themselves.&quot;</p>
<p>Demonstrators in Bonn carried banners reading &quot;Enough is enough&quot; and &quot;Seehofer -- executioner of the disabled, henchman of the drug industry&quot;. One carried a model of a skeleton bearing the slogan &quot;Health reform -- fourth stage&quot;.</p>
<p>The protesters were planning to hand in a petition of 1.2 million signatures opposing the health reform at Seehofer's ministry.</p>
<p>They included not only health professionals but also representatives of self-help groups for rheumatism and multiple sclerosis who fear that essential home care for sufferers will no longer be paid for.</p>
<p>Welfare groups including the German Red Cross and union- and church-based charities issued a statement calling on the government to step in to prevent the elderly and the chronically ill losing their right to preventative care and rehabilitation.</p>
<p>&quot;The state must not simply cast off its responsibility for the quality and extent of health care provisions,&quot; the groups said. &quot;The long-term consequences for society as a whole will be higher than the short-term savings of the health insurers.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
