<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232457" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Eurotunnel up sharply on safety hearing.</title>
<headline>Eurotunnel up sharply on safety hearing.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Channel tunnel operator Eurotunnel SA/Plc were up sharply on the Paris bourse at midday as dealers who had heavily shorted the stock covered positions ahead of an expected reopening of the tunnel to passenger traffic, dealers said.</p>
<p>At 1255 GMT the share was up 4.44 percent at 7.05 francs after earlier falling as low as 6.80 francs.</p>
<p>&quot;There's a meeting with the safety authorities, they're supposed to say something later today,&quot; one trader said.  </p>
<p>A key committee in charge of safety in the tunnel was to meet in London on Tuesday and was expected to make a recommendation to the Inter-governmental Commission (IGC) on whether to re-open the link for passengers, a French safety official said on Monday.</p>
<p>The Channel Tunnel safety authority will convene under the chairmanship of French official Roger Lejuez after having held talks with Eurotunnel, the official said.</p>
<p>The IGC, on the basis of the safety report and results of an evacuation drill last Sunday, will decide on resumption of passenger services.</p>
<p>Only a partial freight rail service is permitted through the Tunnel since a fire two weeks ago injured 34 people and seriously damaged a section of the fixed link.</p>
<p>Eurotunnel staged a drill on Sunday in which around 650 people were evacuated from a train in the Tunnel, walking through the central service tunnel and then taking a train in the adjacant rail tunnel. The exercise took two hours and 20 minutes.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5452</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
