<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232438" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German railway to invest 81 bln dmk in next 5 yrs.</title>
<headline>German railway to invest 81 bln dmk in next 5 yrs.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The German railway, Deutsche Bahn AG, said on Tuesday its supervisory board had approved plans to invest a total of 81 billion marks ($51.8 billion) in the five-year period 1997 through 2001.</p>
<p>Some 49 billion marks will be invested in infrastructure and 32 billion marks in rolling stock, stations, equipment and above all information technology, the railway said in a statement.  </p>
<p>German railway to invest 81 bln dmk in next 5 yrs</p>
<p>State-owned Deutsche Bahn, which has been transformed into a shareholding company in preparation for its eventual privatisation, said it expected to exceed revenue of 30 billion marks for the first time in 1996 while profit should be slightly above the year-earlier level.</p>
<p>In 1995, the railway made a group pre-tax profit of 550 million marks on sales of 29.5 billion marks.</p>
<p>Revenues from passenger rail traffic were slightly above 1995 while freight revenues were slightly down due to smaller transport volumes for coal, ore and steel, Deutsche Bahn said.</p>
<p>Under plans for the railway's privatisation, Deutsche Bahn is to be split into four separate shareholding companies from January 1, 1999, covering intercity passenger transport, local rail services, freight transport and track.</p>
<p>Deutsche Bahn AG will become the holding company for those companies, the statement said.</p>
<p>A freight transport rail company, DB Cargo GmbH, will be set up in the first quarter of 1997 and Deutsche Bahn also plans to combine its rail electricity activities in a new company, DBEnergieversorgung GmbH &amp; Co KG, to be formed on January 1.</p>
<p>DBEnergie will have annual sales of 1.8 billion marks and employ some 530 people.</p>
<p>--David Crossland, Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
