<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232565" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EMU budget pact nears agreement as Bonn rows back.</title>
<headline>EMU budget pact nears agreement as Bonn rows back.</headline>
<byline>Henry Engler</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>It seems a foregone conclusion that the European Union will agree a budget pact that reins in expenditure among nations joining a common currency. The question is at what cost to the EU and its cherished project.</p>
<p>EU finance ministers, unable to settle their differences over a disciplinary budget pact on Monday, have raised expectations that a deal will be struck when they try again on December 12 ahead of a summit of EU leaders in Dublin.</p>
<p>Failure to agree after coming so close would be costly, both in terms of perceptions about the political resolve behind economic and monetary union (EMU) and the negative fallout in financial markets which have bet heavily that a single currency will start on time in 1999.</p>
<p>Germany, virtually alone among its 14 EU partners in arguing for stringent conditions, appeared to soften its stance slightly on Monday, a sign that experts said could ultimately have an impact on the credibility of the single currency, the euro.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it makes it look as though the euro is going to go ahead and the Germans will be fairly compliant,&quot; says David Marsh, European Adviser at Robert Fleming, an investment firm in London.</p>
<p>&quot;They will bend over a fair way towards French and others' demands and the euro may be a bit weaker than they like.&quot;</p>
<p>Most importantly, Bonn opened the door slightly on one key area where agreement is still outstanding -- the definition of exceptional circumstances which would permit governments with excessive deficits to avoid fines.</p>
<p>Germany had come to Brussels seeking a very tough definition of an economic downturn which would allow a country to let its budget deficit exceed the set maximum of three percent of gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>While Bonn's political weight cannot be underestimated and a final deal could still be delayed until next year, tensions have grown within the bloc over an overzealous German obsession with monetary and budgetary rigour.</p>
<p>Against a backdrop of high unemployment, this criticism has resonated most loudly in France, where some senior monetary authorities and former politicians recently questioned the wisdom of too close links with German economic policies.</p>
<p>Whether signs of dissent played a role in Bonn's more open bargaining posture is unclear. What does appear certain, however, is that Europe's economic giant must be willing to compromise if EMU is to go ahead as planned.</p>
<p>That may be a less than welcome to the German public, already worried about a monetary union that might include nations with a history of less than reliable economic and political stability.</p>
<p>&quot;In the end, Germany will have to make concessions,&quot; says Ralph Sueppel, head of research at J.P. Morgan in Frankfurt. But &quot;with every point that Germany gives, criticism of EMU mounts in Germany.&quot;</p>
<p>The job of quelling German uneasiness may ultimately fall in the lap of Chancellor Helmut Kohl.</p>
<p>EU diplomats on Tuesday said part of the reason an agreement was not reached among the EU ministers is German Finance Minister Theo Waigel's decision to seek guidance from Kohl and French President Jacques Chirac who meet next week.</p>
<p>Waigel apparently told his colleagues that such direction, followed by a meeting of the EU's Monetary Committee on December 10, would give them a better chance of sorting out their differences just ahead of the EU summit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
