<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232516" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Dec 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Portugal -- Dec 3.</headline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are leading domestic stories in Portuguese newspapers.</p>
<p>PUBLICO</p>
<p>- European and North American leaders will announce steps to achieve peace in the 21st century at the end of a two-day summit of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) today.</p>
<p>- Portugal Telecom will offer detailed bills, which list the charges of all calls, to more than 500,000 customers in Lisbon and Oporto from this month.</p>
<p>DIARIO DE NOTICIAS</p>
<p>- Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa tells the paper in an interview that he believes that Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu must implement peace agreements already signed without delay in order to help secure peace in the Middle East. Moussa and Netanyahu visited Lisbon to attend the OSCE conference.</p>
<p>- Portugal's biggest car manufacturer, the Ford-Volkswagen AutoEuropa joint venture, will resume normal production tomorrow after a disruption caused by the 12-day French truckers' strike.</p>
<p>DIARIO ECONOMICO</p>
<p>- Portugal's biggest bank, state-owned Caixa Geral de Depositos, will be the strategic partner of a future pulp holding company, Economy Minister Augusto Mateus told the paper.</p>
<p>-- Lisbon newsroom +(351-1) 3538254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
