<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23274" id="root" date="1996-08-29" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea's July C/A deficit widens to $2.28 bln.</title>
<headline>S.Korea's July C/A deficit widens to $2.28 bln.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Korea's current account deficit expanded to $2.28 billion in July from a $534.3 million shortfall a year earlier, preliminary figures released by the central Bank of Korea (BOK) showed on Thursday.</p>
<p>				 July	     June	 July 1995</p>
<p>    Current account   -2,275.5	  -1,074.9	  -534.3</p>
<p>    Trade account     -1,662.5	    -499.7	  -117.2</p>
<p>    Exports (FOB)     10,311.8	  10,893.2	 10,604.0</p>
<p>    Imports (FOB)     11,974.3	  11,392.9	 10,721.2</p>
<p>    Invisible trade     -552.9	    -458.5	   -233.3</p>
<p>Note: figures are in millions of US dollars  </p>
<p>The current account deficit for the first seven months of this year nearly doubled to $11.66 billion from a shortfall of $6.50 billion a year earlier. This was the largest ever seven month deficit against the previous record shortfall of $6.67 billion in 1991.</p>
<p>A central bank statement said sluggish exports and a sharp rise in the invisible trade deficit were the main factors behind the increase in the current account deficit in July.</p>
<p>It said persistently falling prices of semiconductors and steel products in the world market contributed to slowing exports.  </p>
<p>A rise in imports of capital and consumer goods was also blamed for the widening trade deficit.</p>
<p>On a customs-cleared basis, exports fell by 3.6 percent in July year-on-year due to declining overseas shipments of automobiles and machinery and metal products.</p>
<p>A BOK official said exports fell in July for the first time this year.</p>
<p>Exports of heavy industrial goods dipped by 11.3 percent in July on the year, while those of light industrial products rose 9.1 percent.  </p>
<p>Exports rose 9.4 percent for the first seven months of this year compared with a 33.9 percent rise in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Imports rose by 13.6 percent year-on-year in July, much lower than the 35.6 percent rise a year earlier. They rose 11.8 percent in the first seven months over the same 1994 period when they rose 37.5 percent.</p>
<p>In line with facility expansion in the steel and telecom industries, purchases of foreign telecom equipment and machinery increased. Rising oil imports following expansion of domestic refinery facilities also contributed to rising imports.  </p>
<p>The BOK statement said imports of foreign-made cars, clothes and cosmestics continued to rise in July.</p>
<p>The rise in the invisible trade deficit was mainly due to an upsurge in overseas travel and transportation expenses.</p>
<p>The travel deficit rose to $342.5 million in July from $220.4 million a year earlier and $243.7 million in June, the figures show.</p>
<p>The seven-month invisible trade shortfal was a record $4.18 billion against a previous seven month record of $1.8 billion a year earlier.</p>
<p>Import licence issues, which show future import ends, rose 24.1 percent to $12.65 billion in July from a year earlier, compared with a 15.4 percent year-on-year growth in July, 1995.</p>
<p>Letters of credit received during July rose 3.8 percent to $6.18 billion against a 13.5 percent rise a year earlier.</p>
<p>The central bank said earlier the current account deficit would soar to $12 billion for the whole of 1996 but a senior BOK official told reporters the shortfall might exceed $15 billion.</p>
<p>South Korea's current account deficit totalled $8.95 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>--Seoul Newsroom (822) 727 5647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-29"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
