<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232792" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Burma says preparing to be ASEAN member next year.</title>
<headline>Burma says preparing to be ASEAN member next year.</headline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burmese Foreign Minister Ohn Gyaw on Tuesday expressed confidence his country would be ready to join the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) as a full member next year.</p>
<p>Ohn Gyaw told a news conference he was confident Rangoon would make sufficient progress between now and next July to become qualified as a member.</p>
<p>&quot;There are plenty of opportunities to catch up...we know there are different levels of development. Some are technically advanced and some are industrially advanced but whatever it is, there is determination and conviction to contribute to the region...,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Burma, along with Laos and Cambodia, has observer status in the seven-member ASEAN and wants to become a member by next year. ASEAN groups the Philippines, Thailand, Singapore, Malaysia, Indonesia, Brunei and Vietnam.</p>
<p>An announcement after a one-day informal ASEAN summit in Jakarta on Saturday said the group would admit Burma, Laos and Cambodia as full members at the same time, but it stopped short of saying when that would take place.</p>
<p>&quot;Definitely yes. We will be admitted simultaneously along with Laos and Cambodia,&quot; Ohn Gyaw said.</p>
<p>A fresh military crackdown since May on pro-democracy supporters of the National League for Democracy (NLD) of Nobel laureate Aung San Suu Kyi had earlier prompted Philippine and Thai leaders to express reservations about Burma's speedy membership in the grouping.</p>
<p>Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong had also said Burma, one of the poorest countries in the world, may not be ready economically to join ASEAN.</p>
<p>But Malaysia and Indonesia said that the internal conditions in any country seeking to become an ASEAN member should not be an inhibiting factor for such membership.</p>
<p>Burma's government said on Tuesday it had briefly held hundreds of students after they staged night-long street protests in Rangoon, the biggest such demonstrations in several years.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASEAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
