<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232877" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Amcol Holdings trial adjourned to Dec 23.</title>
<headline>Amcol Holdings trial adjourned to Dec 23.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>The court hearing for a trader and a former executive director of Singapore's troubled Amcol Holdings Ltd on Tuesday has been postponed until December 23, court sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The trial was scheduled to start in Singapore's Subordinate Court on Tuesday but the sources said it was given a new date, apparently because the parties were still preparing their cases.</p>
<p>Ng Chee Kheong, 41, and Tay Huay Hong, 49 were charged in October in the Singapore High Court with criminal conspiracy to cheat Amcol into investing US$39.6 million in a now aborted leisure and property development in Mauritius.</p>
<p>Both men pleaded not guilty to charges that carry penalties of up to seven years in jail and were released on bail of Singapore $500,000 (US$357,000).</p>
<p>Ng is accused of receiving a proposal in early April from Maurities businessman Roland Maurel, owner of Sando &amp; Cie, for Amcol to invest US$35.85 million for a 51 percent stake in a joint venture, Guibies Holdings Ltd.</p>
<p>Ng and Tay were alleged to have conspired with another ex-executive director, Lloyd Lochra, whose whereabouts are unknown, to mark up the investment cost of the Mauritius project by US$3.75 million from US$35.85 million.</p>
<p>The inflated amount was to be equally shared among them, according to the charges.</p>
<p>Its board of directors approved Amcol's purchase of 40 percent of the joint venture company for US$39.6 million.</p>
<p>The charge sheets said that in late June, US$300,000 was credited to an account in Banque Central Asia, Indonesia for Ng. They said identical amounts were credited to an account in Coutts &amp; Co, London for Tay, and into a Standard Chartered Bank account for Lochra.</p>
<p>Amcol has been under investigation by Singapore's Commercial Affairs Department regarding payments to various parties, including several former Amcol directors.</p>
<p>(US$1 = S$1.40)</p>
<p>rtr jw mb</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
