<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="232951" id="root" date="1996-12-03" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Dec 3.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Dec 3.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Manila newspapers on Tuesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- Leaders of the House of Representatives agreed on Monday to set aside partisanship for the urgent and common goal of averting a possible food shortage. (BULLETIN)</p>
<p>- The Commission on Elections on Monday shot down the probability of holding a plebiscite on the initiative to pursue Charter changes simultaneously with the barangay (village) elections in May 1997. (TODAY)</p>
<p>- Two bombs found last month at the Ninoy Aquino International Airport and at Subic Freeport, the site of the APEC summit, were real and not part of a security drill as the government claimed earlier, a defense official said. (STANDARD)</p>
<p>- Senate president Ernesto Maceda said he is willing to resign from his post and as senator if the government can prove that there is no irregularity in the alleged 120 billion peso land scam in the Public Estates Authority which he exposed last week. (PHILIPINE STAR)</p>
<p>- The Association of Southeast Asian Nations is becoming a regional institution that supports authoritarian governments with its decision to grant Burma full membership, the Alternative Asian Network on Burma said. (INQUIRER)</p>
<p>				 +++++++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>- The Energy Regulatory Board will raise petroleum prices within the week as it was given the go-signal by a member of the House of Representatives to adjust fuel prices without seeking the opinion of the Department of Justice on the legality of the oil price formula as well as the oil price hikes. (BUSINESSWORLD/BULLETIN/PHILIPPINE STAR/BUSINESS DAILY)</p>
<p>- The Department of Finance is gearing up for another tax restructuring challenge and this time it is drafting a comprehensive tax reform on financial markets. (BUSINESS DAILY)</p>
<p>- Business agreements during the four-day APEC meetings will exceed $5 billion involving 21 projects, Trade Minister Cesar Bautista said. (INQUIRER/BULLETIN/PHILIPPINE TIMES JOURNAL/STANDARD/STAR)</p>
<p>- Foreign investment firm Merrill Lynch warned that the Philippine economy could overheat if the government continued to push for a rapid growth in domestic production. (TODAY/CHRONICLE)</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8938 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-03"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
