<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233082" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Bre-X continues talks with Barrick.</title>
<headline>Bre-X continues talks with Barrick.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The chief executive of Bre-X Minerals Ltd said on Wednesday that his company was still negotiating the carving up of the Busang gold deposit in Indonesia with Barrick Gold Corp, despite reports the deal was sealed up.</p>
<p>A few issues remain to be solved, and Bre-X will have more news on the negotiations &quot;shortly,&quot; chief executive David Walsh said in an interview with Reuters from New York.</p>
<p>&quot;I understand that Dr. (Umar) Said (secretary general of Indonesia's mining department) was pleased with the progress that we've made, and he sympathized with our concerns,&quot; Walsh said.  </p>
<p>The Indonesian government had told Bre-X to carve up its stake in the huge Busang gold deposit on the island of Borneo. The government asked Bre-X to form a joint venture by December 4 with gold giant Barrick, with Barrick getting 75 percent of Bre-X's stake, and Bre-X keeping 25 percent.</p>
<p>Walsh said the companies had technically met the government's deadline by giving the Mines Ministry an update on their progress.</p>
<p>&quot;We've done our work and filed our documentation,&quot; he said. He would not comment on compensation or the structure of any deal.  </p>
<p>Earlier Wednesday, Umar cast some doubt on Bre-X's grasp on Busang, suggesting the Calgary-based company may not have followed proper procedures.</p>
<p>&quot;Why didn't they report to the government (on their find),&quot; Umar told Reuters in Jakarta.</p>
<p>Walsh said Bre-X may have made some mistakes in its early days working in Indonesia but everything has been straightened out now.</p>
<p>&quot;We may have not crossed all the T's and dotted all the I's, but it was not intentional,&quot; he said. &quot;We've put everything in order. Everything has been filed properly.&quot;  </p>
<p>Walsh would not say if he would prefer to work with Vancouver-based Placer Dome Inc, which said this week it wanted to have a chance to bid on Busang.</p>
<p>But he suggested comments from the Indonesian consulate in Ottawa this week may leave the door open to competitive bids.</p>
<p>&quot;I would prefer any way that maximizes shareholder value,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said threats of lawsuits from one of its Indonesian partners and the former owners of the Busang property do not carry any weight.</p>
<p>((Heather Scoffield, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8104))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
