<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233246" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends weaker, March near six-week low.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends weaker, March near six-week low.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended weaker for the fourth consecutive session Wednesday, as a round of fund long liquidation pushed prices to near six-week lows, market sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has not been doing well,&quot; one analyst said. &quot;And it is creating some liquidation.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers said commission house sell-stops were triggered below 104.50 cents a lb in the active March contract, but steady scale-down trade buying and roaster interest trimmed losses.</p>
<p>March coffee fell 0.90 cent a lb on the day, to close at 104.20 cents, it lowest settlement since October 25, after ranging narrowly between 105.80 and 103.80. Spot December futures finished down 1.50 cents, to 112.80, while the outer months ended 0.25 to 1.00 weaker.</p>
<p>The analyst also said a report by the International Coffee Organization showing October exports were way up could have pressured prices today.</p>
<p>The ICO reported Wednesday that exporting members' exports rose to 6.03 million 60-kg bags in October from 4.84 million in September and 5.22 million in October 1995.</p>
<p>From November 1995 to October 1996 total exports were 73.80 million bags, up from 65.29 million bags in the same year ago period, the ICO said.</p>
<p>But low levels of consumer coffee stocks going into the peak consumption period should continue to provide underlying support for the market, the analyst said. She said she expected the market to trade sideways until Late December or January when the flow of new-crop coffee from Central and South America may begin to build stockpiles.</p>
<p>On the charts, traders said March's next support level was seen at 103.00-102 .50, with strong psychological support at the 100.00-cent mark. Resistance was pegged at 107.50 cents.</p>
<p>Turnover reached an estimated 8,811 lots.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
