<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233298" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Treasuries range-bound after Beige Book.</title>
<headline>US Treasuries range-bound after Beige Book.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Treasuries remained mired in narrow ranges after the Federal Reserve released its Beige Book at midday on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond was off 3/32 to 101-22/32, its 6.37 percent yield unchanged from the opening.</p>
<p>&quot;People appear content with their views, content to stay long,&quot; said Chris Rupkey, vice president and economist at Bank of Tokyo/Mitsubishi.</p>
<p>The Beige Book, an account of business conditions around the nation, said the economy grew moderately in November.  </p>
<p>While the Beige Book characterized the labor market as tight, it saw no sign of accelerating wage pressures.</p>
<p>The bond market did not react to that friendly news.</p>
<p>Rupkey noted that despite Wednesday's narrow-ranged trade, the bond market had sold off about a point from Tuesday's intra-day high achieved after the government said October new single-family home sales fell sharply in October.</p>
<p>&quot;The market's tone is slightly negative,&quot; said Rupkey. &quot;If we can cut some of that selloff (from Tuesday intraday highs), it would put the market in a better technical position.&quot;  </p>
<p>To move higher, the market has to see the March futures contract get above 116-00, Rupkey said. In early afternoon trade, the March contract was down 8/32 to 115-24/32.</p>
<p>Rupkey also said the report of the Boskin panel on the Consumer Price Index had mostly been discounted.</p>
<p>As expected, the Boskin panel said U.S. inflation had been overstated by 1.1 percentage points per year. It said the bias in the Consumer Price Index (CPI) would add $148 billion to the federal budget deficit in 2006 if it were not fixed.</p>
<p>The Boskin Panel recommended that the Labor Department publish two prices indexes, one monthly and one annually.  </p>
<p>The Boskin panel said Congress and President Clinton should consider changes in indexing taxes and benefits.</p>
<p>The government's report that U.S. housing completions slipped 0.7 percent to an annualized rate of 1.360 units had no market impact.</p>
<p>&quot;It's kind of a neutral day,&quot; said Rupkey. &quot;If we can't get up above 116-00, we might see some people liquidate a few more bonds before three p.m. (1500 EST/2000 GMT),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Federal Reserve added temporary reserves to the banking system through overnight system repurchases.  </p>
<p>Three-month bill rates were up one basis point to 4.90 percent. Six-month and year-bill rates were unchanged at 4.99 percent and 5.10 percent, respectively.</p>
<p>The two-year note was unchanged at 100-1/32, yielding 5.61 percent. Five-year notes were down 1/32 to 100-3/32, yielding 5.85 percent. Ten-year notes were down 3/32 to 103-4/32, yielding 6.07 percent.</p>
<p>-- N.A. Treasury Desk, 212-859-1679</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
