<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233386" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: CRICKET-TUFNELL, CROFT FIGHT BACK AFTER HOUGHTON CENTURY.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-TUFNELL, CROFT FIGHT BACK AFTER HOUGHTON CENTURY.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Left-arm spinner Phil Tufnell and off-spinner Robert Croft snapped up six Mashonaland wickets in the last nine overs of the day to ease England's plight after they were punished by a sparkling century from David Houghton on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Tufnell and Croft sent the local side tumbling from 258 for three to 279 for nine at the close of the second day of the four-day match in reply to England's first innings of 197.</p>
<p>Mashonaland lead by 82 with one wicket left after Tufnell, who has taken four for 77, and Croft, with four for 65, brought the touring side back into contention.</p>
<p>Until the collapse, England's attack had been dominated by Zimbabwe coach Houghton, who struck 110. He was rarely troubled in a three-hour stay and brought up his century in majestic fashion by sweeping Tufnell over the square leg boundary for six.</p>
<p>He was finally removed by the same bowler, who took a return catch as the batsman pushed forward tiredly, to end a fourth-wicket partnership of 116 with Craig Wishart (45).</p>
<p>Houghton reached three figures from 136 balls, and made his 110 off 141 deliveries, hitting 14 fours and two sixes.</p>
<p>His departure started the Marshonaland collapse.</p>
<p>Croft removed the next four batsmen in 17 balls at a cost of only one run -- three of them to close catches -- and Tufnell continued to transform England's fortunes by having Bryan Strang lbw.</p>
<p>Zimbabwe captain Alistair Campbell earlier scored  55 before he was caught at slip off Tufnell, one of several decisions with which the batsmen or fielding side clearly disagreed.</p>
<p>Andy Caddick was again expensive (10-2-46-0) but Darren Gough bowled a fiery spell -- striking opener Stuart Carlisle on the helmet with one bouncer -- and Alan Mullally again bowled a probing line without success.</p>
<p>Croft's four-wicket haul added to his success with the bat. He finished with an unbeaten 80, easily England's highest score, as they extended the overnight 175 for nine to 197.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
