<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233399" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ABU DHABI: SOCCER-HONOURS EVEN ON FIRST DAY OF ASIAN CUP.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-HONOURS EVEN ON FIRST DAY OF ASIAN CUP.</headline>
<byline>Nadim Ladki</byline>
<dateline>ABU DHABI 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hosts the United Arab Emirates held fancied South Korea to a 1-1 draw and Kuwait left it late to salvage a point against Indonesia on the first day of the Asian Cup on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Indonesia, considered outsiders to qualify for the competition's second round, were two goals up with 17 minutes to go when their defence crumbled to the experienced Kuwaitis.</p>
<p>Indonesia's Widodo Purta stunned Kuwait after 20 minutes with a superb acrobatic overhead kick from 15 meters that rocketed into the top corner.</p>
<p>Man of the match Purta was instrumental in the second goal after 41 minutes when Kuwait keeper Khaled al-Fadhli found his shot too hot to handle and parried it into the path of Ronny Wabia who slotted the ball home from just inside the area.</p>
<p>Hani Saqer pulled one back for Kuwait, tapping in a rebound off the post in the 73rd minute. With six minutes to go Kuwait salvaged a point when Yousif al-Dakhi scored from the penalty spot after substitute Khaled Fairouz was brought down in the area.</p>
<p>In the opening game of the tournament, UAE came from a goal down and held on to earn a draw with South Korea, one of the favourites for the title.</p>
<p>Goalscorer Hwang Sun Hong could have won it for South Korea in injury time when, with only the goalkeeper to beat, he lobbed the ball just wide of the right hand post.</p>
<p>Hwang, running on to a delightful through ball from midfield, scored for South Korea in the ninth minute. He fired a left foot shot from just inside the penalty area into the bottom left corner of the UAE goal.</p>
<p>Hwang, whose speed and sharpness troubled the UAE defence throughout, could have had two more but for good saves from goalkeeper Muhsin Fairouz, the first from a clear header.</p>
<p>But as South Korea's domination began to become embarrassing, the UAE hit back through striker Khamis Saad.</p>
<p>Adel Ahmed turned well to beat Korea's Roh Sang Rae on the left flank before sending a harmless cross into the area.</p>
<p>The Korean defenders failed to clear, presenting Saad with time to control the ball in the goal area and he placed it in the right corner of Kim Byung Ji's goal.</p>
<p>UAE's Croat coach Tomislaw Ivic praised his players and hoped they would now build on the result. &quot;We played a positive game against a very strong team. We hope we could continue and improve,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>South Korea's Park Jong Hwan said his team's finishing was poor. &quot;We should have taken advantage of our many chances,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia, beaten finalists in 1992, play Thailand and former war foes Iraq and Iran meet on Thursday when Group B matches get under way.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ABDBI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
