<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233487" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN BONDS RALLY ENDS - FOR NOW.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN BONDS RALLY ENDS - FOR NOW.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian linear bonds slipped in line with Bunds on Wednesday to end a six-day bull run, but a consolidation phase in upcoming sessions can not hide that further price rises are in the works, dealers said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 2006 OLO closed with a yield of 5.77 percent against 5.72 percent on Tuesday. Bunds were affected by technicals and strong German third-quarter GDP data.</p>
<p>&quot;Today was a bit of an off-day but price levels stay high and the undertone is still very positive,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Others said the market was still well-bid and that the correction was necessary.  </p>
<p>Traders noted that apart from professional business, some end investors were also in the market, but merely to extend the duration of their portfolio.</p>
<p>One said he believed profittaking would remain strictly limited as most investors would wait for next year to cash in on sharply higher prices. &quot;Everybody has been served, so people will wait for next year,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Another said that the benchmark yield could still slip further to 5.65 percent in upcoming weeks.</p>
<p>Traders expected the 10-year yield premium over Bunds to remain stable around the current level of 11 basis points.  </p>
<p>One trader said that the low volume at Tuesday's exchange auction -- just 300 million francs compared to about 20 billion at previous auctions -- had helped keep the spread low.</p>
<p>-- Bert Lauwers, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6815, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
