<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233498" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Crackdown proposed against Bosnia war criminals.</title>
<headline>Crackdown proposed against Bosnia war criminals.</headline>
<byline>Lyndsay Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Major powers grappled on Wednesday with the best way to round up war criminals from the former Yugoslavia as momentum gathered for a crackdown.</p>
<p>The vast majority of the 75 indicted criminals remain at large one year after peace broke out, despite widespread evidence of genocide and other crimes against humanity.</p>
<p>But Carl Bildt, the international community's High Representative in Bosnia, said tougher action may now be needed if the old enemies continued to protect suspects.</p>
<p>&quot;We need to consider new measures if no action is taken by the parties themselves,&quot; Bildt said at the start of a major international conference to review the Bosnian peace process.</p>
<p>&quot;That would also include the ability to pick up those that the parties themselves refuse to hand over to the tribunal.&quot;</p>
<p>The London conference had to send a strong signal of resolve if it wanted to retain any credibility. &quot;Time is beginning to run out and so is the patience of the international community. The message from London on this must be clear,&quot; Bildt said.</p>
<p>The failure of the heavily-armed, 60,000-strong NATO-led peacekeeping force in Bosnia to arrest the dozens of indicted war criminals has exposed it to widespread criticism.</p>
<p>The Yugoslav tribunal, set up by the United Nations in 1993, has indicted over 70 Serbs, Croats and Moslems suspected of war crimes during the Bosnian conflict.</p>
<p>But it was just last week that it won some tangible results, when a Croat who took part in a massacre of Moslems was sentenced to 10 years in jail. It was the first such prosecution since the Nuremburg and Tokyo trials after World War Two.</p>
<p>The most prominent suspects indicted are Bosnian Serb leader Radovan Karadzic and his military chief General Ratko Mladic. Both remain at large.</p>
<p>Canada's Foreign Minister Lloyd Axworthy said no peace would last unless more criminals were punished -- and fast.</p>
<p>&quot;We need action, not words,&quot; Axworthy told the delegates. &quot;Without firm action on war crimes, reconciliation is doomed.&quot;</p>
<p>He said NATO and Bildt should join with the war crimes tribunal at The Hague &quot;to consider additional steps to further restrict the free movement of indicted persons.&quot;</p>
<p>More patrols, training of forces in the identification and detention of suspected war criminals and information campaigns would all make capture more likely, Axworthy said. He also suggested offering rewards for information that led to arrests.</p>
<p>&quot;Bosnian authorities must act decisively to remove all indicted persons from public and high-profile positions in their communities,&quot; he said. &quot;In cases where this does not happen, neither they, nor the organisations to which they belong, should be allowed to participate in activities involving the high representative or any other international organisation.&quot;</p>
<p>But Britain, host of the two-day talks, is wary of any plan for international peacekeepers to hunt down the suspects.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not sure it's fair to expect that to be the responsibility of the military force,&quot; Foreign Secretary Malcolm Rifkind said. &quot;The military force is there to carry out military tasks, it's there to prevent a resumption of the conflict.&quot;</p>
<p>While NATO should arrest criminals if the opportunity arose, Rifkind said this was tricky as suspects were often protected by their own people in areas to which NATO did not have access.</p>
<p>Bosnia's ambassador to the United Nations, Muhamed Sacirbey, said NATO could not claim it lacked the means for a manhunt.</p>
<p>&quot;You are in a position to do the job and you have the tools,&quot; he told reporters at the talks. &quot;This is not an issue of revenge but an issue of reconciliation, of justice.&quot;</p>
<p>Judges at the U.N. tribunal were also piqued, complaining they had been marginalised and saying it was &quot;regrettable&quot; they had been invited to the talks as an observer, not a participant.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
