<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233470" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: BUDAPEST UPTREND SEEN GOING ON WITH HEALTHY BREAKS.</title>
<headline>BUDAPEST UPTREND SEEN GOING ON WITH HEALTHY BREAKS.</headline>
<byline>Emese Bartha</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Budapest Stock Exchange is expected to continue its rise in the near future after setting two successive record highs, although the increase may be accompanied by minor but healthy consolidation, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We can expect some more rises, although this (increase) cannot continue without a break,&quot; said Balazs Bathory of Creditanstalt Securities. &quot;We'll surely face some consolidation in one day or two, but the overall sentiment is very positive.&quot;</p>
<p>On Tuesday the BUX index gained 46.31 points, joining a number of European bourses which set new highs.</p>
<p>Meanwhile on Wednesday when several major markets come off their highs the Budapest market continued its own way upwards to set the second successive high at 3,789.22 points, up 28.23.</p>
<p>Traders cited the dollar's strength as the main driving force behind the market's rise in the past two days which saw a healthy amount of domestic investors joining foreigners on the buying side.</p>
<p>While traders saw strong demand for Hungarian stocks ahead of the year end they said some consolidation has to come.</p>
<p>&quot;Generally, I think that over the next couple of days or one week there will be a period when the market does consolidate,&quot; said Nathan West, salesman at Daiwa Europe in London. &quot;But nothing dramatic.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Most foreigners are not opening new positions...they have done a lot already,&quot; West said. &quot;Although there are some exceptions, particularly in Russia.&quot;</p>
<p>A local trader was more bullish.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel very strong buying pressure on the market,&quot; said Robert Agoston of Daewoo Securities. &quot;Should as good macroeconomic figures come out as the $1.5 billion export...the market may keep on strengthening for two or three weeks.&quot;</p>
<p>Gyorgy Suranyi, President of the Central Bank of Hungary, told Reuters on Tuesday that Hungary's monthly exports have hit a record level of $1.5 billion in November and will be about $14 billion for the year.</p>
<p>Not expecting any substantial correction in the near future, Agoston said there was room for minor consolidation during the upward trend.</p>
<p>&quot;If there's a correction at all on the market it will serve new buying opportunities,&quot; Agoston said.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
