<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233428" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-ZOFF REPORTED INTERESTED IN ITALY COACH JOB.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-ZOFF REPORTED INTERESTED IN ITALY COACH JOB.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dino Zoff, who led Italy to World Cup victory in 1982, is interested in coaching the national team, former team mate Fulvio Collovati said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Speaking on Telepiu 2 pay television, Collovati said he had spoken to Zoff recently and discussed the job left vacant when Arrigo Sacchi resigned suddenly on Sunday night.</p>
<p>&quot;I was able to speak to Zoff yesterday and he confirmed his interest, he indicated he was willing to sit on the bench,&quot; said Collovati, who played with Zoff in the team that beat West Germany 3-1 in Madrid for the world title.</p>
<p>&quot;From what I saw, he is keen. I think that after December 14, Zoff will be called,&quot; the ex-Milan defender said.</p>
<p>December 14 is the date when the Italian soccer federation meets to elect Luciano Nizzola as its new chairman.</p>
<p>Nizzola confirmed on Wednesday that he would announce the name of the new coach as soon as possible after the election but not necessarily that very day. &quot;It's something I will do as soon as possible, on the 14th, 15th or 16th.&quot;</p>
<p>He said there were no candidates other than those well documented by the media -- meaning Zoff, under-21 coach Cesare Maldini, former Parma coach Nevio Scala and the seemingly unavailable Giovanni Trapattoni and Fabio Capello.</p>
<p>Capello and Trapattoni have both publicly ruled themselves out of the running since Sacchi resigned.</p>
<p>Zoff, the most capped player in Italian soccer history with 112 appearances, is currently Lazio president and has not coached actively for more than two years.</p>
<p>Nizzola is known to be a great admirer of the former goalkeeper and Zoff's name has the status and weight that Italy, going through a poor patch internationally, need.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
