<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233504" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bosnia talks focus on war criminals, democracy.</title>
<headline>Bosnia talks focus on war criminals, democracy.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The international community was poised on Friday to adopt new measures to bring indicted Bosnian war criminals to justice if the former warring factions persist in refusing to hand them over.</p>
<p>The final day of an international conference to review the year since the Dayton peace accord ended 43 months of war in Bosnia was also expected to adopt a comprehensive agreement to cement stability in the area.</p>
<p>The conference has been overshadowed by huge protests in Belgrade, where opposition supporters and students are demanding the resignation of Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic, who they accuse of rigging recent local elections.</p>
<p>The London conference, attended by 50 national delegations, has focused on the restriction of freedom of movement across front lines, human rights violations and the issue of war criminals still on the loose.</p>
<p>The international war crimes tribunal for the former Yugoslavia in The Hague has indicted 75 people for crimes against humanity but has only five in jail.</p>
<p>The 50,000-strong NATO-led peace implementation force, due to be replaced later this month by a follow-up force half its size, has no mandate to hunt down war criminals.</p>
<p>But the international community said in London time was running out for the indicted war criminals, most of them Bosnian Serbs, and signalled new measures to hunt them down.</p>
<p>&quot;If there are not developments in the very near future, we will discuss different ways of dealing with this issue in a more direct way,&quot; Carl Bildt, the international community's High Representative in Bosnia, told a news conference.</p>
<p>He declined to say what measures might be taken.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working hard to improve our methods. It's not just the well-known figures. There are some 70 people there. We are now in a position to be much more energetic and active,&quot; U.S. Assistant Secretary of State John Kornblum said.</p>
<p>Kornblum said the state of democracy in Serbia was &quot;deplorable&quot; and laid the blame on Milosevic.</p>
<p>But the United States said Serbia had pledged not to use force to put down the anti-government protests.</p>
<p>Bildt said &quot;forces of repression and retrogression seem to be gaining the upper hand in the regime in Belgrade&quot;.</p>
<p>Milosevic was threatening to &quot;transform Serbia into an isolated and dangerous island of instability inside a region which is trying to build peace&quot;, Bildt said.</p>
<p>The condemnation was echoed by most ministers and diplomats in the elegant halls of Lancaster House, the conference venue.</p>
<p>The only voice of dissent was that of Russia's Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov, who reportedly warned that undue pressure on Milosevic might destabilise the entire region.</p>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major made it plain the West would be looking for a series of detailed political undertakings from the Bosnian leaders.</p>
<p>&quot;The international community will in turn undertake to provide substantial further help and resources, both human and financial,&quot; he told the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;But this international help will be conditional on the willingness in Bosnia and Herzegovina to implement all aspects of the peace agreement.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
