<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233525" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: 1996 set to be boom year for British tourism.</title>
<headline>1996 set to be boom year for British tourism.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain is attracting increasing numbers of tourists as its reputation as a centre of style and culture grows, the government said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The latest figures for 1996 from the Department of National Heritage for 1996 show a surge of 11 percent in overall visitors to 20.4 million and a seven percent increase in spending compared to the same period last year.</p>
<p>&quot;Last year saw records all round -- 24 million overseas visitors spending 12.1 billion pounds ($20 billion). 1996 is on course to do even better,&quot; National Heritage Secretary Virginia Bottomley said in a statement.</p>
<p>Bottomley said the trend of the last few years had now been reversed and Britain was booming compared to its European neighbours, driven by London which she called Britain's greatest asset in attracting overseas visitors.</p>
<p>She stressed the future potential of the tourism industry for Britain and the need to keep working to improve competitiveness in this market.</p>
<p>&quot;Tourism is high on the government's agenda.  It is becoming increasingly vital to the economy in terms of wealth and job creation.  It is set to be one of the world's biggest industries by the year 2000 and is forecast to create up to a million new jobs in the next ten years,&quot; Bottomley added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
