<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233684" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Dec 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - South Africa - Dec 4.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the South African press on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS DAY</p>
<p>- A delegation of national ministers and senior police and justice officials resisted demands by the vigilante group People Against Gansterism and Drugs for the right to carry firearms and wear masks at public rallies, as well as for lists of police informers and people suspected by police of drug offences.</p>
<p>- The London gold price dipped to its lowest level since November 1993, prompting another purge of the Johannesburg Stock Exchange's gold sector on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- Forestry group Sappi Ltd's nett income plummeted 70.2 percent to 404 million rand in the year to September after a sharp downturn in the markets in which it operated and the cost of forward foreign exchange cover affected bottom line.</p>
<p>- Boland Bank Ltd and parent Samgro Investment Holdings Ltd are poised to acquire a 25.6 percent stake in NBS holdings in two seperate transactions involving more than 1.5 billion rand - a move the market had anticipated for quiet some time.</p>
<p>- Defence minister Joe Modise intended submitting an amnesty application to the truth commission before the December 14 cut-off date, his military secretary said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BUSINESS REPORT</p>
<p>- Boland Bank Holdings and Samgro Investment Holdings, its parent, has snapped up 25 percent of NBS holdings, the KwaZulu-Natal based financial services group, for 1.5 billion rand.</p>
<p>- A group of black entrepreneurs adn Dangens Industri, a Swedish based newspaper group, said they had bought enterprise magazine from African Life Ltd in a deal valued at four milion rand.</p>
<p>- Sappi Ltd shares shed a rand in heavy trade after the paper and pulp producer's second half-earnings plunged, pulling earnings a share for the full year to September 30 down 73 percent to 230 cents.</p>
<p>- Oakfields Thoroughbreds and Leisure Industries Ltd, a company with interests in racehorse breeding and racing, has signed a joint venture agreement with the Guangzhou Jockey Club of China that could pave the way for exports to China of up to 1,000 thoroughbreds a year.</p>
<p>- The rand has held up better against a basket of currencies of South Africa's trading partners this week than it has against the dollar alone, analysts said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE STAR</p>
<p>- Alleged serial killer Moses Sithole confessed to a fellow prisoner last year to committing 29 of the 38 murders he is accused of, but denied raping any of his victims, the Pretoria Supreme Court heard on Tuesday.</p>
<p>- Former cabinet ministers Pik Botha and General Magnus Malan provided arms to Jonas Savimbi's Unita movement in exchange for diamonds and ivory which were sold, and the money transferred to Swiss bank accounts, a Pretoria court heard on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom +27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
