<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233666" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African court set to rule on new constitution.</title>
<headline>S.African court set to rule on new constitution.</headline>
<byline>Juliette Saunders</byline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's highest court was expected on Wednesday to give President Nelson Mandela the go ahead to cement his country's transition to democracy by signing a post-apartheid constitution into law.</p>
<p>The Constitutional Court was scheduled to rule at 2.15 p.m. (1215 GMT) on objections by two opposition parties to aspects of a revised draft constitution adopted by the National Assembly and Senate sitting together as a Constitutional Assembly (CA) in October.</p>
<p>Legal and political analysts said the court was likely to certify the text as being in compliance with principles laid down in an interim constitution that put an end to over three centuries of white rule in April 1994.</p>
<p>Government sources said plans were being made for Mandela, who led his country from white rule to democracy after 27 years in apartheid prisons, to sign the constitution next Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the ceremony would take place on International Human Rights Day in the black township of Sharpeville, where 69 black pro-democracy protestors were massacred by police in 1960.</p>
<p>The constitution, which Mandela has called the birth certificate of a democratic South Africa, will entrench a bill of rights enforcing race, gender and social equality in a country characterised by white privilege.</p>
<p>Amongst its more controversial provisions are a prohibition on capital punishment, guaranteed trade union rights and a property clause that could empower the government to redress the skewed pattern of land ownership created by apartheid.</p>
<p>Unless it is amended by at least two-thirds of the nation's legislators, the constitution would make it impossible for any future government to suspend human rights or to favour one section of the population as successive white governments did.</p>
<p>Former president F.W. de Klerk, who released Mandela from prison in 1990 and started negotiations on a transition to democracy, withdrew from a transitional government of national unity immediately after the constitution was adopted by legislators in May.</p>
<p>He said his National Party, which codified white rule in 1948 and agreed to dismantle it in 1990, could better serve the country from the opposition benches of parliament.</p>
<p>The text adopted in May was, however, returned by the Constitutional Court for further work, mainly on the powers of nine provincial governments and on the rights of employers facing industrial action.</p>
<p>Facing the prospect of a divisive national refendum if they failed to agree on improvements, six of the seven parties in parliament reconvened to iron out the glitches identified by the court and returned an amended text on October 11.</p>
<p>Zulu Chief Mangosuthu Buthelezi, who boycotted the adoption of the first version, sent his Inkatha Freedom Party back to the talks in October, but pulled them out again a few days later.</p>
<p>He said the constitution failed to give provinces the extensive federal powers he had demanded since democracy talks began in 1990.</p>
<p>Inkatha and the liberal Democratic Party, citing mainly technical flaws in the text, were the only groups who opposed ratification of the final document.</p>
<p>If the text is approved and signed into law, it will be phased in between January next year and April 1999, when the country is scheduled to face its second democratic election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
