<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233656" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Nairobi bourse boosted by brewery, firm.</title>
<headline>Nairobi bourse boosted by brewery, firm.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Activity at the Nairobi Stock Exchange (NSE) on Wednesday was boosted by big lots traded on Kenya Breweries, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>Turnover was posted at 14.293 million shillings traded on 428,840 shares from 13.583 million shillings. The index was up 4.17 points to stand at 3056.85.</p>
<p>Foreign investors continued to push prices up in the market, by sustaining demand on key shares.</p>
<p>They bought some 72,000 shares of Kenya Breweries at between 50 and 53 from 52. East African Portland Cement was traded at 24 from 23.75. Diamond Trust Bank Kenya was traded at 33 from 33.75, while Kenya Commercial Bank traded at 63.50 unchanged.</p>
<p>In its 1996 annual report, Kenya Breweries said it had paid early retirement benefits to voluntary retirees and had installed two new boilers in August to replace one lost in an explosion in October 1995.</p>
<p>Brokers said those two major projects had eaten into the company's earnings. They added that at the 50 shillings level the price was undervalued because Kenya Breweries had a net asset value of 108.73.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that they've finished paying out all that money we hope they will utilise their current 25 percent excess operating capacity and increase profits,&quot; a senior broker said.</p>
<p>Activity in Agriculturals was low. Sasini Tea &amp; Coffee traded 6,750 shares at 10 unchanged, while 375 shares of George Williamson changed hands at 70 from 71.</p>
<p>Foreign demand has supported prices on many key shares for about the last 1-1/2 months. Many financial analysts say that on average Kenyan prices are undervalued and foreign participation, which has improved greatly in the latter half of the year, is a positive sign for the market, reflecting confidence in its future.</p>
<p>A bourse official said that the much awaited first trading of corporate bonds in the secondary market was scheduled for Thursday.</p>
<p>-- Wambui Chege, Nairobi Newsroom ++254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
