<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233616" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zairean troops rampage in city as rebels advance.</title>
<headline>Zairean troops rampage in city as rebels advance.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>GOMA, Zaire 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hundreds of Zairean government troops went on a rampage of looting and raping in the northeastern city of Kisangani as victorious rebels said they were advancing towards the city from the south and east.</p>
<p>The rebels said on Tuesday night they had captured the town of Kindu, an important stepping stone on the way to Kisangani, but residents said by telephone on Wednesday that the town remained in government hands and the rebels were not evident.</p>
<p>They said Kindu, 400 km (250 miles) south of Kisangani, was a virtual military fortress with large numbers of Zairean soldiers in town. The soldiers, unpaid for months and short of food, had done some limited looting there, they added.</p>
<p>Residents of Kisangani, reached by radio on Tuesday, said Zairean authorities tried to control up to 600 soldiers on the rampage after retreating from rebel-held areas along the eastern borders of the country.</p>
<p>A Kisangani hotel was badly damaged on Tuesday when army forces trying to keep order attacked it with hand grenades in an assault on unruly troops, they added.</p>
<p>On the border between Uganda and Zaire, hundreds of km (miles) to the east of Kisangani, heavy fighting raged on Wednesday between the Ugandan army and Ugandan rebels based in Zaire, Ugandan officers in Kampala said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday night, Zairean rebel officer Jean Kabongo told Reuters at rebel headquarters in Goma that the rebels had added Kindu to the growing list of towns they have taken since the rebellion broke out on the Rwandan border in October.</p>
<p>Buth even without Kindu, the rebels hold a front 550 km (340 miles) long, running north-south parallel to the border.</p>
<p>Earlier this week the rebels said they had entered parts of Kisangani but Kabongo backtracked from this on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Kisangani is surrounded, but we haven't moved in yet. When we do, we will be in a position to travel down the river to Kinshasa. This fighting has been hard for our troops, but they are used to it, they are from here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The rebels say their ultimate aim is to overthrow Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko, who is in the south of France recovering from surgery for prostate cancer.</p>
<p>Rebel leader Laurent Kabila has written to Mobutu blaming him for Zaire's many ills and asking him to resign, according to a summary of the letter made available on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The residents of Kindu speculated that by announcing towns have fallen the rebels were trying to throw Zairean troops off balance and frighten them out of the towns. This was the pattern which the rebels took Uvira, Bukavu and Goma.</p>
<p>Kabongo also said the rebels, known as the Alliance of Democratic Force for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire, would leave mining concessions untouched in the areas they control, provided the mining companies pay taxes to the rebel administration.</p>
<p>The rebels will try to open up new areas to mining, especially in the central region of Kasai, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;All diamond mines and operations, like De Beers in Mbuji-Mayi, will remain in the hands of the companies who have been running them and operating the franchises up until now.</p>
<p>&quot;This is their job. We will change the taxation system in as much as legitimate taxes and permission money are given to us rather than the Zairean government. We will not interfere as long as they continue to respect our regulations,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In Kasai, more diamonds must be mined, the country's mineral wealth exploited. We are going to try and throw the area open for government-sponsored mining licences in areas in Kasai that have not yet been explored,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The rebels say that on their southern front they have captured the mining centre of Kamituga, where they say the South Africa-based Anglo American Corp has been operating.</p>
<p>In Johannesburg, Anglo American Corp and De Beers denied on Wednesday they were operating any mines in Zaire.</p>
<p>The fighting on the Ugandan border was around the Ugandan villages of Buswangwe, Kisehere and Kyabitondo, near Uganda's southwestern provincial capital Kasese, residents said.</p>
<p>The officers said some 100 Ugandan rebels from Zaire had renewed the fighting by attacking army positions on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Hundreds of residents have fled the area and the sound of heavy artillery fire was audible from the distance, said Kasese residents reached by telephone.</p>
<p>Displaced people are moving back to primary schools where they stayed during such an attack in November, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;The fighting is still going on and it is heavy,&quot; one army officer told Reuters in Kampala.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GOMA, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
