<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233639" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe shares extend weakness in thin trade.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe shares extend weakness in thin trade.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean shares continued largely weak in thin volumes on Wednesday although brokers said the selling pressure which had weighed on the market for the past week was beginning to ease.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is still coming down but there's no major selling pressure now. I think we should be seeing the bottom now and by next week we expect the market to stabilise,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>The key 57-industrial index shed 27.70 points to close at 8,053.81, depressed largely by publishing group Zimpapers' 200-cent fall to 2,000 and clothing retailer Edgars' 100-cent loss to 3,400.</p>
<p>Pork processor Colcom shed 25 cents to 340 while pharmaceutical group Caps at 380, food firm Natfoods at 530, seed manufacturer and distributor SeedCo at 210 and tea producer Tanganda at 310 all lost 20 cents.</p>
<p>Also among the losers, transport group Clan, building firm Mash, local conglomerate TA Holdings and tobacco company TSL all traded 10 cents down at 320, 210, 150 and 610 respectively.</p>
<p>Against the trend, tobacco group BAT surged 200 cents to 1,900, agricultural investor Chemco rose 100 cents to 2,400, soft drinks manufacturer Schweppes gained 50 cents to 1,300, furniture and clothing retailer Tedco added 25 cents to 725 and finance group Finhold put on 20 cents to 870.</p>
<p>Minings were active but also weaker with gold producer Ashanti unchanged at 13,000 but Falgold trading five cents down at 110. Wankie Colliery lost 10 cents to 440 while gold mining investor Falcon fell 100 cents to 1,100 and Rio Tinto slid 200 cents to 3,300.</p>
<p>The seven-counter mining index dropped 31.86 points to 1,178.22.</p>
<p>----Emelia Sithole, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
