<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233756" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech PX50 closes higher led by major issues.</title>
<headline>Czech PX50 closes higher led by major issues.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech PX50 index closed higher for the fifth straight session on Wednesday led by blue chip issues.</p>
<p>Three of the four most heavily capitalised shares on the Prague bourse rose with Ceska Sporitelna, the only loser, dropping four crowns to 312.</p>
<p>SPT Telecom led the gainers with a 39 crown rise to 3,125, CEZ rose 10 crowns to 971 and Komercni Banka gained five crowns to 2,085.</p>
<p>Despite the strength of major issues, there were some big decliners in the broader market.</p>
<p>Among the most spectacular fallers was glass fibre maker Vertex which lost 193 crowns to 3,667.</p>
<p>Analysts say Vertex has been plotting a steadily downward course since a takeover battle for the company in June between IPB group and Komercni Banka group which took the price to a 12-month high of 7,204.</p>
<p>&quot;The price was so inflated after the takeover battle. The price shouldn't be over 2,000. It shouldn't be any diferent from where it started ( before the takeover),&quot; said Lindsay Ashford of Zivnostenska Banka.</p>
<p>Other big decliners included Ceska Radiokomunikace which fell 192 crowns to 3,658 and Ceska Pojistovna which lost 105 crowns to 3,000.</p>
<p>Activity remained thin with turnover of 587 million crowns.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
