<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233719" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Currency board to ease Bulgaria access to IMF loan.</title>
<headline>Currency board to ease Bulgaria access to IMF loan.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria is expected to have access to its full annual limit of more than $700 million in International Monetary Fund (IMF) loans if the government implements a currency board, bank officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Bulgaria's 100 percent annual access limit to IMF funds is around $700 million. It is granted only in extraordinary circumstances and Bulgaria was given to understand that it may qualify when it introduces the currency board,&quot; a central banker said.</p>
<p>Two IMF technical missions are expected to arrive in Sofia next week to adjust the 1997 draft budget frame to currency board requirements and help prepare fiscal law amendments which would make the system operational, said an IMF official.</p>
<p>&quot;Funding details have not yet been discussed, but countries under extraordinary circumstances are eligible for 100 percent of their access limit annually or more,&quot; said the official who declined to be named.</p>
<p>The IMF had previously said it would support the implementation of the currency board system with substantial loans within Bulgaria's $580 million quota.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's government last week announced it has accepted the IMF proposal to introduce the currency board system as the only solution to its unprecedented financial crisis.</p>
<p>Under the system, the central bank must not print levs it cannot cover with hard currency reserves, which is expected to remove political pressure from monetary policy.</p>
<p>The Socialist government, which holds the majority in parliament said it planned to introduce the currency board early next year after parliament approved next year's budget and made the necessary legal amendments.</p>
<p>One of Bulgaria's options is to agree on a currency board implementation timetable with the IMF missions in December and make the necessary legal adjustments in the next one or two months and then introduce the currency board.</p>
<p>The alternative is to make the legal adustments as soon as possible and introduce the plan in January, the bank official said.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has no other funding alternative as it has not met the IMF performance criteria and has failed to fulfil structural reform targets for a $115 million second tranche from an IMF stand-by facility, already twice postponed.</p>
<p>Central bank reserves fell to $525.1 million at end-November from $541 million at end-October and $1.4 billion a year ago due to modest interventions on the local forex market to support the plummetting lev, which closed on Wednesday at a new record low of 415-418 to the dollar.</p>
<p>The central bank has said some $500 million in reserves plus the strategic gold reserves worth $450 million were enough to comply with a currency board plan but were insufficient to cover pending foreign debt payments of around $300 million due in the first quarter of next year.</p>
<p>Bulgaria would also stand to receive additional IMF funding to overcome an acute wheat shortfall this year, from a so-called Compensatory and Contingency Financing Facility.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
