<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233757" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Budapest BUX hits record high for second day.</title>
<headline>Budapest BUX hits record high for second day.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hungarian share market bucked a bearish trend on most European markets and extended Tuesday's gains to set the second successive new record.</p>
<p>The BUX index closed at 3,789.22 points, up 28.23, in active trade.</p>
<p>On the BUX futures market, which saw the four nearest maturities rise and the two longest fall, the December instrument gained 20 points to finish at 3,775.</p>
<p>&quot;The (spot) market was strong again due to the strength of the dollar and to good macroeconomic results,&quot; said Balazs Bathory of Creditanstalt Securities.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has also benefited from the fact that pressure on profit-taking, which drove prices lower a few weeks ago, has eased.&quot;</p>
<p>While almost all stocks closed higher, with some of them reaching all-time or 52-week record levels, French packaging company Cofinec plunged.</p>
<p>Cofinec GDRs plunged over 20 percent to 4,250 forints and following this deal trading was suspended for the rest of the day due to an unacceptably quick intraday fall.</p>
<p>Chemicals Borsodchem surged to a new high of 3,700 forints, before coming down a shade to close at 2,695, up 295.</p>
<p>The shares of Hungary's leading meat processor Pick jumped to a 52-week high of 8,550 forints, before closing at 8,505, up 400.</p>
<p>A trader said earlier today that there were bits of encouraging news about Pick and one important element was that Pick would probably have a better 1997 contract with its distributor in Germany, its main export market.</p>
<p>-- Emese Bartha, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
