<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233889" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's Cardoso has not discussed CPMF tax.</title>
<headline>Brazil's Cardoso has not discussed CPMF tax.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazilian President Fernando Henrique Cardoso has not been approached by officials over possible plans to exempt stock market transactions from the so-called CPMF check tax, his spokesman said.</p>
<p>Sergio Amaral told reporters Cardoso would be willing to discuss any proposals made.</p>
<p>&quot;No one has spoken to the president about ending the CPMF,&quot; Amaral said. &quot;No proposals have been taken to the president with regard to changes but if they were, he would study them.&quot;  </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Finance Ministry Executive Secretary Pedro Parente Wednesday confirmed his department was studying whether to exempt stocks from the 0.2 perecent levy because of concerns it could lead to capital flight.</p>
<p>But according to a report by the private Invest News agency, Internal Revenue Service head Everardo Maciel knew of no such studies and said he had no plans to change the tax.</p>
<p>The tax is due to be levied on all financial transactions after January 23 and is intended to raise 400 million reais a month for the health service.</p>
<p>Finance Ministry officials said they had no comment.  </p>
<p>Shares have eased upwards over the past two days following comments by government officials that they feared the tax could provoke investors to flee Brazilian stock markets.</p>
<p>But on Wednesday, the mood changed, with traders saying it looked less likely the government would make any changes.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Industry and Commerce Minister Francisco Dornelles criticized the tax and a newspaper reported that Central Bank Director Gustavo Franco was also concerned.</p>
<p>-- Michael Christie, Brasilia newsroom 55-61-2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
