<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233848" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Dec 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Croatia - Dec 4.</headline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are the main stories in Croatian newspapers on Wednesday.</p>
<p>VJESNIK</p>
<p>- President Tudjman made a surprise visit on Tuesday to the war-ravaged eastern Croatian town Vukovar, currently under U.N. Transitional Administration control.</p>
<p>- Money market: Liquidity improves.</p>
<p>- Employers's association warns it will ask government to indemnify their companies for losses suffered due to the rail strike.</p>
<p>VECERNJI LIST</p>
<p>- Croatian railway traffic at a standstill: The railway workers' strike has ground to a halt virtually all services as of early Tuesday morning, causing huge losses in the Croatian economy.</p>
<p>- Figures for the first nine months of 1996 show the cost of living in the Croatian capital Zagreb has gone up exactly 4.7 percent year-on-year.</p>
<p>- The Plomin Two thermo-electric plant will not be a polluter as all waste materials will be put to good use, says the general manager of the Croatian power company HEP, reacting to allegations to the contrary.</p>
<p>- Foreign consultants hired to design the restructuring of public companies object to the state railways (HZ) being viewed as a &quot;provider of services&quot; rather than a commercial company.</p>
<p>SLOBODNA DALMACIJA</p>
<p>- Rumour has it that local elections and those for the House of Counties will be held on March 16, 1997, while presidential elections may be scheduled for late summer next year.</p>
<p>- Pope John Paul II may visit Sarajevo on April 13, 1997, combining it with his visit to Prague.</p>
<p>- High price of capital poses a threat to economy, says director of the Zagreb money market, Josip Gotovac, in an interview. He says interest rates could be cut from the current 18-25 pct in a joint effort of the government and banks.</p>
<p>- Total first half operating losses of the banking sector put at 18.1 million kuna, compared to a profit of 52.8 million kuna in the same period of 1995, according to a report of the central payments bureau ZAP. -- Zagreb Newsroom, 385-1-4557075</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
