<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233832" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Kazakh capital spends night in fear of earthquake.</title>
<headline>Kazakh capital spends night in fear of earthquake.</headline>
<byline>Chris Bird</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Families quit high-rise apartment blocks or spent the night shivering in cars as panic gripped the Kazakh capital Almaty after a warning from a psychic that a major earthquake was about to strike.</p>
<p>But the calamity, predicted for Tuesday night, never came.</p>
<p>&quot;We received reliable scientific information from Moscow that there would be a powerful earthquake north of the capital,&quot; said Valery Petrov, chief of operations at Kazakhstan's State Committee for Emergency Situations.</p>
<p>&quot;All our services were on high alert and we kept communications open with China, Kyrgyzstan and Russia.&quot;</p>
<p>But diplomats and the Kazakh television news programme Khabar said the prediction originated with a Moscow psychic.</p>
<p>Though Kazakhstan's own Institute of Seismology refused to confirm it, the warning triggered pandemonium.</p>
<p>Vehicles packed roads out of the city as residents packed up belongings and fled apartment blocks for single-storey homes in the country.</p>
<p>Others slept in their cars with engines running to provide warmth in icy temperatures. The late shift at a cigarette factory owned by Phillip Morris was cancelled.</p>
<p>Well-heeled guests at Almaty's Hyatt Regency Hotel were reassured in a letter that the gleaming building of steel and glass was built to withstand a strong quake -- but were nevertheless asked not to stand under its glass atrium.</p>
<p>Diplomats were sceptical about the source of the warning.</p>
<p>&quot;We just let our people know the basic facts, that a psychic in Moscow had predicted an earthquake in the Almaty area,&quot; said Karen Williams, spokeswoman for the U.S. embassy in Almaty.</p>
<p>Tremors regularly shake the city of 1.5 million, built at the foot of the spectacular -- and geologically young -- Tien Shan mountains.</p>
<p>Many people were killed when the city, then a Russian colonial outpost, was rocked by a quake in 1911.</p>
<p>The capitals of the Central Asian republics of Uzbekistan and Turkmenistan also suffered major earthquakes this century. Turkmen President Saparmurat Niyazov was orphaned after an earthquake struck Ashgabat in 1948, killing over 100,000 people.</p>
<p>Seismologists at a seminar in Almaty in September said a large quake would strike the region in the next decade and half.</p>
<p>&quot;All this panic is ridiculous,&quot; said Viktor, an engineer-turned-taxi driver who spent most of Tuesday evening ferrying worried families from blocks of flats to relatives in single-storey houses.</p>
<p>&quot;Of course there will be an earthquake but no-one will be able to predict it.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
