<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="233903" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil gem trade sparkles at new wealth.</title>
<headline>Brazil gem trade sparkles at new wealth.</headline>
<byline>Simona de Logu</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil</dateline>
<text>
<p>The fortunes of Brazil's most famous jeweller H. Stern are rising as more Brazilian women can afford to adorn themselves with gold, diamonds, emeralds and other precious stones.</p>
<p>Thanks to the country's successful battle against inflation, Brazilians have more money to spend on luxury goods like jewelry, according to Hans Stern, the slight, bespectacled 76-year-old gentleman who presides over this glittering empire in the heart of Rio de Janeiro.</p>
<p>H. Stern shops can be found in the United States, the Caribbean, most South American countries, Europe, Israel, Japan and of course Brazil.</p>
<p>He politely refuses to reveal the exact extent of the company's wealth, but admits sales in Brazil have doubled since the government introduced the anti-inflation Real Plan in 1994.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not a public company so we don't have to disclose any figures. There is a lot of envy and jealousy in the world. Why should we instigate that,&quot; Stern said.</p>
<p>His success story of a German Jew who fled the Nazi regime in 1939 and arrived almost penniless in Brazil only to become one of the top 10 jewellers in the world is indeed astounding.</p>
<p>What started off in a small office with only one assistant and $200 from the sale of an accordion brought from Germany has turned into an international operation with 175 outlets and 3,500 employees in 14 countries and a high-rise company headquarters in Rio's elegant Ipanema neighbourhood.</p>
<p>H. Stern, which has mining rights for aquamarines and emeralds, is the only organisation of its kind, handling every aspect of gem production from mining to stone cutting, jewelry crafting and sales.</p>
<p>Business has been going well, with worldwide sales &quot;rising consistently&quot; every since H. Stern opened its doors to the public in 1945.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't really have any competitors,&quot; Stern said. &quot;We all have our own niche in the market. We distinguish ourselves as specialists in gem jewelry and try to develop new designs and collections to make Stern a brand name.&quot;</p>
<p>H. Stern, which specialises in Brazil's vast variety of coloured gems, has cornered a 15 percent to 20 percent share in the domestic jewelry market estimated to be worth $1.1 billion a year and controls 60 percent of Brazilian gem production, making it the country's largest jeweller.</p>
<p>No country in the world has as many different types of precious stone as Brazil.</p>
<p>Brazil produces about 90 percent of the world's aquamarines, 75 percent of amethysts, tourmalines, citrines and other coloured gems and has displaced Colombia as the No. 1 producer of emeralds. Brazil also produces 5 percent of the world's quality diamonds.</p>
<p>Coloured gems other than emeralds, rubies and sapphires are commonly known as semi-precious stones, but Stern, whose favourite gem is a green tourmaline, dismisses this terminology. After all, the single most expensive stone he has ever sold is an alexandrite for $350,000.</p>
<p>&quot;The word semi-precious is really taboo,&quot; he said. &quot;What makes a stone precious is its beauty, purity and durability. There are no half-precious stones, just as there are no half-pregnant women.&quot;</p>
<p>It has been Stern's lifework to make Brazil famous for its coloured stones, which are appreciated more abroad than by Brazilians themselves who have a predilection for all things imported at the expense of the homegrown.</p>
<p>However, Brazil is H. Stern's largest market with half of the company's stores and 70 percent of total revenues. Brazilians are responsible for 80 percent of sales in Brazil, while tourists account for the remaining 20 percent.</p>
<p>Russians have displaced Arabs as the biggest spenders since the downfall of the Soviet Union, arriving with suitcases full of cash to buy the most extravagant pieces, while Americans are still the most eccentric.</p>
<p>A gold dog collar with pink morganites to match the dog's skin ordered by an American woman sticks in Stern's mind as the most unusual order he ever received. But these special orders account for 20 percent of total sales.</p>
<p>But, it is the middle class buyer who purchases jewelry in the $200-$1,500 price range who makes up the bulk of H. Stern's clientele.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has become more popular and more democratic because you can buy jewelry from $100 up,&quot; Stern said. &quot;The fashion trend is toward simple straight lines using smaller stones, using gold and diamonds.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I49100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO, Brazil"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
