<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234185" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Find toys to grow with your child - expert advises.</title>
<headline>Find toys to grow with your child - expert advises.</headline>
<byline>Judith Schoolman</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nothing costs more than a toy that is never used, or tossed into a corner after five minutes.</p>
<p>Some of the smartest, and money-saving, toy selections are not necessarily the action figure of the moment or highly promoted movie tie-ins.</p>
<p>&quot;Find a toy that will grow with the child, to be used different ways at different ages,&quot; said New York-based psychologist Dr. Istar Schwager, adding that no one toy is terriffic for everybody.</p>
<p>Toys that will be used in different ways over time include sets of blocks, puppets and art materials.</p>
<p>It is important when selecting a toy that the purchaser keep in mind the child's age, developmental level, skills and interests, said the consultant to children's media.</p>
<p>Many of the mistakes adults make when giving children gifts comes from having expectations that are too high, and not really understanding developmental levels.</p>
<p>Preschoolers are not ready to understand board games, Schwager said, because they have a hard time dealing with rules and competition.</p>
<p>For them, appropriate toys are those that encourage the imagination, such as blocks and dress up accessories.</p>
<p>By age five or six and up to age nine, children are generally able to play group games, she said. They enjoy practicing new skills, so board games, pick-up sticks, jacks and sports equipment are appropriate.</p>
<p>Pre-teens have distinct interests, such as crafts, art and music. Good gifts support those interests, Schwager said.</p>
<p>Gift givers should always be aware of safety, and it's a wise suggestion to rely on the manufacturer's age guidelines. These are established with a toy's safety and play value in mind.</p>
<p>&quot;Even if a child is precocious, don't get a toy aimed for an older kid,&quot; Schwager said.</p>
<p>Computer games, on just about every kid's wish list, &quot;are fine in balance with other activities,&quot; Schwager said. &quot;They're not good when they're at the expense of not having other toys to play with -- when they're part of the mix with outdoor, social and time alone activities.&quot;</p>
<p>They are appropriate for children aged four or five, &quot;but only at a limited extent,&quot; Schwager said.</p>
<p>As for chess, Schwager suggests parents try it with their kids around ages five or six. At this age they are beginning to understand relationships and rules, she said.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>Looking for toys but haven't got a clue? Here's the list of winners in the ninth annual Duracell Kid's Choice National Toy Survey. A group of children looked at the newest toys and here are their top 10 favourites.</p>
<p>1. Brain Warp (Tiger $24.99)</p>
<p>2. Monkey Madness (Parker Bros. $19.99)</p>
<p>3. Dizzy Dryer (Mattel Inc. $22)</p>
<p>4. Pickin' Chickens (Tyco $20)</p>
<p>5. Traxx Deluxe Train Set (Battat $50)</p>
<p>6. Frantic Ants (Parker Bros. $19.99)</p>
<p>7. Easy Score Arcade (Little Tikes $19.99)</p>
<p>8. Let's Pretend Restaurant (Creativity for Kids $15)</p>
<p>9. Russian Building Blocks (T.C. Timber $39,95)</p>
<p>10. K'nex Dueling Racers (K'nex Industries $14.99)</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>You can write to Judith Schoolman at Reuters, 199 Water Street, 10th floor, N.Y., N.Y. 10038. Her e-mail address is Judith.Schoolman(at)reuters.com.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
