<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234100" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta shares end higher on banks, blue-chips.</title>
<headline>Jakarta shares end higher on banks, blue-chips.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Active buying in the banking sector and of selected big-capitalised stocks pushed Jakarta shares prices higher on Wednesday, brokers said.</p>
<p>The Jakarta Composite Index rose 5.46 points, or 0.88 percent, to close at 626.27 points after touching a low of 620.74. Gainers led losers by 55 to 51, with 66 counters unchanged.</p>
<p>Brokers said market sentiment was likely to stay firm on Thursday as buying interest in banks and several big and medium-capitalised counters remained high.  </p>
<p>But brokers said profit-taking could hold the index back on Thursday, with some investors looking for short-term gains.</p>
<p>They said trading was boosted on Wednesday when a number of overseas buyers entered the market during the afternoon.</p>
<p>Newly-listed Bank Negara Indonesia (BNI), BDNI and Bank International Indonesia were among favoured stocks, brokers said.</p>
<p>BNI topped the active list with 26.6 million shares changing hands. Its price was unchanged at 1,275 rupiah after earlier rising to 1,300 rupiah.  </p>
<p>Brokers said the current downtrend in deposit rates among major banks while lending rates remained stable had triggered fresh buying in the bank sector.</p>
<p>Bank International Indonesia rose 200 rupiah to 2,475 rupiah on a volume of around 10 million shares, while BDNI rose 50 rupiah to 2,450 rupiah on 2.4 million shares.</p>
<p>Blue-chips telecommunications firm Telkom and international telephone operator Indosat were also actively traded on what brokers said was bargain-hunting.</p>
<p>Telkom rose 100 rupiah to 4,025 on 1.8 million shares. Brokers said it was partly due to market talk of a possible higher dividend by the end of the year.  </p>
<p>A company official denied the rumours saying the firm planned to announce the dividend at its annual general meeting scheduled for April.</p>
<p>Indosat rose 100 rupiah to 6,425 rupiah on 1.9 million shares on what brokers said was bargain-hunting. This was also in line with its overnight closing price in New York.</p>
<p>Shipping firm Berlian Laju Tanker fell 25 rupiah to 4,700 rupiah after rising to 4,900 rupiah on a volume of 7.8 million shares on what brokers said was profit-taking.</p>
<p>&quot;It rose earlier following a company announcement it would discuss equity participation in other firms at its extraordinary general meeting in January,&quot; a local broker said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
