<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234142" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Starts-ups sell garage bands, Bowie on Web.</title>
<headline>Starts-ups sell garage bands, Bowie on Web.</headline>
<byline>Samuel Fromartz</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON</dateline>
<text>
<p>If two young music companies on the Internet get their way, consumers will start to think very differently about the way they develop their musical tastes and buy recordings.</p>
<p>Both companies want to take advantage of the well-known attributes of the World Wide Web -- its ability to offer sound, graphics and video at the click of a mouse -- and have latched onto a model that links this information with an online store.</p>
<p>The question is whether the companies -- N2K Inc., which is established with industry heavyweights onboard, and J-Bird Records, a start-up barely up and running -- will succeed and turn music lovers into Web consumers in a big way.</p>
<p>While both are trying to help answer the age-old consumer questions about music, &quot;What should I buy? What sounds good?,&quot; the similarities end there.</p>
<p>Based in New York, N2K might be viewed as a 2-year-old wannabe music conglomerate, with its hands -- or mouses -- in everything from online retailing to artist Web sites, offering what amounts to multimedia magazines with a shopping option.</p>
<p>There are sites for jazz, rock, and classical music, links to non-profit and educational groups, sites for the Rolling Stones and Leonard Bernstein and David Bowie and at the centre, the store, Music Boulevard (http://www.musicblvd.com).</p>
<p>The company was formed by Dave Grusin, Larry Rosen and Jon Diamond, who had previously built GRP records into the music industry's biggest jazz label in the 1980s by focusing very early on the compact disc. After they sold the privately held company to MCA in 1990, they focused on the Internet.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to create a community feel so that people can either be entertained, get an education, and get material about artists,&quot; said Diamond, vice chairman.</p>
<p>&quot;We think that the concept of buying a CD is not a singular experience -- there's the culture of the music, the information about the artist -- and what we offer is this robust database,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Web surfers who interact with the site give the company data on their tastes so that information can be e-mailed to them in the future. An example of this occurred at the Bowie site (http://www.davidbowie.com), where N2K offered a single available only on the Web that has been downloaded by more than 250,000 visitors.</p>
<p>In return, N2K got e-mail addresses that Virgin Records can use for promotional material for a Bowie album.</p>
<p>The company's latest addition was a record label, N2K Encoded Music, led by Phil Ramone, who produced Frank Sinatra's duet albums and has worked with Billy Joel, Paul Simon, Paul McCartney and a host of other biggies.</p>
<p>All the recordings produced by the company will be enhanced CDs, with multimedia content along with music.</p>
<p>So far, according to documents at the Securities and Exchange Commission, N2K has yet to produce any profits from its music business. While revenues have begun to stream in, losses have mounted due to its big investments -- fairly common in this nascent industry.</p>
<p>Trying to tap more capital, it filed for a $36 million initial stock offering in June that so far has not come to market. N2K officials cannot comment about the offer during this &quot;quiet&quot; registration period.</p>
<p>J-Bird Records (http://www.j-birdrecords.com) is marching to the beat of a very different drummer, trying to create a musical free-for-all site for consumers to decide what bands they like.</p>
<p>In the traditional music world, A&amp;R (artist and repertory) executives sign up bands they think are good, put promotional muscle behind them, seek radio play and pubicity, push a product into a retail channel and wait for consumers to come.</p>
<p>Listening to a single on the radio, or watching a video on MTV might actually get someone into a record store for a sale.</p>
<p>Wilton, Conn.-based J-Bird, whose site only recently opened up, wants to trash that formula and offer any band with $600 and a digital tape a site on its Web server. Think of it as the electronic home for 1,000 garage bands.</p>
<p>Founder Jay Barbieri, formerly of EMI Records, said the filters put in place by record companies, promoters, radio stations and critics were too fine.</p>
<p>&quot;Who am I to judge the music? I want to go straight to the public, let them browse through bands and purchase them on the basis of what they sound like, or what they're all about,&quot; he said.&quot;</p>
<p>J-Bird is living up to the model of the Internet as a huge source of information you may -- or may not -- want. The next Nirvana may show up here, it's for you to decide, if you have the patience.</p>
<p>So far only a few bands are available on the site, which is still in an infant stage. Revenue is expected to come from the $600 fee that will refunded to bands after they sell 500 units of their records, which J-Bird also manufactures.</p>
<p>(To contact Sam Fromartz, send e-mail to Sam.Fromartz (at) Reuters.com).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34520">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
