<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234129" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Oman shares stable, bank shares dominate trade.</title>
<headline>Oman shares stable, bank shares dominate trade.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oman's stock exchange inched up 0.13 percent in moderate trade in the holiday-shortened week to Wednesday with interest focused on bank and investment shares.</p>
<p>The Muscat Securities Market said the index closed at 186.79 points from 186.53.</p>
<p>Of the 52 companies traded in the week -- which was shortened by a two-day national holiday -- shares of 19 rose, 23 fell and the rest were unchanged, the exchange said.</p>
<p>Bank and investment company sectors accounted for 58 percent of total trading value of 2.147 million rials ($5.68 million) from 4.87 million rials the previous week.</p>
<p>Some 895,000 shares changed hands in 461 deals, 51 percent fewer than last week's transactions.</p>
<p>Some 154,000 Oman National Holding Company shares worth 642,000 rials were traded, the exchange said. The stock closed at 4.170 rials from 4.160 a week earlier.</p>
<p>The National Industrial Detergents Company rose 0.80 rials to 3.200 rials. Omani United Insurance Company rose 0.40 rials to 1.910 rials.</p>
<p>-- Dubai Newsroom 9714-626990 ($1=0.38 rials)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
