<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234105" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Ultra-Orthodox Jews flex political muscle.</title>
<headline>Ultra-Orthodox Jews flex political muscle.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thousands of black-coated ultra-Orthodox Jews called at a rally on Wednesday for stricter sabbath observance but Tel Aviv mayor Roni Milo warned this would provoke a backlash by secular Jews.</p>
<p>The crowd at the Tel Aviv rally urged the government and Milo to stop what they regarded as desecration of the Jewish sabbath. They said places of entertainment like theatres and restaurants should be closed.</p>
<p>&quot;Return the holiness of the sabbath to Tel Aviv,&quot; said Menachem Porush, one of the rabbis who led the rally.</p>
<p>Witnesses put the crowd, which included Israeli Chief Rabbi Yisrael Lau, at some 10,000.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm telling you not only people on the left who are against the religious, (but) people who are concerned about freedom and rights, concerned that Tel Aviv remain the city of freedom, they are worried by this,&quot; Milo told an ultra-Orthodox rabbi on Israel Television.</p>
<p>&quot;That includes traditionalists, people like me who go on holidays to synagogue, they are very worried by this situation. They are ready even to go out to struggle if you try to harm this, a struggle without compromise.&quot;</p>
<p>Milo, a member of Israel's ruling right-wing Likud party, added: &quot;I suggest that you do what you want in Jerusalem...And let us live our lives in Tel Aviv.&quot;</p>
<p>Tel Aviv municipality's slogan is &quot;the city that never sleeps&quot;. Tel Aviv residents see their city as swinging versus the staid atmosphere of Jerusalem which is holy to Jews, Moslems and Christians.</p>
<p>The rare mass call for places of entertainment in Tel Aviv to be shut on the Jewish sabbath, which runs from sundown on Friday to after sunset on Saturday, marked a flexing of political muscle by ultra-Orthodox Jews whose parties made significant gains in Israel's parliamentary elections last May.</p>
<p>Jewish religious parties won 23 of the 120 seats in parliament. They had 16 seats in the previous parliament.</p>
<p>The vast majority of Israel's Jews do not observe Orthodox Judaism but the small Orthodox parties have acted as kingmakers because no single party has ever won enough votes to govern alone.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
