<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234278" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar ends rangebound US session slightly lower.</title>
<headline>Dollar ends rangebound US session slightly lower.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended a lackluster trading session modestly lower on Wednesday, as currency dealers took a breather following two highly active and volatile sessions on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is definitely a little shell-shocked,&quot; said Lisa Finstrom, foreign exchange analyst at Smith Barney Inc. &quot;I'm not quite sure if people knew what hit them earlier in the week.&quot;</p>
<p>The dollar ended the day slightly lower against the mark at 1.5602/07, down from 1.5610/20 at the open.  </p>
<p>Against the yen, the greenback traded in an extremely tight range throughout the day before closing at 113.10/20, down from 113.27/37 in early trade.</p>
<p>Yen strength, albeit modest, was the predominant theme of the day, with the Japanese currency pushing higher against most European currencies as well as the dollar.</p>
<p>Aiding the yen, were remarks from former Japanese Ministry of Finance official Makoto Utsumi, who reinforced the market's conviction that Japanese authorities do not want the dollar to travel beyond its recent highs near 115 yen.  </p>
<p>Utsumi said on Wednesday that a 105 to 115 yen range versus the dollar was appropriate and an accurate reflection of economic fundamentals in the two countries.</p>
<p>&quot;I think you'll see the yen continue to strengthen relative to other currencies,&quot; said John McCarthy, foreign exchange manager at ING Barings Capital Markets. &quot;If you think the dollar has room to move up, it's going to move up against Europe a lot easier than it is against the yen.&quot;</p>
<p>Keeping the dollar in check on Wednesday were weak U.S. asset markets.  </p>
<p>The Dow Jones Industrials fell over 70 points in the afternoon, before trimming their losses to end the session only 20 points lower.</p>
<p>Bonds stumbled lower as well, disappointed when the Federal Reserve failed to add permanent reserves to the banking system, as many in the market had expected.</p>
<p>&quot;The bond market came off quite heavily and the Dow Jones industrials were down as well,&quot; said Hans Boman, chief spot dealer at Swedbank. &quot;I think some dollar weakness is related to the bonds and stocks.&quot;  </p>
<p>The British pound, which tumbled on Tuesday after reports that British exporters were concerned about its recent strength, rose modestly against the dollar on Wednesday, ending at $1.6428/38 against $1.6407/17 at the open.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, the dollar was relatively flat at 1.3205/15 Swiss francs against 1.3215/25, and modestly higher at Canadian $1.3535/40 versus C$1.3508/13 at the open.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar ended at $0.8002/07, up from $0.7959/64 in early trade.</p>
<p>-- Noah Barkin, 212-859-1673</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
