<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234300" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME hogs and pork bellies fall late, close weak.</title>
<headline>CME hogs and pork bellies fall late, close weak.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>CME hog futures reversed midsession gains and ended weak as easier pork product values prompted liquidation while pork bellies were already showing losses following the bearish out-of-town report, traders said.</p>
<p>Hog futures closed 0.975 to 0.200 cent lower with December off 0.400 at 58.800 cents and February off 0.900 at 76.875 cents. Lightly traded October through distant June lean hogs posted new contract lows. Pork bellies ended 2.125 to 1.475 lower with February off most at 77.850 cents.</p>
<p>Hog futures fell as early expectations of firmer live markets gave way to pressure from weakness in pork products.</p>
<p>The recent strength in most pork product items had helped futures run up to post new contract highs earlier in the week, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Right at this time frame, based on where pork prices have been, there is going to be a lull in demand,&quot; said Karl Skold, Director of Research for Frontier Risk Management.</p>
<p>The USDA reported most pork cuts lower at noon in slow trade and light demand. Cash bellies were quoted lower which added to pressure in belly futures that had developed from Tuesday's bearish CME weekly out-of-town report, traders said.  </p>
<p>The CME reported a net in-movement last week of 3.313 million lbs, well above the range of early estimates of unchanged to in 2.0 million lbs.</p>
<p>Cash belly prices, as well as futures, appeared to be too high priced. Retail interest for bacon seems to subside when cash prices work up toward $80 per cwt and futures were due for a correction after running up around 14.000 cents since late October, they said.</p>
<p>However, some traders said the setback in futures was only temporary. Storage stocks were still below the year ago level and there was no basis to hedge.</p>
<p>Futures were holding only a small premium of 2.000 to 3.000 cents and the market needs around 8.000 cents this time of year to stimulate storing of product.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no incentive to store at this time,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>In hog options, First Chicago bought February 74 puts and sold 74 calls early while Term Commodities bought February 76 calls. Lind-Waldock and LFG bought December 58 calls on the later break, pit sources added.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
