<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234353" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dow Chemical lifts Mycogen stake.</title>
<headline>Dow Chemical lifts Mycogen stake.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dow Chemical Co said Wednesday it raised its stake in Mycogen Corp to 51.8 percent from 47.3 percent in a bid to obtain board control.</p>
<p>In a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, Dow said that its DowElanco unit bought 1.0 million additional cpmmon shares of Mycogen on December 2 at $16.75 a share or $16.75 million.</p>
<p>The purchase raised Dow Chemical's stake in Mycogen to 15,911,802 common shares.  </p>
<p>The 1.0 million shares were puchased from Pioneer Overseas Corp, Dow Chemical said.</p>
<p>&quot;The purpose of the acquisition is to allow DowElanco to obtain control of Mycogen's board of directors ... and to take a more active role in the development and protection of Mycogen's technology rights,&quot; Dow Chemical.</p>
<p>Dow Chemical said Mycogen had informed DowElanco of Mycogen's proposed stock acquisition and technology transaction with a third party that in DowElanco's view &quot;would have impaired Mycogen's technology rights.&quot;  </p>
<p>Dow Chemical added that although Mycogen informed DowElanco of Mycogen's rejection of the transaction, DowElanco feared that the transaction would be revived in a modified form.</p>
<p>Dow Chemical said four of the nine members of Mycogen's board are DowElanco designees. DowElanco has advised Mycogen of DowElanco's right to majority board representation and will take whatever steps are necessary to enforce that right, it said.</p>
<p>Because Mycogen's by-laws limit the size of the baord to nine directors, DowElanco has asked the company to arrange for the resignation of one director to allow DowElanco's designee, Louis Pribila, to be elected, it said.</p>
<p>DowElanco has also proposed the possibility of amending the by-laws to increase the size of the board to eleven at some point in the future, it added.</p>
<p>Dow Chemical said that before the latest share purchase, DowElanco also bought 417,700 Mycogen common shares between June 5 and November 25 at prices ranging from $14.25 to $17.875 a share or $6.8 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25680">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
