<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234331" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CME live cattle end lower on falling beef prices.</title>
<headline>CME live cattle end lower on falling beef prices.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fund long liquidation and commercial selling linked to slipping cash cattle and beef prices knocked CME live cattle futures to new day's lows at the close. Feeder cattle also retreated on spillover weakness in thin trade.</p>
<p>Live cattle closed 1.025 to 0.375 cent a lb lower paced by December at 65.900 cents. Feeder cattle ended 0.675 to 0.325 lower with January off most at 66.475 cents.</p>
<p>Early commercial support in live cattle futures gave way when choice beef values again tumbled sharply Wednesday, adding to long liquidation in the cattle pit. Sell stops and technicals then took prices down to lows, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Beef being down $4 in two days doesn't give the market a lot of confidence,&quot; one trader noted.</p>
<p>He referred to tumbling beef prices the past few days.</p>
<p>At midday, USDA reported choice-grade boxed beef values down $5.89 for light-weight and down $5.41 since last Friday.</p>
<p>Sliding beef prices added to liquidation that started Tuesday when cash cattle failed to trade at $69 as expected.</p>
<p>Demand for beef will likely remain slow and prices pressured until grocers look for meat other than hams and turkeys for after the Christmas holiday.  </p>
<p>&quot;We already had a lot of the first-of-the-month (retail) business done and we are going to have more supplies and it may take into the middle of the month before we start marching higher again,&quot; said Karl Skold, Director of Research for Frontier Risk Management, of beef prices.</p>
<p>Refco and E.D.&amp; F. Man notably sold on the break while spreaders bought February and sold December. In live cattle options, commercials spread long June 64 calls/short June 62 puts and bought February 64 live cattle calls and sold March feeder cattle 62 puts. Volatility in February was up 3/4 of one percent, pit sources said.</p>
<p>Feeders generally followed the lead of live cattle and retreated on spillover weakness. Pressure was also attributed to higher corn futures early which offset support from the rising CME feeder cattle index, traders said.</p>
<p>The latest index was up $0.56 to $65.00 per cwt. The index climbed $1.29 in two days.</p>
<p>Refco sold January early into sell stops, but trading turned light late. Refco sold back months late while R.J. O'Brien bought. ING was an early buyer, pit sources added.</p>
<p>((Jerry Bieszk 312-408-8725))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
