<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234480" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N.'s Ekeus to check on missiles during Iraq trip.</title>
<headline>U.N.'s Ekeus to check on missiles during Iraq trip.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chief U.N. weapons inspector Rolf Ekeus is due in Baghdad on Sunday and will focus on Iraq's refusal to permit the removal of destroyed missile engines for analysis abroad, a U.N. source said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>A U.N. arms team recently unearthed a large number of missile engines and other parts which Iraq destroyed and buried without U.N. supervision shortly after the end of the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
<p>But Iraq last month prevented U.N. inspectors from taking the excavated engines and other parts abroad to determine their origin and to reach a definitive accounting of any remaining missile stocks.</p>
<p>The U.N. Special Commission (UNSCOM) in charge of scrapping Iraq's weapons of mass destruction has information about SCUD missiles which Iraq obtained from the then-Soviet Union before the Gulf War. It also knows about the approximately 40 launched each against Saudi Arabia and Israel during the wa,r as well as roughly how many were used during the 1980-88 Iran-Iraq conflict.</p>
<p>But UNSCOM has not been able to obtain a clear accounting because it later learned Iraq was capable of producing missiles of its own.</p>
<p>Ekeus, UNSCOM's executive chairman, has said between six and 16 missiles remain unaccounted for.</p>
<p>He complained in a letter last month to Iraqi deputy Prime Minister Tareq Aziz that Baghdad's refusal to permit the removal of the destroyed missile parts was a breach of a key Security Council resolution and &quot;a new departure of the most serious character.&quot;</p>
<p>He reluctantly agreed the matter could be dealt with during his next bi-monthly visit to Iraq, now set to begin this weekend, while the missile parts in question remain at a temporary storage site under UNSCOM surveillance.</p>
<p>&quot;It is of paramount importance that in December the matter be resolved in a manner that fully guarantees the Commission's rights and the objectives of the Security Council's resolution,&quot; Ekeus wrote.</p>
<p>Aziz replied that the removal of the destroyed items to the United States and their analysis without Iraqi participation contradicted the spirit of an agreement made in June after a previous standoff between Iraq and UNSCOM.</p>
<p>Aziz added that it was &quot;necessary and highly appropriate that Russian missile engine experts&quot; take part in the analysis, since the engines were Russian-made.</p>
<p>Coincidentally, Ekeus's latest trip to Baghdad comes at a time when the United Nations is close to implementing an agreement concluded last May to enable Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of oil, on a renewable basis, to buy food, medicines and other humanitarian goods to help offset the effects of sanctions in place since Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>A clean bill of health from UNSCOM is a requirement for any easing by the Security Council of the sanctions, which include a ban on Iraqi oil sales. But this is separate from the limited easing of sanctions represented by the &quot;oil-for-food&quot; plan.</p>
<p>Ekeus returned only last weekend from a visit to Gulf states -- but not to Iraq -- to seek voluntary contributions for UNSCOM, whose funds are nearly exhausted.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
