<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234477" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shares end down buffeted by Dow, dollar.</title>
<headline>German shares end down buffeted by Dow, dollar.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's DAX index of top blue-chip shares, coming off an all-time high reached on Tuesday, closed electronic dealings down 0.68 percent as some investors turned to profit-taking.</p>
<p>The final tally in IBIS electronic trading was down 19.87 points at 2,880.89 points, but up from the day's low of 2,858.49 and well above the bourse close of 2,866.07 as the market was encouraged by the dollar recovering above 1.56 marks.</p>
<p>Traders in Frankfurt had expected shares to regain even more ground in the afternoon IBIS session, but DAX shares followed as the Dow rose and fell repeatedly along a 30-point range below its opening at 6,442.69.</p>
<p>The DAX could take another run at the 2,900 barrier in the next several days -- barring further downward pressure from Wall Street, traders said. &quot;The 2,900 mark is in sight, but keep your eye on the Dow,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>The DAX broke through 2,900 for the first time ever in late computer trade on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Dealers said losses on Wall Street on Tuesday -- when the Dow fell more than 79 points -- and the dollar's drop from 23-month highs also reached on Tuesday weighed on DAX shares as German markets opened.</p>
<p>The dollar, a major factor in the price of German exports, edged below 1.56 marks after German economic growth in the third quarter exceeded most expectations. Year-on-year gross domestic product growth doubled to 2.4 percent in the third quarter.</p>
<p>Pharmaceuticals group Schering AG and car maker Volkswagen AG led the way among the day's few gainers.</p>
<p>Schering closed IBIS dealings at 133.00 marks, up three, continuing an steep ascent that began last Tuesday when it traded at 120.20.</p>
<p>Traders said Schering had climbed on one large buy order and said there were rumours in the market that the company could become target of a take-over. But the company denied it would be taken over by any other group.</p>
<p>Volkswagen finished bourse trade up six marks at 598.50. The shares are seen as a buy opportunity below 600 marks, traders said. The stock has been under pressure since suffering a string of setbacks in its legal battle with U.S. giant General Motors Corp.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
