<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234464" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Boutros-Ghali pulls back but does not leave race.</title>
<headline>Boutros-Ghali pulls back but does not leave race.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>In the latest twist to a bizarre election for U.N. secretary-general, Boutros Boutros-Ghali &quot;temporarily&quot; suspended on Wednesday his bid for a second five-year term but without withdrawing from the race.</p>
<p>At the same time, no other candidate has yet officially come forward to contest the election, already jolted by a U.S. veto on Nov. 19 on the only secret ballot so far held by the Security Council.</p>
<p>Security Council President Paolo Fulci of Italy told reporters: &quot;The secretary-general, Dr. Boutros Boutros-Ghali, has indicated to me that he intends to suspend his candidature for the time being.&quot;</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali apparently did not at this time want to risk another vote in the Security Council and see his 14-1 advantage wilt as a result of likely defections, diplomats said. But at the same time he still wanted to keep his name before the council and review developments further.</p>
<p>Some diplomats interpreted his move as beckoning other candidates to step forward. Three African states have already spoken to Fulci but have not submitted names officially.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Boutros-Ghali's spokeswoman Sylvana Foa said the &quot;suspension&quot; did not mean he had withdrawn from seeking re-election. His term expires on Dec. 31.</p>
<p>Foa told reporters: &quot;He is maintaining his candidacy, he has not withdrawn his candidacy. He simply feels there is no reason to take another vote on his candidacy.&quot;</p>
<p>Fulci, in his comments, also said the council &quot;once again underlined the need to have as soon as possible candidatures from African member states so that it can discharge its responsibilities.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the 15-member body would meet again on the issue on Friday and Monday and members hoped names would be submitted by then.</p>
<p>Despite a recommendation from the head of the Organisation of African Unity, African ambassadors have not officially forwarded names of candidates. The OAU in July backed Boutros-Ghali, an Egyptian and the first secretary-general from the African continent.</p>
<p>President Paul Biya of Cameroon, the chairman of the OAU in a letter, dated Nov. 29, recommended that African leaders submit other names besides Boutros-Ghali so that the continent would not lose its hold on the top U.N. post for another five years. The council has agreed to give African candidates preference.</p>
<p>Among Africans spoken of as potential candidates are: Under-Secretary-General Kofi Annan of Ghana, who heads U.N. peacekeeping operations; Ivory Coast Foreign Minister Amara Essy; Hamid Algabid of Niger, secretary-general of the Organisation of the Islamic Conference; OAU secretary-general Salim A. Salim of Tanzania; Foreign Minister Moustapha Niasse of Senegal, and Olara Otunnu, a former Ugandan U.N. envoy who heads the New York-based International Peace Academy.</p>
<p>Envoys from Ghana, the Ivory Coast and Niger have approached Fulci informally about their respective candidates, diplomats said.</p>
<p>In Washington, a White House spokesman said: &quot;We welcome his decision to suspend his candidacy because it's going to allow the names of other well-qualified African candidates to come forward and be considered by the Security Council.&quot;</p>
<p>But spokesman David Johnson repeated that the United States would not be pushing the candidacies of other people for the job. Any candidate Washington would support is bound to be rejected by other members because of anger at its veto of Boutros-Ghali.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
