<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234487" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Workers' rights not an issue for WTO, Brazil says.</title>
<headline>Workers' rights not an issue for WTO, Brazil says.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil believes that a global conference next week should steer clear of workers' rights and focus instead on discussing ways of boosting international trade, Foreign Minister Luiz Felipe Lampreia said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Lampreia said that the December 9-13 summit of the World Trade Organisation (WTO) in Singapore would not be the right forum to consider the so-called &quot;social clause&quot; as this was a matter for the International Labour Organisation.</p>
<p>The &quot;social clause&quot; links workers rights -- such as trade union affiliation, maternity leave and pension protection -- to the opening of trade barriers.</p>
<p>&quot;Brazil has the same position (on workers' rights) as the European Union and most Latin American and Asian countries,&quot; Lampreia told a news conference during a visit to Lisbon.</p>
<p>&quot;Brazil believes that the matter of the protection of workers' rights belongs to the jurisdiction of the International Labour Organisation in Geneva,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the role of the WTO should be to promote the expansion of international trade and thus improve the conditions of workers,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Lampreia has said that Brazil, Latin America's largest country, would not bend to demands from the United States, among others, for trade-linked labour standards at the WTO summit.</p>
<p>Brazil, like many developing nations, fears an attempt by countries such as the United States at the WTO summit to reduce its comparative wage advantage by tying a minimum set of workers' rights to trade issues.</p>
<p>The &quot;social clause&quot; issue is one of a number of disagreements, that threaten to turn the Singapore meeting into a slanging match rather than the trouble-free encounter its organisers have been working feverishly to achieve.</p>
<p>Brazil, among the world's 10 largest economies, will go to the summit as one of the leaders of the southern hemisphere.</p>
<p>Lampreia was speaking on the first day of a three-day official visit to Lisbon before heading to the WTO summit.</p>
<p>He and his Portuguese counterpart Jaime Gama said they had discussed ways to remove bureaucratic obstacles to the recognition of professional qualifications in the two countries.</p>
<p>A perennial thorn in ties between the two nations are the complaints of Brazilian dentists, architects and other professionals in Portugal who say they have a tough time getting their qualifications recognised by the local authorities.</p>
<p>Lampreia said Portuguese investment by industrial and financial services groups such as Sonae Investimentos and the Grupo Espirito Santo had risen substantially in recent years and boosted the number of Portuguese professionals living in Brazil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
