<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234522" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures paused on Wednesday after six consecutive session of gains and slipped back with Bunds ahead of a German unemployment report and the Bundesbank monetary policy council meeting.</p>
<p>Analysts said it wasn't surprising to see some profit taking, especially as some appeared to have become to optimistic about the prospects for German rate cuts soon.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, traders said the contract found good support around 129.50 today and that the bull run, which has propelled the future more than four points higher since the beginning of November, remained intact.  </p>
<p>&quot;People were a bit too excited about how soon a rate cut (in Germany) would come,&quot; Philippe Brossard, head of research at ABN Amro in Paris.</p>
<p>March PIBOR slipped back three basis points pushing out the spread over the equivalent Euromark contract out to 25 basis points from 21 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A 1.0 percent third quarter rise in German gross domestic product gave traders a good excuse to take profits and bond market declines in the U.S. later weighed on the contract.</p>
<p>However, analysts said Thursday's German unemployment report could well post a large market-friendly rise.  </p>
<p>&quot;Unemployment may be a bit more exciting (than GDP). Seasonal factors tend to be bad at the end of the year so the unadjusted number could look quite horrible,&quot; Brossard said.</p>
<p>Although some traders were still holding out for a Bundesbank rate cut after its council meeting on Thursday all 10 economists polled by Reuters expected no change in its repo rate this week.</p>
<p>The 10-year spread between French and German government bonds remained in negative territory at minus three basis points compared with minus five on Tuesday.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
