<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234589" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa takes first steps since surgery.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa takes first steps since surgery.</headline>
<byline>Clarence Fernandez</byline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mother Teresa took her first steps on Wednesday since life-saving surgery last week, and said she was strong and wanted to go home.</p>
<p>Aided by medical staff, Mother Teresa, 86, walked for the first time since her heart operation, said Dr Tarun Praharaj, a member of the panel treating the Roman Catholic nun.</p>
<p>&quot;She walked with support. Just a few steps,&quot; he told reporters in Calcutta.</p>
<p>The missionary was impatient to leave Calcutta's B.M. Birla Heart Research Centre and continue her work, the doctor said.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm quite strong. I want to go home,&quot; Praharaj quoted Mother Teresa as saying.</p>
<p>Praharaj said doctors hoped to let her go home in a few days. &quot;We will try to release her at the weekend. Maybe three, four days from now. But it all depends on her progress.&quot;</p>
<p>The 1979 Nobel Peace Prize winner had surgery last week to clear two blocked arteries and had appeared to be recovering when longstanding kidney and lung problems resurfaced.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa, revered for her life-long devotion to the destitute and dying, has been suffering from an irregular heartbeat, bronchial pneumonia and weak kidneys.</p>
<p>Praharaj said the nun's kidney functions had improved.</p>
<p>&quot;On a scale of one to 10, I would rate her three,&quot; Praharaj said when asked how much Mother Teresa had improved since the surgery.</p>
<p>He said the doctors were keeping their fingers crossed that Mother Teresa would continue to gain strength. &quot;Doctors are encouraged and optimistic. However, Mother is not out of danger yet,&quot; a regular medical bulletin said, citing her continued irregular heart beat.</p>
<p>Praharaj said Mother Teresa was well enough up to sit in a chair for brief periods. She met sisters from her Missionaries of Charity order in the morning, and listened to mass. On Tuesday, doctors said her recovery would be a slow process and she might never be as active as before.</p>
<p>Despite a series of health problems, Mother Teresa had kept up a seemingly tireless pace in her Order and travelled widely before her latest illness. Her order runs 456 homes in 111 countries.</p>
<p>The nun, who was fitted with a heart pacemaker in 1989, had her first heart operation in the United States in 1991 and her second at the Birla centre in 1993.</p>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda planned to make a special trip to Calcutta on Thursday to visit Mother Teresa in the clinic, his office said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
