<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="234552" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish bonds soften, banking statistics awaited.</title>
<headline>Irish bonds soften, banking statistics awaited.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish government bonds were softer in thin late trade on Wednesday on the back of profit-taking and in line with core European markets, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market awaited the release of Irish end-October credit numbers from the central bank on Thursday.</p>
<p>While Irish private sector credit growth is expected to reflect continued strength in the economy, it is not expected to lead to a near-term rise in interest rates, they said.</p>
<p>Some economists see Irish private-sector credit growth as high as 14 percent at end-October compared with 13.3 percent at end-September.</p>
<p>&quot;Thursday's data is much more important than yesterday's EBR data. Everyone knows that Ireland's revenue is strong while there is a big question mark still hanging over Irish interest rates at the moment,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, the market has been very quiet today, trade has been thin. The Irish market is weaker on profit-taking and in line with core European markets in general,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>By 1620 GMT, the 6.5 percent bond due 2001 had eased 25 pence to 102.35 to yield 5.84 percent while the eight percent bond due 2006 had slipped 45 pence to 110.15 to yield 6.44 percent.</p>
<p>	 European analysts said German data showing economic</p>
<p>recovery more robust than expected had weakened prospects for interest rate cuts and could point to trouble ahead for the recent rally in European bonds.</p>
<p>Wednesday's economic data, covering gross domestic product and industrial orders, helped to dampen recent talk about the chances of a German-led round of European interest rate cuts.</p>
<p>--Damien Lynch, Dublin newsroom 353-1-660-3377.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
