<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23474" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-LENTINI SEEKS TO RECAPTURE FORM AT ATALANTA.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-LENTINI SEEKS TO RECAPTURE FORM AT ATALANTA.</headline>
<dateline>BERGAMO, Italy 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Italian international winger Gianluigi Lentini said on Friday he wanted to recapture his top form at Atalanta where he will play for a year on loan from his club AC Milan.</p>
<p>&quot;I just want to go back to being the good player I was before the accident,&quot; said Lentini, 27, who suffered severe head injuries in a near-fatal car crash in 1993.</p>
<p>Lentini, transferred to Milan in 1992 for what was then a world record sum, is on loan in a deal which is said would cost Atalanta around $600,000.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm coming here really looking forward to playing. I chose Atalanta because I'll have the opportunity to play,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Since his accident, Lentini has struggled to regain the form that made him a local hero in Turin, his club before Milan.</p>
<p>The move to Bergamo-based Atalanta reunites Lentini, who fell out with ex-Milan coach Fabio Capello last season, with his former coach at Torino, Emiliano Mondonico.</p>
<p>&quot;Mondonico practically made me,&quot; Lentini said. &quot;He gave me the chance to make my mark and I really hope I can keep my promises here.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERGAMO, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
