<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23509" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: OLYMPICS-AUSTRALIA UPS SECURITY AFTER MASSACRE AND PROTESTS.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-AUSTRALIA UPS SECURITY AFTER MASSACRE AND PROTESTS.</headline>
<byline>Mark Bendeich</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia has stepped up</p>
<p>security spending ahead of the 2000 Sydney Olympic Games after</p>
<p>suggestions the recent Port Arthur massacre and protests against</p>
<p>French nuclear testing highlighted a need for extra vigilance.</p>
<p>The government has boosted funding to its Protective</p>
<p>Security Coordination Centre, which oversees the security of</p>
<p>diplomats and VIPs, by 38 percent in the current financial year</p>
<p>(July-June), according to budget papers released last week.</p>
<p>The details, reported by a local newspaper on Friday, cite</p>
<p>the Port Arthur shooting of 35 people in April and the storm of</p>
<p>local protest against French nuclear tests in the Pacific as</p>
<p>among the biggest recent security threats.</p>
<p>&quot;The massacre...at Port Arthur, Tasmania, showed that a fine</p>
<p>line exists between the measures appropriate to countering</p>
<p>terrorism and responses to serious criminal incidents,&quot; the</p>
<p>centre said in its budget review for the year to June 30.</p>
<p>The massacre in a former convict settlement in Australia's</p>
<p>island state, allegedly by a lone gunman, sparked a national</p>
<p>plan to ban rapid-fire guns. That in turn led to mass rallies of</p>
<p>gun-owners and fears for the prime minister's security.</p>
<p>Addressing one angry pro-gun rally in June, Prime Minister</p>
<p>John Howard wore what looked like a bullet-proof vest under his</p>
<p>jacket. One gun lobbyist warned of bloodshed if the ban held.</p>
<p>The centre also referred in the budget papers to</p>
<p>anti-nuclear protests, which culminated last year in the</p>
<p>fire-bombing of France's consulate in Perth and prompted the</p>
<p>centre to tighten security around all French missions.</p>
<p>But French diplomats were not the only foreign dignatories</p>
<p>accorded high security, the centre's review said, adding that</p>
<p>the risk of incidents at Indonesian missions remained high.</p>
<p>&quot;Additional protection continued to be provided to</p>
<p>Indonesian missions in Canberra, Sydney, Melbourne and Darwin,&quot;</p>
<p>it said.</p>
<p>&quot;While the threat of a serious attack against Indonesian</p>
<p>interest in Australia is assessed to be low, the risk of an</p>
<p>incident causing affront to dignity and embarrassment for both</p>
<p>the Australian and Indonesian governments remain high,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Relations between Australia and neighbouring Indonesia have</p>
<p>at times been rocked by groups in Australia opposed to Jakarta's</p>
<p>rule of East Timor, a former Portuguese colony.</p>
<p>The centre also said it was &quot;amending&quot; security measures for</p>
<p>visits by foreign leaders after an incident in Australia earlier</p>
<p>this year when Malaysian Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad was</p>
<p>abused by a protester posing as a journalist.</p>
<p>The office of Australian Attorney-General Daryl Williams,</p>
<p>who is responsible for the nation's chief security agencies,</p>
<p>declined on Friday to comment on the centre's budget review.</p>
<p>But a security analyst said the centre was clearly using the</p>
<p>string of recent security threats in an effort to persuade the</p>
<p>government to keep bolstering its funding.</p>
<p>&quot;I dare say, if they had a chance to rewrite it (the</p>
<p>review), they would cite the trouble at parliament house last</p>
<p>week as well,&quot; said Australian National University's Michael</p>
<p>McKinley, referring a violent anti-budget riot on August 12.</p>
<p>Australia is seen as a safe country, free of acts such as</p>
<p>the bombing during the Atlanta Olympic Games last month that</p>
<p>killed two people. But internal disquiet does threaten to</p>
<p>increase, McKinley told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Politicians are not well regarded at the moment and there's</p>
<p>an accelerated wealth disparity underway in Australia,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
