<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235182" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US West Coast late crudes steady, ANS deal rumored.</title>
<headline>US West Coast late crudes steady, ANS deal rumored.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast light crudes flattened late along with West Intermediate Intermediate (WTI) crude, while rumors circulated that a cargo of Alaskan grade sold at a slightly firmer discount.</p>
<p>Traders said a West Coast refinery bought a spot supply of Alaska North Slope (ANS) at a discount of $1.87 off January WTI for January delivery.</p>
<p>The latest confirmed January shipment sold early Tuesday at a $1.95 a barrel discount.</p>
<p>The deal remained unconfirmed because the seller never comments, and the buyer was not immediately available.  </p>
<p>Outright ANS prices stayed flat with the spot WTI market, which held at 10 cents over Monday's late levels at $24.75/24.85.</p>
<p>Absolute ANS prices ranged $21.55/21.85 a barrel. Another regional light grade, Line 63, remained unchanged from early levels of $22.75/22.95.</p>
<p>Backed-up heavy crudes at the Mobil and Texaco refineries in Los Angeles forced larger discounts for Kern River grade on Tuesday. Bids were talked down about 10 cents from postings, while offers eased five cents from last week to touch parity with postings.</p>
<p>&quot;I think in January and February we're heading into a discount market,&quot; for heavy crude, a trader said.</p>
<p>But outright Kern prices rose along with a 50-cent increase in Chevron's posted prices on Monday.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau, +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
