<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235256" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: North Europe cocoa demand muted ahead of year-end.</title>
<headline>North Europe cocoa demand muted ahead of year-end.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cocoa consumers in continental northwest Europe were sidelined as London futures traded lower after Tuesday's rallies, traders said.</p>
<p>Physical markets were seen remaining quietly steady until early January.</p>
<p>&quot;Business won't pick up unless prices fall dramatically and there are no reasons that they should,&quot; a German trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the same time, the price upside appears limited by prospects of huge arrivals in West African ports once the current delays are overcome.&quot;</p>
<p>Raw materials buyers did not focus on cocoa supply fundamentals as chocolate plants were preoccupied with end-of-year production schedules and logistical disruptions.</p>
<p>Many manufacturers shut for maintenance during the December 20-January 4 fortnight and wind down raw materials purchases a few weeks in advance.</p>
<p>The French truck strike meant some butter cargoes did not get in and out of the country but this had no impact on prices.</p>
<p>Strike action at German confectionery plants was also ending after a few days of crisis as employers gave in to worker demands to maintain full sick pay arrangements.</p>
<p>London cocoa futures were down on profit-taking and origin sales while sterling was off its lows after tumbling from four-year highs on Tuesday.</p>
<p>March was down four stg at 940 at 1445 GMT.</p>
<p>Large-scale consumer buying was last seen in late November near the November 19 eight-months-lows of 903 stg on March.</p>
<p>Cocoa arrivals in Ivory Coast at the end of November were down an estimated 20 percent from last year at 285,000 tonnes because of rains in August/September, analysts said.</p>
<p>A Dutch trader said sellers used this to hike offers but buyers argued that arrivals should pick up in December and January.</p>
<p>Commenting on consumption, he noted fourth quarter chocolate production had run at high levels and grindings figures in early January should reflect this.</p>
<p>Cif Hamburg bean prices were at 2.32 marks/kg for December, up from 2.27 marks last week.</p>
<p>First quarter 1997 beans were at 2.35 marks versus 2.32.</p>
<p>The cocoa butter ratio was little changed at 2.70 up to March 1997, which implied prices liquid ex-works of 6.53 marks.</p>
<p>Sterling was fixed in Frankfurt on Wednesday at 2.5690 marks compared with 2.5558 marks a week ago.</p>
<p>--Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
