<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235207" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NORWAY: FOCUS - Saga debuts in UK N.Sea oil sector.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Saga debuts in UK N.Sea oil sector.</headline>
<byline>Tanya Pang</byline>
<dateline>OSLO 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway's largest independent oil company Saga Petroleum made its debut into the British offshore oil sector on Wednesday, confirming a widely known $1.23 billion takeover of North Sea explorer Santa Fe Exploration.</p>
<p>The deal, with state-owned Kuwait Petroleum Corp (KPC), is the largest transaction in the British upstream sector since LASMO Plc took over Ultramar Plc in 1991.</p>
<p>It is also the second largest acquisition by a Norwegian company after Kvaerner's 8.9 billion crowns ($1.4 billion) takeover of Britain's Trafalgar House Plc in April.</p>
<p>Analysts said the terms of the acquisition appeared more positive than previously thought.</p>
<p>Weeks of speculation, during which the price of the deal had been leaked, had left analysts downbeat on the premium Saga would pay over estimates of Santa Fe's value which were closer to $700-$800 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Most people are surprised at what seems to be a unique tax break for Saga, which knocks down some of the premium they've paid,&quot; said a London-based analyst.</p>
<p>Saga said the acquisition would be financed without raising new equity. The company will assume a debt of $500 million.</p>
<p>The takeover, effective from June 30, this year, will raise Saga's oil production by 50,000 barrels per day(bpd) to 190,000.</p>
<p>But, more importantly in the long run, it gives Saga a way into Britain's offshore oil sector, with activities over the entire North Sea and the Atlantic margin, which includes areas west of Shetland and Ireland and the Faroese continental shelf.</p>
<p>Santa Fe holds interests in six producing fields while its exploration portfolio consists of interests in 44 blocks offshore on the British shelf, 20 blocks on the Irish shelf and one onshore block in Britain.</p>
<p>It also holds a nine percent stake in the Britannia field, the largest gas field under development in British waters.</p>
<p>&quot;Saga has for a long time been assessing the UK continental shelf with a view to an acquisition in line with the company's strategy and portfolio,&quot; a statement from Saga said.</p>
<p>It said the purchase price was based on its assessment of Santa Fe's estimated reserves -- 200 million barrels of oil equivalent with 70 percent oil and 30 percent gas -- production, and exploration acreage.</p>
<p>&quot;Based on known and probable reserves, we will reach a production of approximately 220,000 bpd of oil equivalent in 2000,&quot; Saga's chief executive Asbjoern Larsen told a news conference.</p>
<p>Larsen said the deal would provide increased value for shareholders at an estimated rate of over 15 percent return on equity after tax.</p>
<p>&quot;We will also get significant strategic values...the company will be very well positioned for future operations on the Irish, British and the Faroese continental shelf,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>An analyst said Saga would benefit from the unique tax relief offered by Norwegian authorities of about 78 percent on the interest costs on the financing loan.</p>
<p>But he said Saga would nevertheless remain under pressure to prove the value of the deal to investors.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm not as negative as yesterday. The tax break is a bit of salvation, but they have paid a very full price. They need to make some exploration discoveries to convince the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Saga's share price fell sharply when trading resumed after the announcement, but quickly bounced back off a low of 96.50 crowns to be 2.5 crowns lower at 103 crowns at 1212 GMT. ($1=6.51 Norwegian crowns)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OSLO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NORWAY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
