<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235373" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>VATICAN: Carey said &quot;very pleased&quot; with Pope meeting.</title>
<headline>Carey said &quot;very pleased&quot; with Pope meeting.</headline>
<byline>Philip Pullella</byline>
<dateline>VATICAN CITY 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Archbishop of Canterbury George Carey prayed before the tomb of St Peter on Wednesday and pronounced his first official meeting with Pope John Paul a success in their difficult dialogue on Christian unity.</p>
<p>&quot;He told us he was very pleased (with the meeting),&quot; Canon Jim Rosenthal, director of communications for the Anglican Communion, told Reuters as Carey toured St Peter's Basilica.</p>
<p>The spiritual head of the 70 million member Anglican Communion visited Christendom's largest church the day after his first official meeting with the Pope.</p>
<p>They met unofficially in 1992 during a visit that was made tense by Carey's criticism before his arrival in Rome of the Roman Catholic ban on contraception.</p>
<p>Carey, accompanied by his wife Eileen, knelt to pray before what archaeologists believe is the burial place of St Peter, the first Pope, directly under the basilica's main altar.</p>
<p>The Anglican leader also visited the crypt where modern popes are buried. He stopped before the tomb of Pope Paul VI, whose 1963-1978 reign coincided with the start of a Catholic-Anglican dialogue after more than four centuries.</p>
<p>The churches split in 1534 when England's King Henry VIII broke with Rome over papal authority. They remain divided over the issue and recently hit a stumbling block over women priests.</p>
<p>At the end of Tuesday's meeting, the Pope, Carey and other prelates in the Anglican delegation delivered a group blessing.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, we expect your blessing for Rome,&quot; the Pope told Carey in an impromptu remark. The future course of relations will be a topic of talks at an official audience on Thursday.</p>
<p>In formal speeches, both emphasised the drive for unity.</p>
<p>&quot;Our churches bear the marks of separation and division,&quot; Carey told the Pope. &quot;We cannot undo overnight doctrinal differences and the bitternesses that have resulted from the legacy of history but we are able to confront them as fellow Christians...&quot;</p>
<p>Carey became Anglican leader in 1990. Two years later the Church of England, mother church of Anglicanism, voted to allow women priests in a move that severely tested relations between Canterbury and Rome. The first were ordained in 1994.</p>
<p>The 76-year-old Polish Pope, who prayed with then Anglican leader Robert Runcie during a historic 1982 visit to Canterbury, told Carey that Anglicans and Catholics had not ceased to be brothers and sisters in God despite differences.</p>
<p>&quot;The task before us is to strengthen that bond, until we reach the full unity that is Christ's will for us,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On Tuesday night Carey worshipped at Rome's Episcopalian church with Cecilia Monge Teran De Erazo, the first woman to be ordained an Anglican priest in Italy's capital.</p>
<p>The Catholic Church says it does not have the authority to allow women to become priests because Christ chose only men as his apostles and was therefore reflecting &quot;divine will&quot;.</p>
<p>Because of their opposition to women priests, a handful of Anglican bishops, more than 300 clergy and thousands of lay members have converted to Catholicism.</p>
<p>Recognition of the Pope's supreme authority over any unified Christian Church, or Papal primacy, has been another thorny issue testing the Catholic-Anglican dialogue.</p>
<p>The Pope said in a 1995 encyclical that for the sake of unity he was willing to seek an accommodation with other Christian denominations on the future role of the papacy.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VATICAN CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VATICAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
