<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235303" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: EU, U.S. seen working to avoid WTO clash on Cuba.</title>
<headline>EU, U.S. seen working to avoid WTO clash on Cuba.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>GENEVA 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union and the United States are working to head off a major row at the World Trade Organisation over Cuba that could seriously undermine the fledgling body, diplomats and trade analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>They said the two powers were positioning themselves to ensure that a WTO panel on the controversial U.S. Helms-Burton law hitting at foreign investment in the Cuban economy did not have to publish its findings.</p>
<p>&quot;It now seems quite clear that this case will not go to its full term,&quot; said one envoy. &quot;Both the big powers recognise the dangers to the global trading system.&quot;</p>
<p>And in an interview with Reuters on Tuesday just before the body's first Ministerial Conference in Singapore next week, WTO Director-General Renato Ruggiero said he hoped the dispute &quot;can be settled out of court.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I believe that this is possible and if the two parties can solve this problem before there is a (panel) ruling, then I think it would be a major victory of the (WTO dispute settlement) system,&quot; he said in an interview.</p>
<p>The analysts said clear evidence of big-power manouevring on the issue was a decision by EU finance ministers this week to a tougher stance towards Havana on human rights, and a U.S. response welcoming the switch.</p>
<p>Creation of the panel, which would normally return its findings around the middle of next year, was agreed by the WTO's Dispute Settlement Body (DSB) last month on the second request from the EU.</p>
<p>Brussels, which has firm backing in its stance from almost every other country in the 125-member WTO, argues that the Helms-Burton law, named for its Congressional sponsors, strikes at the basic rules of international trade.</p>
<p>The EU says its imposition of penalties in the United States on foreign firms that &quot;traffic&quot; in property nationalised in Cuba after the 1959 revolution is an attempt to impose U.S. law on other countries through unacceptable &quot;extra-territoriality&quot;.</p>
<p>The Washington administration says the law, which was signed by President Bill Clinton after Cuba in January shot down two planes flown by anti-communist exiles near Havana, is aimed at helping bring democracy to the island.</p>
<p>At the WTO, U.S. officials have signalled that before a panel, whose findings if confirmed by an appeals board would lead to a request to Washington to change the law, they would also argue the measure was one of national security.</p>
<p>The General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade, the WTO's underlying accord, has a clause that allows member countries to waive all trade rules if it sees its sovereignty threatened.</p>
<p>The clause was invoked by the United States in the 1980s when it imposed a trade embargo on then leftist-ruled Nicaragua -- like Cuba also a member of the WTO and then of its predecessor, the GATT.</p>
<p>But U.S. trade officials totally blocked creation of a panel sought by Nicaragua, which was possible under the old trade body, and the clause was never put to the test.</p>
<p>As the Helms-Burton row has built over the past few months, fears have grown at WTO headquarters in Geneva that whichever way a case went it would strike hard at the body's authority.</p>
<p>Diplomats said that if a panel and an appeals board found against the United States and the DSB asked Washington to review the legislation, Congressional opponents of U.S. membership of the WTO would be given weighty ammunition.</p>
<p>But if the case went against the EU and the panel found the U.S. action was covered by the &quot;defence of sovereignty&quot; clause, this could open the way for any member of the body to abandon the rules whenever it got into a political row with a neighbour.</p>
<p>&quot;Either way, it is a lose-lose situation, so there is a lot of pressure to find a way out,&quot; one key envoy said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GENEVA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
