<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235339" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Cockerill and UGB abandon link idea.</title>
<headline>Cockerill and UGB abandon link idea.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian steel makers Cockerill Sambre and Usines Gustave Boel (UGB) said on Wednesday that they had abandoned a project to become partners.</p>
<p>&quot;Cockerill Sambre and UGB have come to the conclusion that they cannot carry out their project to become partners,&quot; the steel makers said in a statement.  </p>
<p>&quot;An examination of profitability, sensitivity to the economic environment and the financial needs have led to the conclusion that a lasting future for Boel could not be guaranteed without weakening Cockerill,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>Cockerill and Boel had set up a working group to look at how to keep as many jobs as possible as well as a &quot;healthy economic environment&quot; in Belgium's southern Walloon steel industry.</p>
<p>The statement said Boel needed a partner with surplus capacities in half finished products at competitive prices and which could offer &quot;a real outlook for the future at its site in La Louviere&quot; -- conditions Cockerill could not meet.</p>
<p>The two companies said they had decided after several weeks of intense study that they could not be partners because of an &quot;absence of complementary aspects and worthwile economic synergies between the two companies.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Paul de Bendern, Brussels newsroom + 32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
