<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235436" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France calls off controversial Thomson sale.</title>
<headline>France calls off controversial Thomson sale.</headline>
<byline>Marcel Michelson</byline>
<dateline>PARIS</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French government called off the controversial sale of electronics group Thomson SA Wednesday in a major policy reversal after weeks of staunchly defending its controversial choice of a buyer.</p>
<p>It was the second privatisation to be halted in less than a month after the government decided to suspend the sale of a state-owned bank.</p>
<p>It comes at a time when Prime Minister Alain Juppe, at a record low in opinion polls, is anxious to avoid another labour revolt following last month's truckers strike.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry said in a statement the suspension of the proposed Thomson sell-off to Lagardere Groupe was due to objections to the planned sale of the company's consumer electronics unit to South Korea's Daewoo Electronics.</p>
<p>Lagardere said in a statement it was still interested in taking over Thomson, which it said was of strategic importance.</p>
<p>The office of Prime Minister Alain Juppe said renewed talks about the sale could start soon.</p>
<p>&quot;The government will launch consultations as rapidly as possible allowing the privatisation to take place on a basis that will be defined very quickly,&quot; Juppe was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The aim of privatising Thomson addresses the necessity for France to have an electronics and defence industry of global standing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Industry Minister Franck Borotra said in a statement the privatisation of Thomson remained essential.</p>
<p>The government said in October it had selected Lagardere Groupe because it was best for French defence interests and would sell the heavily indebted company for a symbolic one franc after a 10.8 billion franc ($2 billion) state capital injection.</p>
<p>Lagardere planned to merge Thomson's 58 percent owned defence electronics unit Thomson-CSF with its own Matra Defence Espace.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry's surprise suspension announcement came on the day the European Commission had been expected to give the green light to the deal.</p>
<p>The ministry said the Privatisation Commission &quot;declared itself incapable of giving a favourable opinion to the Lagardere Groupe offer, because of the terms of Daewoo Electronics' purchase of Thomson Multimedia.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
