<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235457" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - DEC 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK GENERAL NEWS - DEC 4.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek general press:</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI</p>
<p>--Greece's cities face the threat of being isolated by air, sea and road following the expansion of the farmers' blocakades late last night to Thessaloniki's Macedonia Airport and the strike by port workers.</p>
<p>--Confusion yesterday over the US-proposed moratorium on flyovers over Cyprus. Conflicting statements on whether or not Nicosia had agreed to the suspension of flyovers indicate a lack of coordination. Prime Minister Costas Simitis denies that there has been any decision.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROTYPIA</p>
<p>--The seventh day of the farmers' blockade and farmers plan on marching on Athens and isolating the city. Simitis, however, insists he will not meet with farmers as long as roads are blocked.</p>
<p>--A new study shows that 88 percent of Greeks believe there is some to much corruption in public life.</p>
<p>TA NEA</p>
<p>--Government and farmers face off: today's crucial meeting in Larissa between Agriculture Minister Stephanos Tzoumakas and farmers will determine the course of the protest. The government is not prepared to budge from its already announced package of measures, which has already been rejected by the farmers.</p>
<p>--An OECD report shows Greek teachers the worst paid in Europe, but slightly better than Turkey's.</p>
<p>ELEFTHEROS TYPOS</p>
<p>--Defence Minister Akis Tsohatzopoulos lashes out at the proposed moratorium on Cyprus flyovers, calling such a decision 'incomprehensible'.</p>
<p>ETHNOS</p>
<p>--A Thessaloniki prosecutor has laid charges on those farmers blocking access to the Thessaloniki airport and reports say that police are photographing tractor number plates to detect offenders.</p>
<p>--&quot;There are some issues which must be brought to a close,&quot; President Kiro Gligorov of the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia tells Simitis in their brief meeting. The Greek prime minister said his meetings with Gligorov and Turkish President Suleyman Demirel were &quot;social with a political content&quot;.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
