<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235539" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ dlr takes wild ride with Aussie, ends off highs.</title>
<headline>NZ dlr takes wild ride with Aussie, ends off highs.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The New Zealand dollar ended off its highs on Wednesday after trading a wide range under the influence of wild fluctuations in the Australian dollar.</p>
<p>The Kiwi fell more than a cent overnight, hitting a low of US$0.7005 as the Australian unit dived three U.S. cents, reflecting a sharp fall in gold prices and fund managers reweighting positions after the currency's strong recent run.</p>
<p>&quot;With a range like 0.7005 through 0.7113, you could say there was something there for everybody, and those that missed out were probably half asleep,&quot; an Auckland trader said.  </p>
<p>The currency closed at US$0.7084/91 and 67.40 on its Trade-Weighted Index.</p>
<p>&quot;Strong exporter buying took it to its highs, then a bit of profit-taking out of Asia sold it back down,&quot; another dealer commented.</p>
<p>He said the market was getting &quot;sick&quot; of political to-ing and fro-ing, with expectations of a final coalition deal now shifting from this week to next.  </p>
<p>The caretaker National Party government held a meeting of its MPs, and Labour leaders were meeting New Zealand First after an &quot;exchange of papers&quot; covering both policy issues and allocation of ministerial portfolios.</p>
<p>However, Labour leader Helen Clark said the meeting would certainly not be the last.</p>
<p>Both National and Labour aim to form a coalition government with NZ First after October's general election.</p>
<p>A range of US$0.7060-7110 was expected overnight.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
