<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235567" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Lion says Australian market top priority.</title>
<headline>Lion says Australian market top priority.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brewing group Lion Nathan Ltd said on Wednesday that an improved performance in the Australian beer market was its top priority.</p>
<p>Chief Executive Douglas Myers said the area of weakness in Australia had been market share, which at the end of the 1996 financial year was down 1.4 percent on a year ago at 42 percent. This decline had continued into the first quarter of the current year, to 41.2 percent, and Myers said halting that decline was Lion's number one priority.  </p>
<p>&quot;But to give perspective on the decline, it's worth noting that all of the lost volume was in the light beer category. In fact we gained market share in the larger segments of full and mid-strength beer,&quot; Myers said. He said the light beer market was &quot;notoriously fickle&quot;.  </p>
<p>He noted that Lion's Australian competitor Foster's Brewing Group had enjoyed success with its new light beer just as Lion had done several years ago with Tooheys Blue.</p>
<p>&quot;Our operations generate very large sustainable cash flows, we've been good at reducing costs and we have the financial capacity to reverse the trend of market share in Australia,&quot; Myers told Lion Nathan's annual meeting.</p>
<p>Lion had just launched two new beers in Australia, Sydney Bitter in New South Wales, and Hahn Premium nationally.  </p>
<p>Lion had increased the New Zealand premium beer market to 13 percent through brands like Steinlager, while in Australia that segment was undeveloped at about three percent of the total beer market.</p>
<p>He said market share in New Zealand was stable at 54 percent during the financial year, but the last three months indicated that it had grown to more than 55 percent.</p>
<p>Myers said Lion's breweries in Australia and New Zealand currently had about 46 percent market share but 52 percent of the available profit.  </p>
<p>&quot;While market share is important, share of industry profit has always been more important to Lion Nathan.&quot;</p>
<p>Myers said an eight percent rise in operational earnings in the last financial year confirmed Lion's ability to increase profitability in difficult trading conditions.</p>
<p>The result was achieved in spite of a flat beer market in Australia and a declining market in New Zealand.</p>
<p>In New Zealand, improved operating efficiencies and reduced costs enabled Lion to improve margins and grow earnings from operations. The profit impact of lower volumes in Australia was also offset by improved efficiencies and cost savings.  </p>
<p>Myers said an increased tax charge of NZ$76 million resulted from a 1985-90 New Zealand tax audit and the utilisation of previous losses which were carried forward.</p>
<p>Although net earnings after tax and abnormal items fell to NZ$150 million from $202 million last year, the decline was more than explained by the increased tax charge, Myers said.</p>
<p>He said the year saw further strengthening of the balance sheet, with gearing down to 69 percent from 79 percent last year.  </p>
<p>Earnings before interest and tax at the Wuxi Lion Nathan Taihushui Brewery in China almost doubled to NZ$2.3 million, and Myers said growing barriers to entry for foreign brewers would enhance the value of Lion's Chinese breweries.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom (64 4) 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C313">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
