<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235506" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH-Budget bills update for Dec 4 - overview.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH-Budget bills update for Dec 4 - overview.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>We are probably close to seeing the first of the major contentious budget bills survive the Senate. The vote will probably come later today.</p>
<p>The big picture is that this bill -- relating to university charges -- is worth A$300 million in 1997/98 and is part of A$2 billion in doubtful budget measures, themselves part of the government's aim to cut A$7.2 billion from the 1997/98 budget.</p>
<p>(We have defined &quot;doubtful&quot; budget measures as those attracting Labor and Democrat opposition, leaving the government to rely on the uncertain support of the Greens or Independents.)</p>
<p>So if this bill passes then a sizeable chunk of the doubtful measures will have got through.</p>
<p>All the rest, however, remain doubtful.</p>
<p>This Higher Education Amendment Bill is looking good because it has survived two attempts at serious amendment with Independent support in the past 24 hours.</p>
<p>Classically, the Senate first debates a bill, then goes into an amendment mode -- the committee of the whole -- and then finally votes on whatever comes out of the committee stage.</p>
<p>This bill has not been voted on finally, but the important point is that the non-government parties have failed to amend it in the committee.</p>
<p>One of the amendments attempted to delete a fiscally important measure in the bill: hikes in university charges worth A$66 million in 1997/98.</p>
<p>It is now expected that the non-government parties will try to delete the bill's other big fiscal measure: a drop in the income threshhold that initiates repayment of student debts to the tax office, which is worth A$230 million in 1997/98.</p>
<p>Since Education Minister Amanda Vanstone has spoken warmly of some minor Indpendent amendments, and has even moved her own changes to soften the bill's impact, we can assume that that second fiscal measure will also survive the amendment process.</p>
<p>If so, an essentially unchanged bill will come out of the committee stage and the two Independents will give the government the essential two votes to turn it into law.</p>
<p>NEXT ...</p>
<p>The last word was that the next bill in the Senate would be an uncontentious package of tax law changes and that would be followed by the Telstra Bill.</p>
<p>This would put off until next week all the remaining contentious budget bills, which would be worth A$1.7 billion.</p>
<p>The Senate is supposed to finish the year's sittings at the end of next week.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
