<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235531" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Ex-MOF official says dlr over 115 yen excessive.</title>
<headline>Ex-MOF official says dlr over 115 yen excessive.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Japanese Vice Finance Minister Makoto Utsumi said on Wednesday that a rise in the dollar above 115 yen would be excessive, and said between 105 yen and 115 yen was a reasonable level.</p>
<p>He made the comments in an interview with Reuters Financial Television (RFTV).  </p>
<p>Utsumi, now a professor at Japan's Keio University, also said a recent rally in the Japanese government bond market did not reflect the reality of the Japanese economy, which was recovering gradually.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the institutional investors concentrating on purchasing Japanese government bonds have the assumption that the Japanese economy is growing only one percent or so. I think it does not reflect the reality. It's now the bubble price,&quot; he said. &quot;If they continue to do that, misled by their own misunderstanding of the reality, I would predict they would have a loss,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Referring to foreign exchange rates, Utsumi said: &quot;If the yen weakens beyond 115, say 116, 117, I think it's excessive and the market should recognise this. A level between 105 yen and 115 yen is a reasonable range.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think both sides of the Pacific (Japan and the United States) would have a concern if the yen weakens excessively and if the dollar strengthens excessively beyond fundamentals,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
