<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235537" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Lion blames restructure for staff loss.</title>
<headline>Lion blames restructure for staff loss.</headline>
<dateline>AUCKLAND 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lion Nathan Ltd Chief Executive Douglas Myers said on Wednesday the company's ongoing restructuring was the most likely cause for the departure of several senior managers over the last year.</p>
<p>Myers, asked to explain the resignations of top management over the last year, said Lion had brought in a number of new people when Chief Operating Officer Kevin Roberts joined the company eight years ago.  </p>
<p>&quot;We are in a mature business. That is a fact of life,&quot; Myers said. &quot;Some of those people have found the constraints of our industry such that they have sought fame and fortune elsewhere,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Myers noted that many had gone to top tier enterprises after leaving Lion.</p>
<p>&quot;We've also been through a protracted degree of restructuring and that is not over. When we bought Bond Breweries they were in a state of dis-equilibrium and shock,&quot; he said. Roberts and Myers decided then that leaving intact the regional structure in Australia was an appropriate move to allow  </p>
<p>the breweries to rebuild in their local communities.</p>
<p>But confronting a national competitor in Fosters with a handful of regional breweries &quot;has really proved impossible&quot;.</p>
<p>Under Australian Managing Director Gordon Cairns, Lion would seek to develop a more united, centralised operation in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;Inevitably, as a result of that, there have people whose careers and aspirations have been unable to be met,&quot; Myers said.  </p>
<p>Roberts has already announced his resignation, but will remain on the board. Myers and Roberts said the departure of Roberts, who is leaving to pursue personal interests, was amicable. -- Wellington Newsroom (64-4-4734746)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AUCKLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
