<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235559" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Labour confirms &quot;exchange of papers&quot; with NZ First.</title>
<headline>Labour confirms &quot;exchange of papers&quot; with NZ First.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Labour and New Zealand First parties exchanged papers covering policy issues and allocation of ministerial portfolios, and were set to hold fresh coalition talks later on Wednesday, a Labour spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been an exchange of papers today. It's likely there's going to be a meeting later on today, but a time for that has not been scheduled yet,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>He said he was loath to describe the documents as a definitive coalition proposal. But, asked if they covered both policy areas and portfolios, he said: &quot;They cover everything.&quot;  </p>
<p>NZ First is also in coalition talks with the caretaker National Party government.</p>
<p>Caretaker Prime Minister Jim Bolger declined comment on the state of coalition negotiations as he entered a meeting of National's parliamentary caucus.</p>
<p>National and Labour have both been negotiating to form a government with NZ First since an inconclusive general election on October 12. Parliament is due to convene for the first time by December 13. -- Wellington newsroom 64 4 473-4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
