<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235606" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai stocks end at 40-month low on foreign sales.</title>
<headline>Thai stocks end at 40-month low on foreign sales.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai stocks ended at their lowest level in 40 months as foreigners sold out and fears grew of a major foreign exodus from the bourse, traders said.</p>
<p>The SET Index shed 7.49 points, or 0.83 percent, to close below the key 900-point level at 898.32, on trade worth 3.53 billion baht. The SET-50 closed down 0.55 points to 68.00.</p>
<p>The previous lowest close was at 893.14 on July 27, 1993.</p>
<p>&quot;The first worry is the government's ability to deal with the economy but the other is that people are worried foreign mutual funds might leave the market,&quot; said an analyst at Pacific Finance and Securities.  </p>
<p>&quot;They mostly sold banks ... one reason is economics the other is the policies the government has to improve the economy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thailand is set to post economic growth of under 7.00 percent this year, its lowest for a decade, while carrying a current account deficit of around 8.00 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>&quot;The positions the foreigners took prior to the election are being unwoumd now. They have been net sellers for months now,&quot; said another senior analyst.</p>
<p>Siam Commercial Bank lost four baht to 188, Thai Farmers shed three baht to 135 and Siam Cement dipped 12 to 832.</p>
<p>-- James Mclean (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
