<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235702" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Leprosy down, but not out, in Vietnam.</title>
<headline>Leprosy down, but not out, in Vietnam.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam is reaching World Health Organisation targets for the elimination of leprosy, but the crippling disease is still afflicting many of the country's poorest areas, a WHO official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The official, who declined to be named, said state programmes to wipe out the disease had proven highly effective.</p>
<p>But she said poor health care and access to remote areas meant that at local levels the incidence of leprosy was still high.</p>
<p>&quot;At a national level Vietnam has achieved its goal of bringing the disease under control, but in 15 provinces the incidence is still very high,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Estimates of leprosy victims and the actual number being treated vary widely in Vietnam.</p>
<p>An official at the National Dermatology Institute in Hanoi said earlier this year that an estimated 33,860 sufferers were being treated.</p>
<p>The WHO figures put the number at 5,277 for 1995, with a national prevalence of 0.7 cases per 10,000 people.</p>
<p>According to WHO criteria, leprosy is considered to have been eliminated as a public health problem when the level falls below one case per 10,000.</p>
<p>Last year 38 of Vietnam's provinces and cities were reported to have met this goal, but incidence in the poor central and highland areas of the country remained high, with rates of up to 12.19 cases per 10,000 people.</p>
<p>Anti-leprosy programmes were introduced in Vietnam in the 1960s but took off in 1982 when a government masterplan was launched.</p>
<p>Hanoi says it is aiming to eliminate the disease by 2000.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
