<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235815" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Dec 4.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Israel - Dec 4.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in Israeli newspapers on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>JERUSALEM POST</p>
<p>- Attorney-General Michael Ben-Yair resigns, denies being forced out.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, Egyptian Foreign Minister Amr Moussa express hope for improved relations.</p>
<p>- Israeli parliament debates...doughnut deliveries?</p>
<p>- Property firms eye Hapoalim's Amot stake.</p>
<p>- Adviser to Palestinian President Yasser Arafat: Rethink Israel-Palestinian Authority economic pact.</p>
<p>- Finance Minister Dan Meridor: Low internal revenue predictions for '97 are &quot;relative&quot;.</p>
<p>- Lehman Brothers: Leumi to lead Israeli banks in '97 earnings.</p>
<p>- Menorah Insurance manager Shabtai Angel dies at 60.</p>
<p>GLOBES</p>
<p>- Efforts to reach a compromise on budget cut.</p>
<p>- Rise of 0.5 percent in average salary in third quarter to 5,042 shekels.</p>
<p>HAARETZ</p>
<p>- Netanyahu seeks attorney-general more in line with Likud positions.</p>
<p>- Proposal under consideration in prime minister's office to effectively implement Hebron deal without signing it.</p>
<p>- Settler lectures Golani soldiers on &quot;importance of settlement in Hebron&quot;.</p>
<p>- Deputy Mayor of Jerusalem Shmuel Meir killed in car crach in north of city.</p>
<p>MAARIV</p>
<p>- Electricity prices going up 4.5 percent.</p>
<p>- 2,500 will be made redundant at Bezeq within five years.</p>
<p>YEDIOTH AHRONOTH</p>
<p>- Eliyakim Rubinstein, the former cabinet secretary and negotiator with Jordan, is among the candidates to take the place of attorney-general.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
