<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23592" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: U.S presses Canada on Cuba, Ottawa feels threat.</title>
<headline>U.S presses Canada on Cuba, Ottawa feels threat.</headline>
<byline>Randall Palmer</byline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A special representative of U.S. President Bill Clinton insisted on Friday he was not putting a gun to Canada's head on the thorny issue of ties with Cuba.</p>
<p>But he said if Canada and other allies did not join U.S. efforts to promote democracy in Cuba, Clinton might refuse to extend a waiver of a controversial U.S. law that punishes foreign firms for investing in Cuba.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no threat. There's no gun to anybody's head,&quot; Ambassador Stuart Eizenstat told a news conference before meeting Canadian Foreign Minister Lloyd Axworthy and Trade Minister Art Eggleton.</p>
<p>He spoke instead of the &quot;added advantage&quot; of Clinton extending the waiver if U.S. allies went along with the ideas he is promoting.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the factors the president will consider is the degree to which this new effort that we're embarking on -- of moving from a unilateral approach to a more concerted approach -- is actually something countries are willing to engage in,&quot; said Eizenstat, who visited Mexico on Thursday.</p>
<p>The unstated implication was that if Canada and the others did not come on board, Clinton might not agree next January to extend a waiver on the Title III provision of the hotly debated Helms-Burton Act.</p>
<p>Title III would allow lawsuits to be filed in U.S. courts against foreign firms that own or operate properties seized by the Communist government in Cuba from U.S. citizens or from Cubans that became Americans.</p>
<p>Eggleton and Axworthy told reporters after meeting the envoy that they welcomed the chance to talk and the U.S. commitment to proceeding multilaterally. But they also seemed to perceive a threat that they thought should be removed.</p>
<p>&quot;This whole matter of Helms-Burton is keeping the sword dangling over our head,&quot; Eggleton said.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration is pushing allies to do more to promote human rights and, if trade and aid must continue, to do it in ways that will help the Cuban people rather than the Cuban government.</p>
<p>&quot;We're not saying, join us in an embargo. We understand the reality. We're not naive,&quot; Eizenstat said.</p>
<p>&quot;What we're saying is, if you're going to trade and you're going to invest, do it in ways that help the Cuban people. If you're going to channel assistance to Cuba, channel it to the independent sector rather than to a government that's going to siphon it off.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if Canada would change anything as the result of the visit, Axworthy said, &quot;No&quot; -- pointing out continued government-to-government aid to Cuba -- but that Ottawa was always willing to listen to any good ideas.</p>
<p>He said Ottawa would proceed with legislation in the coming months to counter what it argues is Helms-Burton's illegitimate authority -- the United States going after third countries in its effort to change Cuba.</p>
<p>Axworthy also said if Washington wanted real change it would get rid of its embargo of Cuba.</p>
<p>Some development agencies have criticized U.S. sanctions against Cuba, arguing that they hurt the Cuban people.</p>
<p>Eizenstat said to suggest that the lack of freedom on the part of private groups or individuals was the result of the embargo &quot;rather than the repression of (Cuban leader Fidel) Castro is a quite remarkable statement.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
