<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="235942" id="root" date="1996-12-04" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hot internet sites say advertisers lining up.</title>
<headline>Hot internet sites say advertisers lining up.</headline>
<byline>Dick Satran</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-03</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anybody can become a publisher on the Internet, but making money is another story, said Web site owners at the online advertising symposium here Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a business of haves and have-nots,&quot; said Richard Glassberg general manager of Time Warner's CNN Interactive Marketing and Sales, which handles advertising for CNN's Web sites.</p>
<p>The top 25 advertising sites are taking the lion's share of advertising revenue, said publishers, leaving hundreds of others scrambling to make ends meet in the burgeoning business of online advertising.</p>
<p>The leading site owners at the Jupiter-sponsored conference -- CNN Interactive,  Starwave Corp.'s ESPN Sportszone,  Women's Wire -- all of which are classed as &quot;haves,&quot; claimed they have so much demand from advertisers for their sites they were having trouble making room for more.</p>
<p>Internet ad revenue for the first nine months of the year was $138 million, and it will reach $300 million by the end of 1997, according to Jupiter, the consulting firm that sponsored the conference.</p>
<p>Jupiter said that the top 25 Web site providers gathered 88 percent of the revenue so far this year. A Jupiter analyst said other site providers outside the top tier were having difficulties covering costs and many were expected to disappear over the year ahead.</p>
<p>America Online Inc., which has been gradually working advertising into an income mix that once relied completely upon subscription and connect-time fees, said it was already generating $50 million a year in advertising.</p>
<p>&quot;Our biggest problem now is lack of inventory (of advertising space)  -- we're running out of real estate,&quot; said Ted Leonsis, president of America Online.</p>
<p>The biggest online service and the leading provider of Internet access, America Online is now creating extra &quot;channels&quot; to suit the needs of advertisers, Leonsis said.</p>
<p>Starwave, which runs ESPN Sports Zone, NFL.Com, Family Planet and other sites, is &quot;all sold out&quot; to the end of the year, said Rich LeFurgy, vice president of advertising and marketing for the Seattle-based.</p>
<p>CNN has &quot;only a little bit (of advertising space) left,&quot; said ad dirctor Glassberg, while Women's Wire is &quot;sold out through December,&quot; according to the service's executive vice Gina Garrubbo.</p>
<p>The upbeat remarks of the online site owners were tempered by cautious statements from major advertisers that spend hundreds of millions of dollars to advertise on television and print media, and only small sums on Web sites. Most Internet advertisers are technology companies, while the big consumer products concerns are largely avoiding the Web.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't advertise anywhere on the Web,&quot; said Steve Torok, executive director of sales and marketing operations for Chrysler Corp., who argued that the Web lacked measurement tools and advertising standards that other media use.</p>
<p>Bristol-Myers Squibb's Peggy Kelly questioned the abililty of the Internet to reach a mass market, said that it was difficult to reach a mass market using the Internet, and that instead it should be seen as a direct marketing mechanism for customized one-on-one messages to potential customers. &quot;It's dangerous to see the Web as a mass medium,&quot; Kelly said. &quot;It isn't now and I don't think it ever will be.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-04"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-03"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
