<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236241" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANARY ISLANDS: SOCCER-UEFA PROPOSES AGE LIMIT TO REGULATE EU TRANSFER MARKET.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-UEFA PROPOSES AGE LIMIT TO REGULATE EU TRANSFER MARKET.</headline>
<byline>Mike Collett</byline>
<dateline>TENERIFE, Spain 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>European soccer's governing body UEFA, responding to the Bosman ruling on transfer fees, put forward an age-limit proposal on Thursday to help smaller clubs resist the advances of more prestigious sides and cling to their best young players for longer.</p>
<p>UEFA's executive committee, meeting in Tenerife, said players should be signed on long-term contracts which would keep them at their first club until they reached the age of 24.</p>
<p>During this time they would be subject to a transfer fee.</p>
<p>When a player turned 24 his contract would expire and he would then be allowed to move to another club on a free transfer.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea of this proposal is that smaller clubs who may have spent money and time developing a young player should be able to keep that player under contract for far longer than they are likely to do now,&quot; UEFA deputy general secretary Markus Studer said.</p>
<p>&quot;If another club wants to buy him during his contract then a fee will still be involved. But if a player of 18 for example, has a six-year contract that keeps him at the club that has developed him until he is 24, then at least the selling club has had his services for six years which is more than they would have got out of it before.&quot;</p>
<p>The system would only apply to players who were nationals of countries in the European Union or the EAA (the European Economic Association comprising Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein). It would also only apply to a player moving from one club playing in an EU or EAA domestic league to another.</p>
<p>The UEFA proposal borrows heavily from a system employed in France for many years. There, players are signed during their school-days on long-term contracts until they are 24. A fee is payable only if they are transferred in the interim.</p>
<p>The proposal would have to win the backing of the EU, which shook the soccer transfer market to its foundations last December when it ruled players out of contract were entitled to the same freedom of movement as other EU workers and should not be subject to transfer fees.</p>
<p>But Studer said he saw no reason for the EU to block the plan.</p>
<p>&quot;I think in this day and age you can't guarantee anything but we would surprised if the EU found any fault with this proposal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Last December's EU ruling, the culmination of a five-year legal fight by Belgian player Jean-Marc Bosman, threatened to deprive the EU's smaller and poorer clubs of much-needed finance by barring them from selling promising players to richer clubs when their short-term contracts expired.</p>
<p>It also provided a headache for UEFA, at it applied to only 18 of its 50-member states and had no bearing on transfer markets in European countries outside the EU's jurisdiction.</p>
<p>Although UEFA's new plan cannot guarantee smaller clubs an income from transfers, it does provide a framework under which they would be compensated if a player moved before the end of his contract.</p>
<p>UEFA president Lennart Johansson said on Thursday: &quot;Since the Bosman ruling a year ago, UEFA has worked far more closely with the EU and tried to keep the commissioners aware of our business.</p>
<p>&quot;I think we have a far more understandable approach now, and I think we have hopefully found a system that ensures that the money from professional football and the bigger clubs finds its way down to smaller clubs and amateur football and to keep the grass roots healthy.&quot;</p>
<p>UEFA also wants to extend the principles of the Bosman ruling to non-EU players playing for clubs inside the EU.</p>
<p>&quot;In essence, UEFA wants non-EU players with EU clubs treated as EU nationals,&quot; Studer said. &quot;What we are proposing goes further than just the Bosman ruling which related to EU nationals.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TENERIFE, Spain"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANARY ISLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
