<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236267" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: GOLF-BUNKER PRACTICE PAYS OFF FOR VAN VUUREN.</title>
<headline>GOLF-BUNKER PRACTICE PAYS OFF FOR VAN VUUREN.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two days of bunker practice helped Steve van Vuuren to a share of the first round lead with fellow South African Des Terblanche in the Zimbabwe Open on Thursday.</p>
<p>The 37-year-old van Vuuren, who holed out twice from bunkers, collected six birdies and an eagle with only one dropped shot in his seven-under-par 65.</p>
<p>He was matched later in the afternoon by Terblanche, who had five birdies plus an eagle at the par-five 11th.</p>
<p>Namibia's Schalk van der Merwe was two shots back in third with defending champion Nick Price of Zimbabwe alone in fourth on 68.</p>
<p>Of the other leading names, 1992 Zimbabwe Open winner Mark McNulty and Namibia's Trevor Dodds both carded a level-par 72 while Tony Johnstone, champion in 1993, recovered from a disastrous outward loop of 40 for a one-over-par 73.</p>
<p>Van Vuuren said after his round that practice from the sand on the eve of the tournament had been particularly helpful.</p>
<p>&quot;Although I think I'm a pretty decent bunker player, we don't have any bunkers at my home course in Nelspruit so it's not very often that I have the facility to practice,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Van Vuuren, who has been farming mangoes and chillis for the past year while playing golf part-time, said the key to his round had been a steady start and some solid putting.</p>
<p>&quot;I had a steady first nine, turning in 32 with no dropped shots. Then I holed a trap shot from the back bunker at the second hole for a birdie and that was the shot that really kept the day going.&quot;</p>
<p>Pre-tournament favourite Nick Price picked up five birdies in his 68, with his only blemish a three-putt at the par-four third.</p>
<p>&quot;I hit the ball really good and only missed one green. But, although I'm putting solidly, I didn't make any of real length,&quot; Price said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the greens have fully recovered from the heavy rain on Tuesday...they're still soft and I felt uncomfortable on them after the pace of the greens at Sun City last week.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
