<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236298" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA BASKETBALL-ROCKETS' OLAJUWON RETURNS, SCORES 16 POINTS IN WIN.</title>
<headline>NBA BASKETBALL-ROCKETS' OLAJUWON RETURNS, SCORES 16 POINTS IN WIN.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>Houston Rockets All-Star centre Hakeem Olajuwon, sidelined for the second time this season with an irregular heartbeat, was back in the lineup Wednesday night and scored 16 points in a win over the Boston Celtics.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel normal. I was winded, but that's part of the game,&quot; said Olajuwon. &quot;I'm healthy, but I need to get more minutes to get into better shape.&quot;</p>
<p>The Nigerian-born superstar centre also had seven rebounds and five blocks in 40 minutes, helping Houston (16-2) to its sixth straight home win, 94-89.</p>
<p>Olajuwon, 33, was released from a Houston hospital Monday morning after being treated for a recurrence of atrial fibrillation. Earlier in the day, he had undergone an electrical cardioversion, which returned his cardiac rate to a normal rhythm.</p>
<p>Olajuwon was admitted to Houston's Methodist Hospital the day before for the second time this season.</p>
<p>Olajuwon had 34 points and 17 rebounds in Houston's 103-99 win at Washington on Saturday night. But he said he felt &quot;funny&quot; when he returned to the team hotel after the game and flew to Houston the following morning.</p>
<p>Olajuwon also was admitted to Methodist Hospital after a November 19 game against the Minnesota Timberwolves. He underwent a exercise stress test and an echocardiogram. Both were normal and Olajuwon was released two days later.</p>
<p>He rested for a week and missed three games, all Houston wins. On his return, he scored 21 points in a 102-101 overtime victory over the Portland Trail Blazers.</p>
<p>Olajuwon missed seven games early in the 1991-92 season due to similar heartrate problems.</p>
<p>Olajuwon is an 11-time All-Star who won the Most Valuable Player Award in 1994 and led the Rockets to consecutive NBA championships in 1994 and 1995. He was a member of the U.S. Olympic gold medal team in Atlanta this summer.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
