<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236313" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: SOCCER SHOWCASE-TRANSFER FEUDING A TRADITION FOR ARCH-RIVALS.</title>
<headline>SOCCER SHOWCASE-TRANSFER FEUDING A TRADITION FOR ARCH-RIVALS.</headline>
<byline>Richard Bastin</byline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The battle to sign Sampdoria midfielder Christian Karembeu is just the latest chapter in a long history of feuding over transfers between Barcelona and Real Madrid.</p>
<p>Real thought they were on the verge of signing the Frenchman this autumn but, when the deal fell through, accused Barcelona of throwing a spanner in the works -- with the outcome that Karembeu ended up staying in Italy.</p>
<p>Recent moves involving big names such as Hugo Sanchez, Michael Laudrup and Germany's Bernd Schuster all set the biggest rivalry in Spanish football at fever pitch but were nothing in comparison to the fight for the legendary Alfredo di Stefano.</p>
<p>An impressive Spanish tour in 1953 had put both 'grandees' on the trail of di Stefano.</p>
<p>Barcelona agreed terms, only to see a persistent Real agent come in with another offer for the Argentine striker.</p>
<p>The dispute went as far as then sports minister, Francoist war hero General Moscardo. In what would have been one of the strangest transfer deals ever, Moscardo decreed that di Stefano should play four years in Spain, alternating between the two clubs.</p>
<p>The arrangement was too much for Barcelona, who pulled out.</p>
<p>It proved to be a big mistake for the Catalan club, who had to sit back and watch Real become the undisputed masters of Europe with di Stefano at the helm.</p>
<p>Signing the Spanish league's greatest-ever player changed the course of history for Real, who had won only two of the 22 league championships played by the time of di Stefano's arrival but who have since taken the league title 24 times in 43 years.</p>
<p>More significantly, Real won the first five European Cups between 1956 and 1960 and their overall tally of six remains a record.</p>
<p>Another Latin American star, acrobatic Mexican goalscorer Hugo Sanchez, ushered in a second period of Real dominance.</p>
<p>Sanchez was at the centre of a particularly acrimonious controversy in 1985 when he was close to moving to the Nou Camp after playing a season at Atletico Madrid.</p>
<p>Eventually Barcelona coach Terry Venables stuck by Scot Steve Archibald and Sanchez went across the Spanish capital to the Santiago Bernabeu stadium, where he topped national goalscoring tables four times as Real romped to five successive league titles.</p>
<p>Players who move from one club to another inevitably stir up a passion bordering on hatred and can be guaranteed a traitor's reception on their return.</p>
<p>Both Schuster and Laudrup found out what is was like to go back to Barcelona as Real players.</p>
<p>Laudrup -- an experienced Danish international -- was clearly unable to cope with the hostility of a crowd that had once idolised him and had to be substituted on his second visit.</p>
<p>Overlapping full-back Luis Enrique Martinez will experience the other side of the coin this Saturday when he steps on to the pitch in Madrid wearing the claret and blue of Barcelona.</p>
<p>Martinez's anxiety to hide his move to Barcelona led him to a fight with a photographer as he left a clinic after medical tests for his transfer last year.</p>
<p>He had good reason to worry. A season earlier Croatian midfielder Robert Prosinecki found his plans to join Barcelona set back a year after he was discovered travelling to Catalonia for a check-up.</p>
<p>The fuss surrounding Laudrup and Martinez came despite the fact that they made their moves across Spain as free agents.</p>
<p>Other transfers have proved even more problematic.</p>
<p>Midfielder Luis Milla jumped ship from Barcelona in 1990 and then found himself involved in a bribery scandal after admitting he had been offered money ahead of Real Madrid's dramatic end-of-season game against Tenerife in 1992.</p>
<p>Real squandered a 2-0 lead in the game and surrendered the championship to Barcelona.</p>
<p>Just last season, the Barcelona board wanted to sign Davor Suker and Predrag Mijatovic but then coach Johan Cruyff was unenthusiastic and the Balkan striking pair went to Real.</p>
<p>&quot;There will never again be a Hugo Sanchez or another Mijatovic in the history of Barcelona,&quot; said club vice-president Josep Mussons &quot;If we like a player and we can sign him, we will do so.&quot;</p>
<p>And Barcelona can do so.</p>
<p>While Real Madrid are struggling to refinance debts thought to be as much as 12.5 billion pesetas (around $100 million), the Catalan club is turning in profits.</p>
<p>So when Real president Lorenzo Sanz talks of signing Barcelona winger Luis Figo or paying the 4,000 million pesetas ($31.25 million) necessary to release Brazilian star Ronaldo from his contract, Barcelona officials are entitled to take the threat lightly.</p>
<p>&quot;If Ronaldo goes to Real, (Madrid's young striker) Raul Gonzalez will come to Barcelona,&quot; said another Barcelona vice-president, Joan Gaspart.&quot;April Fools' Day hasn't arrived yet.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
