<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236395" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products bounce higher on crude, Elf strike.</title>
<headline>Med oil products bounce higher on crude, Elf strike.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Med oil products were steady to higher on Thursday, buoyed by crude's gallop higher and the eight-day-old strike by Elf refinery workers.</p>
<p>Gas oil firmed $5.50 on higher futures. Premiums were unchanged at about high cif quotes +$1.50 basis Genoa.</p>
<p>Interest focused on a tender by India for a second purchase of high speed diesel for delivery in January. Cargoes of heating oil were offered around but buying inquiries were lukewarm.</p>
<p>A Russian remains offered loading Dec 15-18 at equivalent to high cif quotes +$1.30. The low sulphur diesel market remains well supplied with little buying interest.</p>
<p>Naphtha held steady tracking higher NWE prices, sharply higher crude and arbitrage trading to the U.S.</p>
<p>A 26,000 tonne cargo of 78 paraffinic material was sold at $229 cif into Tarragona for delivery December 12-20, traders said, confirming higher NWE cargo prices.</p>
<p>An Algerian cargo, initially expected to go to Antwerp, was rumoured sold to the U.S., traders said.</p>
<p>Gasoline held firm with premium unleaded barges assessed at $226/$228 cif. Traders confirmed superplus, premium unleaded and leaded material sold into southern France to Elf because of the eight-day-old strike at its three refineries.</p>
<p>One broker said another French oil company was rumoured to be holding off on selling into Italy, possibly as a safeguard against a threatened one-day, nationwide oil industry strike in France on Tuesday.</p>
<p>High sulphur fuel was marginally stronger with support derived from stronger crude, rather than fundamentals. Although the EdP and Turkish tenders give support there were still around six December ISAB cargoes still unsold. A bunker quality spec cargo was sold out of Italy at around $113 fob and other material was heard offered at $114 fob.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
