<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236481" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Union won't challenge Canadian Air vote order.</title>
<headline>Union won't challenge Canadian Air vote order.</headline>
<byline>Paul Casciato</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian Auto Workers President Buzz Hargrove said on Thursday he cannot legally challenge an unprecedented government order forcing union members to vote on a plan to save Canadian Airlines Corp.</p>
<p>But the defiant Hargrove told a news conference that he was certain the union's 3,700 members at Canadian, who face pay cuts if the restructuring plan goes through, would back whatever recommendation he made.</p>
<p>&quot;If that is to ratify, they'll ratify. If that is to reject it, they will reject,&quot; Hargrove said.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, Labour Minister Alfonso Gagliano invoked a little-used section in the Canadian Labour Code to force the vote, which had been adamantly opposed by Hargrove.</p>
<p>Canadian Airlines spokeswoman Claudia Cattaneo said she thought the vote could be held as early as Monday while CAW leaders said a vote would take at least a week to 10 days to complete.</p>
<p>The CAW, which represents Canadian ticket agents, is the only one of six unions at Canadian that has not accepted the restructuring plan, which Canada's second biggest air carrier called crucial to its survival.</p>
<p>Hargrove, 52, who leads Canada's largest private sector union, said he planned to continue negotiating with Canadian and the government for a better deal on the restructuring package, which includes wage cuts of C$35 million ($26 million) a year from Canadian's 16,400 employees.</p>
<p>Hargrove has rejected wage cuts, saying previous pay concessions failed to help the airline, which has not posted an annual profit this decade. The CAW has called for more government aid and re-regulation of Canada's airline industry.</p>
<p>Canadian, based in Calgary, Alberta, has said it could cease operations early next year unless the plan was implemented. It said the proposal required the support of all its unions.</p>
<p>The plan also includes federal and provincial government support and a C$48 million ($36 million) yearly cut in fees paid to 33 percent-owner AMR Corp., the parent of American Airlines.</p>
<p>Canadian is also trying to postpone about C$170 million ($125 million) in debt payments over the next six months from 70 creditors and equipment lessors, a move contingent on the plan being in place.</p>
<p>Union member Victoria Gonzalez said she did not understand why 10 percent wage and 17.5 percent benefit concessions accepted by CAW members in a collective agreement reached only a year ago were not enough to keep Canadian aloft.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a union in place, so it's very undemocratic what the government is doing,&quot; Gonzalez said. &quot;It's like something out of central America.&quot;</p>
<p>Hargrove, whose union waged a 20-day strike at General Motors Corp. in Canada in October, accused Canadian Chief Executive Kevin Benson of manufacturing a crisis to lure employees into wage concessions.</p>
<p>Industry analysts have said that Canadian's problems had more to do with capacity than wages.</p>
<p>&quot;The big problem has been the fact that there's too much capacity domestically chasing far too few travelers,&quot; said Bunting Warburg analyst Ted Larkin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
