<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236599" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria central bank opposes new budget deficit funding.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria central bank opposes new budget deficit funding.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) said on Thursday that it did not agree to a government request for a loan of 123.5 billion levs to bridge the budget gap because this would further increase inflation.</p>
<p>Parliament is expected on Friday to begin debate on this year's second budget revision, sought by the government after it overshot the macroeconomic targets in the July revision.</p>
<p>&quot;The government's draft contradicts the central bank's policy for supporting the national currency and curbing inflation,&quot; the BNB said in a statement.  </p>
<p>But the central bank is supervised by parliament, in which the governing Socialists have a majority. If parliament approves the draft, then the central bank must comply.</p>
<p>The BNB said financing the budget deficit through direct lending to the government was not appropriate as Bulgaria prepared to introduce a restrictive currency board regime.</p>
<p>&quot;Possible non-inflationary sources of financing the budget deficit are levs from conversion of foreign exchange liquidity from the State Fund for Reconstruction and Development and mainly proceeds from speeded-up privatisation through participation of foreign investors,&quot; the BNB said.  </p>
<p>Bulgaria is expected to introduce a currency board early next year, requiring levs in circulation to be matched by BNB reserves, removing political pressure to print money.</p>
<p>But the BNB urged the government not to wait for external measures, saying it expected parliament to support policy aimed at curbing inflation and imposing tight financial discipline without further delay. The government wants the deficit target raised to 204.2 billion levs, or five to six percent of gross domestic product from 80.7 billion levs, or 4.9 percent of GDP to meet higher domestic debt payments.  </p>
<p>Under the draft to be debated on Friday, 117 billion levs are earmarked for interest and maturity payments on domestic debt that grew to 668.3 billion levs at the end of October from 345.4 billion levs at the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>Some 6.3 billion levs are slated for foreign debt payments.</p>
<p>Domestic debt rose sharply this year because of record high interest rates, currently 180 percent, and sharp falls in the lev, which slumped to 435 per dollar on Thursday from around 70 at the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>Next year's budget must be balanced between revenue and expenditure if a currency board is introduced, which will entail big cuts in public spending.</p>
<p>-- Sofia newsroom +359 2 84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
