<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236518" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAMBIA: Zambia police search opposition leader's house.</title>
<headline>Zambia police search opposition leader's house.</headline>
<dateline>LUSAKA 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zambian police on Thursday briefly held an opposition leader and searched his house in a continued crackdown on politicians who refuse to recognise President Frederick Chiluba's government after controversial elections.</p>
<p>Witnesses said Liberal Progressive Front chairman Rodger Chongwe was picked up from his office in the morning and interrogated before police ransacked his house.</p>
<p>&quot;They say they are looking for a letter my husband wrote to Southern African Development Community (SADC) heads of state on the elections,&quot; Chongwe's wife, Gwenda, told reporters during the search.</p>
<p>&quot;I have told them that they will not find it because I flushed it down the toilet,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Chongwe, who leads an alliance of opposition parties that boycotted November's elections, wrote to SADC leaders last month, warning of a possible military takeover if they did not step in to resolve the country's political crisis.</p>
<p>The parties have rejected the results of the November 18 elections, which they claim were rigged by Chiluba's Movement for Multiparty Democracy (MMD). They say they will lead a disobedience campaign to unseat the Chiluba government.</p>
<p>Several opposition leaders, including former president Kenneth Kaunda, watched police searching Chongwe's house.</p>
<p>&quot;This is disgusting. It is nothing but harrassment of opposition leaders,&quot; Kaunda said.</p>
<p>The former president challenged police to arrest him: &quot;I co-authored the letter to the SADC leaders. Why don't you arrest me as well?&quot; he asked.</p>
<p>Police ended their three-hour search without confiscating any property.</p>
<p>Chongwe is the second opposition leader to have faced police action since the polls.</p>
<p>Zambia Democratic Congress leader Dean Mungomba went into hiding last week after police tried to arrest him for warning his party would resist the Chiluba government with violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAMBIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUSAKA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
