<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236757" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Chase aims to stay a top global bank.</title>
<headline>Chase aims to stay a top global bank.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chase Manhattan Corp's Chase Manhattan Bank aims to be one of a dozen global financial institutions left standing by year 2000, said the president of the bank's Brazilian unit Patrick Morin Jr.</p>
<p>&quot;With the globalization of the economy, we believe that there will be a dozen entirely global institutions by year 2000, and we are sure we will be one of them,&quot; Morin told reporters.</p>
<p>Morin said Chase's Brazil unit will play an important role under the bank's strategy.  </p>
<p>Chase Brazil accounts for three percent of the bank's global profits -- which totaled $2.68 billion in the first nine months of 1996, excluding expenses associated with its merger with Chemical Bank formalized earlier this year, he said.</p>
<p>Unlike competitors Citicorp unit Citibank and Bank of Boston unit Banco de Boston, Chase Manhattan in Brazil will continue focusing on wholesale banking, instead of seeking expansion by entering the retail market.  </p>
<p>&quot;Chase does not intend to be a retail bank in Brazil,&quot; Morin said, adding that Chase's retail strategy is restricted to the U.S. market.</p>
<p>Morin said what Chase has been doing regarding retail banking outside the United States was only to study ways to eventually provide electronic banking technology in Mexico.</p>
<p>&quot;We are closely eyeing Mexico in the light of the North American Free Trade Agreement. We are analyzing how Chase may expand in Mexico,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Chase's Brazil unit has been a key player in the international capital markets, leading $1.5 billion in Eurobond issues by Brazilian companies this year and $600 million in securitizations of exports.</p>
<p>Probably within two weeks, the bank will be the lead manager of a $100 million bond issue by Brazilian pulp and paper maker Grupo Suzano.</p>
<p>Chase in Brazil has total assets of $4.7 billion. It manages $2.3 billion in assets, particularly of institutional investors and funds.</p>
<p>-- Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo Newsroom, 55-11-2485412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
