<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23672" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Andal chairman and president retire.</title>
<headline>Andal chairman and president retire.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Andal Corp said on Friday it Chairman Andrew Frankel and President Alan Cohen retired from those offices effective August 31.</p>
<p>The company said Peter Flood, president of its Multi-Arc Inc subsidiary, has been elected chairman and president.</p>
<p>Flood will also continue to serve as a director of Andal, the company said.  </p>
<p>The company also said Walter Kreil, Jr., vice president and chief financial officer of Multi-Arc, was elected senior vice president and chief financial officer of Andal and was elected to Andal's board.</p>
<p>&quot;Since Multi-Arc has been the core of the business for several years, it seemed reasonable to consolidate management responsibilites in Multi-Arc personnel,&quot; Kreil said in a telephone interview.</p>
<p>In connection with the changes, Andal headquarters will move to the Multi-Arc facility in Rockaway, New Jersey, a statement from the company said.</p>
<p>The company said Frankel and Cohen will continue as directors of Andal.</p>
<p>The company said Frankel and Cohen have assumed the lease on Andal's New York City office and certain other office costs; and Andal has agreed to issue 32,500 shares of its common stock each to Frankel and Cohen.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
