<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236851" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Dec 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Dec 5.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- GOVT STUDIES CPMF TAX EFFECT ON FINANCIAL MARKETS</p>
<p>Finance Ministry officials are studying the effect of the so-called CPMF cheque tax on the financial markets and may decide to exempt the markets from this tax, which takes effect in January.</p>
<p>-- SAVINGS RISE AFTER THIRTEENTH SALARY</p>
<p>Money flowing into investment funds and savings accounts has increased in recent weeks, especially after companies started paying staff their 13th salary.</p>
<p>-- GOVT TO TRY AND PASS CORPORATE TAX BILL TODAY</p>
<p>The government hopes to pass a new corporate tax bill today for 1997 that could increase tax revenues to 113 billion reais from an estimated 94 billion reais in 1996.</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- MINISTER REVEALS NEW PUBLIC WORKS SCANDAL</p>
<p>A government minister has revealed a scandal in which a lower house deputy tried to charge four-percent commission for allocating budget funds to a public works project.</p>
<p>-- LOWER HOUSE APPROVES TEMPORARY WORK</p>
<p>The lower house has approved a bill reducing companies' social security contributions for workers hired with fixed two-year contracts.</p>
<p>-- BRAZIL AHEAD WITH THE INTERNET</p>
<p>Brazil is set to be the first Latin American country to gain access to the Internet II, an enhanced version of the existing computer network which is expected to be ready in the next four years.</p>
<p>FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- INFLATION SEEN UNDER 10 PERCENT FOR 1996</p>
<p>Economists expect Sao Paulo's 1996 inflation rate to be under 10 percent, the lowest since 1950 when inflation stood at 3.59 percent.</p>
<p>-- RE-ELECTION AND SALE OF CVRD DON'T MATCH</p>
<p>Senator Antonio Carlos Magalhaes admitted his proposal to alter the sell-off model of state mining giant CVRD was designed to gain time because the privatization of CVRD and the presidential re-election issue were too much for Congress to stomach at one time.</p>
<p>-- BAMERINDUS MIGHT GET SIX BLN REAIS FROM CENBANK</p>
<p>The Central Bank may lend six billion reais to Brazil's fourth largest private bank Bamerindus to help it overcome a short-term liquidity problem.</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified the stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Simona de Logu, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
