<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236968" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HKMA hopes for light IPO flow ahead of RTGS launch.</title>
<headline>HKMA hopes for light IPO flow ahead of RTGS launch.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) on Thursday requested a delay in upcoming initial public offerings (IPO) to relieve tightness in the money market as it introduces a new money market settlement system.</p>
<p>Starting on Monday, the HKMA will implement a Real Time Gross Settlement (RTGS) system in which banks can use Exchange Fund bills and notes to obtain interest-free intraday liquidity by carrying out intraday repurchase transactions with the HKMA.</p>
<p>&quot;We expressed our wishes to the Hong Kong Stock Exchange that the IPO schedule will not be so tight during the first week of implementation of the RTGS,&quot; an HKMA spokesman said.</p>
<p>Analysts said heavy oversubscriptions of new listings has tightened liquidity in the money market.</p>
<p>In late November, the HKMA injected about HK$3.0 billion into the banking system to soothe tightness caused by month-end and equities-related demand.</p>
<p>With RTGS requiring banks to make real-time settlements instead of daily settlements, traders said a heavy schedule of IPOs could complicate the introduction of the new system.</p>
<p>Analysts said merchant banks have been given verbal requests from the HKMA to delay upcoming launches.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6370</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
