<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="236931" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's Sakakibara says no target zone for yen.</title>
<headline>Japan's Sakakibara says no target zone for yen.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the Japanese Finance Ministry's International Finance Bureau denied on Thursday that he previously said he wants to see the Japanese yen at 108 to 110 to the dollar.</p>
<p>Speaking in a television interview with TV Tokyo, the influential official said: &quot;There was a rumour today that Japan was trying to maneuver the yen to between 108 yen and 110 yen but this is completely groundless. I have not said such a thing to anybody. We don't have a target zone.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We are not thinking of guiding the foreign exchange rate to a certain zone,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Japanese government's foreign exchange policy has not changed,&quot; he said. He added that this was also true for the United States and other G7 countries.</p>
<p>He also said that Japan was watching movements in the foreign exchange markets carefully.</p>
<p>Market participants have been keeping a close eye on Sakakibara as his comments in early November, after the dollar hit this year's high of 114.92 yen, pushed it down sharply.</p>
<p>He had said back then that the market view on Japan's economy was too pessimistic and that he believed it was stronger than the market thought.</p>
<p>Sakakibara, dubbed &quot;Mr Yen&quot; by the foreign media, is said to have been the key figure in driving the dollar above 100 yen last year through aggressive government intervention in foreign exchange markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
