<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237015" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Malaysia tries to stem fall in rubber production.</title>
<headline>Malaysia tries to stem fall in rubber production.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia is taking steps to soften the steady fall in its natural rubber production and wants to maintain output at one million tonnes a year, industry officials said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Ng Kok Tee, deputy chairman of the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board (MRELB), told the Asia Rubber Markets conference that a labour shortage, increased domestic use of natural rubber and Malaysia's transformation into an industrialised economy had led to a decline in production.  </p>
<p>Malaysian production has declined sharply from a high of 1.66 million tonnes in 1988 to 1.08 million tonnes in 1995. Exports slid to 1.01 million tonnes last year from 1.55 million tonnes in 1988.</p>
<p>Domestic consumption increased to 327,439 tonnes in 1995 against 69,642 tonnes a decade ago.</p>
<p>Ng said the industry would also concentrate more on the production of field grade SMR rubber and technically specified rubber (TSR).  </p>
<p>&quot;The planted area for natural rubber will continue to decline from the current 1.7 million hectares to about 1.0 million hectares, but production will consolidate between 900,000 to one million tonnes per annum through replanting with new high-yield (trees),&quot; Ng said.</p>
<p>&quot;For the natural rubber industry, the effects of the tight labour market are felt in terms of higher wages, decline in output and an increase in the cost of production,&quot; said Abu Talib Bachik, secretary of the Malaysian Rubber Research and Development Board, (MRRDB).  </p>
<p>&quot;The largest and main producer of sheet rubber, Thailand, has grasped this reality and is reorienting their productions towards TSRs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Abu Talib said there was a &quot;compelling need&quot; for smallholder farmers to modernise and boost efficiency to raise output.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
