<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237019" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: AT&amp;T launches low-cost Internet service in Japan.</title>
<headline>AT&amp;T launches low-cost Internet service in Japan.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. telephone giant AT&amp;T Corp launched a low-cost Internet access service on Thursday for individual users in Japan.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T Jens Corp, a joint venture between AT&amp;T and 25 Japanese firms, said the service offers Japanese users unlimited access to the Internet for a flat rate of 2,000 yen ($17) per month.</p>
<p>The one-time registration fee is 3,000 yen ($26).</p>
<p>In addition, users need to pay standard telephone service charges.</p>
<p>The rates are lower than those of other such services in Japan, including Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp's planned Open Computer Network (OCN).</p>
<p>NTT will charge 2,300 yen ($20) per month for access to the Internet for up to 15 hours a month under the OCN service expected to start later this month.</p>
<p>Asked about NTT's service, Darryl Green, president of AT&amp;T Jens, said it was important to work with Japan's Posts and Telecommunications Ministry so that NTT &quot;does not use its dominant position&quot;.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T launched an Internet access service for consumers in the United States in March. It has signed up more than 425,000 customers since then and has become the second-biggest provider in the United States, Green said.</p>
<p>AT&amp;T Jens operates a powerful, high-capacity Internet backbone network connected with the United States and Asia-Pacific countries.</p>
<p>It was the first commercial Internet service provider in Japan when it launched a service for users other than scholars and researchers in 1992. Users of the service were mostly businesses.</p>
<p>The giant company's entry into the broader Internet access market in Japan is expected to have a large impact on more than 1,000 secondary service providers which rely on networks of giant carriers such as AT&amp;T.</p>
<p>($1=113 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
