<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237174" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Bond prices fall after 2-1/2-month-long rally.</title>
<headline>Bond prices fall after 2-1/2-month-long rally.</headline>
<byline>Ellen Freilich</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Treasury prices fell sharply Thursday as investors, wary on the eve of the key monthly U.S. employment report, locked in profits from a rally that has lasted more than two months.</p>
<p>&quot;People have a lot of profits, but they held off taking them because of hopes the market would improve,&quot; explained Michelle Laughlin, chief Treasury market strategist at Prudential Securities Inc. When that did not happen, investors booked those profits, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have probably seen the highs for the time being,&quot; added Jim Kenney, head trader at Prudential.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond tumbled 1-15/32, or $14.6875 on a $1,000 bond. Its yield, which moves in the opposite direction, jumped to 6.51 percent -- the highest since Nov. 8 close -- from 6.40 percent at Wednesday's close.</p>
<p>The market's hopes had rested on the possibility that the Federal Reserve would finally meet a seasonal need to add reserves to the banking system by buying Treasury notes and bonds in the open market. Such a move, called a coupon pass, tends to push up bond prices.</p>
<p>&quot;When that didn't happen, they had to give up hope,&quot; said Patrick Dimick, government bond strategist at UBS Securities LLC. And, as bond futures fell, the cash market followed.</p>
<p>Investors were also nervous before the November employment report out Friday.</p>
<p>Payroll growth of about 180,000 jobs is widely expected, but a few economists forecast gains of 200,000 or more, which would support the view that the economy might pick up in the fourth quarter after slowing in the third.</p>
<p>Moreover, the market lacked fresh &quot;good news&quot; to justify a further rise in bond prices, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The market has run out of gas for short-term upward momentum,&quot; said Greg Carr, market analyst at A.G. Edwards &amp; Sons Inc. &quot;We were bumping our heads against levels that we couldn't justify unless we had an expectation that the Fed was going to ease (interest rates).&quot;</p>
<p>With nothing yet to go on that could justify such a move by the central bank, the market was ripe for a sell-off, analysts said.</p>
<p>The bond market, which hates inflation, began its latest surge when the Fed left interest rates unchanged at its September policy meeting.</p>
<p>The 30-year bond yield began falling from more than 7 percent as a stream of government reports showed steady economic growth with inflation under control.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
