<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237123" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NOTICE OF SALE - Waldwick, N.J..</title>
<headline>NOTICE OF SALE - Waldwick, N.J..</headline>
<text>
<p>SUMMARY NOTICE OF SALE</p>
<p>			    Borough of Waldwick</p>
<p>			    (County of Bergen)</p>
<p>				  New Jersey</p>
<p>		    $2,985,000 Bonds Consisting of</p>
<p>		 $2,565,000 General Improvement Bonds</p>
<p>		     $420,000 Water Utility Bonds</p>
<p>	 (Book-Entry Only) (Bank-Qualified) (Non-Callable)</p>
<p>			  dated December 15, 1996</p>
<p>SEALED PROPOSALS will  be received by  the Chief Financial Officer of the Borough of Waldwick, in the County of Bergen, New Jersey (the</p>
<p>					Borough'')</p>
<p>al Building,  15</p>
<p>East Prospect Street, Waldwick, New Jersey 07463 on</p>
<p>at 11:00 o'clock A.M.  at which time  they will be  publicly opened and  announced, for  the  purchase of  the  Borough's $2,565,000 General  Improvement  Bonds  and  $420,000  Water  Utility  Bonds,   each  issue   dated  December   15,   1996</p>
<p> (individually, the   General Improvement  Bonds'' or  the</p>
<p>Water Utility Bonds''; collectively, the</p>
<p>								Bonds'')</p>
<p>The Bonds comprise two issues of bonds payable on December 15 in each year (without the  right of prior redemption)  as follows:</p>
<p>		  $2,565,000 General Improvement Bonds</p>
<p>$130,000 in the year 1997,</p>
<p>$175,000 in the year 1998,</p>
<p>$185,000 in the year 1999,</p>
<p>$200,000 in the year 2000,</p>
<p>$220,000 in each of the years 2001 and 2002,</p>
<p>$225,000 in the year 2003,</p>
<p>$230,000 in each of the years 2004 and 2005,</p>
<p>$240,000 in the year 2006,</p>
<p>$250,000 in the year 2007, and</p>
<p>$260,000 in the year 2008.</p>
<p>			$420,000 Water Utility Bonds</p>
<p>$80,000 in the year 1997,</p>
<p>$65,000 in the year 1998,</p>
<p>$50,000 in the year 1999, and</p>
<p>$45,000 in each of the years 2000 to 2004, inclusive.</p>
<p>The  combined  maturity  schedule  for  the  Bonds  is  as follows:</p>
<p>	    Amount	   Amount	  Amount</p>
<p>    YearMaturing   YearMaturing  YearMaturing</p>
<p>    1997$210,000   2001$265,000  2005$230,000</p>
<p>    1998 240,000   2002 265,000  2006 240,000</p>
<p>    1999 235,000   2003 270,000  2007 250,000</p>
<p>    2000 245,000   2004 275,000  2008 260,000</p>
<p>The Bonds shall be issued in registered form by means of a book-entry system  with  no physical  distribution  of  bond certificates made to  the public. One  bond certificate  for each maturity of each issue will be issued to The Depository Trust Company, New York, New York  (DTC'') and immobilized  in  its  custody.  The   book-entry  system  will   evidence</p>
<p>ownership of the Bonds in the principal amount of $1,000  or any multiple thereof, with  transfers of ownership  effected</p>
<p>on the records of DTC and its participants pursuant to and procedures established by DTC and its participants. This Summary Notice of Sale is intended  only as a brief  summary of the Notice  of Sale to  be made  available to  interested persons (the</p>
<p>				   Notice of Sale '</p>
<p>e  of Sale  is</p>
<p>hereby incorporated herein  by this  reference thereto.  The Notice of Sale and Proposal for Bonds should be reviewed  by potential bidders for additional terms and conditions of the sale of the Bonds prior to bidding on the Bonds.</p>
<p>The Bonds will bear  interest from their date  at a single rate of interest in a multiple of 1/8th or 1/20th of 1%  per annum specified  by the  successful bidder  payable on  each June 15 and December 15, commencing  June 15, 1997, in  each year until maturity. The  purchase price specified must  not be less than  $2,985,000 nor more  than $2,986,000.  Bidders must at the time of making  their bids deposit a  certified, cashier's or  treasurer's check  in  the amount  of  $59,700 drawn upon  a bank  or trust  company Borough. The Bonds will be sold to the bidder specifying the lowest rate of  interest in  accordance with  the terms  set forth in the Notice  of Sale. The  Borough will furnish  the Bonds and the approving legal  opinion of Rogut, McCarthy  &amp; Bhend, A  Professional  Corporation, Cranford,  New  Jersey, Bond Counsel.</p>
<p> The Bonds  will  be designated  as 							qualified tax-exem obligations'' for  purposes  of  Section  265(b)(3)  of  the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended.</p>
<p> Copies of the  Preliminary Official Statement,  the Notice of  Sale  and  the  Proposal  for  Bonds  are  available  by contacting the undersigned  Chief Financial  Officer at  the Municipal Building, 15 East  Prospect Street, Waldwick,  New Jersey 07463 (telephone (201) 652-5858).</p>
<p> By  order  of  the  Borough  Council  of  the  Borough  of Waldwick, in the County of Bergen, New Jersey.</p>
<p> Dated:November 12, 1996</p>
<p>			    /s/ Mary Ann Viviani</p>
<p>			  Chief Financial Officer</p>
<p>			    Borough of Waldwick</p>
<p>(From The Bond Buyer)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
