<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237324" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Judge dismisses Steinhardt lawsuit vs Citicorp.</title>
<headline>Judge dismisses Steinhardt lawsuit vs Citicorp.</headline>
<byline>Rita Farrell</byline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del. 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>A U.S. judge has dismissed a lawsuit in which Steinhardt Group Inc alleged Citicorp and four affiliates had violated the Securities Exchange Act by misprepresenting the value of certain real estate properties, court papers say.  </p>
<p>Judge Sue Robinson of the U.S. District Court in Delaware said in a 25 page decision this week that she dismissed the federal fraud charges because Steinhardt technically &quot;did not purchase a security&quot; as defined by federal law when it invested $42 million in a real estate portfolio (REO's) from Citcorp in 1994 and valued by Citicorp at $415 million.</p>
<p>However, she left standing a fraud claim under state or common law claim because she said Citicorp had failed to convince her otherwise.  </p>
<p>Steinhardt attorney Douglas Eakley told Reuters &quot;Steinhardt intends to appeal the decision rejecting the securities laws claims...We respectfully believe Judge Robinson's conclusion that there was no security represented by this securitaization contract is in error.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Third Circuit (appeals court) reverses Judge Robinson on the securities law claim, then Steinhardt will be able to prosecute its common law claims of fraud, breach of contract and breach of fiduciary duty in federal court along with the federal securites claim.  So it's a wait and see situation.&quot;  </p>
<p>In January, Steinhardt sued Citicorp, alleging it tried to &quot;unload a massive portfolio of illiquid, non-performing assets&quot; on a partnership formed to buy and then securitize the bank's portfolio of 3,100 delinquent residential mortgage loans and 900 foreclosed loans.</p>
<p>In December, 1994, Citicorp issued $384 million in debt securities secured by the portfolio through affiliates Citibank NA, Citicorp North America Inc and Citicorp Securities Inc, which are all named as defendants.  </p>
<p>But according to the Steinhardt lawsuit, &quot;Far from obtaining impartial, accurate and conservative valuations as promised, defendant and their agents allowed a bias to work in their favor&quot; and used &quot;fraudulent inducement&quot; to obtain investors.</p>
<p>Eakley said a notice of appeal will be filed shortly.</p>
<p>A Citicorp spokesman could not be reached for comment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
