<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237326" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton names Albright to State, Cohen to Defense.</title>
<headline>Clinton names Albright to State, Cohen to Defense.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Thursday named U.N. envoy Madeleine Albright to be secretary of state and Republican Sen. William Cohen of Maine as defense secretary in a sweeping and historic shake-up of his national security brain-trust.  </p>
<p>At a news conference, Democrat Clinton also said he was nominating National Security Adviser Anthony Lake to head the Central Intelligence Agency and promoting Lake's deputy, Samuel Berger, to succeed him as national security adviser.</p>
<p>&quot;Today I am pleased to announce the new national security team I have selected to help us meet (new challenges),&quot; Clinton said, listing his four new choices, who stood behind him along with their predecessors. He said their goal would be &quot;to ensure that as we enter the 21st century America remains the indispensable nation.&quot;</p>
<p>With the Albright and Cohen selections Clinton made history and scored major political points in one stroke: U.N. Ambassador Albright, 59, would become not only the first female secretary of state but the highest-ranking woman in U.S. government history, a gratifying break-through for feminists who have lobbied Clinton to reward his strongest voting constituency, women. And Cohen, a moderate who is retiring from his Senate post, fulfils a pledge to add a Republican to the Cabinet in a political conciliation move.</p>
<p>Albright, Cohen and Lake require Senate confirmation. They would succeed outgooing Secretary of State Warren Christopher, Defence Secretary William Perry and CIA Director John Deutch.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
