<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23738" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Boatmen's busy on merger deal.</title>
<headline>U.S. OPTIONS FOCUS/Boatmen's busy on merger deal.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Options on shares of Boatmen's Bancshares Inc and NationsBank Corp were features on Friday after the two companies announced a definitive merger agreement.</p>
<p>Both stocks were heavily traded but most of the options activity centered on Boatmen's, which was up 10-10/16 at 53-9/16 by 1315 CDT (1815 GMT). More than nine million shares changed hands.</p>
<p>NationsBank was down 7-1/8 at 85-1/4 on consolidated turnover of about 5.7 million shares.  </p>
<p>On the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE), the most active Boatmen's options included the September 45 call, the October 45 call and the April 1997 50 call. The most active put was the September 50, with 75 contracts traded.</p>
<p>&quot;It's just typical risk arb positions, nothing out of the ordinary,&quot; said a trader familiar with the action in Boatmen's options. &quot;It's not overly active.&quot;</p>
<p>He said one reason more options hadn't traded was because of the holiday weekend in the U.S., as many would-be participants were already on holiday.  </p>
<p>He added that while activity in Boatmen's options had picked up over the last few weeks, it did not appear that news of the merger deal had leaked.</p>
<p>&quot;There has been a little more volume in the last couple of weeks, but they've been both buying and selling,&quot; he said. &quot;Nothing out of the ordinary.&quot;</p>
<p>Traders said the action in NationsBank options, which trade on the Philadelphia Stock Exchange, also did not suggest insider knowledge of the deal.</p>
<p>The most active NationsBank option was the November 90 call, which traded 1,170 contracts and fell 3-1/16 to 1-15/16.  </p>
<p>Through Thursday, the option had open interest of 1,695, with one added on Thursday.</p>
<p>The NationsBank September 85 call, down 6-1/8 at 1-5/8, traded just more than 1,100 contracts. Open interest through Thursday, when open interest fell by 208 contracts, was 996.</p>
<p>Among NationsBank puts, the September 85 was most active, with 187 contracts changing hands. It was up 1-5/8 at 1-13/15.</p>
<p>In other trading, several ValuJet Inc options drew heavy interest as the stock rallied after the airline on Thursday won tentative approval from U.S. aviation authorities to resume operations.  </p>
<p>The stock rallied 1-1/2 to 12-1/2 on 5.2 million shares.</p>
<p>On the CBOE, ValuJet September 12-1/2 call, the October 12-1/2 call and the December 12-1/2 and 15 all traded more than 1,000 contracts.</p>
<p>The same calls were active on the American Stock Exchange and the PHLX.</p>
<p>--Gregory Crawford, Derivatives desk, (312) 408-8750</p>
<p>E-mail: derivatives@reuters.com</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
