<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237454" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EPP leaders to push for stability pact.</title>
<headline>EPP leaders to push for stability pact.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Union's Christian Democrat leaders said on Thursday next week's EU summit must agree both on plans for the single currency and a stability pact to ensure budgetary discipline continues after January 1, 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;As regards Economic and Monetary Union and the Euro and the stability pact, we want the whole package,&quot; the president of the centre-right European People's Party, Wilfried Martens, told reporters after their pre-EU summit meeting.</p>
<p>He said the six leaders -- Spain's Jose Maria Aznar, Ireland's John Bruton, Luxembourg's Jean-Claude Juncker, Germany's Helmut Kohl, Italy's Romano Prodi and Belgium's Jean-Luc Dehaene -- also demanded an initiative on employment.</p>
<p>But they deferred until March 4 discussion of a draft EU treaty presented by EU president Ireland shortly before they met on Thursday to prepare the bloc for expansion to eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Bruton, who will host the December 13-14 summit, told a news conference earlier there would be agreement on the legal framework for the single currency as well as on a new exchange rate mechanism, the ERM2, which will link the single currency with EU currencies which do not join.</p>
<p>He expressed the hope that there would also at the summit be a deal on the stability pact.</p>
<p>EU finance ministers failed to reach full agreement on the pact at a meeting in Brussels this week but will try again in Dublin on the eve of the summit.</p>
<p>Hopes of a deal on the stability pact increased last Monday when Germany -- virtually alone in arguing for stringent conditions -- appeared to soften its stance slightly.</p>
<p>German Chancellor Kohl refused all comment to reporters on arrival at the meeting of the EPP leaders, saying he had attended the meeting to work and not to give interviews.</p>
<p>The Christian Democrat leaders agreed that the EU should extend its full competence during the ongoing EU intergovernmental conference to fully take on the fight against organised crime like drugs and terrorism.</p>
<p>But Martens said they acknowledged some countries might need a phasing-in period of perhaps five years before they handed over more power on the crime-fighting issue to the EU.</p>
<p>The EPP also agreed to admit Christian Democratic parties from five eastern European countries -- the Czech Republic, Romania, Lithuania, Slovenia and Slovakia -- as observers, as preparation for the day they join the bloc. 052245 GMT dec 96</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
