<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23753" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures still down late on cash.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures still down late on cash.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures, pressured by soft swing prices, stayed mostly lower late Friday, but some expected a slight rebound before the close as shorts covered ahead of the holiday weekend.</p>
<p>At 1400 EDT, Oct was still down by 2.7 cents at $1.88 per million British thermal units, while November was 1.6 cents lower at $2.03. Others were steady to off by three cents.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is oversold and there's pretty good support in the $1.85-1.86 area (in Oct). I don't think I'd want to go home short for the (U.S. Labor Day) holiday in front of the storms,&quot; said one Houston-based trader.  </p>
<p>While Hurricane Edouard offered no threat to the U.S. Gulf, forecasters were monitoring Hurricane Fran, which was 215 miles north-northeast of Antigua at 1100 EDT, with winds of 75 mph moving northwest at nine mph. The storm was not expected to gain any strength in the next day.</p>
<p>Next was Tropical Storm Gustav, about 970 miles west of the Cape Verde islands at 1100 EDT but losing steam.</p>
<p>Though there was little extreme weather on the horizon, traders said even warmer temperatures next week could help September prices as flows begin, particularly after this week's very mild weather.</p>
<p>But few saw any reason for a significant rally near-term.</p>
<p>September cash prices at the Gulf notionally fell a couple of cents Friday to the mid-$1.70s, with swing prices in the $1.60-1.70 area. Midcon prices were steady to up slightly in the low-to-mid $1.60s.</p>
<p>Technically, traders pegged October support at yesterday's low of $1.85 and then at $1.82. Resistance was seen first at $1.955 and then in the $2.08-2.09 area.</p>
<p>NYMEX said 6,306 Henry Hub contracts traded at 1340 EDT.</p>
<p>NYMEX October Permian natgas was off two cents at $1.56, with November still 3.5 cents lower at $1.67. NYMEX said 45 lots traded at 1340 EDT.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, October eased 0.2 cent to $1.64, while deferreds were one-half to two cents lower. The East/West spread narrowed by 2.5 cents to 24 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>NYMEX and KCBT will be closed Monday for the U.S. Labor Day holiday.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
