<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237577" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Bhutto says parrots better off than jailed spouse.</title>
<headline>Bhutto says parrots better off than jailed spouse.</headline>
<byline>Ibrahim Khan</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan's ousted prime minister Benazir Bhutto said after visiting her jailed husband on Thursday that she feared he might be poisoned.</p>
<p>&quot;I fear someone may give cyanide to Asif (Ali Zardari),&quot; she told Reuters after a one-hour talk with her spouse. &quot;I have informed Asif about the sinister elimination plan but he says 'I am ready for every sacrifice for the sake of my country',&quot;.</p>
<p>She described his cell at Landhi Prison near Karachi as a cage worse than that one in which she keeps her parrots at home.</p>
<p>Bhutto, sacked by President Farooq Leghari a month ago, said he was among several people who wanted to eliminate her husband.</p>
<p>The president, once a close political ally of Bhutto, removed her government on disputed charges of corruption and misrule. The caretaker government he appointed has promised to bring undisclosed charges against Bhutto and Zardari.</p>
<p>Bhutto accused Leghari of murdering her estranged brother, Murtaza Bhutto, shot dead by police in Karachi on September 20.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no law in the country,&quot; Bhutto said. &quot;Farooq Leghari is my brother's murderer. He is a worse dictator than (former military ruler General Muhammad) Zia-ul-Haq.&quot;</p>
<p>Murtaza's supporters accuse Zardari of involvement in a conspiracy to kill their leader. He denies the charge.</p>
<p>Leghari's spokesman could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>Zardari's jailers searched a basket of dried and fresh fruit that Bhutto had brought for her husband.</p>
<p>Kicking the bars of his cell, Zardari  shouted: &quot;Jiye (Long live) Bhutto,&quot; as she arrived.</p>
<p>&quot;The authorities are mentally torturing me,&quot; Zardari said. &quot;They want different statements from me.&quot;</p>
<p>Zardari, investment minister in his wife's cabinet, was at the centre of corruption allegations swirling around the ousted government. He and Bhutto deny any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>Bhutto said she had reports that Leghari would be removed between December 25 and 31 because he had failed to produce any proof of the charges he had levelled against her and Zardari.</p>
<p>&quot;The concerned quarters are not happy with Leghari now,&quot; she added cryptically, in an apparent reference to the military.</p>
<p>Bhutto said her husband was caged like a convict, but was in good spirits. &quot;Asif is in high morale. He offers prayers in the cage. He has no television or radio,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She said male intelligence agents had stayed nearby while she talked to Zardari through the bars of his cell.</p>
<p>&quot;I could not talk freely with my husband due to bugging devices in and around it,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The whole conversation has been taped.&quot;</p>
<p>Armed police guarded the jail and police officers stayed in touch with their superiors in Karachi by hand-held radio sets.</p>
<p>&quot;I am very sorry that the government has given one of the worst treatments in jail to Asif, who is a politician and had been federal minister twice,&quot; Bhutto said.</p>
<p>&quot;My hands are clean. Leghari, who is the enemy of the Bhutto family wants to torture me and punish me. Leghari wants to give as much mental torture to Zardari as possible. I am very much disturbed by these tortures,&quot; Bhutto said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
