<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237559" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: New Italian law means 250,000 immigrants can stay.</title>
<headline>New Italian law means 250,000 immigrants can stay.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Parliament approved a law on Thursday that will allow 250,000 previously illegal immigrants whose status had been thrown into doubt to stay in Italy.</p>
<p>The law was adopted in the Chamber of Deputies (lower house) by 261 votes to 126 with two abstentions.</p>
<p>It passed the Senate last month after the centre-left government used a confidence vote to sweep away an avalanche of blocking amendments, most of them from hard-right opponents.</p>
<p>The law covers only foreigners who registered with police under a measure issued as a temporary decree last November offering an amnesty to immigrants who legalised their status.</p>
<p>The measure, which had force of law for 60 days, was subsequently extended but a recent Constitutional Court ruling barred governments from rolling over decrees.</p>
<p>The ruling meant that without the law some 210,000 immigrants whose registration had been acknowledged and some 45,000 whose applications were pending technically could have been expelled from Italy.</p>
<p>Longer-term laws on immigration still have to be drawn up.</p>
<p>The hard-right National Alliance party, which wants tougher action to stop illegal immigrants entering Italy and to expel those who get in, criticised the new bill as a lost opportunity.</p>
<p>&quot;If our cities become less safe, we'll know that the fault lies with a government which has missed a chance to establish more effective rules on expulsion,&quot; senior National Alliance politician Maurizio Gasparri said.</p>
<p>The separatist Northern League, which has a strong anti-immigrant slant, also attacked the bill.</p>
<p>Anti-racist and immigrant groups generally welcomed the measure.</p>
<p>Apart from allowing registered immigrants to stay, it contains provisions from the past decrees which allow police to expel foreigners without appeal if they are considered a threat to public order.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
