<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237984" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - PowerGen flexes muscles with buyback.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - PowerGen flexes muscles with buyback.</headline>
<byline>Jo Winterbottom</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>British electricity generator PowerGen spent 202 million pounds ($328 million) on Thursday buying back five percent of its own shares at 605 pence each in one of the first such moves since rules were changed in October.</p>
<p>PowerGen said in November with its half year results that it would buy back up to 10 percent of shares &quot;when appropriate&quot;.</p>
<p>PowerGen's purchase price was the high of the day and shares had eased back to be up 17.5 pence at 588 pence by 1400 GMT.</p>
<p>The British Treasury moved in October to tighten up legislation around some capital restructurings in order to cut back on tax credits.</p>
<p>&quot;The market had expected PowerGen to flex its muscles and return excess value to shareholders,&quot; said analyst Nigel Hawkins of Yamaichi.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, water and sewerage company Severn Trent bought 2.5 million of its shares or just under one percent from ABN AMRO Hoare Govett.</p>
<p>These shares had been sold by the government earlier on the same day as part of a move to sell off its remaining stakes in a slew of utilities.</p>
<p>PowerGen's decision to go ahead with its buy back spurred shares in other stocks which are seen as likely to be considering similar moves.</p>
<p>Banking group Barclays Plc gained 15.5 pence to 1,031.5 pence while PowerGen's fellow generator National Power strode 16.5 pence higher to 464 pence.</p>
<p>The premium set in PowerGen's buy back should help to boost the company's share price, analysts said, while at the same time enabling short-term investors to move out of the company.</p>
<p>&quot;People left in should be those who see higher value in the company,&quot; said one analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>The move also indicated that PowerGen was not looking to diversify or prepare for any major acquisitions in the near term, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;Investors are probably reassured that PowerGen is giving back value to them instead of diversifying outside their core businesses,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>PowerGen was frustrated in its attempt to buy regional electricity company Midlands Electricity by the government's decision to block the bid earlier this year.</p>
<p>It bought back 10 percent of its shares in May and June for around 400 million pounds.</p>
<p>The latest buyback should also improve prospects for dividend growth, one analyst said, as it will boost PowerGen's earnings per share profile.</p>
<p>&quot;Reducing the number of shares in relation to earnings should enable PowerGen to maintain a stronger outlook for its dividend,&quot; the analyst said. ($1=0.6161 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I17000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
