<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237941" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BRUSSELS LAUNCHES UNLISTED SECURITIES MARKET.</title>
<headline>BRUSSELS LAUNCHES UNLISTED SECURITIES MARKET.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Brussels bourse on Thursday launched a new Interprofessional Market for non-listed securites - MIM - aimed at giving small and medium sized companies an organised forum to address institutional investors.</p>
<p>&quot;It allows companies to give a select offering to a select group,&quot; Johnny Neven, responsible at the bourse for coordinating and promoting the MIM, told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the primary intention of the MIM was to facilitate the financing of non-quoted companies through the issue of equity or convertible bonds. Secondly it would add to the liquidity of trade in unlisted securities.</p>
<p>Five sessions a year are planned, with the next set for February 20.</p>
<p>The MIM is a private market between professionals where no publicity for stocks is allowed and a maximum of 50 people can be sollicited to buy stock. Above that number an operation would be classified as a public offer and be subject to rules of the Belgian Banking and Finance Commission.</p>
<p>&quot;It is easier for companies to go to the Interprofessional Market than straight to the bourse as it costs less, there is less administration and fewer formalities. There are just six or seven pages of rules,&quot; Neven said.</p>
<p>MIM has 56 members of which seven are non-Belgian.</p>
<p>Belgian start-up firm International Brachytherapy SA - involved in cancer treatment through radiation implants - said in November it planned to offer stock on the MIM.</p>
<p>Two other companies named by financial daily L'Echo as also planning to propose stock to investors in Thursday's session are Ecopolis - a Belgian ecological glass waste collector, and Aircraft Distribution and Finance (ADR), a company based in the Dutch Antilles. The bourse was unable to confirm the names.</p>
<p>Ecopolis and International Brachytherapy also said last month they were interested in being quoted on Brussels' &quot;Nouveau Marche&quot; or New Market, a small capitalisation market due to launch in January as part of the Euro-NM project involving the Brussels, Paris, Frankfurt and Amsterdam stock exchanges.</p>
<p>-- Lorrayne Smith, Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6812, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
