<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="237917" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: FOCUS-France seeks to reassure Korea on Thomson.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-France seeks to reassure Korea on Thomson.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>France moved on Thursday to reassure South Korea after its decision to halt the sale of state-owned electronics giant Thomson SA drew a protest from Seoul and withering scorn in the French media.</p>
<p>The government, whose decision to allow part of the group to be sold to Korean firm Daewoo sparked a nationalist backlash, made a U-turn on Wednesday after an independent privatisation commission challenged Daewoo's involvement.</p>
<p>A foreign ministry spokesman said on Thursday that France's ambassador would meet South Korean Deputy Prime Minister Han Seung-soo on Friday to offer an explanation.</p>
<p>&quot;Our ambassador in Seoul will be received tomorrow by the deputy prime minister for economic affairs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ambassador Dominique Perreau would echo comments on Thursday by French Finance Minister Jean Arthuis that the privatisation commission's decision did not rule out an eventual participation by Daewoo in the privatisation, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is not the quality of the companies concerned, not Lagardere nor Daewoo Electronics, that is being questioned. What is being questioned are the terms of the transfer between Thomson and Daewoo,&quot; Arthuis told reporters in parliament.</p>
<p>A government source told Reuters that Perreau would make clear the French government was bound to respect the independent seven-member commission's decision.</p>
<p>&quot;We will explain to the Koreans that the government has no authority over the privatisation commission,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>Seoul earlier demanded an &quot;understandable explanation&quot; for the decision amid charges that racism may have been a factor.</p>
<p>&quot;We have requested an understandable explanation from the French government for our public,&quot; a Korean Foreign Ministry spokesman said. &quot;We would like to know whether the commission's opinion was based on economic factors or public opposition.&quot;</p>
<p>Economic ties with fast-growing South Korea are important for France, which wants a share of Seoul's multi-billion-dollar military spending plans and other industrial projects.</p>
<p>French analysts said the Thomson suspension could seriously chill relations and might dash any hope France may have of winning military contracts over strong U.S. dominance.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Alain Juppe has vowed to go forward with the sale of Thomson but has not yet specified new terms.</p>
<p>Arthuis said he hoped the privatisation would happen before the spring and did not rule out breaking up the company to sell its defence and consumer electronics businesses separately.</p>
<p>French media rained contempt on the government's handling of the sale, branding the suspension a &quot;disaster&quot; and a &quot;fiasco&quot; with execrable public presentation. Newspapers said France's image with foreign investors would be seriously damaged by the debacle.</p>
<p>Influential daily Le Monde lamented the &quot;terribly sad irony&quot; of the good governance theme chosen for a Franco-African summit this week in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso.</p>
<p>President Jacques Chirac was ill-placed to teach Africans lessons on good governance and sound economic management when the Paris government was making such a shambles of its own privatisation programme, it said.</p>
<p>Under the shelved plan, France was to have sold loss-making Thomson to electronics group Lagardere for a symbolic one franc. Lagardere in turn planned to sell Thomson Multimedia to Daewoo -- also for just one franc.</p>
<p>The privatisation commission said the Daewoo deal did not fully reflect the value of Thomson's technology. It also made clear it preferred a rival offer from Alcatel Alsthom.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
