<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238032" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Traders mixed on Urals despite heavy Dec programme.</title>
<headline>Traders mixed on Urals despite heavy Dec programme.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil traders had mixed views on the value of Urals on Thursday following the release of the December loading programme.</p>
<p>The programme schedules the loading of a heavy 2,767,000 tonnes of crude for December despite the planned closure of berth number one from Dec 9-24, and the three- to four-day closure of the main pipeline feeding Novorossiisk planned for some point during the month.</p>
<p>Berth one is the only berth at Novorossiisk that can accommodate tankers of 100,000-140,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>The programme plans a brisk loading schedule of 60,000-80,000 tonne tankers from berths six and seven.</p>
<p>&quot;The programme is for huge quantities,&quot; said one Med refiner. &quot;Even if only 70 percent of the programme gets out, Urals is going to weaken to around (Dated Brent) -40/50 (cents).&quot;</p>
<p>The refiner said that sweet West African grades offered a margin of 50/60 cents a barrel over Urals. Prices for Iraqi Kirkuk crude, expected back on the market this month, are also more attractive, he said.</p>
<p>But other traders said exports of Urals were likely to be heavily crimped by maintenance and bad winter weather at Novorossiisk.</p>
<p>&quot;You'd have to be from another planet to think that we're going to see plenty of Urals in December,&quot; said one trader for a European major.</p>
<p>The trader valued Urals at around Dated Brent -10 cents, with offers still at Dated Brent parity.</p>
<p>West African grades were virtually sold out for December, with just 5-6 million barrels still unsold, traders said.</p>
<p>Two cargoes of Bonny Light, two Forcados and a Brass River were still seen offered. Good buying interest was seen from the U.S. as well as the Med.</p>
<p>A Qua Iboe cargo, already on the water having loaded Dec 2-4, was heard traded at Dated Brent +35 cents. But this was not seen as representative of the market after a third decade Dec cargo traded earlier in the week at Dated +50/55 cents.</p>
<p>--Rosalind Russell, London Newsroom +44 171 542 5387</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
