<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238082" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Most reinsurance rates falling sharply - UK broker.</title>
<headline>Most reinsurance rates falling sharply - UK broker.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The price of reinsurance is continuing to decline ahead of the key January renewal season, a unit of broker Willis Corroon Group Plc said in its December Market Review.</p>
<p>&quot;Good results for the past three years, allied with ever increasing capital resources, whether internally generated or being attracted from outside the industry, are leading to further substantial softening in rates for virtually all classes,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is of obvious concern to reinsurers who are striving to protect their market shares and at the same time to maintain an adequate return to their shareholders.&quot;</p>
<p>The reinsurance market was approaching the January 1 renewal season, when many programmes are re-negotiated, &quot;with a certain degree of trepidation,&quot; Willis Faber &amp; Dumas Limited said in the report.</p>
<p>However, Willis Faber, which provides reinsurance broking and advisory services, said that some buyers of reinsurance shared the concern about falling rates, aware that a violent reduction would almost certainly lead to a counter reaction in a few years time.</p>
<p>This view was echoed earlier this week at a London International Insurance and Reinsurance Market Association (LIRMA) forum meeting on the renewal season.</p>
<p>One reinsurer told the meeting that some European insurers were opting to remain with their existing programmes, despite in some cases having received more competitive offers.</p>
<p>In addition to good results and surplus capacity, recent consolidation within the reinsurance industry is also driving prices lower, Willis Faber said, noting that three of the top 10 reinsurers in 1994 are no longer independent.</p>
<p>&quot;Faced with such formidable reinsurance groups both in size and scope, some smaller reinsurers are falling back on price as the main competitive weapon to maintain their current portfolios.&quot;</p>
<p>Other pressures on rates include a stronger presence by Lloyds of London syndicates following the market's success in overcoming its past problems and the comeback of the retrocession market.</p>
<p>&quot;Reinsurers...can now purchase retrocession protections at prices and levels of deductible which have not been seen since the late 1980s,&quot; Willis Faber said.</p>
<p>In the longer term, the trend towards electronic trading will add further downward pressure to prices, it added.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Insurance News 44 171 542 2769</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8200318">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
