<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238292" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German chemical sector pay talks deadlocked.</title>
<headline>German chemical sector pay talks deadlocked.</headline>
<dateline>HANOVER, Germany 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The latest round of wage talks in the German chemical sector, where traditionaly cosy labour relations have been strained by planned cuts to sick entitlements, remained deadlocked on Thursday.</p>
<p>Chemical industry trade union IG Chemie said an initial offer by employers including a 2.5 percent pay rise and a cut in sick pay was &quot;completely unacceptable&quot;.</p>
<p>IG Chemie, representing some 590,000 workers in the industry, went into the negotiations asking for a 4.2 percent rise in wages and for sick pay to be kept at 100 percent of salary.</p>
<p>In return for full sick pay, which employers can cut to 80 percent under a new federal law, it has said it is prepared to make concessions in others areas, such as existing worker bonuses.</p>
<p>But the BAVC chemical employers federation's proposal would mean sick pay trimmed to 80 percent of salary for the first four weeks of illness. Only after that would employers top up health insurance payments to make up a full salary.</p>
<p>German chemicals group BASF AG backed down on attempts to introduce the cut to sick pay in October after the move was met by walk-outs by some 13,000 of its workers.</p>
<p>The failure to find agreement in the chemical sector follows a surprise pact on sick pay concluded in the metal and engineering industry by negotiators which had also met in the northern town of Hanover.</p>
<p>--Mark John, Bonn Newsroom +49 228 260 97150</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOVER, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
