<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238252" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: British Air ends policy excluding Jews in lounge.</title>
<headline>British Air ends policy excluding Jews in lounge.</headline>
<dateline>ALBANY, N.Y. 1996-12-04</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc has decided to stop excluding Jews from a lounge for Middle East travelers at London's Heathrow airport where a New York prosecutor was asked to leave while praying, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>New York Attorney General Dennis Vacco said the airline disclosed their new policy in a letter to the prosecutor, Aaron Tyk, who had been told in October by an employee at the lounge that it &quot;was not for Jews.&quot; Tyk was in transit back to the United States from a vacation in Israel.</p>
<p>In the letter, a British Airways general manager Barbara Cassani said, &quot;To avoid any future misunderstanding, we have simplified our rules and clarified that the Oasis Lounge is available to all transferring passengers to and from the Middle East, including Israel.&quot;</p>
<p>British Airways initially denied the incident happened, and then gave differing explanations. It said that Israel was not considered a Middle Eastern destination for the lounge's purposes, and then said Tyk did not have the correct ticket for the lounge even though Tyk said the employee who had asked him to leave did not check his travel documents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-04"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALBANY, N.Y."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
