<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238240" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Dec 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Dec 5.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carried the following stories in its Thursday edition:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - D.C. Financial Officer Anthony Williams fired 11 public school employees who handled budget matters, the first major shake-up in the central office since Julius Becton took charge of the troubled system last month.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A panel of economists appointed by Congress reported on the accuracy of the consumer price index, setting the terms for a potentially explosive political battle that could affect most of the households in the United States.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>UNITED NATIONS - Secretary General Boutros Boutros-Ghali suspended his candidacy for reelection in a significant advance for the campaign by the United States to deny a second term to the veteran Egyptian diplomat.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The United States signalled a chilly new phase in its up-and-down relationship with Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic by announcing that the Voice of America will beam more news programs into his country.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - A federal judge has ruled that the Loudon County school system must teach an autistic child in a regular classroom rather than with other disabled students, giving advocates of mainstreaming a victory in a two-year battle that drew national attention.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - Federal and state officials are struggling to respond to new marijuana laws in California and Arizona that critics say are so loosely written that even some people suffering from sinus headaches could legally possess the drug.</p>
<p>---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
