<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238237" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Columbia astronauts prepare for landing.</title>
<headline>Columbia astronauts prepare for landing.</headline>
<byline>Julie Vorman</byline>
<dateline>CAPE CANAVERAL, Florida 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Astronauts hastily readied shuttle Columbia early on Thursday for its journey home as NASA officials anxiously watched the skies to see if they would remain clear long enough for a Florida landing.</p>
<p>Weather forecasts said scattered clouds and a low-pressure front moving across Florida would make conditions &quot;marginally acceptable&quot; for a landing at 7:33 a.m. EST (1233 GMT), said National Aeronautics and Space Administration spokesman Rob Navias.</p>
<p>Conditions were better at a back-up landing site at Edwards Air Force Base in California, he said. NASA prefers to land the shuttles whenever possible at Kennedy Space Centre to avoid the additional $1 million cost of ferrying the shuttle from California to Florida.</p>
<p>Space agency officials ordered the orbiter's five-member crew to return to earth one day earlier than planned after a crucial navigation tool unexpectedly failed on Wednesday and weather conditions began to worsen at all of the shuttle's landing sites.</p>
<p>The decision to call Columbia home early also came after a stuck airlock hatch last weekend forced NASA to scrap a pair of planned spacewalks.</p>
<p>Ground controllers remained concerned about the stuck hatch, which could present an additional problem in the unlikely event that Columbia's cargo bay doors are unable to close properly at about 4 a.m. EST (0900 GMT). Although the cargo payload doors have always operated smoothly for landing preparations, if there is a problem the astronauts would have to pry open the stuck hatch and make a spacewalk to manually crank the doors.</p>
<p>If bad weather forces a delay, Columbia has a second landing opportunity at Kennedy Space Centre at 9:10 a.m. EST (1410 GMT), NASA said. The orbiter could also land at Edwards Air Force Base in the Mohave Desert later on Thursday, where skies were expected to be clear all day.</p>
<p>During the night, shuttle commander Ken Cockrell tested all 38 steering jets on the orbiter to make sure they were working for Columbia's high-speed landing.</p>
<p>The latest technical problem knocked out one of the shuttle's three crucial navigation units, known as inertial measurement units.</p>
<p>Although NASA flight director Wayne Hale said the &quot;primary factor&quot; for the crew's early return was the weather, he acknowledged the two equipment problems also played a role. &quot;They certainly indicate that you ought to button things up and be prepared to come down at the earliest opportunity,&quot; he said, referring to the stuck hatch and the broken navigation unit.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE CANAVERAL, Florida"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
