<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238321" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German shipowners see high 1997/98 new deliveries.</title>
<headline>German shipowners see high 1997/98 new deliveries.</headline>
<dateline>HAMBURG 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>New shipping investments resulted in 130 new deliveries to German owners worth five billion marks in 1996 and this rate of deliveries could be maintained in 1997 and 1998, the shipowners' association VDR said.</p>
<p>In 1995, German shipowners took delivery of 100 new vessels worth four billion marks. Strong orders up to the first half of this year made the rate of deliveries likely to continue.</p>
<p>VDR's annual report said a wave of new orders was seen between October 1995 and April 1996, which should help further modernise the 12.5 million gross registered tons (GRT) fleet currently owned by German companies and individuals.</p>
<p>Some 44 percent of the 1,560-vessel fleet flies the German flag while others have been flagged out.</p>
<p>The figures apply to ships above 4,000 grt.</p>
<p>VDR said of the 130 newbuildings, more than 100 would be added to the German-flag fleet which receives some tax breaks.</p>
<p>VDR complained that aid totalling 100 million marks in 1996 would be cut to 40 million marks or even lower in 1997.</p>
<p>A fall in new orders to 30 in the second half of 1996 versus more than 100 a year earlier already reflected this development, it added, also citing worries about an increasing tonnage overhang in world charter markets.</p>
<p>-Vera Eckert, Hamburg newsroom, +49-40-41903275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
