<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238378" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: FAO says sanctions against Burundi hitting hard.</title>
<headline>FAO says sanctions against Burundi hitting hard.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO) said on Thursday that economic sanctions against Burundi were hitting the central African country's ability to feed itself and refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;As a result of the embargo on food imports, the nutritional status of the population in general and of the internally displaced people and dispersed populations in particular, is likely to be seriously affected,&quot; FAO said in a report.</p>
<p>Burundi's Tutsi-dominated military government took power on July 25 in a coup. Regional states including Tanzania, Kenya and Zaire imposed economic and political sanctions six days later.</p>
<p>An FAO assessment mission visited the country in October, making field visits to five of 15 provinces.</p>
<p>FAO said Burundi, which derives four fifths of its export earnings from coffee, was forecast to produce a total of 3.5 million tonnes of food, three percent less than in 1995.</p>
<p>Burundi's coffee production in 1996/97 was forecast at 30,000 tonnes with harvesting generally starting in June and running through the second half of the calendar year.</p>
<p>But the special report said the deepening socio-political crisis in July 1996 and the economic sanctions have disrupted coffee marketing activities.</p>
<p>&quot;It has been reported that there will be a 20 to 25 percent quality loss if this year's coffee crop is not processed by January 1997 and an almost total loss of the harvest if not processed by April 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Given the embargo on all exports and imports, the resulting loss in foreign exchange earnings from coffee exports will adversely affect the country's commercial import capacity when the sanctions are lifted,&quot; FAO said.</p>
<p>Output of tea, which provides 10 percent of Burundi's export earnings, was forecast to exceed 7,000 tonnes in 1996 due to favourable weather but processing capacity has been reduced due to the closing of two plants because of a lack of spare parts.</p>
<p>Burundi has sold no tea on the international market since August 2, 1996 because of the embargo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURUN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
