<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238614" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ debt ends weaker after Brash comment, rumours.</title>
<headline>NZ debt ends weaker after Brash comment, rumours.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>New Zealand debt markets weakened at Thursday's close after a sliding currency undermined progress in the money market, and selling in global markets overnight hit the local bonds.</p>
<p>The three year bonds ended five basis points weaker while the 11/06 yield climbed eight, breaking back up through seven percent -- a crucial psychological level on the way down -- to 7.04 percent.  </p>
<p>The 90-day bank bills and their corresponding futures contracts ended largely flat after a promising open, as the currency fell away on the back of comments by Reserve Bank governor Don Brash.</p>
<p>After addressing a summit of exporters in Wellington, Brash told reporters the Kiwi dollar was near the top of its cycle. The Kiwi shed more than 40 basis points on the back of the comment, even though Brash said there was nothing new in it. Further weakness stemmed from a summit spokesman quoting Brash as saying he was comfortable with some flexibility in the 0-2 percent inflation target band over the business cycle.  </p>
<p>One bond dealer said market sentiment had not been helped by small &quot;scurrilous&quot; rumours of a supposed end to samurai issuance in New Zealand dollars, and also rumours that influential Japanese Finance Ministry official Eisuke Sakakibara had been talking about a hike in Japanese interest rates.</p>
<p>He said the Sakakibara rumours had impacted on the Australian market, and subsequently on New Zealand. However, he warned against reading too much into the market's weakness.</p>
<p>&quot;I think this is just corrective actually. I can't get too worried about this sort of thing -- the market is just getting itself in a fluster about nothing.&quot;  </p>
<p>Confirmation by Prime Minister Jim Bolger that parliament would reconvene on December 12 was well received by the market as it could force New Zealand First's hand, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our position is now a little more known in terms of getting a result, because if they have to sit by the 12th, NZ First is going to have to mnake their position known by the Monday, Tuesdy or Wednesday before parliament sits, or risk a no-confidence motion being moved and then having to pick a side,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>Nationalist NZ First, which holds the balance of power, is negotiating with both the caretaker conservative National Party government and the centre-left Labour Party over the shape of the new government, following an inconclusive general election in October.</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>NZD VS	  3 YR	   10 YR	* NZD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p>USD	   117   (+3)     97  (+5)   * FUTURES     -17  (-4)</p>
<p>CAD	   249  (-17)     87  (-5)   * PHYSICALS    17  (+3)</p>
<p>AUD	    33   (-5)    -11  (-2)</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Catherine McCaw (64 4) 471 4275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
