<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238658" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-S&amp;P sees saturated Australian casino industry.</title>
<headline>RTRS-S&amp;P sees saturated Australian casino industry.</headline>
<dateline>MELBOURNE 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Standard and Poor's Corp said it considers the Australian casino industry to have reached saturation point, given the rise in the nimber of casinos to 14 from eight in 1992.</p>
<p>&quot;Consequently, business and financial risks associated with increased casino competition have heightened,&quot; S&amp;P said in a report on the gaming industry.</p>
<p>The ratings agency said the casino industry returned a operating profit margin of 6.5 percent in fiscal 1995 compared with 14.8 percent in fiscal 1992.  </p>
<p>&quot;Over the same period, yields on both assets and funbds employed have almost halved, while total liabilities as a proportion of total assets have risen sharply to 38.6 percent,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said that although gaming was one of Australia's fastest growing industries, with national gaming spending growth of 16 percent per year in the two decades to 1995, there has also been a rise in gaming industry debt.</p>
<p>S&amp;P estimated gaming industry debt to be more than A$1.5 billion in Australia and New Zealand, with further increases likely.  </p>
<p>&quot;Standard &amp; Poor's expects business risk for casino operations to increase once the permanent Sydney and Melbourne casinos open,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>The A$1 billion Sydney casino to be operated by Sydney Harbour Casino Ltd will open in late 1997 while Crown Ltd's A$1.6 billion Melbourne casino will open around February 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Already, intense competition for lucrative premium players, and an under-estimation of overall patrons requirements has underscored unanticipated financial losses from several, newly listed entrants to the industry,&quot; S&amp;P said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Opportunities arising from state differences in per capita gaming expenditures, combined with increased market targeting of lucrative Asia-Pacific patrons, suggests gaming industry turnover will continue to grow at double-digits,&quot; S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>The ratings agency said market saturation in Australia's gaming industry had brought uncertainty in the risk profile to resemble that of the U.S. gaming industry.</p>
<p>&quot;Standard &amp; Poor's therefore expects the Australian gambling industry's overall risk profile to resemble that of the U.S. industry, where more than 80 percent of the gaming company-related ratings fall within the 'BB' and 'B' category.&quot;  </p>
<p>S&amp;P said it expected Australia to have an additional 35,000 gaming machines installed by the year 2000. Australia currently has 140,000 gaming machines, double the level in 1991 and second in the world only to the United States with 450,000 machines.</p>
<p>The ratings agency said gaming growth also was attracting new industry entrants, such as Fosters Brewing Group Ltd, through expansion of its hotel ownership network.</p>
<p>Qantas Airways Ltd was also continuing to assess the market potential for gaming services to be offered on international flights, S&amp;P said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97912">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MELBOURNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
