<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238792" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Discovery Channel, BBC team up in major venture.</title>
<headline>Discovery Channel, BBC team up in major venture.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Discovery Channel said on Thursday it had teamed up with the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) in a US$500 million venture to make programmes and launch new channels.</p>
<p>It said in a statement Discovery Communications Inc, the parent of cable television's Discovery Channel, and BBC Worldwide Ltd, the state-owned BBC's commercial arm, would launch new channels in the United States and elsewhere.</p>
<p>The venture would also create hundreds of hours of new programmes, the statement said.</p>
<p>It said Discovery would finance the venture, which would have access to the BBC's vast programme library.</p>
<p>The statement quoted Discovery founder John S. Hendricks, who part-owns the company, as saying: &quot;I can't think of a better partner for what I'm sure will be a very exciting journey.&quot;</p>
<p>The statement did not say what kind of programmes the venture would make, but both Discovery Channel and the BBC are strong in wildlife and evironmental programmes.</p>
<p>Discovery Communications is owned by Liberty Media Corp, a division of Tele-Communications Inc, Cox Communications, Advance Newhouse Communications and Hendricks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I9741109">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
