<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238739" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Jakarta subversion trials start next week - report.</title>
<headline>Jakarta subversion trials start next week - report.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three subversion trials involving members of a small left-wing group accused of instigating Jakarta's July 27 riots will begin next week, the Kompas newspaper reported on Thursday.</p>
<p>Kompas, a leading Indonesian daily, quoted court officials as saying the three cases being tried at the Central Jakarta State Court involved five members of the People's Democratic Party (PRD), including chairman Budiman Sudjatmiko.</p>
<p>&quot;All the cases are ready to be tried on December 12,&quot; I Gde Ketut Sukarata, chief judge of the court, was quoted as telling reporters.</p>
<p>No court officials were available to confirm the report but defence lawyer Dwiyanto Prihartono told Reuters: &quot;We have not been officially informed but it is 90 percent sure it will be December 12.&quot;</p>
<p>The government and military blamed the small left-wing PRD for the riots, the capital's worst in more than 20 years.</p>
<p>Independent labour leader Muchtar Pakpahan and four other PRD members will be tried on similar charges in the South Jakarta State Court in another three trials.</p>
<p>An official at the South Jakarta court told Reuters on Thursday that these three cases were still being processed and no dates had been set for the trials.</p>
<p>Subversion carries the death penalty in Indonesia.</p>
<p>Marzuki Darusman, deputy chairman of Indonesia's official National Commission on Human Rights, said on Wednesday it was not clear why the 10 men, arrested soon after the riots, were being tried.</p>
<p>&quot;One question still lingers. Why were they detained? What is the connection between their detention and the events of July 27,&quot; Darusman said.</p>
<p>The dossiers of Pakpahan, from the unrecognised Indonesian Welfare Labour Union, and the nine PRD activists were submitted to the two Jakarta courts on Monday with officials saying they expected the trials to begin within two weeks.</p>
<p>Another three PRD activists in Surabaya, in East Java, and three in Semarang in Central Java were also expected to have dossiers in their cases handed over soon to the courts.</p>
<p>At least five people died in the riots, which erupted after police raided the headquarters of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) and evicted supporters of ousted PDI leader Megawati Sukarnoputri.</p>
<p>Megawati was ousted from the post by a government-backed faction in June. Political analysts have said the government moved to sideline Megawati because it feared she would draw votes from the ruling Golkar party in next year's parliamentary elections.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
