<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238804" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia cocoa output seen down despite Q4 rebound.</title>
<headline>Malaysia cocoa output seen down despite Q4 rebound.</headline>
<byline>Barani Krishnaan</byline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Favourable weather drove up Malaysia's cocoa output in the last quarter of 1996, but total production is still expected to be lower than in 1995, government officials and growers said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We still maintain an estimate of 122,000 tonnes for this year compared to the 131,000 tonnes produced in 1995,&quot; said Mohamed Musa Jamil, Malaysian Cocoa Board director-general.</p>
<p>The board forecast output in 1997 to fall further to 120,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>&quot;There might be some good crop carried forward to the first quarter of next year due to the improved weather,&quot; Musa told Reuters by telephone from the east Malaysian state of Sabah on Borneo island, where the bulk of the nation's cocoa is grown.</p>
<p>Malaysian cocoa prices have firmed due to the shortage of beans in the domestic market and relatively higher prices on the London Commodity Exchange due to the strength of the pound against the ringgit, traders said.</p>
<p>The ringgit is currently trading at around 4.15 to the pound, compared to 3.96 in December last year.</p>
<p>&quot;All cocoa traders are short (of beans) and are fighting to buy whatever's left in the market,&quot; said Anthony Tsen, a cocoa farmer in Tawau, Sabah's main cocoa-growing area.</p>
<p>Prices for top-grade beans from Tawau average between 3,180 and 3,300 ringgit ($1,261 and $1,309) a tonne currently, the cocoa board said.</p>
<p>Growers said floods and heavy rains since late 1995 have destroyed the two cocoa harvests between April and June and July and September this year.</p>
<p>The growers, who were almost resigned to a bad final crop between October and December, said a slowdown in rains and fresh flowering on cocoa trees in the last couple of months should allow them to salvage most of the year-end harvest.</p>
<p>&quot;It's no big cheer but at least it's something,&quot; said Tsen, who estimated output at his farm in Tawau will improve by about 16 percent to 42.4 tonnes between October and December this year, compared to 36.7 tonnes in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Growers, however, said the future of the industry looked grim in the long-term with more and more plantation houses and corporations moving out of cocoa in favour of palm oil, a highly-valued agricultural commodity in Malaysia.</p>
<p>Golden Hope Bhd, which runs BAL Estate, the biggest cocoa plantation in Tawau, said in September that it would switch to palm oil from cocoa by mid-1999, a move seen by growers as an affirmation of the industry's bleak outlook.</p>
<p>The cocoa board said it was banking the future of the industry on smallholders, who already control about 57 percent of the 215,000 hectares of cocoa fields in Malaysia.</p>
<p>&quot;We're introducing high-yielding cocoa clones to these smallholders with the hope that they will support the crop in the new millenium,&quot; said board director-general Mohamed Musa.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-2308911)</p>
<p>	 ($1 =2.52 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
