<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238863" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - Dec 5.</title>
<headline>INDONESIAN STOCKS - factors to watch - Dec 5.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main factors likely to affect Indonesian stocks on Thursday:</p>
<p>* The Dow Jones industrial average ended down 19.75 points at 6,422.94 after shaking off a loss of more than 75 points on Wednesday as investors stepped in to pick up bargains late in the session.</p>
<p>* Chairman of the influential Association of Indonesian Moslem Intellectuals and Technology Minister Jusuf Habibie said on Wednesday there was no worry about how national developments and politics would fare once President Suharto and the the 1945 generation of current leaders are no longer in power.</p>
<p>MARKETS</p>
<p>* The Jakarta Composite Index rose 5.46 points, or 0.88 percent, to close at 626.27 points on Wednesday following active buying in the banking sector and of selected big-capitalised stocks.</p>
<p>* On Thursday, the rupiah was quoted at 2,347.50/48.00 in early trading against the opening of 2,347.50/48.50.</p>
<p>STOCKS TO WATCH</p>
<p>* Timber firm Sumalindo Lestari on market talk of a possible tender offer. The firm has denied the rumours.</p>
<p>* Footwear manufacturer Ganda Wangsa on reports the firm had set up a footwear trading firm to boost Ganda's sales in the domestic market.</p>
<p>* Telkom on talk of a possible higher dividend payment at the end of this year. The firm has denied the talk.</p>
<p>** Detergent manufacturer Unggul Indah Corporation on reports it planned to expand into the property sector.</p>
<p>* Indofood on plans to acquire its principal distributor Indomarco early next year.</p>
<p>-- Jakarta newsroom +6221 384-6364</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
