<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23890" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Quebec separatists suffer court setback.</title>
<headline>Quebec separatists suffer court setback.</headline>
<byline>Don Macdonald</byline>
<dateline>QUEBEC CITY 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The separatist Quebec government's independence drive suffered a setback on Friday when a judge ruled that a lawyer can continue his court battle to prevent any attempt by the French-speaking Canadian province to secede unilaterally.</p>
<p>Quebec Superior Court judge Robert Pidgeon ruled that lawyer Guy Bertrand can proceed with his application for a court injunction against any future referendums that would lead to a unilateral declaration of independence by Quebec.</p>
<p>Last October, Quebec separatists lost a referendum on sovereignty by one percentage point. The Parti Quebecois government is determined to hold another referendum on sovereignty, but the vote may be more than two years away.</p>
<p>In court hearings last spring, Bertrand, a flamboyant former hardline Quebec separatist turned ardent federalist, had charged that referendums leading to Quebec's unilateral declaration of independence would amount to an attempted &quot;coup d'etat&quot; and a violation of his constitutional rights.</p>
<p>In his ruling on Friday, Pidgeon said Bertrand's application for an injunction deserved a full hearing before a court.</p>
<p>&quot;Certain of the constitutional questions raised by (Bertrand) deserve to be looked at fully by a judge,&quot; Pidgeon wrote in French in his 62-page decision.</p>
<p>The separatist Parti Quebecois government tried to block Bertrand's application, arguing the courts had no place in deciding what should be a purely political matter.</p>
<p>Pidgeon said it will be up to the judge who hears the injunction application to decide whether Bertrand's constitutional rights were threatened by the Quebec government's independence drive.</p>
<p>Canada's Justice Minister Allan Rock told reporters in Quebec City he was pleased with the judge's decision, saying it meant the courts and the Canadian constitution would have a role in any Quebec secession process.</p>
<p>&quot;We are completely satisfied with the judgment that was rendered. Canadians everywhere should be encouraged to see that the courts do have a role to play and that the rule of law stands for something important in this country,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rock said the federal government would consider any future referendum on sovereignty to be purely consultative, and that to secede from Canada, Quebec must obtain the agreement of the other provinces and Ottawa through a constitutional amendment.</p>
<p>Quebec's Justice Minister Paul Begin played down Friday's ruling and made it clear his government believes the courts have no place in deciding the political future of Quebec.</p>
<p>&quot;We submit that Quebec and Quebeckers through their National Assembly and by a democratic vote in a referendum can alone decide their future,&quot; Begin said.</p>
<p>In a statement from Chicoutimi, 124 miles (200 km) north of Quebec City, Bertrand said the judgment was a victory for democracy in Quebec and Canada.</p>
<p>&quot;This judgment is a victory for all Quebec citizens whose rights and freedoms are imperiled by the threat of unilateral secession,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUEBEC CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
