<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="238960" id="root" date="1996-12-05" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - December 5.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - December 5.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-12-05</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- Chaos delays housing subsidies as the new regulations are difficult to interpret and two thirds of applications have to be returned by the authorities.</p>
<p>- Economic research institute KI forecasts a brighter 1997 and 1998 with GDP taking off, while inflation will remain low.</p>
<p>- Supermarkets will be launched on the internet next spring and will offer customers food shopping over the net.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- Umbrella trade union organization, LO, wants to negotiate with umbrella employer's organization SAF about a new central labour market deal to facilitate wage formation in the future.</p>
<p>- Sweden will not be in the first batch of European countries joining Europe's planned Economic and Monetary Union (EMU) on January 1, 1999, economic research institute KI forecasts.</p>
<p>- Mobile telephone operators with little traffic on their networks could lose their frequency.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- There is room for the Riksbank, central bank, to continue lowering its key repo rate as the Swedish economy is developing favourably in almost all areas, according to the paper.</p>
<p>- Investment company Investor AB, the key holding company in the Wallenberg family's financial empire, and Finnish finance family Ehrnrooth are planning to set up a new bank in Finland.</p>
<p>- Stolen ideas, unloyal competition and staff moving to competitors are growing problems for information companies, which call for better legal protection.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-05"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-05"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
