<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23991" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELARUS: Top Belarus politician blasts president.</title>
<headline>Top Belarus politician blasts president.</headline>
<byline>Larisa Sayenko</byline>
<dateline>MINSK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Belarus politician accused President Alexander Lukashenko on Friday of attempting to set up a dictatorship in the former Soviet republic.</p>
<p>The speaker of the Belarus parliament, Semyon Sharetsky, told Reuters that a draft constitution, due to be put to a national referendum on November 7, would dangerously increase the powers of the ruler.</p>
<p>&quot;The world community should not be indifferent to the fact that President Lukashenko, who leads this European state of 10 million people, is trying to establish a dictatorship with his new constitution,&quot; Sharetsky said.</p>
<p>The new constitution calls for a two-chamber parliament with a 110-seat majority-elected house of representatives and a regionally-represented senate with a third of its members named by the president.</p>
<p>Lukashenko's aides shrugged off Sharetsky's charge. &quot;If there was a dictatorship they wouldn't have the right to say things like this,&quot; Sergei Posukhov, Lukashenko's political adviser, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;The people have asked us to establish order and that's our main aim.&quot;</p>
<p>Lukashenko, 41, won presidential polls in 1994 on promises to restore order, fight corruption and repair the strong links with Russia that were disrupted by the collapse of the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>But during his period in office he has battled against nationalist opponents, trade unions and parliament and Sharetsky said the current parliament was ready to try to impeach him.</p>
<p>&quot;This constitution, which has been prepared in secret, aims to gather all power in one man's hands,&quot; he said. &quot;We should not be fooled by his quasi-democratic rhetoric and his methods, like this referendum.&quot;</p>
<p>Lukashenko signed a pact with Moscow in April to create a strong economic and political union which he believes could grow into a federation.</p>
<p>But nationalist groups, scared by the prospect of renewed Moscow domination and Russia's backing for Lukashenko, protested against the deal.</p>
<p>Lukashenko responded by cracking down on the nationalist opposition and jailing nearly 200 people for taking part in demonstrations against the pact.</p>
<p>The United States last week granted political asylum to two opposition leaders, Zenon Poznyak and Sergei Naumchik.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINSK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELARUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
