<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="23995" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: West presses for end of Bosnian Croat mini-state.</title>
<headline>West presses for end of Bosnian Croat mini-state.</headline>
<byline>Kurt Schork</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top U.S. envoy flew into Sarajevo on Friday to help put an end to Bosnia's breakaway Croat mini-state, clearing the way for a Moslem-Croat federation Washington brokered in 1994.</p>
<p>U.S. Assistant Secretary of State John Kornblum returned to the Bosnian capital for talks with the heads of Moslem and Croat officials to ensure an end to breakaway Herceg Bosna before the end of the month.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect Herceg Bosna to go up in a puff of smoke by midnight on Saturday at the latest,&quot; a U.S. source who asked not to be named told Reuters on Friday.</p>
<p>Early on Friday the commander of NATO ground forces in Bosnia held crisis talks with Bosnian Serb leaders after the worst day of violence since the Dayton peace agreement was signed in December.</p>
<p>General Sir Michael Walker flew to Banja Luka to meet Bosnian Serb Acting President Biljana Plavsic after a tense confrontation on Thursday between NATO troops and Serb police in Zvornik and Mahala in northeastern Bosnia.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher won agreement from Bosnian factions in Geneva on August 14 that Herceg Bosna, which emerged from the ashes of 10 months of vicious fighting between Moslems and Croats in 1993, would cease to exist on August 31.</p>
<p>Croat nationalists in the rocky western part of Bosnia have made no secret of their desire to secede and form a union with neighbouring Croatia, which they view as their motherland.</p>
<p>The fighting ended In April 1994 when the United States brokered an agreement for a Moslem-Croat federation which nominally controls 51 per cent of Bosnia under the terms of the Dayton peace agreement. A Serb republic administers the rest.</p>
<p>However federation institutions have been slow to form for a number of reasons, including Herceg Bosna's refusal to cede power and cease to exist.</p>
<p>Armed and supported by Croatia and dominated by warlords who maintain a grip over the local population, Herceg Bosna has proved resilient.</p>
<p>U.S. sources blamed the Croats for holding up progress on the issue.</p>
<p>The European Union coordinator in Mostar, the chosen &quot;capital&quot; of Herzeg Bosna, on Friday named six Croats reputed to be paramilitary gang bosses and called on them to stop ethnic terror in the ethnically divided town.</p>
<p>Straining the issue further, Bosnian Serb leaders, who have never concealed their desire to join up with neighbouring Serbia, called the Moslem-Croat federation an artifice.</p>
<p>&quot;By the Washington agreement (the West) tailored such an artifical creation. Now it remains for them... to draw (the Bosnian Serb republic) into a process of reintegration. They will not succeed in that,&quot; Bosnian Serb premier Gojko Klickovic told reporters.</p>
<p>Klickovic was speaking after meeting U.N. special envoy Iqbal Riza in Pale to discuss Thursday's crisis in Zvornik, which highlighted the deep-seated ethnic hatred in Bosnia after 43 months of civil war.</p>
<p>The U.N. was demanding swift punishment for the organisers of a mob that besieged a group of U.N. officials in the northeastern town of Zvornik for six hours, a spokesman said.</p>
<p>&quot;The United Nations expects swift and decisive actions against those who organised and led the mob on its rampage,&quot; said Alex Ivanko of the International Police Task Force (IPTF).</p>
<p>The crisis began on Thursday afternoon, when a crowd of some 600 Serbs surrounded the IPTF headquarters in Zvornik.</p>
<p>The Serb crowd was apparently retaliating against NATO action in a nearby village of Mahala to detain a group of Bosnian Serb police who had been involved in a shooting incident with Moslems after beating them up.</p>
<p>The violence underscored steadily rising tensions across Bosnia in the run-up to general elections scheduled for September 14 for a three-member presidency and parliament for a loose union of Serb and Moslem-Croat entities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
