<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24018" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Discount rate unch, banks' reserves up -Yugo cbank.</title>
<headline>Discount rate unch, banks' reserves up -Yugo cbank.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Yugoslav central bank kept its discount rate for September unchanged at 4.5 percent, or 68.15 percent a year, by raising banks' reserve requirements, central bank vice-governor Ratko Banovic said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;We made no changes in the discount rate for September, but in order to keep it unchanged, we had to introduce a 10-percent reserve requirement for the banks,&quot; Banovic told Reuters.</p>
<p>According to Banovic, tampering with the reserve requirement was the only way to prevent the discount rate from rising. The discount rate was last cut to a monthly 4.5 percent in June.</p>
<p>The National Bank of Yugoslavia (NBY) sets its discount rate based on a basket of various parameters including inflation, interest rates on the open money market, expected monetary developments, credit demand, money supply and the rate on its short-term bonds sold on the Belgrade bourse.</p>
<p>The central bank was worried growing inflation would force it to adjust the discount rate. July monthly inflation jumped to 6.6 percent from 3.3 percent a month earlier.</p>
<p>But August took the pressure off when inflation slowed to 2.3 percent, according to figures released by the Statistics Office on Friday.</p>
<p>Banovic said the NBY will keep the discount rate as its key instrument for regulating market liquidity but the rate cannot be the only instrument used.</p>
<p>&quot;The discount rate is a very subtle instrument, and in an economy like ours, where companies and banks are in a difficult situation, the discount rate cannot be the only instrument of regulating market liquidity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;By changing the discount rate we try to send signals both to banks and companies. Sometimes they understand, but sometimes they don't,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the beginning of 1996, the discount rate and the interest rate on the NBY's short-term bonds sold via the Belgrade bourse were at much higher levels.</p>
<p>&quot;The end of every year is marked by surging liquidity among the banks, and we wanted to sop up surplus liquidity by attracting it to our short-term bonds (and) offering higher interest rates. And it worked,&quot; Banovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;Our bonds are good instrument, they are a reliable investment with guaranteed payment of interest. Those bonds allowed us to keep monetary stability,&quot; he added. -- Gordana Filipovic, Belgrade newsroom, +381 11 222 4254</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
