<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24024" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Two large Polish banks eye Russian market.</title>
<headline>Two large Polish banks eye Russian market.</headline>
<byline>Krzysztof Wojcik</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank Handlowy SA, Poland's biggest state-owned commercial bank, and the cooperative giant Bank Gospodarki Zywnosciowej SA want to boost their presence on the Russian market, their officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>Handlowy, which concentrates on foreign trade and large corporate accounts, already has a representative office in Moscow but wants to start full banking operations there in the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;Preparations are advanced and we will apply for a full operational banking licence in line with Russian banking law,&quot; Krzysztof Jakubiszyn, deputy head of Handlowy's banking cooperation department, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Handlowy's Moscow representative office now provides mostly information and promotion.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to follow our (Polish) clients' Russian businesses in the broad spectrum of activities, from agriculture to petrochemicals, without focusing on any particular sector,&quot; Jakubiszyn said.</p>
<p>Bank Gospodarki Zywnosciowej SA, focused on food-related businesses, aims to create a Polish-Russian bank. But first it wants to set up a Moscow office with two branches, in Smolensk and Kaliningrad, BGZ's deputy president said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are applying for opening our representative office in Moscow and we may expect the Russian central bank's agreement soon,&quot; BGZ's Ryszard Tupin told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said plans of the bank's eastward expansion followed an April meeting of Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz and Russian Deputy Prime Minister Oleg Davydov in Warsaw, aimed at facilitating banking cooperation between the two countries.</p>
<p>Russia is Poland's third largest trading partner with 1995 turnover at $3.2 billion, up 35 percent against 1994, and with the trade balance $686 million in Russia's favour.</p>
<p>BGZ wants its Kaliningrad office to help sell Polish agricultural products through the Russian enclave's Yantar Free Trade Economic Zone.</p>
<p>The Smolensk office is to service credit lines assigned by the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development for the Smolensk area, as well as trade under a bilateral agreement between the Russian region and Czestochowa in south Poland.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
