<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24129" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Aug 30.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Hungary - Aug 30.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Here are highlights of stories reported by Hungary's press, based on information by Nepszabadsag's Hungary Around the Clock service. For further details on how to subscribe to Hungary Around the Clock, please contact Monica Kovacs at (361) 351 2440 or fax your request to (361) 351 7141.</p>
<p>ALL PAPERS</p>
<p>- The cabinet accepted a bill on the final account of the two social insurance funds for 1995. It also decided that the Hungarian Investment and Development Bank will continue operation as a 100 per cent state-owned institution. @</p>
<p>- The Free Democrats acknowledged the nomination by senior coalition partner the Socialist Party of Tamas Suchman for the post of minister of industry at the coalition consultative meeting on Thursday and discussed the constitutional drafting process.</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Gyula Horn received US Republican Senator Richard G. Lugar in his office on Thursday. @</p>
<p>- A Finance Ministry committee initiated by the finance minister is to be set up to look into errors during bank and loan consolidation between 1992 and 1994 in response to a report by the State Audit Office revealing errors costing the state billions of forints.</p>
<p>- Government commissioner Imre Karl said the government intends to introduce price increase in the energy sector proportionate to cost which will be acceptable to both investors and the public alike.</p>
<p>- Police Colonel Erno Kiss was named head of the new Central Crime Fighting Directorate. @</p>
<p>- The German holding company Allianz AG has bought the remaining shares in the insurance firm Hungaria Biztosito.</p>
<p>- The municipal general assembly of Budapest amended a decree Thursday reintroducing the use of locks on the wheels of cars exceeding the parking time limit as from October 1.</p>
<p>MAGYAR HIRLAP</p>
<p>- US permanent NATO representative Robert Hunter said Thursday that the US administration has a high appreciation of the Hungarian-Romanian basic treaty, while NATO had marveled at the finalisation of the document. The British Foreign Office warmly welcomed the progress made by Hungary and Romania. @</p>
<p>- Trading in the regional electricity companies' shares on OTC markets has come to a standstill since the government announced the delay in energy price increase.</p>
<p>- The French Mirage 2000-5 fighter made its debut in a demonstration fight at Kecskemet air base.</p>
<p>VILAGGAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Half of the French company L'electricite de France's Edasz package is expected to be sold to the German firm Bayernwerk, and the entire Demasz stake is intended for sale to the Austrian company EVN. @</p>
<p>- The plastics company Pannonplast has realised the first of its acquisitions this year by buying the plastics processing firm Kaposplast.</p>
<p>NAPI GAZDASAG</p>
<p>- Hungary remains the preferred East European country for Austrian investments, according to an Austrian daily.</p>
<p>- The net revenue of the central budget from customs duties grew HUF 322 billion in the first half of this year.</p>
<p>NEPSZABADSAG @</p>
<p>- Police and customs officials suspect a medical company performing eye surgery, Optic Chance Kft, of money laundering and evading payment of over HUF 150 million corporate taxes.</p>
<p>		     -- Budapest newsroom (36-1) 266 2410</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
