<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="241972" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: TENNIS-BECKER CASHES IN ON EVENT HE ONCE CALLED &quot;PERVERSE&quot;.</title>
<headline>TENNIS-BECKER CASHES IN ON EVENT HE ONCE CALLED &quot;PERVERSE&quot;.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Warner</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Boris Becker finished the most lucrative week of his life with a $1.875 million payoff on Sunday after winning a tournament he once described as &quot;perverse&quot; because it offered too much money.</p>
<p>Becker cashed in on his superb run of form at the end of the year with a 6-3 6-4 6-4 defeat of defending champion Goran Ivanisevic in the final of the Grand Slam Cup, the richest event in the game.</p>
<p>It was the first time the Australian Open champion had won the tournament which he boycotted in its inaugural year in 1990, saying it was &quot;perverse&quot; to play for so much money.</p>
<p>But the 29-year-old German has changed his mind about the event. He relished the chance to win in front of 11,000 fervent fans in his home town of Munich and took just 83 minutes to defeat the big-serving Ivanisevic.</p>
<p>It boosted his 1996 prize money to more than $4.3 million.</p>
<p>&quot;I knew I had to return well against Goran who has the best serve of all time,&quot; Becker said. &quot;It has been a home game this week and I have enjoyed it.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Bearing in mind I was playing against the best server in the game, that was as good as I could play today. There were no lapses in my game. That is why it seemed so easy.&quot;</p>
<p>Becker has produced some of the best tennis of his life in the last few months since he returned to the circuit following a serious wrist injury sustained at Wimbledon.</p>
<p>Last month he just lost a dramatic five-set final against world number one Pete Sampras at the ATP world championship, also on German soil in Hanover.</p>
<p>Ivanisevic, who produced a superb comeback from two sets down to beat Russia's French Open champion Yevgeny Kafelnikov over five sets in Saturday's semifinals, was unable to make an impact.</p>
<p>&quot;He was just too good. I didn't know what to do,&quot; said the Croat, who almost pulled out of the event at the start of the week because of illness.</p>
<p>&quot;He is playing his best tennis ever. He played too well. I didn't have any chance.&quot;</p>
<p>Some of the top players have been unable to deal with Ivanisevic's power this week, during which he has taken his aces for the year past 1,500, a record.</p>
<p>But three-times Wimbledon champion Becker was soon on top of the titleholder's serve, making a key break to lead 5-3 in the first set after Ivanisevic netted a forehand. In the next game the German served out for the set after 23 minutes.</p>
<p>Becker, who beat Britain's Tim Henman with relative ease in the semifinals, took the initiative right at the start of the second set, breaking Ivanisevic in the first game with another crisp passing shot. Some 28 minutes later he was two sets ahead.</p>
<p>The German effectively clinched the match when he broke again in the fifth game of the third set with a smash to lead 3-2.</p>
<p>The top performers at the four grand slams -- Wimbledon, and the U.S. French and Australian Opens -- qualified for a shot at the big money in Munich.</p>
<p>Becker was guaranteed $250,000 for just turning up at the tournament since he had won one grand slam. He added another $1.625 million for winning the tournament.</p>
<p>Some players have been criticised here for taking the money and running without putting up much of a performance. Andre Agassi was booed off court after he lost in the first round but picked up a cheque of $100,000.</p>
<p>Becker, by contrast, has been worth his money. Even in the later stages of his career, the German has proved that he is still one of the most formidable opponents on a fast court.</p>
<p>Despite his defeat Ivanisevic ended the week with $812,500 in his pocket. In five years at the tournament, the Croat has won an astonishing $3.6 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
