<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24194" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Strike-hit Salvador mine has stocks for three days.</title>
<headline>Strike-hit Salvador mine has stocks for three days.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Codelco's strike-bound Salvador mine has enough copper concentrates to keep up production at the Potrerillos smelter and refinery for three days, a Codelco official said.</p>
<p>If the strike continues and those stocks run out, the refinery will bring in copper concentrates from Codelco's Chuquicamata mine, said the official.</p>
<p>&quot;There are stocks for three days at the refinery and smelter,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Salvador open pit mine and the concentrator have been paralyzed by the strike, which started at midnight local time (0400 GMT), said the official.</p>
<p>But Potrerillos and the division's Pacific port of Barquito are both working at near-normal levels, Codelco officials said.</p>
<p>All three locales together form state-owned Codelco's Salvador division, which employs some 2,400 people.</p>
<p>Codelco officials will closely evaluate absenteeism levels later Friday, said the official by telephone from the mine in northern Chile's arid Third Region.  </p>
<p>Under local labor codes, if more than 50 percent of workers have shown up for work after the three Friday shifts, then Codelco's latest wage offer is automatically accepted and the strike ends, said the official.</p>
<p>But with near-total absenteeism at the mine itself, where about 1,400 of the division's 2,400 unionized employees work, that outcome looked unlikely.</p>
<p>The third shift starts at 3 p.m. local time (1900 GMT), meaning full absenteeism figures won't be known until after that time, the official said.</p>
<p>--Roger Atwood, Santiago newsroom +56-2-699-5595 x211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
