<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242151" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Multinational force commander goes to Zaire.</title>
<headline>Multinational force commander goes to Zaire.</headline>
<byline>Christian Jennings</byline>
<dateline>BENI, Zaire 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Canadian commander of a multinational force in central Africa visited eastern Zaire on Sunday to gain more information on how to help Rwandan refugees in the rebel-held territory.</p>
<p>As the mission looked increasingly tenuous because of French doubts, a spokesman at the force headquarters in the Ugandan capital Kampala said Lieutenant-General Maurice Baril had crossed the border from Rwanda.</p>
<p>The general said last week he wanted more information about the location, number and condition of the refugees in Zaire so he could decide how to help them.</p>
<p>He said reconnaissance flights had tracked 165,000 refugees still left in Zaire after the return of other Rwandan Hutu refugees to Rwanda but some U.N. aid sources maintained there must be at least 430,000.</p>
<p>The multinational force said Baril was meeting rebel leader Laurent Kabila, who opposes deployment of the force for fear it might restore the authority of Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko.</p>
<p>Kabila's military commander, Andre Kissasse Ngandu, said in an interview published on Sunday the United Nations was inflating the number of refugees still in rebel-held areas as an excuse to bring in foreign forces.</p>
<p>&quot;They are following the command of the colonial forces who divide us and began all these problems...They are looking for excuses to help this former colonial force to harm and divide our people,&quot; Ngandu said.</p>
<p>He told the Kenyan newspaper the Sunday Standard that France was meddling.</p>
<p>France had been the main advocate of international military intervention to help refugees, but a cabinet minister said in an interview published in Paris on Saturday the mission is no longer tenable.</p>
<p>&quot;France continues meddling in Zairean and African affairs. They love causing pain and suffering to African countries...We are ready for them. And if they come as soldiers, then we are ready to fight them as soldiers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ngandu said government troops were deserting to join the rebel campaign and march on Kinshasa but reports from the northeastern town of Bunia suggested resistance might stiffen.</p>
<p>Since the rebellion broke out near the Rwandan border in October among Zaireans of Rwandan ancestory, the rebels, backed by the Rwandan army, have routed the Zairean army across a 450 km (280 miles) front.</p>
<p>Rebels based in the northeastern town of Beni said on Sunday their forces were attacking Bunia, 150 km (90 miles) to the northeast. &quot;Bunia hasn't fallen yet. We're still in the process of taking it,&quot; said a rebel officer.</p>
<p>But people in the northeastern capital Kisangani quoted residents of Bunia, contacted by radio, as saying the army had secured the town well.</p>
<p>Ngandu said more than 300 Zairean army soldiers, including a colonel and three captains, had defected to the rebels of the Alliance of Democratic Forces for the Liberation of Congo-Zaire.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone, mothers, children and men are joining us every night and day to fight our common enemy. Yet they (the government) dream that we cannot take Kinshasa. We have the arms and the people have the will to fight. We will reach Kinshasa very soon,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UGANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BENI, Zaire"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
