<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242290" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Europe sees information technology deal at WTO.</title>
<headline>Europe sees information technology deal at WTO.</headline>
<byline>Chris Johnson</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>European and U.S. negotiators were meeting on Sunday to try to thrash out an Information Technology Agreement (ITA) to remove barriers on computer and telecommunications products by 2000, a European source said.</p>
<p>&quot;I would hope you will find a coming together of the European and U.S. fairly soon so we can push the others,&quot; said the source, who declined to be named.</p>
<p>Top trade officials from 128 nations were due to meet in Singapore on Monday for the first ministerial conference of the World Trade Organisation (WTO).</p>
<p>Europe and the United States both hope to agree an ITA before the meeting ends on December 13, but still have several important disagreements over which products should be included and excluded from the deal.</p>
<p>U.S. negotiators want a &quot;broad&quot; agreement covering a wide range of products, estimated to be worth up to $1 trillion a year in world trade.</p>
<p>But they want to exclude fibre optics, graphic display tubes, photocopiers and capacitors -- circuits used in electronic goods.</p>
<p>The European Union (EU) is unhappy with these exclusions, but feel a deal can be done.</p>
<p>&quot;We're pretty close on all the issues,&quot; the source told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;A deal is within reach. We have to push very, very hard.&quot;</p>
<p>The source said both sets of negotiators realised the importance of coming to an acceptable agreement this week, even if the final signing was delayed until later.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever deal is done -- a deal now or a bankable deal for later -- the work will have to be done now at the WTO,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>EU and U.S. teams have both laid out a busy schedule of bilateral meetings for the next three days, mainly with Asian and South American countries, to solve disagreements over ITA.</p>
<p>Both teams have said any ITA needs a &quot;critical mass&quot; of information technology producing and consuming countries to sign on to the accord, before it can be agreed.</p>
<p>The EU has said it has a &quot;priority list&quot; of 16 core non-European states it wants to join the deal but stresses the list is may be expanded to other states.</p>
<p>The current list covers Australia, Canada, Chile, China, Hong Kong, Indonesia, Japan, Korea, Malaysia, Mexico, New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, Taiwan, Thailand and the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;We both hope this is going to be a really concrete thing, a nugget...if not finally agreed, then laid out to be agreed later,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A U.S. spokeswoman confirmed that the EU-U.S. working level negotiators were meeting to set up a framework for negotations this week. She gave no further details.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
