<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242318" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Cautious rebound expected for Hong Kong stocks.</title>
<headline>Cautious rebound expected for Hong Kong stocks.</headline>
<byline>Jennifer Genevieve</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A sharp selloff in Hong Kong stocks last week created an oppportunity for investors to snap up shares at lower levels, but some caution is likely this week before prices resume their record-breaking path, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index lost 388.83 points, or 2.88 percent, to 13,102.73 on Friday, as U.S. Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan's comments sparked renewed interest rates jitters.</p>
<p>But the U.S. November employment report later soothed frayed nerves with a rise of 118,000 in non-farm payrolls, well below economists' forecasts of a 179,000 rise.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't expect the Fed to raise rates at all at its December 17 meeting and probably we are not going to see any rate hike within these two months so the market should probably stabilise and might go back to 13,500 by the end of the year,&quot; said Alex Tang, head of research at Yamaichi International.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng index has been rising steadily since the beginning of September, reaching a record high of 13,744.30 on November 28.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect market sentiment to calm down a bit next week and the very sharp fall on Friday, which has shaken investor confidence, will cool down some of the buying fever,&quot; said Ben Kwong, director of research at Dharmala Securities.</p>
<p>He said economic data were not strong enough to justify fears of rising interest rates in the near term and investors had overreacted to Greenspan's comments on Friday.</p>
<p>Greenspan said the Fed must be wary when &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; infects stock and other asset markets. He also said that while U.S. inflation had been low recently, its future course was uncertain and the Fed had to be forward looking.</p>
<p>His comments hit stock markets worldwide.</p>
<p>&quot;This probably will provide us with an opportunity for entry again back to the Hong Kong market,&quot; said Tang at Yamaichi.</p>
<p>&quot;The focus is likely to be on blue chip companies again which will lead the rebound,&quot; he said, adding that caution created by Friday's selloff would encourage investors to seek the more liquid stocks in the market.</p>
<p>Tang saw a trading range of 13,000 to 13,500 for the Hang Seng index in the week ahead. &quot;The problem with the Hong Kong market is probably turnover might dwindle ahead of the Christmas holidays.&quot;</p>
<p>Kwong said the index was likely to trade in a range of 12,800 to 13,300 this week. &quot;For medium term investors, I think it is a good opportunity to buy,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>China property group Nam Fong International Holdings Ltd is due to make its stock market debut on Monday. The company offered 340 million new shares at HK$2.88 each, with 272 million offered to private and institutional investors and 68 million to the public. The public offering was 165.6 times subscribed and analysts expect the stock to make strong gains.</p>
<p>Shares in Solartech International Holdings Ltd, a cable maker and exporter, are due to start trading on Thursday. The 125 million share offering at HK$1.20 per share was expected to be about 128 times subscribed, market sources said.</p>
<p>Blue chip Johnson Electric Holdings Ltd is due to release its interim results on Monday.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong newsroom (852) 2843 6345</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
