<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242305" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Eighth body found from Japan mudslide, six missing.</title>
<headline>Eighth body found from Japan mudslide, six missing.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>Authorities found an eighth body on Sunday and searched for six others still missing after a mudslide swept through a mountain road construction site in central Japan, police said.</p>
<p>Searchers used sniffer dogs in chilly weather amid fears of a second mudslide to scour the steep stream bed for the remaining six workers missing and feared dead near Otari village in Nagano prefecture, 230 km (140 miles) northwest of Tokyo.</p>
<p>Seven bodies were recovered on Saturday.</p>
<p>The mudslide tore through a steep river valley on Friday morning after rains melted heavy snow that had accumulated upstream last week.</p>
<p>Of 20 workers caught in the landslide, six were rescued.</p>
<p>The torrent of mud and rocks washed away a bridge and blocked access to a hamlet of about 30 people, police said. Eight people were injured, one critically.</p>
<p>Dumptrucks, a crane and cars were mixed with the boulders and thick mud that surged down a fast-moving stream and dragged the workers in their path. One of the bodies was found four km (2.4 miles) downstream from the construction site.</p>
<p>The missing and dead workers, which include three women, were among a crew of about 50 who were restoring an embankment that had been damaged in a 1995 landslide, police said.</p>
<p>Many of the workers were migrant labourers who had sought work from outlying regions of Japan, construction company officials said.</p>
<p>The accident occurred in a ski resort and hot spring spa area, a region of steep, rugged mountains prone to landslides.</p>
<p>Otari is 10 km (six miles) from one of the main ski slopes to be used in the 1998 Winter Olympics at Nagano.</p>
<p>The highway restoration project was not connected with preparations for the Winter Games, police said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
