<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242312" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>MACAU: Macau tries to confront wave of violent crime.</title>
<headline>Macau tries to confront wave of violent crime.</headline>
<byline>Harald Bruning</byline>
<dateline>MACAU 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A government crackdown on illicit casinos and a slowdown in the economy have sparked a wave of gangster warfare and violent crime in Portuguese-administered Macau, police and casino sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is that a growing number of triad gangsters are fighting over shrinking profits from illegal casino-related businesses,&quot; a police source told Reuters.</p>
<p>Responding to the violence, which included a botched assassination attempt on a top gambling inspection official in late November, police have set up 24-hour undercover patrols in the enclave's nine casinos and other betting centres.</p>
<p>But some within the administration say a government crackdown on organised crime, particularly casino loansharking operations, may have helped set off a series of bombings, gang fights, murders, robberies and muggings since late 1995.</p>
<p>After the assassination attempt, Governor General Vasco Rocha Vieira said his administration's determination to take a tough line might have caused &quot;uneasiness&quot; among the half dozen triads, or organised crime syndicates, believed to be operating in Macau, which reverts to Chinese rule in December 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;More and more suspected triad gangsters have been barred from entering the casinos, including very big triad bosses, and they are very angry about that,&quot; one source said.</p>
<p>The crime wave prompted China's de facto mission in Macau, the local branch of the Xinhua news agency, to urge the government to get even tougher.</p>
<p>Police sources said the influx of rival gangs from Hong Kong and Taiwan has led to fights over shrinking business in illegal activities.</p>
<p>&quot;The cake is getting smaller but the number of people trying to get a piece of it is getting bigger,&quot; one source told Reuters, adding that gangs were fighting &quot;territorial wars&quot; over lucrative gambling tours and loansharking operations.</p>
<p>The sluggish state of Macau's economy has aslo been blamed for the gang-related violence.</p>
<p>&quot;Macau's economic recession has reached the triads, and that's why they have become more violent,&quot; one industry source said.</p>
<p>Casino sources said this year's gross takings at Macau's nine registered gaming houses will fail to match the double-digit growth of past years because Hong Kong gamblers have become &quot;scarcer and more thrifty&quot;.</p>
<p>Some 5.5 million people visited Macau in the first eight months of 1996, up 4.7 percent compared with the same period last year. But the number of vistors from Hong Kong -- which make up two thirds of all arrivals -- fell 6.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Because of '97, Hong Kong people save more and spend less on gambling in Macau,&quot; a croupier at the Pelota Basca Casino said.</p>
<p>Casino sources said Hong Kong's impending handover to Chinese rule in July 1997 has prompted triads to increase their activities in Macau, which they now see as being thwarted or at least under threat by the government crackdown.</p>
<p>Police sources said that while it is possible to keep casino-related crimes in check, the nature of the business will always attract a criminal element.</p>
<p>&quot;Light draws flies and casinos draw criminals,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>Despite the concerns, gambling mogul Stanley Ho said on Sunday he would open his 10th casino in Macau before the Chinese Lunar New Year in early February through his company Sociedade de Turismo e Diversoes de Macau (STDM).</p>
<p>STDM operates Macau's nine casinos and its subsidiaries run the enclave's lotteries as well as its greyhound and horse tracks. Economists estimate the company accounts for about 25 percent of Macau's gross domestic product.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MACAO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MACAU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MACAU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
