<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242479" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Protester dies after India politician arrested.</title>
<headline>Protester dies after India politician arrested.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>A man who set himself on fire to protest against the arrest of India's best known woman politician died in hospital on Sunday, United News of India (UNI) said.</p>
<p>Sultan Pasha, who set himself alight on Saturday, died in a government hospital in the southern city of Madras, where Jayaram Jayalalitha spent her first night in jail after being arrested in a corruption case.</p>
<p>News agencies said several dozen supporters of Jayalalitha, who was chief minister of Tamil Nadu state until her All India Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam (AIADMK) party was routed in local polls last May, were detained on Sunday.</p>
<p>Thirty-eight AIADMK activists were detained when they blocked traffic in Madurai city to protest against Jayalalitha's arrest, the Press Trust of India (PTI) said.</p>
<p>Another 14 were detained in Madras when they tried to burn an effigy of the current chief minister, M. Karunanidhi, PTI said. It quoted police as saying three state-owned buses were damaged in Madras when protesters pelted them with stones.</p>
<p>Jayalalitha, a former movie idol, was charged on Saturday with ordering some 85 million rupees' ($2.4 million) worth of excess spending on 45,302 television sets for villagers while she was Tamil Nadu's chief minister. She denied any wrongdoing.</p>
<p>Since her party was trounced in the state elections, Jayalalitha, 48, has been charged in seven corruption cases ranging from foreign exchange to income tax violations.</p>
<p>Four teams of officials continued on Sunday to search her Madras residence, UNI said. A jeweller was brought in to weigh seized jewellery, it said.</p>
<p>Jayalalitha told authorities she did not need any special facilities in Madras central jail, where she spent her first night sleeping on a bedsheet on the floor, news agencies said.</p>
<p>UNI said she was given rice gruel in an aluminium bowl for breakfast.</p>
<p>The state government, wary of critics who said Jayalalitha had been victimised, said Jayalalitha had been given a fan, a cot, a table, a chair, magazines, newspapers, mineral water to drink and hot water for her bath.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
