<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242403" id="root" date="1996-12-08" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Rubin plays down importance of stock price drop.</title>
<headline>Rubin plays down importance of stock price drop.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-08</dateline>
<text>
<p>By Rich Miller, Economics Correspondent</p>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin on Sunday played down the importance of last week's steep slide in global stock markets and urged investors to focus on the long-term.</p>
<p>&quot;What people really ought to be looking at is not these kind of day to day fluctuations but what they think economic conditions are going to be like over time,&quot; the Treasury chief said on NBC television's &quot;Meet the Press&quot; programme.</p>
<p>Equity prices dropped from Tokyo to New York on Friday after Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan raised the possibility that the high-flying Wall Street market might be overvalued.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average of blue chip shares fell by over 140 points before stabilising to end the day 55.16 points down.</p>
<p>Rubin said the central bank chief was merely asking a question about the level of the stock market, not saying that it had risen too far.</p>
<p>&quot;I interpret the chairman as simply raising a question, not suggesting an answer,&quot; the Treasury chief said. &quot;It is a very important distinction.&quot;</p>
<p>Rubin, who meets weekly with Greenspan to discuss the economy and other issues, said he had not been surprised by the Fed chairman's remarks but made clear that the central banker spoke on his own.</p>
<p>Senate Majority leader Trent Lott was not as reticent as Rubin in taking on the Fed, calling last week's stock market slide a testament to Greenspan's strength.</p>
<p>&quot;I've always been a little nervous about the Fed,&quot; the Mississippi Republican told the Fox News Sunday television programme. &quot;I don't want to bash them ... but I think interest rates should be lower.&quot;</p>
<p>Rubin, a former Wall Street executive, declined to say whether he thought the stock market had risen too far, despite repeated questioning.</p>
<p>But he did say that markets follow fundamentals over time and that the U.S. fundamentals had been &quot;very good&quot; during President Bill Clinton's first four years in office.</p>
<p>What was important now was whether the Clinton administration and Congress could work together to tackle the economic problems facing the United States, including balancing the federal government budget.</p>
<p>To help in that regard, Rubin left open the possibility of adjusting the Consumer Price Index (CPI), which is used to calculate annual cost-of-living increases for Social Security and other government benefit programmes.</p>
<p>A congressionally-appointed commission last week concluded that the CPI overstates inflation by 1.1 percentage points per year, effectively costing the government billions of dollars a year in extra pension and other payments.</p>
<p>Rubin agreed that the CPI was an imperfect measure of inflation. &quot;The question is, based on scientific and technical analysis, can we arrive at a better version of the CPI?</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think that we should rule out a change in the CPI if, based on a technical analysis, there is a broad-based agreement that the CPI can be changed in a such a way as to better, more accurately reflect inflation,&quot; Rubin added.</p>
<p>Speaking on the same television programme, U.S. House Budget Committee chairman John Kasich from Ohio said Republicans were in favour of changing the way the CPI is measured, but that Clinton needed to take the lead on any adjustments.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-08"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-08"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
