<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242837" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: OLYMPICS-OLYMPIC COMMISSION WRAPS UP 2004 VENUE ASSESSMENT.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-OLYMPIC COMMISSION WRAPS UP 2004 VENUE ASSESSMENT.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The International Olympic Committee's evaluation commission ended its three-month tour of 11 city's bidding to host the 2004 Olympic Games on Monday with praise for three aspects of Cape Town's application.</p>
<p>Commission chairman Thomas Bach declined at a news conference to make any comment on Cape Town's chance of becoming the first African venue for the event.</p>
<p>But he said the 15-member commission had agreed, as it had in all the other candidate cities, to give three &quot;impressions&quot; of the visit:</p>
<p>&quot;The commission appreciates the support lent to the candidature by the different levels of government.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission takes note of the detailed analysis and planning undertaken by the candidature in connection with the transportation requirements of the Olympic Games and their integration into the future transportation system of the city.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission highly appreciates the candidature's youth education programme -- 'A Journey to Light the Sky' -- which is very creative. The candidature's student ambassadors are truly enthusiastic and a tribute to the Olympic values,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>South African President Nelson Mandela urged the IOC on Saturday to validate the five-ringed Olympic symbol by awarding the event to the African continent for the first time.</p>
<p>Bach, a German fencing gold medallist, said the IOC selection college would meet on March 6 and 7 to narrow the field to four or five and would decide in September which city should host the Games in 2004.</p>
<p>Rome, Stockholm, Athens and Rio de Janeiro are rivals believed to have a chance of beating Cape Town, where a coalition of community groups opposes the bid.</p>
<p>The IOC commission met on Monday with opponents who argue it is too soon after South Africa's transition from white rule to tackle a project as expensive and as risky as the Olympic Games.</p>
<p>He made no comment on their arguments, but said he would be suspicious of any country that claimed 100 percent support for an application to host the Games.</p>
<p>Independent polls have shown up to 80 percent support for the bid with blacks generally more enthusiastic than whites.</p>
<p>Bach said allegations that Cape Town and South Africa were still too violent and crime-ridden to take on the project would not influence the commission's report.</p>
<p>&quot;Security has always beeen a matter of concern for the IOC because we want to have athletes and spectators and all the other members of the Olympic family in a safe environment.</p>
<p>&quot;But the situation in eight years time can be very different from the situation today...Our main focus is how the candidature committee wants to tackle that problem,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bach likened the race for the Games to a marathon, adding: &quot;If you think you are close to the finish, I should warn you that is a wrong impression. You haven't even left the stadium.&quot;</p>
<p>Chris Ball, chief executive of the non-profit bid company managing Cape Town's campaign, said the IOC team's visit had not raised any unexpected or unanswerable questions.</p>
<p>&quot;One learns plenty from them, but they are not here as advisers. They are here to make a technical evaluation. It's going to be a tough competition, but I think there is a fair chance of us being in that final group,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
