<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="242867" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: SOCCER-BECKENBAUER SET FOR SHOWDOWN WITH KLINSMANN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-BECKENBAUER SET FOR SHOWDOWN WITH KLINSMANN.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bayern Munich president Franz Beckenbauer plans to clear the air with Juergen Klinsmann early in the new year following the striker's outspoken criticism of the team's playing style and his threat to leave at the end of the season.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll speak to Juergen,&quot; Beckenbauer said on Monday. &quot;A discussion is unavoidable.&quot;</p>
<p>The former Tottenham star lashed out on national television just hours after he scored Bayern's goal in their 1-0 win over Borussia Moenchengladbach on Saturday, sending his side into the annual winter break at the top of the Bundesliga.</p>
<p>&quot;If it goes on like this, I'm leaving,&quot; Germany's Euro 96 captain said, blasting Bayern for playing too defensively.</p>
<p>Beckenbauer said he believed Klinsmann's criticism stemmed partly from his own failure to make an impression on the first half of the German season. He has scored just five times.</p>
<p>&quot;The frustration of the last few weeks and months all came out,&quot; the former World Cup winning coach and captain wrote in his newspaper column for the Bild daily. &quot;When he starts scoring, he'll be happy again.&quot;</p>
<p>Beckenbauer said club officials would sit down with Klinsmann early next year.</p>
<p>&quot;Now it's Christmas time, a time to think things over,&quot; Beckenbauer said. &quot;So we'll only have the discussion at the beginning of next year. After that, all disagreements must be cleared up because there can be only one target -- the title.&quot;</p>
<p>Klinsmann said he respected Bayern coach Giovanni Trapattoni, who was also his boss at Internazionale Milan, but his defensive system made it difficult for strikers to operate.</p>
<p>But Beckenbauer backed the Italian. &quot;A lot of injuries forced him to go for safety. Our success has proved he was right,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the second half of the season, when everyone's fit, we'll play attractive football.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
