<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243064" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius leasing firm issues $5 million of bonds.</title>
<headline>Mauritius leasing firm issues $5 million of bonds.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mauritian leasing company, Finlease opened on Monday a public issue of 100 million rupees ($5 million) of guaranteed bonds (debentures) that will be used to finance the growth of the company's leasing activities, company officials said.</p>
<p>The present issue is for a toum, payable quarterly on March 9, June 9, September 9 and December 9 every year.</p>
<p>The bonds will mature after six years on December 9, 2002, but the company may at its discretion, redeem the bonds in part or in full after December 9, 1999, the company said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the event of oversubscriptions, the company may retain additional applications for up to 25 percent of the present issue, in which case 125 million rupees will be raised,&quot; Hein said.</p>
<p>He added that the bonds would be quoted on the Stock Exchange of Mauritius after the public issue which closes on December 23, 1996.</p>
<p>Finlease is a wholly owned subsidiary of Fincorp Investment, which is guaranteeing to the bonds.</p>
<p>Finlease began operating in August 1995 and made profits before tax of 2.39 million rupees for fiscal year ending June 30 on turnover of 21.92 million rupees.</p>
<p>&quot;To date, leasing facilities totalling 383 million rupees have been approved out of which 211 million rupees have been funded,&quot; Hein said.</p>
<p>&quot;In addition, under the (central) Bank of Mauritius refinancing line for EPZ (Export Processing Zone) companies, facilities of 132 million rupees have been approved out of which 64 million rupees have been funded,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In December 1995, Finlease raised 250 million rupees during a first public issue of bonds, which are now listed on the Stock Exchange of Mauritius.</p>
<p>($1=20.0035 Mauritian rupees).</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
