<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243068" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Tea production remains high in Kenya.</title>
<headline>Tea production remains high in Kenya.</headline>
<dateline>MOMBASA, Kenya 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Erratic weather in the Rift Valley has undermined Kenya's tea production, but output is still running up on than last year, brokerage company African Tea Brokers (ATB) reported on Monday.</p>
<p>The firm put the crop figure for October at 23,310,040 kg, an increase of 557,043 over the same month in 1995.</p>
<p>The report added that the cumulative January-October crop total stood at 213.16 million kg, an increase of 12.09 million over the previous year.</p>
<p>But the weather - ranging from hot and dry to cold and very wet, sometimes with severe hail - had affected leaf development.</p>
<p>&quot;Kenya's main growing regions have received seasonally high rainfall with very cold temperatures while severe widespread hail has been reported in Kericho and parts of Sotik (in the western Rift Valley),&quot; ATB said.</p>
<p>&quot;Growth has been inhibited while future crop loss had been caused by hail,&quot; the brokerage company added.</p>
<p>Four sales were held during the month of October when a total of 222,336 packages were sold at an average price of $1.50. Comparative figures for the same month last year were 263,907 packages sold at an average price of $1.23.</p>
<p>Pakistan, Egypt and Sudan were dominant buyers. Yemen, Middle Eastern countries, the UK, North America, South Africa and latterly from the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) were also in the market. Somalia bought lower grades.</p>
<p>--Nairobi Newsroom +254-2 330-261</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KENYA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOMBASA, Kenya"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
