<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243074" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African platinum mine calm after ethnic feuding.</title>
<headline>S.African platinum mine calm after ethnic feuding.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>South Africa's largest miners' union vowed on Monday to track down the culprits responsible for ethnic clashes in which at least 37 blacks were killed at or near a platinum mine north-west of Johannesburg at the weekend.</p>
<p>The National Union of Mineworkers said in a statement it would do all it could to ensure that those behind the violence were brought to book.</p>
<p>&quot;We will leave no stone unturned in finding out who are the perpetrators of the violence,&quot; said NUM deputy secretary Gwede Mantashe.</p>
<p>If any NUM member was found to have been involved, they would face disciplinary action and possibly lose their union membership, Mantashe added.</p>
<p>Police said fighting between members of different tribes broke out on Saturday morning at a squatter camp called Freedom Park near the Wildebeesfontein mine in Rustenburg.</p>
<p>The clashes, between members of the Sotho and Xhosa tribes, spread to a hostel for migrant workers at the mine, owned by Impala Platinum Holdings.</p>
<p>Army troops and policemen moved in on Sunday to patrol the area and to prevent further clashes. Police spokeswoman Captain Belinda Kleynhans said the violence appeared to have subsided.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation is very quiet now. From yesterday (Sunday) afternoon and evening there have been no further incidents,&quot; Kleynhans told Reuters.</p>
<p>She said around 200 policemen and 50 soldiers were on the ground and if no further conflicts arose some could be pulled out by Monday afternoon.</p>
<p>South Africa's mining industry is built on a labour system under which men leave their wives and families for months at a time to work on the mines. Mine hostels are largely segregated on ethnic lines.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
