<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243054" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZIMBABWE: Zimbabwe stocks end weaker amid profit-taking.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe stocks end weaker amid profit-taking.</headline>
<dateline>HARARE 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwean stocks were largely weaker in active trade on Monday, hit by continuing profit-taking, brokers said.</p>
<p>The key 57-share industrial index dropped 40.86 points to close at 8,016.40, dragged down largely by hotel and supermarket chain Meikles Africa's 100-cent fall to 2,100 and publishing group Zimpapers' 50-cent loss to 2,000.</p>
<p>&quot;Some profit-takers are still around and the market was a bit weak but I still think the market will stabilise soon. We should be seeing the last week of weakness,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Haddon and Sly traded 25 cents down at 475, hotel chain Zimsun was 20 cents off at 380, pork processor Colcom shed 15 cents to 325 while battery manufacturer Chloride and building firm Mash lost 10 cents each to 100 and 210 respectively.</p>
<p>Against the trend, blue-chip conglomerate Delta rose 15 cents to 3,365 in a turnover of 4.03 million shares to an external buyer while engineering group Gulliver and steel window manufacturer Radar gained 20 cents each to 250 and 270 respectively.</p>
<p>Minings saw predominantly light volume trades with gold producer Ashanti sliding 500 cents to 12,000, nickel company Bindura fell 100 cents to 900 while Falgold eased five cents to 105.</p>
<p>The seven-stock mining index dropped 54.76 points to 1,115.13.</p>
<p>----Emelia Sithole, Harare Newsroom: +263-4 72 52 27/8/9----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HARARE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZIMBABWE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
