<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243057" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>KENYA: Twelve killed as Rwandans meet old neighbours.</title>
<headline>Twelve killed as Rwandans meet old neighbours.</headline>
<dateline>NAIROBI 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Twelve people have been killed in Rwanda as more than 500,000 refugees returning from Zaire make first contact with their old neighbours, whom some of them tried to massacre in 1994, the United Nations said on Monday.</p>
<p>The U.N. Human Rights Field Operation in Rwanda, in a report on the refugee return which started in mid-November, said the 12 included four of the refugees and two of their associates.</p>
<p>&quot;Also four genocide survivors and two associates have been reportedly killed by returnees, apparently in an attempt to eliminate witnesses to crimes committed in 1994,&quot; added the report, quoted by the U.N. Department of Humanitarian Affairs.</p>
<p>The figures are an indicator of the kind of reception the returning refugees can expect in Rwanda.</p>
<p>Some of the refugees took part in the genocide of 1994, when Hutu extremists slaughtered about 800,000 Rwanda Tutsis and moderate Hutus. They could face prosecution or vengeance.</p>
<p>The U.N. report said the Rwandan authorities had detained 162 of the returning refugees but some of these were in voluntary detention for fear of revenge attacks.</p>
<p>The United Nations has received reports that 26 of the detainees were mistreated on arrest or during detention.</p>
<p>It said that in general the local Rwandan authorities were respecting national directives that they arrest genocide suspects only after the case files are complete.</p>
<p>The returning refugees include more than 4,300 members of the old national army, the Forces Armees Rwandaises (FAR), which also took part in the attempt to wipe out the Tutsis.</p>
<p>The present Tutsi-dominated army, the Rwanda Patriotic Army, put an end to the genocide by overthrowing the old government.</p>
<p>The U.N. report said property problems could be the biggest impediment to rapid reintegration of the refugees.</p>
<p>Many Tutsis have taken over the property of absent Hutus and might not welcome back the former owners, especially if they suspect the Hutus of trying to kill them.</p>
<p>The report said that out of 75,000 Rwandans who came home from neighbouring Burundi in July and August, about 2.65 percent or almost 2,000 people are now in detention.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NAIROBI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KENYA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
