<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24312" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: India's Mathura oil refinery to shut Sept 3-30.</title>
<headline>India's Mathura oil refinery to shut Sept 3-30.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>State-owned Indian Oil Corp (IOC) will shut its 160,000-barrel-per-day (bpd) Mathura oil refinery for scheduled maintenance between September 3 and 30, sources close to the IOC said on Friday.  </p>
<p>Traders had earlier said that only a 50,000-bpd crude distillation unit at the refinery will be shut. But the source said the entire refinery will be shut for maintenance.</p>
<p>The Mathura refinery is located near the Taj Mahal in Agra south of New Delhi. Over recent years the smoke emissions from the refinery have been blamed for discolouring the Taj Mahal and there has been proposals to move it.  </p>
<p>The scheduled shutdown has prompted IOC to issue its fourth tender to buy 25,000 tonnes of 180-centistoke grade fuel oil for delivery in September.</p>
<p>This latest tender, which is for September 25-29 delivery to Goa or Kandla on the west coast, brings IOC's total fuel oil import requirements for September to 100,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>This is a large jump from India's fuel oil imports over the last two months when it bought only 10,000 tonnes in July and 14,000 tonnes in August, traders said.  </p>
<p>As a result of the controversy surrounding the Mathura refinery, India has started to use the cleaner 0.25-percent sulphur diesel for the areas surrounding the Taj Mahal called the Taj Trapezuim.</p>
<p>The country will need 120,000 tonnes of 0.25 percent sulphur diesel a month, half of which will be sourced from domestic refineries like Mathura and the other half from exports.</p>
<p>The plan is to prepare India for a gradual shift to lower lower sulphur diesel by April 1999 to help curb pollution.</p>
<p>--Singapore Newsroom (+65-8703084)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
