<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243127" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Text of draft Czech-German WW2 declaration.</title>
<headline>Text of draft Czech-German WW2 declaration.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following is the draft text of the joint Czech-German declaration aimed at addressing the World War Two history of the two neighbouring lands.</p>
<p>The text, obtained by Reuters on Monday and confirmed as authentic by diplomatic sources, is expected to be initialled by both countries' foreign ministers shortly before Christmas.</p>
<p>(The translation from the Czech original by Reuters):</p>
<p>- - - - - - - - - - -</p>
<p>INTRODUCTION</p>
<p>The governments of the Czech Republic and of the Federal Republic of Germany, having in mind the Agreeemnt between the Czech and Slovak Federal Republic and the Federal Republic of Germany on good neighbourhood and friendly cooperation from February 27, 1992, in which the Czechs and the Germans held out their hands,</p>
<p>Appreciating the history of fruitful and peaceful living of the Czechs and the Germans beside each other, during which a rich cultural inheretence was created which still endures today,</p>
<p>Being certain that the injustice cannot be erased, at best reduced, and that there must not be further injustice caused by it,</p>
<p>Being aware that the Federal Republic of Germany fully supports the Czech Republic to be accepted as a member of the European Union and the North Atlantic alliance in strong conviction that this is in the common interest,</p>
<p>Putting up their hands for credibility and openess in bilateral relations as a basis for persistent reconcialiation focused for the future,</p>
<p>They together declare:</p>
<p>POINT 1</p>
<p>Both parts are aware of their obligation and responsibility to further develop Czech-German relations in the spirit of good neighbourhood and partnership and help through it the creation of a unified Europe.</p>
<p>The Czech Republic and the Federal Republic of Germany today share common democratic values, respect human rights, basic freedoms and norms of international law, and are devoted to the basis of a legal state and to the policy of piece. On this basis they are committed to friendly and close cooperation in all areas important for common relations.</p>
<p>Both sides also are aware of the fact that the common course to the future needs a clear word about the past, with respect that the reason and the result must not be omitted.</p>
<p>POINT 2</p>
<p>The German side admits the responsibility of Germany for its role in the historical development which led to the Munich Agreement from the year 1938, (which led) to the escape and the expelling of people from the Czechoslovak border, as well as of the split and annexation of the Czechoslovak Republic.</p>
<p>It is sorry for the suffering and injustice, which were caused on the Czech peoples by the National-Socialist crimes of the Germans. The German side pays homage to the victims of the National-Socialist government of violence and to those who resisted this government of violence.</p>
<p>The German side also is aware of the fact, that the National-Socialist policy of violence against the Czech people helped to create the basis for the after-war escape, the expelling, and foreced resettlement.</p>
<p>POINT 3</p>
<p>The Czech side is sorry, that by the post-war expelling, as well as by the forced resettlement of Sudeten Germans from then-Czechoslovakia, by expropriating and revoking citizenship much suffering and injustice was caused on innocent people, and with respect to the character of collective guilt.</p>
<p>It especially is sorry for the excesses which were against elementary humanitatiran principles and also with the accepted legal norms of the time, and it also regrets that on the basis of law number 115 of May 8, 1946, it permitted these exceses were taken to be injustices and therefore the actions were not punished.</p>
<p>POINT 4</p>
<p>Both sides agree that the injustices committed belong to the past, and thus they will focus their relations toward the future. Because they continue to be aware of the tragic chapters of their history, they are agreed to further give preference to the understanding and joint agreement with each side remaining obliged by its legal order and (each side) respects, that the orther side has a different legal opinion. That is why both sides delcare, that they will not burden their relations with political and legal questions from the past.</p>
<p>POINT 5</p>
<p>Both sides confirm their obligations from the articles 20 and 21 of the agreement between the Czech and Slovak Federal Republic and the Federal Republic of Germany on good neighbourhood and friednly cooperation from February 27, 1992 in which the rights of the German minority in the Czech Republic and people of Czech origin in Germany are given.</p>
<p>Both sides are aware, that this minority and these people play an importnat role in the common relations and observe, that their support still is in the mutual interest.</p>
<p>POINT 6</p>
<p>Both sides are convinced, that the entry of the Czech Republic into the European Union and free movement in this area further eases the coexistence of Czechs and Germans. In this regard they (both sides) express their satisfaction that on the basis of the European Agreements of Association between the European Union and its member states and the Czech Republic was achieved significant progress in the area of economic cooperation including the possiblity for entreprenuerial activites according to article 45 of those agreements.</p>
<p>Both sides are prepared, in the context of their accepted legal norms to take into account during the consideration of requests for residence and entry to the job market, humanitarian and other reasons, including relations with relatives and family and other ties.</p>
<p>POINT 7</p>
<p>Both sides will create Czech-German Future Fund. The Geramn side declares, that it is ready to put into the fund 140 million marks. The Czech side declares, that it is ready to put into the fund (20 respectively 25) million marks. Both sides will close a special agreement about the joint administration of the fund.</p>
<p>This joint fund will serve for financing of projects of common interest (meetings of youth, care of old people, construction and operation of health resort sanatoria, care of monuments and graves and their reconstruction, support for minorities, partnership projects, a Czech-German discussion forum, joint scientific and environmental projects, the teaching of languages, and cross-border cooperation.</p>
<p>The German side acknowledges its obligation of responsibility to all who became victims of National-Socialist violence. That is why the projects, by which it is appropriate, should work mainly for the benefit of the victims of National-Socialist violence.</p>
<p>POINT 8</p>
<p>Both sides agree that the historic development of relations between Czechs and Germans especially in the first half of the 20th Century demand joint scruitiny and therefore (both sides) stand for the continuation of the successful work to date of the Czech-German Commission of Historians.</p>
<p>Both sides also consider the maintenance and care of cultural heritage, which connects Czechs and Germans, as an important contribution toward building bridges to the future.</p>
<p>Both sides will arrange the establishment of a Czech-German Discussion Forum which will be supported mainly from the means of the Czech-German Future Fund and on which, under the auspices of both governments and for the participation of all ciricles having an interest in closer and good Czech-German partnership, a Czech-German dialogue will flourish. (END TEXT)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
