<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243117" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine to test An-70, An-140 early 1997.</title>
<headline>Ukraine to test An-70, An-140 early 1997.</headline>
<byline>Rostislav Khotin</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's Antonov aircraft designer is to complete test versions of two new aircraft this year, opening a new era in the former Soviet republic's aviation industry, a senior official said on Monday.</p>
<p>Viktor Shyshkov, Antonov's deputy head designer, said in an interview that he saw a huge world market for the passenger An-140 and the cargo An-70.</p>
<p>&quot;We will finish the two models by the end of December and start test flights in the first quarter of next year,&quot; Shyshkov said, adding that a second An-140 would be ready in early 1997.</p>
<p>Former Soviet airlines have ordered about 200 An-140s for the next two years, Antonov said recently, putting world demand at 600 to 900 planes and domestic demand at 100 planes in the next few years.</p>
<p>Ukraine also has high hopes for exports of the An-70 which experts say will be cheaper than and able to compete with the U.S.Lockheed Hercules C-130 -- widely used to transport Western including NATO, forces and equipment. Antonov says output will reach 24 planes a year.</p>
<p>Antonov blamed human error for the crash of the first prototype, which apparently went out of control and collided with an Antonov plane shadowing it on a test flight in February 1995.</p>
<p>The plane is meant to replace the Ilyushin-76 of the Soviet airforce and the four-propeller An-12. It can carry 35 tonnes for 3,500 km (2,200 miles) without refuelling, designers say.</p>
<p>Funding for the An-70 came from the state budget but Antonov and a Ukrainian-Russian consortium financed the An-140, which carries 52 passengers and 4.9 tonnes of cargo.</p>
<p>The short-haul turbo-prop plane is meant to replace the ageing An-24, widely popular in the former Soviet Union and developing countries worldwide.</p>
<p>&quot;The new plane is twice as good as the An-24. We wanted to design a cheap plane which could get international certification quickly so as to speed up production,&quot; Shyshkov said.</p>
<p>In the Soviet era, Ukraine and Russia built more than 3,000 short-range planes, including the An-24 and a cargo version, which now have up to 40 percent of the market, experts say.</p>
<p>&quot;We see a very big international market for the An-140s -- especially in China, Africa and Latin America. But our main customer will definitely be Russia,&quot; Shyshkov said.</p>
<p>He said the new plane would suit for remote Russias regions in the North, the Urals, Siberia and the Far East in particular.</p>
<p>&quot;The An-140 is very convenient for such difficult conditions. It does not need proper concrete runaways -- the soil is enough for landings and take-offs,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The new plane's two engines are on top of the wings, keeping them a safe distance from the ground during landings on runways which are in a bad state of repair, he added.</p>
<p>Antonov hopes the new plane will be the first of a family, which will eventually include a cargo version, an executive jet and a 68-seat passenger plane. --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C23">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
