<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243246" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Dec 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bosnia - Dec 9.</headline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Sarajevo press on Monday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>OSLOBODJENJE</p>
<p>- Bosnia is offered to enter Europe but Bosnians are prevented to stay in Europe, writes &quot;Oslobodjenje's columnist, Zoran Pirolic, on the issue of forced return of Bosnian refugees from the West.</p>
<p>- Bosnian businessmen visit Macedonia and agree with their partners that Skopje serves as transit point for goods to be transported to Bosnia.</p>
<p>- The Bosnian Army 5th corps began destruction of its surplus arms. All work will be completed within 20 days, Atif Dudakovic, commander of the 5th corps told a news conference.</p>
<p>- A Malaysian businessman opens &quot;Orient Bank&quot; in Bosnia and says that investment will follow Islamic principles.</p>
<p>- New navigation gear donated by French governement will be set up soon at the Sarajevo airport, Bakir Karahasanovic, manger of the airport told Oslobodjenje.</p>
<p>DNEVNI AVAZ</p>
<p>- Three-man presidency meeting is scheduled for Wednesday. The constitution of the council of ministers will be the main issue on their agenda.</p>
<p>- Bosnian health workers go on 24 hour warning strike on Monday to demand federal government meet their demands to pay them salaries.</p>
<p>--Sarajevo newsroom, +387-71-663-864.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
