<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243388" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Coles' Eck may be paid less - Clark.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Coles' Eck may be paid less - Clark.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coles Myer Ltd's new managing director and chief executive officer (CEO) Dennis Eck may be paid less than outgoing CEO Peter Bartels, Coles Myer chairman Nobby Clark said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Asked in an interview on Australian Broadcasting Corp radio if Eck's pay would be comparable to Bartels', Clark said: &quot;I'm not sure that it will be, but that's a matter for disclosure at the appropriate time and in the appropriate form.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Eck, you will find, when you look at the structure of the company will be doing a different job to Mr Bartels, in a different way with a different management team and what we pay him will be reasonable and appropriate,&quot; Clark said.</p>
<p>Bartels resigned late on Monday as Coles Myer's managing director and CEO and is to be replaced by Eck from January 1.</p>
<p>Bartels had been under pressure through 1996 due to the group's financial performance. The disclosure of his A$2.8 million 1995/96 pay package further enraged Coles shareholders at the company's annual meeting last month.</p>
<p>Coles' shares closed up three cents at A$4.52 on Monday.</p>
<p>New Zealand's Brierley Investments Ltd owns 6.8 percent of Coles.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I6560002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
