<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24344" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dole camp asks Clinton to finalize debate details.</title>
<headline>Dole camp asks Clinton to finalize debate details.</headline>
<dateline>IRVINE, Calif 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>With party conventions over, Republicans have signalled they are ready to move into the next phase of the campaign and meet with President Clinton's aides to hammer out details of presidential debates.</p>
<p>The Dole campaign released a letter Friday inviting their Clinton counterparts to meet with Dole campaign manager Scott Reed to discuss particulars of the televised debates.</p>
<p>&quot;Next week, a small group of representatives from each of our campaigns should meet to address participants, format, timing and logistical issues surrounding the debates,&quot; Dole manager Scott Reed wrote to Clinton chief Peter Knight.</p>
<p>Tentative dates for the debates are Sept. 25, Oct. 9 and Oct. 16. The vice presidential debate is scheduled for Oct. 2.</p>
<p>Nelson Warfield, Dole's press secretary, said starting to plan now would give plenty of lead time, which he said the Clinton campaign was going to need.</p>
<p>&quot;They have a bigger challenge than we do. They have to explain how Bill Clinton had been on two sides of so many issues,&quot; Warfield said, taking a dig at Clinton for what critics charge are flip-flops on issues.</p>
<p>&quot;In fact,&quot; he continued, &quot;I guess one of the proposals should be for the debate to give him twice as much time so he can be on both the pro and the con.&quot;</p>
<p>Former South Carolina Gov. Carroll Campbell, who was on Dole's vice presidential short list before Dole decided on Jack Kemp, will head Dole's team.</p>
<p>Kemp, campaigning with Dole in southern California, said he will be ready for his debate with Vice President Al Gore but would not clue reporters in to his strategy.</p>
<p>&quot;Quarterbacks don't talk about the game before the game,&quot; the one-time pro football player said, using a sports analogy that has become a staple of the Republican ticket. &quot;I'll be prepared.&quot;</p>
<p>A decision was expected by mid-September on whether Texas billionaire Ross Perot, the Reform Party candidate, would be allowed to participate in the debates sponsored by the Commission on Presidential Debates, a non-profit, non-partisan group that took over in 1988 from the League of Women Voters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="IRVINE, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
