<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24348" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton warns supporters against overconfidence.</title>
<headline>Clinton warns supporters against overconfidence.</headline>
<byline>Michael Conlon</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton, visibly tired and facing a non-stop battle against Bob Dole in the 68 days left before voters choose between them, warned on Friday against overconfidence and said the fight had just started.</p>
<p>&quot;Any contest is not over until its over and this is a contest and its not over. It's just starting,&quot; Clinton told a meeting of Democratic party leaders</p>
<p>With polls showing him ahead of his Republican rival by as much as 15 points, Clinton recounted how sports teams often blow a lead. He told Democrats to remind the country that they are the party that &quot;represents most of the people&quot; but to approach the campaiagn with humility.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not a party of the past but a party of the future,&quot; Clinton said, repeating the themes he stressed in accepting the party's nomination at the close of its convention Thursday night -- a strong economy, expanding job opportunities, educational excellence and fighting crime.</p>
<p>He made no mention either time of the resignation of key political strategist Dick Morris, who was alleged in a sensationalist supermarket tabloid to have had a long-running affair with a $200-an-hour prostitute who claimed Morris allowed her to listen in on some of Clinton's telephone calls.</p>
<p>The disclosure, just hours before Clinton accepted the nomination for a second term, shadowed the 50-year-old chief executive's final moments at the convention, but some analysts questioned whether it would become a campaign issue in his fight against the 73-year-old Dole.</p>
<p>Clinton, Vice President Al Gore and their wives were headed for a two-day bus tour in parts of Missouri, Illinois, Kentucky and Tennessee designed to be a reprise of an attention-grabbing, momentum-building trip the ticket made in 1992 through Eastern states after the convention in New York.</p>
<p>Dole had stops scheduled in California and New Mexico.</p>
<p>Republican party chairman Haley Barbour issued a critique of the Democratic conclave on Friday, saying &quot;you feel like a mosquito in a nudist colony -- there are so many tempting targets you don't know where to start.&quot;</p>
<p>He said voters will see only one thing from the event, that &quot;The Clinton Democrats believe if we'll just give the government enough of our money, and enough control over our lives and businesses, government can solve all our problems.&quot;</p>
<p>A poll Gallup published on Friday by USA Today and CNN said Clinton's lead over Dole had grown to 13 points, up one point since last weekend. But Democratic pollster Stan Greenberg told the same audience Clinton addressed on Friday that the race is &quot;going to narrow&quot; before the Nov. 5 election.</p>
<p>Greenberg also said the public saw Democrats as thinking about the future compared to &quot;an ageing Bob Dole thinking about the past&quot; and that Clinton's strongest support comes from senior citizens and voters under 30.</p>
<p>He said his polling showed two-thirds of the public saw a significant part of the convention. Major network ratings indicated both party conventions were lightly watched.</p>
<p>Clinton admitted on Friday that he was &quot;drained&quot; after the convention and a nearly 700-mile (1,125 km) campaigning train ride that brought him to the convention city. Earlier, at a post-midnight reception, he said: &quot;Man, I'm dog-tired.&quot;</p>
<p>Reaction to his closing convention speech was mixed. Some delegates appeared bored, disappointed there were no soaring phrases. One Iowa man cautioned a yawning delegate to stop because &quot;the television cameras will catch you.&quot;</p>
<p>But the mass of 20,000 delegates and supporters cramming Chicago's United Centre were too fired up to complain.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
