<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243456" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK Tel to launch VOD fully in fall 1997.</title>
<headline>HK Tel to launch VOD fully in fall 1997.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong Telecommunications Ltd's interactive mulitmedia services unit Hongkong Telecom IMS said on Monday it was planning a full launch of its commercial interactive television in the third quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>In February, the unit said it had postponed the launch date of the HK$10 billion video-on-demand and home shopping network to mid-1997 from July 1996 to enable it to offer better technology, Internet access and more options.</p>
<p>Rose Cheung, senior consultant for special projects at Hongkong Telecom IMS, said by telephone the group planned to launch the service formally and fully in the third quarter of next year, while the mid-1997 target referred to a soft launch when the network would be available only to a &quot;limited&quot; number of users. She declined to specify the number.</p>
<p>&quot;We will offer the world's first commercial interactive TV in the fall of 1997,&quot; said William Lo, managing director at Hongkong Telecom IMS.</p>
<p>&quot;During its first year's launch, more than 100,000 households will be able to enjoy video-on-demand, banking shopping and high-speed Internet access through this home network, which comprises many DAVIC (Digital Audio-Visual Council) standard components,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Lo was speaking at the opening ceremony of the 15th DAVIC meeting and the first ever held in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Geneva-based DAVIC, set up in 1994, aims to promote digital audio-visual applications and provision of services based on specifications that maximize inter-operability among different countries, and includes over 200 companies from 25 countries.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6590</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
