<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243509" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dollar finishes firmer in U.S. trade.</title>
<headline>Dollar finishes firmer in U.S. trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar ended firmer versus other major currencies after senior financial officials' remarks helped boost world asset markets, experts said.</p>
<p>During a television interview on Sunday, U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin reassured investors that Federal Reserve Chairman Alan Greenspan was merely raising a question last week about the level of the stock market, not voicing an opinion about whether prices are too high.</p>
<p>Greenspan roiled markets last week when he said the Fed must be wary when &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; infects stocks and other asset markets because that could hurt the economy.</p>
<p>On Monday at a monthly meeting of central bankers in Basle, Switzerland, Bundesbank President Hans Tietmeyer and Bank of England Governor Eddie George echoed Rubin's remarks by saying financial markets had over reacted to Greenspan's comments.</p>
<p>&quot;The overnight statements from Tietmeyer, George and Rubin down-playing Greenspan's statements on Friday helped the dollar out a bit...,&quot; said Brian McCarthy, market analyst at Ruesch International.</p>
<p>The dollar finished at 1.5575/85 marks and 113.40/50 yen, up from 1.5520/23 marks and 113.13/18 yen at the open.</p>
<p>Tietmeyer and George were not the only central bankers to affect foreign exchange trading Monday, remarks by Swiss National Bank (SNB) board member Jean-Pierre Roth pressured the Swiss franc, which slid to its lowest level in 30-months against the German mark. At the gathering in Basle, Switzerland, Roth told reporters the SNB was &quot;pleased&quot; with the recent weakness in the franc and was continuing easy monetary policy that has been in effect since August.</p>
<p>&quot;That would, if anything, continue to support the fact that 'Swissy' would go weaker,&quot; said David Durrant, a senior currency strategist at I.D.E.A. Inc.</p>
<p>The Swiss economy remains in a prolonged slump. A weaker currency could help bolster economic growth by making Swiss-made exports more affordable to foreign buyers.</p>
<p>The dollar also gained against the Swiss currency, closing at 1.3278/88 francs compared with 1.3223/33 at the open.</p>
<p>Currency experts on Monday also looked ahead to a meeting of European Union leaders in Dublin, Ireland on Friday and Saturday in which officials will work toward the planned launching in January 1999 of a single European currency or European Monetary Union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;Should we get some comments that would be derogatory towards EMU suggesting that there would be problems, we should instantly get ready to get our (deutsche)mark rally hats on because marks probably going to move favorable to the other currencies in Europe...,&quot; I.D.E.A.'s Durrant said.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, sterling inched higher to close at $1.6465/75, up from $1.6460/70 at the open.</p>
<p>The dollar fell to Canadian $1.3550/55 from C$1.3572/77 at the open.</p>
<p>The Australian dollar closed at $0.8023/28, up from $0.7995/00 at the open. -- Donna Sells 212-859-1668</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
