<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243513" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: China okays U.S. warship visits to Hong Kong.</title>
<headline>China okays U.S. warship visits to Hong Kong.</headline>
<byline>Charles Aldinger</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Moving to improve U.S.-China ties, visiting Defence Minister Chi Haotian said on Monday Beijing had tentatively approved continued U.S. warship visits to Hong Kong after the colony is turned over to China by Britain next year.</p>
<p>Chi met President Bill Clinton at the White House and made the confidence-building announcement in talks with Defence Secretary William Perry at the Pentagon, according to a senior U.S. defence official, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>China will resume sovereignty over Hong Kong, a British crown colony since the 19th century, at midnight on June 30, 1997. The United States had sought the continued visit of warships to Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;China agreed in principle to continue U.S. ship visits to Hong Kong&quot; after the hand-over, the U.S. defence official told reporters. He said details and the frequency of such visits still must be worked out.</p>
<p>He said the two countries had also agreed to further high-level military exchanges and were discussing a proposed agreement on measures to avoid warship incidents in the western Pacific, where both navies operate.</p>
<p>The official said the meetings at the start of a twice-delayed, two-week visit by Chi touched on contentious issues from arms proliferation, Taiwan and trade, but were positive in nature.</p>
<p>&quot;The tone in all these meetings ... has been warm and friendly. Both sides have a determination and desire to improve the relationshoip,&quot; the official stressed.</p>
<p>&quot;Minister Chi said that what China wants in Hong Kong is stability and prosperity, that they will follow the terms of the China-U.K. declaration of Hong Kong, which is basically that China is one country with two systems -- the capitalist system in Hong Kong and the socialist system in China.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton and China's President Jiang Zemin met last month at the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation forum in Manila as the two countries moved to shore up ties strained by trade disputes and U.S. concern over alleged Chinese arms and nuclear technology transfers to Pakistan and Iran.</p>
<p>U.S. relations with China went into a long downward spiral after the Tiananmen crackdown, but Clinton and Jiang agreed at their Nov. 17 meeting to end the official estrangement.</p>
<p>Chi told reporters at the Pentagon after he met Clinton for about 20 minutes at the White House that news media had exaggerated reports of nuclear arms proliferation by China.</p>
<p>&quot;I think on some of such issues the media have blown the issue (out) of proportion, have exaggerated the issue,&quot; he said in response to a question from reporters.</p>
<p>&quot;Some of the issues have been exaggerated and some of these issues simply do not exist,&quot; Chi said, adding that China had carefully guarded its technology exports under a Missile Technology Control Regime agreement with Washington.</p>
<p>The U.S. official said that Perry told Chi on Monday that even if China continued to legally sell arms to Iran, the move could come back to haunt Beijing because China was increasingly dependent on oil from the Gulf.</p>
<p>Perry himself told reporters the arms controversy would be a key subject during the visit, the first by a Chinese defence minister to the United States since 1988.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing is more important to security and stability, not only of the region but in the entire world, (than) that two great powers, China and the United States, work together in the spirit of cooperation to prevent any weapons of mass destruction or the materials for those weapons from being proliferated to other countries,&quot; said Perry.</p>
<p>Chi, leading a 20-member delegation of military and foreign ministry officials, will meet Deputy Secretary of State Strobe Talbott at the the State Department on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I am confident through the talks between me and Dr. Perry we will be able to usher in a new stage in the relations between our two militaries,&quot; Chi told reporters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
