<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243794" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN Council to vote informally Tuesday on top post.</title>
<headline>UN Council to vote informally Tuesday on top post.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.N. Security Council will hold its first informal poll on Tuesday in the contest for secretary-general, now that Boutros Boutros-Ghali has stepped aside in the race for the top U.N. post.</p>
<p>Council president Paolo Fulci said that the so-called straw poll would include the four candidates who had been nominated on Friday. No new names were added on Monday, he said.  </p>
<p>The four nominated on Friday were: Kofi Annan of Ghana, the U.N. undersecretary-general for peacekeeping; Hamid Algabid of Niger, secretary-general of the Organisation of Islamic Conference; Amara Essy, foreign minister of the Ivory Coast; and Ahmedou Ould-Abdallah of Mauritania, the former U.N. special envoy for Burundi who is executive secretary of the Washington-based Global Coalition for Africa.</p>
<p>Salim A. Salim of Tanzania, the secretary-general of the Organisation of African Unity, who South African was expected to nominate on Monday, however, did not submit his name.</p>
<p>Any winning candidate has to get at least nine votes and no veto from one of the five permanent members -- the United States, Russia, China, Britain and France.</p>
<p>But in the confusing U.N. procedures, members can vote for more than one candidate and a veto does not necessarily preclude another vote -- and another veto -- on the same candidate. Any candidate approved by the council must be endorsed by the 185-member General Assembly.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MAURTN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NIGER">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
