<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243798" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU ministers urge Ciba gene-maize decision.</title>
<headline>EU ministers urge Ciba gene-maize decision.</headline>
<byline>Patrick Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union environment ministers urged the European Commission on Monday to stick to a December 18 deadline for a decision on whether to allow Ciba Geigy's gene-modified maize to be released on EU markets.</p>
<p>Ministers from the Netherlands and Spain in particular urged European Commissioner Ritt Bjerregaard to take a decision, one EU official told reporters.</p>
<p>A European Commission source said last Friday that ports in Spain, Portugual and the Netherlands were the most likely among EU countries to have received maize shipments containing a gene-modified corn strain made by Swiss chemicals company Ciba-Geigy AG and grown in the United States.</p>
<p>A U.S. official told Reuters on Monday it was unlikely that U.S. maize exporters would have shipped maize before the EU's duty-free tariff regime came into force while a government spokesman in Lisbon denied that Portugal had imported gene-modified maize in breach of EU rules.</p>
<p>&quot;Portugal has not imported any U.S. gene-modified maize. We are awaiting the decision of the European Commission,&quot; Augusto Vilela of the Agriculture Ministry told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bjerregaard, who faced sustained criticism from ministers over repeated delays to the decision, raised the prospect of changing rules for future approvals of genetically modified organisms to include a labelling requirement.</p>
<p>&quot;It was quite clearly a political commitment on her part to make sure that in future cases you have labelling requirements,&quot; a Commission official told reporters.</p>
<p>That too was criticised by several ministers according to British Environment Minister John Gummer, who told reporters that raising the labelling issue would confuse an already complex problem.</p>
<p>The Commission is due to discuss and possibly decide on December 18 whether to allow imports of the modified maize, which Ciba Geigy altered to make it resistant to the corn-borer pest and to increase its tolerance to certain weedkillers.</p>
<p>A Commission decision to clear the maize, which U.S. authorities have approved, will depend on advice from EU committees on food, animal feed and pesticides.</p>
<p>European Union environment ministers themselves failed last June to agree on the French- backed proposal to approve the maize, with some citing fears about the environmental effects of releasing the new strain and others saying that a &quot;marker gene&quot; used in the Ciba maize could undermine the effectiveness of an antibiotic used in animals and humans.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
