<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243875" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: U.N. approves start of oil-for-food deal with Iraq.</title>
<headline>U.N. approves start of oil-for-food deal with Iraq.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Nations on Monday authorised the start of a long-delayed &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal with Iraq, enabling Baghdad to make a limited return to the world oil market for the first time since its 1990 invasion of Kuwait.</p>
<p>Under the deal, concluded in May but held up by disputes over implementation, Iraq will be able to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months to buy food, medicine and other humanitarian goods to help offset the effects of sanctions in force for the past six years.</p>
<p>Both the oil sales and the purchase of humanitarian supplies are subject to close U.N. monitoring.</p>
<p>If all goes well, the Security Council may renew the deal when the initial six months expire.</p>
<p>Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali gave the final go-ahead in a report to the Security Council. Under an April 1995 council resolution on which the scheme is based, the initial six-month period begins at one minute after midnight -- at 0500 GMT Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a victory for the poorest of the poor of Iraq, for the women, the children, the sick and the disabled,&quot; Boutros-Ghali said.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope the humanitarian dimension will always prevail in the work of the United Nations,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>He was referring to the dire effects of the sanctions imposed on Iraq since shortly after President Saddam Hussein sent his troops into Kuwait in August 1990.</p>
<p>The U.N. Children's Fund (UNICEF) has said 4,500 children under the age of five are dying each month from hunger and disease, and the U.N. World Food Programme estimates about 180,000 children under five are malnourished.</p>
<p>Under the &quot;oil-for-food&quot; arrangement, Iraq will be able to export slightly under 600,000 barrels of oil a day, according to current prices. Before the Gulf War, it exported over three million barrels a day.</p>
<p>After months of negotiations, the United Nations and Iraq signed an agreement, or memorandum of understanding, covering the oil deal on May 20 this year. But its implementation was further delayed until Iraq November 25 accepted all U.N. conditions.</p>
<p>These include arrangements under which some 150 U.N. inspectors will ensure that the food and other supplies reach all sectors of the population, not just those favoured by the Iraqi government. Another 32 inspectors from Lloyds Register will check on the import of the humanitarian goods,</p>
<p>In addition, 14 U.N. inspectors from the Dutch-based Saybolt company will monitor the outflow of Iraqi oil at three locations. These are: at pipeline metering station at Zakho, on the Iraq-Turkish border; at the Turkish terminal of Ceyhan; and at the Iraqi Gulf port of Mina al-Bakr.</p>
<p>Most of the oil is to be exported through the Iraqi-Turkish pipeline.</p>
<p>The last element to fall in place was a report to Boutros-Ghali last Friday that the metering equipment at Zakho, previously out of order, had been repaired and was now functioning.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
