<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243997" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Florida official says Prudential blocked probe.</title>
<headline>Florida official says Prudential blocked probe.</headline>
<dateline>TALLAHASSEE, Fla.</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida Insurance Commissioner Bill Nelson Monday charged Prudential Insurance Co. of America with obstructing a state probe into allegations the company misrepresented insurance policies as investments.</p>
<p>Nelson filed a formal administrative complaint alleging Prudential destroyed documents and ignored subpoenas in an investigation that began in April 1995 into allegations it &quot;churned&quot; customer accounts and misrepresented some policies. Churning is when brokers or agents trade a customer's account without permission to generate commissions.</p>
<p>He said the allegations stretched over at least 14 years and may involve more than 100,000 Florida policyholders.</p>
<p>The insurance commissioner said that unless the company provided the requested documents, it could face sanctions possibly including loss of its license to operate in Florida.</p>
<p>&quot;By my order today, I'm putting the burden on Prudential to show why I should not impose the stiffest of fines or revoke or suspend its license to do business in Florida,&quot; Nelson said at a news conference in Tallahassee.</p>
<p>Florida is one of a handful of states that have not agreed to settle with the Newark, N.J.-based insurance company over charges that its agents throughout the 1980s misrepresented its products and sold insurance policies as investments.</p>
<p>The Florida officials said Prudential sold plain life insurance policies to elderly people by pitching them as tax-favoured investments or &quot;inflation safety nets.&quot;</p>
<p>Nelson said he would give the &quot;benefit of the doubt&quot; to Arthur Ryan, the newly named chief executive of Prudential, in the hope the company would begin cooperating with Florida investigators.</p>
<p>Prudential said the company was open to talks with state officials.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, Prudential reached an agreement with 43 other states to pay a $30 million fine and set up a fund for policyholders who could prove their accounts were churned by the company's agents.</p>
<p>The company also has agreed in a separate $410 million class-action lawsuit that it would reimburse policyholders for similar practices. That case is still pending before a federal judge in New Jersey.</p>
<p>Prudential is the largest of a number of insurance companies to be charged with such practices nationwide in recent years.</p>
<p>Florida Attorney General Bob Butterworth said his department also was investigating the company. &quot;We will pursue all the options available to us to ensure that all those who suffered are fairly compensated,&quot; Butterworth said.</p>
<p>&quot;That will include the RICO act as well as civil theft,&quot; he said, referring to the state's Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organisation Act, which can lead to triple damages in certain cases.</p>
<p>Holding up a full-page advertisement in the Sunday edition of the New York Times, Butterworth said Prudential used consumer confidence in the company to deceive mostly elderly policyholders.</p>
<p>&quot;When they talked about selling you 'a piece of the rock,' then they go ahead and hit you over the head with it,&quot; Butterworth said. &quot;A piece of the rock&quot; is Prudential's longstanding advertising theme line.</p>
<p>Butterworth also accused the firm of persuading policyholders to use the current value of their policies as collateral to purchase other products, allowing agents to earn additional commissions.</p>
<p>Nelson and Butterworth said they would file objections seeking to block the settlement in the New Jersey case. A hearing is set for Jan. 21.</p>
<p>&quot;This settlement is a bad deal for policyholders. It does not begin to compensate Florida consumers whose pockets were picked,&quot; Nelson said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLAHASSEE, Fla."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
