<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243991" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: McDonald's to open in 100th and 101st countries.</title>
<headline>McDonald's to open in 100th and 101st countries.</headline>
<dateline>OAK BROOK, Ill. 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>McDonald's Corp., which opened its first fast-food restaurants outside the United States in 1967 in Canada and Puerto Rico, said Monday it was expanding into its 100th and 101st countries.</p>
<p>The world's largest restaurant chain said it planned to open outlets in Minsk, Belarus, and in Papeete, Tahiti, on Tuesday.</p>
<p>McDonald's also opened what it said was the world's first ski-through restaurant in the popular Swedish ski resort of Lindvallen about 280 miles northwest of Stockholm.</p>
<p>&quot;With the openings of countries No. 100 and No. 101, McDonald's is present in nations accounting for about 75 percent of the world's population,&quot; Jim Cantalupo, president of McDonald's International, said in a statement.</p>
<p>McDonald's said it operates more than 20,000 restaurants on six continents.</p>
<p>&quot;Nearly half of McDonald's systemwide sales and more than half of the company's operating income come from outside the U.S.,&quot; Cantalupo said.</p>
<p>McDonald's will open three restaurants in Minsk, where it has invested more than $15 million. One outlet is planned for Tahiti.</p>
<p>In Eastern Europe, McDonald's operates 200 restaurants in 14 countries. &quot;We're committed to continuing that growth in Eastern Europe,&quot; Cantalupo added.</p>
<p>At the ski-through restaurant in Sweden, called &quot;McSki,&quot; skiers order hamburgers and French fries through a special window and ski off, munching as they go.</p>
<p>The restaurant, which also has indoor seating for about 140 people, is some 110 yards from the resort's main ski lift, which can carry about 3,000 people an hour.</p>
<p>&quot;The idea for the ski-through was actually under the theme of being where our customers are. Our guests decide where we should be,&quot; said Swedish McDonald's spokesman Bjorn Kallstrom at the opening ceremony for McSki.</p>
<p>Kallstrom said McDonald's aims to have 200 restaurants in Sweden by the year 2000, up from 120 today.</p>
<p>&quot;If we find the sites we see that we can easily have that number of restaurants,&quot; Kallstrom said. &quot;We don't have any plans for more ski-throughs in Sweden, but who knows what will happen in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>Kallstrom said McSki has aroused interest from McDonald's operations in other countries as well.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BYELRS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FPOLY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I66100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OAK BROOK, Ill."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
