<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="243974" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka says fiscal reform vital for good growth.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka says fiscal reform vital for good growth.</headline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lankan Deputy Finance Minister G.L. Peiris on Monday pledged his government's commitment to controlling debt, cutting the budget deficit and continuing fiscal reforms to boost economic growth.</p>
<p>The government's efforts to tackle the chronic budget deficit would help achieve sustainable high economic growth, Peiris told a debt management conference in the Sri Lankan capital.</p>
<p>&quot;The root cause of our economic problems being the weakness in the fiscal structure, we have emphasised the vital need to pursue a firm fiscal consolidation strategy as a matter of urgency,&quot; Peiris said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has ... taken initiatives to regularise and consolidate market-friendly policy strategies in a medium-term policy framework.</p>
<p>&quot;These would lay a firm foundation for a sustainable high growth path in a free and competitive environment&quot;, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;Without strict adherence to fiscal discipline, we may remain caught up in a vicious cycle of slow growth and poverty,&quot; Peiris said.</p>
<p>Peiris effectively controls the Finance Ministry's day-to-day operations. President Chandrika Kumaratunga holds the finance portfolio.</p>
<p>The government hopes to cut the budget deficit to 4.5 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) by 1999, against an earlier projected 8.7 percent for calendar 1996. GDP growth is forecast to rise to about 5.5 percent in 1997 from 3.7 percent in 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
