<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244225" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: British E coli outbreak claims tenth victim.</title>
<headline>British E coli outbreak claims tenth victim.</headline>
<dateline>HAMILTON, Scotland 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>A tenth person has died in a food poisoning outbreak in Scotland, Scottish Secretary Michael Forsyth said on Monday.</p>
<p>Forsyth told a political meeting the latest victim of E Coli bacteria poisioning had died in hospital in Glasgow but he gave no further details.</p>
<p>The poisoning first appeared among pensioners attending a lunch and was traced to cook meat pies supplied by an award-winning Scottish butcher's shop.</p>
<p>Officials say there are now 204 confirmed cases of E coli poisoning, making it the worst such outbreak in Britain.</p>
<p>E coli is a common gut bacteria that is normally harmless, but a toxic strain that lives in cattle can be passed to humans via manure or improper slaughtering.</p>
<p>Recent outbreaks of E coli poisoning have been reported in the U.S. and Japan. More than 20 cases in Washington state, Colorado, California and Canada were linked to unpasteurised apple juice. In 1993, 500 people were affected in the Seattle area and three children died after eating undercooked hamburgers.</p>
<p>In Tokyo last July, 11 people, mainly schoolchildren, died and 9,500 became ill in an outbreak there.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMILTON, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
