<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244218" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Touch lepers, Britain's Princess Diana urges.</title>
<headline>Touch lepers, Britain's Princess Diana urges.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Princess Diana told a charity conference on Monday that lepers need to be touched to show they are not completely reviled.</p>
<p>Diana, who has made headlines by holding hands with AIDS patients, lepers and others afflicted with frightening diseases, looked radiant and tanned as she spoke about the horrors of leprosy.</p>
<p>&quot;It has always been my concern to touch people with leprosy -- trying to show in a simple action that they are not reviled nor are we repulsed,&quot; she said in a speech marking the 30th anniversary of the International Federation of Anti-Leprosy Associations (ILEP) in London.</p>
<p>More than 500,000 new cases of leprosy had been diagnosed in the past year, she said.</p>
<p>&quot;It has not disappeared from the list of medical diseases. It is not a condition that only exists in the Old Testament of the Holy Bible,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Leprosy, a nerve disease, can cause disfigurement as victims lose extremities such as fingertips. It is relatively easy to treat with drugs but is common in poor slums where treatment is not available.</p>
<p>The charity is one of six Diana decided to concentrate on after dropping her patronage of most ahead of her divorce in August from heir-to-the-throne Prince Charles.</p>
<p>Admirers noted Diana sported a new, slightly straighter hairdo as she arrived at the meeting in central London.</p>
<p>Later on Monday she was due to fly by Concorde to a charity ball in New York.</p>
<p>She will be a guest of honour at the Costume Institute ball, a $1,000-a-seat gala evening sponsored by fashion designer Christian Dior.</p>
<p>Travelling with her sister, Lady Sarah McCorquodale, Diana will stay in a hotel overlooking Central Park and near to the Metropolitan Museum of Art where the ball is being held.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
