<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244326" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel to let 750 Palestinian merchants enter.</title>
<headline>Israel to let 750 Palestinian merchants enter.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Israeli army said on Monday it had further eased restrictions on the entry of Palestinians to its territory, allowing 750 more merchants from the West Bank and Gaza Strip to enter the Jewish state.</p>
<p>&quot;The Israel defence authority authorised additional easings of conditions for entry into Israel,&quot; an army statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;As of last night, 750 additional merchants will be permitted to enter Israel (500 from the Gaza Strip and 250 from the West Bank),&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials said, however, that they had yet to receive the new permits. There has commonly been a lag between Israel's announcing issuance of new permits and the actual distribution.</p>
<p>A spokesman for the coordinator of Israeli activities in the West Bank and Gaza Strip said the additional permits would raise to 3,500 the number of merchants and businessmen allowed to enter Israel.</p>
<p>Israel imposed a ban on the entry of Palestinians from the West Bank and Gaza Strip after the first in a wave of four Moslem militant suicide bombings killed 59 people in Israel in February and March.</p>
<p>It periodically tightens and eases the closure based on its security concerns. At present, Palestinian officials say, 41,000 Palestinians enter Israel to work.</p>
<p>Closures have caused many hardships to the more than two million Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza, many of whom depend to a large extent on Israel for their livelihood.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
