<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244418" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian parliament to decide top minister's fate.</title>
<headline>Belgian parliament to decide top minister's fate.</headline>
<byline>Geert De Clercq</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium's parliament, already beset by public disgust at the country's child sex and murder scandal, was set on Monday to review allegations that Deputy Prime Minister Elio Di Rupo had sex with under-age boys.</p>
<p>The parliament must decide if the allegations, totally unconnected with the discovery three months ago of the bodies of four sexually-abused young girls, are serious enough for Di Rupo to be indicted.</p>
<p>Di Rupo, a francophone socialist and homosexual, denies the allegations. But they have further undermined public confidence in a political and legal system widely seen as thoroughly corrupt.</p>
<p>The Cour de Cassation, Belgium's highest court, handed a report on the allegations to the president of parliament on Monday.</p>
<p>Leaders of the parliamentary parties meet at 1500 (1400 GMT) to decide when a special commission will review the report.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission could meet today, but it could also be tomorrow,&quot; parliament president Raymond Langendries told Belgian VTM television.</p>
<p>The commission will then make a recommendation to parliament, which will vote on it in plenary session, possibly on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The accusations came at a time of crisis in Belgium over revelations of a child sex and paedophilia ring responsible for the deaths of several young children. There is no suggestion of any link between Di Rupo and such a ring but the accusation further undermines the authority of government in acting.</p>
<p>Revelations of police and judicial bungling in earlier investigations in the hunt for missing children have further fuelled public anger and disgust.</p>
<p>In October more than 250,000 people took to the streets of Brussels in support of the victims and their families in a demonstration that crossed the country's language divide and rapidly turned into a show of anger at the system.</p>
<p>The government has rushed through a series of legal reforms and the leaders of the main political parties on Saturday began a process that should lead to long-awaited political reforms.</p>
<p>But that still may be too late for Di Rupo, even if parliament decides he has no case to answer.</p>
<p>Parliament has three options. It can decide the allegations against Di Rupo are unfounded and clear his name, it can decide to indict him or it can ask the court for a further investigation.</p>
<p>It is also possible that the court itself has asked for more time to investigate.</p>
<p>In Belgium, only parliament can indict ministers and only the Cour de Cassation can try them.</p>
<p>A similar procedure brought down former NATO Secretary General Willy Claes, who was forced to resign in October 1995 after parliament indicted him over allegations of bribery when he was a Belgian economics minister in the late eighties.</p>
<p>An indictment would mean sending Di Rupo to the Cour de Cassation for a full investigation -- a move which would end his political career.</p>
<p>Even if parliament decides the charges are unfounded, the allegations have already prompted some politicians to call for his resignation on the grounds that a publicly-known homosexual should not hold high government office.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
