<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244415" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's Prodi said to be open over industry aid.</title>
<headline>Italy's Prodi said to be open over industry aid.</headline>
<dateline>TURIN, Italy 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The President of Italy's Piedmont region said on Monday Prime Minister Romano Prodi was &quot;open&quot; to the question of some form of state aid and incentives to boost ailing industries.</p>
<p>Enzo Ghigo told reporters after meeting Prodi that the Prime Minister had told him he would take the issue into &quot;serious consideration after the 1997 budget is approved and in a wider context of Italy's economic relaunch.&quot;</p>
<p>Prodi, in Turin for an official visit, did not touch on the issue when meeting reporters.</p>
<p>On Saturday, speaking at the opening of the Bologna Car Show, Prodi appeared to dash the hopes of the domestic car sector when he said he did not believe special financial incentives were the best way to revive flagging Italian car sales.</p>
<p>But Industry Minister Pierluigi Bersani said in an interview published on Monday he was studying measures to help crisis-hit domestic enterprises.</p>
<p>Bersani told the weekly Mondo Economic he would take a series of steps as soon as parliament passed the budget law, due by the end of December.</p>
<p>These measures would be specially aimed at supporting those companies operating in the durable goods sector and which are having to face stagnation in consumer demand.</p>
<p>Italian industry, led by the powerful employers' federation Confindustria, has in past days strongly criticised Prodi's government, saying it is not doing enough to help business.</p>
<p>Prodi, speaking to reporters in Turin, limited himself to saying: &quot;If the industrialists' role is one of scepticism that's fine...I want a united country going into Europe.&quot;</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TURIN, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
