<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244462" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Nobel Prize winners gather in Sweden for awards.</title>
<headline>Nobel Prize winners gather in Sweden for awards.</headline>
<byline>Birgitta Forsberg</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The 1996 Nobel prize winners have gathered in Stockholm to receive their prestigious awards and attend a banquet on Tuesday, the 100th anniversary of founder Alfred Nobel's death.</p>
<p>The winners of five of the six awards will receive Nobel gold medals and cheques of $1.2 million a prize from Sweden's King Carl XVI Gustaf at a formal ceremony before joining 1,300 guests for a black tie dinner that will be televised live.</p>
<p>The winners of the 1996 Nobel peace prize, East Timor's Bishop Carlos Belo and resistance leader Jose Ramos-Horta, will receive their awards in Oslo in neighbouring Norway as stipulated in the will of Nobel, a Swedish scientist.</p>
<p>The joint winner of the 1996 economics award, Canadian William Vickrey, 82, died from a heart attack three days after winning the prize.</p>
<p>His friend and colleague, Professor C. Lowell Harris, will receive the prize on his behalf.</p>
<p>The Columbia University professor won the prize jointly with Briton James Mirrlees for their separate contributions to the economic theory of incentives under asymmetric information.</p>
<p>Polish poet and critic Wislawa Szymborska, who has been described as the &quot;Mozart of Poetry&quot;, was awarded the literature prize.</p>
<p>The Swedish Academy said the shy, chain-smoking poet deserved the prize &quot;for her poetry that with ironic precision allows the historical and biological context to come to light in fragments of human reality&quot;.</p>
<p>The scientific prizes, first awarded in 1901 at the bequest of Nobel, have once again been dominated by Americans, confirming a widely held view that U.S. colleges are producing the world's best scientific research.</p>
<p>Some of the winners at a news conference in Stockholm voiced concern about continuing cutbacks in government funding for basic research around the world.</p>
<p>&quot;Directed research can never replace basic research,&quot; said chemistry prize winner American Robert Curl.</p>
<p>&quot;In basic research, you never know what will happen, you can never promise any results. Directed research had never given us laser and we would never have discovered our own DNA.&quot;</p>
<p>Curl shared the chemistry prize with fellow countryman Richard Smalley and Briton Sir Harold Kroto for a 1985 discovery of a form of the carbon element in the faceted shape of a soccer ball, which gave rise to a new form of chemistry.</p>
<p>The physics prize was awarded to the U.S. trio of David Lee, Douglas Osheroff and Robert Richardson for their quantum physics discovery on the superfluidity of the helium-3 isotope, a breakthrough in low temperature physics.</p>
<p>The medicine prize went to Australian Peter Doherty and Switzerland's Rolf Zinkernagel for discovering how the immune system recognises and can then kill infected cells, unlocking the mystery of how a vaccine needs to be composed.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
