<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244421" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</title>
<headline>F.O. LICHT - Daily coffee report.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following is a direct contribution from statistician F.O. Licht in Ratzeburg, Germany. Please address any queries to Helmut Ahlfeld on +00 49 4541 88920.</p>
<p>COFFEE: World market for December 6, 1996</p>
<p>Robusta futures in London closed mostly lower continuing the recent downward slide. Anti-inflatory remarks by US Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan which had rattled the US-dollar and stock markets had no immediate impact on the coffee market. By the close, front-month January was unchanged at $1,311 per tonne while March lost $11 to close at $1,239 per tonne. Traders said the March volume reflected heavy trades in January/March and March/May switches. In New York arabica futures came under slight pressure as the CSC daily warehouse report showed 1,000 bags pending classification in New Orleans and 10,500 in Miami, a hint of supplies coming in. Moreover there were finally some delivery notices issued on December 6. A second factor for the weaker tone was news yesterday of a drop in Colombian grower prices which could put pressure on the differential. Long term the reduction in coffee prices is bullish, but short term the market could respond negatively. There is still much debate about the size of the Brazilian 1997/98 crop with some suggesting flowering has been erratic. This might provide some underpinning to a market that otherwise would probably come under increased pressure. At the close December was off 70 points at 111.75 cents/lb while March lost 20 points to close at 103.25 cents/lb. The outer months lost between 0.15 and 1.15 cents/lb. The physical market remained dull this week with few spot sales, as the steep backwardation in the futures market left roasters unwilling to pay high prices for nearby delivery. Most processors are expected to shun the market and scrape by from their own inventories until the December contract expires in two weeks.</p>
<p>FUNDAMENTALS</p>
<p>COLOMBIA - Fabio Trujillo, leader of the Independent National Coffee Growers Union, denied reports of an immediate strike to protest against the cut in Colombia's internal coffee price. He said growers were dismayed by the price cut but there were no immediate plans to organize a work stoppage. With the price cut, growers who have been paid 235,500 pesos per 125 kg load since August will now receive 221,500 pesos. This is a hard blow as growers suffer from a steep rise in production costs because of higher-than-expected inflation this year.</p>
<p>THAILAND - According to industry sources rains have delayed Thailand's coffee crop by about a month. Thai beans are not expected until January, it was said.</p>
<p>FRANCE - France imported 548,754 bags of coffee in September 1996, 2.8 per cent more than was imported the same month the previous year. That brought total imports since the beginning of 1996 up to 5.044 million bags, 6.9 per cent more than was imported the same period in 1995. Total imports in calendar year 1995 dropped by 5.5 per cent to 6.246 million bags. Major suppliers of green coffee in January/September 1996 were Ivory Coast (590,600 vs 566,200 bags), Uganda (399,600 vs 199,700 bags), Brazil (535,800 vs 672,000 bags) and Colombia (414,200 vs 399,700 bags). The country exported 878,600 bags of coffee in January/September 1996, 12 per cent more than was exported the same period in 1995. Total exports in calendar year 1995 dropped by 7.4 per cent to 1.074 million bags.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
