<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244483" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Monday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Monday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Monday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Joao Vale de Almeida reminded accredited journalists that they were invited to attend a reception sponsored by the Spokesman's Service at 1730/1630 GMT on the 15th floor of the Breydel building. He said the Commission president and members would attend.</p>
<p>Vale de Almeida also noted that the Commission would hold its weekly meeting in Strasbourg on Tuesday. He said the official agenda would be available at around 1500/1400 GMT on Monday in his office.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, spokesman Willy Helin denied reports that a decision had been taken concerning Wallonian state aid to Forges de Clabecq. He said a decision should be taken on December 18.</p>
<p>Asked about information campaigns on the single currency in the UK, spokeswoman Elisabetta Olivi said they were financed by the Community budget but that instruments and applications could differ from one member state to the other.</p>
<p>Vale de Almeida said Commission President Jacques Santer had met U.S. Special Envoy and Commerce Undersecretary Stuart Eizenstat to discuss the upcoming EU-U.S. summit in Washington. He said genetically modified maize had been on the agenda and that Eizenstat had expressed U.S. concern about the recent debate in Europe on this issue.</p>
<p>Vale de Almeida noted that the ban concerned the release of genetically modified maize on the EU market.</p>
<p>In answer to a question, spokesman Nicolaas Wegter said Commissioner Hans van den Broek was astonished by Croatian President Franjo Tudjman's award for military actions to a former Bosnian Croat army commander indicted by the U.N. War crimes tribunal.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/96/1134: Accounting: new European approach on statutory auditing to be launched.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1135: Fisheries: Commission proposal for TACs and quotas for 1997.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1140: New trade agreements signed between the European Union and the Faroe Islands.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/323: Speech by Commissioner Sir Leon Brittan to the opening ceremony of the WTO ministerial.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/324: Speech by Commissioner Edith Cresson at at international conference on &quot;second chance&quot; schools.</p>
<p>- ME96/9.12: Midday Express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G155">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
