<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244564" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: ONIC seen juggling French barley export data.</title>
<headline>ONIC seen juggling French barley export data.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>French cereals office ONIC plans to cut its estimate for barley exports to countries outside the European Union by 100,000 tonnes and raise its forecast for exports within the EU by a similar amount, grain industry sources said on Monday.</p>
<p>A draft ONIC report prepared for publication on Thursday predicts France will export 1.1 million tonnes of barley to non-EU countries in 1996/97 (July/June) against the 1.2 million forecast last month and 221,000 tonnes exported in 1995/96.</p>
<p>ONIC now puts barley exports to other EU countries at 2.2 million tonnes against 2.1 million last month, the sources said.  </p>
<p>France exported 2.244 million tonnes of barley to its EU partners in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The ONIC draft targets barley carryover stocks of 1.375 million tonnes at end-June 1997, against the 1.285 million forecast last month and 629,000 tonnes at the end of June 1996.</p>
<p>ONIC is slightly raising its estimate for the 1996 barley crop to 9.488 million tonnes from 9.473 million last month.</p>
<p>This represents a sharp jump from 7.739 million tonnes of barley produced last year.</p>
<p>ONIC raises its estimate for the delivered crop to 6.890 million tonnes from last month's forecast of 6.830 million.</p>
<p>The figures were drawn up by an industry panel for official publication on December 12 and remain subject to confirmation.</p>
<p>-- Paris newsroom +331 4221 5432</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
