<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244626" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS UPDATE - DEC 9.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - GREEK FINANCIAL NEWS UPDATE - DEC 9.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Leading stories in the Greek financial press:</p>
<p>ISOTIMIA</p>
<p>--The finance ministry is on the trail of what could be a massive scandal involving insider trading on bonds and interest rates before official announcements, confidential sources say.</p>
<p>IMERISIA</p>
<p>--The government has decided to take the second step in the partial privatisation of the Greek telecoms organisation OTE, with the offer of a further 7.0-12 percent share package, at the same time sending a message that denationalisations will be a basic tool of economic policy.</p>
<p>--This week will see the first change in the banking sector with the contract for the sale of the Bank of Attica most probably being signed on Thursday. The agreements for the Bank of Crete and the reform of the National and Commercial Bank Groups is expected to speedily follow.</p>
<p>--The development ministry is preparing to intervene in the market as the farmers' blockade begins to have an effect on prices.</p>
<p>--The national economy ministry's intentions regarding a new administration for the stock exchange is expected to become known today, following a meeting with National Economcy and Finance Minister Yannos Papandoniou and bourse president Manolis Xanthakis.</p>
<p>--Radical changes also expected at the Agricultural Bank from the new board, in an attempt to give the bank's uninspired course a kick-start.</p>
<p>KATHIMERINI (Sunday)</p>
<p>--The fall of inflation to below 8.0 percent in the first time in 23 years - to 7.7 percent - has the government confident that December inflation can fall further to between 7.3-7.5 percent. These forecasts, however, are dependent on developments in the ongoing farmers' blockade, which will continue for the moment.</p>
<p>--Business circles, however, believe that the November inflation rate of 7.7 percent is simply the first indication that efforts must be stepped up and an austere economic policy followed.</p>
<p>--There will be a radical change to the administrative staff of the state's banks, mutual funds and capital markets, sources say. The governent appears determined to place new people in crucial banking positions to lead a change in attitudes in state-run organisations.</p>
<p>--Make business not war, says Turkish magnate Rhami Koc. Koc says cooperation between Greek and Turkish businessmen can contribute to the economic development of the two countries and be a defining factor in the overall improvement of bilateral relations.</p>
<p>TO VIMA (Sunday)</p>
<p>--The government is adamant it will not give in to the protesting farmers, with Prime Minister Costas Simitis reportedly saying he would prefer to see the government fall than retreat. The government believes that to give in now would open the gates for a series of strikes and demands that would scuttle the economic policy decided on.</p>
<p>--The famrers' road block were to be expected as the government's entire agricultural policy was geared to such an explosion. Cotton farmers for years based up to 80 percent of their income on Community support. New procedures have forced producers to face the moment of truth, with subsidies now only covering 40 percent of income and expected shortly to drop to nil.</p>
<p>--Dozens of cases of tax evasion - mainly involving non-payment of VAT - will be revealed shortly on the order of Deputy Finance Minister George Drys.</p>
<p>--The battle of the C.V.s is underway at OTE following last week's rejection of the leading candidate. Now the spotlight falls on the remaining three candidates.</p>
<p>--Maria Petrakis, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
