<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244693" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH-Budget bills update for Dec 9 - overview.</title>
<headline>RTRS-CANBERRA WATCH-Budget bills update for Dec 9 - overview.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government's schedule for the Senate's processing of budget bills has again proven optimistic.</p>
<p>The bulk of the contentious budget bills -- those that may need the uncertain support of Greens or Independents to pass -- are queued up behind the Tesltra privatisation bill to be dealt with this week, the last week of sittings for 1996.</p>
<p>These bills contain doubtful measures worth about A$1.7 billion in 1997/98, the first full year of operation for most of them.</p>
<p>The first two bills, which tighten social security payments, were supposed to be debated from Monday afternoon with completion on Monday night.</p>
<p>In fact, the Telstra (Dilution of Public Ownership) Bill is not yet finished.</p>
<p>Labor, the Greens and, especially, the Democrats are in a very bad mood over the likely passage of the Telstra and they might easily force a prolonged debate before the final vote.</p>
<p>They could even delay the Telstra vote until Tuesday.</p>
<p>All of this is pressing the budget bills up against the Friday deadline. The only slack in the schedule is that all the contentious bills are supposed to be over by Thursday night, leaving Friday with only uncontentious bills.</p>
<p>But at this stage it is looking increasingly likley that the final value of Peter Costello's Australian budget tightening will be determined in the small hours of Saturday morning.</p>
<p>THE BIG PICTURE</p>
<p>The measures at stake are about a quarter of the budget.</p>
<p>The government announced in August measures that would cut the 1997/98 budget by A$7.2 billion, presumably the first instalment on the A$8 billion fiscal tightening that Treasurer Peter Costello promised in March.</p>
<p>Of those measures, about A$2 billion became doubtful in following weeks when the Labor and Democrats parties said they would, or might, oppose them, leaving the government relying on the Greens or, more realistically, Independents.</p>
<p>Of the doubtful measures, one major item worth about A$300 million (the university student charges bill) has now definitely passed, leaving something like A$1.7 billion outstanding and still doubtful.</p>
<p>One big item in the still-doubtfuls box -- the measure to exclude newly arrived migrants from social security -- was fairly well rejected last week, with a threatened cost to the budget of A$130 million in 1997/98.</p>
<p>But the government says it will send it back and ask the Senate to think again.</p>
<p>This is the first budget bill to be dealt with this week, immediately after the final Telstra vote. Contentious measures:</p>
<p>-- Activity tests. The government wants to impose several new requirements on people receiving unemployment benefits, such as a tighter definition of the sort of job they can reject and still receive money. Value: A$106 million in 1997/98, A$116 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Social security advances. In some circumstances, the Social Security Department will pay in advance. The government wants to restrict this. Value: A$28 million in 1997/98, minus A$2.5 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Earnings credits. Social security beneficiaries can sometimes spread out income they earn to reduce the effect on their entitlements. The government wants to end this. Value: A$76 million in 1997/98, A$83 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>SOCIAL SECURITY LEGISLATION AMENDMENT (FURTHER BUDGET AND OTHER MEASURES) BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill was also listed for Monday but will probably now be delayed until Tuesday. Contentious measures:</p>
<p>-- Superannuation means testing. The government wants to count retirement savings in means testing for social security beneficiaries aged between 55 and retirement age. Value: A$93 million in 1997/98, A$65 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Rent assistance. The government wants to reduce social security for some single people in share accommodation. Value: A$33 million in 1997/98, A$41 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>NATIONAL HEALTH (BUDGET MEASURES) AMENDMENT BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill was listed for Tuesday afternoon. Measures:  </p>
<p>-- Pharmaceutical benefit scheme changes. The government wants people to pay more for each prescription. Value: A$134 million in 1997/98, A$147 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>TAXATION LAWS AMENDMENT BILL (NO.3), 1996</p>
<p>This important bill arrived in the Senate too late to be dealt with this year under normal rules, but the non-government parties have accepted that an exception should be made and it has been listed for Wednesday morning. Measures: </p>
<p>-- Research and development tax break legislation. Companies can deduct 150 percent of R&amp;D spending from taxable income. The government wants to cut this to 125 percent. Value: A$430 million in 1997/98, A$440 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Research and development syndication. The government says the syndication rules encourage exploitation of its tax break with false R&amp;D projects, so it wants to abolish the syndication. Value: A$288 million in 1997/98, $400 million in 1999/00.  </p>
<p>-- Medical expenses rebate. People whose medical expenses exceed A$1,000 a year get a tax rebate, depending on their income. The government wants to raise the income threshold. Value: A$26 million in 1997/98, A$24 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Co-operatives financing tax break. The government wants to end this small tax break, mostly affecting primary producers. Value: A$2 million in 1997/98, A$6 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>CHILDCARE LEGISLATION AMENDMENT BILL, 1996</p>
<p>Much progress has already been made on this bill. It is now listed for Wednesday. Contentious measure:  </p>
<p>-- Childcare subsidies. The government wants to cut them. Value: A$45 million in 1997/98, A$53 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>SOCIAL SECURITY (NEWLY ARRIVED RESIDENTS' WAITING PERIODS) BILL, 1996.</p>
<p>The Senate has already dealt with this bill, amending it heavily last month. But the government plans to send it back to the Senate on Thursday for a rethink. Contentious measure:  </p>
<p>-- Migrants' social security waiting period. The government wanted to generally exclude migrants from social security for two years after arrival. Value before amendment: A$140 million in 1997/98, A$194 million in 1999/00. The Senate amendments cost most of the bill's value, according to government estimates: A$130 million in 1997/98, A$400 million over four years.</p>
<p>STUDENT AND YOUTH ASSISTANCE (WAITING PERIOD) BILL, 1996.</p>
<p>The last of the contentious budget bills, and one of the smallest, this is listed for Thursday. Contentious measure:  </p>
<p>-- Student income support (&quot;Austudy&quot;). The government wants to tighten eligibility, in part by excluding younger people. Value: A$63 million in 1997/98, A$78 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>BOUNTY LEGISLATION AMENDMENT BILL, 1996</p>
<p>This bill is not expected in the Senate until next year, although a Senate committee has reported on it, Labor and the Democrats expressing their displeasure.  </p>
<p>-- Bounties abolition. The government wants to abolish, or bring forward the abolition of, bounties on computers, shipbuilding, machine tools and books. Value: A$36 million in 1997/98, A$49 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>AGED CARE MEASURES</p>
<p>The government's aged care bill is not expected to appear even in the lower house before next year. It should include:</p>
<p>-- Nursing home charges. The government wants people to pay more. Value: A$125 million in 1997/98, A$194 million in 1999/00.  </p>
<p>CHILDCARE REGULATION</p>
<p>This measure will be effected by a regulation (made by a minister), which parliament might seek to override.</p>
<p>-- Childcare rebate limit. The government seeks a limit to entitlement to the childcare tax rebate to 50 hours a week. Value: A$30 million in 1997/98, A$36 million in 1999/00.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273-2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
