<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244733" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian wool prices expected to firm.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian wool prices expected to firm.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian wool prices are expected to firm at sales this week in Sydney, Melbourne and Fremandle, Wesfarmers Dalgety Ltd said in its weekly market preview.</p>
<p>Wesfarmers this view was based on signs of strengthening for some wools last week when the eastern market indicator rose four cents to 556 cents a kg, clean. About 143,800 bales will be offered, the largest offering of the season to date.</p>
<p>Wesfarmers said last week's stable prices were encouraging as sales this week represent the final opportunity buyers have to complete orders for December and January delivery.  </p>
<p>Wesfarmers said stockpile sales were relatively large last week, indicating forward trading over the next few months.</p>
<p>Sharp grower resistance, evidenced last week by escalating clip withdrawals prior to sale, was also expected to prevent significant downside in the market.</p>
<p>However, the exceptionally large rostered quantity for sale would test the strength of these positive factors, restricting upside and keeping prices at current levels, Wesfarmers said.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
