<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244717" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Listless Australian dlr ends treading water.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Listless Australian dlr ends treading water.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar took the opportunity to catch its breath on Monday after the volatility of last week, opting for a lacklustre day constrained to a narrow range to start the week off, traders said.</p>
<p>And although there was some important labour force data due later in the week, the local market would probably be content to follow offshore leads for the time being, they said.</p>
<p>By 4.30 p.m. (0530 GMT) the Australian dollar was sitting at US$0.7983/88, almost unchanged from an opening US$0.7982/87, although it was up on its Friday close of US$0.7950/55.</p>
<p>On the day, the unit traded a US$0.7982/87 range.  </p>
<p>The story was the same on the crosses -- the unit holding steady after recouping some of Friday's local losses in offshore trade as the U.S. market steadied on the weaker than expected November payrolls data.</p>
<p>In trade weighted terms, the dollar ended unchanged from its opening level of 59.2, having closed last week at 58.8.</p>
<p>Against the yen, the capping of the U.S. dollar above 113 held the Australian dollar to just above 90 yen. Late in local trade the unit was buying 90.19/29 yen, level with an early 90.19/29, and up on the local close last week of 89.10/20.  </p>
<p>&quot;I think it's just consolidating after the falls of last week,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's very quiet ... there's nothing happening.&quot;</p>
<p>There was a lack of activity and volume on the day, and with only a few pieces of major data due out ahead of Christmas, offshore would continue to lead the local market, traders said.</p>
<p>Good exporter demand was seen supporting the unit on any dips to US$0.7950/60, while the area just above US$0.8000 was expected to provide enough resistance to cap the unit, although US$0.8040 was seen as possible ahead of local employment data on Thursday.  </p>
<p>The November employment report, seen by the market as the most important piece of Australian data left this year, is expected to show the labour market remaining soft, and unemployment holding up near 9.0 percent.</p>
<p>Forecasts of economists surveyed by Reuters centre on a 10,000 rise in employment levels and an unemployment rate of 8.7 percent.</p>
<p>A forward indicator of the labour market, the ANZ job advertisement series, was released on Monday and showed a 2.1 percent rise in November.  </p>
<p>ANZ chief economist Saul Eslake cautioned against reading too much into the first rise in four months, and said it was still likely that unemployment would reach, and perhaps exceed, 9.0 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank private sector credit data, also released on Monday, showed a 0.7 percent rise in Ocotber, to be 11.3 percent higher over the year.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, the major event on the day is a dinnertime address by Federal Treasurer Peter Costello at the Australian Business Economists seminar in Sydney.  </p>
<p>September quarter balance of payments data due Tuesday are expected to have little market impact, as the contribution of net exports to gross domestic product was contained in last week's National Accounts, but the data will help economists finalise forecasts for Wednesday's net foreign debt.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
