<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244896" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: Quiet welcome planned for N.Korean defectors.</title>
<headline>Quiet welcome planned for N.Korean defectors.</headline>
<byline>Brian Williams</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>The biggest group of North Korean defectors since the 1950-53 Korean War headed for asylum in Seoul on Monday from Hong Kong after their dramatic escape through China raised fears of a surge in refugees.</p>
<p>In a sign of changing times and growing nervousness about what a North Korean collapse could mean for Seoul's economy, only a quiet welcome was planned for the group of 17.</p>
<p>The case also puts an unwelcome spotlight on Hong Kong as a refugee centre for North Koreans, just as the British colony enters the final months of its handover to China, one of Pyongyang's few allies.</p>
<p>&quot;These cases are not the sort of problem they (British authorities in Hong Kong) need when they're tidying up the house,&quot; one Western diplomat said. &quot;Its an awkward problem.&quot;</p>
<p>The 17 escapees, who sneaked into Hong Kong 16 days ago after a month-long trek across China, were due to arrive on a scheduled Korean Airlines flight, a foreign ministry spokesman said.</p>
<p>Among them are 16 members of a single family, whose flight was financed by relatives in the United States, and a security guard.</p>
<p>The Korean clan has been joined in Hong Kong by two other North Koreans, at least one an intelligence operative, seeking asylum, Seoul media reported on Sunday. The latest two are not on the flight to Seoul.</p>
<p>After a brief meeting with the press at a restricted part of Seoul Airport where there is no public access, the group will be whisked away for days of questioning to determine that none of them are bogus defectors.</p>
<p>The group moved from one safe house to another in their journey down the length of China, easily finding refuge among the estimated two million ethnic Koreans who live in the country.</p>
<p>South Korea also once rolled out the red carpet for communist defectors, mostly escaping solo or in groups of twos or threes, but the latest bold escape by a bloc of 17 has raised fears that North Korea may be cracking up.</p>
<p>Recent defectors have been weak and emaciated, reflecting near-famine conditions in much of the North that is struggling to survive the effects of floods and industrial collapse.</p>
<p>An uncontrolled refugee exodus from the North, signalling a breakdown of internal controls -- similar to the German experience -- is part of a nightmare scenario for Seoul, which would be left to pick up the pieces from any collapse in Pyongyang.</p>
<p>The North Korean family will be offered asylum and a modest payment by South Korea.</p>
<p>Seoul media have speculated each person will get about 10 million won ($12,000) to help them settle and find work, a sum that will not go far in high-cost South Korea.</p>
<p>The South Korean government is drawing up plans for reception centres for North Koreans -- half-way houses that will offer immediate shelter and vocational training -- and the first could be ready next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
