<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244854" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks advance to firm close.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks advance to firm close.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks advanced steadily to close higher on Monday despite concerns about anti-speculation measures for the territory's booming property market, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;We expected to see this bounce in the morning, but at any rate this pick-up was expected,&quot; said Glenn Lesko, head of equities trading at HG Asia. &quot;If it were not for the government's (possible) anti-speculation measures, we would see a stronger move up.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index put on 41.50 points to end at 13,144.23.  </p>
<p>Trading in the afternoon was relatively calm after wide swings in the index in the morning.</p>
<p>Turnover was robust at HK$8.54 billion, though well below Friday's HK$13.80 billion.</p>
<p>On Monday, Hong Kong's Financial Secretary Donald Tsang said he had assigned a team to study a recent uptrend in property prices and look at speculative activity.</p>
<p>The comments seemed to dampen investor sentiment in the morning but brokers were sceptical the outgoing British colonial government would be able to initiate severe enough action to curtail the price boom.  </p>
<p>Utilities shares led the market while properties underperformed all other sectors.</p>
<p>Henderson Land eased HK$0.25 to HK$75.75 and Cheung Kong also fell HK$0.25 to HK$66.75.</p>
<p>Sun Hung Kai Property recovered from earlier losses to end HK$0.25 ahead at HK$96.75, buoyed by news its sale of luxury flats at the weekend had gone well.</p>
<p>HK Electric gained HK$0.50 to HK$26.25 and China Light &amp; Power rose HK$0.20 to HK$33.70 following a statement from HK Electric denying market rumours of a merger of the two companies.  </p>
<p>Blue chip industrial Johnson Electric, which announced a robust 38.3 percent rise in earnings on good gains in sales and profit margins, added HK$0.45 to HK$20.15.</p>
<p>Newcomer and China property developer Nam Fong International, which debuted at HK$3.80, was the day's second most active stock, ending at HK$3.675 on heavy trade of HK$635.85 million.</p>
<p>Trading in Hang Seng Index futures also picked up in the afternoon. The December contract ended up 105 points at 13,185, a 41-point premium to the cash market, with 20,500 contracts traded. -- Kathleen Kearney (852) 2843 6933</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
