<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244823" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: RESEARCH ALERT - Great Eagle to outperform HSI.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Great Eagle to outperform HSI.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Lehman Brothers Asia Holdings Ltd said on Monday it had issued an &quot;outperform&quot; recommendation on Great Eagle Holdings.</p>
<p>Lehman said the property group was set to outperform the Hang Seng Index on growing contributions from its hotel operations, the recent resolution of key issues holding up a major redevelopment project in Hong Kong's Mongkok district and the likely spin-off of its office holdings.</p>
<p>The office spin-off was likely to take place after completion of the 1.8 million square foot Mongkok development, which is expected to generate a profit of HK$2.8 billion for Great Eagle, Lehman said.</p>
<p>Great Eagle engages in property development and investment in Hong Kong and has worldwide property operations.</p>
<p>Lehman's property analysts Michael Leary and Patrick Chau said the company's prospects have been greatly enhanced by two hotel acquisitions -- one in Melbourne and the other in Toronto -- as well as the upturn in Hong Kong's grade A office rents.</p>
<p>Lehman said Great Eagle's net asset value was revised to HK$45 to reflect its enhanced capital value. It gave no comparative figure.  </p>
<p>Earnings per share estimates have been revised to HK$2.15 for fiscal 1996 and HK$2.45 for fiscal 1997, it said.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6352</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BERM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I85000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
