<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244957" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: WTO told liberalised trade will safeguard peace.</title>
<headline>WTO told liberalised trade will safeguard peace.</headline>
<byline>Robert Evans</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trade officials from 128 countries started a landmark meeting here on Monday to ringing appeals for a greater opening up of global commerce.</p>
<p>Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong, opening the five-day Ministerial Conference of the World Trade Organisation (WTO), told the officials that liberalisation meant more trade, more investment and more peace.</p>
<p>&quot;This will mean even higher standards of living for all. Growing economic prosperity will in turn lead to greater international security and stability. This is not fantasy, but a vision within reach,&quot; he declared.</p>
<p>WTO Director-General Renato Ruggiero urged the ministers to agree on key sticking points despite their political sensitivity.</p>
<p>The Singapore WTO meeting, which aims to draw up a blueprint for global trade in the 21st Century, should send a clear message to the world, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be a firm message about our determination to fight the marginalisation of people and regions, and about the power of trade to promote growth which allows governments to address problems of distribution,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Ruggiero said an Information Technology Agreement (ITA) to free trade in information and telecommunications products was critical.</p>
<p>&quot;In the economy of the 21st century, knowledge, like water, will be an essential resource,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;By liberalising information technologies we can educate our people on a scale unimaginable 10 or 20 years ago, empowering them to compete in the global economy,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the human dimension of globalisation. This is why liberalisation is the wellspring of progress for all the world's peoples.&quot;</p>
<p>There are deep disagreements over the ITA -- what it should include, how far it should go and how soon it should come into force. The United States is pushing hard for an ITA pact this week that would cut tariffs by 2000.</p>
<p>Acting U.S. Trade Representative Charlene Barshefsky urged the WTO ministers to seize the opportunity on an infotechnology pact, saying it would help put less costly technologies in the hands of businesses around the globe.</p>
<p>&quot;That's why we must reach agreement this week,&quot; Barshefsky said. &quot;Remaining issues are ripe for decision. We have an historic opportunity to eliminate tariffs on these products. We must seize it.&quot;</p>
<p>The European Union differs with Washington over just what products should be covered by a deal, estimated to be worth up to $1 trillion a year in world trade, arguing that it is partly designed to favour U.S. goods and does not take EU interests fully into account.</p>
<p>Goh told reporters he believed some kind of ITA agreement would be made before the meeting ends on Friday, but it would not include &quot;zero tariffs by 2000&quot;.</p>
<p>In his speech, Goh said the vision of peace and prosperity would fade quickly unless everyone worked together.</p>
<p>Developing countries needed time to absorb the wide-ranging accords on trade in goods, services, textiles, farm produce and intellectual property reached in the 1986-93 Uruguay Round negotiations that also created the WTO, Goh said.</p>
<p>And he warned the big powers, who are keen to get controversial &quot;new issues&quot; on to the WTO agenda, not to push the emerging economies too hard.</p>
<p>The key such issue is linking trade with labour standards, on which Washington particularly is keen and most developing nations are not. They see such links as a Western attempt to take away their advantage of cheap labour.</p>
<p>&quot;Realistically, global trade liberalisation has to progress in an incremental manner, even though some of us may prefer quantum leaps,&quot; Goh said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
