<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="244909" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam steel output hits record, glut emerges.</title>
<headline>Vietnam steel output hits record, glut emerges.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam has produced a record 1.6 million tonnes of steel this year, a threefold increase from 1995, the official Vietnam News Agency (VNA) said on Monday.</p>
<p>VNA quoted Ho Nghia Dung, director of the state-owned Vietnam Steel Corporation (VSC), as saying that an industry master plan was targeting output of 2.5-3.0 million tonnes by the turn of the century and 7.5-8.0 million by 2010.</p>
<p>The increase in steel output will go some way to meeting domestic demand, which has been boosted by a construction boom.</p>
<p>Vietnam imported 800,000 tonnes of steel in 1995 and, according to a recent newspaper report it had matched that level by the end of October this year despite a government-imposed curb on sales of steel from abroad.</p>
<p>However, the semi-official Vietnam Investment Review said last month that a glut of steel in the domestic market, largely the result of cheap imports, had begun to push production lower.</p>
<p>It said more than 400,000 tonnes of steel was sitting in store houses, more than half of it stock held by the VSC.</p>
<p>&quot;Though the government banned steel imports in March 1996, the market is still saturated because of surplus and breaches of the ban,&quot; the weekly said, adding that steel producers in Vietnam had been obliged to sell at &quot;war prices&quot;.</p>
<p>It said the steel industry was also faced with a downturn in new construction, which has emerged because some recent hotel and office complex projects have not performed as well as expected.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
