<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245103" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Bangert Pontier overhauls Dutch &quot;no-lose&quot; options.</title>
<headline>Bangert Pontier overhauls Dutch &quot;no-lose&quot; options.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>Dutch securities house Bank Bangert Pontier said on Monday it had revamped an innovative &quot;can't lose&quot; derivatives product it launched last year in such a way as to exempt it from income tax.</p>
<p>The securities house is urging holders of its ESCAPE (Equity Structured Call and Put Exposure) product to convert to its successor ESCAPE 1.1, which involves the minimum risk exposure required to prevent returns being taxed as investment income.</p>
<p>&quot;Subscription to the new ESCAPE 1.1 is exclusively open to holders of the old ESCAPE on a one-for-one basis,&quot; Bangert Pontier said in a statement.</p>
<p>The ESCAPE 1.1 is an option product aimed at enabling investors to profit fully from a rise in Dutch share prices while protecting them against a market fall.</p>
<p>The product comprises an option on two warrants on the AEX share index -- a call spread warrant and a put spread warrant issued by Britain's Midland Bank.</p>
<p>Bangert said the combination of the two warrants was such that investors would profit fully from a rise in the AEX index during the five-year life of the options and would receive the full value of their original investment if the AEX fell.</p>
<p>ESCAPEs were a halfway house between saving and investing.</p>
<p>When it first launched ESCAPEs last December, Bangert said returns would be tax-exempt because capital gains on investments in shares, bonds and options are not taxed in the Netherlands.</p>
<p>But the finance ministry said later ESCAPE was different because there was no risk of loss.</p>
<p>&quot;In view of this standpoint, Bank Bangert Pontier consulted with the Finance Ministry to find out the extent of risk an option such as ESCAPE should bear in order to avoid being qualified as an interest-bearing investment,&quot; Bangert said.</p>
<p>The new ESCAPE 1.1 had been modelled on the outcome of these talks and included a sufficient element of risk, it said.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to be qualified an (untaxed) investment product, the risk should amount to at least seven percent, below that percentage, the product is considered a loan on which profits are taxed,&quot; Bangert said.</p>
<p>The issue price of the ESCAPE 1.1 is 5,350 guilders, while investors will receive back at least the amount of their original investment in last year's ESCAPE, 4,853.50 guilders, in case the AEX falls during the five-year period of the product.</p>
<p>Banger said the finance ministry had agreed not to tax the ESCAPE 1.1, as the risk involved was over seven percent.</p>
<p>Subscription for the one-to-one conversion of old ESCAPEs into ESCAPE 1.1s will be open to holders of the old products from Monday to 1500 GMT December 13.</p>
<p>There are currently 23,269 ESCAPEs outstanding, Bangert said.</p>
<p>The issue price of the ESCAPE 1.1 has been set at 5,350 guilders, the old ESCAPE's closing price on November 29.</p>
<p>The difference between the new issue price and the original launch price of 4,853.50 guilders was liable for tax, Bangert cautioned.</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam newsroom +31 20 504 5000, Fax +31 20 504 5040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
