<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245171" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: PEARSON BUYS TML PUBLICATIONS STAKE.</title>
<headline>PEARSON BUYS TML PUBLICATIONS STAKE.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>International media group Pearson plc has bought a 50 percent stake in Times Media Ltd's Business Day and Financial Mail publications for 87.5 million rand, it was announced on Monday.    </p>
<p>Also included in the arrangement is a television production company, African Business Channel (ABC), which currently produces a nightly business news programme on South African national television. ABC is already a 50/50 partnership between TML and FT Television.</p>
<p>Pearson, owner of U.K newspaper the Financial Times, said in a published announcement a new company called African Business Media Ltd will be formed to house the various interests.    </p>
<p>Pearson said the acquisition would be &quot;earnings enhancing&quot; from the beginning and should be completed around the end of the year.</p>
<p>It said there would be strong liaison between the South African publications and the Financial Times, which would lend its international skills and network to assist the further development of Business Day and Financial Mail.</p>
<p>Business Day has a daily sale of 40,200 and the Financial Mail, a weekly publication, a sale of 31,100, the announcement said.</p>
<p>The deal follows months of speculation that Pearson will take a stake in TML's financial publications. </p>
<p>The potential deal was recently threatened by publishing group Caxton Ltd which last week won an interdict against TML parent Omni Media Corporation Ltd to prevent it from publishing magazines, suburban newspapers and &quot;free-sheets&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
