<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245152" id="root" date="1996-12-09" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Bonn sick pay law flounders after pay deal.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Bonn sick pay law flounders after pay deal.</headline>
<byline>Mark John</byline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-09</dateline>
<text>
<p>A law designed to spearhead a cut in German labour costs was thrown into doubt on Monday after an admission by German metal and engineering employers that they were not in a position to enforce it.</p>
<p>The law, which from last October allows companies to cut sick pay entitlements by 20 percent, was originally seen as a 12 billion mark ($7.82 billion) gift from Chancellor Helmut Kohl to employers who have long bemoaned Germany's high labour costs.</p>
<p>But with mass protests by German workers discouraging more and more companies from putting the law into effect, it now looks like a booby-trap that could ultimately blow up in the face of both German industry and Kohl's government.</p>
<p>Gesamtmetall, the metal and engineering employers' group, acknowledged on Sunday it would have to live with a regional wage deal signed in the sector last week that did not implement the sick pay law.</p>
<p>Beleaguered Gesamtmetall president Werner Stumpfe said that although the deal in the northern state of Lower Saxony was &quot;very disappointing&quot;, it accepted that it would probably set the tone for settlements in other regions.</p>
<p>The admission prompted a jubilant IG Metall, the huge metal and engineering trade union that has led resistance to the law, to repeat its call on Monday for sick pay to be maintained at full salary for all of the 3.2 million workers it represents.</p>
<p>The opposition Social Democrats (SPD) meanwhile promised that they would use any further such spurning of the law to seek a reversal of the bill in the Bonn parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;This idiocy must be put aside,&quot; SPD parliamentary leader Rudolf Scharping was quoted as saying in the Cologne-based &quot;Express&quot; newspaper, adding that such an initiative could start at the beginning of next year.</p>
<p>While such a move would have little impact on the overall austerity package brought in by Kohl to ensure entry to the single European currency in 1999, it would be seen as an embarrassing political defeat.</p>
<p>For employers, it would mean that one of the most ambitious attempts to secure a reduction in German labour costs would have foundered within a matter of months.</p>
<p>The set-back for the law in the metal and engineering sectors has been mirrored by similar retreats in the food, chemical and other industries.</p>
<p>The latest victory for workers was the decision by the German unit of Swiss food giant Nestle SA on Sunday to continue full sick payments after weeks of strikes by employees in its Hamburg and Berlin plants.</p>
<p>But the next test for the law starts on Monday as Germany's banking employers -- the only ones so far to have imposed the cuts successfully -- meet trade unions to find a way of averting new protests threatened by normally peaceable bank staff.</p>
<p>Emboldened by the back-down in the metal sector, union leaders going into the talks said they would launch further protests as soon as this week if the cuts were not immediately reversed.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom +49 69 756525 ($1=1.5338 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-09"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-09"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
