<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245202" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: FEATURE-Canadian gallery makes Renoir a movable feast.</title>
<headline>FEATURE-Canadian gallery makes Renoir a movable feast.</headline>
<byline>Russell Blinch</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dream had lived in the mind of curator Colin Bailey for more than five years: to assemble one of the greatest collections ever of Impressionist master Renoir.</p>
<p>After some bartering and cajoling with the world's great museums, private galleries and individual collectors, Bailey is about to see his dream come true. An exhibition of some 65 works entitled &quot;Renoir's Portraits: Impressions of an Age,&quot; opens on June 27 and runs through Sept. 14 at The National Gallery of Canada in Ottawa.</p>
<p>It travels to the Art Institute of Chicago for a run from next Oct. 21 to Jan. 4, 1998 and then to the Kimbell Art Museum in Fort Worth, Texas from Feb. 8 to April 26, 1998.</p>
<p>Bailey, British-born chief curator of Canada's premier art gallery, said the exhibition was the culmination of many years of hard work. And in some respects the results exceeded even his expectations.</p>
<p>&quot;The works are so important that it becomes a very big undertaking,&quot; Bailey said in a telephone interview. &quot;I sometimes feel humbled at how successful we've been.&quot;</p>
<p>Some of the paintings such as those from Japan have never been on public display. Others, as in the case of works from Russia, have not been seen in the West for several decades.</p>
<p>REUNITING RENOIR WORKS</p>
<p>Bailey went to great lengths to reunite works that Renoir meant to be seen together. He obtained the 1871 portrait of Madame Marie Octavie Bernier from the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York for the exhibition and traveled to Dresden, Germany, where he managed to obtain from a gallery the painting of her husband, Capt. Edouard Bernier. &quot;There is certainly a chemical reaction to bringing works together that cannot normally be seen under the same roof,&quot; Bailey said.</p>
<p>Edmond Pillsbury, director of Fort Worth's Kimbell museum, who has worked with Bailey on the collection, said it would yield a lot of new information about Renoir and boost the artist's already towering reputation. &quot;The selection of the art will be staggering,&quot; Pillsbury predicted.</p>
<p>Pierre Auguste Renoir, who was born in 1841 and died in 1919, was considered the most accessible of the 19th century Impressionist school. He was loved by many for his romantic visions, particularly the women and crowd scenes he painted.</p>
<p>Many scholars have been fascinated by his portraits, especially those painted under commission. Renoir took his commissioned portraits as seriously as his other works, leaving his mark as an avant-garde artist of the day.</p>
<p>THE LEADING IMPRESSIONIST PORTRAITIST</p>
<p>&quot;Renoir is the leading portraitist of the Impressionists and some of the works are absolutely sublime,&quot; said Douglas Druick, curator of paintings, prints and drawing at the Art Institute of Chicago.</p>
<p>The works in the collection range from 1862 to 1917 and have been gathered from a variety of sources. They include rare works and some that are better known such as &quot;Madame Georges Charpentier and her Children&quot; from the Metropolitan.</p>
<p>It was the scholarship that the exhibition would produce that Bailey used most often as an argument when convincing galleries and collectors to lend their precious works.</p>
<p>Bailey has been fascinated by the deeper meanings behind the portraits and has been eager to learn more about the sitters that Renoir portrayed -- sometimes even from the direct descendants themselves. He traveled to Japan, France, Russia and the United States to talk personally to museums and collectors in a dogged effort to obtain the best works.</p>
<p>&quot;It's an article of faith that you have to see everything in person and it's also a great pleasure,&quot; Bailey said.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau 416-941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
