<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245412" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Texas Instruments to cut capital spending.</title>
<headline>Texas Instruments to cut capital spending.</headline>
<dateline>SAN FRANCISCO 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Texas Instruments Inc Vice Chairman Pat Weber said Tuesday his company plans to reduce its capital expenditure &quot;significantly&quot; in 1997.</p>
<p>Weber also told investors at the Montgomery Securities Tech Week conference that Texas Instruments plans to beef up its profitable digital signal-processing chip business. The company also intends to bring stability to its computer memory chip business and to enter new markets such as networking, he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;While we faced a tough year in 1996, we want to look at the bright side. The 80 percent price decline in memory chips in the past year is what's driving growth in the personal computer industry,&quot; Weber said.</p>
<p>To increase profits Texas Instruments plans to sell more digital signal-processing (DSP) chips -- specialized microprocessors that can handle sound and video and all types of consumer electronics. Much of the company's profits came from DSP chips this year, Weber said.  </p>
<p>Weber also said Texas Instruments was determined to reduce the volatility of its memory chip business. The company will seek more joint ventures with Asian companies in building and operating memory chip plants as a way of sharing the risk, he said.</p>
<p>To enter new markets, Texas Instruments plans to develop more semiconductor products for telecommunications equipment, computer networking, computer monitors and advanced displays.</p>
<p>Weber said Texas Instruments plans to reduce its capital expenditures significantly in 1997 because it spent so much in recent years. He declined to specify by how much the company would lower its outlays next year. In 1996, it spent $2.3 billion.</p>
<p>Weber declined to comment when asked by an investor whether the company's defense business was up for sale. &quot;We don't comment on rumors,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN FRANCISCO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
