<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245459" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Nickles hopes US Senate passes budget by deadline.</title>
<headline>Nickles hopes US Senate passes budget by deadline.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Assistant Senate Majority Leader Don Nickles said on Tuesday that the Senate will try to pass the budget by its April 15 statutory deadline.</p>
<p>He also said he hoped that the balanced budget amendment to the Constitution would come up &quot;very early&quot; in the new congressional session.</p>
<p>Nickles (R-Okla.) noted to a National Association of Manufacturers' breakfast that in the last Congress, the balanced budget amendment was one vote short of passing the Senate, and that in the new Congress, Senate Republicans have gained two additional seats.  </p>
<p>Nickles echoed comments of his colleagues by saying Republicans would not take the lead on adjusting the Consumer Price Index, and the Clinton Administration and Democrats in Congress must support any changes. A special commission reported last week that the CPI overstates inflation by 1.1 percent annually.</p>
<p>&quot;Republicans won't march up to do it unless the Administration is willing to go along and Democrats as well,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Nickles also expressed the hope that budget figures from the Congressional Budget Office and the White House's Office of Management and Budget would be &quot;in sync&quot; for negotiations.  </p>
<p>On Social Security, Nickles said there was &quot;merit&quot; in a proposal that would allow people to take a portion of their Social Security and let them invest it. He also said he would like to have product liability reform but that he was not interested in passing a bill that would be vetoed by President Clinton.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
