<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245458" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: ARCO Chemical sets $2.6 bln spending plan.</title>
<headline>ARCO Chemical sets $2.6 bln spending plan.</headline>
<dateline>NEWTOWN SQUARE, Pa. 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>ARCO Chemical Co said Tuesday its directors approved a $2.6 billion capital spending program for the years 1997-2001.</p>
<p>In addition, the company said, its capital spending program for 1996 was increased to reflect the recent acquisition of Olin Corp's isocyanates business.</p>
<p>For 1996, ARCO Chemical's capital spending program is set at $750 million, including amounts allocated for the purchase of Olin's isocyanates business, the company said.</p>
<p>For 1997, $450 million has been budgeted for capital spending for all of the company's businesses, it added.  </p>
<p>About 70 percent -- or $1.8 billion -- of the five-year budget is targeted for growth projects in the company's core urethanes and performance chemicals businesses, ARCO said.</p>
<p>These projects include expansion of the propylene oxide/styrene monomer and butanediol facilities at Channelview, Texas, and construction of new world scale facilities in Rotterdam, the Netherlands, it said.</p>
<p>The remaining 30 percent of the five-year budget is targeted for environmental, health and safety projects, caretaker and maintenance projects, and administrative programs, the company said.</p>
<p>Chief Executive Alan R. Hirsig observed, &quot;Our new capital spending plan will implement ARCO Chemical Co's long-term strategy of focusing on the core (propylene oxide) businesses, integrating an even greater share of our production into value-added derivatives, and maintaining the company's technological superiority.&quot;</p>
<p>The company said it expects to fund its capital spending program through operating cash flows supported by the flexibility it has for either refinancing or additional borrowing. -- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEWTOWN SQUARE, Pa."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
