<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245680" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: BELGIAN POLICE MAKE NEW ARREST IN CHILD SEX CASES.</title>
<headline>BELGIAN POLICE MAKE NEW ARREST IN CHILD SEX CASES.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian police made an arrest on Tuesday in investigations into the disappearance four years ago of nine-year-old Moroccan girl Loubna Benaissa in the Ixelles quarter of Brussels.</p>
<p>The investigating magistrate in Neufchateau, the nerve centre since mid-August of investigations into the disappearance of several children stretching back over the past seven years, said Jacques Genevoix had been arrested.</p>
<p>Genevoix was a suspect early on following Loubna's dissappearance in August 1992 on the way to local shops, but it was only recently that fresh evidence involving him came to light.</p>
<p>The tempo of investigations into the string of missing children got new impetus three months ago following the arrest of rapist Marc Dutroux and the subsequent rescue of two sexually abused young girls and discovery of the bodies of four more.</p>
<p>The parents of dead girls Julie Lejeune, Melissa Russo, Eefje Lambrecks and An Marchal as well as the family of Loubna and the mother of another missing girl, Elizabeth Brichet have led a campaign to make sure the investigations continue.</p>
<p>In Octocer some 250,000 people marched through Brussels in a show of support for the victims and their families.</p>
<p>Dutroux, his second wife Michelle Martin, as well as accused accomplices Michel Nihoul, Michel Lelievre and Mikael Diakostavrianos were arrested in August. They remain in jail while enquiries continue.</p>
<p>To date, no direct link has been established between Dutroux and Genevoix -- although he is known to have been acquainted with Nihoul.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
