<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245682" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Costain revamps, sees debt wipeout.</title>
<headline>Costain revamps, sees debt wipeout.</headline>
<byline>Arindam Nag</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Troubled British engineering and construction firm Costain Group on Tuesday announced 52 million pounds ($86 million) of asset sales and top board changes as it struggled to refocus after bigger-than-expected losses.</p>
<p>The group said it was selling its U.S. coal units to Rencoal Inc of the U.S. for 28.6 million pounds and its one-third stake in the Spitalfields development site to Malaysia's Metacorp for 23.4 million pounds.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the announcement of its interim results, the group has become aware of losses significantly greater than forecast,&quot; the company said in a statement.</p>
<p>Costain, which clinched a last-ditch survival refinancing in July before plunging deeper into the red in the first half, said the sale of its loss-making U.S. Coal arm represented the final stage of its planned exit from U.S. mining.</p>
<p>Its chief executive Alan Lovell said the firm would be in a position to wipe out most of its long-term debts estimated at more than 38 million stg by next January.</p>
<p>&quot;The sale will help us to wipe out a net debt position of 38 million stg as on October end,&quot; Lovell told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We are getting rid of our dead wood. There will be no more sales, the restructuring is over,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Lovell said the group had also arranged for new short-term facilities from UK banks which would facilitate the restructuring and would continue until mid-June but he declined to specify the terms of the facility.</p>
<p>Costain reported half-year losses of 19.2 million stg in the six months to June 30 and Lovell declined to forecast full year results or when the company would return to profit but said 1997 &quot;was crucial.&quot;</p>
<p>However, he said the group was doing &quot;profitably&quot; in its construction and civil engineering businesses.</p>
<p>Lovell is to step down as chief executive but remains in place until a successor has been appointed.</p>
<p>The company's chairman Christopher Benson is also stepping down to be replaced by current deputy chairman Azman Firdaus bin Shafii.</p>
<p>Worse than anticipated geological conditions had hit production at its U.S. Coal unit, which Costain said would result in an 11 million pound lower trading result than expected.</p>
<p>Its Middle East construction businesses had also slipped further into the red and the company said it expected full year losses to be be 4.0 million pounds higher than forecast when it reported half year results about three months ago.</p>
<p>Constain announced that it has conditional option agreements with Indonesian industrialist Hendri Luhur and the Kuwaiti Kharafi family for them to subscribe to 13.4 million shares at 40-50 pence each for a total 5.4 millions stg between March 1 and June 30, 1997. Luhur would become a new shareholder in the group.</p>
<p>Lovell said the group expected to conclude a 750 million stg bridge contract in Penang in a joint deal with Luhur.</p>
<p>He said Costain expected big, long-term construction contracts in southeast Asia, currently witnessing a spate of industrial reforms.</p>
<p>The shares in the company, which has not paid a dividend since November 1991, has been delisted from the London Stock Exchange since November 7, 1996.</p>
<p>Lovell said he expected it to relist once the sale of U.S. Coal, targeted for the end of December, was over.</p>
<p>($1=.6047 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
