<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245707" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - Shell's European refining cuts disappoint.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Shell's European refining cuts disappoint.</headline>
<byline>Tom Ashby</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oil giant Royal Dutch/Shell said on Tuesday it would respond to poor European downstream margins by selling a Swiss oil refinery and closing two European lubricant plants, but analysts said the measures fell well short of the major restructuring the market had been expecting.</p>
<p>Shell said it would sell its Cressier oil refinery in Switzerland, but keep its options open on the Berre l'Etang refinery in southern France, where workers downed tools on Tuesday due to industry-wide cuts.</p>
<p>It also announced a major cost-cutting drive in its European &quot;back-office&quot; operation, which could yield as many savings as the refinery measures, said Paul Skinner, a director of Shell International Petroleum.</p>
<p>But stock market analysts said the measures were not as radical as the market had hoped, and the news knocked five pence off Shell shares in London to 981 pence on Tuesday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not exactly a radical ruthless restructuring of their European downstream business,&quot; said Alan Marshall, oil analyst at Robert Fleming Securities.</p>
<p>Shell's announcement follows more severe European cut-backs by other oil companies such as BP, Mobil and Chevron.</p>
<p>&quot;Compared to the BP/Mobil merger, this is pretty tame and given that Shell's exposure to refining is bigger than theirs, I think the market will be disappointed by this,&quot; Marshall said.</p>
<p>Skinner said the measures addressed the problem of low profitability at the weakest of Shell's 14 European refineries. Shell's dominant 13 percent European market share had hindered the company's efforts to form a larger cooperation with another firm and that talks on this had failed.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not had success and that has been a little bit disappointing and frustrating,&quot; Skinner told journalists. &quot;But if we seem to be doing it unit by unit, I don't think you should preclude the possibility that at some stage a more wide-ranging rationalisation might be a possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the root of the problem was a 10 percent excess capacity in European oil refining, particularly evident in the production of gasoline, of which Europe exports 14 million tonnes per year.</p>
<p>European refining margins had been around $1.50-2.00 per barrel for the past few years, and Skinner did not expect any great improvement in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>He said he hoped to announce a definitive policy towards the Berre l'Etang refinery, which employs 400 people, in January, adding that the plant was in an area of more than 1.5 million tonnes per year excess gasoline supply.</p>
<p>But Skinner was upbeat about the performance of its UK Shell Haven refinery, which had been threatened with closure: &quot;We are satisfied that the action we have taken here is appropriate in relation to that refinery which has the ability to produce very high quality products,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Skinner said 40 jobs would be lost in the Pernis, Netherlands lubricant plant and 70 in Ghent, Belgium, although Shell would try to avoid redundancies.</p>
<p>Jeremy Hudson, oil analyst at Salomon Brothers in London, said Shell's message was disappointing.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not really what the market, and the industry, was looking for. The amount of capacity Shell is reviewing appears to be quite small,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8145</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
