<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245776" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Cricket-Azharuddin leads Indian charge against South Africa.</title>
<headline>Cricket-Azharuddin leads Indian charge against South Africa.</headline>
<dateline>KANPUR, India 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>An unbeaten 88 by Mohammed Azharuddin put India in the driver's seat as their overall lead swelled to 330 runs on the third day of the third and deciding test against South Africa on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Azharuddin punished the South African attack, hammering 15 boundaries as India, starting the day at seven for one wicket for an overall lead of 67 runs, reached 270 for five at the close.</p>
<p>South Africa scored 177 in reply to India's first innings' total of 237.</p>
<p>Azharuddin, who scored a brisk hundred and a half century in the second test, executed some scintillating drives on both sides of the field, and was particularly severe on paceman Lance Klusener, whom he struck for eight boundaries.</p>
<p>Left-arm spinner Paul Adams was despatched to the fence six times in Azharuddin's chanceless 142-ball knock during which the former India captain added 71 runs for the fifth wicket with skipper Sachin Tendulkar.</p>
<p>Tendulkar (36) hit four boundaries before he edged Klusener to wicket-keeper Dave Richardson.</p>
<p>Rahul Dravid, undefeated on 33 at the close, hit four fours in 109 minutes to share in a 78-run stand with Azharuddin.</p>
<p>Earlier, night-watchman Anil Kumble cut and drove with panache, striking five boundaries before he was caught by Herschelle Gibbs at point off pace bowler Fanie de Villiers for 41.</p>
<p>The only wicket to fall before lunch was that of opener Nayan Mongia who departed in the 10th over of the day when Klusener trapped him leg before wicket for 18.</p>
<p>Left-hander Saurav Ganguly, who hit six boundaries in his 41, was caught by Brian McMillan at silly-point off spinner Pat Symcox.</p>
<p>De Villiers and Klusener both finished with two wickets as the South African spinners failed to make an impression on an uneven wicket.</p>
<p>India, who have not lost a home series since their 1986-87 loss to Pakistan, won the opening test in Ahmedabad, but South Africa levelled the series with a crushing 329-run triumph in Calcutta.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANPUR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
