<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245835" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Zimbabwe Hartley on par with world platinum mines.</title>
<headline>Zimbabwe Hartley on par with world platinum mines.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zimbabwe's Hartley platinum mine will have an operating cash margin higher than that of platinum mines in South Africa, Delta Gold NL said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Delta Gold holds 33 percent of the $287 million Hartley platinum project, with fellow Australian company BHP Ltd holding the rest.</p>
<p>The mine recently began commissioning and will be in production in 1997 with full output reached in 1998, Louis Rozman, Delta Gold's manager: business development and mining, said at a Metal Bulletin conference in Johannesburg.</p>
<p>Grozman said Hartley had a projected cash operating margin of $26 a tonne of ore, which is significantly higher than that of South African producers.</p>
<p>He said that in addition to about $33 of platinum recovered from each tonne of ore, a further $30 of other precious and base metals would be won.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hartley platinum mine has an operating cash margin of $26, significantly higher than the major producers in the industry,&quot; Grozman said.</p>
<p>He said the low cost was due to the shallow mining depths at Hartley of around 100 to 500 metres below surface, compared with many South African mines which reach 800 metres to 1.5 kilometres below the earth's crust.</p>
<p>Rustenburg Platinum Holdings Ltd, the world's largest platinum mine, had a cash operating cost of around $14 and another major producer, Impala Platinum Holdings Ltd, had a cash operating cost of $11, Grozman said.</p>
<p>The Hartley platinum mine would push Zimbabwe into the top ranks of platinum producers -- currently dominated by South Africa, which produces around 70 percent of the world's platinum, Russia and North American countries.</p>
<p>The Zimbabwean mine would seek to process some 2.16 million tonnes of ore per annum.</p>
<p>It aimed to produce 150,000 ounces of platinum, 110,000 ounces of palladium, 11,500 ounces of rhodium and 23,000 ounces of gold in the first stage.</p>
<p>The mine would also aim to produce 3,200 tonnes of nickel, 2,300 tonnes of copper and 87,000 pounds of cobalt.</p>
<p>-- Marius Bosch, Johannesburg newsroom +27-11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZIMBAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
