<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245956" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>ESTONIA: Estonian shares surge again, index climbs.</title>
<headline>Estonian shares surge again, index climbs.</headline>
<dateline>TALLINN 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Estonian stock market was booming again on Tuesday as most bank shares, led by largest bank Hansapank, climbed and pulled the main list volume to 40.2 million kroons, dealers said.</p>
<p>The stock exchange index rose 2.8 per cent to 141.83.</p>
<p>Hansapank turned over some 15.6 million kroons and closed with a big gain to 144.25 kroons versus 136.50 kroons.</p>
<p>&quot;Hansapank is like an indicator, when it is doing well then others follow it,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Also, we have big amounts of money on the market but only limited possibilities to invest it,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Traders also said that generally positive corporate news was being reflected in the stock price rises.</p>
<p>Hansapank was also active in foreign markets. Some 2,000 shares were sold for 17.50 marks in the free market of the Frankfurt stock exchange versus 17.40 previously.</p>
<p>In Helsinki, Hansapank traded more than 3.5 million kroons and closed higher at 53.90 markka versus 52 markka previously.</p>
<p>Shares in Forekspank were also active again on turnover of nine million kroons. It closed at 97.50 kroons versus 94.25.</p>
<p>&quot;All the banks' eleven month results were good and there are already expectations about next year,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>Second biggest bank, Savings Bank, traded more than five million kroons but closed down at 62.55 kroons versus 63.35.</p>
<p>Tallinna Pank shares gained more than three kroons and on turnover of 3.2 million kroons closed higher at 54.95 kroons against 51.90.</p>
<p>The over-the-counter market was also active with 10 million kroons of shares traded.</p>
<p>The Norma plastics maker was most-traded, turning over 3.4 million kroons to close slightly higher at 35 kroons.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ESTNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TALLINN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ESTONIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
