<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245939" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria seeks gas barter deal with Russia.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria seeks gas barter deal with Russia.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria has offered Russia a barter deal for the remaining 10 years of their 20-year intergovernmental agreement for natural gas supplies, Bulgaria's trade minister said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In a statement carried by the state news agency BTA, Atanas Paparisov said the first 10 years of an intergovernmental agreement with Russia for natural gas supplies would expire at the end of March.</p>
<p>&quot;The term during which Russia will supply Bulgaria with natural gas in return for its participation in construction works at Russia's Yambourg gas field will expire at the end of the first quarter of 1997,&quot; BTA quoted Paparizov as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The trade ministry has offered Russia's Gazprom a list of goods and services to be supplied (to Russia) against part of the gas to be delivered to Bulgaria,&quot; Paparizov said.</p>
<p>Bulgaria and Russia signed a 20-year agreement in 1986. Russia will continue supplying the same quantities of gas during the second 10 years, but had been expected to pay cash.</p>
<p>Bulgaria currently imports 3.34 billion cubic metres of Russian gas per year against its Yambourg participation, gas officials said.</p>
<p>This year Bulgaria is expected to import another two billion cubic metres of Russian natural gas for cash payment and firms have been bidding for quotas.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
