<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245998" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: MOL not seen affected by Iraqi oil flow.</title>
<headline>MOL not seen affected by Iraqi oil flow.</headline>
<byline>Emese Bartha</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The resumption of Iraqi oil exports will have little direct impact on Hungarian oil and gas company MOL unless world oil prices change substantially, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Iraq, under economic sanctions imposed in 1990 after it invaded Kuwait, re-entered the international oil markets today after the United Nations gave clearance on Monday to start limited exports under an &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal.</p>
<p>&quot;I think it's mostly neutral for MOL due to its production per refinery ratio and because MOL follows world market prices in its pricing,&quot; said Gabor Sitanyi, London-based analyst for Hungarian stocks at ING Barings.</p>
<p>MOL's production per refinery ratio is around 25 percent and this is not particularly high, Sitanyi said.</p>
<p>&quot;The higher this ratio is the better it is for the company if oil prices go higher,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Iraqi Oil Minister Amir Muhammad Rasheed said earlier that Iraq would pump 650,000 barrels of crude oil on Tuesday from Kirkuk in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>Another London-based analyst had a similar opinion of the impact on MOL.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq does not really directly affect (MOL) because the primary source of supply from the Adria (pipeline) is Libya,&quot; said James Oates, director for central and east Europe at UBS in London.</p>
<p>&quot;It might be advantageous if the oil price might fall a little bit but I have a view that world oil prices are not going to be dramatically affected.&quot;</p>
<p>At 1215 GMT in London January Brent crude oil was 16 cents off at $23.94.</p>
<p>MOL imports most of the oil it refines from Russia but it has made steps to implement a strategic plan calling for a decrease in Hungary's dependence on Russian oil.</p>
<p>Earlier this year MOL, jointly with Chevron Corp, won the right to explore for oil off the coast of Qatar.</p>
<p>MOL was also continuing talks about further oil exploration and production concessions with partners in North Africa and the Middle East.</p>
<p>&quot;The opening of the Adria pipeline from Rijeka in Croatia is an opportunity to first of all diversify supply and also diversify the kind of oil that they buy,&quot; Oates said. &quot;This might make their operations a little bit more optimal.&quot;</p>
<p>Oates said the cost of the input is somewhat less important for overseas investors than the price that MOL charges.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the major point there has been that investors were very disappointed by the delay in the implementation of price rises and were relatively disappointed by the level of rises that the Hungarian government wanted to impose.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hungarian government, after it had postponed the energy price increases to January 1997 from October 1, 1996, decided in November to raise retail gas prices by 18.8 percent and electricity prices by 24.9 percent.</p>
<p>Details of the rises, including how much MOL and the electricity suppliers could retain, have not yet been revealed.</p>
<p>On the Budapest Stock Exchange MOL shares closed at 1,860 forints, up 25.</p>
<p>-- Budapest newsroom +36 1 327-4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
