<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245974" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: Slovenian shares down on profit taking.</title>
<headline>Slovenian shares down on profit taking.</headline>
<dateline>LJUBLJANA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Slovenian shares eased on Tuesday as short-term profit taking took the steam out of a recent rally and market participants the decline could continue short term.</p>
<p>The 10-share SBI index fell 3.91 points to 1,188.9, the first fall after five days of gains.</p>
<p>&quot;Many short-term investors are realising their profits by selling shares that rose recently,&quot; said Karmen Cerar, a trader at brokerage Poteza.</p>
<p>Turnover rose to 172.1 million tolars from 106.4 million. Overall 10 shares fell, four rose, three remained unchanged and eight were untraded.</p>
<p>Drug maker Lek A issue was again the most actively traded, falling 0.05 percent to 20,000 tolars on volume of 4,829 shares. Lek has dominated trading since September when it listed its &quot;A&quot; issue, attracting foreign buyers to the bourse.</p>
<p>Preferred shares of Dolenjska bank were the leading decliner, falling 8.70 percent to 10,500 tolars on volume of 11 shares.</p>
<p>Brokerage Dadas was the biggest gainer, rising 5.69 percent to 9,850 tolars on volume of 60 shares. Traders said Dadas rose in a technical reaction to Monday's sharp fall. -- Ljubljana newsroom, 386-61-125-8439</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LJUBLJANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
