<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="245916" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Communists unveil plan to cut Yeltsin's powers.</title>
<headline>Communists unveil plan to cut Yeltsin's powers.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Recent victories in regional elections have given communists hope they can change the Russian constitution and limit President Boris Yeltsin's powers, party leader Gennady Zyuganov said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The Russian constitution, written by Yeltsin's team and approved by a referendum after the president quashed the former parliament with military force in 1993, gives the executive branch strong powers while parliament has only a limited role.</p>
<p>Changing the constitution is very difficult. It requires parliament to convene a constitutional assembly to ratify the change and then send it to voters or to local legislatures for approval. The current constitution has never been altered.</p>
<p>Asked about the likelihood of such changes, Zyuganov invoked history saying that Soviet state founder Vladimir Lenin had failed to predict dramatic changes on the eve of Russia's Bolshevik revolution.</p>
<p>&quot;Russia is an unpredictable country,&quot; said Zyuganov, who lost against Yeltsin in this summer's presidential race.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe recent election results create opportunities to change the constitution,&quot; Zyuganov told reporters at his office in parliament, using a map of the sprawling country to illustrate his point.</p>
<p>Zyuganov was referring to regional gubernatorial poll results in which his Communist Party and its allies have done well. Russia's governors make up the upper house of parliament, which has a say in altering the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;(The changes) would be done to limit the powers of the presidential team, which tries to meddle in all aspects of life and impose its notions, which often border on illegal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Someone today showed me a map of Russia with red spread across the country -- you can see the progress in the colours,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Zyuganov said the Communist Party was looking towards the regions outside Moscow to support its efforts to weaken the president's powers and push its agenda.</p>
<p>&quot;Our citizens share the opinion that the constitution is ripe for change and they actively support reform,&quot; a relaxed Zyuganov said while offering his guests grapes, cookies and tea.</p>
<p>&quot;We know that the provinces of Russia have not rotted to the same degree as the capital. The provinces of Russia have always radiated a healthy spirit and there is hope they will influence Moscow,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The communist leader outlined his preferred system of goverment in detail, much like that in place before the collapse of the Soviet Union in 1991 when parliament, at least on paper, had more power than the executive branch.</p>
<p>Yeltsin's improving health -- he is now resting at a country home near Moscow following heart bypass surgery -- will do nothing to improve the situation in Russia, Zyuganov said.</p>
<p>&quot;I wish him better health, but even when he was completely sober and healthy he didn't solve a single problem,&quot; he said. &quot;So nothing will change.&quot;</p>
<p>Yeltsin is scheduled to return to the Kremlin on December 25.</p>
<p>Zyuganov, who leads the largest faction in parliament, gave no sign of backing down in his opposition to the government's 1997 budget. The Duma, the lower house of parliament, is set to vote on the budget on Sunday.</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;We are in favour of constructive discourse and will do everything to make this possible.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
