<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246097" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombian stocks dip despite foreign buying.</title>
<headline>Colombian stocks dip despite foreign buying.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks drifted down in busy trade despite some foreign fund interest in blue chips, brokers said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bogota's IBB index dipped 0.45 percent to 834.47 in a 4 billion peso volume. Medellin's IBOMED general price index, meanwhile, ended 0.04 percent down at 13,201.49 in volume of one billion pesos.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign funds were active today. They were especially active in buying up large packets of attractive shares such as Banco Ganadero, Cementos Argos and insurance company Suramericana de Seguros,&quot; a Bogota broker said.  </p>
<p>Despite the purchases, neither the market nor the individual stocks were able to overcome the market's ongoing inertia and illqudity.</p>
<p>On the Bogota exchange, Banco Ganadero ordinary shares fell 1.19 percent to 249 in a 1.3 billion peso volume, while Suramericana remained unchanged at 18,500 in a 1.14 billion peso volume.</p>
<p>One broker said he thought most of the 5.5 million shares in Banco Gandero, the country's largest bank in terms of assets, were bought by a single foreign fund.  </p>
<p>&quot;The large volumes suggest the buyer was a foreign fund attracted by the share's low price and recent demand on Wall Street. Hopes are also high for good year-end results,&quot; the broker added.</p>
<p>However, Ganadero ended lower as the final trade of the day was made at a lower price than earlier transactions.</p>
<p>There was also keen interest in brewing giant Bavaria, unchanged at 4,035 in a 290 million peso volume, and in savings and loans society Sociedad de Ahorro y Capitalizacion Bolivar, also flat at 3,300 in a 396 million peso volume.  </p>
<p>Cementos Argos remained unchanged at 5,190 in a 359 million trade.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems foreign funds bought up cement and Bavaria shares in order to meet portfolio requirements,&quot; the broker explained.</p>
<p>The Medellin exchange saw another cross-deal in cement manufacturer Cementos Paz del Rio, which remained steady at 880. Bavaria dipped 0.37 percent to 4,035, while cigarette manufacturer Coltabaco was unchanged at 3,000.</p>
<p>-- Javier Mozzo, Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
