<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246141" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHILE: Chile close to reaching 96 inflation goal - Massad.</title>
<headline>Chile close to reaching 96 inflation goal - Massad.</headline>
<dateline>SANTIAGO 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Chile's economy will almost certainly meet the government's 6.5 percent inflation target for this year, with the 1997 goal of 5.5 percent looking &quot;perfectly attainable,&quot; said Central Bank president Carlos Massad Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If there are no surprises this month, the inflation target for the year will be met,&quot; Massad said in a speech to businessmen.</p>
<p>Official figures showed consumer prices increased 6.2 percent in the first 11 months of the year with prices expected to rise 0.3 percent this month.  </p>
<p>This will be the sixth consecutive year in which Chile's annual inflation rate has fallen.</p>
<p>Although consumer price rises have slowed in recent months, the underlying inflation rate, which measures price rises over the last 12 months, remains stubbornly high, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have seen progress in recent months on the inflation front and, although the underlying inflation figure is above our target for the year, we are hoping for more progress on this front in the near future.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bank figures showed consumer prices rose 6.6 percent in the 12 months to November.</p>
<p>The government's 5.5 percent for next year is &quot;perfectly attainable&quot;, although progress will be quicker if companies compensate for higher costs by improving productivity instead of passing costs on to consumers, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If this does not happen, the Central Bank will have to persevere with its restrictive policy for as long as necessary to break the inflationary inertia,&quot; said Massad.</p>
<p>The Bank has jacked up interest rates twice in the last year to put a brake on the economy, which looked in danger of overheating with inflation set to overshoot the government's target.</p>
<p>Consumer prices rose 8.2 percent last year and 11.4 percent in 1994.</p>
<p>-- Rodrigo Martinez/Margaret Orgill, Santiago newsroom, 562-699-5595 x212</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTIAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHILE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
