<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246161" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Three declared innocent in Brazil massacre trial.</title>
<headline>Three declared innocent in Brazil massacre trial.</headline>
<byline>Simona de Logu</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Rio de Janeiro state court on Tuesday declared innocent two police officers and another man accused of killing eight street children and wounding six in a 1993 shooting spree, a court spokesman said.</p>
<p>A seven-member jury accepted the innocent pleas of Lt. Marcelo Ferreira Cortes, police officer Claudio Luiz Andrade dos Santos and locksmith Jurandir Gomes de Franca and absolved them of all charges, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Six children died when men opened fire indiscriminately on about 70 children playing or sleeping on the steps of the city's Candelaria Church early on July 23, 1993.</p>
<p>Two children killed earlier were left nearby, and six were injured in the shooting spree, which caused a worldwide outcry.</p>
<p>The outcome of the trial, seen as a test case of Brazil's justice system, came as no surprise to human rights activists, who had expected the three men to be freed even though Cortes had been identified as one of the killers by a surviving victim of the massacre, Wagner dos Santos, 24.</p>
<p>&quot;This trial is a disgrace. We are outraged,&quot; said Cristina Leonardo, Santos' lawyer. &quot;I expected them to be freed. Santos' testimony is not being taken seriously by the prosecution itself.&quot;</p>
<p>Santos, who was supposed to testify at the trial, left Brazil prematurely to return to Switzerland, where he had fled because he had become disillusioned with the justice system following two attempts on his life after the killings.</p>
<p>He refused to testify at the latest trial because he felt the testimony of two former police officers who confessed their part in the massacre was being taken more seriously than his.</p>
<p>Former officers Marcus Vinicius Borges Emmanuel and Nelson Oliveira Dos Santos Cunha said Cortes did not take part in the shootings.</p>
<p>Another police officer, Carlos Jorge Liaffa, who Santos also identified as one of the killers, was never charged because Cunha and Emmanuel said he did not take part.</p>
<p>Cunha and Emmanuel were convicted in two earlier trials and sentenced to 309 and 261 years in jail, but have only been confined to police barracks for as long as they can appeal their sentences.</p>
<p>They can appeal several times until their sentences are reduced to 30 years, the maximum anyone can serve under Brazilian law. One already had his sentence reduced to 220 years at a retrial.</p>
<p>Leonardo said the only positive development in the Candelaria trials was that for the first time in Brazil a poor, defenceless witness like Santos received police protection and was able to testify in court.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
