<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246284" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Canada says substantial WTO progress on infotech.</title>
<headline>Canada says substantial WTO progress on infotech.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Norton</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Substantial progress is being made toward an information technology agreement (ITA) in talks at the World Trade Organisation (WTO) ministerial conference this week, Canadian Trade Minister Art Eggleton said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I must say that in terms of ITA we are pushing hard to get an agreement by the end of the week and I think we're making very substantial progress on doing that,&quot; he told reporters at a short briefing during a meeting-packed day.</p>
<p>He said despite vocal objections from some countries like Malaysia to negotiating an ITA deal in Singapore, others were ready to go ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing's for sure until we finish the negotiations, but it's certainly moving in a very positive direction right now.&quot;</p>
<p>The ITA aim is for elimination of tariffs in the lucrative and fast-growing world info-tech market, estimated at some $600 billion.</p>
<p>Canada, the United States, Japan and the European Union are trying to get agreement amongst themselves on ITA terms, while calling on other WTO members, especially Asian-Pacific nations that are key exporters of such technology, to join in.</p>
<p>The Big Four trade countries want an ITA by the time the WTO conference ends on Friday.</p>
<p>Eggleton said that &quot;more and more countries are coming on board and it's looking better all of the time,&quot; but cautioned that &quot;we still have a lot of i's to dot and t's to cross and very little time in which to do it.&quot;</p>
<p>He said another major question at the WTO, whether labour standards should be linked with trade and the WTO's role in the area, had not yet been taken up.</p>
<p>&quot;We haven't got to labour standards yet but if we can continue some momentum that we've started in terms of some other issues on the table we might be able to come up with something positive on that.&quot; The question of China's admission to the WTO had been discussed on Tuesday, Eggleton said, but Canada had not changed its position that China would have to meet the same rules and obligations as other members.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't want to lower the bar in terms of the obligations that have to be met.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked if China had shown a willingness to be more flexible about terms for joining, Eggleton said: &quot;They've come some way but they've got a long way to go.&quot;</p>
<p>Market access for agriculture was one important area for Canada in considering China's membership, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We are making progress on the industrial products but like a lot of other negotiations on trade, agriculture is a sensitive area and that's one where we need some further attention.&quot;</p>
<p>China has been pushing to enter the WTO on the favourable terms granted to developing nations, but many Western countries, most notably the United States, insist China's economy is too large for such treatment.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
