<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246201" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia's Howard launches strong attack on Hanson.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia's Howard launches strong attack on Hanson.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard launched his strongest attack yet on anti-immigration politician Pauline Hanson on Tuesday, saying she held simplistic views against foreign investment.</p>
<p>Hanson had challenged Howard in parliament to say what he was doing about the high level of foreign investment in Australia.</p>
<p>Howard replied that Hanson seemed to think the government could &quot;close the doors of this country to foreign investment (but) continue to have a high standard of living, continue to generate jobs&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is a simplistic notion,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hanson, an independent, sparked a passionate debate on immigration and aboriginal affairs when her maiden speech in parliament in September warned the country was in danger of being swamped by Asians.</p>
<p>Rejected by all major political parties, she also says Aborigines are treated too favourably.</p>
<p>Hanson claims to represent ordinary white Australians and on Tuesday she turned her attention to foreign investment in Australian companies, such as national carrier Qantas Airways Ltd.</p>
<p>&quot;What is the government going to do to promote Australian ownership of our companies and to promote Australian-made products from Australian-owned companies?&quot; she asked Howard.</p>
<p>Howard rejected the assumption that foreign investment was harmful, and cited the establishment of an Australian car industry by U.S. firms after World War II as an example.</p>
<p>&quot;You, by your question, suggest that there were no benefits to foreign investment,&quot; he said. &quot;I thought the establishment of a motor manufacturing industry in Australia...provided jobs in manufacturing for people.&quot;</p>
<p>If there was a problem with foreign investment, then the answer was attacking the lack of Australian savings that forced the country to either borrow or sell equity to pay its way, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is easy to go around this country touching sensitive chords about foreign ownership, but the reality of the situation is that if we do not want large foreign investment in this country, what we have to do is to boost our own savings and we also have to lift our productivity.&quot;</p>
<p>Howard was criticised for failing to condemn Hanson's September speech, although he said he was above responding to every speech by independent politicians.</p>
<p>Later, however, the entire parliament responded by issuing a declaration against racism.</p>
<p>Opinion polls have shown up to two-thirds of Australians agree with Hanson's calls to cut immigration, although not necessarily her other views.</p>
<p>Economists say the amount of foreign investment in Australia stems from the country's intractable current account deficit. Essentially, the country must finance its trade obligations by borrowing or by selling ownership in businesses or real estate, they say.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
