<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246329" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkey sacks military officers in &quot;Islamist purge&quot;.</title>
<headline>Turkey sacks military officers in &quot;Islamist purge&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkey's military announced on Tuesday it had sacked nearly 70 officers and NCOs for discipline problems in what the Turkish press says is a clean out of Islamist officers in the armed forces.</p>
<p>&quot;The lack of discipline and the moral situation of 33 officers and 36 non-commissioned officers was reviewed and it was decided to end their relation with the Turkish armed forces,&quot; the military said in a statement after a two-day council meeting.</p>
<p>Turkey's media has said most of the offenders were suspected of having Islamist tendencies. The influential armed forces is one of the country's most secular bodies.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan, Turkey's first Islamist leader, was absent from the opening day of the council in a break with tradition but he attended Tuesday's second session.</p>
<p>Erbakan, in coalition with a secularist party, has been ineffective in bringing Islamist policies to bear in areas of public life regarded by the generals as within their remit.</p>
<p>He has gone back on promises to scrap a military deal with Israel and throw out a U.S.-led air force that patrols northern Iraq from a base in Turkey.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
