<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246310" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Taiwan urges WTO not to delay entry until China joins Taiwan.</title>
<headline>Taiwan urges WTO not to delay entry until China joins Taiwan.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Wong</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan wants to join the World Trade Organisation (WTO) soon and feels it would be unfair to delay its accession until after China's long-delayed application wins approval, a Taiwan official said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We are qualified and we want to get in any time soon. It doesn't matter which other country gets in when,&quot; said Vincent Siew, head of a special mission of 12 Taiwan legislators attending on the sidelines of the WTO ministerial conference.</p>
<p>Asked if Taiwan thought it was unfair that its entry to the WTO appeared to hinge on Chinese membership, Siew sidestepped the question and said Taipei was only concerned as to when Taiwan would be admitted.</p>
<p>&quot;If we can meet the norms and criteria, if we complete the process of accession...and we still cannot get in, that would be unfair to us,&quot; Siew added.</p>
<p>On the question of Taiwan's entry being considered after Chinese accession, Siew said: &quot;That was not my expectation.&quot;</p>
<p>Taiwan is attending the week-long meeting in Singapore with observer status and under the name Chinese Taipei. It has sent an official delegation as well the group of 12 legislators from Taiwan's Legislative Yuan representing all parties.</p>
<p>Siew said a meeting of Taiwan officials on Monday with major trading partners the United States, the European Union, Japan and Canada showed their sympathy for Taiwan's position.</p>
<p>But talks focused on the substance of trade concessions and methods rather than a timetable for assessing Taiwan, the world's ninth largest trading nation, for membership.</p>
<p>&quot;From Taiwan's point of view, it would be good for China to be admitted, such a major economic power, but at the same time Taiwan is already quite open and should be admitted as soon as possible,&quot; said legislative delegation member, Parris Chang.</p>
<p>Taiwan has given top priority to entry to the WTO and will support reaching an Information Technology Agreement (ITA) if it becomes a member, Siew said.</p>
<p>China, which regards Taiwan as a rebel province, has agreed that Taipei should be allowed to hold separate talks on membership.</p>
<p>Beijing's application has bogged down amid disagreement with the United States on fulfilling the terms of a &quot;road map&quot; for its entry to the world trade body and on U.S. insistence that it join with developed nation status.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
