<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246487" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Three sailors arrested for Thanksgiving rape.</title>
<headline>Three sailors arrested for Thanksgiving rape.</headline>
<dateline>GROTON, Conn. 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three sailors from the U.S. Naval Submarine base at New London were in custody Tuesday on charges they raped a 16-year-old girl over the Thanksgiving holiday weekend, police said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Groton Chief of Detectives Lt. Matthew Morton said in a telephone interview that the investigation was continuing and they were looking for a fourth sailor. The three arrested men are accused of sexually assaulting the girl at the Navy Lodge motel operated by the service for military personnel, he said.</p>
<p>The sailors, being held on $100,000 bond each, were identified as Seaman Recruit Lionel Benjamin, 18, Seaman Recruit Raymond Johnson, 17, and Fireman Recruit Luis Jones, 20. They were arrested Monday night.</p>
<p>Benjamin and Johnson were charged with sexual assault in the first degree. Jones was charged with sexual assault in the third degree and attempted sexual assault in the first degree.</p>
<p>The girl, who lives in Groton, went to the room voluntarily, Morton said. The sailors were arrested after the motel registration was traced to one of them.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GROTON, Conn."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
