<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246480" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Virginia prepares to execute killer.</title>
<headline>Virginia prepares to execute killer.</headline>
<dateline>JARRATT, Va 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Virginia prepared Tuesday to execute Larry Allen Stout, who killed a mother of two by stabbing her in the neck during a robbery.</p>
<p>Stout, 33, admitted killing Jacqueline Kooshian, owner and operator of Trimble's Cleaners in Staunton Feb. 17, 1987.</p>
<p>He was scheduled to be die by injection at 9 p.m. EST.</p>
<p>Stout spent his last day visiting with lawyers and ministers. He ordered sausage pizza, french fries and cherry pie for his last meal.</p>
<p>The Supreme Court turned down his last appeal Tuesday afternoon and Virginia Gov. George Allen announced later in the day that he would not intercede.</p>
<p>&quot;One of the most fundamental human rights is the right to live one's life free from deadly criminal violence inflicted by others,&quot; Allen said in a statement.</p>
<p>The timing of the execution, on International Human Rights Day, sparked a protest at the state Capitol in Richmond Tuesday afternoon. Another was planned Tuesday night outside the Greensville Correctional Centre, where the execution was to take place.</p>
<p>Stout was to be the sixth person executedin Virginia this year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JARRATT, Va"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
