<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246623" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. begins debate on liver transplant allocation.</title>
<headline>U.S. begins debate on liver transplant allocation.</headline>
<byline>Joanne Kenen</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The government opened hearings Tuesday to determine whether it should become involved in deciding how to allocate scarce livers for transplants.</p>
<p>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) began three days of hearings involving patients, surgeons, hospital officals, medical ethicists and organ donor groups in a bid to find the best system for allocating livers.</p>
<p>Livers for transplants are in short supply, with about 4,000 available each year for 7,000 people who are waiting. Last year, 800 people died while waiting for a new liver.</p>
<p>&quot;In recent years, the debate around the allocation system for livers has been the most vexing and controversial issue confronting the transplant community,&quot; HHS Assistant Secretary Dr. Philip Lee said in opening the hearings.</p>
<p>HHS will probably decide what action to take early next year. A key issue is whether there should be a national waiting list or if organs should be assigned through the regional system introduced five years ago.</p>
<p>Critics say the regional system means vast inequities, with people in some states waiting only days or weeks for a new liver while others may wait a year or more.</p>
<p>&quot;The system does not treat patients fairly,&quot; University of Pittsburgh transplant surgeon Dr. John Fung told Reuters after testifying. &quot;They don't have a voice, they don't have access.&quot;</p>
<p>There are also questions about giving priority to the chronically ill or to those with acute liver failure, whether to favour a few big national transplant centres or continue the recent trend of encouraging more smaller regional centres, and whether the government should have a more direct role in setting these policies.</p>
<p>The government, which has both public health concerns and an interest as a major source of transplant financing, has shaped policy since 1984 when Congress passed the National Organ Transplant Act.</p>
<p>Since then, the government has contracted with the United Network for Organ Sharing (UNOS), based in Richmond, Virginia, to oversee many aspects of organ donation and transplant policy. At issue now is whether HHS assumes a larger role in steering UNOS and transplant allocation policies.</p>
<p>UNOS recently announced that starting Jan. 20 patients who suffered acute sudden liver failure would go to the top of the waiting list, ahead of seriously ill people with chronic illness. It said the change would free up about 200 more livers over the next three years but critics said it would make it hard for the chronically ill ever to get transplants.</p>
<p>UNOS announced on Tuesday that it would have &quot;grandfather&quot; clause in the new policy so that people with chronic disease on waiting lists in January could become urgent priorities if their conditions deteriorated.</p>
<p>&quot;We must increase the supply of livers dramatically,&quot; said UNOS president Dr. James Burdick, adding that the new policy had been misinterpreted by the public and would not hurt the sickest patients. &quot;The number of acute liver patients is small and the difference in the rules will have minimal impact on the uncertainties facing those who wait,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This position was supported by several of the surgeons who testified, but other surgeons shared Fung's critical view.</p>
<p>Dr. Charles Miller of New York's Mount Sinai Medical Centre said the new UNOS system allowed some people to get transplants years before they really needed them while others died waiting.</p>
<p>&quot;We need standardised criteria,&quot; he told Reuters. &quot;How many people need transplants in the next 12 months? It may be that there are less than 4,000. If you administer it right, there may not be a shortage.&quot;</p>
<p>Many of the experts testified that the problem of scarce organs could be resolved by getting more people to donate.</p>
<p>&quot;Organ donation not organ allocation is the problem,&quot; said Dr. Anthony D'Alessandro of the University of Wisconsin.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
