<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246609" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US corp bond secondary trade quiet,new issues eyed.</title>
<headline>US corp bond secondary trade quiet,new issues eyed.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. corporate high-grade secondary activity experienced yet another quiet session as players focused on the slew of new issues hitting the market, dealers said.</p>
<p>Spreads to U.S. Treasuries were seen unchanged across most maturities, they added.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been very quiet with not much two-way flow seen, however, retail has been pretty active,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Turning to the primary arena, a slew of new corporate debt deals hit the market as issuers capitalized on attractive interest rates to wrap up year-end financing, dealers said.  </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank Financial Inc, a unit of Deutsche Bank AG, issued $1.1 billion in 6.70 percent subordinated 10-year notes to yield 54 basis points over Treasuries via lead mananger Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>The size of the offering was increased, from an initial $1.0 billion, to meet investor demand, the lead manager said.</p>
<p>&quot;Deutsche's deal was posted all sold and is currently being agressively bid for on the street,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Also, Nike Inc set $200 million in 6.375 percent seven-year notes to yield 34 basis points over Treasuries via joint managers Goldman Sachs and Salomon Brothers.  </p>
<p>The Nike deal was also upped in size, from an initially expected amount of $150 million, to meet investor demand, syndicate sources said.</p>
<p>Another $360 million was issued by the National Power Corp of Philippines (NAPOCOR) in a two-part debt offering via Salomon Brothers.</p>
<p>The first tranche, $200 million in 10-year 7.875 percent guaranteed bonds, were priced to yield 167 basis points over U.S. Treasuries.</p>
<p>The second tranche, $160 million in 8.40 percent 20-year bonds, were priced to yield 190 basis points over Treasuries.  </p>
<p>Among other issues priced on Tuesday were Consolidated Natural Gas' $150 million in 6.625 percent notes, which were priced to yield 43 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>Still, dealers said more deals are on the horizon as we approach the end to the calendar year.</p>
<p>&quot;The potential for more more issuance is there...deals are currently being worked on as we speak,&quot; said one high-grade syndicate source.</p>
<p>Among upcoming debt offerings are Crown Cork &amp; Seal's $1.2 billion debt offering via Salomon Brothers and Philip Morris' $500 million debt offering via Goldman Sachs.  </p>
<p>Turning to the high-yield sector, prices were seen trading up by 1/8 to a 1/4 point in light volume as players focused on media and telecom paper, dealers said.</p>
<p>CAI Wireless Systems Inc debt continued on its decline of the last few days and was seen bid at 46 with a 50 offer, traders said.</p>
<p>On Monday, the paper was quoted at a 50 bid, 55 offer continuing a slide that began on Friday when the debt was hit the hardest.</p>
<p>On Friday, the paper dropped more than 20 points after news that Bell Atlantic Corp and NYNEX Corp might reevaluate the method they use in getting video to homes.</p>
<p>The regional Bells have $100 million invested in CAI.</p>
<p>People's Choice TV debt was unchanged from Monday's levels of 34 bid, 36 offer, gaining two points from its initial 10 point drop on Friday, traders said.</p>
<p>CS Wireless was seen trading at a 32 bid, 35 offer, traders added.</p>
<p>Among new secondary issues, Colt Telecom's new issue was seen trading at a 57-1/2 bid, traders said.</p>
<p>--Nancy Leinfuss, 212-859-1675</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
