<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246736" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: Telcoms ring up records on Portuguese bourse.</title>
<headline>Telcoms ring up records on Portuguese bourse.</headline>
<text>
<p>1810 GMT - With telecom stocks providing the impetus, the PSI20 share index jumped to a record high on Tuesday before closing slightly below the peaks.</p>
<p>*Traders said the market should remain firm on Wednesday even if the near euphoria that surrounded telecom trade should diminish.</p>
<p>*Portugal Telecom and mobile phone debutant Telecel accounted for 73 percent of the 16.7 billion escudos of overall share business.</p>
<p>*&quot;The market has all the right conditions to continue climbing but trade should be calmer,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>*The PSI20 index ended 0.56 percent higher at 5,040.25, just below its 5,054.79 high.</p>
<p>*Traders said that the strength of the telecommunications sector, with Portugal Telecom finishing nearly three percent higher and Telecel jumping 19 percent, owed much to the heavy oversubscription at the mobile phone company's float on Monday.</p>
<p>*Traders see Telecel, which closed at 9,500 against its 7,950 flotation price, targetting 10,000 escudos.</p>
<p>($1=157.06 escudos)</p>
<p>--Paula Cordeiro, Lisbon bureau, 3511-3150035</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
