<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246757" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Russia, NATO to discuss expansion, future ties.</title>
<headline>Russia, NATO to discuss expansion, future ties.</headline>
<byline>David Ljunggren</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian Foreign Minister Yevgeny Primakov is likely to bring both good news and bad news to NATO ministers on Wednesday -- Moscow still opposes their expansion plans but wants to work out future relations.</p>
<p>In a sign the Kremlin might have decided that negotiating a charter governing ties with NATO takes precedence over protests about enlargement, Primakov asked NATO secretary-general Javier Solana on Tuesday when the talks could begin.</p>
<p>NATO officials said the 16 foreign ministers would be waiting to see how strongly Primakov reiterated Moscow's protests about the planned enlargement, which Russia has consistently portrayed as a threat to its national security.</p>
<p>But given NATO's determination to carry out plans to extend membership to Moscow's former east European allies, Russia might accept it is better off adopting a different tack.</p>
<p>&quot;It is interesting that they (the Russians) are now indicating a willingness to talk to us on the essentials. They are no longer asking us to change the enlargement policy before they can talk,&quot; a NATO official told reporters.</p>
<p>U.S. State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns later told reporters: &quot;There's obviously interest here, but I think the Russians want to hear formally from NATO tomorrow.&quot;</p>
<p>Some diplomats said Primakov's apparent eagerness to start talks might be more than a tad mischievous, since NATO members had yet to agree among themselves what kind of deal the alliance could offer Russia.</p>
<p>&quot;I am expecting interesting talks,&quot; the taciturn Primakov told Russian television on arrival in Brussels, hours after the NATO ministers ignored the latest outburst from Moscow and agreed to push ahead with plans for eastward expansion.</p>
<p>They called a special summit in Madrid on July 8-9 to name its first new members from former communist Europe and the first new additions for more than 25 years. The Czech Republic, Hungary and Poland are on most observers' lists of favourites.</p>
<p>The ministers also agreed to send a new peace force to Bosnia for 18 months from next January and criticised Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic for failing to respect the results of municipal elections in November.</p>
<p>But the trickiest issue facing NATO is how to work out a charter on future ties with Russia while trying to persuade Moscow that the alliance has no hostile intentions.</p>
<p>U.S. Secretary of State Warren Christopher vowed NATO would not station nuclear missiles on the territory of new members, but Moscow is more interested in the concessions it can wring from its old foe.</p>
<p>Defence officials say one possibility would be to form a new structure which might give Moscow some influence in how the alliance was run.</p>
<p>Shortly before Primakov left Moscow, Russia dismissed suggestions it was softening its opposition as &quot;fantasy&quot;, but diplomats say the ferocity of such statements is at least in part aimed at its domestic audience.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NATO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
