<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246728" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian parliamentarians split on Di Rupo sex probe.</title>
<headline>Belgian parliamentarians split on Di Rupo sex probe.</headline>
<byline>Geert De Clercq</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>A special commission of Belgian parliamentarians on Tuesday wrangled over the fate of Deputy Prime Minister Elio Di Rupo who faces fresh allegations he had sex with under-age boys.</p>
<p>Parliamentarians told reporters during a break in the meeting, which convened on Tuesday morning, that some of them had called for the probe to be dropped because they thought the new set of allegations were paperthin.</p>
<p>Those in favour of dropping the investigation were mainly from Di Rupo's French-speaking socialist PS party, while others, mainly members of the liberal opposition, said the investigation should press on.</p>
<p>A discreet homosexual, Di Rupo, 45, has denied any involvement in sex with children below the age of consent of 16.</p>
<p>As a member of the PS, the second biggest party in the centre-left coalition, he is the number two in the government after Prime Minister Jean-Luc Dehaene himself.</p>
<p>&quot;The new allegations must also be investigated by the court,&quot; commission member Pierre Chevalier for the Flemish opposition liberal VLD party told Reuters.</p>
<p>The Cour de Cassation, Belgium's highest court and the only one capable of judging a minister, handed the commission a report on Monday about the original allegations against Di Rupo by a sole witness, rejecting them as baseless.</p>
<p>Compiling the case, the Brussels prosecutor had already pulled together another file of allegations, this time anonymous, and spoke on Monday of more to come.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no way we could just drop these allegations. It is logical that the court investigates them too,&quot; said Didier Reynders for the francophone opposition liberal PRL party.</p>
<p>But PS commission member Serge Moureaux said, &quot;The second file is very different from the first case. It consists of various items of dubious value.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It will problably be a long debate,&quot; Albert Ghelen of the French-speaking Christian democrat PSC -- a coalition partner -- said.</p>
<p>A continuation of the high court investigation against Di Rupo would leave a sword of Damocles hanging over him for weeks, possibly months, and would further paralyse the government.</p>
<p>Just when Di Rupo might have been able to breathe a little easier following Monday's news of the rejection by the Cour de Cassation of the initial allegations by the only identified witness, he and Belgian politics received another blow.</p>
<p>Jean-Pierre Grafe, a minister in a French-speaking regional government who has also been accused of paedophilia, suddenly announced his resignation.</p>
<p>He said he was innocent but could not continue to function in the current over-heated climate.</p>
<p>The Cour de Cassation on Tuesday handed a report to the French-speaking government on the allegations against Grafe, and Belga news agency said chief public prosecutor Eliane Lieckendael had asked for him to be indicted.</p>
<p>The full parliament must endorse any decision by the special commission -- to reject the allegations, to uphold them and indict the minister or to ask for more investigations.</p>
<p>The Di Rupo affair has been another nail in the coffin of Belgian public confidence, shaken since the arrest in August of rapist Marc Dutroux, the subsequent rescue of two young girls and the discovery of the bodies of four more.</p>
<p>In October more than 250,000 people took to the streets of Brussels in support of the victims and their families in a demonstration that crossed the country's language divide and rapidly turned into a show of anger at an incompetent system.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
