<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246885" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India steps up patrols after killing of 30 tribals.</title>
<headline>India steps up patrols after killing of 30 tribals.</headline>
<dateline>GUWAHATI, India 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian security forces stepped up patrols in the remote northeast state of Nagaland on Tuesday after separatist Naga guerrillas massacred 30 members of a rival tribe, authorities said.</p>
<p>Naga militants armed with guns and hand grenades shot dead 30 bus passengers, including 14 women and two children, and wounded 32 on Monday at Maiamnala, 105 km (65 miles) from Nagaland's state capital of Kohima, near the Burmese border, police said.</p>
<p>At least 20 Naga guerrillas stopped a bus carrying more than 80 passengers and asked ethnic Naga tribesmen to get off. Then they lined up the Kukis by the side of the road and fired indiscriminately, authorities said.</p>
<p>All the dead members were Kukis, locked in a bitter rivalry with the Nagas, they said.</p>
<p>Twenty-eight people were killed immediately and two died on the way to hospital, police said. The wounded, including 24 in serious condition, were admitted to hospital in nearby Dimapur.</p>
<p>Security forces stepped up patrols along strategic National Highway 39, which authorities say tribals use to transport drugs from Burma to Europe and the Balkans.</p>
<p>The Nagas and Kukis began fighting in mid-1992 for control of the highway, which links the border town of Moreh with Burma.</p>
<p>Authorities say $1 billion worth of drugs is transported every year on the road, which was once firmly under the control of Kukis before the Nagas laid claim to it.</p>
<p>They estimate more than 1,000 people have been killed in ethnic violence, which has been centred in Manipur state where Nagas and Kukis live side by side. Manipur borders Nagaland, where Monday's massacre took place.</p>
<p>&quot;We have taken all the precautions to prevent further violence taking place in Manipur, and both paramilitary and military have been deployed on the National Highway 39,&quot; Manipur police chief Bimal Chandra Singh told Reuters by telephone from the state capital of Imphal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUWAHATI, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
