<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246985" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Branson eyes Canada as Virgin territory.</title>
<headline>Branson eyes Canada as Virgin territory.</headline>
<byline>Cynthia Osterman</byline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER, British Columbia</dateline>
<text>
<p>Flamboyant British entrepreneur Richard Branson announced his ambitions Monday to turn Canada into Virgin territory.</p>
<p>Branson said the opening of his sprawling Virgin Group's first Virgin Megastore music shop in Canada heralded plans for the full-scale entry of other Virgin businesses.</p>
<p>Over the next 18 months these will include Virgin Atlantic Airways, Virgin Cola, Virgin Jeans and Virgin Cosmetics -- &quot;everything Virgin,&quot; Branson said in an interview.</p>
<p>Even his newly launched record company V2 Music Group, which returns him to the business where he got his start, will set up shop in Canada and scout for talent here.</p>
<p>The Virgin Megastore in Vancouver, which Branson predicted will become the highest grossing music store in Canada, &quot;will be a forebearer of other Virgin ventures,&quot; he said. &quot;Canada has been one of the major omissions&quot; in the empire.</p>
<p>Branson said he would follow a pattern in Canada that had been successful elsewhere -- enter with the Virgin record store or airline, build awareness of the brand name and then expand. There are currently 61 Virgin Megastores throughout the world.</p>
<p>The 46-year-old Branson, famous for his colorful antics, planned to stay less than a day in Vancouver before rushing back to London where he is preparing for an around-the-world hot-air balloon trip leaving from Morocco early next year.</p>
<p>He promised an attention-grabbing stunt for the opening of the Vancouver store but declined to reveal details. Branson last week donned a white bride's dress and took to the catwalk for the opening of a new Virgin store for weddings in London.</p>
<p>The 45,000-square foot Vancouver Megastore store cost C$8.5 million ($6.3 million) and opens on Tuesday. Virgin expects it to generate sales of C$20 million ($14.8 million) in its first year and plans other Megastores in Toronto, Montreal and Edmonton, Alberta.</p>
<p>Then within the next year, Virgin Atlantic Airways plans to begin flights between Britian and Canada, Branson said. Initial service would probably be offered between London's Heathrow airport and Toronto. The airline was likely to order two Boeing Co. 747s for the service, he said.</p>
<p>Known for his willingness to take on corporate giants like British Airways Plc, Branson has spread into myriad ventures including Virgin Cola which challenges Coca-Cola Co. and its own line of blue jeans which confronts Levi Strauss. The Virgin line of cosmetics is due to be launched next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER, British Columbia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
