<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="246937" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Kotak says buy India M&amp;M despite slowdown.</title>
<headline>Kotak says buy India M&amp;M despite slowdown.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Goldman Sachs affiliate Kotak Securities said it recommended a buy on shares of Indian automobile firm Mahindra &amp; Mahindra despite a demand slowdown.</p>
<p>Kotak said Mahindra's top management made a series of presentations in Singapore and Hong Kong recently and answered questions about slowdown in demand and inventory build-up.</p>
<p>The Kotak report summarised the management's response to &quot;some of the most frequently asked questions.&quot; Excerpts from the report by Anand Aithal of Goldman Sachs and Sangeeta Mehta of Kotak Securities are reproduced below</p>
<p>+ Are the good times over for the industry?</p>
<p>Although there has been a slowdown in sales growth in the first seven months of this fiscal year absolute growth for the industry is still a respectable double-digit figure and can hardly be characterised as slump in demand.</p>
<p>In part, slower growth could represent a response to weaker industrial growth and to a smaller degree higher fuel prices. More fundamentally, slower growth ought to have been expected, given that sales growth was measured at a much higher base level than in previous years.</p>
<p>+ What is M&amp;M's inventory position?</p>
<p>M&amp;M's figures show a small fall for April-October 1996 in the absolute level of inventory from both the tractors and automotive divisions even though M&amp;M's level of production and sales has increased during this fiscal year.</p>
<p>M&amp;M monitors inventories at its dealers through its 18 area managers, and here again the company sees no sign of inventory build up. It still receives advance payments from dealers for certain models, a good indicator for continuing strong final demand.</p>
<p>+ Which leading indicators does M&amp;M watch?</p>
<p>At the macro level, management believes the most important indicator to watch is sales of heavy commercial vehicles on the basis that final demand in this category is most sensitive to changes in the real economy. So far, the demand growth slowdown is real but not catastrophic.</p>
<p>+ In terms of M&amp;M's results, the most important leading indicators are in relation to performance of the rural economy. Thanks to a good monsoon, this year's agricultural GDP growth is likely to be nearly 4.0 percent, against last year's 0.9 percent.</p>
<p>+ What about the urban market?</p>
<p>Although less important to M&amp;M, the company is increasing production of its upmarket Armada utility vehicle, without any diversion of production of rural vehicles, partly because recent excise duty changes were helpful relative to its main rival, the Tata Sumo.</p>
<p>+ What are M&amp;M's major capex plans?</p>
<p>There have been no major changes in capital expenditure plans. M&amp;M plans to invest around $300 million in the next three years, to be funded from its recent Euroconvertible bond issue of $115 million, debt (around $100 million) and internal accruals.</p>
<p>+ How are labour negotiations progressing?</p>
<p>Labour unions at Kandivli appear to have accepted the principle of productivity-enhancing improvements, arguments are now simply about money. The company expects to reach a settlement with utility plant workers in the final quarter of fiscal 1997 and tractor workers soon thereafter.</p>
<p>The impact of labour settlement would be to improve longer-term productivity, although there would be an upfront cost in terms of higher wages and backpay. M&amp;M has made provisions for backpay in its recent half year results.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
