<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247028" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: WIDESPREAD SHAREOWNERSHIP KEY TO HEALTHY MARKETS.</title>
<headline>WIDESPREAD SHAREOWNERSHIP KEY TO HEALTHY MARKETS.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Widespread share ownership enhances liquidity, reduces volatility and makes price manipulation difficult -- all key to a healthy equity market, New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) official George Sofianos said.</p>
<p>&quot;Regulation to maintain investor confidence, privatisation and education, are ways to encourage equity culture,&quot; Sofianos told a conference on the modernisation of Greece's capital market.</p>
<p>Diversified equity investing is the best strategy for long term investors, he said, noting that shareownership in the U.S. is widespread, numbering 51 million shareholders, about one third of the adult population.</p>
<p>With IPOs, transfers from Nasdaq, the American stock exchange and non-U.S. cross-listings, NYSE listings as of end- November amounted to 2,866 companies.</p>
<p>Of these, 285 were non-U.S. listings. And experience so far has shown that combined trading increases following cross- listing, both at the home market and at the NYSE, Sofianos said.</p>
<p>NYSE employs 480 people in its regulatory group engaged in member firm regulation, enforcement and market surveillance, about one third of the exchange's staff.</p>
<p>The Big Apple's premier stock exchange uses computers for market surveillance, helping the review of information stored and updated daily in its data bases.</p>
<p>Stockwatch and ICASS are mechanisms that identify aberrational trading as it occurs, allowing an audit trail. The capability is there for analysts to investigate for posible insider trading or market manipulation.</p>
<p>Clearance and settlement are trade-plus three (T+3) since June 1995 while the challenge for the future is to move to T+1 with complete dematerialisation and multicurrency clearance and settlement, Sofianos told the conference. --George Georgiopoulos, Intercontinental Hotel Newsroom +301 902.3666, ext. 6680</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
