<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247181" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>CYPRUS: Cyprus protests at Turkish remarks on missiles.</title>
<headline>Cyprus protests at Turkish remarks on missiles.</headline>
<dateline>NICOSIA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Cyprus protested to the UN on Tuesday over Turkish remarks that it would not tolerate the deployment of long-range missiles on the divided island.</p>
<p>&quot;For as long as there is a strong military presence of Turkey in Cyprus we have an obligation to build our own defence and in doing this we are not going to seek approval from Turkey,&quot; Foreign Minister Alecos Michaelides told Reuters.</p>
<p>President Glafcos Clerides protested to UN Cyprus special representative Han Sung-Joo over Turkish remarks on Monday concerning Cyprus's reported intention of purchasing a Russian missile system for the island.</p>
<p>&quot;No one should expect that Turkey may tolerate the deployment of long-range missiles, threatening its security,&quot; Foreign Ministry spokesman Omar Akbel said, according to Anatolia news agency.</p>
<p>Greek Cypriot officials have kept silent on the reports the government is interested in purchasing Russian-built S300 surface-to-air missiles to boost its air defences.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to buy anything we think is necessary for our defence. That is our moral obligation,&quot; said Michaelides.</p>
<p>The heavily militarised eastern Mediterranean island has been divided since Turkey invaded the northern third in 1974 after a brief Greek Cypriot coup in Nicosia engineered by the military ruling in Greece at the time.</p>
<p>Turkey has some 30,000 troops deployed in northern Cyprus, declared a breakaway Turkish Cypriot state only Ankara recognises and one of the most heavily militarised areas in the world, according to UN reports.</p>
<p>The 10,000 strong Greek Cypriot national guard is engaged in a comprehensive programme to upgrade its capabilities but remains significantly weaker than the Turkish forces in the north. It also has a defence pact with close ally Greece.</p>
<p>The Greek Cypriot side says a significant step towards defusing tension on the island and paving the way to a comprehensive settlement would be to demilitarise the island. The Turkish Cypriot side says demilitarisation can be discussed only as part of a more comprehensive package on the Cyprus problem.</p>
<p>Michaelides, who described Akbel's comments as &quot;unacceptable&quot; said the government is ready to embark on a discussion for the demilitarisation of the island &quot;tomorrow&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We don't need arms in Cyprus but it must be demilitarised totally,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CYPR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NICOSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CYPRUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
