<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247193" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish president meets politicians on scandal.</title>
<headline>Turkish president meets politicians on scandal.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish President Suleyman Demirel on Tuesday began a series of meetings with opposition figures to discuss a security scandal undermining the Islamist-led government.</p>
<p>Demirel met far-right leader Alparslan Turkes at the presidential palace and was scheduled to hold talks later in the day with main opposition leader Mesut Yilmaz, the president's office said. Further meetings were set for Wednesday.</p>
<p>The government has been shaken by reports of links between its junior coalition partner True Path Party and right-wing gangsters alleged to have carried out political killings of Kurdish rebel sympathisers.</p>
<p>True Path head Tansu Ciller, also the foreign minister, discussed keeping Turkey's fight with Kurdish guerrillas inside a legal framework at a meeting with Demirel on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The president and I...are sensitive on the subject of legitimate forces being used in all of the state's struggles. We are in total agreement on this subject,&quot; Ciller said after the meeting.</p>
<p>A Turkish paper said on Tuesday that Prime Minister Necmettin Erbakan had received a report saying Ciller paid $8.3 million from a slush fund to a Turkish underworld gang in 1994 to kill Kurdish guerrilla leader Abdullah Ocalan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
