<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247421" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: France's SNCF, Jet Services drop TGV cargo project.</title>
<headline>France's SNCF, Jet Services drop TGV cargo project.</headline>
<byline>Stuart Todd</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>French road and air express distribution company, Jet Services and state railways utility, SNCF, have abandoned a project to move freight between Paris and major provincial cities on high-speed trains, officials from both concerns told Reuters.</p>
<p>Jet Services had planned to operate cargo-configured TGV carrying up to 160 tonnes of freight on a nightly Lille-Paris-Lyon-Marseille rotation from spring 1998.</p>
<p>The decision reflected continuing disagreement over the project's costs and cargo capacity, industry sources said.</p>
<p>Junior French Transport Minister Anne-Marie Idrac had backed the project in underlining that no public aid was being sought in its implementation.</p>
<p>At a meeting held last month, Jet Services Chairman and Chief Executive Roger Caille and SNCF President Louis Gallois decided to officially abandon the project, an SNCF official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;In Jet Services' view, the financial terms proposed by SNCF were incompatible with the quality of service being offered, &quot; said SNCF's Michel Gouin, head of SNCF Fret Intermodal Traffic and Parcels Delivery business unit.</p>
<p>The terms involved Jet Services purchasing two cargo-adapted TGVs for just under 100 million francs each, as well as a contribution towards fixed costs for traction, infrastructure and power supplies, Gouin said.</p>
<p>The SNCF had proposed operating the TGV Cargo trains between 10.00 p.m. (2100 GMT) and 5.00 a.m. (0400 GMT) which Jet Services did not consider to be optimal but nevertheless &quot;workable&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Overall, during the course of the negotiations we had the feeling that the conditions that the SNCF had proposed at the outset were changing little by little to our disadvantage,&quot; a Jet Services official told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;In particular, the price we were being asked to pay was increasing, while at the same time the capacity of the cargo-configured TGVs was being reduced. It's a missed opportunity but maybe this kind of project was a little premature for the SNCF,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The Jet Service official said: &quot;We saw a high-speed rail service for freight as complementary to an on-going strategy of expanding our overland and air transport networks.</p>
<p>&quot;However, having tried to get this project on track since 1992 we couldn't wait around any longer for it to come about and for that reason thought it best to break-off negotiations with the SNCF,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gouin said the SNCF still saw a future for a high-speed rail service for freight.</p>
<p>&quot;Clearly we are disappointed we couldn't reach an agreement with Jet Services but the &quot;concept&quot; has in no way been called into question. We are in contact with the German railways on the question, while Federal Express' expansion plans at Charles de Gaulle airport could one day incorporate an air/rail link,&quot; Gouin added.</p>
<p>&quot;While it's difficult to see any real development before the turn of the century, the TGV Cargo remains a strategic long-term objective in SNCF Fret's plans,&quot; he said. --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
