<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247403" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Highlights of Tuesday's Commission briefing.</title>
<headline>Highlights of Tuesday's Commission briefing.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are highlights of the midday briefing by the European Commission on Tuesday:</p>
<p>Spokesman Joao Vale de Almeida said Competitiveness Advisory Group Chairman Percy Barnevik would hold a news conference at 1130/1030 GMT on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Vale de Almeida said news releases on the Commission's meeting decisions would be available from 1530/1430 GMT from the spokeman's services.</p>
<p>Vale de Almeida said Commissioner Emma Bonino had reacted to both the contents and tone of recent Scottish Fisheries Minister Raymond Robertson's declaration on the issue of salmon minimum import prices.</p>
<p>Spokesman Peter Jorgensen briefed on Monday's Environment Council. He said the ministers had failed to adopt the conclusions on climate change but managed a common position on the the fifth environmental action program. He said the Council had also adopted a resolution on leghold traps where they asked the Commission to take the necessary measures in order to implement an import ban by the end of March 1997.</p>
<p>Jorgensen said that the Council expressed its concern on timing, potential trade problems and on labelling issues related to genetically modified maize and soybeans.</p>
<p>Spokesman Josep Coll i Carbo said the Commission and a representative of the Palestinian Authority would sign an agreement at 1630/1530 GMT in the DG1B Sciences 14 building. He said this would be followed by a briefing.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>The Commission released the following documents:</p>
<p>- IP/96/1141: EU agrees strong new moves to control wildlife trade.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1143: Commission suports SMEs in Finland with ECU 11 million.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1144: European broadcasters honoured in Dublin at first Echo tv and radio awards.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1146: Baltic Sea States Chairman-in-office visits the European Commission.</p>
<p>- IP/96/1147: ECU 27.5 million of 1996 TACIS funding for Ukraine.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/325: Speech by Commissioner Emma Bonino at &quot;Echo Awards'.</p>
<p>- Speech/96/326: Speech by Commissioner Erkki Liikanen on draft Community budget for 1997 at the European Parliament.</p>
<p>- The mutually beneficial effects of greater co-ordination of economic and structural policies, final report by the Commission.</p>
<p>- Business and consumer surveys, final results, November 1996, No 11.</p>
<p>- Taxes and duties at November 1996 (national currencies and ECU).</p>
<p>- Oil bulletin No 848.</p>
<p>- Main points on the agenda of Tuesday's weekly Commission meeting.</p>
<p>- ME96/10.12: Midday Express.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
