<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247544" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: UPM, M-SERLA TO HOLD JOINT INFO.</title>
<headline>UPM, M-SERLA TO HOLD JOINT INFO.</headline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finnish forest industry groups UPM-Kymmene and Metsa-Serla said on Tuesday they would hold a news conference at 1200/1000 GMT at Hotel Palace in Helsinki.</p>
<p>A spokeswoman for UPM, Europe's largest forestry group, and an official at Metsa-Serla's main owner Metsaliitto said the news conference was about a &quot;significant corporate arrangement&quot;.</p>
<p>A Metsaliitto spokesman confirmed that it would be a joint news conference.</p>
<p>The Helsinki bourse earlier said trade in shares of both firms had been suspended at their own request.  </p>
<p>Analysts asked to speculate on the news said the companies are highly unlikely to announce a merger but may signal some kind of asset swap, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;A merger would be highly unlikely, 'significant corporate arrangement' signals some swaps in units or factories,&quot; said one, requesting anonymity amid speculation.</p>
<p>&quot;My rough guess would be (the news will involve) an elimination of cross-ownership in (pulp mills) Metsa-Rauma and Metsa-Botnia -- this is shooting from the hip,&quot; said Lars Kjellberg at Enskilda Bank in Stockholm.</p>
<p>Both have holdings in the pulp mills.</p>
<p>UPM-Kymmene has officially been in operation since May through the merger of Repola and Kymmene. Metsa-Serla is mainly owned by cooperative Metsaliitto.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I47101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
