<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247666" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Copper market traders eye backwardations.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Copper market traders eye backwardations.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Backwardations in nearby spreads in the copper market suggest surplus metal is becoming increasingly scarce, metals traders said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Pointing to rising London Metal Exchange (LME) inventories, analysts generally agree that the copper market is heading for oversupply, brought on by easing industrial growth and the start of new mining and smelting capacities.</p>
<p>However, some metals traders said indications are emerging that suggest supplies may not be all that plentiful.</p>
<p>A backwardation exists when a nearby copper contract is more expensive than a forward contract.</p>
<p>&quot;If you look at prices for copper very nearby, they are extremely tight, even though the cash-to-threes (three-month) is about US$150 (a tonne),&quot; one LME metals trader said.</p>
<p>The tightness is particularly evident in mid-December, where one-day backwardations are nearing US$20 a tonne, which is just below the one percent of contract price limitation based on a current copper price of about US$2,125 a tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;There is this very tight periods between December 13 and December 18,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>Strong rumours that a large investment broker has been caught short and is looking to cover his positions has been linked to the scenario.</p>
<p>&quot;When you see these sorts of spreads being paid it should attract nearby metal... If you've got metal and you can sell it tomorrow and buy it back the day after for $20.00 less, why not,&quot; another trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;On the other hand, if you're short, you have to buy it back then sell it the next day at a US$20.00 loss.&quot;</p>
<p>In times of oversupply, holders of excess metal, such as producers and consumers, typically take advantage of the potential profit by &quot;lending&quot; copper to the market, thereby pocketing a profit.</p>
<p>&quot;This situation should be attracting metal, but there is no metal coming in, the LME trader said.</p>
<p>As a result, backwardations in the market are increasing, he added.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
