<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247634" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ shares end slightly down on inflated turnover.</title>
<headline>NZ shares end slightly down on inflated turnover.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>* New Zealand share prices end slightly lower</p>
<p>* Turnover inflated by trade in Tenz, Lion, CHH</p>
<p>* Pulp and paper returns to favour. Telecom sheds 10 cents</p>
<p>---------------------------(Dec 10)---------------------------</p>
<p>Price movements at close</p>
<p>	    LAST CHG</p>
<p>  131   +1  * NZSE-40 cap index -3.60 at 2,357.57</p>
<p>  341   +2  * NZSC cap index -19.66 at 4,892.38</p>
<p>280   +8  * NZSE-10 cap index -3.74 at 1,176.11   344   -6  * Volume NZ$82 million. Futures -3 at 1,180</p>
<p>730  -10  * Other movers - -15 -2  </p>
<p>New Zealand share prices ended slightly lower on Tuesday on turnover inflated by activity in the Tenz fund, Lion Nathan and Carter Holt Harvey.</p>
<p>The NZSE-40 Capital Index ended 3.60 points down at 2,357.57 on turnover worth NZ$84 million.</p>
<p>The Tenz fund was responsible for almost NZ$15.4 million of the total, with several trades done through Cavill White Securities.</p>
<p>Lion Nathan was also actively traded, with stock worth NZ$13.22 million going through, much of it through SBC Warburg.</p>
<p>Lion ended six cents down at NZ$3.44.  </p>
<p>Pulp and paper enjoyed a return to favour after losing ground last week. FCL Paper gained eight cents to NZ$2.80 and Carter Holt Harvey rose two to $3.41.</p>
<p>The main mover on the day was Telecom, down 10 cents at NZ$7.30. Tim Snedden at ANZ Securities said weakness may have been allied to concerns about the New Zealand dollar, should a centre left coalition become the government.</p>
<p>New Zealand First, which holds the balance of power, is expected to make an announcement at 5 p.m. (0400 GMT) on the timing and form of a coalition announcement.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 473 4746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
