<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247815" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam says tackling host of economic troubles.</title>
<headline>Vietnam says tackling host of economic troubles.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam is tackling obstacles in the way of a target of annual economic growth of nine to 10 percent before the end of the century, a deputy minister said in an interview published on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;...a number of shortcomings have emerged and if they had not been dealt with in time they would have hampered growth,&quot; Deputy Minister of Planning and Investment Vo Hong Phuc told the monthly Vietnam Economic Times.</p>
<p>Phuc reeled off a litany of industrial problems, including low efficiency, poor product quality, stockpiling of goods, sluggish distribution, incompetent trade management and loopholes in financial management.</p>
<p>&quot;Funds keep being lost, the state revenue has reached a low point, various expenditures have not been met and many social problems have been tackled too slowly,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the communist leadership pledged to press ahead with its decade-old reform of the economy along market lines and set ambitious growth targets in a five-year plan.</p>
<p>The reform drive has brought several years of vigorous economic growth, which has averaged more than 8.2 percent since 1991, and improved living standards for many in what remains one of the world's poorest countries.</p>
<p>The economic take-off has been boosted by a strong flow of investment from abroad.</p>
<p>Licences have now been granted for foreign investment projects worth about $23 billion, equivalent to one year's gross domestic product. But less than 30 percent of that money has been implemented so far.</p>
<p>Investors say bureaucracy, corruption and an opaque legal and regulatory environment have slowed projects and complain that the playing field is tilted heavily in favour of the country's sprawling state sector.</p>
<p>Phuc said the foreign-invested sector has enjoyed preferential treatment in recent years and predicted that recent amendments to the foreign investment law would streamline administration and improve the business environment for firms from abroad.</p>
<p>He said Hanoi's policy of attracting foreign investment to rural areas, home to about 80 percent of the population and the majority of poor people, had yielded very limited results.</p>
<p>Turning to the recent leap in Vietnam's trade deficit, Phuc said the management of deferred letters of credit had not been particularly sound. His ministry and the central bank had been instructed to control the import of goods on such a basis, he said.</p>
<p>The United Nations, in a recent report, said restricting borrowing for imports may have limited success in plugging a trade gap equivalent to 19.4 percent of GDP.</p>
<p>&quot;Tighter administrative controls might eventually cap the deficit in the short term, but even these may be eventually skirted,&quot; it said. &quot;A lasting solution will require more fundamental reforms.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
