<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247801" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian minister seen shedding light on Busang.</title>
<headline>Indonesian minister seen shedding light on Busang.</headline>
<byline>K.T. Arasu</byline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian Mines and Energy Minister Ida Bagus Sudjana is expected to shed some light on the Busang gold find saga when he appears before a parliamentary commission, industry sources said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said that although there was no fixed agenda for the routine commission hearing on Wednesday, legislators were expected to raise questions related to the find in Kalimantan.</p>
<p>&quot;It is expected to be a very interesting meeting,&quot; said one source who has been following closely the drawn out dispute over Busang, estimated to contain some 57 million ounces of gold. The current value of the gold amounts to more than $21 billion.</p>
<p>Canada's Bre-X Minerals Ltd, which discovered the find, is being pushed by the Indonesian government to link up with Barrick Gold Corp to develop the property.</p>
<p>Bre-X has said it had a partnership deal with President Suharto's eldest son, Sigit Harjojudanto, while Barrick has teamed up with his eldest daughter, Siti Hardianti Rukmana.</p>
<p>The government sent the firms a letter dated November 22 asking Bre-X to retain a 25 percent stake in the property, with Barrick taking 75 percent. The companies have been advised to allocate a 10 percent stake to the Indonesian government.  </p>
<p>Mines and Energy Ministry secretary-general Umar Said said on Monday that Bre-X and Barrick had agreed to the contents of the letter, but Bre-X said no deal had been done yet.</p>
<p>The sources said the legislators were expected to seek a clarification from Sudjana on the current status of the Busang property and when its development was likely to begin.</p>
<p>They said the legislators were also expected to question Sudjana on his decision to strip his director-general Kuntoro Mangkusubroto of his authority to approve contracts of work.</p>
<p>Sudjana made the decision in October, but denied it was linked to Kuntoro's delaying the issuing of contracts of work to Bre-X for the richest parts of the Busang find until it sorted out an ownership dispute with local businessman Jusuf Merukh.</p>
<p>Merukh claims he owns 40 percent of the entire Busang find and has threatened to file a $1.9 billion lawsuit against Bre-X if it did not begin talks to resolve the dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission members are expected to seek an explanation from Sudjana why he removed Kuntoro's powers and transfered them to himself,&quot; another source said.</p>
<p>The sources said they also expected Sudjana to be questioned over his decision last April to cancel a contract given to a company to construct the ministry's $150 million MIGAS Centre.</p>
<p>The ministry's Umar Said told a news conference last week the contractor had failed to deposit the required $5.9 million with a bank as a guarantee before undertaking the project.</p>
<p>&quot;He only deposited less than half the required amount despite repeated reminders,&quot; he said, adding that the project had been delayed for more than two years.</p>
<p>The industry sources said Sudjana was also expected to be asked to clarify allegations of financial irregularities involving himself and a state coal mining company.</p>
<p>Sudjana has denied the allegations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
