<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="247877" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Tokyo stocks post solid gains by close.</title>
<headline>Tokyo stocks post solid gains by close.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tokyo stocks pocketed handsome gains on Tuesday, helped by Wall Street's rebound overnight and bullish semiconductor data, brokers said. They said investor interest in high-tech shares, in particular, propelled the indices.</p>
<p>The Nikkei 225 closed at 20,822.12, up 218.41 points or 1.06 percent. Its December futures gained 120 points to 20,790.</p>
<p>&quot;Blue-chip demand kept the benchmark at a healthy level, but when it neared 21,000, profit-taking pressure discouraged further gains,&quot; a &quot;Big Four&quot; trader said.  </p>
<p>The over-the-counter index rose 24.50 points or 1.8 percent to 1,384.61.</p>
<p>Nippon Telegraph and Telephone Corp (NTT) surged past the 900,000 yen level for the first time in over a year, finishing 29,000 yen higher at 912,000 yen.</p>
<p>&quot;NTT shares have been climbing steadily thanks to foreign investor buying after a restructuring plan was announced and the Tokyo market on the whole is being encouraged by the rise,&quot; one broker said.  </p>
<p>Shares of Toyota Motor finished at a record high of 3,270 yen after adding 20 yen. Promise Co Ltd fell on news that it would restrict the hours for lending at its ATM machines. It lost 50 yen to 5,690 yen.</p>
<p>Sahres in Suzutan Co Ltd continued to slide, losing another 27 yen to 420, after Japan's securities watchdog launched a probe on Monday into alleged improper insider trading by the company's president.</p>
<p>Among sectors, pulp/paper was the only major loser, but advancers were headed by credit/lease, air transport, ceramics, real estate and communications.--M. Iijima,Tokyo Equities Desk</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
