<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248036" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Bank of Spain has scope to cut rates - Caruana.</title>
<headline>Bank of Spain has scope to cut rates - Caruana.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>The latest reduction in Spanish government bond, or bonos, yields is giving the Bank of Spain room to reduce official rates, the general director of the Spanish Treasury Jaime Caruana told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The Treasury, following the market, has been reducing interest rates at every auction in a very speedy way. This gives the Bank of Spain scope,&quot; Caruana said in an interview recorded for Reuters Financial Television.</p>
<p>But he added that the decision is up to the central bank, which sets its policy to ensure stable prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank of Spain has to follow a monetary policy which procures stability in consumer prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Spanish economists are eyeing December 13 and 24, days of the Bank of Spain's next repos, as the days when the central bank could cut its key money market rate, currently at 6.75 percent.</p>
<p>December 13 would also be before the central bank can get a glimpse of the next set of consumer price data.</p>
<p>-- Tiziana Barghini, Madrid Newsroom, + 341 585 8340</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
