<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248094" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Dec 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Dec 10.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in this morning's Paris newspapers.</p>
<p>-- President Jacques Chirac and Chancellor Helmut Kohl aim to reach an agreement on a &quot;monetary stability pact&quot; when they next meet in Dublin on Friday and Saturday. Kohl reaffirms Germany will take part in Franco-German surveillance satellite programme, but delays financial involvement. (Les Echos, La Tribune, Le Figaro, Liberation).</p>
<p>LES ECHOS</p>
<p>-- Paris bourse's blue-chip CAC-40 index bounces back after last Friday's plunge.</p>
<p>-- Prime Minister Alain Juppe does not rule out breaking up Thomson prior to privatisation, first selling defence unit Thomson-CSF, then consumer electronics unit Thomson Multimedia.</p>
<p>-- Conservative parliamentarians suggest creation of &quot;first job contract&quot; for young unemployed, funded by state.</p>
<p>-- CGT union rail chief Bernard Thibault in an interview calls on government to abandon plan to create separate railways infrastructure company, demands return to multiannual rail contracts between state and SNCF.</p>
<p>LA TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- State-owned Caisse des Depots controls 90.59 percent of Credit Foncier de France after buyout, uncertainty reigns over the future of the Credit Foncier.</p>
<p>-- Club Mediterranee shares rise 8.8 percent on rumours of capital reshuffling after the five majority shareholders break their pact.</p>
<p>LE FIGARO-ECONOMIE</p>
<p>-- Eurotunnel shuttle service for passengers and cars to resume today after fire.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>LIBERATION (Economic section)</p>
<p>-- State-owned nuclear materials group Cogema, part of Framatome, may be consulted by United States which seeks to dispose of military plutonium and recycle it for electricity production.</p>
<p>-- Workers at oil refineries call for strike toaday against planned job cuts.</p>
<p>THE INTERNATIONAL HERALD TRIBUNE</p>
<p>-- Public cheer masks Franco-German discord over nature and ways of implementing a future &quot;monetary stability pact&quot;.</p>
<p>-- SGS-Thomson analog chip manufacturer expects a 1996 revenue around $ 4.1 billion.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 4221 5381</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
