<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248160" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India business not patriotic like Chinese, PM says.</title>
<headline>India business not patriotic like Chinese, PM says.</headline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda told Indian businessmen on Tuesday that they lacked the patriotism of their Chinese counterparts who had become key players in funding Beijing's economic reforms.</p>
<p>He told a meeting of the Federation of Indian Chambers of Commerce and Industry (FICCI) that of some $20 billion invested in China recently, 80 percent was funded by overseas Chinese.</p>
<p>&quot;This cannot be said about Indians,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Departing from his prepared speech, Deve Gowda questioned the commitment of businessmen to the country's welfare since independence from Britain in 1947.</p>
<p>&quot;How much Indian money has been siphoned out since independence?&quot; he asked. &quot;I am not going to blame the previous prime ministers, the finance ministers and the government alone. Let us collectively work together for the country.&quot;</p>
<p>Deve Gowda told FICCI's 69th annual meeting that he would consider their request to remove a recently introduced minimum alternate tax on companies when the next year's budget is prepared.</p>
<p>But he said it would be unfair to blame the tax, among other issues cited as the cause for a slide in the country's capital markets.</p>
<p>&quot;Too much sensational statistics is being fed in to suggest an economic slowdown,&quot; Deve Gowda said. &quot;It is true that certain sectors have to improve but others have done reasonably well.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
