<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248124" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - Dec 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Netherlands - Dec 10.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the main stories in Dutch newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>FINANCIEELE DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- British food and drink combine Grand Metropolitan emerges once again as possible buyer for Dutch BolsWessanen. (p1)</p>
<p>- Economic affairs minister Hans Wijers urges cabinet to cut collective tax and premium burden by Dfl 10 bn and boost investments by Dfl 4 bn a year. (p1)</p>
<p>- Amsterdam Stock Exchange association votes unanimously in favour of merger with EOE-option exchange. (p1)</p>
<p>- Dutch PTT (KPN) and textiles company Ten Cate have been awarded 1995 Henri Sijthoff Prize for the year's best financial reporting. (p1)</p>
<p>- Temp agency Randstad and unions reach agreement on wages for part-timers. (p2)</p>
<p>- Losses for shareholders in bankrupt sports-only TV channel Sport7 amount to a maximum of Dfl 280 million. (p3)</p>
<p>- Philips Electronics sells large TV plant in Greeneville in the U.S. (p3).</p>
<p>- Automation group Roccade sells its 50 pct stake in Raet to Getronics. (p3)</p>
<p>VOLKSKRANT</p>
<p>- Parliament wants to set up an independent institution to control price setting. (p2)</p>
<p>- Walloon government talks with steel concern Hoogovens about taking over steel firm Forges de Clabecq. (p2)</p>
<p>- Biochemicals and food group Gist-Brocades takes over dairy ingredients division of U.S. Cultor Food Science in New York. (p2)</p>
<p>- Expenditure on education in the Netherlands is relatively low, according to OECD report, Education at a Glance.</p>
<p>DE TELEGRAAF</p>
<p>- Amsterdam grants a discount on fines, if they are paid immediately. (p1)</p>
<p>- Real estate fund VastNed to issue new shares next spring to finance its planned takeover of rival Pays-Bas Property Fund. (p23)</p>
<p>- Banks are extremely wary of financing catering industry, according to catering industry association research. (p23)</p>
<p>- Software company AND International Publishers to get Amsterdam Stock Exchange listing on Thursday. (p25)</p>
<p>ALGEMEEN DAGBLAD</p>
<p>- French president Jacques Chirac increases pressure on Dutch to change liberal drugs policy. (p1)</p>
<p>- Coalition agrees on High-Speed rail link (HSL) after cabinet's willingness to invest an extra Dfl 250-300 million to remedy bottlenecks. (p1)</p>
<p>TROUW</p>
<p>- U.S. Lucent Technologies sheds 258 of the 833 jobs at its plant in Huizen. (p7)</p>
<p>- Motivation of Royal Dutch/Shell staff is deteriorating, due to reorganisations. (p7)</p>
<p>-- Amsterdam Newsdesk +31-20-504-5000 (FAX 31-20-504-5040)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
