<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248101" id="root" date="1996-12-10" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Dec 10.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Sweden - Dec 10.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following are some of the leading stories in the Swedish papers this morning. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>DAGENS NYHETER</p>
<p>- A new government environment package to be unveiled in the new year is expected to create several thousand new jobs over the next three years. The package will involve spending 13 billion crowns over three years.</p>
<p>- Export companies are more optimistic about the economy especially those involved in metals and the electronic industries, according to the latest figures from an industrial index, VI. The index for the fourth quarter showed an improvement in sentiment from three months ago.</p>
<p>SVENSKA DAGBLADET</p>
<p>- Employers do not want to pay additional sick pay, on top of the 75 percent of wages, that previous labor market deals give employees the right to following a two-week period of illness. Employers will have to pay the first 28 days of sick leave starting in 1997, an increase from the previous 14 days. Then, employers say that the deal about additional sick pay of 85 percent of wages is not valid anymore.</p>
<p>- Christmas underwear advertisements by Hennes &amp; Mauritz selling women's lingeries have been defaced across Stockholm with billboards smashed and other spray painted with feminist symbols.</p>
<p>- The Stockholm bourse continued to rise on Monday led up by drugs company Astra.</p>
<p>DAGENS INDUSTRI</p>
<p>- The battle for stock trading commissions in Sweden is heating up another notch. Net Fondkommission AB will become the first Swedish brokerage to offer large financial institutions an opportunity to bypass brokers and register trades directly on the Stockholm stock exchange. Net and two other brokerages have signed agreements with the bourse that will allow them to offer customers direct electronic trading.</p>
<p>- Motor vehicle starter manufacturer, Gylling Optima Batteries AB, has decided to raise new capital with a 80 million crown new share issue directed at the general public and part-owners Kjell Spanberg and Lennart Brag.</p>
<p>- Two Swedish forestry firms Sodra Skogsagarna AB and Stora Kopparbergs Bergslags AB have announced they will increase prices for long-fibre pulp to $610 a tonne from $560 in January. Several American companies have announced similar price hikes.</p>
<p>-- Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-10"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
