<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248364" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Burlington says 1997 budget $650 mln.</title>
<headline>Burlington says 1997 budget $650 mln.</headline>
<dateline>HOUSTON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burlington Resources Inc said on Wednesday that its exploration and production budget for 1997 would be $650 million, which is over $100 million larger than the 1996 capital program.</p>
<p>The company said that it expects the 1997 budget to provide for continued growth in production, replacement of produced reserves, and improvement in operating costs.  </p>
<p>The capital program is dominated by internal development and exploration spending exceeding $550 million, an increase of over 30 percent from the 1996 level, it said.</p>
<p>Burlington Resources said it plans to double exploration capital spending versus 1996 by implementing a $220 million program.</p>
<p>Drilling would account for 60 percent of the exploration budget with the remaining 40 percent to be spent on lease acquisitions and seismic data purchases to further add to the company's inventory of exploration opportunities.  </p>
<p>The company said that 60 operated and 25 non-operated exploratory wells are to be drilled.</p>
<p>Burlington said it would focus on the Ellenburger Trend in the Permian Basin of West Texas; the Deep Penn play in the San Juan Basin of New Mexico; the company's seven million mineral acres in Montana, North Dakota, and Wyoming; and both onshore and offshore Gulf Coast Basin.</p>
<p>The focus would include the Garden City Field in south Louisiana; the Vermilion and West Cameron areas in the Gulf of Mexico; and the recently acquired Eugene Island Block 205.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOUSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
