<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248339" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends uneventful session mostly weaker.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends uneventful session mostly weaker.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee futures ended mainly a touch lower in dull trade Wednesday, pressured by a bout of mixed commission house and local profit taking, floor sources said.</p>
<p>The market rallied this morning on speculative and trade buying, dealers said, touching off buy-stops in the active March contract near 109.00 cents a lb. But March stopped short of key psychological resistance at 110.00 cents, peaking at 109.50 cents.</p>
<p>March futures eased 0.10 cent per lb, to close at 108.10, after ranging from 109.50 to 107.10. May dipped 0.35, to 105.50, while spot December ended 1.25 higher at 119.00.</p>
<p>Turnover was fairly light, at an estimated 7,281 lots.</p>
<p>Traders said March futures appeared to be stuck in a near-term range between 110.00 and 107.00 cents, with keen producer selling seen above the 110.00 level and roaster interest at the dips.</p>
<p>On the fundamental side, traders await the U.S. Department of Agriculture's revised 1996/97 world coffee production estimate slated for release after Friday's close.</p>
<p>Analysts expected few changes from the June USDA figures, which put 1996/97 global output at 99.1 million 60-kg bags, up from 86.8 million bags the previous season.</p>
<p>In June, the USDA pegged top-grower Brazil's 1996/97 output at 27.5 million bags, while Colombia's crop was estimated at 13.0 million bags.</p>
<p>In the past, the December report has included a preliminary estimate of the next year's Brazilian crop, but USDA officials would not confirm that a forecast of the 1997/98 Brazilian coffee crop would be published this time.</p>
<p>Traders also await the U.S. Green Coffee Association of New York's November consumer coffee stock figures due after the close on Monday.</p>
<p>--Patricia Avidan, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
