<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24840" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: GM to keep most of its 82 models - WSJ.</title>
<headline>GM to keep most of its 82 models - WSJ.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>General Motors Corp has decided to keep most of its 82 models but to revamp many of them to differentiate them better and target them to consumers, The Wall Street Journal reported Friday.</p>
<p>GM has been the target of suggestions from some critics that it get rid of its many individual models. Although GM is moving to eliminate some models, it plans to introduce a like number of new ones over the next several years.</p>
<p>GM will try to define sharply the differences between a Pontiac and a Chevrolet and between a Buick and an Oldsmobile, using what it calls a &quot;brand management strategy,&quot; G. Richard Wagoner told the Journal. Wagoner is an executive vice president who has led the restructuring of GM's North American vehicle unit.</p>
<p>GM has traditionally defined itself by offering numerous vehicle models thorugh six marketing divisions, each of which has its own dealership system.</p>
<p>The rationale behind maintaining about the same number of models, Wagoner said, is that every existing vehicle has a potential customer base that GM is reluctant to abandon.</p>
<p>At the same time, GM is moving to capitalise on the truck boom by building more pickups and sport utility vehicles.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
