<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248516" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: OLYMPICS-ROME WARY OF EUROPEANS OVER 2004 GAMES BID.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-ROME WARY OF EUROPEANS OVER 2004 GAMES BID.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian Olympic Committee head Mario Pescante on Wednesday raised the fear that European countries could vote against Rome's bid for the 2004 Summer Games for reasons of self interest.</p>
<p>He also said that Rome, considered one of the front runners, faced very tough opposition from increasingly impressive presentations by Athens and other European cities but he expected Italy's bid to make the final shortlist.</p>
<p>Seven European cities -- Stockholm, Athens, France's Lille, Rome, Seville, Istanbul and St Petersburg -- are among the 11 candidates for 2004.</p>
<p>Pescante suggested that, even if ruled out early on, many would back a non-European bid to keep their hopes alive for 2008 since an Olympics staged in Europe would be unlikely to be followed by a Games on the same continent.</p>
<p>Athens, which tried and failed to win the centennial Games staged last summer in Atlanta, is seen by Rome as its major European competitor, although Cape Town is considered a sentimental and political favourite.</p>
<p>Pescante told an informal lunch for foreign journalists in Rome that Seville had made the best presentation at a recent IOC gathering in the Mexican resort of Cancun.</p>
<p>&quot;Seville had the best presentation at Cancun, I have to admit it. They have a good team. But they won't win because the memories of Barcelona are still too strong,&quot; said Pescante, one of three Italian members of the IOC.</p>
<p>He said he had &quot;the sensation&quot; that France was putting Lille forward as a trial run for a subsequent bid by Paris and wondered whether Madrid was similarly behind Seville.</p>
<p>&quot;This could mean that several countries will not vote for a European city,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;If England is hoping, if Germany is hoping, if Spain and France want the Games, it means more complications.&quot;</p>
<p>London and Germany's Ruhr region have announced they intend to bid for the 2008 Games with national backing.</p>
<p>Pescante said Athens had lost out last time because &quot;there was a power clash going on...the mayor was from one party and the head of the bid committee from another&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;We arrived in Athens and we were amazed. One said 'Come with us, forget him he won't be re-elected' or 'No, don't take that car, it belongs to the council'.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Italians, as Latins, are used to it. But the Swedes or Germans arrive and have the impression that one cannot live like that. That is what condemned Athens.&quot;</p>
<p>Pescante said the Greek capital had learned from the experience and was now strongly united behind the bid.</p>
<p>&quot;At a recent party to celebrate the Grand Duke of Luxembourg's 50th year in the IOC, (ex-king) Constantine of Greece talked of nothing other than Athens's bid,&quot; he said. &quot;It is a very united bid.&quot;</p>
<p>A shortlist of four or five cities will be selected at the end of March and the winner announced in September.</p>
<p>Rome, which hosted the 1960 Olympics, was praised in October by an IOC commission evaluating the bids for its security plans, its professionalism and proposed athletes' village.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
