<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248627" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Late bond market prices.</title>
<headline>Late bond market prices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is how major world bond markets were trading in late European business on Wednesday.</p>
<p>GERMANY - Bunds, futures extend losses as U.S. Treasuries slide, despite tame PPI data, which rose 0.4 percent, but with core PPI up 0.1 percent. The March Bund future on the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE) was trading at 99.92, down 0.88 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>BRITAIN - UK gilts fell sharply in seesaw trade after U.S. inflation data and slid further as locals watched selling on Wall Street gain pace. March long gilt future closed at 109-09, down 28/32. More downward pressure seen for Thursday. The March long gilt future on LIFFE was trading at 109-07/32, down 30/32 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>FRANCE - December bond future drops with U.S. bonds, Bunds. Concerns about stability pact weigh. BoF member's call for rate cuts helped contract reduce losses, boosted PIBOR on GLOBEX. The December notional bond future on the MATIF in Paris settled at 128.30 down 0.40 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>ITALY - Italian debt markets ended nearly 70 basis points down after markets generally gave a weak performance in a lacklustre day. Traders note however that Btps held up slightly better than Bunds and others with spread over Germany narrowing slightly - although lira wilted further against mark. The March bond future on LIFFE was trading at 127.90 down 0.58 from Tuesday's settlement price.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - U.S. Treasuries fall back to session lows in late morning. Bearish comments by Fed's Broaddus on inflation hurt mkt. Players said saw &quot;better buying&quot; after initial dive, supported by talk of widespread Fed and central bank buying. Fears of slowing Japanese buying add to negative sentiment. The March Treasury bond future on the Chicago Board of Trade was trading at 113-03/32, down 1-09/32 from Tuesday's settlement price. The long bond was quoted to yield 6.58 percent.</p>
<p>JAPAN - Key March Japanese goverment bonds (JGB) futures ended sharply down in Tokyo. Traders said there were rumours that public funds were selling cash JGBs. Tight supply and demand balance seen supporting JGBs on downside in the near term. In after hours trading the March future on LIFFE was trading at 124.98, down 0.51 from Tuesday's settlement price on the Tokyo Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>EUROBONDS - The primary market's stop-start end to the year was in stop mode on Wednesday with just a few deals launched. LB Schleswig-Holstein added a $100 million tranche to its recent June 2000 offering. ING set a 400 million Danish crown step-up 10-year bond. SGZ Bank emerged with a 250 million mark five-year FRN.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
