<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248620" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK's Clarke &quot;sympathises&quot; with Euro currecny.</title>
<headline>UK's Clarke &quot;sympathises&quot; with Euro currecny.</headline>
<byline>Richard Murphy</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Finance minister Kenneth Clarke on Wednesday expressed sympathy for a single European currency and accused anti-European members of the ruling Conservatives of wrecking Britain's negotiating position on the matter.</p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer Clarke, opening a two-day parliamentary debate on the European Union, ran into jeers from fellow Conservatives when he told them jettisoning the pound sterling would not mean joining a European superstate.</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Major's Conservatives are bitterly divided over the single currency, which the European Union plans to introduce from 1999.</p>
<p>Clarke said Britain was right to keep its options open on whether or not to join economic and monetary union (EMU).</p>
<p>&quot;I have made it quite clear that I am sympathetic to the idea of economic and monetary union,&quot; Clarke said.</p>
<p>&quot;Whatever we decide, whether in or out, EMU will affect us. British interest lies in staying involved and making sure that Britain's interests are protected and advanced.&quot;</p>
<p>Clarke, widely believed to be ready to resign if Major gives way to right-wing pressure over the single currency, said the government's freedom to opt in or out of monetary union was the envy of several of the other 15 EU member states.</p>
<p>Major has resisted strong pressure from back-benchers to declare now that Britain would never acquiesce in what they regard as a serious undermining of national sovereignty.</p>
<p>The debate is being staged ahead of a European Union summit meeting in Dublin this weekend, and follows persistent demands by some Conservative MPs for the government to rule out British membership of a single currency for the next five years.</p>
<p>Addressing his remarks chiefly to vociferous opponents on his own side of the house, Clarke said he was as opposed as any Conservative to the creation of a European &quot;superstate&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Treating the debate about EMU as if it were a debate about the creation of a superstate arouses public fears and deprives the public of sensible information about the issues,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In my view there are fewer and fewer people on the continent who see EMU as a tool for further political integration.&quot;</p>
<p>Commenting on current European discussions on a &quot;stability pact&quot; that could impose fines on countries within monetary union which ran up excessive budget deficits, Clarke said it was vital that the single currency -- or euro -- zone was properly set up.</p>
<p>&quot;No stability pact -- no matter how strict, no matter how dire the punishment for transgressions -- could hold such a euro zone together,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Clarke said he would probably favour Britain joining a single European currency if the advantages outweighed the disadvantages, but it was too soon to determine where the balance lay.</p>
<p>The opposition Labour party, which is well ahead of the Conservatives in opinion polls, said joining a single currency would not end Britain's freedom in other areas such as taxation.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not accept that that removes our freedom to make decisions on taxation and other issues in this House of Commons,&quot; finance spokesman Gordon Brown said during the debate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
