<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248729" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GHANA: Ghana's Rawlings inches towards election victory.</title>
<headline>Ghana's Rawlings inches towards election victory.</headline>
<byline>Harry Mouzalas</byline>
<dateline>ACCRA 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ghanaian President Jerry Rawlings inched towards victory on Wednesday in a slow-motion election count after Saturday's presidential and parliamentary poll.</p>
<p>Edward Mahama, who has been lying a distant third behind Rawlings and second-placed John Kufuor, threw in the towel as the president's victory looked like a foregone conclusion.</p>
<p>&quot;I want to avail myself of this opportunity...to concede that I am out of the race and to congratratulate Flight-Lieutenant J. J. Rawlings for his victory,&quot; Mahama of the People's National Convention said in a statement.</p>
<p>With results in from 179 of the 200 constituencies, Rawlings enjoyed a comfortable lead with 56 percent of votes.</p>
<p>His main rival, Kufuor of the opposition's Great Alliance, had 41 percent, according to the results from the National Election Commission. Mahama had less than three percent.</p>
<p>In the parliamentary ballot, the president's National Democratic Congress party had 117 seats in the 200-seat assembly. The combined opposition had 62 seats.</p>
<p>No incumbent has been re-elected since Ghana, which has a history of coups, won independence from Britain in 1957.</p>
<p>A landslide win in the parliamentary election would further strengthen the hand of Rawlings, who has dominated the West African nation's political scene for almost two decades.</p>
<p>Anxiety was running high in the capital Accra about the delayed announcement of the final result, which were originally expected on Monday or Tuesday.</p>
<p>Even Rawlings complained in a speech on Tuesday, saying the prolonged delay was unfortunate.</p>
<p>Proclamation of final results was expected late on Wednesday because of the need to double-check some returns from the interior, Election Commission chairman Kwadwo Afari-Gyan said.</p>
<p>Rawlings, 49, a charismatic former air force pilot, twice seized power in the West African nation. He ruled unchallenged for 15 years before first winning a popular mandate in 1992.</p>
<p>The election commission put turnout at about 80 percent.</p>
<p>Commonwealth and Organisation of African Unity observers have paid tribute to the conduct and fairness of the elections. &quot;This is by far the best organised election I have seen in West Africa,&quot; one Western monitor said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ACCRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GHANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
