<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248804" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria domestic debt rises 26 pct in November.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria domestic debt rises 26 pct in November.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's domestic debt rose by 171 billion levs to 839.3 billion levs in November because of a fall in the lev and new government securities issues placed to bridge the budget gap, Finance Ministry figures showed.</p>
<p>Some 114 billion levs of the rise were due to the lev decline, which boosted the price of dollar-denominated bad loan bonds and deposit guarantee bonds, figures showed.</p>
<p>Ten new treasury paper issues were sold to financial institutions last month to finance the central government budget deficit, boosting domestic debt by some 62.5 billion levs.</p>
<p>The lev fell to 354 per dollar on November 30 from 242 on November 1 in the central bank daily dollar fix used in the calculations.</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry has issued $79 million worth of floater coupon T-bonds this year so far to cover foreign currency deposits of companies and individuals in five of the 13 banks, against which the central bank has filed insolvency suits.</p>
<p>Bad debt bonds worth 32 billion levs and $1.8 billion respectively were issued two years ago to cover banks' non-performing loans extended to state companies before 1991. @</p>
<p>The Finance Ministry said recently it planned to meet most maturity and coupon payments on treasury papers by rollover issues of government securities to bridge the budget gap.</p>
<p>The central government budget deficit topped the annual target by 92.5 percent in November, rising to 155.4 billion levs.</p>
<p>The parliament tentatively approved on Friday a budget revision including a 115 billion lev loan to the government to cover domestic debt payments, despite the central bank's opposition.</p>
<p>The revision, this year's second, was sought by the government after it overshot the macroeconomic targets in the July revision. The bill will have a second reading this week. -- Anastas Petrov, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-876032</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
