<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="248906" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish brokerages' gross PLN 111.63 mln in Q1-Q3.</title>
<headline>Polish brokerages' gross PLN 111.63 mln in Q1-Q3.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Polish brokerage houses grossed 111.63 million zlotys profit in the first three quarters of this year against a 36 million zloty gross profit in the whole of 1995 and 140 million in 1994, the Central Statistical Office said.</p>
<p>Total revenue of brokerages in the first nine months was 541.3 million zlotys of which income from broking and advising services accounted for 259.9 million zlotys.</p>
<p>&quot;The main source of revenue for brokerages was the income from broking and advising services which almost doubled against last year,&quot; the Office (GUS) said in a report.</p>
<p>It said brokerage margins accounted for almost 70 percent of their revenue.</p>
<p>Out of the country's 50 brokerages 28 reported a gross profit in the first three quarters of this year and 22 reported a loss, GUS said.</p>
<p>It said brokerages' operating costs were 35.2 percent higher than in 1995 and after the first three quarters were at 429.6 million zlotys.</p>
<p>The number of accounts opened rose in the first nine months by 18.3 percent against 1995 to 976,900.</p>
<p>&quot;The rise in the number of accounts can be explained by the transformation of the mass privatisation certificates into paperless form and a bullish bourse,&quot; GUS said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
