<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249073" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil banks seen gaining with stock sale overseas.</title>
<headline>Brazil banks seen gaining with stock sale overseas.</headline>
<byline>Fatima Cristina</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Brazilian government decree allowing local banks to issue stock for trading overseas will open a new door to cheaper funding, boosting liquidity and raising exposure to foreign investors, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the healthiest way to raise money abroad,&quot; said Mario Alberto Dias Lopes Coelho, an analyst at Austin Asis banking consulting firm.</p>
<p>President Fernando Henrique Cardoso earlier this week signed a decree allowing Brazilian banks to sell non-voting shares and issue American Depositary Receipts (ADRs) abroad.  </p>
<p>The proposal had been approved by a meeting of the National Monetary Council (CMN) in October.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very positive because banks will be allowed to increase capital without losing control,&quot; said Nuno Fernandes of Caspian Securities in New York.</p>
<p>Analysts added that the sale of preferred shares overseas will increase the liquidity of Brazilian bank stocks and raise the profile of the country's major financial institutions in the international markets.  </p>
<p>Currently 29 Brazilian banks, including federal, state and investment banks, are listed on the Sao Paulo Stock Exchange (Bovespa), but brokers noted trade is concentrated on large banks like Bradesco, Banco Itau and federal bank Banco do Brasil.</p>
<p>Analysts also said banks are the companies which traditionally pay more dividends, which may encourage foreigners to increase their investment in bank stocks.  </p>
<p>&quot;If a foreign investor is looking for dividends, the banking sector is an attractive investment opportunity,&quot; said Ricardo Jorge Hinrichsen, from Sirotsky &amp; Associados consulting firm.</p>
<p>Moreover, Brazilian banks will have to improve bookkeeping practices to comply with U.S. accounting standards in order to issue ADRs, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;This will make Brazil's banking system much more transparent,&quot; said Guilherme Ache, research chief at local investment bank Banco Pactual.  </p>
<p>Initially, only Brazil's largest banks will be likely to sell non-voting shares overseas.</p>
<p>But once the bigger institutions are listed on foreign markets, small and mid-sized banks also will begin looking for ways to offer stock to investors abroad, analysts said.</p>
<p>Market sources said that Bradesco and Unibanco are likely to be the first banks to issue ADRs in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>Officials at those banks were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>-- Sao Paulo Newsroom, 55-11-2485412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
