<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249135" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BURMA: Burma says U.S. preparing sanctions amid unrest.</title>
<headline>Burma says U.S. preparing sanctions amid unrest.</headline>
<byline>Vithoon Amorn</byline>
<dateline>RANGOON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Burma said on Wednesday the United States was seeking to use government restrictions on opposition leader Aung San Suu Kyi's movements during current student unrest as an excuse to impose sanctions.</p>
<p>The U.S. embassy in Rangoon denied the charge.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. embassy has tried to bring her outside, knowing that it will be refused. I can see the trend is definitely heading toward creating more pressure for sanctions,&quot; a senior government official told Reuters.</p>
<p>The official repeated an earlier clarification that the ruling State Law and Order Restoration Council's (SLORC) request for Suu Kyi to temporarily confine herself in her house was made out of sincere concern for her safety.</p>
<p>A U.S. embassy spokeswoman said: &quot;We are not trying to create anything. Perhaps the easiest way to resolve this is to check with the individual concerned.</p>
<p>&quot;Why don't you ask Aung San Suu Kyi if she is being unlawfully detained?&quot; she added.</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton in early October slapped a visa ban on senior SLORC officials after Rangoon arrested hundreds of pro-democracy activists in late September.</p>
<p>The U.S. Senate in July passed legislation allowing Clinton to impose economic sanctions if repression in Burma worsened or if Suu Kyi was rearrested.</p>
<p>The SLORC had asked the Nobel Peace laureate not to leave her lakeside residence for two days last week after Rangoon's biggest street protests since pro-democracy uprisings in 1988.</p>
<p>Suu Kyi's aides said she had since chosen to stay inside her compound rather than seek government approval to go out.</p>
<p>Officials of her National League for Democracy party (NLD) said she had also declined to go out to avoid being drawn into the unrest, which had become more muted by Wednesday.</p>
<p>Burmese security forces arrested about 20 students following scattered protests in the tightly secured capital Rangoon, witnesses and diplomats said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Some 50 Yangon University students held a brief anti-government protest in front of the U.S. embassy in the centre of the city late on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;They gathered near the embassy after either walking or taking buses to the embassy. About 20 students were arrested,&quot; a student source said. &quot;We want to continue protesting but it is difficult to organise now.&quot;</p>
<p>Police and soldiers kept watch at checkpoints around the university and the Yangon Institute of Technology for the sixth straight day.</p>
<p>All university campuses have been closed since Monday. Student sources said on Wednesday that campus authorities had told parents to take home boarding students for two weeks.</p>
<p>Last week's anti-government student street protests were Rangoon's biggest since 1988 pro-democracy uprisings, which were crushed by the military, leaving thousands killed or in jail.</p>
<p>At the peak of the recent protests, thousands of students from two colleges took to the streets. Authorities broke up the demonstrations, held over 860 students and later freed them.</p>
<p>The students were protesting against alleged police brutality during a brawl in October between some institute students and restaurant owners. They also want to be allowed to set up student unions on campus.</p>
<p>Official Burmese media on Wednesday quoted top officials of the SLORC as warning against further disturbances.</p>
<p>Powerful military intelligence chief Lieutenant General Khin Nyunt told Burmese writers at a ceremony on Wednesday to beware of the threat to Burma posed by internal and external destructive elements. He did not identify the elements.</p>
<p>Diplomats said the SLORC had issued circulars to all embassies in Rangoon, informing them the SLORC had exercised maximum restraint despite sustained student protests.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BURMA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RANGOON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BURMA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
