<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249187" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Manila says trade reforms will not harm farmers.</title>
<headline>Manila says trade reforms will not harm farmers.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippines rejected on Wednesday claims by a British-based aid group that farm trade liberalisation will harm the country's corn farmers and said the basic premise of the report is &quot;flawed.&quot;</p>
<p>Oxfam, a privately funded aid group, said in a report that the Philippine's move last year to liberalise corn imports would badly affect the six million people dependent on corn farming in the country.  </p>
<p>&quot;Their reasoning is flawed,&quot; Philippine Agriculture Secretary Salvador Escudero III told Reuters in an interview after reading Oxfam's report at the World trade Organization (WTO) ministerial meeting in Singapore.</p>
<p>&quot;The people they are referring to do not plant corn exclusively. These people plant corn in between planting other crops. The imports they are referring to are mainly yellow corn, which we are importing for industrial use,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>The Philippine official said that corn imports, which are expected to reach as high as 500,000 tonnes in calendar year 1997 compared with 400,000 tonnes this year, will not displace farmers because most of them plant white corn.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of our farmers plant white corn, which is for human consumption,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Oxfam said in its report made available at the Singapore coonference that the replacement of a quota system in the Philippines with a tariff system in line with WTO rules will expose &quot;domestic producers to increasingly intense competition from imports.&quot;  </p>
<p>The group also accused the U.S. of providing up to US$5.0 billion in subsidies to American corn farmers. Washington has said it no longer provides subsidies to U.S. farmers.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
