<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249375" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Spot US propane steady to high, data awaited.</title>
<headline>Spot US propane steady to high, data awaited.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot propane prices were steady to higher in thin trade late Wednesday ahead of Energy Information Administration data on stocks and retailer demand in the Midwest, players said.</p>
<p>EIA data is to be released later Wednesday and many players said they were expecting a draw.</p>
<p>In the Midwest, spot propane had a day of jumpy activity, trading in the morning at 72.25 cents and then later at 81.50 cents. The latest deal was in the mid-79.00 cent range.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been all over the place,&quot; said one Conway player, adding &quot;a couple of retailers have been in the market snooping.&quot;</p>
<p>In general, many retailers have held off on buying barrels for winter heating storage in anticipation that high prices seen throughout the summer and fall will come down.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, sagging NYMEX crude oil futures kept a lid on prices in the U.S. Gulf Coast, where trade was very thin.</p>
<p>Mont Belvieu, Texas, spot propane held steady between 54.25 cents and 54.75 cents a gallon, about two cents below Tuesday.</p>
<p>The lower propane prices took down ethane, which was in the 36.00 range in late trade.</p>
<p>-- Laney Salisbury, New York Energy Desk, 212 859-1631</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
