<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249377" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX electricity trims loss amid natgas recovery.</title>
<headline>NYMEX electricity trims loss amid natgas recovery.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX electricity settled lower Wednesday, trimming an earlier loss amid a rebound in the natural gas market, market sources said.</p>
<p>The electricity complex was pressured for most the session due to above-normal temperatures and outlook of abundant hydropower in the Northwest and California next week.</p>
<p>A late recovery in the Gulf Coast gas market, tied to revised forecasts of cold weather in Texas and the Northeast this weekend, lifted prices at other major receipt points around the U.S.</p>
<p>January natgas prices delivered to the San Juan/Blanco Hub finished at $3.15-$3.23 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>January 1997 California-Oregon Border (COB) futures settled down 21 cents at $23.90 a megawatt hour (MWh) after bouncing between $23.40 and $24.50.</p>
<p>The February COB contract finished up 20 cents at $19.00. Other COB months were inactive.</p>
<p>January Palo Verde (PV) futures settled down 31 cents, cutting a dollar loss.</p>
<p>February PV finished up eight cents at $19.46. Deferred PV contracts ended five to 50 cents lower.</p>
<p>Despite bearish fundamentals for electricity, short-term outlook for the complex remained linked to natural gas, brokers and traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;We held support for the past three days,&quot; said a Houston trader, noting January COB appeared well-supported at $23.40 and January PV $23.75.</p>
<p>Thursday's temperatures in the Rockies and Pacific Northwest were predicted to peak in 30s-50s degrees Fahrenheit and bottom in the teens to 30s. Those in the Southwest were forecast to peak in the 50s-70s and bottom in the 30s-50s.</p>
<p>Extended outlook indicated the western half of the country would remain warmer-than-normal through the end of the week with periods of scattered showers.</p>
<p>--New York Power Desk +1 212 859 1622</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
