<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249497" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX natgas stay mixed late, fronts hold gains.</title>
<headline>NYMEX natgas stay mixed late, fronts hold gains.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures remained mixed late Wednesday in moderate trade, with front months holding modest gains on reports of firmer cash but still bound in recent technical ranges, sources said.</p>
<p>At 1400 EST, January was up 2.4 cents at $3.42 per million British thermal units after climbing early to $3.52. February was 4.5 cents higher at $3.175. Others were mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;Cash firmed this morning. It was playing catch up with the screen, but the weather is not that supportive,&quot; said one Texas-based trader, adding he expected prices to test the lower end of the recent range.  </p>
<p>Technical traders pegged January resistance in the low-$3.50s and then at $3.70. Support was seen at $3.19, then $3.11 and then $3.04.</p>
<p>Traders said an early rally on rumors of a U.S. Gulf production problem lost steam after news a small fire on a Mobil offshore Louisiana gas platform cut only 43 mmcfd.</p>
<p>A Reuter poll on Wednesday's weekly AGA gas stock report showed most expected an 84-92 bcf draw. Last year at this time inventories fell by 75 bcf.</p>
<p>Northeast temperatures were expected to remain slightly above-normal through Friday, then return to more seasonal levels by Saturday. In Texas, well above-normal temperatures were expected to ease to more normal levels by the weekend.</p>
<p>In the cash, Gulf Coast prices firmed 20 cents early Wednesday to about the $3.40 level. Midcon pipes gained 15 cents or more to the mid-$3.30s. Gas at the New York City gate was talked little changed in the $4.05-4.10 range.</p>
<p>NYMEX said 27,929 Hub contracts traded by 1330 EST.</p>
<p>NYMEX Alberta natgas remained untraded at 1400 EST, with January bid two cents lower at $1.61.</p>
<p>NYMEX Permian natgas also was untraded at 1400 EST.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, January was still one-half cent higher at $3.26, while deferreds were steady to five cents higher. The East/West spread widened by 1.9 cents to 16.0 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
