<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249458" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: N.Y. top insurance regulator to leave for new job.</title>
<headline>N.Y. top insurance regulator to leave for new job.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>New York's top insurance regulator Edward Muhl will leave the insurance department to join Peterson Consulting LLC, effective December 30, the consulting firm said.</p>
<p>The New York insurance department said Muhl's departure was not official yet and declined further immediate comment, saying a statement would be forthcoming later in the week.</p>
<p>Muhl, who has been superintendent of insurance for the state of New York since 1995, will become executive vice president and member of the board of Peterson Consulting.  </p>
<p>Peterson Consulting, which is an independent international firm, said Muhl will have offices in Philadelphia and New York and will travel extensively.</p>
<p>Muhl commented on his departure in a statement released by Peterson.</p>
<p>&quot;Peterson Consulting LLC has an excellent reputation for service to its clients and a particular strength in serving the insurance industry,&quot; Muhl said in the statement.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe I've found the aggressive entrepreneurial environment where I can make a significant contribution to problem solving for our clients,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;I had committed to the Governor to remain as Superintendent as long as it took to resolve the significant issues pending before the department and to organize and reform the department's regulatory direction,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have accomplished what we set out to do in a relatively short period of time due in major part to the quality of the department's staff,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Governor Pataki, in the Peterson statement said: &quot;Superintendent Muhl was extremely successful in balancing the interests of our citizens, the industry and government. I am pleased with the job Ed has done for New York and this administration.&quot;</p>
<p>Muhl was appointed Superintendent of Insurance by the governor in late 1994 and was confirmed by the senate in early 1995.</p>
<p>Peterson Consulting said it has 550 insurance professionals, accounting, business, engineering and computer specialists who help clients manage the economics of disputes, regulation and change.</p>
<p>-- 212-859-1716</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
