<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249518" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fidelity cuts Magellan management fees by a third.</title>
<headline>Fidelity cuts Magellan management fees by a third.</headline>
<byline>Michael Ellis</byline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fidelity Investments cut the management fee charged on its flagship Magellan Fund by more than a third due to its poor performance this year, according to the company's monthly fund guide.</p>
<p>The fee for the massive mutual fund, the largest in the United States, fell from 0.73 percent of total assets at the end of March to 0.47 percent at the end of September, costing the mutual fund company tens of millions of dollars.</p>
<p>The monthly fee is based on the fund's performance relative to the 36-month moving average of the S&amp;P 500.  </p>
<p>It is reported twice a year,</p>
<p>&quot;In this case there was a negative performance adjustment and the managment fee has come down as a result,&quot; said Fidelity spokesman Scott Beyerl.</p>
<p>Beyerl said Fidelity collected $127.3 million in management fees for the six months ended Sept. 30, down from $175.7 million over the same six-month period last year.</p>
<p>David O'Leary, president of Fidelity watchers Alpha Equity Research, said the change may cost the company and the fund managers as much as $150 million a year.  </p>
<p>&quot;That's not going to make (Fidelity President) Ned Johnson happy,&quot; O'Leary said.</p>
<p>Eric Kobren, president of the independent publication Fidelity Insight, said the management fee cut at Magellan and other funds may have been behind the recent number of fund manager departures from Fidelity.</p>
<p>Magellan, weighed down by a heavy exposure to bonds, fell below the S&amp;P 500 36-month moving average in April for the first time in seven years. Despite the departure of fund manager Jeffrey Vinik in June, Magellan has continued to fall behind the strong returns of the market index.  </p>
<p>&quot;It still hasn't turned the corner. It doesn't help to have eight percent (of assets) in bonds when the market is going up,&quot; O'Leary said. &quot;I'm shocked he didn't sell more of the bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>Robert Stansky, who took over Magellan from Vinik, cut the fund's stake in bonds to 8.7 percent of assets at the end of October, the most recent date data is available. That's down from 9.8 percent at the end of September and 20.7 percent when Vinik departed at the end of May, but still too high for O'Leary and other Magellan watchers.  </p>
<p>While the stock market rose to record levels in November, with the Dow Jones Industrial Average gaining 8.36 percent and the S&amp;P500 rising 7.56 percent during the month, Magellan rose only 6.47 percent, according to the fund guide.</p>
<p>Magellan's total assets rose to $55.9 billion at the end of November from $53.2 billion at the end of October, according to the fund guide, but investors pulled out more than $800 million in November, O'Leary said.</p>
<p>Magellan's investments in stocks rose in October to 89.8 percent of total assets from 88.9 percent at the end of September, according to the fund guide.</p>
<p>Stansky raised Magellan's stake in technology stocks to 11.6 percent of total assets at the end of October from 10.1 percent at the end of September and increased investments in healthcare companies to 3.3 percent at at the end of October, up from nil in September, the fund guide said.</p>
<p>    -- Boston bureau (617) 367-4176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
