<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249511" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. may require NASD exam for bankers selling funds.</title>
<headline>U.S. may require NASD exam for bankers selling funds.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank employees who sell mutual funds or securities would have to pass the same exams brokerage firm employees take, under a rule proposed Wednesday by U.S. bank regulators.</p>
<p>The rule would require bankers who sell mutual funds to take examinations administered by the National Association of Securities Dealers. Those who sell stocks or bonds would take a more extensive exam.</p>
<p>About 3,000 employees at 300 banks -- about 15 percent of the 2,000 U.S. banks that sell mutual funds -- would be affected by the rule, according to the Federal Reserve.</p>
<p>The vast majority of banks already have brokerage firm employees selling such products, according to the Fed, which proposed the rule jointly with the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;The regulation will ensure that bank sales representatives have adequate product and regulatory knowledge pertaining to those securities being recommended and sold at the retail level,&quot; the regulators said in the proposed rule.</p>
<p>Bank sales of mutual funds are rising rapidly, growing to $11.4 billion in the second quarter of this year from $8.6 billion in the first quarter of 1994, the Fed said.</p>
<p>Surveys have shown that bank customers are sometimes confused about the difference between bank accounts, which are insured by the government against loss, and investments in funds and securities, which generally have no such guarantees.</p>
<p>The American Bankers Association praised the proposed rule. Donald Ogilvie, executive vice president at the trade group, said bank employees already took classes and seminars like brokerage employees but &quot;could not prove to the public that their training and qualifications met industry standards.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Now they can,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
