<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249616" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Market watchdogs to focus on Internet - BAWe.</title>
<headline>Market watchdogs to focus on Internet - BAWe.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Market regulators will be keeping an increasingly close eye on the impact of the Internet on securities trading and information, the head of Germany's securities watchdog, the BAWe, said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;IOSCO (International Organisation of Securities Commissions) and its members will keep their eye on Internet developments and submit suggestions about monitoring securities trading over the Internet at a later point,&quot; BAWe President Georg Wittich said in the text of a speech for delivery to a university audience.</p>
<p>The text was made available in advance.</p>
<p>The BAWe itself would take a more intensive look than usual at use of the Internet in its annual review of German securities firms, with particular emphasis on cross-border usage, Wittich said.</p>
<p>Wittich said the BAWe's efforts in the two years since it started operations to monitor German securities dealing and ensure more market transparency were bearing concrete results.</p>
<p>So far this year, the agency passed on 21 cases of suspected insider dealing to public prosecutors, of which seven had led to prosecution, Wittich said.</p>
<p>The BAWe, whose central task is to enforce Germany's new ban on insider dealing, monitors hundreds of thousands of reports of securities transactions daily and investigates any potential aberrations.</p>
<p>The agency also registered 1,290 so-called ad-hoc reports -- reports of market-moving news which German companies are now obliged to produce on a regular basis -- in the first three quarters of 1996 compared with 1,441 in 1995 as a whole.</p>
<p>The new rule that forces German companies to reveal shareholdings of more than five percent had also boosted market transparency, Wittich said.</p>
<p>&quot;Better market transparency is at the same time the most effective measure to prevent insider dealing,&quot; Wittich said.</p>
<p>Wittich made no comment in his speech to a controversial interview he gave on Wednesday to the Handelsblatt newspaper, in which he appeared to offer a loose interpretation of insider dealing.</p>
<p>Wittich was quoted as saying that certain uses of privileged market information may not be illegal and the decisive factor in deciding whether to punish insider trading was the degree of impact the transactions had on the price of the stock involved.</p>
<p>The Handelsblatt interpreted Wittich's comments as a green light for brokers to engage in insider dealing -- a meaning which Germany's Stock Exchange head Werner Seifert later said had been misconstrued.</p>
<p>--Frankfurt Newsroom, +49 69 756525</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I33030">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
