<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249635" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Flood damage cost $2.2 billion - N.Korean minister.</title>
<headline>Flood damage cost $2.2 billion - N.Korean minister.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Korean Foreign Minister Kim Yong-nam said in an interview broadcast on Wednesday floods had caused damage of around $2.2 billion this year and left the country with a &quot;significant&quot; shortfall in food supplies.</p>
<p>The Stalinist state had previously put the damage from the July floods at $1.7 billion.</p>
<p>Kim's remarks, in an interview with Germany's ZDF television, appeared to be an unusually frank admission by a senior member of the secretive country's government.</p>
<p>He also said the North Korean economy had been hit hard by the demise of its communist allies in eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union.</p>
<p>&quot;A further cause of our economic difficulties are the environmental catastrophes which hit our country in 1995 and 1996. A significant shortfall in food supplies resulted from these,&quot; Kim added.</p>
<p>&quot;Floods after heavy rain in 1995 caused damage of around $15 billion,&quot; he said, according to a German translation of his remarks provided for ZDF by his ministry.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1996, the storms hit the rice-growing areas of the western coast. The damage was $2.2 billion.&quot;</p>
<p>Aid agencies have already warned the country faces a large shortfall in essential food supplies.</p>
<p>Official figures show North Korea will need 5.5 million tonnes of grain next year, but this year's harvest had yielded just 3.5 million tonnes, International Red Cross officials based in Pyongyang have said.</p>
<p>Kim told ZDF, which said its team was the first from a western European television company to be allowed into North Korea since 1992, that he would welcome more German investment.</p>
<p>&quot;Our country is in the middle of of northeastern Asia, so it's strategically important,&quot; he said. &quot;There are many opportunities for economic involvement.&quot;</p>
<p>Kim said in the interview, recorded on November 26, that he was sure his country's economic difficulties were temporary and thanked foreign countries, particularly Germany, for their humanitarian help.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
