<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249713" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Argentaria to use 96 profits to cut costs.</title>
<headline>Argentaria to use 96 profits to cut costs.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spain's Corporacion Bancaria de Espana (Argentaria) said on Wednesday it would used 42 billion pesetas from this year's profits to reduce its financial costs.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to anticipate the future in order to increase financial margin and the dividend in the next few years,&quot; chairman Francisco Gonzalez said in a press statement.</p>
<p>The Bank of Spain and the banking group's external auditors had approved the decision, aimed at &quot;maximising shareholder value&quot;, the chairman said.</p>
<p>Given the effective savings this will produce, Argentaria said it will propose to the general shareholders' meeting a total dividend of 277 pesetas gross per share against 1996 results, of which 128 pesetas were already paid in October. 1995's total dividend was 270 pesetas.</p>
<p>The bank also said the board had named Francisco Gomez Roldan CEO for the group, and Ramon Bustamente as non-executive vice-chairman.</p>
<p>1996 earnings would be used to &quot;drastically reduce the average interest rate on large-scale liabilities taken on at fixed and long-term interest rates&quot;, as part of the strategy to strengthen the group, the note said.</p>
<p>The move will &quot;significantly improve net interest income and profits in 1997 and following years, as well as ROE and earnings per share,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
