<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249730" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Germany loses initial court battle in deposits row.</title>
<headline>Germany loses initial court battle in deposits row.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Court of Justice advocate-general Philippe Leger has rejected Germany's attempt to outlaw the deposits guarantee directive 94/19/EC, a Court official said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>If the court follows the advocate-general's opinion, which it generally does, it would clear the way for final agreement on a similar draft directive to protect small investors when an investment firm goes bankrupt.</p>
<p>Germany took the Council and the European Parliament to court in 1995 for adopting, against its will, a directive which provides minimum compensation of 20,000 Ecus for bank deposits when a failed firm's assets are not sufficient to cover its liabilities.</p>
<p>The German government argued in court that this was a question of subsidiarity, but the advocate-general stated that the subsidiarity principle should be better defined to avoid other legal disputes, the official said.</p>
<p>Germany particularly contested provisions banning German banks from exporting their generous protection schemes to other EU markets. It also opposed the so-called topping-up clause which allows branches of other EU banks in Germany to join the local guarantee scheme.</p>
<p>The draft directive on investor compensation schemes, COM(96)169, is ripe for final agreement between parliament and Council. A conciliation committee on the legislation is scheduled to meet on December 18.</p>
<p>The court ruling is expected within the next three months, the court official said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
