<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249709" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Irish bonds well down, little overseas interest.</title>
<headline>Irish bonds well down, little overseas interest.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Irish bonds were well down in thin trade on Wednesday amid a lack of overseas interest in the domestic market, dealers said.</p>
<p>Dealers said comments made by the Irish central bank in its quarterly bulletin had not helped.</p>
<p>&quot;The central bank is guarded on its inflation outlook for next year and that is negative for the market,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;All told, the Irish market is very weak with few people overseas interested in playing. We really are on the outskirts of things at the moment,&quot; the dealer added.</p>
<p>By 1620 GMT, the 6.5 percent bond due 2001 had slipped 80 pence to 100.95 to yield 6.16 percent while the eight percent bond due 2006 had eased 85 pence to 108.00 to yield 6.72 percent.</p>
<p>The Irish central bank said in its quarterly bulletin that it expects GNP to grow at 6.0 percent in 1996 followed by a modest deceleration to 5.0 percent in 1997. It said that inflation for the year as a whole is now expected to average 1.7 percent.</p>
<p>Following three years of very strong growth, however, some pick-up in inflation is expected, it warned. The bank forecast consumer price inflation of 2.3 percent in 1997.</p>
<p>It said that it did not target any bilateral exchange rate and there was nothing sacrosanct about sterling parity. An official said the bank was more concerned about the EMU criterion on price stability than currency stability.</p>
<p>Dealers said the market awaited the start of the European Union finance ministers' meeting in Dublin on Thursday and the two-day EU summit meeting in Dublin, starting on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be interesting to see what transpires at the summit. I don't expect any deal to be made between Germany and France over the matter of fines if countries don't meet the deficit criteria,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>--Damien Lynch, Dublin newsroom +353-1-660-3377</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
