<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="24974" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq's Hamdoun says minor problems hinder oil deal.</title>
<headline>Iraq's Hamdoun says minor problems hinder oil deal.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq's U.N. ambassador Nizar Hamdoun said on Friday that minor problems still needed to be resolved before his country's oil-for-food deal with the United Nations could be implemented.</p>
<p>Hamdoun also said that certain parties were seeking to delay implementation of the plan, but Baghdad was determined to carry it out as it believed it would be the prelude to total removal of U.N. sanctions, imposed after Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;The fixing of a time limit concerning outstanding minor points is insignificant against what has been achieved in this field,&quot; he said in an interview with the official al-Iraq newspaper.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;We have to remember that there are certain circles which through constant procrastination are trying to delay.&quot; He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>Iraq and the U.N. agreed in May on how to apply a 1995 Security Council offer for Baghdad to export limited quantities of its blocked oil exports to pay for urgent humanitarian needs.</p>
<p>Differences on procedural issues have delayed implementation of the plan, allowing exports worth $2 billion over six months of which $1.13 billion will remain at Iraq's disposal after paying 30 per cent for the 1991 Gulf War reparations and other U.N. costs.</p>
<p>A U.N. relief official in Baghdad said discussions with the Iraqi side were still continuing to try to resolve issues pertaining to the number of international monitors to be placed in Iraq to supervise distribution of food.</p>
<p>Holdbrook Arthur, director of the United Nations World Food Programme (WFP) in Iraq, said that apart from monitors he needed to solve &quot;serious operational problems&quot; related to the transport and handing out of food rations to rebel Kurds in northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;I am concerned about the number of monitors but for me their significance is down the line. For me there are other issues to consider which are more important,&quot; Arthur told Reuters.</p>
<p>He said the difficulties were not insurmountable but would hamper smooth distribution to the Iraqi Kurds once the humanitarian supplies started pouring in.</p>
<p>The Rome-based WFP sent Arthur to Iraq to administer the relief programme emanating from the oil-for-food scheme. Arthur was WFP's country director in Somalia, Rwanda, Burundi and Tanzania before assuming his Iraq post early this month.</p>
<p>He said he met senior Iraqi officials on Thursday and would travel to northern Iraq on Saturday to report on the problems.</p>
<p>&quot;They (Iraqis) have promised to resolve any difficulty I may face,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hamdoun said he believed Iraqi crude would reach international markets in a short time. He gave no specific date.</p>
<p>&quot;The implementation of the memorandum of understanding will constitute an important opening...for the total lifting of the economic embargo,&quot; Hamdoun said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
