<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249700" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish shares end lower on international trends.</title>
<headline>Swedish shares end lower on international trends.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>In line with international trends, Swedish shares ended lower on Wednesday as Federal Reserve chairman Alan Greenspan's Friday comments about &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; of financial markets lingered.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is noticeably cautious after Greenspan's statement last Friday and it feels as if nervousness will continue tomorrow,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>The general index dropped 1.81 percent to 2,281.97 in turnover of 3.98 billion crowns.</p>
<p>Plummeting shares in drugs company Astra also had a negative impact. The stock closed 9.5 crowns down at 329.5.</p>
<p>Astra, which has been driven by rumours that Swiss rival Roche will place a takeover bid on the company, started falling back on Tuesday as rumours subsided.</p>
<p>On Wednesday, investment company Investor's chief executive Claes Dahlback said that Roche had not contacted Investor about its Astra stake. Investor dropped four crowns to 281 crowns.</p>
<p>Telecommunications group Ericsson dropped five crowns to 200 crowns. But the market took little notice that the company was sued by U.S. telecommunications group Qualcomm regarding patents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
