<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249829" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Afghan airline, still flying in the face of ruin.</title>
<headline>Afghan airline, still flying in the face of ruin.</headline>
<byline>Tim Johnston</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>After 17 years of war, Afghanistan is a country of memories: its infrastructure and industry lie in ruins, its middle class have mostly fled, and survival is the over-riding concern for much of its remaining population.</p>
<p>But small reminders of a pre-war normality still exist.</p>
<p>The national airline, Ariana, has survived -- just -- and is attempting to rebuild its past glory.</p>
<p>&quot;We were better than any other airline in the region,&quot; says Ad Sharza; one of the founders of the airline, a former colonel in the U.S. Air Force and Ariana's current General Manager.</p>
<p>Ariana is a fading echo of its former self. Its fleet consists of four 40-year-old Boeing 727s and a Soviet-built Tupolev.</p>
<p>The glory days when the young and adventurous used to board its planes in London, Paris and Rome to fly to the east ended with the Soviet invasion of Afghanistan in 1979.</p>
<p>By changing to accommodate new masters and ideologies, the airline has managed to stay intact.</p>
<p>The most recent change happened in late September when the purist Islamic Taleban seized control of Kabul.</p>
<p>In line with Taleban policy that banned women from working, stewardesses were told to stay at home, although they still receive their salary.</p>
<p>Destinations such as Delhi, Tashkent and Mashad in Iran -- all in countries the Taleban believe supported the ousted government -- were dropped from the itinerary. They were replaced by destinations in more Taleban-friendly Pakistan.</p>
<p>Some things have not changed. Kabul Airport, a graveyard of dismembered planes and rusting trucks, is still subject to occasional air raids by the opposition.</p>
<p>Passengers wait patiently in the sub-zero temperatures of the partially-glazed terminal. Baggage is searched manually: the security equipment was destroyed or looted during the civil war that followed the communist's defeat in 1992.</p>
<p>Travellers huddle in the uncarpeted departure lounge, its only furniture two sofas. There is also a small stack of arrester parachutes waiting to be fitted to military jets that share the airport.</p>
<p>Schedules have become a casualty of the war. Tickets issued to passengers for a recent flight to the southern Afghan city of Kandahar were dated, but listed no time of departure.</p>
<p>Ad Sharza, 59, returned to Afghanistan from the United States two years ago to rebuild the airline to its former stature.</p>
<p>&quot;I've seen the good days and I was part of creating those.&quot; he says. &quot;The only reason I have come back is that in my last days I want to do what I did in my youth: build the airline so it can take its rightful position in the industry.&quot;</p>
<p>He says that only one Ariana plane has been a direct casualty of the war. The plane's nose-cone was shot off in 1992 while it was bringing the first post-communist president into Kabul. The pilot managed to land but the plane was subsequently damaged beyond repair in the fight for the city.</p>
<p>However, the war has caused heavy financial damage to the airline. &quot;We had a financial reserve, but now we have exhausted it and we are reduced to begging. Whatever money we have we spend on maintainance, servicing and training.&quot; says Sharza.</p>
<p>&quot;There is not much we can do about service and in-flight entertainment.&quot; The Taleban banned films and non-religious music and the in-flight meal consists of meat, rice, bread, and tea in a styrofoam cup.</p>
<p>Dowlat Girwal, Ariana's president since the Taleban takeover, says the airline aspires to being an international carrier and will provide an international standard of service.</p>
<p>&quot;Being an international airline, we will abide by international tastes and regulations. We intend to provide the standard of service that international traffic expects.&quot; he says.</p>
<p>In spite of the Taleban's edicts about employing women, Girwal says he intends to employ stewardesses.</p>
<p>&quot;Until (the Taleban takeover) two months ago, we had stewardesses, and soon we will have them again.&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Sharza says the airline is vital to Afghanistan and should be considered for development aid.</p>
<p>&quot;In this country an airline is not a luxury. Afghanistan is a landlocked country. With its environment, the quality of its roads and its weather, an airline is like an artery.&quot; he says.</p>
<p>Ticket prices are kept low for local travellers. A ticket for the 45-minute flight to Kandahar costs the equivalent of $15 for an Afghan. Foreigners are charged $63.</p>
<p>Sharzah wants to see Ariana expand its international routes. &quot;I want to Ariana to fly all the way from the (United) States in the west to Beijing and Tokyo in the east.&quot; he says.</p>
<p>He admits there will be considerable problems in the process of rebuilding Ariana, but remains upbeat.</p>
<p>&quot;I need money and long-range aircraft. Provided I have the finance, aid and technical support, I can rebuild this airline within a year and a half,&quot; says Sharza.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
