<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249887" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: RESEARCH ALERT - Bradesco upgraded to buy.</title>
<headline>RESEARCH ALERT - Bradesco upgraded to buy.</headline>
<text>
<p>-- Caspian Securities said in a report it had raised its rating on Brazilian private bank Bradesco to buy from market performer.</p>
<p>-- &quot;We are upgrading Bradesco ... in light of the bank's current depressed valuation and expectation of a 43 percent appreciation in price in fiscal year 1997,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>-- Bradesco's price has dropped 10 percent and it has underperformed the local market by 37 percent since Caspian cut its rating on the bank on May 8, Caspian said.</p>
<p>-- &quot;This was probably due to the uncertainties related to the timing of the decline in interest rates,&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>-- Bradesco is Brazil's largest private bank.</p>
<p>-- Caspian said Bradesco's expected strong earnings growth of 16 percent a year during 1997-98 is not fully reflected in its current valuation.</p>
<p>-- Earnings growth will be driven by increases in credit volumes, which will offset an expected decline in net interest margin, it said.</p>
<p>-- &quot;Bradesco's most important strengths are its large capital structure and diversified revenue stream,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>-- Its chief weaknesses, it said, are asset quality deterioration and increased competition from foreign institutiions.</p>
<p>-- But asset quality should stabilize by mid-1997 and foreign bank competition should not hurt the bank, it said.</p>
<p>-- Bradesco preferred was off 0.02 reais at 7.28 reais, while its common voter was down 0.06 reais at 6.76 reais at 1352 local/1552 GMT on the Sao Paulo bolsa.</p>
<p>-- James Craig, Sao Paulo Newsroom 5511 248-5413</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
