<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="249855" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Dupont sets $4 billion alliance, employee transfers.</title>
<headline>Dupont sets $4 billion alliance, employee transfers.</headline>
<dateline>WILMINGTON, Del.</dateline>
<text>
<p>DuPont Co. said Wednesday it tentatively agreed to form technology and consulting alliances with Computer Sciences Corp. and Andersen Consulting expected to be worth more than $4 billion over 10 years.</p>
<p>The nation's largest chemical company said that if final agreements were reached, about 3,100 employees would be offered jobs with CSC and Andersen while DuPont would retain 1,100 of the 4,200 employees in its information systems operation.</p>
<p>The Wilmington, Del.-based company did not say what would happen to any of the 3,100 affected employees who did not want to work for CSC or Andersen.</p>
<p>It said in a statement that the alliances were meant to support its growth strategies and help boost value for shareholders.</p>
<p>The $4 billion apparently was what DuPont would spend to buy contract services from the two companies over 10 years but it did not cite any expected cost savings or other specific monetary benefits from the alliances.</p>
<p>Under the agreement, El Segundo, Calif.-based CSC would manage DuPont's global mainframe and personal computer networks and its telecommunications system. CSC also would be responsible for computer applications in Europe and Canada, DuPont said.</p>
<p>CSC, with about 40,000 employees and sales of $5.2 billion for the fiscal year ended in September, provides technology management and consulting services.</p>
<p>Andersen Consulting will provide DuPont with business solutions in manufacturing, marketing, distribution and other areas for the company's chemicals and energy businesses.</p>
<p>Andersen Consulting provides management and technology consulting to clients around the world.</p>
<p>In addition to producing commodity chemicals and brand-name products such as Teflon for cookware coatings and Lycra for stretch fabrics, DuPont owns Conoco, a major oil producer.</p>
<p>DuPont stock fell $2.50 to $92.625 and Computer Sciences rose 25 cents to $84.75, both on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILMINGTON, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
