<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250025" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Heinz ends talks for Bumble Bee tuna.</title>
<headline>Heinz ends talks for Bumble Bee tuna.</headline>
<dateline>PITTSBURGH</dateline>
<text>
<p>H.J. Heinz Co. said Wednesday it has ended talks to acquire the production plants of Bumble Bee tuna from Bumble Bee Seafoods Inc., a unit of Unicord Public Co. Ltd. of Bangkok.</p>
<p>A statement by Heinz and Questor Partners Fund LP, an investor group, did not explain why discussions were halted. But analysts said the potential purchase, valued at more than $200 million, was under close scrutiny by the Federal Trade Commission.</p>
<p>Heinz officials were not available for comment.</p>
<p>Analysts said a merger would have given the Pittsburgh-based food giant, which owns Star-Kist tuna, too much market share. Star-Kist tuna already is the world's leading tuna producer in terms of sales.</p>
<p>Analyst Laurie Feldman at Bear Stearns said Heinz decided to terminate discussions after receiving a &quot;second request for information from the FTC.&quot; She said she did not know when the company received that request.</p>
<p>&quot;Had (Heinz) purchased just the supply rights, they would have had 85 percent of all the tuna volume in the world, said Feldman. &quot;That's just too much.&quot;</p>
<p>Had the transaction gone through, Questor would have purchased Bumble Bee tuna, and in turn would have sold its three production plants to Heinz.</p>
<p>Heinz's stock fell 37.5 cents to $35.75 on the New York Stock Exchange shortly before midday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I41500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PITTSBURGH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
