<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25018" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Clinton's triumph marred by scandal.</title>
<headline>Clinton's triumph marred by scandal.</headline>
<byline>David Nagy</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>President Bill Clinton, his hour of triumph marred by the bombshell resignation of a top aide in a sex scandal, launched his bid for a second term on Thursday with a pledge to lead America boldly into the 21st century.</p>
<p>&quot;Tonight let us resolve to build that bridge to the 21st century, to meet our challenges, protect our basic values and prepare our people for the future,&quot; Clinton said in a speech prepared for his acceptance of the Democratic nomination.</p>
<p>Implying he would be both a wiser and fairer leader than Republican challenger Bob Dole, and one who would replace irresponsible tax-cutting promises with sound moves to spur economic growth, he added:</p>
<p>&quot;We must give Americans the tools they need to make the most of their God-given potential ... and we must build a strong united American community.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton was preceded on the podium by Vice President Al Gore, who accepted the nomination for the vice presidency in a brief speech.</p>
<p>Gore had spoken at length on Wednesday night and made only a brief address in which he appealed &quot;to members of the Republican Party, the Reform Party (of Ross Perot) and independents to join us in this cause which claims our hearts.&quot; He called for a civil presidential campaign.</p>
<p>Clinton could only hope his national television audience would focus on his visionary rhetoric rather than the sudden distraction of a sex scandal that forced the abrupt resignation of an aide who helped craft his very words: top campaign strategist Dick Morris.</p>
<p>A clearly stunned White House announced only hours before the prime-time television address that Morris had resigned late on Wednesday night, shortly before a report in the New York Post that he had had a long affair with a $200-an-hour Washington call-girl.</p>
<p>The Post picked up the report from the tabloid Star magazine.</p>
<p>Among the things Morris had reportedly done to impress the woman, the report said, was to let her eavesdrop on a phone chat with the president himself and take advance peeks at the speeches first lady Hillary Rodham Clinton and Vice President Al Gore delivered to the convention earlier this week.</p>
<p>Clinton issued a terse statement saying he valued Morris as a friend and adviser -- many credit him with devising Clinton's new &quot;family values&quot; campaign strategy -- and most analysts said they doubted it would affect the outcome of an election in which the president is heavily favoured over Dole.</p>
<p>Still, seldom has any U.S. presidential nominee had to deliver a televised acceptance speech under circumstances as strained as these -- and especially for Clinton, a man dogged for years by character questions including allegations of sexual philandering.</p>
<p>Senator Dianne Feinstein, a liberal California Democrat and Clinton backer, called the Morris affair &quot;a big bump&quot; for the president's campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;It comes at the worst possible time on one of the biggest days for the president,&quot; Feinstein said ruefully.</p>
<p>Clinton could do nothing but carry on presenting the visionary message, that has so far put him well out front of Dole in opinion polls, and hope the public would pay heed.</p>
<p>&quot;Our strategy (for the 21st century) is simple but profound: Opportunity for all, responsibility for all, a strong American community where everyone has a place and plays a role,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He boasted he had changed &quot;the old politics of Washington,&quot; adding, &quot;For too often leaders ask, 'Who's to blame?' We ask, 'What are we going to do?'&quot;</p>
<p>He asserted that he and the Democrats could promote prosperity without harming social programmes they claim Dole and the Republicans would slash.</p>
<p>&quot;Tonight let us proclaim to the American people, we will balance the budget, and let us also proclaim we will do it in a way that preserves Medicare, Medicaid, education and the environment,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;As long as I am president, I will never allow cuts that devastate education for our children, pollute our environment, end the guarantee of health care under Medicaid, or violate our duty to our parents under Medicare. Never.&quot;</p>
<p>Clinton began his big day hoping visionary promises like that would be what America discussed round the breakfast table on Friday.</p>
<p>Instead, it seemed the Republicans and the anti-Clinton public had another &quot;character&quot; issue to seize upon related to the 50-year-old president and his choice of controversial aides.</p>
<p>Speaking in Santa Barbara, California, Dole did not directly refer to the sexual scandal but said the departure of Morris, who had advised Clinton to chart a more centrist political course, would make the president drift back to the left.</p>
<p>&quot;Morris has been trying to make President Clinton a Republican, now maybe he'll revert to the liberal Democrat that he really is,&quot; Dole told reporters.</p>
<p>In Chicago, the White House entourage issued a terse statement on Clinton's behalf saying: &quot;Dick Morris is my friend, and he is a superb political strategist. &quot;I am and always will be grateful for the great contributions he has made to my campaigns and for the invaluable work he has done for me over the last two years.&quot;</p>
<p>However the affair plays out, Clinton will hit the road Friday for a bus tour across several states in his fight to become the first Democratic incumbent re-elected to a second term since the days of Franklin D. Roosevelt.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
