<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250174" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Iraq, U.N. freeze dispute over missile engines.</title>
<headline>Iraq, U.N. freeze dispute over missile engines.</headline>
<byline>Leon Barkho</byline>
<dateline>BAGHDAD 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq and the United Nations have agreed to put off until February further talks on a dispute over removing scrapped missile engines, chief U.N. weapons inspector Rolf Ekeus said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;We have agreed to freeze it (the missile problem) temporarily until our next meeting in February,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Iraq last month prevented U.N. arms inspectors from moving the engines outside the country for analysis. Ekeus said the Iraqis told him removal of the parts required a political decision and both &quot;agreed to disagree&quot; and defer discussing the issue.</p>
<p>&quot;We could not agree as Iraq is not prepared to do it. So we agreed to disagree in the form of freezing the issue for the time being and address it again at our next political-level meeting,&quot; Ekeus said.</p>
<p>He said the file on banned long-range missles still remained open.</p>
<p>Asked how many more banned missiles the United Nations thought lraq was still hiding, he told reporters: &quot;It is a significant number that is not accounted for.&quot;</p>
<p>Ekeus is head of the U.N. Special Commission (UNSCOM) disarming Iraq under the 1991 Gulf War ceasefire terms. In the past, he said, his commission suspected that Iraq was concealing six to 16 of its long-range missiles.</p>
<p>The destroyed engines belong to about 85 missiles with ranges beyond 150 km (90 mile) maximum Iraq is allowed to possess or manufacture under the ceasefire.</p>
<p>Ekeus said two-thirds of the parts were packed in boxes at UNSCOM headquarters in Baghdad ready for shipment abroad and one third remained at a warehouse in the outskirts of Baghdad under close U.N. surveillance.</p>
<p>Ekeus said his commission had information about the number of Scud missiles that Iraq acquired from the then Soviet Union before the 1990-1991 Gulf crisis but it later discovered that Iraq could produce its own rockets.</p>
<p>He said he asked Iraq to take major steps to close its weapons files in all areas -- ballistic, chemical and biological warfare. &quot;We have not accounted for all prohibited items,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not solved any of the issues which were on when we came. What we have done is that we had a good seminar spirit,&quot; Ekeus, a former Swedish diplomat, said.</p>
<p>He said both sides had agreed to continue discussions on the missile issue early next year. Removal of the overall curbs on Iraqi oil exports depends on testimony from Ekeus that Iraq has complied with disarmament demands.</p>
<p>Ekeus said that at this stage it was impossible to give Iraq the certificate.</p>
<p>Iraq said on Tuesday it resumed partial oil exports worth $2 billion over six months in line with a U.N. offer designed to alleviate the suffering of the Iraqi people under crippling U.N. trade sanctions, imposed after Iraq invaded Kuwait in 1990.</p>
<p>&quot;It (the oil deal) is a great relief for all of us, first for the Iraqi people and obviously for us (UNSCOM),&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BAGHDAD"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
