<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250172" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Bethlehem's Christmas dimmed by cash crunch.</title>
<headline>Bethlehem's Christmas dimmed by cash crunch.</headline>
<byline>Rula Halawani</byline>
<dateline>BETHLEHEM, West Bank 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A cash crunch and Israeli import restrictions threaten to dim Christmas lights in the birthplace of Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Mayor of Bethlehem Elias Freij on Wednesday said declining tax revenues due to economic hardships in Palestinian self-rule areas have forced the municipality to cut down on decorations in the city.</p>
<p>&quot;Bethlehem municipality is not broke, but we have no liquidity, and although we will celebrate and decorate Bethlehem, it will not be the same as the previous years because of lack of sufficient funding,&quot; Freij said.</p>
<p>Freij told Reuters that decorating Bethlehem for Christmas costs his municipality $70,000 &quot;but this year we have less than $40,000 and it will not be sufficient to decorate the city...as we did in previous years&quot;.</p>
<p>The mayor blamed Israel's closure of the West Bank, which he said caused hardship among Bethlehem's 40,000 residents and cut tax revenues to the city.</p>
<p>He said the cash-strapped Palestinian Authority was not helping.</p>
<p>The Palestinian Authority, in charge of parts of the West Bank and Gaza Strip, &quot;has also not paid a penny to the municipality this year because they are also short of funds&quot;, Freij said.</p>
<p>Bethlehem businessman Nicola Kanawati, who usually helps decorate the city, said officials at Israel's Ashdod port were blocking the entry of three truckloads of decorations imported from the United States saying the ornaments were sub-standard.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been running for two weeks trying to bring the goods out of the port but without any success,&quot; Kanawati said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Israelis say the products are not up to standards. But the fact of the matter is that my agent says that the boxes have not been opened,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>No officials from the Ports Authority were immediately available to comment on the report.</p>
<p>Kanawati said the decorations, including a Christmas tree to be erected at Manger Square, cost about $130,000.</p>
<p>He said that workmen have begun putting up decorations used last year instead.</p>
<p>Thousands of Christian pilgrims flock to Bethlehem at Christmas. The town sports tinsel and fur-coated Santas but has rarely seen a white Christmas.</p>
<p>An employee at the Bethlehem municipality said Finland was donating a 14-metre (46-ft)-high Christmas tree and its decorations this year.</p>
<p>With Christmas only two weeks away, the tree has not yet been erected. But municipal workers have hung posters and some lights.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have Santa Claus, and the protocol celebrations this year as usual, but things might not be the same,&quot; Freij lamented, appealing for foreign funding.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel has frozen and destroyed Bethlehem's economy,&quot; he said of the closure imposed after suicide bombings by Moslem militants killed 59 people in the Jewish state last February and March.</p>
<p>At least 40 percent of Palestinian workers in Bethlehem are unemployed, and as a result, only 20 percent of residents pay taxes to city hall, Freij said.</p>
<p>Israel handed over Bethlehem to Palestinian rule only days before Christmas last year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BETHLEHEM, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
