<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250244" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Northwest drops top cargo posts.</title>
<headline>Northwest drops top cargo posts.</headline>
<byline>David Gersovitz</byline>
<dateline>MINNEAPOLIS 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Northwest Airlines Inc will no longer have a dedicated cargo division president or vice-president cargo finance, an airline spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Industry sources added that the move is part of restructuring designed to boost the carrier's freight division's financial performance.</p>
<p>The spokesman's statement confirmed the substance of a recent internal announcement of the reorganisation.</p>
<p>Only a few years ago, Northwest was one of the few major U.S. airlines that had a dedicated cargo executive of vice-presidential rank within the airline. Now, it will be one of the few that does not.</p>
<p>The incumbent president of Northwest Cargo, Bill Slattery, held the rank of executive vice-president with the parent company. Slattery has been reassigned to the position of vice-president special projects, reporting to Northwest president and chief executive officer John Dasburg.</p>
<p>Ken Levinson, vice-president cargo finance and planning, has taken over new duties as vice-president of tax, risk management and insurance.</p>
<p>Northwest Cargo's marketing and sales functions will report to Mike Levine, the airline's executive vice-president marketing and international.</p>
<p>Responsibility for cargo operations, including freighter scheduling and handling, will be the responsibility of Don Washburn, executive vice-president customer service and operations.</p>
<p>&quot;Integrating cargo into the mainstream of Northwest's operating and marketing structures will help us even better coordinate services for passengers and shippers,&quot; Dasburg said in a recent internal announcement to staff.</p>
<p>However, industry sources said that Levine, widely credited with the greatly improved performance of Northwest's passenger results, felt that a more intensive cargo marketing strategy under his supervision would improve the division's bottom line. --Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MINNEAPOLIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
