<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250287" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Dec 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Washington Post page one - Dec 11.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Post carried the following stories on the front page of its Wednesday edition:</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - When a blue-ribbon panel reported last week that the government's consumer price index had been overstating the inflation rate, it was an assertion by five of the country's top economists that much of what the experts thought they knew about the U.S. economy was just plain wrong.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The competition to be the next Labor Secretary has set off an intense battle between leaders of organised labor and African-Americans that may force President Clinton to choose between two of his most loyal constituencies.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BASKERVILLE, Va. - Hundreds of black farmers have filed administrative complaints or lawsuits charging that U.S. Agriculture Department loan officials discouraged, delayed or rejected their applications because of their race.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>WASHINGTON - The Saudi Arabian government has given the Clinton administration data meant to support the Saudis' belief that the June bombing of a military housing complex was carried out by Shiite extremists trained in Lebanon and supported by Iran.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>UNITED NATIONS - The search for an African diplomat to win election as the next U.N. secretary-general ran into a new roadblock as the United States and France each signaled its intention to veto the candidate favored by the other.</p>
<p>---</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
