<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250281" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Dec 11.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Wall Street Journal - Dec 11.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following stories were reported in Wednesday's edition of The Wall Street Journal:</p>
<p>- Some traders say there is cause to question whether Japanese institutions, which have been big buyers of U.S. Treasury debt securities over the past year and a half, will continue their buying binge.</p>
<p>- Hoechst is expected to announce an offer to buy the 43.3 percent of French pharmaceutical group Roussel-Uclaf that it doesn't already own, in a deal valued at $3.04 billion or more.</p>
<p>- A car maker's group agreed with consumer advocates on a way to test less powerful air bags.</p>
<p>- Ford has run afoul of federal antitrust regulators over its plan to buy Budget Rent A Car.</p>
<p>- Enron said it resumed building its $2.5 billion Dabhol Power Project in India after a 16-month stalemate.</p>
<p>- Cotter's True Value said it would merge with ServiStar in what will create the largest independent chain of hardware dealers in the nation.</p>
<p>- Keyboard makers who haven't put warnings about repetitive stress injuries on their products are the most vulnerable to injury verdicts.</p>
<p>- OSHA is getting ready once again to develop workplace standards to reduce repetitive stress injuries.</p>
<p>- The U.S. current account deficit widened to a record $47.96 billion in the third quarter.</p>
<p>- Regulators are raising concerns about looser terms on syndicated loans, which are made by groups of banks to corporate borrowers.</p>
<p>- Coca-Cola and Cisneros Bottling were fined nearly $2 million by Venezuelan regulators.</p>
<p>- American Express scored a small victory in its battle to market a bankissued charge card in the U.S.</p>
<p>- A growing number of firms are using announcements of purchases by corporate insiders as a means to sing the praises of their stocks.</p>
<p>- The Dow Jones industrials rose, but other indexes fell as investors awaited inflation news.</p>
<p>- Delta Air put its $100 million ad account up for review, potentially ending its 51-year relationship with BBDO.</p>
<p>- Bond prices slipped in quiet trading as investors absorbed a surge of corporate bond issuance while awaiting clearer signs on inflation.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
