<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250300" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US W.Coast prods mixed on weak NYMEX, low supplies.</title>
<headline>US W.Coast prods mixed on weak NYMEX, low supplies.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast spot products prices were mixed late Tuesday amid a NYMEX collapse and perceived shortages caused by local refinery outages.</p>
<p>Front-month NYMEX gasoline fell late by 2.02 cents a gallon to 66.86 cents while heating oil dropped 2.51 cents a gallon to 69.62 cents.</p>
<p>Lower NYMEX prices helped pushed CARB gasoline one cent lower from the morning to 69.75/70.50 cents a gallon.</p>
<p>Fundamentals were weakened by a report that PADD 5 West Coast gasoline stocks rose 5.63 million barrels last week, and stood 1.9 million over year-ago levels.  </p>
<p>But strength came from ongoing reports of lost production at the region's refineries.</p>
<p>In Richmond, Calif., Chevron's fluid catalytic cracker (FCC), a unit which puts about 50,000 barrels-per-day of gasoline into California markets, will remain down through December 25, sources said.</p>
<p>The news helped lift bids for conventional grade gasoline a half cent to 68.50 cents a gallon late Tuesday.</p>
<p>Bay-area gasolines rose to parity with L.A. grades, lifted by talk of tightness following the Richmond problem.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
