<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250415" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German forwarders plan 1.9-2.5pct road rates hike.</title>
<headline>German forwarders plan 1.9-2.5pct road rates hike.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>German freight forwarders have been recommended to raise prices from February 1 to stop a slump in market rates, forwarders association BSL said.</p>
<p>The BSL has recommended rises of 1.9 percent in house-to-collection point &quot;client rates&quot; and of 2.5 percent for collection point to door &quot;house freight&quot; prices.</p>
<p>The price hike would apply to groupage services by road but not to air or sea cargo rates, the association noted.</p>
<p>The &quot;client rate&quot; refers to the cost of transport from a shipper's premises to an agreed collection point.</p>
<p>The &quot;house freight&quot; rate covers final delivery to the recipient, which is generally but not always carried out by the forwarder and is thus charged separately.</p>
<p>A BSL spokeswoman said: &quot;There is a massive price war on the market, falling prices and an explosion in fuel costs. We want to go against this ruinous price competition.&quot;</p>
<p>Forwarders saw these &quot;moderate&quot; rises as the only solution to their difficult economic situation, she added.</p>
<p>The house freight rate was being increased by slightly more than the client rate to take account of the higher fuel costs generated by city transport, the spokeswoman noted.</p>
<p>Market rates for road transport services in Germany have fallen substantially since fixed tariffs were dropped on January 1, 1994, industry observers noted.</p>
<p>It was unclear how many forwarders would follow the price recommendations in practice given this market pressure, they pointed out.</p>
<p>The price recommendations will go to industry associations for comment and then to the German cartel office before they can be introduced.</p>
<p>Air Cargo Newsroom Tel +44-171-542-7706 Fax +44-171-542-5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
