<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250526" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Ex-President Gorbachev says he could support Lebed. [CORRECTED 12:55 GMT]</title>
<headline>Ex-President Gorbachev says he could support Lebed. [CORRECTED 12:55 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev (corrects title from &quot;Former Russian President&quot;) said on Wednesday he would be ready to support popular strongman Alexander Lebed if Lebed in turn co-operated with &quot;other democratic forces&quot;.</p>
<p>In an interview with Europe-1 radio during a visit to Lyon in central France, Gorbachev said novel power combinations or new political figures could succeed President Boris Yeltsin.</p>
<p>&quot;For example I don't at all rule out that Lebed will prepare himself. He is not ready now -- even if he won elections, he would not know what to do with power,&quot; Gorbachev said.</p>
<p>&quot;But if he used his time in a rational way, in co-operation with other democratic forces, I for my part would be ready to back him. If he chooses union with democratic forces, with democratic parties, with the elite then there will be an opportunity,&quot; Gorbachev said.</p>
<p>The former president added that there were however other possibilities including Moscow mayor Yury Luzhkov.</p>
<p>Yeltsin sacked Lebed as secretary of his Security Council in October, saying he was fed up with his argumentative character and presidential ambitions. Lebed said that he would start polishing his political machine for a presidential bid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
