<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250569" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: SOLVAY SAYS NOT RAISING OFFER FOR SODI-DEVNYA.</title>
<headline>SOLVAY SAYS NOT RAISING OFFER FOR SODI-DEVNYA.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-10</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgian chemical group Solvay said on Tuesday that it did not intend to raise its offer for Bulgarian state-owned chemical complex Sodi-Devnya and that a rival bid was running into trouble.</p>
<p>Asked about a recent Bulgarian media report of an increased bid by Solvay, spokesman Paul Muys said, &quot;We cannot comfirm this, but it looks like the offer by General Chemical is running into trouble, that the agreement between them and the government is not working out.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Formally, there is no offer by Solvay that matches that of General Chemicals,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;(A deal with Solvay) depends on Bulgaria's willingness or interest in Solvay,&quot; Muys said. &quot;If the Bulgarians don't come forward with new interest (in Solvay's offer) there is no reason to increase our offer,&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I would like us to go ahead (with buying Sodi-Devnya).&quot;</p>
<p>Bulgaria hopes to close a privatisation deal with one of six foreign investors vying for its largest and most profitable chemical complex Sodi Devnya soon.</p>
<p>The bidders are South Korea's LG Group, Solvay, Rhone-Poulenc, General Chemical Group and Sulfa Katanz.</p>
<p>The value of the plant, which exports 10 to 12 percent of the calcinated soda traded in the world, has not been announced.</p>
<p>Its export markets include the Far East, the Middle East, Latin America and western Europe.</p>
<p>Sodi-Devnya, which can process 1.2 million tonnes of calcinated soda annually, currently operates at 80 percent of capacity. Its net profit for last year was 3.5 million.</p>
<p>The chemical giant is one of 15 state enterprises that the government plans to sell by the end of the year to raise cash for the country's current expenses and debt payments.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-10"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
