<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250736" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Malaysia refuses to let WTO take up workers' rights.</title>
<headline>Malaysia refuses to let WTO take up workers' rights.</headline>
<byline>Nick Edwards</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysia rejected attempts to put labour rights on the official agenda of the World Trade Organisation on Wednesday, raising the possibility that the world body would fail to agree a declaration at its first ministerial meeting this week.</p>
<p>The United States has said the issue must be included if it is to back the final declaration when the conference ends on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The debate on the issue of labour standards has indeed proven to be a divisive factor,&quot; said Malaysia's international trade and industry minister, Rafidah Aziz, in a speech to the conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We reject any move to discuss and deliberate labour standards and other social clauses in the WTO,&quot; Rafidah said.</p>
<p>Late-night talks on Tuesday were thought by diplomatic sources to have made some headway on a Malaysian proposal to allow a reference to labour rights in the final declaration.</p>
<p>The proposal was to state that labour issues should be dealt with only by the International Labour Organisation (ILO) and that further mention of the issue would not be made at the WTO.</p>
<p>Diplomatic sources say the Malaysian proposal is unlikely to go far enough to satisfy U.S. envoys, who have indicated that unless labour rights are mentioned in the final ministerial statement, it will be blocked.</p>
<p>The sources said there was a chance that failure to resolve the row could prevent the issuance of a final ministerial declaration at this week's 128-nation conference.</p>
<p>Rafidah said Malaysia was not opposed to labour rights, but stressed they should be dealt with by the ILO.</p>
<p>&quot;The WTO cannot be regarded as a multi-purpose organisation that can be called upon to debate and address the range of social issues affecting members and the various social ills of the world,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The WTO should focus on trade and on the promotion of world trade,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>Rafidah said the introduction of labour, investment and competition issues had dominated the meeting and diverted attention from the review of the existing WTO programme.</p>
<p>&quot;Everything is centred upon issues that shouldn't be there in the first place,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>But Rafidah said Malaysia did see merit in creating a WTO working group to study the issues raised by members on trade-related competition, laws and policies, along with anti-competitive practices and abuse of trade measures, provided that such a study does not lead to negotiation within the WTO.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
