<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25080" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US West Coast products idle on volatile NYMEX.</title>
<headline>US West Coast products idle on volatile NYMEX.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. West Coast product prices idled late on Thursday, with activity fading because of volatile NYMEX values.</p>
<p>Heating oil for September delivery led the rally with a 1.63-cent rise to 63.67 cents a gallon. Front-month gasoline finished 1.39 cents higher at 63.72 cents</p>
<p>Both contracts expire Friday.</p>
<p>Low heating oil stocks ahead of winter demand and fears of further hurricanes in the Carribean lifted the market.</p>
<p>American Petroleum Institute showed a 463,000 barrel fall in distillate stocks last week.  </p>
<p>Locally, traders heard Mobil was looking to buy conventional grade gasoline because of ongoing problems with a fluid catalytic cracker in Torrance, California.</p>
<p>Mobil declined comment and left traders wondering how long the widely-rumoured problem would continue.</p>
<p>Crude players said the alleged trouble left Mobil with excess heavy crude.</p>
<p>Even players who disputed the rumour said speculation that Mobil would buy forced traders to hold their positions.</p>
<p>Los Angeles regular unleaded was seen unchanged between 66.50 and 67.50 cents early on Thursday.  </p>
<p>Premium traded at a 7.50 cent premium, as more buyers came in on reports of the refinery units.</p>
<p>Unocal Corp in Northern California continued to return to normal production levels after shutting a crude unit last week for repairs, traders said.</p>
<p>And Cheveron was rumoured to begin shutting a unit in early September at its Los Angeles refinery.</p>
<p>Offers for CARB gasoline in Los Angeles stayed at 71.50 cents. Bids were nearly invisibile because of NYMEX volatility, but they stood notionally at 70 cents.</p>
<p>Distillates remained notionally unchanged on Thursday.</p>
<p>-- David Brinkerhoff, Los Angeles bureau +1 213 380 2014</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
