<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250904" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan's current account surplus continues decline.</title>
<headline>Japan's current account surplus continues decline.</headline>
<byline>Yvonne Chang</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan's current account surplus continued to shrink in October, but at a slower pace, and analysts predicted the politically sensitive indicator would begin to rise again sometime next year.</p>
<p>The figure was down 19.6 percent in October from a year earlier at 367.4 billion yen ($3.25 billion), the Finance Ministry announced on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The drop in what is Japan's broadest measure of trade in goods and services was slightly steeper than earlier predictions by economists, but still in line with the recent trend. Economists had expected a drop of about 10 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The year-on-year decline in the current account surplus is gradually narrowing. We confirmed that trend,&quot; Mamoru Yamazaki of Paribas Capital Markets told Reuters Television.</p>
<p>The current account surplus has been falling on a year-on-year basis every month since December 1994. It totalled 457.1 billion yen ($4.04 billion) in October 1995.</p>
<p>The year-on-year drop in September was more than 35 percent and economists had expected the pace of the fall to slow in October, mainly due to a slight decline in the trade surplus that month.</p>
<p>The overall trade surplus fell 12.9 percent in October from a year earlier to 470.86 billion yen ($4.16 billion), the 23rd consecutive month it has declined on a year-on-year basis.</p>
<p>Economists said that while exports had been increasing, led by vehicles, import growth was still greater than that of exports.</p>
<p>But Japan's trade surplus with the United States in October rose 31.3 percent from a year earlier to 354.79 billion yen ($3.13 billion), mainly due to a strong rise in vehicle exports. This was the first such rise in 20 months.</p>
<p>Yamazaki predicted the year-on-year surplus would continue to shrink for a while, but said Japan was likely at some point next year to see year-on-year growth in both its current account and trade balance surpluses.</p>
<p>Financial markets are particularly sensitive about any signs in the data of an increasing trade imbalance. Japan's huge trade surpluses, especially with the United States, have been a source of trade friction.</p>
<p>Such friction sent the Japanese currency sky-rocketing to an all-time high of 79.75 yen to the U.S. dollar in April last year, dealing a heavy blow to Japanese industry. The dollar was trading at about 113 yen on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Yamazaki said that with Japan's machinery orders and private capital spending picking up, current economic activity was stronger than had been generally expected.</p>
<p>Other economists agreed that Japan's surplus would likely reverse its trend sometime next year, saying a planned consumption tax increase from three to five percent from April 1, may cut into imports.</p>
<p>&quot;Starting from sometime next year, Japan's surplus may start rising again due to the recent recovery in exports and the slowdown in import volume,&quot; Susumu Kato, chief economist at BZW Tokyo, told RFTV.</p>
<p>However, a Ministry of Finance (MOF) official said the current account surplus was likely to continue to decline, despite the weakening of the yen against the dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;We conducted hearings and most companies have told us that they basically do not intend to change their overseas production and investment plans despite the weaker yen. I don't think the declining trend will change,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>He said the pace of the decline would slow due to increased exports, but these would not be enough to stop the fall in the surplus as growth in imports continued to exceed that of exports, and there was also a deficit in services trade. ($=113 yen)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
