<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="250941" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japanese U.S. bond buying up sharply in Oct - MOF.</title>
<headline>Japanese U.S. bond buying up sharply in Oct - MOF.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese investors' net purchases of foreign bonds increased sharply in October, as they bought U.S. bonds after expectations of a U.S. rate rise had receded, an official at the Ministry of Finance (MOF) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Net purchases of foreign bonds by Japanese investors totalled 1.6741 trillion yen in October, compared with 440.1 billion yen a month earlier. The October figure is the largest since 1.9997 trillion yen in June 1995.</p>
<p>Net purchases of U.S. bonds increased to 1.0011 trillion yen in October, up sharply from 249.6 billion yen in September.</p>
<p>Fears of a U.S. rate increase were dashed by an unexpected decrease in U.S. non-farm payrolls in September, the MOF official said.</p>
<p>Also, other U.S. economic data for September such as the producer price and consumer price indexes was in line with expectations, supporting the view that the U.S. economy was slowing down, he added.</p>
<p>Those indicators had helped to boost U.S. bond purchases by Japanese investors, the official said.</p>
<p>Net purchases of British bonds also increased to 130.2 billion yen from 32.8 billion yen in September.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
