<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25092" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Magna builds seat unit in Douglas &amp; Lomason deal.</title>
<headline>Magna builds seat unit in Douglas &amp; Lomason deal.</headline>
<byline>David Lawder</byline>
<dateline>FARMINGTON HILLS, Mich. 1996-08-29</dateline>
<text>
<p>Marking another step in the consolidation of the automotive interior parts industry, Canada's Magna International Inc. said Thursday it will acquire seat maker Douglas &amp; Lomason Co. for about $135 million in cash.</p>
<p>Under the deal, Magna made a $31-a-share tender offer for all of Douglas &amp; Lomason's 4.45 million common shares outstanding, which include some managment stock options to be bought at lower option prices.</p>
<p>Douglas &amp; Lomason shares rose 37.5 cents to $26.125 on Nasdaq prior to the merger announcement.</p>
<p>The acquisition will beef-up Markham, Ontario-based Magna's North American car and truck seating business, allowing it to better compete with Johnson Controls Inc. and Lear Corp..</p>
<p>Family-controlled Douglas &amp; Lomason, which had 1995 revenues of $561 million, was finding it more difficult to compete for new seating contracts from automakers, said James Hoey, chief financial officer.</p>
<p>&quot;Unfortunately, in the auto industry these days, a $500 million company is not a big company any more,&quot; Hoey said. &quot;This merger makes us much more competitive.&quot;</p>
<p>Douglas &amp; Lomason's profits have been hurt in the past year by model changeovers that had limited production at some key customers, but were recovering, analysts said.</p>
<p>The company earned $11.2 million on sales of $299 million in the first six months of 1996, up from year-earlier earnings of $4.7 million on sales of $285.7 million.</p>
<p>Some analysts said the deal was encouraged by Ford Motor Co. because it wanted Magna to become a stronger competitor to Lear and Johnson Controls, its principal seat suppliers.</p>
<p>Douglas &amp; Lomason currently supplies seats for the Ford Contour and Mystique cars and other models, while Magna's only major seat contract is for Chrysler Corp.'s minivans.</p>
<p>A Ford spokesman said the automaker did not take an active role in encouraging the merger, but he added that Ford was pleased with the deal.</p>
<p>Ford plans to cut its roster of 2,300 tier-one suppliers -- those it deals with directly -- in half over the next five years.</p>
<p>&quot;The deal really levels the seating field somewhat,&quot; said John Casesa of Schroder Wertheim &amp; Co. &quot;It should give Magna the critical mass to be a bigger player in that market.&quot;</p>
<p>Magna's traditional strength has been instrument panels, door panels and other interior components.</p>
<p>Magna, Johnson Controls and Lear have been working to build up their capabilties to supply complete interiors to automakers, including seats, instrument panels, door panels and carpeting.</p>
<p>Johnson Controls Inc. last month agreed to acquire Holland, Mich.-base Prince Automotive for $1.35 billion in cash to build up its non-seating capabilities.</p>
<p>Lear also has made several acquisitions in the past year to add to its capabilities.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-29"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FARMINGTON HILLS, Mich."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
