<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251049" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Striking French bus drivers win retirement at 55.</title>
<headline>Striking French bus drivers win retirement at 55.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Striking bus drivers in the southwestern French city of Toulouse have won the right to retire early at 55 and striking fishermen in Corsica have won a hefty state subsidy, officials said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>After an eight-day stoppage, public bus drivers in Toulouse voted late on Tuesday to return to work, the SEMVAT transport authority said.</p>
<p>Employers yielded on most of the strikers' grievances including retirement at 55 instead of 60 and a 35-hour, instead of 38-hour, working week.</p>
<p>Jean-Luc Rueff, spokesman for the Toulouse drivers' branch of the CFDT, France's biggest union, confirmed the strikers had accepted the offer.</p>
<p>In a separate dispute, Corsican fishermen won a 12-million franc ($2.4 million) subsidy from the state to help purchase new boats and re-equip existing vessels. Authorities also granted their demand for cheaper fuel.</p>
<p>The fishermen lifted a week-long blockade of several ports which had paralysed traffic between the French Mediterranean island and the mainland, including passenger ferries.</p>
<p>The latest labour unrest was partly inspired by government concessions to striking truck drivers last month which included a cut in retirement age to 55 from 60, shorter working hours and a wage rise. The truckers had set up some 200 blockades on main roads across the country.</p>
<p>Louis Viannet, leader of the Communist CGT union, cautioned on RTL radio that SNCF state railways may be heading for &quot;a major conflict&quot; as workers fight a management restructuring plan.</p>
<p>&quot;Railway workers are very determined to make themselves heard, not only to defend their status but also to defend a public service and the future of the SNCF as a big national company,&quot; Viannet said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
