<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251101" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Canada stocks expected to outdo U.S. in 1997.</title>
<headline>Canada stocks expected to outdo U.S. in 1997.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canadian shares will shrug off the gloom expected to hit U.S. equity markets and post nearly double-digit increases during 1997, a Reuters survey of world stock markets shows.</p>
<p>Seven analysts studying Canadian equities who took part in the poll made an average prediction of 6,470 points for the benchmark TSE 300 index at the end of next year.</p>
<p>Compared with Tuesday's close in Toronto of 5,919, this represents an increase of around 9.5 percent, and stands in sharp contrast to expectations for south of the border where U.S. stocks are expected to fall around six percent.</p>
<p>Not all of those polled were optimists -- there is also a view that the Canadian market will follow Wall Street into a bear trend.</p>
<p>Following are a selection of views on next year's performance of Canadian stocks:</p>
<p>KATHERINE BEATTIE, TECHNICAL ANALYST MMS INTERNATIONAL</p>
<p>&quot;We're in a general long-term up-trend. The stock market is still going to be the best place to invest, given the relatively low interest rates.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We will start inching up, but even if we do get two or three interest rate hikes in the first couple of quarters next year -- which I think is going to cause a correction in the markets -- it's not going to put bonds or bills at a competitive-enough level.&quot;</p>
<p>JOHN ING, PRESIDENT MAISON PLACEMENTS CANADA INC, TORONTO</p>
<p>&quot;The inevitable increase in rates has got to happen sometime within the next 12 months, and that will test the markets.&quot; Ing predicts a decline to 5,750 points by the close of 1997 and further to 5,400 a year later.</p>
<p>MICHAEL METZ, CHIEF INVESTMENT STRATEGIST, OPPENHEIMER &amp; CO, NEW YORK</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Toronto Stock Exchange is in the middle of a bull market.&quot; He said foreign investors would flood to Canada's market as it would be seen providing better value than the United States. &quot;A lot of market watchers, myself included, think the U.S. market is over-stretched.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
