<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251179" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - U.S. technology trade publications.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - U.S. technology trade publications.</headline>
<text>
<p>For the week of Dec. 9, here are some of the top stories reported in major U.S. technology trade publications.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>PC WEEK - Microsoft Corp's Internet strategy is entering a new phase as it begins to elaborate its own strategy for &quot;pushing&quot; information content over networks to computer users, PC week reported Dec. 9. The strategy involves incorporating &quot;push&quot; features in a variety of client and server software to be released over the next six months that enable users to send and receive pre-selected types of information content over the Web, the magazine said.</p>
<p>------------</p>
<p>COMPUTERWORLD - Faced with the rapid switch to newer electronic mail systems based on browser software, traditional interoffice electronic mail desktop software programs from IBM, Microsoft and Novell Inc &quot;appear to be dying,&quot; Computerworld reported Dec. 9. The obituary for the older category of e-mail software comes despite the fact that 1996 was a banner year for deployment of the older style of electronic mail program, the magazine noted.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>COMMUNICATIONS WEEK -</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>COMPUTER RESELLER NEWS - Microsoft Corp may drop plans to make its Windows NT operating system run on the Power PC chip, reneging on its previous commitment to make NT software independent of Intel Corp microprocessors alone, Computer Resellers News reported in its December 9 issue. Power PC chips are produced by a joint venture of Motorola Inc and International Business Machines Corp and Apple Computer Inc.</p>
<p>Quality has suffered as the three leading computer notebook makers have rushed to meet demand for their latest top-of-the-line laptop computers, Computer Reseller News reported in its December 9 issue, citing several national distributors of the products. Problems plaguing Toshiba Corp's U.S. unit, Compaq Computer Corp and IBM have affected core operating software, internal hardware and disk drives, leading to mechanical flaws, overheating and shock hazards, the article said.</p>
<p>-----------  </p>
<p>INFOWORLD - Santa Cruz Operation Inc plans to enter the systems management business this week when it annouces UNIX server technology that will distribute software programs to network computers (NCs), Infoworld reported Dec. 9.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>INFORMATION WEEK - Compaq is expected to announce next month that it has won contracts to install Windows NT workstations in place of Sun Microsystems Inc units on the trading floors of two major Wall Street brokerages, Information Week reported in its Dec. 9 issue.</p>
<p>Computer Sciences Corp and a team of a GE Capital unit and Andersen Consulting unit are bidding on a deal worth up to $4 billion over 10 years to handle DuPont Co's information systems, Information Week reported Dec 9.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>ELECTRONIC BUYERS' NEWS - IBM's plans to inject another $440 million into its disk drive business reflects its commitment to make the huge investments necessary to allow it to compete at the high of the storage systems business, EBN said in its December 9 issue.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING TIMES - Motorola Inc is set to offer its full suite of cable-modem technologies at this week's Western Cable show to the industry on a royalty-free basis in a bid to resolve the impass over standards that has divided competing hardware makers and kept the company from reaching critical mass, EE Times reported Dec. 9.</p>
<p>TeleCruze Technology, a start-up company co-founded by a former executive at Cirrus Logic Inc, is developing a chipset for use in Internet-ready television sets that provides flicker-free displays and could resolve the nagging issue of how best to display text on screen, EE Times reported Dec. 9. Zilog Inc has licensed a subset of the technology, it said.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>COMPUTER RETAIL WEEK - Rival camps signed up new allies last week in their battle to set a defacto standard for the next generation of higher-speed modems capable of transmitting Internet communications at up to 56 kilobits per second, Computer Retail Week reported Dec. 9. U.S. Robotics Corp won the backing of Hitachi Ltd, while the Rockwell International Inc ROK.N /Lucent Technologies Inc camp lined up Compaq Computer Corp, Hewlett-Packard Co, Toshiba Corp, AST Research Inc, 3Com Corp, Netcom On-Line Communications Inc and Cisco Systems Inc.</p>
<p>-----------</p>
<p>MACWEEK - Apple Computer's board met December 4 to discuss the company's future operating system plans, MacWeek reported December 9, citing unnamed sources. Informal talks with Be Inc continued after the board meeting on a deal to license or buy the Be operaing system to serve as the basis for its new Macintosh system software. Apple faces a self-imposed January deadline to set forth a strategy for the next-generation of its operating system software, the article said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
