<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251143" id="root" date="1996-12-11" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK nude advert for &quot;Striptease&quot; found not indecent.</title>
<headline>UK nude advert for &quot;Striptease&quot; found not indecent.</headline>
<byline>Leslie Adler</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>A British advertising watchdog group on Tuesday said it ruled that an advertisement for the movie &quot;Striptease&quot; featuring actress Demi Moore pictured nude was not indecent.</p>
<p>The poster and magazine advert, designed by the Curio Creative Group for film distributor Rank-Castle Rock/Turner, showed Moore naked, with her legs crossed and one knee drawn up to her chest.</p>
<p>The Advertising Standards Authority (ASA), an industry self-regulatory body, said it received multiple complaints that the advert was indecent. One complainant also objected to the presence of a handgun at the foot of the poster as irresponsible.</p>
<p>The ASA, however, said the nudity was not gratuitous because it was relevant to the film's plot about a striptease artist. The ASA also did not uphold the complaint about the gun, noting that the advertisers said the gun was used to create dramatic intensity and was used by Moore in the film.</p>
<p>The ASA did uphold complaints against a poster advert for Molson beer that featured a lookalike of footballer Eric Cantona, in a re-creation of an incident in which Cantona karate-kicked a crowd member at a match. The advert featured three super-imposed can-can girls and the strapline.</p>
<p>The ASA said the portrayal of the incident could compromise Cantona commercially or professionally and said the ad could be seen as condoning anti-social behaviour, although it said it did not believe that readers would infer an endorsement of Molson by Cantona.</p>
<p>The ASA also upheld a complaint against an advert in Vanity Fair magazine for designer Katharine Hamnett's London shop, which showed a male transvestite sitting between two men in suits. The transvestite had one hand inside the fly of each of the other men's trousers.</p>
<p>The ASA said it asked the advertiser -- which said the advert was designed to be thought-provoking and amusing and was chosen to fit the style of the magazine -- to avoid this approach in the future.</p>
<p>Complaints that poster and national press advertisements for Punch magazine were offensive were not upheld by the ASA. The adverts showed photographs with Mr. Punch's head superimposed on other people's bodies, including one photo in which a runway model was shown grabbing her crotch and another featuring a footballer showing a V sign.</p>
<p>The ASA said that although the ads were distasteful and represented the provocative nature of the magazine -- which is published by Liberty Publishing, part of the Harrods empire owned by Mohammed Al-Fayed -- they had not caused serious or widespread offense.</p>
<p>The ASA also did not uphold a complaint against a poster ad for Wexford Irish Cream Ale, which showed a woman running her fingers through the hair of a red-haired apprehensive clergyman. The picture was accompanied by the words &quot;What to do whilst the Wexford settles,&quot; while below the photo read the answer &quot;... tell the redhead you're not married.&quot;</p>
<p>The ASA said the ad was clearly intended to be lighthearted and did not imply that clerics misused alcohol or broke their vows.</p>
<p>-- London Advertising Newsdesk +44 171 542 2815</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-11"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
