<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251236" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NY/NJ agency plans to intervene in rail merger.</title>
<headline>NY/NJ agency plans to intervene in rail merger.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Port Authority of New York and New Jersey said on Thursday that it authorized its legal staff to intervene in any merger plans that involves Conrail, which is the subject of a bidding war.</p>
<p>The Authority added it wants the federal Surface Transportation Board which must approve any merger to make opening the port to competing freight railroads a condition of approval.  </p>
<p>In October the announcement of a proposed merger of Conrail, the dominant long-haul railroad in much of the northeast, with CSX Corp spurred a competing bid from Norfolk Southern.</p>
<p>The Port Authority plans to hire a consultant to analyze the impact of any merger and would have to intervene 45 days after March 1, when the bidders must file their plans with the federal regulators, staff members said at a board meeting authorizing the intervention.  </p>
<p>The two main aims of the Port Authority would be protecting the port, which now handles more than one million cargo containers each year and is expected to ship three million by 2015, as well as ensure improved freight links to other markets, according to a prepared statement.</p>
<p>The staff recommendation approved by the board said that unless a merger creates direct access by a competing long-haul railroad to the region and local port, its benefits may be minimal, and highlighted the potential advantages Norfolk and other Atlantic ports might gain.  </p>
<p>But the general council Jeff Green said that the Port Authority has not determined whether it would favor one of the bidders over the other.</p>
<p>&quot;We may ultimately conclude not to intervene, to intervene on one side or the other, to intervene solely for the purpose of bringing rail access to the port, but it's going to be a fact-based intervention.&quot;</p>
<p>Other staff official said it was unlikely that the Port Authority would not intervene.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212-859-1610.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
