<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251320" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Natgas futures open up on pipeline news, then ease.</title>
<headline>Natgas futures open up on pipeline news, then ease.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX Henry Hub natgas futures opened higher Thursday after news of a pipeline rupture surfaced, but then softened when TransCanada said no deliveries were affected and cash prices eased, sources said.</p>
<p>At 1130 EST, January was 5.3 cents lower at $3.44 per million British thermal units after hitting a high of $3.565, up 7.2 cents. February fell 4.9 cents to $3.19.</p>
<p>&quot;Cash was softer early, but there are a lot of people pulling gas out of storage already and the weather looks supportive,&quot; one futures source said, noting low inventories and cooler forecasts are preventing January from diving.  </p>
<p>American Gas Association said Wednesday U.S. gas stocks fell by 72 billion cubic feet (bcf) to 75 percent of capacity, still 214 bcf, or eight percent, below year-ago levels.</p>
<p>In the Consuming Region East, stocks declined by 40 bcf to 84 percent full.</p>
<p>Counteracting the lower-than-expected storage drawdown was news that one of TransCanada Pipelines three 30-inch gas pipelines ruptured late Wednesday near Vermillion Bay in western Ontario.</p>
<p>However, the company said no deliveries were affected since they were able to re-route the gas along an adjacent pipeline.</p>
<p>Traders said there was major support in January was at $3.19-3.20, then $3.11 and $3.04. Resistance was seen in the low-$3.50s and then at $3.70. Major resistance was pegged at the contract high of $3.80.</p>
<p>In the cash market, Gulf Coast prices were talked early in the mid-$3.30s, down about five cents from Wednesday. Midcontinent prices were steady to lower in the low-to-mid $3.30s, while Appalachian gas traded in the high-$3.50s to mid-$3.60s, down more than 10 cents on the day.</p>
<p>A storm is moving into the Northeast this weekend, forecasters said, likely to bring widespread precipitation and wind. The six- to 10-day outlook is calling for temperatures throughout most of the U.S, excluding the East Coast, to be below- to much below-normal.</p>
<p>NYMEX Permian basin natgas futures were untraded after settling Wednesday at $3.25, up 20 cents.</p>
<p>Permian cash prices on Wednesday were around $3.25.</p>
<p>NYMEX Alberta natgas futures were also untraded following Wednesday's settlement at $1.63.</p>
<p>Physical December gas at the AECO storage hub traded Wednesday around $1.50 per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, January dipped to $3.285, down six cents. Open interest for December 11 rose by 48 to 2,668. The East/West spread widened by 0.7 cent to 15.5 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
