<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251465" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NBA basketball-CELTICS BEAT RAPTORS IN TRIPLE OVERTIME.</title>
<headline>NBA basketball-CELTICS BEAT RAPTORS IN TRIPLE OVERTIME.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rick Fox made a three-pointer at the triple-overtime buzzer as the Boston Celtics snapped a six-game losing streak with a 115-113 victory over the Toronto Raptors in the longest game this season on Wednesday.</p>
<p>It was Boston's first regular-season triple-overtime game in nearly 30 years.</p>
<p>Fox scored 24 points and David Wesley added 20 and 10 assists in 57 minutes for the Celtics, who had seven players in double figures. Barros scored 15 of his 18 points on three-pointers, Eric Williams had 15 points and a career-high 10 rebounds and Radja scored 13 points.</p>
<p>Damon Stoudamire had 31 points and 12 assists for the Raptors.</p>
<p>In Charlotte, Anthony Mason had 25 points and 21 rebounds and Dell Curry sank a tie-breaking three-pointer with 35 seconds left as the Charlotte Hornets handed the Denver Nuggets their eighth straight loss, 101-97.</p>
<p>Mason had his first career 20-20 game.</p>
<p>Curry made a three-pointer from the right wing to give Charlotte the lead for good. Rice scored 16 and Smith added 13 for the Hornets.</p>
<p>In Chicago, Michael Jordan scored 27 points and Scottie Pippen had 26 points, nine rebounds and eight assists as the Chicago Bulls remained unbeaten against the Minnesota Timberwolves with a 103-86 victory.</p>
<p>Chicago, playing without suspended forward Dennis Rodman, snapped a season-high two-game losing streak.</p>
<p>Minnesota held a 50-49 edge at halftime but the Bulls opened the second half on a 10-2 run for a 59-52 advantage. Jordan had four points in the run.</p>
<p>In New Jersey, Kendall Gill scored 24 points and got even with former coach George Karl as the New Jersey Nets surrendered a 19-point lead but rebounded for a 110-101 victory over the Seattle SuperSonics.</p>
<p>Gill, who said he got an undeserved reputation for bad work habits when he played for Karl in Seattle, victimised his former coach and gave Nets first-year coach John Calipari the biggest win of his young career.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a good win for the whole team,&quot; Gill said. &quot;We just beat a team that's playing for the championship.&quot;</p>
<p>In Philadelphia, Tim Hardaway shut down Allen Iverson and scored the go-ahead layup with 26 seconds left as the Miami Heat rallied for their 10th straight road victory, 84-79 over the Philadelphia 76ers.</p>
<p>A driving layup by Iverson -- who was held to eight points -- gave Philadelphia its last lead at 79-78 with 38 seconds to go. Hardaway scored 12 seconds later, then forced Iverson to miss a 14-footer with 5.7 seconds left.</p>
<p>Hardaway had 21 points and eight assists and Mourning had 20 points and 17 rebounds for Miami.</p>
<p>In Washington, Chris Webber scored 23 points, grabbed 11 rebounds and handed out seven assists to lead the Washington Bullets to a 106-95 victory over the Cleveland Cavaliers, ending their season-high five-game losing streak.</p>
<p>Juwan Howard scored nine of his 25 points in the opening quarter for Washington, which took the lead for good with 2:23 remaining in the period on a three-point play by Rod Strickland.</p>
<p>Terrell Brandon had 28 points and Chris Mills 21 for Cleveland.</p>
<p>In Los Angeles, Shaquille O'Neal had 33 points and 10 rebounds as the Los Angeles Lakers rallied for their fourth consecutive win, 79-76 over the road-weary Indiana Pacers, to take over the Pacific Division lead.</p>
<p>O'Neal, whose fifth rebound was his 4,000th, added five blocked shots.</p>
<p>Reggie Miller was held to 14 points for Indiana.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
