<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251450" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: SOCCER-GERMAN VETERAN SCHUSTER SIGNS FOR MEXICAN CLUB.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-GERMAN VETERAN SCHUSTER SIGNS FOR MEXICAN CLUB.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>German veteran Bernd Schuster, whose career has been full of controversy, joined Mexican soccer club UNAM on Wednesday at the age of 36.</p>
<p>&quot;The concept of age is something that has never worried me,&quot; said the midfielder, who will start playing for the club in the second half of the current Mexican season.</p>
<p>Schuster is one of the most talented players his country has produced but his international career was restricted to 21 caps for West Germany before he fell out with his team-mates in 1984.</p>
<p>Of his former clubs, he left Spanish giants Real Madrid and Barcelona and Germany's Cologne in problematical circumstances while earlier this year he walked away from German side Bayer Leverkusen with $1.9 million compensation after another row.</p>
<p>The money was awarded in compensation after a four-month legal battle with Leverkusen, who had barred him from playing. Schuster's original contract with the club had been until the end of June 1997.</p>
<p>He joins several other world-class veterans, who are playing out their days in Mexico. These include Michel and Emilio Butragueno of Spain and Francois Omam-Biyik of Cameroon.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
