<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251423" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>India: CRICKET-INDIA'S FIRST-EVER SERIES WIN OVER SAFRICA.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-INDIA'S FIRST-EVER SERIES WIN OVER SAFRICA.</headline>
<dateline>KANPUR, India 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>India sealed their first-ever series victory over South Africa with a resounding 280-run win in the third and final test on Thursday as paceman Javagal Srinath and left-arm spinner Sunil Joshi shared four of the last five wickets.</p>
<p>South Africa, 127 for five overnight in pursuit of an improbable 461 to win, were bowled out for 180 five minutes after lunch on the final day, giving India the rubber 2-1.</p>
<p>Any lingering doubts about the outcome vanished when South Africa lost three early wickets, including overnight batsmen Brian McMillan and Dave Richardson without any addition to their scores.</p>
<p>Joshi, who finished with three for 66, had McMillan brilliantly caught by substitute Vangipurappu Laxman for 18 on the fourth ball of the morning.</p>
<p>Medium-pacer Srinath trapped Richardson leg before for five.</p>
<p>Pat Symcox struck leg-spinner Anil Kumble for a six over mid-off before giving Joshi a return catch after making 11.</p>
<p>Lance Klusener and Fanie de Villiers held on grimly for 47 minutes to delay the inevitable.</p>
<p>Venkatesh Prasad bowled de Villiers for two and Srinath had Paul Adams caught by Mohammad Azharuddin in the slips for one to end the innings seven balls after lunch.</p>
<p>Klusener struck five boundaries in his unbeaten 34 .</p>
<p>Srinath returned the best figures for India in the second innings with three for 38 while Prasad had two for 25.</p>
<p>Azharuddin, sacked as captain earlier this year and nearly dropped from the side altogether, was named both the man of the match and the man of the series.</p>
<p>The elegant 33-year-old right-hander, who scored the joint fourth fastest test century from 74 balls in the second test in Calcutta, stroked 163 not out in the second innings here, his 16th century in 75 tests, and put the match out of South Africa's reach.</p>
<p>India, who have not lost a home test series since their 1986-87 defeat to Pakistan, won the opening test in Ahmedabad and South Africa levelled the rubber with a crushing 329-run triumph in Calcutta.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANPUR, India"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
