<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25140" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Venice festival screens Schloendorff's war drama.</title>
<headline>Venice festival screens Schloendorff's war drama.</headline>
<byline>Vera Haller</byline>
<dateline>VENICE, Italy 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two films exploring the search for self in very different ways -- &quot;The Ogre&quot; by German director Volker Schloendorff and American Tom DiCillo's &quot;Box of Moonlight&quot; -- were shown on Friday at the Venice Film Festival.</p>
<p>Schloendorff's film, starring John Malkovitch, is a World War Two drama about a simple French car mechanic whose love of children lands him wrongly accused of sexually abusing a girl.</p>
<p>Instead of being jailed, he is sent to the front and almost immediately captured by the Germans. Through a twist of fate, he ends up at an SS preparatory school where he befriends the boys.</p>
<p>Finding the acceptance he never received in France, the former mechanic begins to embrace Nazism and avidly pursues the mission given him by German officers to scour the East Prussian countryside looking for new, young recruits for the school.</p>
<p>&quot;The Ogre&quot; includes beautiful outdoor scenery shot in Poland, France and Norway. Other scenes were filmed at the Babelsberg studios near Berlin where the director recreated &quot;Jagershof&quot;, the magnificent residence of Hermann Goering.</p>
<p>The film is based on the 1970 novel &quot;The Erl-King&quot; by French writer Michel Tournier.</p>
<p>&quot;What fascinated me about Tournier's novel was that he did not approach the war in ideological or political terms, but rather through German mythology,&quot; Schlondorff told a news conference. &quot;This film is a fairy tale.&quot;</p>
<p>The other film screened on Friday takes place in the backwoods of Tennessee.</p>
<p>DiCillo, an independent director who has earned respect with his earlier works &quot;Johnny Suede&quot; and &quot;Living in Oblivion&quot;, offers a quirky comedy in his newest movie, &quot;Box of Moonlight&quot;.</p>
<p>The protagonist, played by John Turturro, is Al Fountain, an electrical engineer from Chicago who is an unhappy slave to punctuality, order and authority.</p>
<p>When the job he is supervising in Tennessee ends earlier than expected and he is not due home to his wife and son for another week, Fountain makes an uncharacteristically impulsive decision to hire a car and drive off with no set destination.</p>
<p>He ends up staying with a young modern-day hermit called &quot;The Kid&quot; who lives the woods in a half-built house and dresses like frontier-man Davy Crockett in a buckskin suit.</p>
<p>After a few days with &quot;The Kid&quot;, Fountain loosens up and returns to his family a more relaxed man.</p>
<p>&quot;As human beings we live our lives in a very certain way. It's very hard to allow ourselves to really appreciate the preciousness of life and that's what this film is all about,&quot; DiCillo said.</p>
<p>The Venice Film Festival, in its third day on Friday, continues until September 7, when one of 17 films in competition will be awarded the Golden Lion prize. &quot;Box of Moonlight&quot; and &quot;The Ogre&quot; are among the competitors.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C32">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VENICE, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
