<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251511" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: BULGARIA REVISES 96 BUDGET TO FUND DEFICIT.</title>
<headline>BULGARIA REVISES 96 BUDGET TO FUND DEFICIT.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's parliament on Thursday passed a budget revision including a 115 billion lev loan to the government to help cover a 123.5 billion lev gap in this year's budget deficit for domestic debt payments.</p>
<p>&quot;The deficit rose due to large interest payments on the ever increasing domestic debt,&quot; Finance Minister Dimitar Kostov told reporters.</p>
<p>Interest payments due on a 839.3 billion lev domestic debt amount to 125.3 billion.</p>
<p>The sharp depreciation of the lev against the dollar also boosted the deficit because it increased the lev denomination of foreign debt payments.</p>
<p>The lev slumped from 70 against the dollar to 515 on Thursday.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's central government budget deficit on November 30 comprised 192.5 percent of the annual target in the unrevised budget, Finance Ministry figures showed.</p>
<p>Under the revision, which had a first reading last Friday, the deficit target rose to 204.2 billion levs or five to six percent of GDP from 80.7 billion levs or 4.9 percent of GDP to meet higher domestic debt payments.</p>
<p>Apart from the central bank loan, the rest of the 123.5 billion lev gap will be funded from tax revenue and government securities.</p>
<p>The loan, with a five year grace period, is due to be disbursed by the central bank despite its strong opposition.</p>
<p>The Bulgarian National Bank (BNB) said lending the government more money to finance the budget deficit was inappropriate as Bulgaria prepared to introduce a restrictive currency board regime and would further increase inflation.</p>
<p>The revision, this year's second, was sought by the socialist government after it overshot the macroeconomic targets in the July revision.</p>
<p>&quot;This revision reflects the incompetence of the government while the low rate of tax collection speaks of widespread corruption,&quot; opposition deputy Muravei Radev told parliament.</p>
<p>The government has issued large quantities of Treasury paper to raise cash and new issues now often find few buyers.</p>
<p>Socialist deputies said that the government had no other source of funds except the central bank due to the stagnant domestic money market.</p>
<p>The BNB suggested it would be less inflationary for the government to speed up long-heralded privatisations and channel some cash from the State Fund for Reconstruction and Development.</p>
<p>Bulgaria is expected to introduce a currency board early next year, requiring levs in circulation to be matched by BNB reserves, removing political pressure to print money.</p>
<p>Next year's budget must be balanced between revenue and expenditure if a currency board is introduced, which will entail big cuts in public spending.</p>
<p>-- Sofia newsroom +359 2 84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
