<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251519" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: UPDATE: ATHENS BOURSE WANTS CLOSER MONITORING OF FIRMS.</title>
<headline>UPDATE: ATHENS BOURSE WANTS CLOSER MONITORING OF FIRMS.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Athens bourse will submit plans for closer monitoring of securities firms to the Stock Exchange Commission, it said in a statement on Thursday.</p>
<p>It will propose a strengthening of the supervisory role of the Board of Directors by creating a special office that will report directly to the board.</p>
<p>The plans follow weeks of turbulence at the bourse after a settlement scandal rocked the exchange to its foundations and stopped trading for four days in November.</p>
<p>Three separate audits are being carried out after the Delta Securities scandal and an investigating magistrate said he had seized 700,000 shares at the bourse clearing house on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Magistrate Constantinos Ganiatsos is investigating the 2.6 billion drachma Securities scandal. Three Delta officials have been charged with fraud after the firm tried to settlement its accounts with bad cheques.</p>
<p>Ganiatsos also said he had asked banks for information on a number of persons suspected of being involved in the scandal.</p>
<p>The scandal and allegations of rampant illegal short-selling at the bourse have helped to cut daily volume to half or less of its normal levels.</p>
<p>Brokers have said that some firms were selling shares short and then taking advantage of the clearing house's heavy backlog to delay settlement and payment.</p>
<p>An offshoot of the scandal has been a tightening of existing measures such as strict inforcement of a 48-hour settlement rule.</p>
<p>This has also caused further upheavals. Delivery in Greece is still of physical paper and brokers have complained that the settlement period is too short.</p>
<p>In recent weeks a number of brokerages have been suspended from trading for a day as the penalty for failing to settle on time with the clearing house.</p>
<p>The bourse announcement on Thursday also said conditions for issuing licences to securities firms should be stricter, while a special license should be required for activities such as consulting and lending.</p>
<p>&quot;These proposals will be submitted to the Stock Exchange Commission, which is responsible for issuing the final decision,&quot; the bourse statement said.</p>
<p>It did not say when the proposals would be put to the commission nor when a decision was expected. It gave no further details of what would be contained in the proposals. --Margarita Sotiropoulou, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
