<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251660" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigeria says local elections to be held this year.</title>
<headline>Nigeria says local elections to be held this year.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nigerian information minister Walter Ofonagoro on Thursday said that multiparty local elections will be held this month as scheduled, although no date has yet been announced, the national news agency said.</p>
<p>&quot;Nigerian democracy is on the right course and any time this month we shall hold the local government election,&quot; the News Agency of Nigeria quoted Ofonagoro as saying.</p>
<p>Speculation has been mounting in local media that adequate preparations have not been made for the first multiparty elections since the army annulled a 1993 ballot and plunged Nigeria into political crisis.</p>
<p>So far no date has been set and no voters' register has been prepared for the vote due to take place in the last quarter of the year according to the military government's timetable to restore elected rule by October 1998.</p>
<p>General Sani Abacha's plan for democracy in Africa's most populous nation has been criticised by both Western countries and local opposition activists for taking too long.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
