<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251655" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: World economies to boost SAfrica exporters - Sanlam.</title>
<headline>World economies to boost SAfrica exporters - Sanlam.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Expectations of favourable international economic conditions next year would generate greater opportunities for South African exporters, South African financial services giant, Sanlam, said on Friday.</p>
<p>Johan Louw, Sanlam's chief economist said in a statement that exports in 1997 were expected to expand by 7.5 percent with the outlook for commodity demand and price increases particularly favourable.</p>
<p>&quot;Had it not been for the expected better exports, South Africa's economic growth rate would have been considerably weaker than the projected 2.3 percent,&quot; Louw said.</p>
<p>Growth in imports was seen slowing to 3.6 percent.</p>
<p>Louw said growth in European and Asian economies, with the exception of Japan, was expected to accelerate considerably. The U.S. economy was, however, seen growing at a slower rate.</p>
<p>Looking at domestic fundamentals, Louw said the rand, which Sanlam believed to be undervalued, would stabilise especially in the second half of 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;(We) believe the rand is currently greatly undervalued and that the expected improvement on the current account of the balance of payments will contribute to a more stable rand in the coming twelve months,&quot; Louw said.</p>
<p>Sanlam saw the rand U.S. dollar exchange rate at approximately 4.85 by the fourth quarter of 1997.</p>
<p>The rand, which has lost nearly 30 percent of its value against the dollar this year, closed on Thursday at 4.7510 bid on the U.S. unit.</p>
<p>The inflation rate was seen averaging around 10.0 percent in 1997, rising from an anticipated average 7.5 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>Louw said CPI was seen pushed higher by the rand's depreciation, rising food prices and above-inflation wage increases.</p>
<p>Other contributing factors included higher fuel prices due to a rising dollar price of crude oil and the weaker rand, and an expected one percentage point increase in VAT to 15 percent in the March 1997 Budget.</p>
<p>&quot;However, a gradual deceleration in price increases should occur from around the middle of 1997, which will lower the inflation rate to around eight percent by the end of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>This would be helped along by an expected reduction in the Bank rate, currently at 17 percent, which would lower bond rate and ultimately reduced housing costs.</p>
<p>The recent wave of food price increases was expected to taper off in the second half of 1997 amid expected more favourable agricultural conditions and demand for higher wages was also seen levelling off slightly next year.</p>
<p>-- Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
