<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251610" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Dec 13.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Sports News - Dec 13.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>Michael Slater, who was axed from the Australian cricket team last month, has finally made a public statement about the decision and stated that while it was bad and hurt &quot;there's no use sulking, getting angry or upset, you've just got to get on with it&quot;.Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Mark Woodforde yesterday defended himself and his doubles partner's extra earnings from the Australian Olympic Committee's Medal Incentive Scheme, saying it was unfair to suggest, as a Sydney paper did, that just because he and Todd Woodbridge made a lot of money on the professional tour they should give their Olympic money back. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>IMG has proposed to the presidents of the various state and territory federations of soccer clubs the creation of a A$600,000 State-of-Origin series in the middle of next year. If approved the event may resurrect interstate soccer in Australia. Page 18.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>Australian rugby playing legend David Campese was presented the key to the city of Sydney by Lord Mayor Frank Sartor yesterday, at a lunchtime ceremony honouring the Wallabies. Campese said that his retirement would involve running his business, playing golf and little time for watching rugby, a practice he said he disliked. Page 39.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australian golfer Wayne Grady currently holds the lead at 66 in the A$200,000 Coolum Classic. He is closely followed by Craig Parry, David Bransdon, Peter Lonard and Philip Chapman, who were all on 67 at end of the play yesterday. Page 39.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In an interview with Peter Stone, Greg Norman said that he began to play the best golf of his life once he passed the age of 40. One of Norman's rivals, Nick Faldo, once said that he would retire well before such an age, but at the age of 39 looks to have at least 10 more years at the top. Page 38.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Pakistan's cricket coach Mushtaq Mohammad said that one-day cricket has the potential to kill the development of Test cricketers, but he still believes that his young touring squad is one of the best to attack a limited-overs series. Pakistan is currently training for Sunday's international against Australia. Page C8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The central Goldfields Shire of Maryborough is taking legal action against the Victoria Racing Club for its failure to grant approval for the TeleTrak propriety racing system. The shire claims the system could be worth up to A$11 million a year for Victoia. Page C8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Michael Slater has another chance to prove his cricket skills are still worthy of inclusion in the Australian team when he plays in the Australia A cricket team it its match against the West Indies today. Slater was dropped last month from the Australian cricket team. Page C8.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE HERALD SUN</p>
<p>Alan Border has stated Dean Jones offended too many people in the Australian cricket establishment to ever play for Australian again, saying that Jones had a falling out with national coach Bob Simpson and selector Trevor Hohns which effectively ended his career. Page 112.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Glen Boss, Sydney's leading jockey, has given stewards a &quot;personal guarantee&quot; there will be no repeat of the two misconduct charges which cost him A$800 yesterday. Boss received the charges for allegedly yelling obscenities at Australian Jockey Club steards during an adjourned inquiry into his ride on Brimstone at Warwick farm on November 30. Page 109.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Stuart Law has had to give up his place in the Australian one-day cricket team with the return of Steve Waugh from a groin injury. Law has proven himself to be a fine player under pressure and is unlucky to be squeezed off the team. Page 106.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE DAILY TELEGRAPH</p>
<p>TABCorp, the Victorian gaming and wagering company, may buy NSW TAB when it is privatised next year by the Carr Government. The purchase would give TABCorp a monopoly on the nation's massive A$8 billion-a-year wagering market and be a start to a national TAB betting operation. Page 112.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Gold medallist swimmer Hayley Lewis will try her hand at triathlon as a wildcard entry in the St George Triathlon Grand Prix. Triathlon will become an Olympic sport for the next Olympics. Lewis is uncertain how she will fair in triathlon as she is so fr untested in such an event. Page 110.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In its first year of professionalism, the NSW Rugby Union has recorded a A$442,043 loss. The loss was revealed at the NSWRU's annual general meeting on Tuesday, but it was minimal for a first year in the professional league, NSWRU chairman Ian Ferrier said. Page 110.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
