<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251641" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Quebec plans to cut C$200 mln to meet deficit goal.</title>
<headline>Quebec plans to cut C$200 mln to meet deficit goal.</headline>
<dateline>QUEBEC CITY 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Quebec government said on Thursday that is seeking to cut an additional C$200 million from its expenditures to meet its budget deficit forecast for the 1996/97 fiscal year.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a problem of about C$200 million,&quot; Quebec Premier Lucien Bouchard told reporters.</p>
<p>Treasury Board President Jacques Leonard said the government remains committed to meeting its deficit target of C$3.2 billion for fiscal 1996/97, which ends March 31. The government also intends to meet its objective of a zero deficit in the year 2000, he said.  </p>
<p>Bouchard said he hoped at least C$100 million of the shortfall would come from reduced payroll costs for Quebec's 440,000 public employees. The C$100 million would be part of a government proposal for cuts to take effect on January 1.</p>
<p>The cuts were part of a counter-offer by the Quebec government in negotiations with six of the province's largest public sector unions. The counter-offer called for 15,000 government job cuts by July 1, 1997. The government seeks workforce cuts of about C$1 billion for fiscal 1997/98, of which C$800 million would come from measures negotiated with the six big unions.  </p>
<p>The leadership of five of the six unions told reporters late on Wednesday that they agreed tentatively to the government's offer and would recommend their membership accept it on Monday.</p>
<p>Bouchard said the 15,000 job cuts would not be layoffs, but voluntary departures compensated through severance payments funded from surplusses in employee pension funds and government contributions. If the union memberships accepted the offer, its details would be negotiated in January.</p>
<p>In the current fiscal year, another C$100 million of government workforce cost savings would come from other payroll expense reductions, including those for staff at the National Assembly, the provincial police and judges.</p>
<p>On Thursday, leaders of four medical federations representing Quebec's 19,000 physicians said they would not accept a six percent salary cut imposed by the Bouchard government, which is scheduled to take effect January 1.</p>
<p>In protest, the federations have scheduled a one-day strike for Wednesday.</p>
<p>((Reuters Montreal bureau 514-985-2434))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="QUEBEC CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
