<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251784" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary BCE milling wheat futures mixed, maize flat.</title>
<headline>Hungary BCE milling wheat futures mixed, maize flat.</headline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A week-long downward trend was broken on Thursday on the Budapest Commodity Exchange and traders said milling wheat prices could rise further but maize was expected to remain depressed.</p>
<p>&quot;January milling wheat prices saw an upward correction, but trends for the March and May maturities are still unclear,&quot; said Sandor Torok of Agrokont Broker.</p>
<p>Milling wheat for January rose by the 400 forints limit to end at 27,200 forints but March and May dropped by the limit to close at 27,400 and 27,430 forints.</p>
<p>&quot;Speculation has pushed down the May price and it would probably climb back to between 29,000 to 30,000 forints,&quot; Torok said.</p>
<p>He added that most maize futures prices were speculative as there was too little information about next year's harvest to trade on, but he expected 1996 crop prices to stagnate or ease slightly in the short term.</p>
<p>Maize futures remained unchanged except for the October 1997 maturity, which closed at 19,900 forints, down 400.</p>
<p>Total turnover of the BCE grain section was 827.4 million forints or 1,841 lots, of which 919 were maize and 872 were milling wheat.</p>
<p>(Lot size is 20,000 kg for all contracts. $=163.24 forints)</p>
<p>-- Denes Albert, Budapest newsroom +36 1 327 4040</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
