<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251742" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Egypt, UAE deliver arms to Bosnia.</title>
<headline>Egypt, UAE deliver arms to Bosnia.</headline>
<byline>Dan De Luce</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two ships sent by Egypt and the United Arab Emirates with heavy weapons for the Bosnian federation army have docked at the Adriatic port of Ploce, diplomats said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Workers are now unloading the arms, supplied under the U.S.-sponsored &quot;train and equip&quot; aid programme designed to strengthen the Moslem-Croat federation army, said James Pardew, an American envoy overseeing the project.</p>
<p>He told reporters that the Egyptian ship carried 24 long-range howitzers and 18 anti-aircraft guns, while the UAE military had sent 36 105 mm howitzers with ammunition and planned to send 42 AMX tanks and 44 armoured reconnaissance vehicles in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>Washington's European allies have declined to back the military aid programme, arguing that it risks reigniting the Bosnian conflict that ended a year ago and that the area is already overloaded with weapons.</p>
<p>But Pardew said arming the Moslem-Croat federation would ensure a balance of military power and deter Bosnian Serb forces, who enjoyed a big advantage in heavy weaponry during the war, from thinking of overrunning the federation.</p>
<p>&quot;The train and equip programme is designed to support the federation's right of self-defence,&quot; he said. &quot;The programme is no threat to anyone who wants lasting peace in Bosnia and who supports the full implementation of the Dayton peace agreement.&quot;</p>
<p>Under the Dayton accords, Bosnia is a loose union comprising a Serb republic and a Moslem-Croat federation.</p>
<p>The United States has already delivered tanks, armoured personnel carriers, M-16 rifles and communications equipment to the federation and retired U.S. army officers have begun training four brigades.</p>
<p>The U.S. weapons are being kept at storage sites in Bosnia until mutually distrustful Moslem and Croat officers overcome their reluctance and merge their armies into a single fighting force, Pardew said.</p>
<p>U.S. military aid has been contingent on a unified Moslem-Croat army and the removal of foreign Islamic fighters from Bosnia.</p>
<p>Moslems and Croats fought a 10-month war during the main conflict between the Moslem-led Bosnian government and Serb forces.</p>
<p>U.S. officials say the military aid programme does not violate an arms control agreement signed by the Serbs and the Moslem-Croat federation.</p>
<p>Pardew accused the Serbs of failing to abide by the pact. &quot;I'm certainly not happy with the Bosnian Serbs' (weapons) reduction. They are absolutely out of compliance and show very little inclination to comply with the agreement,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He hinted that Washington might consider increasing its military aid to Bosnia unless the Serbs observed the arms control pact.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Serbs are out of compliance on the arms control agreement then that changes the entire calculation and we'll have to reconsider our options at that point,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
