<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251757" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: INTERVIEW-Warta plans group with banks.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Warta plans group with banks.</headline>
<byline>Malgorzata Rzepka</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Insurer TUiR Warta SA plans to form a group with some of the country's leading banks to defend its market position against growing foreign competition, Warta president Andrzej Witkowski said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Witkowski told Reuters in an interview the group would include Bank Przemyslowo Handlowy (BPH), Kredyt Bank, Powszechny Bank Kredytowy (PBK) and Polish Development Bank (PBR) which already holds a stake in Warta, Poland's second-largest insurer.</p>
<p>Warta plans to offer between 865,380 and 2,596,139 new registered shares to BPH, Kredyt Bank, PBK and two minority shareholders, with the issue likely to be set in January, Witkowski said.</p>
<p>It has not yet been decided how the shares would be allocated. Currently Warta has 3.46 million shares.</p>
<p>&quot;By creating the group Warta will become stronger in terms of capital, will be more credible and it will have a chance to introduce joint banking-insurance products,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Warta would also benefit from gaining access to the banks' branch networks that would offer both banking and insurance products.</p>
<p>Warta has about 18 percent of the Polish non-life insurance market.</p>
<p>Witkowski said the group wanted to participate in the privatisation of one of Poland's biggest banks next year, but he did not name the bank.</p>
<p>Poland plans to offer in 1997 about 65 percent of PBK to a strategic investor or a group of investors and has also signalled plans to float about 30 percent of the country's leading commercial bank Bank Handlowy SA.</p>
<p>Witkowski said Warta together with the banks also planned to buy 34 percent of shares in BPH, currently held by the state treasury.</p>
<p>He said the group would include other insurers as PBK had two insurance subsidiaries and Warta had a 36.8 percent stake in life insurance joint venture with Bank PKO BP, Warta-Vita.</p>
<p>He added the smaller firms in the group were likely to concentrate in specific areas.</p>
<p>Warta itself would continue to focus on large companies, notably air, marine and foreign trade insurance -- the areas in which it is most experienced, Witkowski said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have offers for small businesses but our main goal is insuring large firms,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150106">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
