<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251707" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAWI: PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Dec 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Malawi - Dec 12.</headline>
<dateline>BLANTYRE 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in the Malawi press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE NATION</p>
<p>- Traditional chiefs in Lilongwe district, central Malawi, asked Members of Parliament from the main opposition Malawi Congress Party (MCP) in the district to return to parliament immediately.</p>
<p>- Vice President Justin Malewezi on Wednesday appealed to the tobacco sector, the country's biggest foreign exchange earner to stop violating children's rights by employing them and instead provide education in all tobacco estates in the country to ensure they get basic education.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>THE DAILY TIMES</p>
<p>- The Human Rights Consultative Committee on Wednesday called on Speaker of the National Assembly, Rodwell Munyenyembe to suspend parliamentary deliberations until negotiations are completed and all parties boycotting proceedings return to the house.</p>
<p>Five human rights organisations in a signed statement said they were concerned with the speaker's manner of conducting parliamentary business without following the constitutional provision which requires a quorum of two-thirds majority of elected member at the beginning of any sitting.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BLANTYRE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAWI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
