<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251796" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Bucharest bourse turnover rises, prices fall.</title>
<headline>Bucharest bourse turnover rises, prices fall.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Strong buying in fertiliser maker Azomures SA took Bucharest stock exchange turnover up to 54 million lei from 42.1 million previously.</p>
<p>But thin demand for other stocks pushed most prices down, sending two independent indices to year lows, traders said.</p>
<p>Seven stocks touched new lows, three drifted higher, one stayed unchanged and five had no trade.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's higher turnover level does not mean investors' interest has grown,&quot; said a trader. &quot;There was one investor buying large share packages in Azomures, despite its rising price. Otherwise, interest was as thin as ever.&quot;</p>
<p>Azomures, which took 86 percent of turnover, opened at 11,100 lei, its closing price in the previous session, and rose to 11,500 by the end of trading.</p>
<p>Brokers said parliamentary approval on Wednesday for a new reformist government had little impact on the market.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps it is to early to expect some enthusiasm from this market, which barely responds to anything,&quot; said a broker.</p>
<p>The new cabinet, a coalition grouping the centrist Democratic Convention, Social Democrats and representatives of ethnic Hungarians in Romania, has pledged to support the expansion of Romania's budding capital market.</p>
<p>It also says it will work out rules to encourage foreign portfolio investors, so far absent from the local market.</p>
<p>On Thursday, syringe maker Sanevit SA remained suspended for the eighth consecutive session pending an announcement on a recent shareholders' decision to add imported equipment to its capital base.</p>
<p>Two unofficial value-weighted indices - the VAB, computed by Vanguard SA, and  Bucharest Investment Group 's BIG -- fell to year lows. The VAB dropped 2.9 percent to 273.4 points and the BIG slipped 2.86 percent a 272.6 points.</p>
<p>		DEC 12  DEC 10   Week's change  1996 high  1996 low</p>
<p> VAB-Index  273.4   281.6	-7.0  pct     879.29    273.4</p>
<p> BIG-Index  272.60  280.64     -6.97 pct     820.9     272.60</p>
<p>($=3,687 lei)</p>
<p>-- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
