<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251826" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Yugo c.bank says will keep dinar stable - newspaper.</title>
<headline>Yugo c.bank says will keep dinar stable - newspaper.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Yugoslav central bank and the federal government are trying to maintain stability of the dinar despite numerous economic problems, a senior central bank official was quoted Thursday by Politika daily as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The National Bank of Yugoslavia (NBY) is trying to maintain a stable dinar exchange rate. If we were asked, there would be no devaluation but many economic problems affect the rate,&quot; NBY Deputy Governor Bozidar Gazivoda was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;The federal government also does not plan a change of the (dinar) exchange rate,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the economic situation was very complex and the central bank was trying to maintain stable prices and a relatively stable dinar exchange rate by implementing an adequate monetary policy.</p>
<p>The dinar (black market) rate fluctuations over past few days were mainly psychological and temporary, the paper quoted him as saying.</p>
<p>The dinar has been sliding on the black market since last weekend. Street dealers in Belgrade pay 3.7 dinars for the German mark, and up to four dinars in other Serbian cities.</p>
<p>The dinar was last devalued by 70 percent in November 1995 and fixed at 3.3 to the German mark.</p>
<p>The black market rate has remained stable at around 3.4 to the German mark until the November elections.</p>
<p>More than twenty days of protests over annullment of opposition election results have caused growing political uncertainty and pushed the dinar down. -- Beti Bilandzic, Belgrade newsroom, 381 11 222 4305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
