<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251833" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria to focus 1997 privatisation on big firms.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria to focus 1997 privatisation on big firms.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Heavily-indebted Bulgaria plans to concentrate its privatisation efforts on a few major companies in 1997 to raise cash to fund a big projected budget deficit under a tough new monetary regime.</p>
<p>Privatisation Agency director Vesselin Blagoev told Reuters stakes in the Bulgarian Telecommunications Company (BTC), the Himko chemical plant and several other big companies would be offered for sale next year.</p>
<p>&quot;The main difference between 1996 and 1997 will be that we shall not dedicate so much effort to the number of deals but we shall direct most of our efforts into selling the big companies,&quot; he said in an interview on Thursday.</p>
<p>He said the agency, which until early this week was talking exclusively to U.S. firm General Chemical Co about the sale of a 60 percent stake in the Sodi Devnya soda ash plant, was now negotiating with all the shortlisted companies. He declined to comment further.</p>
<p>Belgian chemical group Solvay said on Tuesday it did not plan to increase its bid for the plant but it believed General Chemical's offer of $160 million had run into trouble.</p>
<p>One early draft of Bulgaria's 1997 state budget puts the deficit at 370 billion levs ($736 million), 320 billion of which would have to be financed by privatisations if a currency board is introduced as expected early next year.</p>
<p>This would be worth roughly $1 billion if the lev is pegged at about 300-350 as expected, and Blagoev said meeting the target was feasible as the agency was expecting to close several deals worth $100 million or more. The number of deals would depend on international market conditions.</p>
<p>A currency board is a form of fixed exchange rate regime which matches levs in circulation with central bank reserves, which would halt the current lev slide and restore confidence.</p>
<p>The government, which must meet foreign debt payments of $1.3 billion next year, will offer 25 percent of BTC, which had 1995 turnover of $244.6 million, to an international operator.</p>
<p>Blagoev said the agency hoped to receive a cabinet decision on the shortlist of financial advisers for the sale on Thursday. &quot;In less than two months we shall have the financial adviser working on the deal,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A new telecommunications law should be in place by the first quarter of 1997 and bids could be invited around the end of the second quarter or the beginning of the third. &quot;It has to be complete before the end of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said a deadline for presentation of bids for Himko, whose 1995 turnover was $151.5 million and which exports 89 percent of its production, would be announced in about a month.</p>
<p>South Korea's Daewoo Corp, which in September bought 67 percent of the Sheraton Sofia Balkan hotel for $22.3 million, has also expressed interest in forklift truck maker Balkankar Holding, in buying Balkanbank, one of the country's troubled banks, and in bidding for a GSM mobile telephone operator contract.</p>
<p>Blagoev said the privatisation agency had completed 435 deals worth 90 billion levs in cash and transferred liabilities this year up to December 6. The total number of deals since 1993 was 969. &quot;The number of deals is important because we are creating support for the process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has the lowest level of foreign investment in the region. Investors are deterred by excessive red tape and inconsistent and arbitrarily applied laws, while privatisation has faced opposition from powerful local business interests.</p>
<p>A car making joint venture between Rover Group Ltd, a subsidiary of German automaker Bayerische Motoren Werke AG, and a Bulgarian consortium, closed down in April.</p>
<p>Rodacar said the government had ignored its pleas for tax breaks and a new trade deal with the Czech Republic meant imported Skodas were cheaper than cars assembled in Bulgaria.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's biggest privatisation deal to date is the sale of 55 percent of transporter SOMAT to Germany's Willi Betz Internationale Spedition GmbH for $55 million in August 1994.</p>
<p>-- Sofia newsroom +359 2 84561 ($ = 503 Bulgarian Levs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
