<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25180" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Mafia turncoat accused of ordering Italian murders.</title>
<headline>Mafia turncoat accused of ordering Italian murders.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Mafia boss accused of ordering revenge killings while cooperating with police has fuelled argument over Italy's costly and controversial witness protection programme for Mob informers.</p>
<p>The detention of turncoat Giuseppe Ferone on Thursday also added to debate over the reliability of evidence given by former Mafiosi and raised fears that some criminals were cooperating with magistrates to further their own aims.</p>
<p>&quot;Giuseppe Ferone, the turncoat with a licence to kill, reopens with sickening force the problem of collaborators with justice,&quot; said the Rome daily newspaper La Repubblica in a front-page editorial on Friday.</p>
<p>Ferone, an informer living in a safe house near Rome, was detained with four others in connection with a savage double murder on Tuesday in the eastern Sicilian city of Catania.</p>
<p>He was accused with ordering the shootings of Santa Puglisi, the 22-year-old widowed daughter of a Mafia boss, and 14-year-old Salvatore Botta as revenge for the killings of his own son and father in 1994.</p>
<p>Puglisi was killed as she knelt to pray at her young husband's grave.</p>
<p>Police sources said Ferone was also believed to be responsible for the murder last year of Carmela Minniti, wife of jailed Mafia boss Benedetto &quot;Nitto&quot; Santapaola.</p>
<p>A sixth person was detained in Catania on Friday.</p>
<p>The arrests came after a married couple unexpectedly turned up a Catania police station on Wednesday and said that they wanted to &quot;get a weight off their consciences&quot;.</p>
<p>Ferone was reported to have denied any involvement in the killings but has admitted that a large cache of weapons seized in Catania on Thursday belonged to his clan.</p>
<p>Nearly 1,000 former Mafia members have turned state's evidence, but Italy has for years debated the trustworthiness of once-bloodthirsty mobsters who swore a religious allegiance to an organistion committed to fighting the state.</p>
<p>Catania's acting chief prosecutor Mario Amato on Friday agreed that the Ferone case highlighted weaknesses with the turncoat system. &quot;But overall, the benefits of the programme justify the high costs such as this,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>Worries about the reliability of informers returned to the fore earlier this month when ferocious Mafia boss Giovanni Brusca, accused of killings and bombings, suddenly began collaborating with police.</p>
<p>Magistrates, wary of Mafia plots to discredit other prominent turncoats whose evidence has been instrumental in convicting leading bosses in the past, have said they will treat Brusca's evidence cautiously.</p>
<p>La Repubblica said Italy was currently protecting 6,241 people, most of them family members of turncoats, at an overall cost to the state of around $53 million.</p>
<p>Under the official witness protection programme, Mob turncoats such as Tommaso Buscetta are given reduced sentences, a salary and a new identity with safe houses made available at home and abroad.</p>
<p>They must however adhere to a strict code of conduct and secrecy. Some 24 people have been expelled from the programme in the past for breaking the agreement.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Giorgio Napolitano suggested in a speech on Thursday that the state could finance the cost of police protection with seized Mafia assets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
