<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251917" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil deputy wins support for budget inquiry.</title>
<headline>Brazil deputy wins support for budget inquiry.</headline>
<dateline>BRASILIA 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Brazilian opposition deputy has mustered enough signatures to create a high-powered inquiry into suspected fraud in the budget, but the initiative is largely symbolic and the probe unlikely to take place, a party spokesman said Thursday.</p>
<p>Dep. Miro Teixeira of the Democratic Workers Party (PDT) gathered more than enough support for a Parliamentaty Commission of Inquiry (CPI) to investigate the budget-making process, a party spokesman said.  </p>
<p>&quot;But the government will not let it happen. It's in no one's interest. The only thing it would achieve would be a fight between deputies,&quot; said the spokesman.</p>
<p>Teixeira's proposed inquiry comes as Congress reels from its latest corruption scandal.</p>
<p>Dep. Pedrinho Abrao resigned as lower house leader of the government-allied Brazilian Labor Party last week after claims he demanded a bribe from a construction company in return for approval of a dam project included in the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>Abrao has denied the allegation. On Thursday, a congressional panel decided not to recommend he be stripped of office, and instead referred the matter to another committee.</p>
<p>The scandal has threatened to distract Congress from government's attempts to muster support for a constitutional amendment allowing President Fernando Henrique Cardoso to run for a second term.</p>
<p>-- William Schomberg, Brasilia newsroom 5561 2230358</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRASILIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
