<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251952" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Argentine Molino Canuelas to buy Brazil mill-paper.</title>
<headline>Argentine Molino Canuelas to buy Brazil mill-paper.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Argentine wheat miller Molino Canuelas, part of the Navilli group, is negotiating to buy a mill in the Brazilian region of Rio Grande do Sul, the financial daily Gazeta Mercantil said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The newspaper did not specify which mill it would buy or whom it was buying it from.</p>
<p>The operation, part of the company's strategy of expanding within the Mercosur trade group, will involve a total investment of $52 million of which $12 million will be aimed at raising the mill's production to 600 tonnes per day from 450, Gazeta said.</p>
<p>Molino Canuelas will have shipped 168,000 tonnes of wheat flour to Brazil by the end of 1996 for earnings of approximately $68 million, double the volume achieved in 1995, the newspaper quoted the company's international trade manager as saying.</p>
<p>It aims to sell 300,000 tonnes to Brazil in 1997, said trade manager Jorge Mario Paredes, adding that Molino Canuelas currently accounts for 40 percent of Brazilian flour imports and is aiming for a 20 percent share of the total Brazilian market.</p>
<p>The company last year bought a mill in Uruguay with annual capacity of 144,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Paredes said its marketing strategy was based on financing conditions which gave customers the option of 360 days' credit at international interest rates.</p>
<p>Production costs were low at around $38 per tonne and Molino Canuelas had its own fleet of 157 trucks, he added.</p>
<p>The Navilli group owns four mills in Argentina with a processing capacity of 900,000 tonnes per year, Gazeta said.</p>
<p>--Joelle Diderich, Rio de Janeiro newsroom +55 21 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C182">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
