<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251940" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: IMF official raps Colombia's fiscal policy.</title>
<headline>IMF official raps Colombia's fiscal policy.</headline>
<byline>Tom Brown</byline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A top International Monetary Fund official issued a stern warning about Colombia's traditionally prudent economic policies, saying the government's yawning fiscal deficit and failure to cut public spending were &quot;very worrisome.&quot;</p>
<p>The warning, a virtual red alert on the state of the Colombian economy, came in a letter from IMF deputy director Stanley Fischer to Finance Minister Jose Antonio Ocampo and central bank director Miguel Urrutia.  </p>
<p>Excerpts from the letter, in which Fischer also criticized Colombia's inability to reduce inflation averaging 22 percent over the past 20 years, were published in Thursday's editions of Bogota's El Espectador newspaper.</p>
<p>Central bank director Miguel Urrutia acknowledged receiving the letter in remarks to reporters at a public ceremony Thursday. But he declined to comment on its content, saying only that it was &quot;informal&quot; and did not represent an official IMF report.  </p>
<p>Fischer lashed out in his letter at what he described as the government's abject failure to cut public spending -- which he said was &quot;extremely high&quot; for a developing country -- and slash its burgeoning fiscal deficit.</p>
<p>The central government's fiscal deficit is expected to total 4.0 percent of gross domestic product this year and to reach 4.3 percent of GDP in 1997, according to the central bank.  </p>
<p>A central bank source consulted by Reuters conceded that the deficit had reached &quot;explosive&quot; levels and said the situation was particularly dangerous since the government was financing the deficit with surplus cash from Colombia's social security system, which is expected to dry up by 1999 or the year 2000.</p>
<p>But the source said Fischer's letter -- which was received two weeks ago and now threatens to hurt Colombia's sovereign debt rating because it was leaked to the media -- was exaggerated in some respects. Fischer would ultimately have to change his assessment of the economy, the source said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The deficit is very, very worrisome ... but it isn't as catastrophic as all that,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said central bank figures varied substantially from those cited by Fischer in some respects. Fischer gives the impression that the Colombian state has grown out of all proportion to its ability to finance itself since 1992, the source said.  </p>
<p>But the consolidated public sector deficit is not expected to exceed 2.0 percent of GDP this year, thanks to privatizations and other efforts toward government downsizing.</p>
<p>The consolidated public sector figures include state oil company Ecopetrol, the state telephone company, electric power companies and the Social Security system, among others.</p>
<p>&quot;He's going to have to correct himself, partly,&quot; the source said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's true that the deficit is explosive and that the government hasn't done enough about it. What isn't true is that the government is too big,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>On the plus side, the source also noted that the public sector was less heavily indebted today than it was nearly a decade ago, thanks to the sell-off of some money-losing businesses and the pre-payment of debt under the previous government of President Cesar Gaviria.</p>
<p>-- Bogota newsroom, 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
