<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="251935" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Poll finds Colombia lawman most popular politician.</title>
<headline>Poll finds Colombia lawman most popular politician.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's chief prosecutor, Alfonso Valdivieso, a crusader against narcotics and official corruption, is the country's most popular politician, according to a poll published Thursday.</p>
<p>In a survey by the respected El Espectador newspaper, 33 percent of those asked said they would vote for Valdivieso if presidential elections were held tomorrow.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Horacio Serpa, seen by many as President Ernesto Samper's natural heir, mustered only 17 percent support in the poll. The next presidential elections are due in 1998.</p>
<p>Valdivieso, regarded here as a U.S. favourite, has made enemies at home for his fight against corruption, which has included investigating allegations that Samper financed his 1994 election campaign with drug money.</p>
<p>On a visit to Miami last week, Valdivieso said he would score Samper's presidency with about three out of 10.</p>
<p>Noemi Sanin, a Conservative Party member and former ambassador to Britain, scored 18 percent in the poll. Alvaro Uribe, the hardline governor of the northwestern province of Antioquia, was backed by 5 percent of respondents.</p>
<p>The survey of 1,000 people was conducted jointly by El Espectador and the CM&amp; television news programme on Dec. 9 and 10 and has a margin of error of 3.1 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
