<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25204" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy's drive for EMU hurt by slowing economy.</title>
<headline>Italy's drive for EMU hurt by slowing economy.</headline>
<byline>Crispian Balmer</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's economy slowed in the second quarter of 1996, putting further strain on the government's flagging efforts to become a founding member of the single European currency.</p>
<p>Provisional data released by statistics office Istat on Friday, showed Italy's gross domestic product (GDP) falling 0.5 percent between April and June compared with the first quarter. On a year-by-year basis the economy grew 0.5 percent.</p>
<p>Analysts said faltering industrial output, the strong lira and stringent Bank of Italy monetary policy had all combined to stall economic growth.</p>
<p>&quot;Given that under a year ago we were experiencing growth of over three percent, I think one can say Italy is now in a mild recession,&quot; said Riccardo Barbieri, Italian analyst with Morgan Stanley in London.</p>
<p>In the first three months of 1996, GDP grew 1.5 percent year-on-year and 0.5 percent quarter-on-quarter.</p>
<p>Most economists expect the current economic cycle to touch bottom this quarter followed by a slight pick up towards the end of the year, but this will not provide much comfort to the Treasury as it grapples with the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>The package is due to be unveiled by the end of September and Prime Minister Romano Prodi hopes it will significantly boost Italy's chances of complying with the Maastricht Treaty and joining European economic and monetary union (EMU) by 1999.</p>
<p>Economists say he faces a daunting challenge.</p>
<p>&quot;The GDP data is certainly not good news for the government in terms of the budget. It was a difficult-enough task in the first place and they are now getting no help from the business cycle,&quot; said Ilaria Fornari, analyst at JP Morgan in Milan.</p>
<p>The government has said the budget will cut next year's deficit by 32.4 trillion lire ($21.4 billion), but it has already promised not to touch welfare spending or pensions.</p>
<p>Investors fear the latest GDP data will persuade Prodi to produce an even tamer budget than already feared.</p>
<p>&quot;Budget policy has to remain restrictive despite the fact that the economic cycle demands a more expansive policy. Maastricht should prevent Prodi giving a spur to the economy,&quot; said Lucia Trevisan, economist with Milan brokers Caboto.</p>
<p>The GDP stagnation has not come as a surprise, with recent industrial production and order data in retreat and Italy's main European trading partners all suffering economic slowdowns.</p>
<p>Despite regular cries of alarm from senior industrialists, the Bank of Italy maintained high interest rates for over a year before finally easing its key discount rate in July.</p>
<p>Indeed, with inflation falling sharply in recent months, real Italian interest rates have actually risen.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank of Italy's restrictive monetary policy has weighed especially heavily on GDP,&quot; Trevisan said.</p>
<p>The economy has slowed more rapidly than the government has anticipated. Just over a year ago it was still predicting annual growth of three percent for 1996 against a current target of 1.2 percent. Most analysts forecast growth of closer to 0.7 percent.</p>
<p>This decline will inevitably hurt tax inflows and at the same time lead to more unemployment benefit payments, thereby jeopardising the government's public sector borrowing targets.</p>
<p>However, analysts are confident the economy will not slide much further, pointing to a pick up in real salaries this year, for the first time since 1992, which should boost consumption.</p>
<p>In addition, other European economies are starting to turn around, giving hope to Italy's army of exporters. $1 = 1,512</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
