<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252075" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGBs to focus on Tokyo share prices.</title>
<headline>JGBs to focus on Tokyo share prices.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key March Japanese government bond futures contract is expected to be caught in a range near 125.00 on Friday.</p>
<p>JGBs will likely be supported on the downside by investors' bargain-hunting, traders said.</p>
<p>A fall in Tokyo share prices, on the other hand, would make JGBs heavy on the upperside, they said.</p>
<p>&quot;If Tokyo share prices fall below 20,000 yen, profit-taking sales of JGBs may appear,&quot; a trader for a city bank's securities affiliate said. City banks in particular, may be forced to sell JGBs if that happens, the trader said.  </p>
<p>The March contract's rise on LIFFE will also provide support to JGBs in Tokyo, a trader for a brokerage house said.</p>
<p>The March closed at 125.01 on LIFFE overnight, up from Thursday's Tokyo close of 124.89.</p>
<p>The first trader said he did not think the Bank of Japan would raise interest rates at the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;Worries about (Japan's) financial system are beginning to re-emerge, and I doubt interest rates would be raised before (corporate) book-closings at the end of March,&quot; the trader said.</p>
<p>-- Tokyo Treasury Desk, +81-3-5473-3748</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
