<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252194" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares fall, off lows on support.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares fall, off lows on support.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares fell sharply then recouped some of their losses on Thursday after the cancellation of a law allowing the government to sell state property, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 closed 1,005.29 points, or 1.09 percent lower at 90,823.50, sharply down from the midday close of 93,134.84 which was up 1.42 percent from Wednesday.</p>
<p>It sank 2.5 percent to a low of 89,524 in the afternoon on news that the constitutional court annulled a law that would enable the government to sell state property as part of its measures to raise funds to plug deficits.</p>
<p>&quot;Panic sales, mainly in shares of largely state owned firms were sparked by the constitutional court decision,&quot; said Nazmi Sarikaya from Disbank.</p>
<p>&quot;The market was already nervous in the past few days due to rumours of a possible downgrading expected in Turkey's credit rating soon,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Afternoon volatility caused daily trade volume to leap to 17.01 trillion lira from Wednesday's 13.69 trillion.</p>
<p>Several brokers expect an upward reaction on Friday, with the help of selective buys based on year-end profit prospects.</p>
<p>&quot;The index met support at 90,500 during today's fall, but it may ease towards 87,000 in the medium term if it cannot exceed the 92,500 mark tomorrow,&quot; Murat Emrali from Eczacibasi securities told Reuters.</p>
<p>Other brokers said the index could drift sideways between 90,000 and 92,000 for a while.</p>
<p>Non-stop losses have totalled 3.8 percent since Friday's all-time high close of 94,407.22. The index had leapt 2.89 percent last week after a 5.49 percent surge the previous week and hit nine record closes in the last two weeks.</p>
<p>Of the 231 shares traded, losers outdid gainers by 114 to 61 and 56 were stable. The 85-share industrial index eased 0.45 percent to 95,897.28 and the 15-share financial index dived 2.49 percent to 88,028.06.</p>
<p>Actives were led by largely state owned flat steel giant Eregli, down 500 lira at 12,000 and Ihlas Holding, up 1,250 lira at 16,000. They made up 13 percent of the total turnover.</p>
<p>-- Aydan Eksin, Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
