<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252298" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mass. board to consider Middlesex County bailout.</title>
<headline>Mass. board to consider Middlesex County bailout.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Massachusetts emergency board on Friday will consider proposals to allow Middlesex County to borrow funds to cover debt payments due the same day, a spokesman for the state's treasurer said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The emergency board, which has not met since it was established through legislation in 1991, is composed of State Treasurer Joe Malone, Attorney General Scott Harshbarger and a representative from Gov. William Weld's Administration and Finance Department.</p>
<p>On Tuesday, Moody's Investors Service, citing the county's possible default on $4.5 million of unrated revenue anticipation notes, lowered its rating on Middlesex general obligation bonds to B.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have had a formal request to meet and the board will meet Friday morning,&quot; said Malone's spokesman Eric Fehrnstrom.</p>
<p>But Fehrnstrom and Ed Cafasso, a spokesman for Harshbarger, said it was unclear if the impending default by the state's largest county would qualify it for emergency borrowing under the statute.</p>
<p>The law defines an emergency in part &quot;as a sudden unavoidable event or series of events that could not be foreseen.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is unclear whether a default on notes that everyone knew were due can be construed as unforeseen,&quot; said Cafasso.  </p>
<p>Another source close to the board members said a default &quot;could be just the wake-up call these guys need. The (Weld) administration has long called for the elimination of county government. The state could very well say, 'Okay, we'll take over your debt service and in exchange you go out of business.'&quot;</p>
<p>Other sources questioned whether emergency funds were really needed and suggested that the county, which runs from Cambridge to Lowell, could use other sources of funds.</p>
<p>The immediate source of the fiscal distress is the county hospital. The hospital's sale is to close five days after the notes are due, but proceeds and remaining receivables will not be nearly enough to meet all hospital-related liabilities.</p>
<p>--Leslie Gevirtz, 617-367-4142</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
