<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252349" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tribune's WGN-TV, Chicago Bulls settle suit with NBA.</title>
<headline>Tribune's WGN-TV, Chicago Bulls settle suit with NBA.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Chicago Bulls settled a long legal battle with the National Basketball Association Thursday, winning the right to televise up to 15 games each season over the Tribune Co's WGN-TV cable superstation.</p>
<p>Under the five-year settlement, Tribune-owned WGN, which broadcasts freely in Chicago and across parts of the country on several cable systems, can televise as many Bulls' games as it wants in the Chicago area, but was limited 15 games in each of the next four seasons over the cable &quot;superstation.&quot;</p>
<p>Advertising proceeds from the superstation broadcasts of the four-time champion Bulls will be split among the league, WGN-TV and the Bulls.</p>
<p>For the remainder of the current season, the cable superstation can broadcast 12 more Bulls games, paying a &quot;superstation tax&quot; to the league. The Bulls and WGN will also pay a fee to the NBA covering a portion of the &quot;tax&quot; for broadcasts made over the past two seasons.</p>
<p>But WGN's national reach may be narrowing. Tele-Communications Inc, the nation's largest cable provider, may remove WGN from some of its systems outside the Chicago area.</p>
<p>The Bulls first filed an anti-trust suit against the NBA in 1990 after the league blocked the team from airing games over the superstation, with the NBA arguing that the broadcasts were an unfair intrusion into other teams' markets.</p>
<p>A federal judge held two trials and issued injunctions that allowed the team to broadcast first 25 then at least 30 games per season. But the league appealed and a higher court in September ordered a new trial. The settlement would end the litigation, the Bulls said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47510">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
