<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252304" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot resid prices mostly lose despite crude.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot resid prices mostly lose despite crude.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot residual fuel prices mostly moved lower Thursday despite firmer crude, with high sulphurs still under the most pressure from rising supply and some refinery problems in the U.S. Gulf, sources said.</p>
<p>&quot;Coker problems in the (US) Gulf are holding down high sulphur, but (low sulphur) demand has been okay at the rack,&quot; said one cash trader, noting buyers have backed off this week after the wild swings in crude.</p>
<p>In New York Harbor, three percent lost another 25-50 cents to $17.00-25 a barrel, with 2.2 percent down about the same amount to the $18.50 level, traders said.  </p>
<p>But despite relatively mild weather this month, several utilities said they expected very little downside from here, particularly if crude stabilizes.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a little too early (in the heating season) for resid to go soft. There's too much potential for a rally if we get (cold) weather,&quot; said one East Coast utility.</p>
<p>Another eastern utility agreed. &quot;I think prices will stay relatively firm. More people are burning oil now,&quot; he said, referring to fuel oil's competitive edge over natgas.</p>
<p>But USG refinery problems like Star's damaged H-oil unit in Louisiana continued to plague HSFO, sources agreed.</p>
<p>NYH physical one percent slipped more than a quarter to about $21.75-22.00. Traders said January one percent paper was still quoted at about $21, little changed on the day.</p>
<p>At the U.S. Gulf Coast, one percent slipped 25 cents or more to $18.50-75, while three percent notionally was off a quarter to $15.75, traders said.</p>
<p>No NYH or USG deals were reported.</p>
<p>New York city gate swing gas prices were down slightly Thursday to the $3.95-4.05/mmBtu area compared to NYH one percent resid at a $3.47/mmBtu equivalent. For January, New York gas was quoted at $1.50 over the screen, or about $5.00/mmBtu, well-above resid paper at a $3.33/mmBtu equivalent.</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
