<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252367" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Guarantee Life plans acquisitions.</title>
<headline>Guarantee Life plans acquisitions.</headline>
<byline>Patricia Vowinkel</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Guarantee Life Cos Inc, which converted from a mutual into a publicly-traded stock company a year ago, plans to use its financial flexibility to fund an acquisition campaign to help spur growth, top company officials said.</p>
<p>The company can raise at least $130 million for acquisitions in the individual life or excess of loss medical business, Guarantee Life chief executive Robert Bates said earlier this week.  </p>
<p>The acquisitions and new sales growth are expected to help the company boost its return on equity to the 11-12 percent range from a current level of just under eight percent.</p>
<p>When return on equity reaches around 11 to 12 percent, earnings would rise to about $1.90-$2.00 a share compared to $0.93 a share in 1995, chief financial officer William Bauhard said.</p>
<p>Guarantee Life said it was comfortable with analysts' First Call 1997 consensus estimate of $1.59 a share, but declined comment on the 1996 fourth quarter forecast of $0.37 a share.  </p>
<p>Guarantee Life, which as a mutual company was owned by its policyholders for 95 years, is just one of a handful of U.S. insurers that have demutualized in an effort to gain better access to the capital markets and improve competitiveness.</p>
<p>Mutual companies are much more restricted in their ability to raise capital and therefore finance growth.</p>
<p>The company, which plans to target small individual life insurance companies or individual life books of business, in June acquired Security Life Insurance Co of America's entire universal life insurance block of business for $8.5 million.  </p>
<p>Guarantee Life is willing to add up to $50 million to its currently debt-free balance sheet and has about another $40 million left over from its initial public offering to use for acquisitions, Bauhard said.</p>
<p>Guarantee Life also has a $30 million line of credit and could possibly increase that by another $30 million, he said.</p>
<p>In addition to individual life, Guarantee Life also may seek to purchase additional excess of loss medical business, Bates said.</p>
<p>That line of business had been under pressure but has recently begun showing signs of a recovery, Bates said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We began seeing indications in October that it was firming up,&quot; he said. &quot;How significant and how sustained that will be only time will tell,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In the company's employee benefits business, new sales are up 42 percent through the first nine months of 1996 and are up 29.5 percent on a same-office basis.</p>
<p>Individual life sales are up 22 percent for the first nine months.</p>
<p>Revenues for the first nine months of 1996 were $216 million compared to $218.7 million a year ago. Top line growth was down because the company exited a medical product line in California and because of the earlier weakness in the excess of loss medical business.</p>
<p>Although Guarantee Life adopted a shareholder rights plan earlier this year, the company said it was not aware of any specific effort to gain control of the company.</p>
<p>Guarantee Life last year rejected an unsolicited $17.50 a share offer from American Mutual Life Insurance Co.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
