<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252397" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Rep. Kasich to push for charity tax credit.</title>
<headline>U.S. Rep. Kasich to push for charity tax credit.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>House Budget Committee Chairman John Kasich said he will push for passage of a new tax credit for individuals who donate money to charity when Congress reconvenes in January.</p>
<p>Kasich said proponents of the tax credit faced an uphill battle. He said he was looking at a number of options to raise revenue needed to pay for the plan, including closing corporate tax loopholes and repealing the Earned Income Tax Credit for working poor people without children.</p>
<p>Kasich and Indiana Republican Sen. Dan Coats have drafted a &quot;compassionate tax credit&quot; bill allowing individuals to receive a maximum $500 tax credit and married couples a $1,000 credit for contributions to charitible groups.</p>
<p>To qualify for the donation, charities would have to spend 75 percent of their receipts on poverty programs.</p>
<p>&quot;We're going to make a good run at this.  I believe (House Speaker) Newt Gingrich is interested in an effort like this working,&quot; Kasich told a special forum held to discuss the tax credit proposal.</p>
<p>Kasich is also considering a roughly five percent cut in federal block grants to states under the new welfare law. States use the block grant funds to provide cash aid and other services to poor women and children.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
