<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252373" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Advertising, consumerism critic Vance Packard dies.</title>
<headline>Advertising, consumerism critic Vance Packard dies.</headline>
<dateline>EDGARTOWN, Mass. 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vance Packard, author of &quot;The Hidden Persuaders&quot; and other books criticising advertising and the consumer society, died early on Thursday in Martha's Vineyard Hospital, an aide said. He was 82.</p>
<p>&quot;It was a massive heart attack Friday evening and he never regained consciousness,&quot; Packard's longtime aide, Andrew Greenwood, said.</p>
<p>Packard, who worked as a journalist until the mid-1950s, gained fame with his 1957 book &quot;The Hidden Persuaders,&quot; which exposed many of the psychological tools Madison Avenue used to build sales.</p>
<p>A 1987 Forbes magazine article paid homage to him for disclosing advertising techniques. Women will pay 25 cents for a bar of soap that cleans their hands, he pointed out, but $2.50 for one that promises to make their hands beautiful. Selling plain soap is peddling product performance; add some skin cream and you are selling hope.</p>
<p>Born in Granville Summit, Pennsylvania, Vance Oakley Packard obtained a bachelor's degree from Pennsylvania State University and a master's degree in journalism from Columbia University in 1937, the same year he began writing a column for the Boston Record newspaper.</p>
<p>He later worked as a feature writer and editor for the Associated Press and as a staff writer for American and Collier magazines.</p>
<p>Packard criticised the decline of the American family and the loss of community ties in his 1972 book, &quot;A Nation of Strangers,&quot; and targeted the consumer society in such books as &quot;The Waste Makers&quot; (1960) and &quot;The Ultra Rich: How Much Is Too Much?&quot; (1989).</p>
<p>Packard, who lived on the summer resort island of Martha's Vineyard off the coast of Massachusetts, is survived by his wife, Mamie Virginia Packard, and their three children, Vance, Randall and Cynthia.</p>
<p>Greenwood said final funeral arrangements were not yet set.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GOBIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="EDGARTOWN, Mass."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
