<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252423" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Expert testifies DNA evidence unreliable in Simpson.</title>
<headline>Expert testifies DNA evidence unreliable in Simpson.</headline>
<byline>Michael Miller</byline>
<dateline>SANTA MONICA, Calif 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>An expert testifying in O.J. Simpson's civil trial told jurors on Thursday that DNA evidence used to link the former football star to the murders of his ex-wife and her friend was not reliable.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe there is an unacceptable risk or chance, by the way these samples were handled, of there being cross- contamination,&quot; Dr. John Gerdes said.</p>
<p>His testimony came as Simpson's defence team pursued its two-pronged theory that Los Angeles Police Department forensic experts botched the collection and testing of hair and blood samples and that evidence was planted by police in order to frame the former athlete.</p>
<p>Gerdes, the clinical director of a Denver, Colorado, DNA lab and one of the country's leading authorities in the field, said tests carried out at the LAPD's crime laboratory could not be trusted because of the way the samples were collected and the way the tests were conducted.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel that with the sample collection and manipulation and the PCR setup and protocols (at the laboratory), there is a risk of contamination,&quot; he said. PCR is a form of DNA testing.</p>
<p>Gerdes said DNA testing in a hospital setting was far more reliable than testing samples taken from a crime scene because samples obtained in a hospital were &quot;sterile&quot; while crime scene samples were &quot;dirty.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, Gerdes said, such samples had to be collected on cloth &quot;swatches,&quot; placed in bags, taken out and dried, and then placed in other bags, with each manipulation increasing the risk of one sample being cross-contaminated by another.</p>
<p>Simpson was acquitted of the June 12, 1994, murders of Nicole Brown Simpson and Ronald Goldman by a criminal court jury in October 1995. He is now being sued by the families of the victims in the civil wrongful death case.</p>
<p>The civil case jury heard from witnesses earlier, as did the criminal case panel, that the odds against blood in the case belonging to anyone other than Simpson and the victims were in the billions to one range.</p>
<p>But Gerdes said even the results of tests done at other laboratories were unreliable. The California Department of Justice Laboratory in northern California had a defect in its testing system that made some of its results &quot;suspect&quot; while the possible cross-contamination at the LAPD laboratory made the remainder unreliable, he said.</p>
<p>The third testing centre in the case, Cellmark Laboratories in Maryland, used a system that would amplify the errors of cross-contamination made in the LAPD laboratory, Gerdes said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA MONICA, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
