<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252520" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. spot prods up as NYMEX jumps on Bayway outage.</title>
<headline>U.S. spot prods up as NYMEX jumps on Bayway outage.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. spot product differentials pared much of their early Thursday strength, slipping back as traders pondered the effects of the Tosco Bayway cat cracker outage.</p>
<p>However, outright prices were stronger on the back of the NYMEX gains, which jumped higher on the refinery news.</p>
<p>Unleaded gasoline differentials firmed during early action as sellers pulled back from the market, traders said. Most players viewed the news of the fire at Tosco's 140,000 barrel per day (bpd) fluid catalytic cracker cautiously, since no information on the length of the outage was available.</p>
<p>&quot;Tosco wasn't in the market buying, and there was no real price effect with all the imports coming into New York Harbor,&quot; one trader said, referring to the large amount of gasoline expected in coming days from Europe and the Caribbean.</p>
<p>In NYH, prompt conventional unleaded M5 gasoline was offered at about 0.25 cent under the screen, down at least 0.5 cent from levels early in the day.</p>
<p>U.S. Gulf conventional unleaded M4 for the 36th cycle on the Colonial Pipeline was talked between 5.85 to 5.95 cents below NYMEX, with back 35th cycle slightly below that level.</p>
<p>-- Matt Daily, New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1626</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
