<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252522" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ohio bill calls for $1.1 bln school bond program.</title>
<headline>Ohio bill calls for $1.1 bln school bond program.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Ohio lawmaker has introduced a bill to create a $1.1 billion bond program for school capital improvements by changing the state's regulations on the pricing and distribution of beer and wine.</p>
<p>State Rep. Gene Krebs, R-Camdem, proposed the adoption of a moderately deregulated system for beer and wine of no minimum mark ups or minimum prices along with a set increase in the excise tax. He said the plan would raise $113 million a year in tax revenue on beer and wine, $73 million more than is currently being collected.</p>
<p>Those funds would be used to back $1.1 billion of bonds for school capital projects, according to synopsis of Krebs' bill.</p>
<p>As for how school districts could access the bond program, Krebs proposed using a Tax Effort Index he unveiled last month.</p>
<p>The index, which is based on a formula that considers a school district's rate of self-imposed taxation along with its income level and property valuation, is aimed at identifying districts in need of state assistance.</p>
<p>Under Krebs' bill, school districts' ranking in the index would be the first criteria for qualifying for the bond program.</p>
<p>The bill also includes a a five percent reduction in the personal property inventory tax, dropping the rate to 20 percent. The tax proposal would result in a revenue loss of about $22 million for counties and about $51 million for school districts, according to the bill's synopsis.</p>
<p>--Karen Pierog, 312-408-8647</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
