<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252730" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French capital markets closing report.</title>
<headline>French capital markets closing report.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>French bond futures drifted lower in a nervous session buffeted by the moves in the United States but found strong support at 128.12, a level the contract touched several times during the day.</p>
<p>The mood at the short end of the curve was more upbeat. PIBOR contracts started well, reacting to a Bank of France monetary policy council member's calls late on Tuesday for aggressive rate cuts, independently of German.</p>
<p>Traders said the move prompted some short covering before PIBOR contracts got another boost from people betting on positive statements on interest rates from President Chirac.  </p>
<p>&quot;People are positioning themselves for a punt,&quot; an analyst at a French bank said. &quot;I doubt anything's really going to happen but giving the political misgivings about interest rate policy why not at least be long of the short end?&quot;</p>
<p>He said PIBOR remained well supported by the fact interest rates would stay low whatever Chirac might say in a television interview at 1950 GMT this evening. &quot;You won't lose much, but there might be a surprise,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some said similar caution ahead of the broadcast was weighing slightly on the franc which moved as low as 3.3843 against the mark from 3.3788 late on Wednesday.  </p>
<p>However others said the franc weakness was more the result of people buying dollars for francs in an otherwise light market. One said concern about calls for a rail strike from Communist-led union CGT might be having an affect.</p>
<p>The Chirac speech was not seen as having any lasting impact however. Most said he would reaffirm the need to follow the current policies aimed at getting the country in shape for European monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;I think he'll underline his commitment to Europe and his commitment to internal security,&quot; Iain Lindsay, senior bond analyst at Credit Lyonnais said.  </p>
<p>&quot;He's unlikely to say revolutionary things in such an interview,&quot; Philippe Brossard, head of research at ABN Amro in Paris, said.</p>
<p>Analysts said the French bond market remained tolerably well supported by domestic investors, which continued to lead to slight outperformance when other bond markets declined.</p>
<p>The 10-year spread between French and German bond yields moved out to minus eight basis points from minus six on Wednesday,</p>
<p>&quot;We still see the spread turning even more negative every time the markets move down,&quot; Brossard said.  </p>
<p>As expected the Bank of France left the intervention rate unchanged after its bi-weekly monetary policy council meeting.</p>
<p>The Treasury sold 335 million Ecu of government bonds at auction with a total bid to cover ratio of 4.7.</p>
<p>-- David Clarke, Paris Newsroom +331 4221 5542</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
