<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252777" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BANGLADESH: PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Dec 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bangladesh Newspapers - Dec 12.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Bangladesh press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE DAILY STAR</p>
<p>Bangladesh and India are expected to sign a long-term agreement on sharing of the Ganges water on Thursday ending two-decade-old dispute between the two neighbours.</p>
<p>The Amnesty International has expressed concern over reported police repression on citizens and urged the government to investigate into such incidents of police violence.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>THE INDEPENDENT</p>
<p>India's Prime Minister Deve Gowda is expectd to pay a brief visit to Bangladesh on December 16 to participate in the silver jubilee celebration of the country's liberation war.</p>
<p>The World Bank is likely to go for spot audits of the bank-funded development programmes to check corruption.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>BANGLADESH OBSERVER</p>
<p>Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina, now visiting Delhi, said on Wednesday that a deal on Ganges water sharing would be a &quot;momentous occasion&quot; in relations between Bangladesh and India and a &quot;stepping stone&quot; for a greater bilateral cooperation.</p>
<p>The government on Wednesday constituted a four-member committee to suggest a policy on the &quot;circuit breaker&quot; which now restricts price movements in the stock market.</p>
<p>---</p>
<p>FINANCIAL EXPRESS</p>
<p>Bangladesh on Wednesday called for consensus on issues to be incorporated in the declaration of the first ministreal conference of World Trade Organisation (WTO) in Singapore.</p>
<p>Bangladesh has about 6.3 million child labourers of whom 0.32 percent are working as sex workers, Unicef officials said in Dhaka on Wednesday.</p>
<p>-- Dhaka Newsroom 880-2-506363 REUTER</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BANDH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BANGLADESH"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
