<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252855" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Uncertainty clouds Bre-X Busang negotiations.</title>
<headline>Uncertainty clouds Bre-X Busang negotiations.</headline>
<byline>Heather Scoffield</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bre-X Minerals Ltd. and Barrick Gold Corp. are trying to forge an alliance to mine the huge Busang gold deposit in Indonesia despite a cloud of uncertainty over the rights to the find, Bre-X's chief executive said Thursday.</p>
<p>But the negotiations with Barrick are progressing slowly, Bre-X Chief Executive Officer David Walsh told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We're moving ahead, albeit at a snail's pace,&quot; he said, adding that legal issues stood in the way of a full agreement. &quot;We're trying to get them to appreciate our views and the legal stance that we've taken.&quot;</p>
<p>Last month the Indonesian government advised Bre-X to form a joint venture with Toronto-based Barrick to operate Busang. The government, which also requested a 10 percent stake, set a Dec. 4 deadline, but the two companies announced after that date that several issues remained outstanding.</p>
<p>Since then, the Indonesian government has raised doubts about Bre-X's grip on Busang, estimated to contain at least 57 million ounces of gold, worth about $21 billion at today's prices.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has stopped processing the previous application for contracts of work by Bre-X because of various problems,&quot; Umar Said, Indonesia's secretary-general of mines, told Reuters in Jakarta on Thursday. &quot;Therefore the previous application by Bre-X that has been delayed must be stopped and must be said to have been cancelled.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Bre-X and Barrick must jointly submit new applications for work on the deposit. Without contracts of work granted by the Indonesian government, Bre-X cannot proceed to exploit the find.</p>
<p>Walsh defended his company, saying its permits and applications for the gold property were &quot;in good standing.&quot;</p>
<p>He said two Bre-X officials met with Umar in Jakarta Thursday and were assured everything was in line. &quot;The telephone call that I got from Rolie (Francisco), he was quite pleased with the meeting. He said we're making very good progress in our relationship (with the mines ministry),&quot; Walsh said.</p>
<p>Bre-X spokesman Steve McAnulty, explaining the apparent contradiction, said: &quot;What the government wants to do in essence is that if an agreement with Barrick is made, the existing applications will be replaced with new applications.&quot;</p>
<p>Bre-X earlier said that Umar had apologised for the misunderstanding, saying his comments were &quot;erroneously reported in a Dec. 11 Reuters newswire article.&quot; But Peter Thomas, a Reuter spokesman in London, said the international news and information company was confident the quotations in its Dec. 11 story from Jakarta were accurate.</p>
<p>Umar's comments to Reuters Thursday were essentially repeating what he said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Despite a barrage of statements from Bre-X on Thursday, Barrick was still seeking clarification on the situation from the Indonesian government.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still seeking clarification and we want to hear directly from the government of Indonesia,&quot; Barrick spokesman Vince Borg said in Toronto. &quot;We're not saying anything until we talk directly to the government of Indonesia.&quot;</p>
<p>Bre-X, too, is waiting for the Indonesian government to make a move.</p>
<p>Walsh said he still had high hopes that Indonesian President Suharto would open up an auction for Busang, allowing other mining companies to bid on the project. He said Bre-X had not made a formal request for an auction, but added: &quot;We understand that the president is reviewing the situation.&quot;</p>
<p>An auction would be advantageous for Bre-X shareholders and for Indonesia, he said. &quot;We're not soliciting offers. We are getting other phone calls,&quot; Walsh said. &quot;I am talking to principals of other companies.&quot;</p>
<p>He said he had spoken to executives at Placer Dome Inc., Newmont Mining Corp. and Teck Corp.</p>
<p>In Vancouver, Placer Dome spokesman Hugh Leggatt said any suggestion of an open auction on Busang was encouraging. His company has made a formal request for an open bidding process.</p>
<p>But gold mining analyst Bill Belovay of CIBC Wood Gundy said Barrick's competitors may be trying to make a deal with Bre-X more expensive for Barrick. &quot;They're playing games,&quot; he said. &quot;One has got to read between the lines.&quot;</p>
<p>Belovay said Busang was so fraught with uncertainty that he has a hard time understanding why the major gold producers would be interested. &quot;One doesn't even know what percentage (Barrick) will end up with. One doesn't even know how to keep Suharto happy,&quot; he said. &quot;To me it's a whole big nightmare.&quot;</p>
<p>Investors were confused by Thursday's developments, analysts said.</p>
<p>Bre-X, whose stock was halted all day on Wednesday, fell 85 cents to C$19.80 in heavy trading of more than 8.6 million shares. Barrick, which lost C$2.75 on Wednesday, regained C$1 to C$39.50 in trading of more than 2 million shares.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
