<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="252908" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - December 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Daily Variety - December 12.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following stories appeared in Thursday's edition of Daily Variety:</p>
<p>HOLLYWOOD - William Mechanic, who has been Peter Chernin's right-hand man in restructuring 20th Century Fox, has been named chairman and CEO of Fox Filmed Entertainment.</p>
<p>HOLLYWOOD - ABC has inked a deal with Carsey-Werner Co for the production house's TV version of the Orion comedy theatrical &quot;Dirty Rotten Scoundrels.&quot;</p>
<p>NEW YORK - ABC News won the bidding war for George Stephanopoulos, the Clinton administration adviser who's segueing to the private sector as the President begins a second term. The network on Wednesday named Stephanopoulos, 35, as a contributing correspondent.</p>
<p>HOLLYWOOD - After all the fanfare, Primary Colors may not bemade at Universal Pictures after all. The Mike Nichols pic, to which John Travolta and Emma Thompson are still attached, is now being shopped elsewhere.</p>
<p>HOLLYWOOD - Kevin Costner has committed to Universal Pictures' For the Love of the Game for producers Sydney Pollack and Amy Robinson.</p>
<p>ANAHEIM - Time Warner 's TBS will likely lose its right to cablecast Atlanta Braves baseball games, which for more than a decade have propelled the superstation into the cable stratosphere, helping it finish among the two or three highest-rated cable networks year after year.</p>
<p>-- New York Newsdesk 212 859-1610</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
