<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253010" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cotter, ServiStar deal not seen as hardware threat.</title>
<headline>Cotter, ServiStar deal not seen as hardware threat.</headline>
<byline>Chris Scott</byline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-11</dateline>
<text>
<p>The merger between Cotter &amp; Co and ServiStar Coast to Coast Corp is not expected to cause competitors like Sears, Roebuck and Co or Home Depot to shift business strategies, industry analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The smaller hardware stores have been struggling to compete with the larger stores for market share,&quot; said Christopher Vroom, an analyst at Alex. Brown &amp; Sons.</p>
<p>&quot;I see this as a merger out of weakness, not out of strength,&quot; he said, &quot;and I don't see the new company as a stronger threat to Home Depot or Lowes (Cos.) (than before).&quot;  </p>
<p>Combining the nation's number-one and number-three hardware store co-operatives will create a network of more than 10,500 independent stores with total annual sales of $4.5 billion. Both Cotter, which sells products to True Value Hardware stores, and ServiStar expect the deal to increase their competitiveness and improve operating efficiencies as they leap-frog over number-two Ace Hardware Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;About 150 of the 382 employees affected as a result of the merger will be offered the chance to move to Chicago,&quot; said Paul Pentz, ServiStar's chief executive, and the president and chief operating officer of the new TruServ Corp.  </p>
<p>Pentz said TruServ will have a net loss of 314 jobs once 68 jobs move to E. Butler, Pa., where ServiStar is located.</p>
<p>TruServ, made up of the True Value, ServiStar and Coast to Coast chains, is not expected to suddenly become a threat to larger players like Home Depot or Lowes, said analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think the merger will have much of an effect on Home Depot's strategies or operations,&quot; said Skip Helm, an analyst at William Blair &amp; Co.</p>
<p>Alex. Brown analyst Vroom agreed. &quot;Together, Home Depot and Lowes control 17 percent of the (hardware) market nationwide,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>&quot;We're projecting that to be 50 percent by 2000, and this merger has not changed that view,&quot; Vroom said.</p>
<p>The major do-it-yourself hardware superstores did not appear fazed at the prospect of a massive network of independent operations, since they compete for different customers.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see any change in our strategy (because of the True Value/ServiStar merger),&quot; confirmed a Lowes spokesman. &quot;Competition exists with the smaller hardware stores, but we try to differentiate ourselves as more of a destination warehouse, where you can buy materials for an entire project.&quot;</p>
<p>As Joseph Ronning, an analyst at Brown Brothers Harriman &amp; Co, points out, &quot;Stores like Sears look for the 'fix-it' customer, while the Home Depots look for the 'build-it' customer.&quot;</p>
<p>Officials at Home Depot could not be reached for comment.</p>
<p>In a prepared statement, Ace Hardware said the merger was neither a surprise, nor a threat to Ace's &quot;continued growth in the industry.&quot; Ace Hardware is a co-operative of more than 5,000 independent hardware stores in 50 states and 56 nations.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I64800">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-11"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
