<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253162" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Netanyahu attends funeral for slain settlers.</title>
<headline>Netanyahu attends funeral for slain settlers.</headline>
<byline>Colleen Siegel</byline>
<dateline>BEIT EL, West Bank 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and cabinet members attended the funeral on Thursday of a Jewish settler and her 12-year-old son killed in an Arab guerrilla attack.</p>
<p>Their presence in a crowd of thousands was a show of government solidarity with the more than 130,000-strong settler community at odds with Netanyahu over his talks with the PLO on Israeli troop redeployment from the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>Etta Tzur and her son Ephraim were killed when gunmen shot at their family car near the self-ruled town of Ramallah in the West Bank on Wednesday. Her husband and four other children were wounded. Israel said the guerrillas escaped into Ramallah.</p>
<p>Israel blamed the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine, an opponent of its peace deals with the PLO, for the attack. The PFLP declined to comment on the allegation.</p>
<p>Maher al-Taher, a spokesman for the group, said in Damascus that Palestinians were duty-bound to attack Jewish settlers.</p>
<p>A settler leader urged the government to respond to the incident by taking a &quot;Zionist decision&quot; and settling more Jews in areas captured by Israel in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>&quot;For any Jewish blood spilled, 1,000 Jewish families will come here to live,&quot; Pinhas Wallerstein, head of the Council of Jewish settlements in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, told Israel Radio.</p>
<p>Since taking office in June, the right-wing Netanyahu government has given the go-ahead for the construction of thousands of homes in existing settlements but has yet to establish any new outposts.</p>
<p>Palestinian President Yasser Arafat, asked by reporters in Gaza to comment on the killings, kept silent. A PLO official said the Palestinian Authority, which runs self-rule in parts of the West Bank and Gaza, condemned the attack.</p>
<p>At the graveside, National Infrastructure Minister Ariel Sharon, a champion of Jewish settlement, sniped at the Israel-PLO peace accords that set up a Palestinian police force overseen by Arafat.</p>
<p>&quot;The murderers continue to go about their business. The Oslo (peace) accords that put the question of protection of Israeli citizens in the hands of a war criminal by any law continue to cause bloodshed,&quot; Sharon said.</p>
<p>In Gaza, Palestinian Justice Minister Freih Abu Medeen saw the shooting in a different context, telling reporters it played into the hands of Netanyahu by giving him ammunition to postpone further a Hebron deal.</p>
<p>&quot;Anything that will delay and kill our dream, we condemn,&quot; Medeen said. &quot;Israel needs these incidents. Israel needs these attacks. Israel will find a cover for its delays...This is a gift for Mr Netanyahu.&quot;</p>
<p>Israel lashed out at the Palestinian Authority and closed off Ramallah after the attack.</p>
<p>&quot;I think the Authority should understand there is no point in peace talks or agreements if they do not result in security,&quot; Finance Minister Dan Meridor told Army Radio.</p>
<p>&quot;This demand has been conveyed to them very sharply and clearly and they must take action,&quot; Meridor said.</p>
<p>Netanyahu gave no indication the killing would affect talks with the PLO on Hebron, where some 400 Jewish settlers live or study amid 100,000 Palestinians.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIT EL, West Bank"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
