<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253298" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Nine suspected Moslem militants detained in France.</title>
<headline>Nine suspected Moslem militants detained in France.</headline>
<byline>Christian Curtenelle</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>French police said they rounded up nine suspected Moslem militants across the country on Thursday, more than a week after a bomb ripped through a Paris commuter train and killed four people.</p>
<p>The swoop, the second this week ordered by anti-terrorism magistrate Laurence Le Vert, was not directly linked to the train blast but instead focused on a network suspected of planting bombs in France last year, police said.</p>
<p>The nine were detained for questioning in the Paris area, in the northern city of Lille, and in the Mediterranean port city of Marseille. Searches of several buildings yielded nothing.</p>
<p>All 14 people detained in Tuesday's dawn raids in the Paris region were released within hours and police said they had made little progress. Last year's wave of attacks killed eight people and injured more than 160.</p>
<p>A police spokesman said &quot;the operation has no direct link&quot; with last week's attack at the Port-Royal station, which investigators believe was carried out, like the 1995 bombings, by Islamic guerrillas angry over French backing for Algeria.</p>
<p>Nine days after the train blast, the probe has apparently made little progress although Interior Minister Jean-Louis Debre said on Wednesday 160 people had been questioned.</p>
<p>Investigators said both swoops aimed to destabilise French networks backing Algerian's Islamic Armed Group (GIA), and specifically targeted a ring allegedly run by Ahmed Zaoui, the GIA's former European leader who was given a suspended four-year jail sentence by a Belgian court in November 1995.</p>
<p>The government is attempting to rush through parliament a bill allowing police to search homes at night when dealing with terrorism suspects.</p>
<p>The Senate laws committee on Wednesday approved the proposal, which would end the current ban on pre-dawn raids.</p>
<p>But the left-wing Magistrates Union said the amendment meant yielding to terrorists bent on weakening democracy. They also said it contradicted a ruling by the Constitutional Council watchdog that night searches were contrary to the constitution.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's laws are absurd. Police can carry out night-time searches for prostitution and drug trafficking, but not terrorism,&quot; Justice Minister Jacques Toubon said.</p>
<p>&quot;They lie in wait, for example in front of a house or a flat where they have to watch suspects burning documents, and they can't go in before 6 a.m,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>In a separate probe, anti-terrorist magistrate Jean-Louis Bruguiere was due to meet colleagues in Turin to discuss Italy's &quot;operation Shakba&quot; in which 19 people were arrested last month on suspicion of belonging to an Algerian guerrilla network.</p>
<p>Bruguiere on Wednesday questioned suspected GIA member Djamel Lounici who has been held in Naples since May 1995.</p>
<p>Lounici, 34, is due to go on trial in Naples next April on charges of smuggling arms to Moslem guerrillas in Algeria.</p>
<p>He is also awaiting extradition to France where he is being tried in absentia with 33 fundamentalists accused of backing Moslem guerrillas in Morocco.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
