<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253289" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS-Siemens on course for robust growth.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Siemens on course for robust growth.</headline>
<byline>Neal Boudette</byline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>German electronics and engineering giant Siemens AG said it is on course for robust growth over the next three years despite its earlier forecast of flat earnings in 1996-97.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect significant earnings growth again in fiscal 1998,&quot; chief executive Heinrich von Pierer said at the company's annual news conference on Thursday. &quot;We are on the right course.</p>
<p>In his speech, Pierer outlined a range of new business, productivity and international initiatives that are supposed to put profits back on the upswing.</p>
<p>Siemens, which in November predicted no increase in 1996-97 profit from last year's, said on Thursday it expected to show a clear profit increase again in 1997-98.</p>
<p>Pierer declined to predict, however, by how much 1997-98 profits would rise.</p>
<p>&quot;Although we have announced a &quot;breather' on the earnings side for fiscal 1997, this certainly does not mean we have retreated from our medium-term profit goals,&quot; Pierer said. &quot;It is clear we are making solid progress in improving our earnings structure.&quot;</p>
<p>He said Siemens expected moderate sales and orders growth in 1996-97 to lead to profit equal to last year's 2.5 billion marks ($1.6 billion) before extraordinaries.</p>
<p>The impact of Germany's economic rebound next year should come in the 1997-98 business year because electrical and electronic industries lag the general economy, Pierer said.</p>
<p>Earnings in 1996-97 will be flat as a result of profit declines expected in its components, transportation, medical equipment and auto parts businesses, Pierer said. Improved results in energy, communications and information would balance out these setbacks.</p>
<p>The components business, which was Siemens' most profitable area for the year that ended September 30, should turn in lower profits as a result of sharp drops in semiconductor prices.</p>
<p>The Transportation Systems Group (VT) would also face price pressures, restructuring expenses and high costs for large railway projects in Asia.</p>
<p>Reorganisation and new product costs will probably push the medical engineering systems group into a 1996-97 loss, while the industrial and building systems group also restructures, Pierer said.</p>
<p>To stay on track for its growth targets, Siemens is starting a new unit, Siemens Financial Services, to consolidate financing for all of its operations, he said.</p>
<p>The company also aims to focus its business away from Germany to Asia and the Americas, where sales growth is higher and labour costs lower.</p>
<p>&quot;Business in Germany will continue to grow, but its share of our total will decline from the current 40 percent to less than 30 percent by the year 2000,&quot; Pierer said.</p>
<p>Pierer expected Siemens to employ more than half of its workforce outside Germany in two years. Personnel costs in Germany, which rose seven percent last year to add 1.4 billion marks in costs, was one of the factors limiting 1996-97 profits.</p>
<p>To raise productivity, Siemens has adopted a new performance-based salary system for managers, and is restructuring purchasing methods to reduce costs by one billion marks, he said.</p>
<p>Earnings per share for 1995-96, which ended September 30, were 4.48 marks on Germany's DVFA basis, up from 3.97 marks in 1994-95, Pierer said. Siemens proposed a dividend of 1.50 marks for 1995-96, up from 1.30 marks the year before. -- Bonn Newsroom (49-228) 260 97 150 ($1=1.5453 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
