<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253371" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>PORTUGAL: FOCUS-Race for Portugal cigarette maker wide open.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-Race for Portugal cigarette maker wide open.</headline>
<byline>David Brough</byline>
<dateline>LISBON 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A race between U.S., Spanish and French-led groups to buy Portugal's dominant state-owned cigarette manufacturer Tabaqueira is too close to call before an expected cabinet decision on Monday.</p>
<p>Analysts said the two best-placed bids were probably those of Spanish tobacco company Tabacalera, which is 52 percent state-owned and allied to Madeira company Empresa Madeirense de Tabacos, and U.S. group Philip Morris, in partnership with Portuguese group  Jorge de Mello.</p>
<p>The third offer by French group Seita could not be ruled out, although it bid the least at 4,800 escudos per share, valuing the company at 31.2 billion escudos ($200 million).</p>
<p>The Competition Council, which this month cleared all three bids, saying they abided by competition rules, raised a question mark over the distribution element of the Philip Morris bid, an official source said.</p>
<p>If Philip Morris won, it would control more than 90 percent of the Portuguese market. Tabaqueira already controls about 70 percent of the national market.</p>
<p>The cabinet's final choice of the winner on Monday could well be a political decision, analysts said.</p>
<p>Mark Howard of Lloyds Bank Fund Managers said he believed that the political argument favoured Tabacalera.</p>
<p>&quot;In my view there has to be much closer cooperation between the Spanish and Portuguese economies and that has to extend to the grassroots in terms of business cooperation,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Analysts said Tabacalera was anxious to win because it feared that if Philip Morris were chosen, its present deal to manufacture Philip Morris brands in Spain could be under threat as the U.S. firm moved its southern European centre to Portugal.</p>
<p>Tabacalera produces Philip Morris brands Marlboro and L&amp;M in Spain under licence.</p>
<p>Tabacalera offered the highest price -- 5,610 escudos per share, valuing Tabaqueira at 36.47 billion escudos.</p>
<p>But a special jury presiding over the privatisation had ranked the group led by Philip Morris first among the bidders. Beside the price, the jury took into account the industrial plans that each candidate presented for Tabaqueira.</p>
<p>Philip Morris offered 5,100 escudos per share for the 65 percent stake of Tabaqueira that the government is offering, which would bring in 33.2 billion escudos.</p>
<p>Juan Simon of Portuguese investment bank Banco Efisa said the strength of the Philip Morris bid lay in its proposals to boost production and create jobs.</p>
<p>The bid by Philip Morris foresees the creation of 100 jobs, a new shift at Tabaqueira's factory at Albarraque near Lisbon and a hike in annual production to 21 billion cigarettes by 2001 from 10 billion now, a source linked to the bid said.</p>
<p>The production increase would bring in additional revenues to the government from cigarette taxes.</p>
<p>Analysts said Philip Morris's partnership with the Jorge de Mello group was significant as the Portuguese group already held 51 percent of loss-making food company Nutrinveste, a major employer. Tabaqueira owns the other 49 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;If the Jorge de Mello group took over Nutrinveste completely, it could solve one headache for the government,&quot; said one Lisbon-based analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Philip Morris was anxious to win the deal in Portugal to spread risks from its home market where it was under siege from a strong anti-tobacco lobby, analysts said.</p>
<p>The Tabaqueira selloff is part of a Portuguese government privatisation programme that is expected to bring in at least $450 million this year and a similar sum in 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PORL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42900">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LISBON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PORTUGAL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
