<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253543" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine sets new rules for strategic investors.</title>
<headline>Ukraine sets new rules for strategic investors.</headline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukraine's State Property Fund has established new rules for strategic investors in the privatisation of 208 enterprises, its chief said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Parliament last month abruptly halted the privatisation of the 208 medium-sized and large enterprises, designated by the government to be made available for strategic investment, until rules were drawn up to halt corruption.</p>
<p>&quot;We will continue putting the enterprises out to tender, having implemented new rules for the process,&quot; Yuri Yekhanurov, the head of the state privatisation agency (FDM), told an investment conference.</p>
<p>&quot;The Fund is continuing with its strategy to attract strategic investors in these enterprises,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yekhanurov did not say what rule changes had been made.</p>
<p>Parliament has said it will allow the privatisation process to continue once it is satisfied with the rules.</p>
<p>The government has stated that its goal in 1997 is to increase foreign investment through privatisation. Foreign investment has reached about $1.2 billion in the five years since Ukraine won independence former the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>--Natalya Zinets, Kiev Newsroom +380 44 229 2264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
