<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253677" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Wool prices improve slightly at NZ sales.</title>
<headline>Wool prices improve slightly at NZ sales.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wool prices improved only slightly at Napier and Christchurch sales on Thursday despite a 2.5 percent fall in the exchange rate against the U.S. dollar, Wools of New Zealand said .</p>
<p>Provisional market indicator movements showed the fine segment up eight cents to $7.76; medium up 23 to $5.23; strong up one to $4.11 and lamb down six to $3.85. The market indicator was up two cents to $4.50.</p>
<p>On offer was 4,081 clean tonnes in 34,584 bales, the main components being 37 percent crossbred fleece, 20 percent second shear, 11 percent halfbred fleece and 10 percent merino fleece.  </p>
<p>Compared with a week ago, merino fleece was mixed with 18 micron and finer 2.5-5 percent cheaper and 19 to 23 microns 2-4 percent dearer; merino bulky skirtings were two percent dearer; halfbred fleece and halfbred bulky skirtings 2-3 percent dearer; crossbred fleece unchanged to one percent dearer; cotts two percent dearer; second shear the same to slightly dearer; first lambs unchanged; second lambs 2.5 percent cheaper; bulky skirtings up to three percent dearer; and second shear bellies and pieces up to fully 2.5 percent dearer. Main interest came from western Europe, China, Nepal, Turkey and local mills with support from Iran and India, Wools of New Zealand said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
