<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253655" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AUSTRALIA TRANSPORT-Foreign, local bids seen for rail group.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AUSTRALIA TRANSPORT-Foreign, local bids seen for rail group.</headline>
<byline>Marie McInerney</byline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A number of international and local groups are believed to have lodged interest in the sale of the Australian National (AN) rail operations, although the fate of key passenger services including the transcontinental Indian Pacific remains unclear.</p>
<p>The Federal Government announced last month it would sell the troubled AN which operates South Australian and Tasmanian freight operations, workshops servicing the interstate freight system, and the Indian Pacific, Ghan and Overlander services.</p>
<p>The Indian Pacific is a Sydney to Perth passenger service, while the Ghan is an Adelaide to Alice Springs service. The Overlander goes from Melbourne to Adelaide.</p>
<p>The government will inject A$2 billion into AN, freeing it from its A$780 million debt, with bids to be invited early in 1997.</p>
<p>Transport Minister John Sharp has said the government does not expect to recoup the money, and estimates for the sale price for the AN businesses have varied from A$100 million to A$500 million.</p>
<p>Sharp said anyone taking over AN, which is expected this week to report a A$250 million loss in 1995/96, would have to commit considerable capital investment to get it up to speed.</p>
<p>Infrastructure investor Macquarie Bank has expressed interest in all of AN, and is expected to bid through a number of consortia, involving units of Howard Smith Ltd and Australian National Industries Ltd, and possible overseas interests.</p>
<p>New Zealand's Tranz Rail has said it would be keen to buy into AN's assets, possibly in conjunction with its U.S. shareholder Wisconsin Central Transportation Corp, while Britain's Scottish Rail and Amtrak in the U.S. Have been named as potential bidders.</p>
<p>Australian transport group TNT Ltd, which this week signed a rail freight services joint venture with Toll Holdings Ltd, is also seen to be considering a bid, sources said.</p>
<p>The AN portfolio includes SA Freight, comprising 1650 kilometres of track of three gauges, which carries six million tonnes of freight annually, primarily coal for the Electricity Trust of SA and grain, and Tasrail which carries bulk cement, coal and containers on 730 kilometres of narrow gauge track.</p>
<p>AN owns and maintains 6,118 kilometres of track, and operates railway workshops and other services which are under contract mainly to the National Rail Corporation (NRC).</p>
<p>It transferred its interstate freight services, which represented about 70 percent of its business, to the NRC in 1992, plus locomotives and rolling stocks,</p>
<p>Sharp has said the move to sell AN and the government's NRC stake complemented South Australian and Northern Territory moves to create a joint corporation to manage the long awaited A$1 billion construction of an Alice Springs to Darwin rail link.</p>
<p>He said the Commonwealth could offer incentives, such as infrastructure bonds for a private sector builder/operator.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Sharp said on Thursday the TNT/Toll venture signalled the importance of private industry to the renaissance of Australian rail, with international experience showing the private sector to be up to four times more efficient.</p>
<p>The spokesman said it was difficult to compare domestic freight charges yet, as private operations were very new but there was the potential for savings with economies of scale.</p>
<p>Sharp has acknowledged the government could have difficulty selling off the loss-making passenger services and said it would resume control if it could not find a buyer.</p>
<p>The Indian Pacific, the Overland from Adelaide to Melbourne, and the Adelaide to Alice Springs Ghan carried 244,000 passengers in 1995/96.</p>
<p>The government's Office of Asset Sales is currently undertaking a scoping study to design the shape of the final sale process of AN, with expressions of interest to be lodged in early 1997 and sales to be completed by June 30, 1997.</p>
<p>The government will retain ownership of the national rail track and, as part of its A$2 billion commitment, has said it will spend A$161.4 million on track upgrading and honour a A$360 million order for 120 new mainline locomotives.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I71000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
