<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253649" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: NZ bonds end weaker but 90-days rally slightly.</title>
<headline>NZ bonds end weaker but 90-days rally slightly.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>----------------------Snapshot at close-------------------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>FUTURES					  PHYSICAL YIELD</p>
<p>90-DAY BILLS (MAR) 92.82  (-0.06)	90-DAYS 7.93   (-0.02)</p>
<p>3-YR BONDS   (MAR) 93.10  (-0.13)	02/00   6.95   (+0.11)</p>
<p>10-YR BONDS  (MAR) 92.63  (-0.19)	11/06   7.33   (+0.13)</p>
<p>OVERNIGHT CASH 8.20 PCT (PREV 8.50)    US 5-YR  6.10 (PREV 5.99)</p>
<p>NZD/USD 0.6972/79 (PREV 0.6958/65)     US 10-YR 6.35 (PREV 6.22)</p>
<p>TWI 66.42 (PREV 66.40)		     US 30-YR 6.59 (PREV 6.49)</p>
<p>--------------------------(Dec 12)------------------------------</p>
<p>* NZ bonds sell off in line with global markets  </p>
<p>* Poor govt bond tender of Feb 2001 bonds</p>
<p>* Market awaits RBNZ's monetary policy statement</p>
<p>New Zealand bonds sold off in line with offshore developments at Thursday's close after a choppy day, while the money market continued to thrive in its new 0-3 percent inflation target environment.</p>
<p>Bond dealers said yields improved slightly very late in the session on the back of a slightly stronger Australian market but ended pretty much on their closing levels, with the 11/06 maturity off 13 basis points and mid bonds off 11.  </p>
<p>Global market weakness was blamed for the rise in yields, but dealers said extra supply from a NZ$100 million government tender of February 2001 bonds had not helped.</p>
<p>One said the tender, in which the bonds yielded 7.108 percent, had gone very poorly, as expected.</p>
<p>&quot;Its only saving grace was that it was a five-year bond, not a 10-year bond, or it probably wouldn't have gone off altogether,&quot; she said.  </p>
<p>&quot;The 01 bond was lying pretty expensive on the curve, so it was reasonably expensive to get to. The 01s have closed under where they were issued in the tender, so at least that's something.&quot;</p>
<p>Money market dealers said flows had been steady and sentiment remained robust after Wednesday's sharp rally on the back of a new centre-right coalition government, which widened the target band for underlying inflation to 0-3 percent from 0-2 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;The facts that the bonds sold off...is nothing to skitter the bank bills really,&quot; one said, adding that dealers would be waiting for the Reserve Bank's monetary policy statement on December 17 to see if the market could push rates lower.</p>
<p>Cash at 8.20 percent was still higher than it probably should be but was drifting lower, he said.</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>Figures in brackets compare against previous day's close</p>
<p>NZD VS	  3 YR	   10 YR	* NZD 3-YR/10-YR SPREAD</p>
<p>USD	   102   (-1)     99  (-3)   * FUTURES     -32   (-1)</p>
<p>CAD	   212   (-4)     84  (-1)   * PHYSICALS    40   (+2)</p>
<p>AUD	    52   (-3)     -2  (-8)</p>
<p>----------------------------------------------------------------</p>
<p>-- Catherine McCaw (64 4) 471 4275</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
