<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253660" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: FEATURE - Aborigines bury town founded on asbestos.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Aborigines bury town founded on asbestos.</headline>
<byline>Michael Perry</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian town of Baryulgil is being buried and its inhabitants, the Banjalang Aborigines, could not be happier.</p>
<p>The Banjalang have been fighting for 14 years to have their asbestos-poisoned land made safe.</p>
<p>Four of the town's 23 houses have been bulldozed, burned and buried in massive pits and all Baryulgil's topsoil removed and roads sealed with concrete to decontaminate the small aboriginal township of the deadly substance.</p>
<p>Replacement homes, built and wrapped in a bubble of plastic while workers demolished the old houses, have been connected to electricity, water and sewerage -- a first for the town.</p>
<p>In time the 60-odd Banjalang left in the town hope all 23 houses will be demolished.</p>
<p>&quot;I never thought we'd live to see it,&quot; says Neil Walker, 62, a Banjalang who worked the town's now-closed asbestos mine and who has since contracted asbestosis.</p>
<p>Prolonged inhalation of asbestos fibres can cause asbestosis, the gradual degeneration of the lung, and mesothelioma, a fatal cancer of the lungs, heart and abdomen.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel very good,&quot; says Walker on the telephone, wheezing to get his breath.</p>
<p>&quot;After all these years talking they are finally doing something,&quot; he adds, watching his home of 41 years being destroyed by a worker covered from head to toe in protective overalls and mask and constantly watering down the dust.</p>
<p>From almost 40 years until 1979 Baryulgil, 500 km (310 miles) north of Sydney in the state of New South Wales, was the site of a chrysotile (white asbestos) mine which relied exclusively on the Banjalang for labour.</p>
<p>In a deadly twist, the town relied on the mine's blue asbestos tailings for landfill for houses and for the local school sand pit.</p>
<p>This correspondent visited Baryulgil in 1991 to find a town neglected by black and white bureacracy despite a rising incident of breathing and lung disorders.</p>
<p>Dust carrying asbestos fibres drifted through the flimsy houses as each truck passed along the town's dirt roads.</p>
<p>Few miners had been medically tested, but 14 had been diagnosed with scarring of the lungs from asbestos fibres, a forerunner to asbestosis and mesothelioma. Of those, 11 have now been given compensation for asbestos-related illnesses.</p>
<p>Change has been a long time coming -- despite successive government reports calling for the town to be cleaned up.</p>
<p>The Banjalang's problem was that they were trapped in a dangerous Catch-22 situation.</p>
<p>Officially their land was the responsibility of the Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Community (ATSIC), Australia's top indigenous affairs body.</p>
<p>But ATSIC refused to make funds available to clean up Baryulgil because Australia's national government had built alternative accommodation a few kilometres (miles) down the road -- although one report said the new buildings were unsound.</p>
<p>While roads in and out of Baryulgil were sealed, those inside the community were not and local logging trucks continued to stir up asbestos.</p>
<p>Again the Banjalang were in a Catch-22. The roads outside the community were the responsibility of the local government, those inside were under ATSIC control.</p>
<p>The local government said it would seal the roads immediately, given a government grant, but national government policy at the time denied the Banjalang funding while they lived at Baryulgil.</p>
<p>A 1990 report by Australia's race discrimination commissioner said the years of inaction at Baryulgil could be blamed on the town's indigenous status.</p>
<p>But now, under an agreement between ATSIC, the New South Wales state government and the New South Wales Aboriginal Land Council, A$2.4 million has been allocated for the first stage of Baryulgil's rehabilitation.</p>
<p>The money has sealed the town's roads and paid for the demolition and replacement of four old houses, as connecting the town with electricity, water and sewerage.</p>
<p>But if Baryulgil's bureaucratic gridlock has ended, a clean bill of health is still some way off.</p>
<p>A further 10 houses are earmarked for second stage rehabilitation, but funds are still to be approved, an ATSIC spokesman said. The first funds took five years to become available after an agreement to clean up Baryulgil.</p>
<p>Walker says there have been no more recorded cases of asbestosis or mesothelioma, but Baryulgil's children still suffer an unusually high level of asthma and bronchitis.</p>
<p>&quot;I think our luck has changed and we will be all right, if we get more funding,&quot; says Walker, trying to catch his breath.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
