<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253702" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia's Howard says f'casts on track.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia's Howard says f'casts on track.</headline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australian Prime Minister John Howard told parliament on Thursday that budget forecasts &quot;in their various areas&quot; were on track.  </p>
<p>Asked whether the government's budget predictions were still on track after Thursday's job's data, Howard said the data showed solid employment growth but such figures were &quot;notoriously unpredictable&quot;.</p>
<p>He added: &quot;The second point I'd like to make is that reducing unemployment is something that will only be achieved over time.</p>
<p>&quot;The best advice available to me is that the budget predictions in their various areas are on track and I can only, in relation to that, repeat the advice that I have received.&quot;  </p>
<p>The Australian Bureau of Statistics said earlier that its seasonally adjusted estimate of the number of employed persons rose 24,400 in November to 8.40 million, against 8.37 million in October and 8.33 million a year earlier.</p>
<p>The seasonally adjusted unemployment rate fell to 8.5 percent in November from 8.8 percent in October, compared with 8.5 percent in November 1995.</p>
<p>Economists had expected employment to rise around 10,000 in November, seasonally adjusted, with the unemployment rate easing to 8.7 percent.  </p>
<p>The government has forecast average employment growth of 1.5 percent for the 1996/97 year and a 2.0 percent rise in employment between the June quarter 1996 and the June quarter 1997.</p>
<p>It has forecast an average unemployment rate of 8.5 percent for the 1996/97 year and an average of 8.25 percent unemployment for the June quarter in 1997.</p>
<p>-- Canberra Bureau 61-6 273 2730</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
