<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253743" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: PRESS DIGEST - HK newspaper headlines - Dec 12.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - HK newspaper headlines - Dec 12.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Hong Kong press on Thursday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- MING PAO DAILY -- Tung Chee-hwa won a landslide victory to become the first Chief Executive of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region. He promised to safeguard freedom and rule of law after the handover, and urged political groups not to politicise matters.</p>
<p>-- EXPRESS DAILY -- Many members of the Selection Committee changed their minds and followed the majority to vote for Tung, including actress Lisa Wang who had expressed clearly her support for Peter Woo before the selection.</p>
<p>-- SOUTH CHINA MORNING POST -- Legislator Emily Lau was unrepentant last night after being arrested outside the venue where the selection of the Chief Executive was held, and criticised police for abusing their power and supressing freedom of expression.</p>
<p>-- Sino Land confirmed its reputation as the most aggressive bidder in town at Wednesday's government land auction, beating seven competing developers to clinch a commercial site in North Point for $760 million.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG DAILY NEWS -- Research showed that Hong Kong men had become more domesticated and were spending more time shopping and at home with children, while women were more independent and willing to spend money.</p>
<p>-- HONG KONG STANDARD -- Fund managers were pushing for more &quot;transparency&quot; on insurance products to be made available under the Mandatory Provident Fund.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
