<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253768" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Hanoi fetes foreign investors after year of doubt.</title>
<headline>Hanoi fetes foreign investors after year of doubt.</headline>
<byline>John Chalmers</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam said on Thursday that a stack of foreign joint-venture projects would be approved in the coming days, ending a year marred by doubts about investors' appetite for the communist country on an upbeat note.</p>
<p>Several top politicians, dressed in smart Western suits, applauded enthusiastically, a brass band struck up and a giant red ribbon was snipped as a major foreign investment fair opened in Hanoi.</p>
<p>&quot;Foreign investors have made big efforts in investing in Vietnam,&quot; senior Politburo member Lieutenant-General Le Kha Phieu told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to say that there is no need for foreign investors to be worried when they come and invest in Vietnam.&quot;</p>
<p>Vu Huy Hoang, General Director of the Ministry of Planning and Investment's Foreign Investment Department, said licences for 322 foreign-invested projects worth $5.2 billion in total had been granted so far this year.</p>
<p>However, he said a traditional end-of-year flurry of project approvals -- including a licence for South Korea's Hyundai Motor Co to open a car and truck plant -- would take the 1996 total to more than $7.0 billion.</p>
<p>That would roughly match the record set in 1995 and could go some way to scotching talk, largely based on a sharp slowdown earlier this year, that after several years of excitement, investor fatigue has now set in.</p>
<p>Hoang said some $24.5 billion worth of projects had now been approved since the party embarked on reforms of the Soviet-style economy and opened doors to the outside world.</p>
<p>However, less than a third of that sum has been implemented.</p>
<p>Foreign investors often complain of endless red tape, rampant corruption and an opaque legal system. Many were startled earlier this year when police swept through city streets pulling down billboards and brand name signs in foreign languages.</p>
<p>That came in the run-up to a key Communist Party congress at which the leadership called for party cells to be established in all walks of life, including foreign-invested ventures.</p>
<p>Phieu, who is ranked fifth in the Politburo and is tipped by some observers as a possible successor to General Le Duc Anh as president, said investors had nothing to fear from party cells.</p>
<p>However, foreign diplomats and business executives in Vietnam say the shrill rhetoric that characterised the congress has already translated into a more difficult business climate.</p>
<p>&quot;What the party congress has done is give the forces of control a renewed mandate, and foreign businesses and others are suffering increased harassment by agencies of the Ministry of the Interior, including the economic police and the Taxation Department,&quot; Australia's Ambassador to Hanoi, Susan Boyd, said in a recent speech in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>She said those trying to negotiate new joint venture deals were finding that local partners were demanding a degree of control incommensurate with their contribution to the venture.</p>
<p>The government, anxious to keep investment flowing in, has approved amendments to the foreign investment law that are partly designed to make inroads into bureaucracy and create a level playing field for foreign-invested and domestic firms.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
