<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253853" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Shenzhen B shares end sharply lower on crackdown.</title>
<headline>Shenzhen B shares end sharply lower on crackdown.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shenzhen's B share index fell sharply on Thursday as a result of a new crackdown by securities authorities on mainland Chinese buying B shares, brokers said.</p>
<p>The B index fell 11.23 points, or 6.02 percent, to 175.22 after hitting an intra-session low of 171.07, on turnover of HK$395.77 million, compared with Wednesday's HK$509.83 million.</p>
<p>Of 43 Shenzhen-listed B shares, 41 fell and two rose.</p>
<p>Brokers said that, on orders from the securities authorities, securities firms in Shenzhen have stopped accepting B share trading account applications from domestic investors unless they use funds from outside mainland China.  </p>
<p>&quot;Today's retreat could also be seen as the continuation of a technical correction in light of the surge of the index over the past few weeks,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>&quot;A modest rebound is likely after the steep falls since Tuesday,&quot; another broker said.  </p>
<p>An official of the Shenzhen Foreign Exchange Management Bureau under the People's Bank of China said that money used to purchase B shares must come from outside mainland China.</p>
<p>&quot;It is illegal for Chinese to buy B shares with foreign currency from within the mainland,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Brokerages know the rules well but some violate them, he added.</p>
<p>&quot;Institutions took the crackdown as an excuse to cash in on the market's recent strong gains,&quot; said a broker at Shenzhen J &amp; A Securities.  </p>
<p>Weifu, the biggest loser, fell HK$0.90, or 15 percent, to HK$5.10 on volume of 994,300 shares. Southern Glass fell HK$0.82 or 12.11 percent to HK$5.95 on trade of 2.91 million shares.</p>
<p>Changan Automobile traded the most on volume of 7.02 million shares and fell HK$0.60 to HK$5.20 on institutional selling, brokers said.</p>
<p>Building materials producer Fangda bucked the trend, rising HK$0.13 to HK$8.78, with trading of 2.56 million shares.</p>
<p>Refrigerator maker Meilin inched up HK$0.02 to HK$6.70 on the day's second most active trade of 4.64 million shares.  </p>
<p>The A market also fell on profit-taking, brokers said.</p>
<p>The A index lost 11.04 points, or 2.22 percent, to 487.41 on turnover of 14.24 billion yuan compared with 14.86 billion in the previous session.</p>
<p>The composite index slumped 11.36 points, or 2.40 percent, to 461.66.</p>
<p>Pharmaceutical issue Yunnan Baiyao plunged 0.86 yuan, or 7.32 percent, to 10.89 yuan.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
