<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="253817" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Crudes firm in quiet late Asia, Minas strong.</title>
<headline>Crudes firm in quiet late Asia, Minas strong.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Crude oil prices staged a minor recovery during Asian business hours on Thursday after plunging overnight, while Minas and Widuri attracted strong premiums in the wet market, traders said.</p>
<p>Some traders said, however, that the market could slump again under pressure from a combination of factors, including the resumption of Iraqi crude oil exports. They said the market was very quiet with very little activity heard taking place.</p>
<p>January IPE Brent futures plunged by $1.13 on Wednesday to close at $22.16.</p>
<p>January cash Brent was notionally assessed at $22.15/22.25.  </p>
<p>Brent/Dubai spreads were mostly steady, with February Brent/Dubai notionally assessed at $1.80/1.85, virtually unchanged from late U.S. trading levels. March Brent/Dubai was notionally assessed at similar levels.</p>
<p>In the wet market for regional crudes, tight availability due to brisk demand among Japanese utility companies lifted premIums for Minas and Widuri for January. Demand was also seen from China. The rise in premiums for January Minas was evident in deals done recently. The most recent deal -- 300,000-barrels sold by a Japanese trading company to China -- was done at a premium of 65 cents.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
