<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254034" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian coalition uses muscle to clear Di Rupo.</title>
<headline>Belgian coalition uses muscle to clear Di Rupo.</headline>
<byline>Jeremy Lovell</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium's governing coalition used its muscle in a parliamentary commission on Thursday to win a vote clearing Deputy Prime Minister Elio Di Rupo of allegations he had sex with under-age boys.</p>
<p>&quot;The commission...considers that in the present state of the reports sent to parliament there are no indications of guilt and therefore no elements that would justify his indictment,&quot; commission chairman Raymond Langendries told reporters.</p>
<p>The full parliament is expected to rubber-stamp the decision later on Thursday.</p>
<p>But the commission's 7-4 vote after three days and nights of often bitter debate that at times revealed strains within the centre-left coalition promptly triggered opposition charges of a cover-up.</p>
<p>&quot;This is an exclusively political decision,&quot; said Didier Reynders, a member of the opposition Francophone Liberals. &quot;This is not what the population expected.&quot;</p>
<p>The Di Rupo case has further undermined public confidence in Belgium's establishment. The country has been shaken since last August's arrest of child rapist Marc Dutroux, the subsequent rescue of two young girls and the discovery of the bodies of four more.</p>
<p>More than 250,000 people took to the streets of Brussels in October in support of the victims' families in a demonstration that united the country's divided linguistic communities and became a show of disgust at a system seen as corrupt.</p>
<p>There have also been floods of denunciations, with child rights groups reporting hundreds of letters a day and a special police hot line receiving thousands of calls.</p>
<p>As a counterbalance to the vote, the commission approved a draft law short-circuiting cumbersome parliamentary procedures and allowing the Cour de Cassation, Belgium's highest court, to investigate allegations against government ministers without having to consult parliament first.</p>
<p>Under the new law, due to be voted on by parliament on December 19, the court can investigate at will but still needs parliamentary approval to indict or arrest a minister.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a well balanced decision which restores the honour of someone who has been haunted by unacceptable allegations,&quot; said Serge Moureaux, a member of the Francophone Socialists who together with their Flemish counterparts and the Dutch- and French-speaking Christian Democrats form the government.</p>
<p>However, the new law also means that the court, the only body allowed to judge ministers, can investigate any further allegations that emerge about Di Rupo.</p>
<p>The number two in the government had already been cleared of allegations in one case file that he had sex with boys under the legal age of consent of 16 years, and denied the mostly anonymous charges in two other files that were handed to the commission on Monday.</p>
<p>In the climate of suspicion in Belgium between the judiciary and politicians -- and with the deep public distrust of the system -- the new law is equivalent to parliamentarians declaring open season on themselves but it does avoid the media circus that surrounded the allegations against Di Rupo.</p>
<p>In response to the crisis of confidence the government has rushed through a series of legal reforms, and political leaders have begun a process that should lead to democratic changes.</p>
<p>But Belgian politics received another blow on Monday when Jean-Pierre Grafe, a minister in a French-speaking regional government who has also been accused of paedophilia, unexpectedly announced his resignation.</p>
<p>He said he was innocent but could not continue to function in the current over-heated climate.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
