<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254177" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>EU: EP AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - DEC 17-18.</title>
<headline>EP AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE AGENDA - DEC 17-18.</headline>
<text>
<p>Committee on Agriculture and Rural Development</p>
<p>[[ Tuesday 17 December 1996 ]]</p>
<p>PUBLIC MEETING</p>
<p>1. Adoption of draft agenda (PE220.698 ) ===] In the presence of the Commission 2. Geographical indications &amp; designations of origin for agricultural products &amp; foodstuffs - Amend. Reg.EEC 2081/92 (T04927) CNS96159 COM(96)0266 C4-0439/96 + AGRI Fond R FANTUZZI Giulio. (PSE) (PE219.628 ) - Adoption of draft report 3. The legal protection of biotechnological inventions (T04629) COD95350 COM(95)0661 C4-0063/96 + AGRI Avis A GRAEFE ZU B. (V )</p>
<p>(PE217.836 ) F JURI Fond R ROTHLEY Willi. (PSE) (PE218.021 ) - Adoption of draft opinion 4. General Community strategy for the forestry sector (T03499) INI0287 INI0287 B4-0186/94 B4-0186/94 B4-0462/94 B4-0462/94 B4-0051/94 B4-0051/94 + AGRI Fond R THOMAS David E. (PSE) (PE213.578/REV) - Adoption of motion for a resolution Possibly, adoption of motion for a resolut ion 5. Joint discussion 5.1 System for the identification and registration of bovine animals (proposal for a Council regulation) (T05011) CNS96228 COM(96)0460 C4-0545/96 + AGRI Fond R MAYER Xaver. (PPE) (PE219.621 ) - Consideration of draft report 5.2 Labelling of beef and beef products (proposal for a Council regulation) (T05010) CNS96229 COM(96)0460 C4-0546/96 COS0437 C4-417/96 C4-0417/96 + AGRI Avis A MAYER Xaver. (PPE) (PE219.622 ) F ENVI Fond R PAPAYANNAKIS Mihail. (GUE) - Consideration of draft opinion 6. Veterinary checks (amendment of Directives 71/118, 72/462, 85/73, 91/67, 91/ 492, 91/493, 92/45 and 92/118) (T04873) CNS96109 COM(96)0170 C4-0334/96 CNS96110 COM(96)0170 C4-0335/96 + AGRI Avis A KINDERMANN Heinz. (PSE) + AGRI Avis KINDERMANN Heinz. (PSE) F ENVI Fond R OLSSON Karl-Erik. (ELD) (PE219.875 ) - Exchange of views Further exchange of views 7. Young farmers and the problem of succession in European agriculture (Commission report) (T04990) COS0458 COM(96)0398 C4-0500/96 + AGRI Fond R CAMPOS Antonio. (PSE) - Exchange of views 8. Quality policy for agricultural products and agri-foodstuffs (T04588) INI0444 INI0444 B4-0028/96 B4-0028/96 + AGRI Fond R MULDER Jan. (ELD) - Exchange of views 9. Decision on procedure 10. Appointment of rapporteurs and draftsmen - decisions on procedure - approval of coordinators' decisions 11. Any other business 12. Date of next meeting (in BRUSSELS) (PE/II/OJ/97-01 ) - FIN - END OF DOCUMENT.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
