<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254103" id="root" date="1996-12-12" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Belgian MPs to take no further action on Di Rupo.</title>
<headline>Belgian MPs to take no further action on Di Rupo.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Belgian parliamentary commission voted on Thursday by seven to four to take no further action on allegations that Deputy Prime Minister Elio Di Rupo had sex with under-age boys, a commission member said.</p>
<p>The vote, pitting representatives of the country's governing centre-left coalition against the opposition, came after three days and nights of often bitter arguments among the 11-member commission. The vote must be endorsed by the full parliament.  </p>
<p>&quot;There is no reason to indict Di Rupo...There is no indication of guilt,&quot; Francophone Socialist Jean-Paul Henri told reporters.</p>
<p>But the commission approved a draft law short-circuiting cumbersome parliamentary procedures and allowing the Cour de Cassation, Belgium's highest court, to investigate allegations against government ministers without having to consult parliament first.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very positive that we now have a law that allows the Cour de Cassation to investigate allegations against ministers without the intervention of parliament,&quot; said Flemish Christian Democrat Tony Van Parys.</p>
<p>However, some representatives of the opposition immediately accused the ruling coalition of mounting a cover-up in the affair that has scandalised the nation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-12"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
