<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254269" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-FRENCH FIRST DIVISION PROGRAMME.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FRENCH FIRST DIVISION PROGRAMME.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>French first division matches this weekend (standings in brackets):</p>
<p>Saturday (all 2000 GMT):</p>
<p>Nantes (8) v Paris Saint-Germain (2) Japhet N'Doram, the player at the heart of Nantes' record 14-match unbeaten run in the league, is nursing an ankle injury and could be absent. PSG, whose Brazilian Leonardo and France defender Alain Roche are also unavailable through injury, are desperate to win after successive defeats in the first division and League Cup.</p>
<p>Monaco (1) v Cannes (15)</p>
<p>Leaders Monaco must improve their home domestic form after a 0-0 draw with Guingamp and a laboured League Cup win over second division Troyes if they want to go into the winter break next weekend at the top of the table. Scot John Collins is doubtful with a pulled muscle.</p>
<p>Nancy (18) v Lyon (10)</p>
<p>A match between two sides who have beaten Paris St-Germain in the last eight days. Striker Phil Gray, who hit Nancy's winner in their 2-1 victory in Paris last weekend, is away on World Cup duty with Northern Ireland, but they hope to give a debut to Tony Cascarino, just signed from Marseille. Lyon will be without injured striker Alain Caveglia, who helped them beat PSG at home in the League Cup on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Lille (12) v Bastia (3)</p>
<p>Lille's top scorer Miladin Becanovic is doubtful with tendinitis, while Bastia will be without Anton Drobnjak, on World Cup duty for Yugoslavia. Slovenian Ermin Sijak is expected to stand in.</p>
<p>Bordeaux (5) v Rennes (11)</p>
<p>Brazilian central defender Gralak returns for Bordeaux after suspension, while playmaker Johan Micoud, injured during their 2-1 defeat at Auxerre, is doubtful. Rennes have the worst away record with only two points out of possible 33.</p>
<p>Strasbourg (6) v Metz (7)</p>
<p>Strasbourg will be looking to bounce back after their 2-0 defeat at Le Havre ended a run of three wins in row. Metz will be without defender Jeff Strasser, on World Cup duty with Luxembourg.</p>
<p>Caen (19) v Le Havre (14)</p>
<p>Le Havre, disappointed at going out of the League Cup midweek, are looking to extend their four-match unbeaten run in the league but will be without Croatian striker Ardian Kozniku.</p>
<p>Guingamp (9) v Nice (20)</p>
<p>Liberian striker Christopher Wreh returns for Guingamp after missing Wednesday's League Cup defeat to third division Nimes through suspension. Nice have won one game and lost nine away.</p>
<p>Montpellier (17) v Lens (16)</p>
<p>Neither Montpellier nor Lens have won in their last six matches. But Lens can take heart from a midweek League Cup win away to second division Niort.</p>
<p>Sunday (2030 GMT)</p>
<p>Marseille (13) v Auxerre (4)</p>
<p>Marseille are one-up after scoring a midweek 3-2 League Cup win over the same rivals at home. Captain Jean-Philippe Durand is doubful but striker Xavier Gravelaine is expected to return from suspension. Champions Auxerre will be without injured France defender Alain Goma. Midfielder Christian Henna could return and striker Lilian Laslandes is making good recovery from an injury.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
