<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254355" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Late bond market prices.</title>
<headline>Late bond market prices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is how major world bond markets were trading in late European business on Friday.</p>
<p>GERMANY - Bunds build on earlier strong gains after stability pact agreed along German lines. Pact makes prospect of Euro appear less inflationary. The March Bund future on the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE) was trading at 100.12, up 0.27 from Thursday's settlement price.</p>
<p>BRITAIN - UK gilts surged into the close on Friday following news that EU heads of government meeting in Dublin have agreed terms of  EMU stability pact. Bunds reversed losses and rallied. Analysts said market will be eager to see details of the terms. The March long gilt future on LIFFE was trading at 108-31/32, up 12/32 from Thursday's settlement price.</p>
<p>FRANCE - 10-yr bond futures climb on GLOBEX after Dublin deal on European stability pact. Franc jumps vs mark to 3.3725, highest since year's peak of 3.3715 hit on April 25. The December notional bond future on the MATIF in Paris settled at 128.06 down 0.24 from Thursday's settlement price.</p>
<p>ITALY - Italian bond futures pushed higher in late afternoon trade with some help coming from better trends in overseas markets although German bunds were still lower on the day. LIFFE BTP Dec contract pushes through resistance at 127.60. Markets still watching news from EU summit in Dublin. The March bond future on LIFFE was trading at 128.60 up 1.27 from Thursday's settlement price.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - U.S. Treasuries jump late morning as dollar firms vs yen. Bearish sentiment prevails, but retail said buying--traders. Short-end said caught bid on shift from falling stocks. Rumored central bank buying also seen boosting intermediates Market ignores jump in Oct inventories, dip in December sentiment.The March Treasury bond future on the Chicago Board of Trade was trading at 113-04/32, up 20/32 from Thursday's settlement price. The long bond was quoted to yield 6.59 percent.</p>
<p>JAPAN - Japanese Goverment Bonds (JGB) ended Tokyo firmer on flight-to-quality buying, particularly in the shorter-end of the market, prompted by losses in Tokyo stock prices. Earlier, JGBs were depressed in line with stocks for fear of profit-taking JGB sales to offset losses on stocks.In after hours trading the March future on LIFFE was trading at 125.16, up 0.36 from Thursday's settlement price on the Tokyo Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>EUROBONDS - The primary market saw only one deal on Friday morning ahead of the weekend and with the seasonal slowdown gaining momentum. Kreditanstalt fuer Wiederaufbau's finance arm launched a C$100 million six-year deal at a 26 basis points spread over Canadian government bonds via lead manager Toronto-Dominion. The Canadian dollar sector has been quiet of late with just a handful of deals in the fourth quarter and today's offering should have a pretty clear run.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
