<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254332" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: India helps keep wheat firm, oil survives Iraq jitters.</title>
<headline>India helps keep wheat firm, oil survives Iraq jitters.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wheat futures ended the week above the psychological threshold of $4 per bushel in the Chicago futures pits, underpinned by buying from India and Iraq.</p>
<p>Confirmation that India bought wheat from Australia rather than the United States led some U.S. traders to take a &quot;bearish&quot; view of American export prospects.</p>
<p>Even so, a buying spree by importers around the globe kept even the U.S. market firm. India needs twice the one million tonnes it bought from Australia. Chicago Board of Trade (CBOT) December wheat futures ended at $4.06 per bushel, up 2 cents. Traders said a key factor was that India, home of the &quot;Green Revolution&quot; in Third World agriculture, turned from wheat seller to importer.</p>
<p>U.S. soybeans also were higher on spillover support from Thursday's news that the US Department of Agriculture cut by 30 million bushels its estimate for 1996-97 U.S. soybean carryover stocks.</p>
<p>Grains were further underpinned by news of wet weather in Argentina which may have harmed some of the crops. Forecasts for colder weather in the United States, that may fire up demand for heating fuel, helped buoy oil prices after a sell-off earlier in the week on news that the United Nations finally eased a 1991 Gulf War embargo on exports by Iraq. Other commodity markets were quiet and not much changed in a lull ahead of the Western Christmas holidays, although in thin volume they could become volatile if there is a sudden exit of &quot;hot&quot; money from other financial assets, traders said.</p>
<p>Some leading commodity prices at 2015 GMT</p>
<p>						Friday	    Thursday</p>
<p>    Gold ($/ounce)			368.70		368.45</p>
<p>    IPE Brent ($/barrel) (Jan)	 23.55		 22.33</p>
<p>(London Metal Exchange)</p>
<p>    COPPER (three months/tonne)   2,130.00	    2,148.00</p>
<p>    ALUMINIUM			   1,512.00	    1,528.00</p>
<p>Ldn futures)</p>
<p>    COFFEE ($/tonne) (Mar)	  1,278.00	    1,275.00</p>
<p>    COCOA (sterling/tonne) (Mar)    920.00		932.00</p>
<p>    WHITE SUGAR ($/tonne) (Mar)     203.60		299.60</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
