<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254469" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOTSWANA: Botswana says committed to privatisation.</title>
<headline>Botswana says committed to privatisation.</headline>
<byline>Ben Hirschler</byline>
<dateline>GABORONE 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Botswana plans to privatise key state corporations and utilities over the next few years in a bid to increase efficiency, vice-president and finance minister Festus Mogae said on Friday.</p>
<p>An interdepartmental task force has been appointed to study the issue and a privatisation policy paper was likely towards the end of 1997, he told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>Diamond-rich and virtually debt-free Botswana is under no budgetary pressure to sell state assets to raise funds, but Mogae said it was the correct approach for the benefit of the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not in a hurry since we don't need the money. The consideration is to try and introduce efficiency into the system,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>First on the block will be Air Botswana which the government hopes to privatise as soon as it returns to profitability.</p>
<p>Mogae said the flag carrier would have been in the black already, but for the fall in the pula currency which has pushed up its dollar denominated fuel and maintenance costs sharply.</p>
<p>Botswama Telecommunications Corp (BTC) is likely to be next with other utilities such as Botswana Power Corp and Water Utilities Corp following later.</p>
<p>Mogae said he believed the government should dispose of 100 percent of such state corporations, reserving a fixed amount -- perhaps 20 percent -- for domestic investors.</p>
<p>The state will also need to plough back some of the proceeds of the privatisation to ensure remote regions of this large but sparsely populated country receive reasonable service.</p>
<p>While the government and the opposition accepted the case for privatisation Mogae said no decisions had been taken on methods.</p>
<p>He noted that the state Botswana Development Corp (BDC) had already disposed of key holdings, most notably with the sale of shares in brewery holding company Sechaba.</p>
<p>Further BDC disposals are in the pipeline. The organisation said in its 1995 annual report that it planned to sell 41 of its 114 operations within five years.</p>
<p>The Botswana Confederation of Commerce, Industry and Manpower earlier this year listed key parastatals it considered ripe for privatisation with BTC, Air Botswana and the Botswana Meat Commission placed as top candidates.</p>
<p>Local businessmen and international investors have been urging the government to push ahead with privatisation, arguing the process is vital if it wants the private sector to be the driving force behind further economic development.</p>
<p>Privatisation could also give a boost to Botswana's young stock exchange, currently struggling with few investors and a dearth of listed stocks.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BOTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GABORONE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOTSWANA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
