<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25444" id="root" date="1996-08-30" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: S.Korea's Chun to appeal death sentence - Yonhap.</title>
<headline>S.Korea's Chun to appeal death sentence - Yonhap.</headline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-08-30</dateline>
<text>
<p>Former South Korean president Chun Doo Hwan plans to appeal the death sentence given him this week by a Seoul court for mutiny, treason and corruption, the Yonhap news agency said on Friday.</p>
<p>Yonhap quoted one of Chun's lawyers, Lee Yang-woo, as saying Chun had decided to contest the Monday's ruling on the advice of his legal counsel.</p>
<p>&quot;We will submit the appeal to the court tomorrow morning at the earliest,&quot; Lee was quoted as saying.</p>
<p>Lee and other lawyers for Chun were not immediately available for comment.</p>
<p>Yonhap gave no details about the grounds on which Chun would appeal.</p>
<p>Chun has seven days to appeal his conviction. He was sentenced with his successor, Roh Tae-woo, who was given a 22-1/2 year jail sentence for his secondary role behind Chun in a 1979 coup and the 1980 massacre of pro-democracy rebels in the southern city of Kwangju.</p>
<p>Both men were also convicted of massive corruption during their terms from 1980-93.</p>
<p>Chun has been keeping Koreans guessing over whether he intends to dispute the ruling of a court he said was part of a judicial circus orchestrated by current President Kim Young-sam to boost his popularity ratings.</p>
<p>Many Koreans believe Kim will pardon Chun before he leaves office in early 1998. But by not appealing, Chun would force the president to make a quicker decision.</p>
<p>An appeals process could drag through the courts for many months.</p>
<p>Chun has remained defiant throughout the trial, defending his grab for power as a move to restore stability following the assassination of President Park Chung-hee.</p>
<p>Chun denied being in the chain of command during the Kwangju massacre in which about 200 people were killed, by official count, when paratroopers stormed the city to put down a citizen's revolt against martial law.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-30"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-30"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
