<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254588" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>KAZAKHSTAN: Deutsche Telekom given deadline for Kazakh deal.</title>
<headline>Deutsche Telekom given deadline for Kazakh deal.</headline>
<byline>Larisa Kokovinets</byline>
<dateline>ALMATY 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Deutsche Telekom AG has until the end of December to take up a 49 percent share in Kazakhstan's state telecoms monopoly or face losing the 825 million mark ($535.1 million) deal, a senior Kazakh official said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;If the contract is not signed by 31 December 1996, then the deal is anulled,&quot; Sarybai Kalmurzayev, the powerful head of Kazakhstan's State Property Committee, told Reuters in an interview in the capital Almaty.</p>
<p>He said that if Deutsche Telekom did not complete the deal a new tender would be held to sell off NAK Kazakhtelekom.</p>
<p>A framework agreement announced in May saw the German telecoms giant agree to pay off the Kazakh firm's debts and increase the vast Central Asian republic's 2.1 million phone lines to 4.5 million within 10 years.</p>
<p>Of the total, about 460 million marks would go to pay off a 1992 loan made to Kazakhtelekom by German investment agency Kreditanstalt fur Wiederaufbau.</p>
<p>Deutsche Telekom would in its turn receive a 49 percent stake in Kazakhtelekom with the right to manage the enterprise for up to 15 years.</p>
<p>Kalmurzayev said in October that the deal had been delayed over Deutsche Telekom's desire for a monopoly over present and future telecoms services.</p>
<p>But, as with other large enterprises up for privatisation in the oil-rich former Soviet republic, Kazakhtelekom's large debts also appear to be an obstacle.</p>
<p>&quot;I think one of the reasons the deal has been delayed is because of Kazakhtelekom's rising debts,&quot; Kalmurzayev said.</p>
<p>Kazakhtelekom chief Serik Burkitbayev told the weekly Panorama newspaper last month the enterprise's debts totalled 2.6 billion tenge ($37.5 million) while creditors in turn owed the enterprise 8.7 billion tenge ($121 million).</p>
<p>The Kazakh government, short of money to pay the 16.9 million population's wages and pensions, is looking to a quick fire-sale of large state-owned enterprises to fill its coffers and get the stalled economy back on its feet. ($ = 1.541 German Marks)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KAZK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ALMATY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="KAZAKHSTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
