<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254605" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HUNGARY: Hungary plans to boost pension funds from 1998.</title>
<headline>Hungary plans to boost pension funds from 1998.</headline>
<byline>Sandor Peto</byline>
<dateline>BUDAPEST 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hungary said on Friday it is planning to become one of the first countries in central and eastern Europe to overhaul a cumbersome pension system left over from communist times.</p>
<p>The pension reform, planned to enter operational phase in 1998, is likely to boost the country's capital markets and gross domestic product (GDP), the finance ministry said.</p>
<p>Ministry Commissioner Istvan Gyorffi told a news conference that the planned system, approved by the government on Thursday, would help private pension funds to grow and increase the GDP by one to 1.5 percent annually from 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;The system, which is new in central and eastern Europe, would guarantee old-age safety, with ensuring pensions proportionate to savings and attracting revenues from the informal sector,&quot; Gyorffi said.</p>
<p>The current system, &quot;pay as you go&quot;, in which pension contributions of the employees are distributed to the beneficiaries, disregards the differences in individual savings, encouraging the evasion of contribution payment, Gyorffi said.</p>
<p>According to the government's plans, the obligatory pension system would have two tiers, with one-third of the pension contributions paid in private pension funds.</p>
<p>The &quot;pay as you go&quot; part of the system would be also changed so as to encourage contribution payment.</p>
<p>For Hungarians starting their career from 1998, usage of the second tier would be obligatory, while there would be a transition period for other employees until 2009.</p>
<p>Gyorffi said the private pension funds were likely to keep savings equivalent to three percent of GDP by the year 2000, 16-17 percent by 2010 and 40 percent by 2020.</p>
<p>These funds would create long-term savings, currently missing from the economy, which would be first invested in the domestic capital and debt markets, he said.</p>
<p>But it would be rational to allow the funds to enter the international markets after three or four years of operation, Gyorffi added.</p>
<p>The costs of the reform would burden the state budget by some 60 billion forints in 1998, but its beneficial impacts on the budget are likely to counterbalance costs for the longer term, the commissioner said.</p>
<p>The massive increase of long-term savings would help the country reduce its high interest rates, Gyorffi said.</p>
<p>The existence of private pension funds would also have a beneficial impact on capital markets, but the funds were likely to invest considerable part of their money in state securities as Hungary's capital markets are still narrow, he added.</p>
<p>The government plans to submit the draft laws of the pension reform at the end of January, following a nation-wide discussion, and the parliament is expected to approve the laws by early April, Gyorffi said.</p>
<p>The share capitalisation of the Budapest Stock Exchange was 733 billion forints at the end of October.</p>
<p>Hungary's GDP will be around 6600 billion forints in 1996. @</p>
<p>($1=163.2 forints)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWELF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUDAPEST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HUNGARY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
