<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254635" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ALBANIA: PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Dec 13.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Albania - Dec 13.</headline>
<dateline>TIRANA 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Friday's Albanian newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>KOHA JONE</p>
<p>- Students, who toppled the communist dictatorship exactly six years ago, have asked the government to improve conditions in their hostels.</p>
<p>- Students in the southern town of Gjirokaster protested peacefully over the lack of improvement of living conditions and police violence against a fellow student.</p>
<p>- Azem Hajdari, the December 1990 student revolution leader and currently head of the Independent Trade Unions, called on students to wake up otherwise they would help let a dictatorship be built, just like their fathers did.</p>
<p>- Hajdari has refused to attend a party celebrating the ruling Democratic Party's December 12 anniversary because he was suspended from its national council after coming to lead the Independent Trade Unions.</p>
<p>- Albanian President Sali Berisha's daughter has given birth to a daughter.</p>
<p>- Alleged members of a criminal gang charged with a fatal bombing and political assassination have gone on hunger strike to protest against a ban barring them from meeting their families.</p>
<p>- A Greek farmers revolt has cut off Albania from its important imports. Prices have risen, the money market has been shaken.</p>
<p>GAZETA SHQIPTARE</p>
<p>- The key opposition Socialist Party has called for a fresh general election in 1997.</p>
<p>- A seven percent tax increase on flour imports may cause a rise in bread prices.</p>
<p>- Mining trade unions are pressing the government to cancel a contract with an Italian company saying it is hindering privatisation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TIRANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ALBANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
