<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254786" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia Congress, in reversal, approves anti-drug law.</title>
<headline>Colombia Congress, in reversal, approves anti-drug law.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>In an abrupt about-face, Colombia's Congress overwhelmingly approved on Thursday the retroactive seizure of property and assets accumulated by the country's billionaire drug barons over the past 20 years.</p>
<p>The lower house of Congress, which rejected the measure just 48 hours earlier, passed it by a huge 103-4 majority.  </p>
<p>The surprise vote in the House of Representatives followed the bill's unanimous approval in the Senate earlier Thursday.</p>
<p>The Senate had already approved the bill last week, but a new vote was scheduled on Thursday by a legislative committee that overturned the lower house's rejection of the 20-year time limit on so-called asset forfeiture Tuesday night.</p>
<p>The House had rejected the time limit by 59-57, ruling instead that property linked to convicted drug lords should only be liable to forfeiture if it was accumulated in the aftermath of Colombia's 1991 constitution.</p>
<p>Government officials led by President Ernesto Samper rejected the House vote as a national disgrace, saying it was tantamount to legalizing all ill-gotten gains acquired since Colombia's booming trade in narcotics began in earnest in the late 1970s.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
