<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254730" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>VENEZUELA: PDVSA to re-offer Catatumbo block in 1st half 1997.</title>
<headline>PDVSA to re-offer Catatumbo block in 1st half 1997.</headline>
<dateline>CARACAS 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Venezuela's state oil company Petroleos de Venezuela (PDVSA) plans to re-offer a profit sharing contract for exploration and production in the Catatumbo block in the first half of next year, a top company official said Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The Catatumbo area should be offered under broadly the same arrangement in the first half of 1997,&quot; Juan Szabo, coordinator of exploration and production, told reporters at a breakfast meeting.</p>
<p>Catatumbo, located on the southwestern shore of Lake Maracaibo, was one of two areas which PDVSA failed to allocate during a bidding round for 10 new areas in January.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem with Catatumbo was the lack of geological information,&quot; Szabo said.</p>
<p>Exploration and surveys in areas adjacent to the block should provide potential bidders with enough information to make the block attractive, he added.</p>
<p>The Sombrero block in central western Venezuela which was also rejected by bidders in January's auction, meanwhile, is still restricted by low natural gas prices, Szabo said.</p>
<p>&quot;This area contains a lot of gas related to crude and prices for gas are very low,&quot; Szabo said.</p>
<p>Szabo said the Sombrero area could be re-offered if natural gas prices improved.</p>
<p>-- Paul Hughes, Caracas newsroom, 582 505 2600</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300003">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CARACAS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VENEZUELA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
