<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254743" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: COCOA--Bahia main crop may only be 800,000 bags.</title>
<headline>COCOA--Bahia main crop may only be 800,000 bags.</headline>
<byline>Brian Homewood</byline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bahia's main cocoa crop, originally forecast at a meager 1.0 million 60-kilo bags, could turn out to be even lower, farmers and traders predicted.</p>
<p>Some estimates for the crop, harvested from October to April, are now as low as 800,000 bags.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't be surprised if it turned out to be that small,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;The way it's going at the moment, it might be impossible to get one million bags out of this crop,&quot; he added, noting that arrivals at the moment are extremely light.</p>
<p>Arrivals figures have been averaging around 70,000 bags per week, compared to over 100,000 last year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a frustrating environment at the moment,&quot; the dealer said. &quot;Volumes here are low and the market in New York is dead. It goes up and down $20 here and there without any real direction. People are thinking about Christmas and they couldn't give a monkey's about cocoa.&quot;</p>
<p>Farmers said the combination of low world prices, falling productivity and the spread of witch's broom disease has been responsible for roughly halving Bahia's cocoa production in the last five years.</p>
<p>However, the current midcrop also suffered the consequences of a two-month drought during the crucial flowering period in June and July.</p>
<p>To rub salt into the wounds, the rain came too late to save the crop but just in time to quicken the spread of witch's broom. Farmers said at the start of the crop that they were finding the fungus in around 40 percent of the harvested pods, which had to be thrown away as a result.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have 800,000 bags and 850,000 at the very most,&quot; said cocoa farmer Ronaldo Monteiro. &quot;It will not be more than that.&quot;</p>
<p>Until the drought struck, predictions had been that the crop could reach a respectable 2.0 million bags.</p>
<p>Monteiro said that main areas were already into the period known locally as the &quot;bonga&quot; -- when the crop proper has gone and farmers are left to harvest the leftovers.</p>
<p>He said the only good news for farmers was that the rains which have fallen recently have helped next year's midcrop, which is developing promisingly and could start early. The midcrop is harvested from May to September.</p>
<p>The internal price for cocoa was to reported at 20 Real per 15 kilo arroba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100144">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
