<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254878" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish bourse aims to draw idle gold into economy.</title>
<headline>Turkish bourse aims to draw idle gold into economy.</headline>
<byline>Tulin Aygunes</byline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul's one-and-a-half years old gold exchange is seeking to expand its operations to draw the country's idle gold into the Turkish economy while lowering the amount of gold imports and gold savings kept by individuals.</p>
<p>&quot;Under the exchange's restructuring plans, the main target is to benefit from idle gold and use this source within the national economy,&quot; Kaan Aytogu, the general secretary of the Istanbul Gold Exchange, told Reuters in an interview.</p>
<p>He said that to realise these targets, the Exchange was working to launch a futures and options market at the start of 1997 and a gold refinery was expected to begin operations by mid-1997. The refinery was designed to have a 100-tonne annual capacity.</p>
<p>&quot;Our long-term target is to minimise international gold inflow which comprises Turkey's gold supply, lower gold saving (except the gold held by financial sector) and rapidly increase manufactured gold exports,&quot; Aytogu said.</p>
<p>&quot;To provide economic stability and growth, the resources should be channelled in an optimal way to investments. Turkey's problem is not using existing resources in the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>Nearly 6,000 tonnes of gold, worth about $70 billion, is estimated to be kept in the form of jewellery and coins in Turkey. Aytogu said another 60 tonnes was expected to be produced in the next eight years in five mines to be opened.</p>
<p>Turkey has the world's third biggest gold trading volume after Italy and India, at an estimated 250 tonnes, including scrap gold. Turnover is approximately $3.2 billion, or two percent of the gross domestic product.</p>
<p>Aytogu said the bulk of the imported gold was used by jewellers and some of the manufactured gold was exported via tourists.</p>
<p>&quot;There are around 40,000 gold manufacturers in Turkey, employing 250,000 people. Our jewellery sector earns Turkey around $2.5 billion through exports (per year),&quot; Aytogu said.</p>
<p>He noted that the sector needed to be standardised to raise consumer confidence and certificated jewellery production should be encouraged to increase exports.</p>
<p>On November 20 Turkey approved a draft law to allow jewellers to declare their unregistered physical inventories of precious metals.</p>
<p>The law, part of the government's revenue-raising package unveiled in September, hopes to raise around 70 trillion lira. About 700 tonnes of precious metals, mainly gold, are expected to be declared.</p>
<p>Aytogu said gold banking and gold-based instruments should be improved in the coming years to increase liquidity in the financial markets.</p>
<p>Traded volume on the gold exchange has totalled 243 tonnes since its inauguration on July 26, 1996.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
