<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="254966" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX natgas ends mixed, Jan sets new high on cold.</title>
<headline>NYMEX natgas ends mixed, Jan sets new high on cold.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX January Henry Hub natgas futures ended at new highs Friday in moderate trade, with forecasts for well-below normal temperatures over much of the nation driving the front of the complex up sharply.</p>
<p>January, which rallied late to a new high of $3.87 per million British thermal units, finished 32.2 cents higher at $3.851. February also hit a new benchmark of $3.47, then closed up by 20.3 cents at $3.415. Others ended mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;We're up on (cold) weather, but it may be a bit overdone,&quot; said one East Coast trader, noting January has rallied almost 20 percent in the last four sessions.  </p>
<p>Smith Barney forecaster Jon Davis expects successive waves of Arctic cold to keep U.S. temperatures east of the Rocky Mountains below-normal through the month.</p>
<p>With storage low and winter not yet begun, traders said they expected the bears to remain sidelined until milder weather returns.</p>
<p>Technical traders still pegged support in January in the $3.19 area, then $3.11 and $3.04. Resistance was now seen at the new contract high of $3.87, with major resistance at the all-time spot continuation high of $4.05.</p>
<p>In the cash, Gulf Coast prices climbed 20 cents Friday to near the $3.60 area. Midcontinent pipes were 10-15 cents higher in the mid-$3.40s. New York city gate gas was talked five to 10 cents higher at about $4.05-4.10.</p>
<p>The 12-month strip gained 5.7 cents to $3.562. NYMEX said 40,483 Hub contracts traded, up from Thursday's revised tally of 37,350.</p>
<p>NYMEX January Alberta natgas finished three cents higher at $1.68, while deferreds did not trade. NYMEX said two Alberta lots traded.</p>
<p>NYMEX Permian natgas again was untraded, with January settling unchanged at $3.25. Permian futures have not traded in 12 consecutive sessions.</p>
<p>On the KCBT, January ended 24 cents higher at $3.67, while deferreds closed up by two to 16.5 cents. The East/West spread widened by 8.2 cents to 18.1 cents (NYMEX premium).</p>
<p>--J Silha, New York Power Desk 212-859-1624</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
