<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255042" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wis. Energy CEO seeks U.S. utility consensus.</title>
<headline>Wis. Energy CEO seeks U.S. utility consensus.</headline>
<dateline>WILLIAMSBURG, Va. 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Electric power industry consensus is needed to move restructuring forward through a national strategy, according to Richard A. Abdoo, chairman of Wisconsin Energy Corp.</p>
<p>&quot;If Congress defers to the states, our industry will be subjected to regulatory roulette -- gambling with consumers' dollars,&quot; Abdoo told an Energy Daily conference Friday.</p>
<p>Earlier American Electric Power Co's chairman told the conference federal legislation should be relatively narrow, giving individual states key authority.  </p>
<p>And Tuesday, CMS Energy Corp chief executive William T. McCormick Jr told Reuters significant changes will come in the electric power industry, but they will not include federal mandating of retail wheeling.</p>
<p>There's &quot;not enough support to get (legislation) out of committee,&quot; he explained, predicting the states would overtake Congress in this area.</p>
<p>However, Abdoo said, as more and more consumers become aware of the disparity of electricity prices among states &quot;the consumer focus will intensify, and so will the pressure on Congress.&quot;  </p>
<p>The &quot;industry must acknowledge that the restructuring debate is being steered and motivated more and more by a focus on the consumer,&quot; he said, warning: &quot;There should not be a civil war among utilities to rewrite laws to suit utilities.&quot;</p>
<p>He said &quot;State borders should not bind us -- we should adopt a national perspective on this national issue.&quot;</p>
<p>Although AEP serves seven states and could potentially face seven different timetables for deregulation, Draper called for &quot;narrowly confined&quot; federal legislation that should ensure there is reciprocity among the states and address any roadblocks to a level playing field for all power suppliers.</p>
<p>&quot;However, if the states create a patchwork of policies that are incompatible with effective operation of the electric utility system, we would then advocate appropriate federal action to achieve&quot; some uniformity, Draper said.</p>
<p>As an industry, Abdoo said, &quot;we must acknowledge that those who seek to defend their own turf are hurting consumers -- and hurting today's electric power industry.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;Those dragging their feet cite many reasons, but many have one motive: they are afraid to compete.&quot;</p>
<p>He cited companies using stranded costs or environmental reasons to delay or deny restructuring.</p>
<p>((-- Jim Brumm 212-859-1710.))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WILLIAMSBURG, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
