<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255267" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Workaholic Sperling joins Clinton economic team.</title>
<headline>Workaholic Sperling joins Clinton economic team.</headline>
<byline>Steve Holland</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gene Sperling may be the hardest working man in a White House known for workaholics.</p>
<p>Picked by President Bill Clinton to head his National Economic Council, Sperling, 38, has been the NEC deputy since Clinton took office and has played a major role in coordinating U.S. economic policy.</p>
<p>A one-time collegiate tennis player, the bespectacled Sperling is known for his 20-hour work days and his single-minded focus on economic numbers-crunching to put Clinton's policies in the best possible light.</p>
<p>During his tenure he has seen the U.S. budget deficit fall from a record high $290 billion in 1992 to $107 billion, the lowest it has been since 1981.</p>
<p>During that time the U.S. economy has created more than 10 million new jobs. Inflation is tame, economic growth is moderate and welfare rolls are down.</p>
<p>The White House National Economic Council was created by Clinton when he took office to put prime importance on improving the U.S. economy. It coordinates U.S. economic policy among relevant government agencies the way the National Security Council coordinates foreign policy.</p>
<p>It was led first by now-Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin and then by the departing Laura Tyson. Sperling was deputy to both and has worked as both a policy wonk and as a political operative, looking to put the best spin on Clinton's policies.</p>
<p>For example he was instrumental in blunting the appeal of Republican Bob Dole's centrepiece campaign proposal for a 15 percent across-the-board tax cut and focusing attention on Clinton's proposals for targeted tax cuts.</p>
<p>The work has been satisfying for him but at least one romance foundered on the shoals of Sperling's own love affair with the White House. He can often be spotted there late at night raiding the snack-food machines because the regular cafeteria is closed.</p>
<p>When stories came out early in Clinton's term about how the White House seemed like one long graduate study seminar where policy was debated between bites of pizza, Sperling was a key character.</p>
<p>Reporters groan when told Sperling is scheduled to hold a briefing because of his tendency to talk on and on -- but usually imparting useful information.</p>
<p>Sperling has no heavyweight economic credentials. He dropped out of the Wharton School at the University of Pennsylvania. He had on-the-job training as the chief economic adviser for then-New York Gov. Mario Cuomo.</p>
<p>Sperling is a native of Michigan who received his undergraduate degree from the University of Minnesota, where he majored in political science and was captain of the tennis team. Like Clinton, he is also a graduate of Yale Law School.</p>
<p>He worked on the 1988 presidential campaign of Democrat Michael Dukakis, and was in Clinton's election &quot;war room&quot; in 1992.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
