<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255361" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>Italy: Italian Senate to hold confidence votes on budget.</title>
<headline>Italian Senate to hold confidence votes on budget.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's centre-left government called three confidence votes in the Senate (upper house) on Friday to sweep aside some 3,000 opposition amendments blocking passage of the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>Civil service minister Franco Bassanini told the assembly the government felt constrained to call the votes after senators from the centre-right Freedom Alliance and separatist Northern League refused to withdraw the avalanche of amendments.</p>
<p>The votes will take place on Monday, parliamentary officials said.</p>
<p>Northern League members rose to their feet after the announcement and shook empty cans of plum tomatoes sold by the Cirio company. Prime Minister Romano Prodi faces possible indictment in a legal case related to the company.</p>
<p>Bassanini said the government was submitting three so-called umbrella amendments grouping all the articles of the budget bill and was putting them to confidence votes.</p>
<p>It was doing so &quot;without any sense of satisfaction and without arrogance&quot;, he said.</p>
<p>Prodi has a comfortable majority in the Senate and his expected victory will strip away the blocking amendments.</p>
<p>The budget bill, designed to slash 62.5 trillion lire ($41 billion) from next year's deficit, is vital to Italy's hopes of joining Europe's planned single currency from the start in 1999.</p>
<p>Prodi's cabinet has said timely passage of the budget would be impossible if all the amendments had to be voted on.</p>
<p>Both houses must approve the budget by December 31. Costly provisional measures take effect if the deadline is missed.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot allow that now because we know it would be a sign of weakness and uncertainty of our will...to realise the objectives which are needed to join European monetary union from the start,&quot; Bassanini said.</p>
<p>The main opposition Freedom Alliance has been boycotting key votes on the budget in protest over a government request for special powers to legislate on some areas of policy, including fiscal reform, without recourse to parliament.</p>
<p>It has also organised street demonstrations against the package, which includes some 12.5 trillion lire of so-called &quot;Euro-tax&quot; measures to raise revenue.</p>
<p>Part of the &quot;Euro-tax&quot; is a one-off levy on income next year to help reduce the public deficit to the three percent of Gross Domestic Product required for countries aiming to join EMU.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
