<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255489" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Bombay shares end slightly lower, range-bound.</title>
<headline>Bombay shares end slightly lower, range-bound.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Late short covering pulled shares from a slide to finish little changed on Thursday but the undercurrent was shaky, brokers said.</p>
<p>The 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) closed 0.21 points down at a provisional 2,880.05, after moving between 2,850.06 and 2,893.70.</p>
<p>&quot;The market attracted short-covering towards the close. Otherwise, it was a very dull day,&quot; said Mehul Patel, dealer at Mukesh Babu Securities Ltd.</p>
<p>The 50-share National Stock Exchange index dropped 3.35 points to a provisional 823.65.  </p>
<p>The net traded value was 7.46 billion rupees in 35 million shares at the NSE.</p>
<p>He said business was mostly of position-squaring because of the last day of weekly account at the BSE.</p>
<p>Traders expect carry-forward charges to stay low as buyers were mostly foreign funds who do not carry-forward trades but take delivery.</p>
<p>&quot;Technically, the market looks ripe for rebound,&quot; said one analyst. &quot;But confidence levels are low.&quot;  </p>
<p>Bajaj Auto rallied 15.75 rupees to 740 and Gujarat Ambuja Cement 10.50 to 232 on foreign fund buying and scattered short covering, traders said.</p>
<p>ACC firmed 10.50 rupees to 1,010.50, Indian Hotel 13.75 to 675 and Hindustan Ciba 59 to 3,000.</p>
<p>Nestle fell 18.0 rupees to 177, Ranbaxy 4.25 to 520, Hindustan Lever 9.25 to 781, ITC 5.0 to 278.50 and M&amp;M 2.25 to 308.75.</p>
<p>--RANJIT GANGADHARAN, Bombay Newsroom +91-22-265-9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
