<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255410" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: Kofi Annan - cool head and straight talker.</title>
<headline>Kofi Annan - cool head and straight talker.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A soft-spoken straight- talker, Kofi Annan of Ghana has achieved the near-impossible feat of walking through U.N. political minefields unscathed.</p>
<p>A member of a family of traditional chiefs married to a Swedish artist and lawyer, Annan, 58, has held a variety of U.N. posts around the world before becoming the undersecretary-general for peacekeeping operations in March 1993.</p>
<p>He was a personnel director, a security coordinator, a budget director, a programme manager, a controller and a refugee agency executive, to name a few of his positions in Addis Ababa, Cairo, Ismalia and New York over the past 30 years.</p>
<p>Yet U.S. Ambassador Madeleine Albright, who forced Annan's boss, Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali, out of office for allegedly not streamlining the U.N. system enough, was among the American-educated Annan's strongest supporters.</p>
<p>And even his detractors admit that most of his staff have been fiercely loyal to him for years.</p>
<p>Bosnia's ambassador Muhamed Sacirbey, a harsh critic of the U.N.-led forces in his country, had nothing but praise for Annan, in charge of peacekeeping at the height of the Balkan war.</p>
<p>&quot;People trust him because he is honest,&quot; said Sacirbey. &quot;He doesn't try to hide behind a false argument. He defends his positions on merit.&quot;</p>
<p>Annan is expected to be officially confirmed as the new U.N. secretary-general after France, the last holdout in the Security Council, dropped its objections to his candidacy on Friday. France had preferred Boutros-Ghali or an African from a French-speaking country.</p>
<p>Annan would be the first U.N. secretary-general from a sub-Saharan African country and the only one from the U.N. bureaucracy itself.</p>
<p>With the United Nations suffering from a surplus of criticism and a shortage of funds, he faces the daunting task of convincing the world he is a diplomat, manager, humanist and visionary.</p>
<p>&quot;In the world of today, if we buy into the illusion that we can make the world habitable for a few, we will make it uninhabitable altogether,&quot; he once said, paraphrasing the late French President Francois Mitterrand.</p>
<p>Working from a 37th floor office decorated with carvings and plaques, Annan is known to his supporters as cool and unruffled. &quot;He sometimes shifts his weight slightly from one foot to another, but that's about all the tension you can see,&quot; said a member of his staff.</p>
<p>He also has a wicked sense of humour. Diplomats recall asking him during the race for secretary-general how well he spoke French. &quot;I now speak English with a French accent,&quot; he replied, in reference to Paris' insistence on mastery of the language.</p>
<p>Annan began his higher education at the University of Science and Technology in Kumasi, Ghana. He first left home in 1959 on a Ford Foundation grant to Macalester College in St. Paul, Minnesota, where he received a bachelor's' degree in economics.</p>
<p>He then studied at the Institut Universitaire de Hautes Etudes Internationales in Geneva after which he joined the World Health Organisation. From 1965 to 1971, he worked for the Ethiopia-based Economic Commission for Africa in Addis Ababa.</p>
<p>By then, at age 33, Annan said he had enough. &quot;I went through my mid-life crisis very early and needed to sit back and do some thinking.&quot; For relaxation he attended the prestigious Massachusetts Institute of Technology where he earned a master's degree in management.</p>
<p>In 1974 he returned to Ghana as managing director of the country's tourism agency but by 1976 he was at U.N. headquarters in New York and Geneva where he worked for the High Commissioner for Refugees before returning to U.N. posts in New York again.</p>
<p>During his long career, he was frequently tapped for sensitive special assignments. After Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait, he was sent to repatriate 900 U.N. staff, negotiate for the release of Western hostages and help resolve the plight of 500,000 stranded Asians in Kuwait and Iraq.</p>
<p>Annan is married to Swedish-born Nane Lagergren, a lawyer and judge before she became a full-time painter. Her father, Gunnar Lagergren, is a noted international jurist, and her mother is the sister of Raoul Wallenberg, the Swedish diplomat who rescued tens of thousands of Jews from the Nazis in Hungary near the end of the Second World War.</p>
<p>The couple tell of the last letter the family received from Wallenberg before he disappeared forever, presumably into a Soviet gulag or concentration camp. &quot;Kiss the little one for me,&quot; he wrote, shortly after Nane was born.</p>
<p>The Annans, both of whom were married previously, have three children: Ama, 26, Nina, 25, and Kojo, 23.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
