<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255569" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Stock prices zonked by skittish investors.</title>
<headline>Stock prices zonked by skittish investors.</headline>
<byline>Pierre Belec</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Stocks were zonked this week by fears that the sizzling bull market may be overdone. But is this an irrationally exuberant sell-off or the start of a long-awaited correction?</p>
<p>Just as the market was slowly regaining its footing after the prior week's plunge on Federal Reserve Board Chairman Alan Greenspan's warning about the speculative fervor of financial markets, stocks were again slammed.</p>
<p>This time, the selling stemmed from bearish talk that Japanese investors, who have been financing the national debt, might be losing their appetite for U.S. bonds.</p>
<p>The speculation sparked a leap in Treasury bonds' long-term interest rates, which had been declining to the applause of Wall Street.</p>
<p>The Treasury's key 30-year bond, a benchmark for lending rates for mortgage and home equity loans, spiked up to 6.62 percent from 6.36 percent just a week ago.</p>
<p>Japanese investors have been borrowing in Japanese yen at low interest rates, then flipping into dollars to buy U.S. bonds that yield more than 6 percent vs. Japanese bonds yields of less than 3 percent.</p>
<p>The concern on Wall Street was that if the Japanese shop elsewhere for better yields, the Fed might be forced to raise interest rates to make the bonds more attractive.</p>
<p>The leap in long-term interest rates threw the Dow Jones industrial average for a two-day loss of 170 points on Wednesday and Thursday before the gauge of 30-blue-chip stocks steadied on Friday.</p>
<p>A week earlier, the Dow was stunned by a warning from Greenspan about  &quot;irrational exuberance&quot; in financial markets. His comments were taken to mean that the central bank might boost interest rates to slow the upward drive in stocks and bonds.</p>
<p>The stock market has been on a rocket ride for the last two years, propelled by falling interest rates and strong corporate profits.</p>
<p>The spirited rally had boosted the Dow nearly 30 percent to a record of 6,547.79 on Nov. 25 -- its 43rd record close this year.</p>
<p>Greenspan's warning reminded investors that the market was breaking all sorts of speed limits and the rally may have gone too far.</p>
<p>The market's dramatic response to Greenspan's comments and and talk of weaker Japanese demand for bonds, illustrated the degree of apprehension on Wall Street over the possibility that stocks could be headed for a nasty fall.</p>
<p>Worried about preserving their profits, investors have been putting every possible scenario and rumour under a magnifying glass, causing the stock market to react violently as everyone jumped on the bandwagon.</p>
<p>With the Dow index up a whopping 1,370 points this year, investors have been looking over their shoulders, wondering when the next big sell-off could come.</p>
<p>The experts said the trick will be in posting a legitimate correction rather than a sell-off based on fear.</p>
<p>They said the market psychology has changed after this week's shakeout.</p>
<p>&quot;People have sobered up and a lot of confidence has been squeezed out of this market,&quot; said Hugh Johnson, chief investment officer at First Albany Corp., in Albany, N.Y.</p>
<p>&quot;Prior to the sell-off, the confidence was bordering on euphoria,&quot; he said. &quot;The confidence was that you could buy stocks, and they would only go up now that confidence has been replaced by caution and guardedness by all investors.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts said the drop in the Dow index from its record high of 6,547.79 to an intra-day low Friday of less than 6,250 would qualify as some sort of correction.</p>
<p>In late trading Friday, the index was up 0.77 of a point at 6,304.10. For the week, it was off 217.60 points.</p>
<p>But the jury is still out as to whether this is the beginning of a bear market or a pause caused by the precautionary withdrawal of buyers.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the correction is underway, the correction itself will tell us if it is just simply a spike or an extended drop,&quot; said John Geraghty at North American Equity Services, a consulting firm.</p>
<p>&quot;The first clue that it is a bona fide bear market will be when the buyers show a reluctance to return and they prefer to shift to other less risky investments,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
