<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255526" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Indian call money ends higher, gilt prices crash.</title>
<headline>Indian call money ends higher, gilt prices crash.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indian call money closed higher on Friday driven by fears of tighter liquidity over the next week while prices of government securities fell in thin trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said call money was quoted around eight percent at close of trade against the day's opening 6.75-7.25 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is nervous,&quot; said a dealer at a state-run bank. &quot;Sentiment has been affected by projections of large outflows from banks towards corporate tax payments. The supply of funds also seems to have shrunk slightly.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts estimate tax payments by corporates, to be made before December 15, to be between 40 and 50 billion rupees.</p>
<p>Dealers said another reason for the firming of call rates could be that lenders had diverted funds to invest in treasury bills available on tap with the Reserve Bank of India.</p>
<p>&quot;For most of last week, call rates were below four percent while on-tap bills offer 4.6 percent,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;Several lenders seem to have put their money in on-tap bills.&quot;</p>
<p>Dealers also said some big lenders seemed to be absent from the market. &quot;One large state-run bank, normally a lender, and a financial institution are both off the market today,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;This also helped push up rates.&quot;</p>
<p>Prices of government securities fell sharply in light trade, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said only three securities were traded on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The shallowness in the market is being exposed,&quot; said a dealer. &quot;There has been a sharp fall in very low volumes, which is a bad sign.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the fall in prices had been caused by the RBI's announcement of a securities auction. The RBI announced on Wednesday that it would auction 20 billion rupees of three-year government of India securities on December 23.</p>
<p>Dealers said some market players seemed to be selling stocks to invest in the new security and this selling pressure was driving down prices.</p>
<p>The 13.50 percent 1997 government of India stock traded on Friday at 101.91 rupees against its last traded price of 102.30.</p>
<p>The 13.50 percent 1998 stock shed 10 paise to 101.90 rupees and the 11.64 percent 2000 dropped 30 paise to 95 rupees.</p>
<p>Three-month commercial paper was quoted at 12.5 percent, a dealer at brokerage Mata Securities said.</p>
<p>Three-month certificates of deposit were quoted between 10.0 and 11.0 percent while one-year certificates were quoted 12.25 percent, the dealer said.</p>
<p>-- Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
