<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255958" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Madonna not planning to soften her bad-girl image.</title>
<headline>Madonna not planning to soften her bad-girl image.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Dubrowski</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pop star Madonna, whose career has spawned a variety of makeovers, says she has no plans to tone down her bad-girl image now that she's a mother.</p>
<p>In one of her first postpartum interviews, the Material Girl, whose stage antics have sparked controversy around the world, said on Thursday night the birth of her daughter in October has forced her to put her career on hold for a while.</p>
<p>But she has no plans to adopt a more traditional role as mother. &quot;I'm an artist and I will explain that to her and I hope she'll understand it,&quot; Madonna said, adding that she hopes to start writing songs again in March.</p>
<p>The 38-year-old actress also said she has no plans to marry the child's father, Carlos Leon, who lives with Madonna in the Los Angeles suburb of Los Feliz.</p>
<p>&quot;I can think lots of married couples or nuclear families that are terribly unhealthy and have terribly dysfunctional children,&quot; she said. &quot;I don't think that's a guarantee that your child is going to be happy.&quot;</p>
<p>Madonna, whose suggestive videos have earned the wrath of religious groups, said she was not concerned her reputation as a sex queen will make it hard to raise her daughter.</p>
<p>&quot;I consider myself to be a very moral person,&quot; Madonna said. &quot;I consider myself to have an enormous amount of integrity. I think what's important for me is to be honest with her and to share with her the knowledge that I have of the world of humanity, to teach her self respect, to teach her how to think for herself and be independent,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>In her latest film, &quot;Evita&quot;, which opens in New York and Los Angeles on Christmas Day, the one-time wife of actor Sean Penn plays Eva Peron, the illegitimate daughter of a poor farmer who overcomes the odds and becomes the wife of Argentina's President Juan Peron, played by Jonathan Pryce.</p>
<p>&quot;Evita&quot;, based on the popular opera by Andrew Lloyd Webber and Tim Rice, is an entirely musical film. Madonna said playing such a powerful woman as Evita &quot;was the role of a lifetime&quot; because she felt the two women shared many of the same characteristics.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that Evita was driven by a certain kind of sadness and I can relate to that, growing up without a parent, growing up poor and growing up in a place where there was not a lot going on and feeling this hunger and desire to see the world, to educate yourself, to make something of your life and become something important.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I think those things motivated her and they certainly motivated me.&quot;</p>
<p>Madonna said she was also drawn to the character by the many similarities to her own career as she clawed her way to the top of the music charts.</p>
<p>&quot;I think a lot of the same things that happened to her happened to me,&quot; Madonna said. &quot;I think people wanted to undermine her achievements by saying that she was a whore and that she slept her way to the top and I think people did the same thing to me.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I don't think it's possible to sleep your way to the top.&quot;</p>
<p>Madonna said her experience with &quot;Evita&quot; has prompted her to seek out better parts in future films and avoid projects that aren't challenging.</p>
<p>&quot;Now that I've worked in a great film I only want to be in great movies,&quot; she said. &quot;Having a child has nothing to do with that. If I don't feel 100 percent committed to the role, completely passionate about it, if I don't feel like I'm going to learn something about it, I don't want to do it.&quot;</p>
<p>She said she plans to raise her daughter, Lourdes Maria Ciccone Leon, as a Catholic and would like to have another child in a few years.</p>
<p>She also said she plans to keep her daughter out of the spotlight and make sure that she does not become poisoned by fame.</p>
<p>As to what type of music she would like to work on next, Madonna said she hopes to do a record of so-called standard songs like &quot;My Funny Valentine&quot; or Gershwin tunes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
