<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255906" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AUSTRALIA TRANSPORT-UPS sees Australia flights.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AUSTRALIA TRANSPORT-UPS sees Australia flights.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Morrison</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S.-owned express freight carrier United Parcel Service (UPS) could start flying its own planes to Australia if growth in the Australian market continued at the current rate, a senior company official said on Friday.</p>
<p>UPS, which started serving Australia in 1991, currently uses commercial airlines to carry packages in and out of the country, UPS general manager Australia Terry Hales said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;If things continue the way they are I could see very quickly the realisation of that ...&quot;, Hales said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is certainly not beyond the terms of possibility at all. I would say that we have a plan that it would happen in the next five years,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>UPS does not use its own planes, which currently total 300 worldwide, to fly to Australia as there was not enough export business from Australia, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't fly planes into Australia. The market is not yet large enough to warrant bringing in an airplane every day full up and then turn them around and fly them back,&quot; Hales said.</p>
<p>&quot;We have no problems filling them up coming in. Going out is another matter on a regular basis,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hales said Australia imports four times as much air freight as it exports. However, he said UPS projects large export growth, albeit from a low base in Australia.</p>
<p>&quot;Our volume of revenue forecasts are in the region of 34 percent (growth) in calendar 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The import business is seen growing at a more modest pace.</p>
<p>&quot;We still feel fairly bullish that we will still grow in the (import) market, probably seven or eight percent which is reasonable for the business,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>UPS uses Australia as a service centre rather than a hub for the Asia Pacific. Hales said UPS was spending US$400 million on its Asia Pacific hub terminal in Taiwan, which was chosen due to its proximity to other Asian nations and the United States.</p>
<p>&quot;When you sit down and work out the best location to service the customers, in our case we came out with Taiwan as the best location for the Asia Pacific,&quot; Hales said.</p>
<p>However, he did not rule out Australia becoming an Asian Pacific hub in the future.</p>
<p>UPS currently uses Honolulu as a connection point for freight bound for Australia.</p>
<p>Cargo is transferred to a Qantas Airways Ltd flight to carry it the rest of the way to Australia.</p>
<p>But this could change in the future if growth continued at the current pace, Hales said.</p>
<p>Atlanta-based UPS is privately owned.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
