<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="255913" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Expert tells Simpson jury not to trust DNA evidnce.</title>
<headline>Expert tells Simpson jury not to trust DNA evidnce.</headline>
<byline>Michael Miller</byline>
<dateline>SANTA MONICA, Calif 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>An expert testifying in O.J. Simpson's civil trial told jurors on Thursday that DNA evidence used to link the former football star to the murders of his ex-wife and her friend was not reliable.</p>
<p>&quot;I believe there is an unacceptable risk or chance, by the way these samples were handled, of there being cross-contamination,&quot; Dr. John Gerdes said.</p>
<p>He added that &quot;every one of the blood drops&quot; at the murder scene outside Nicole Brown Simpson's condominium was &quot;excessively contaminated.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, Gerdes said, the results of a DNA test known as PCR performed on blood found in Simpson's white Ford Bronco were not to be trusted and there was not enough blood to make a more exhaustive test, called RFLP, reliable.</p>
<p>His testimony came as Simpson's defence team pursued its two-pronged theory that Los Angeles Police Department (LAPD) forensic experts botched the collection and testing of hair and blood samples and that evidence was planted by police in order to frame the former athlete.</p>
<p>Gerdes, the clinical director of a Denver DNA lab and one of the country's leading authorities in the field, said tests carried out at the police crime laboratory could not be trusted because of the way the samples were collected and the way the tests were conducted.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel that with the sample collection and manipulation and the PCR setup and protocols (at the laboratory), there is a risk of contamination,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Gerdes, a pivotal witness for Simpson's defence, said DNA testing in crime cases was not as accurate as similar testing in hospitals because crime case samples, by their very nature, are &quot;dirty.&quot;</p>
<p>In addition, Gerdes said, such samples had to be collected on cloth &quot;swatches,&quot; placed in bags, taken out and dried, and then placed in other bags, with each manipulation increasing the risk of one sample being cross-contaminated by another.</p>
<p>The jury heard from witnesses earlier that the odds against blood in the case belonging to anyone other than Simpson and the victims were in the billions to one range.</p>
<p>There was to be no court session on Friday while attorneys resolved a conflict over the videotaped testimony of Dr. Henry Lee, a crime scene expert for the defence.</p>
<p>Simpson was acquitted of murder charges in the June 12, 1994 killings of Nicole Brown Simpson and Ronald Goldman by a criminal court jury in October 1995. He is now being sued by the families of the victims in the civil wrongful death case.</p>
<p>Earlier on Wednesday, jurors heard from Detective Kelly Muldorfer, who investigated a theft from Simpson's white Ford Bronco while it was in a police impound garage. A civilian tow-truck driver was fired after admitting he took credit card receipts from the Bronco as souvenirs.</p>
<p>Muldorfer said she could not recall seeing any blood on the centre console of the vehicle. Blood tested as being from Simpson and Goldman was later recovered from the console.</p>
<p>Police Lt. Frank Spangler said when he arrived at the murder scene outside Nicole Brown Simpson's condominium in the early hours of June 13, Detectives Mark Fuhrman and Ron Phillips were already there.</p>
<p>He said Fuhrman was wearing a jacket and that he was out of Spangler's sight for about 30 minutes while Phillips showed Spangler the murder scene. He said that when he next saw Fuhrman he was not wearing a jacket.</p>
<p>Simpson's defence contends Fuhrman picked up one of two gloves at the murder scene and later planted it on Simpson's estate. They want the jury to think Fuhrman put the glove in his jacket pocket and transported it to the former athlete's home when he went with other detectives to inform Simpson of the death of his ex-wife.</p>
<p>Attorneys for the plaintiffs maintain Simpson dropped the glove as he was trying to get on to his property unseen after committing the murders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA MONICA, Calif"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
