<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256065" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: S&amp;P puts Handelsbanken on creditwatch.</title>
<headline>S&amp;P puts Handelsbanken on creditwatch.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. credit ratings agency Standard &amp; Poor's on Friday put Swedish commercial Handelsbanken on creditwatch with negative implications after its 23 billion crown ($3.4 billion) takeover bid for mortgage bank Stadshypotek.</p>
<p>S&amp;P affirmed the bank's short-term credit and counterparty credit ratings at A-1 after the cash bid made on Thursday.</p>
<p>The agency said the transaction &quot;will sharply weaken Svenska Handelsbanken's capitalisation&quot; although capital adequacy should improve fairly quickly based on the strong earnings capacity of the group.</p>
<p>&quot;If the acquisition is completed in its current form, then Svenska Handelsbanken's Tier 1 capital ratio will likely fall below five percent from 8.7 percent reported at the end of September 1996,&quot; S&amp;P said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;The reduced level of capital will make the bank one of the lowest capitalised banks in Europe,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>S&amp;P said it would meet with Handelsbanken management shortly to discuss the transaction which still needs regulatory and shareholder approval.</p>
<p>Handelsbanken, Sweden's biggest bank by assets, on Thursday announced a 22.9 billion crown bid for Stadshypotek which is Sweden's largest mortgage lender with a third of the market.</p>
<p>The state holds 34 percent of Stadshypotek and the government has already given tentative approval to Handelsbanken's offer on the condition that no higher bids are received.</p>
<p>Swedish insurer Skandia on Friday said it was analysing the rival bids for Stadshypotek and was continuing to prepare its prospectus for a proposed merger with the mortgage bank.</p>
<p>&quot;Preparations ahead of Skandia's extraordinary general meeting scheduled for Thursday, December 19, 1996, as well as the work to prepare Skandia's prospectus to the shareholders in Stradshypotek continue according to plan,&quot; Skandia said in a statement.</p>
<p>Skandia's chairman Sven Soderberg, said the company was analysing the current situation after Handelsbanken's bid for</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
