<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256159" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy centre-right to hold on to budget amendments.</title>
<headline>Italy centre-right to hold on to budget amendments.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior member of Italy's opposition Freedom Alliance said on Friday that it would not withdraw a raft of amendments to the 1997 budget, making a confidence vote in the Senate (upper house) more likely.</p>
<p>&quot;We will not withdraw our amendments and we will leave the assembly when votes are held on those parts (of the bill) which we consider unacceptable and unconstitutional,&quot; Giulio Maceratini, Senate leader of the hard-right National Alliance party, told reporters.</p>
<p>The Freedom Alliance has submitted well over half of the more than 3,000 amendments in the Senate to the centre-left government's 62.5 trillion lire ($41 billion) budget.</p>
<p>It opposes plans by Prime Minister Romano Prodi's government to assume special powers to legislate on some areas of policy, including fiscal reform, without recourse to parliament and has been boycotting key budget votes in protest.</p>
<p>The government has said so many amendments have been submitted that it will be impossible for the Senate to approve the budget by a December 19 deadline and has accused the opposition of obstructionism.</p>
<p>Senate budget commission chairman Coviello Romualdo said earlier that the government could call four or five confidence votes in the Senate to sweep the amendments aside.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +39 6 6782505</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
