<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256151" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: Italy's Prodi returns fire against industrialists.</title>
<headline>Italy's Prodi returns fire against industrialists.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi lashed out at Italy's industrial elite on Friday, accusing them of unprecedented meddling in domestic politics.</p>
<p>&quot;Never before in a highly developed country have we seen private industry interfere so heavily in the political life of that country,&quot; Prodi told reporters in Dublin where he is attending a summit of European Union leaders.</p>
<p>Relations between Prodi's seven-month old government and employers' organisation Confindustria have deteriorated rapidly in recent weeks, with industrialists up in arms over the 1997 austerity budget.</p>
<p>The chairman of car giant Fiat, Cesare Romiti, on Thursday launched a scathing attack on the Prodi administration.</p>
<p>&quot;Italy is going through a tragic moment,&quot; Romiti told a conference in Milan. &quot;The political class is poor in terms of personalities...and Italians realise they don't have a crumb of hope for the future,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Earlier this week, Confindustria chief Giorgio Fossa said the government risked being blown away and urged it to drop planned tax hikes in the 1997 budget.</p>
<p>But Prodi said the industrialists were showing &quot;political immaturity&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;It is because they realise that this government is going to last,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The 1997 budget is currently being examined by parliament which has until the end of the year to approve the deficit cutting package.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
