<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256208" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Mediaset in accord with GTE, Telenor.</title>
<headline>Mediaset in accord with GTE, Telenor.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italian television group Mediaset said it has signed an accord with U.S. telephone company GTE and Norway's  Telenor in view of future developments in the Italian telecoms sector.</p>
<p>&quot;The consortium accord has been signed,&quot; a Mediaset spokesman said, confirming Italian press reports.</p>
<p>&quot;And when a company for the bid (to manage a PCN standard mobile phone service) is created, the natural outcome will be for the consortium partners to come in as shareholders,&quot; he said, adding this would likely be in the near future.</p>
<p>Mediaset has already joined forces with Albacom, a joint venture between British Telecom and Italian state bank BNL to bid for a third Italian mobile phone licence.  </p>
<p>Holdings in the PCN consortium and in the new company to be set up have not yet been defined, although industry sources said BT as the main telecoms operator would probably have the majority.</p>
<p>The date for the tender to operate the Personal Communications Network mobile phone service, based on the state-of-the-art DCS 1800 technology, has not yet been fixed but is expected to take place in the first half of next year.</p>
<p>Italy's current mobile phone operators are state-controlled Telecom Italia Mobile (TIM)  TIMI.MI and the Olivetti controlled Omnitel consortium.</p>
<p>GTE Corp is one of the world's major operators in the telephony sector and already is present in the Italian market. According to Italian press reports, GTE could be a potential buyer of Seat, the telephone directory publishing unit of state telecoms holding Stet, to be spun off soon.</p>
<p>State-owned Telenor is Norway's sector leader and one of the main Scandinavian operators in network services, voice-data applications and mobile telephony.  </p>
<p>Industry sources estimate that investment needed to set up a PCN network would be between 2.5 and 3.0 trillion lire.</p>
<p>Mediaset and its partners have underlined that its participation in a tender for the third licence would conditional on the rules being &quot;fair and equal&quot; to avoid creating privileges for other operators.</p>
<p>Mediaset has also expressed an interest in Omnitel and has weighed up the possibility of making a bid for the entire Olivetti group as this would be the only way of securing the Omnitel business in the immediate future.</p>
<p>But Omnitel is not up for sale and Mediaset said last week that the chances of it launching a bid for Olivetti were very slim.</p>
<p>-- Milan newsroom +392 66129589</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
