<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256211" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: India faces opposition protest over WTO pact.</title>
<headline>India faces opposition protest over WTO pact.</headline>
<byline>Jawed Naqvi</byline>
<dateline>NEW DELHI 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>India's government came under opposition fire on Friday for accepting an agreement sealed at this week's World Trade Organisation (WTO) inaugural conference.</p>
<p>&quot;When we could take on the world over the CTBT (Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty), why couldn't we resist pressure on this occasion?&quot; former prime minister Atal Bihari Vajpayee said on behalf of the main opposition Bharatiya Janata Party.</p>
<p>India, regarded as a threshold nuclear power, has refused to sign the Nuclear Non-proliferation Treaty or the CTBT, on both occasions against U.S. advice.</p>
<p>Indian Commerce Secretary Tejendra Khanna, however, said in Singapore that while India had not been able to keep the highly sensitive issue of labour standards out of the WTO's final declaration, it had made sure its concerns were fully reflected.</p>
<p>Finance Minister P. Chidambaram put a different spin on the labour issue.</p>
<p>He told parliament's lower house India had won a key battle over international labour standards, but was not happy with a decision by the WTO on investment and trade competition.</p>
<p>&quot;I think barring some unhappiness about the reference to two working groups on trade and investment, our brief has been faithfully adhered to by our delegation,&quot; Chidambaram told the parliamentarians.</p>
<p>Before he spoke, irate lawmakers had forced the abrupt adjournment of both houses of the Indian parliament and demanded a government statement on India's stance at the trade talks, accusing Prime Minister H.D. Deve Gowda of caving in to multinationals.</p>
<p>But Chidambaram's comments failed to placate the deputies.</p>
<p>The Bharatiya Janata Party's (BJP) Vajpayee said the government should not have accepted any agreement for which there was no support in parliament.</p>
<p>Vajpayee found surprise support from the communists, often regarded by the BJP as foes.</p>
<p>&quot;As the BJP member has said, the government obviously has the text of the agreement. It couldn't have signed it without having it. So why is it hiding it from us?&quot; asked Nirmal Chatterjee of the Communist Party of India-Marxist.</p>
<p>The Communist Party is a key ally of the 13-member ruling United Front alliance.</p>
<p>Chidambaram promised to hold a full discussion on the issue in parliament on Monday when the text of the agreement would be available.</p>
<p>Khanna, the commerce ministry's top official, told reporters at the WTO that ministers in Delhi had been briefed fully on what had happened in Singapore and &quot;would reassure&quot; parliament.</p>
<p>He said the WTO's closing declaration had said definitively that labour standards were the province of the International Labour Organisation and not the WTO.</p>
<p>It had also pledged that the 128 WTO members would not use trade measures to improve working conditions in the developing world which countries like India saw as a disguised attempt to undermine low-cost labour advantages, Khanna said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a very positive step because this was always lurking on the horizon,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW DELHI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
