<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256247" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: Nightshifts to lift Nedcar output to 210,000 units.</title>
<headline>Nightshifts to lift Nedcar output to 210,000 units.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Nedcar, a joint venture car plant between AB Volvo, Mitsubishi Motors Corp and the Dutch government, said on Friday new nightshifts would raise output by 30-35 percent from January.</p>
<p>&quot;The production will increase from 160,000 currently to 210,000 to 215,000 from January,&quot; said chief operating officer Chris de Wulf said in an interview.</p>
<p>De Wulf, who becomes company president at the start of the year, said the plant was still on schedule to reach the ultimate production target of 280,000 cars per year by 1998.</p>
<p>&quot;We have the capacity, although it will depend on the market size. We will be ready in principle in 1998, but will probably only reach (280,000 units) in 1999,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said further rises in output would come from increased investment and a steady streamlining of the production process.</p>
<p>In September the Dutch carmaker said it had failed to obtain a permit from the minister of social affairs to introduce nightshifts at its factory in the southern Netherlands town of Born.</p>
<p>The ministry said it would not give the permit to start a permanent nightshift as this would contravene legislation limiting nightshifts to 28 per 13 weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;We couldn't use a fixed nightshift, so we will adopt a rolling shift,&quot; said chief operating officer, Chris de Wulf.</p>
<p>The pioneering plant was the first to produce cars for separate car manufacturers on the same production line when its first Mitsubishis rolled out in spring 1995. The line was already producing Volvos.</p>
<p>However, it ran into difficulties and admitted in August that its output targets were over-ambitious, spurring speculation that Mitsubishi at least were considering shifting some of their production to another European site.</p>
<p>-- Philip Blenkinsop, Amsterdam Newsroom, +31 20 504 5000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
