<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256318" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-AUSTRALIA TRANSPORT-Industry wants stronger say in planning.</title>
<headline>RTRS-AUSTRALIA TRANSPORT-Industry wants stronger say in planning.</headline>
<byline>Richard Pullin</byline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Australia's tourism industry is seeking a stronger voice in transport planning, urging government backing for private sector infrastructure projects.</p>
<p>&quot;Tourism has never been given a seat at the transport planning table and that ought to change,&quot; Tourism Task Force lobby group chief executive Christopher Brown told Reuters.</p>
<p>While little quantitative work had been done on the impact of transport projects on tourism, their importance was clear, particulary in a country the size of Australia, Brown said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one thing to get people to this island continent...but we've got tourism product all over the country, so we have to move them around,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Transport was also the key to encouraging regional development and broadening the tourism base.</p>
<p>&quot;If we're going to spread the dividend into the bush, then we need to physically do it by transport,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The number of international visitors to Australia is expected to top the four million mark in 1996, and grow nine percent a year through to 2005.</p>
<p>Domestic tourism has grown more moderately in recent years, but is expected to increase at between two and three percent a year over the next five to ten years, according to a recent report by the Tourism Task Force.</p>
<p>The A$80,000 study on tourism transport needs, funded by government and industry, recommended the development of a national database of transport infrastructure projects and reforms to boost private sector involvement.</p>
<p>Brown said the report revealed there was no long-term view on transport, despite the huge number of potential projects.</p>
<p>He said planners should be looking ahead by 10 or 20 years and thinking in terms of strategy rather than on a project-by-project basis.</p>
<p>Brown said it was also clear governments were unable to commit the necessary funds to public transport infrastructure, and should look to foster private funding.</p>
<p>This could be done by maintaining infrastructure bonds, which offer a tax break to private investors, and providing a one-stop-shop approach for developers and financiers to stop bureaucratic duplications.</p>
<p>Governments should also constantly review planning and approval processes to remove any unnecessary regulations.</p>
<p>&quot;The government ought to become proponents of these projects ...they ought to be working with the private sector to attract investment,&quot; said Brown.</p>
<p>The report found Australia was well served by air transport, but recommended that government free-up access to Australia on a regional basis.</p>
<p>Tourist travel on roads was seen as part of total travel demand, while Australia did not have the population to support a comprehensive national rail system.</p>
<p>However, a number of discrete rail projects were planned and the government should develop a national strategy for the industry, the study said.</p>
<p>Cruise shipping was seen as a potential growth area, given the worldwide boom. &quot;That's one area where we can actually grow a market based on new infrastructure,&quot; Brown said.</p>
<p>Governments could also aid the industry by reform of port charges, as well as navigation regulations and fuel excise and duty.</p>
<p>The report identified and analysed 13 transport projects which it said were of national importance, while another 150 were submitted to the authors.</p>
<p>Some of these projects included the Sydney to Canberra high-speed rail proposal, a highway project in Western Australia's Kimberley region and cruise ship terminals in Cairns and Darwin.</p>
<p>However, it warned that Australia's attraction as an investment destination was diminishing as other countries, particularly the growing Asian economies, began to compete for funds.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1871</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GTOUR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
