<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256335" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian dlr hesitant after hard week.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian dlr hesitant after hard week.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar finished a seesaw week on a relatively steady note given all its initial promise had been wiped out by a shock cut in interest rates.</p>
<p>A sluggish Friday session was characterised by thin, nervous trading with local and Japanese buying providing a cushion at 79 cents while offers were lined up at US$0.7950 chart resistance.</p>
<p>Traders said the market was hesitant about where the dollar went next following Wednesday's easing in policy with some concerned its yield premium might no longer be fat enough to tempt offshore investors. Until that concern was resolved -- one way or the other -- further sideways consolidation was likely.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0600 GMT) the local currency was hovering at US$0.7928/33 having bounced in a tight US$0.7910/7942 range through the day after finishing Thursday at US$0.7923/28.</p>
<p>This was actually not far from last Friday's US$0.7950/55 close but a long way from the US$0.8020 level held just before the Reserve Bank sprang its surprise rate cut on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Interim support was seen at US$0.7910 and US$0.7890 with the key level being US$0.7850, which marked last week's low. The currency needed to clear US$0.7950 to counter the risk of a deeper correction and would have to break US$0.8050 to revive the uptrend so rudely interupted by the RBA.  </p>
<p>On the crosses, it was holding firm at 89.72/82 yen from 89.33/43 late here Thursday thanks to Japanese demand and a modest bounce in US$/yen.</p>
<p>In trade weighted terms it edged up to 58.9 from a previous 58.8 close, but again was well short of Tuesday's 59.6 high.</p>
<p>Sentiment had been supported overnight by the launch of a 30 billion yen dual currency samurai bond, the first yen/A$ issue since December 3 when the dollar plunged three cents in a day.</p>
<p>The fresh supply went some way to reassuring dollar bulls that A$ assets were still attractive to Japanese investors despite this week's 0.5 point cut in official cash rates.  </p>
<p>But concerns persisted that the latest cut had so thinned the A$'s yield premium over its U.S. counterpart that offshore investors might become uncomfortable with their long positions -- some of which had to be very long indeed after a year of record yen/A$ issues and of borrowing in yen to lend in dollars.</p>
<p>There was also a chance U.S. rates could be rising next year, although soft U.S. consumer price and retail sales data on Thursday suggested to many that the Federal Reserve would be in no hurry to tighten.</p>
<p>Equally, there had been scares about a possible rise in Japanese rates which analysts also felt were premature.  </p>
<p>The only domestic data out were Q3 housing starts which fell a much sharper than expected 7.3 percent. This was regarded as old news and emphatically ignored by the markets.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, commodity prices have been offering little in the way of direction in recent weeks, although a steady rally in copper prices has supported sentiment since the currency has a reasonable correlation with the red metal over time.</p>
<p>The Commodity Research Bureau futures index bounced 1.26 points to 241.75 Thursday but remained in a clear downtrend having peaked at 263.79 in April.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
