<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256326" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: Australian government wins historic budget battle.</title>
<headline>Australian government wins historic budget battle.</headline>
<byline>Bradley Perrett</byline>
<dateline>CANBERRA 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A historic assault on Australia's budget deficit by conservative prime minister John Howard survived parliamentary challenge this week, promising to return the country to surplus later in the decade.</p>
<p>Minority parties repeatedly attempted to block measures worth more than a quarter of the A$7.2 billion (A$5.7 billion) programme, but time after time the budget bills passed on knife-edge votes with the support of two independents.</p>
<p>&quot;I was hoping that about A$6 billion would survive,&quot; said a top government official.</p>
<p>&quot;But it looks like we'll get almost A$7 billion.&quot;</p>
<p>The success means that the government should slash the underlying deficit to under A$6 billion this fiscal year (to June 30) from A$10.3 billion in 1995/96.</p>
<p>As the budget cuts work up to full steam next fiscal year the deficit should fall below A$2 billion in underlying terms -- that is, excluding asset sales. The year after that is supposed to produce a small surplus, the first since 1990/91.</p>
<p>The motivation behind the cuts is the currently popular theory in Australia that its intractably high current account deficit and interest rates stem from a shortage of savings.</p>
<p>If the government would stop borrowing, economists say, the country could satisfy more of its own demand for investment and the government could let the economy grow faster -- by lowering interest rates -- without fear of inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;When I talk about the desirability of budget deficits being lower, I have in mind lower interest rates,&quot; Howard told reporters on Friday.</p>
<p>The Liberal-National government announced the budget programme soon after it won office in March, ending 13 years of Labor rule.</p>
<p>The election campaign had been played out under the fiction that there was nothing wrong with the budget.</p>
<p>Labor defied economists' forecasts and stuck by its rosy projections of surpluses to come -- and the conservatives were happy to play along, since they hardly wanted to talk about the need for cuts during an election campaign.</p>
<p>Then Howard and Treasurer Peter Costello took office and announced within days that the budget was a mess and they would have cut spending and hike revenue.</p>
<p>The problem was the upper house of parliament, the Senate, where the government was two votes short of a majority and almost all opposing senators except a solitary independent were strongly to the left of the new government.</p>
<p>The breakthrough came on budget day, August 20.</p>
<p>As Costello prepared to spell out the intricate programme that would be the largest single fiscal tightening in Australian history, a Labor senator defected.</p>
<p>There were now two independents -- who ended up providing the two votes that the government needed.</p>
<p>The independents forced some changes on the government during the budget votes this week, but officials estimated on Friday that they had cost only A$200 million or A$300 million a year, compared with annual spending of A$136 billion.</p>
<p>On most bills they backed the government.</p>
<p>Costello and Howard actually promised A$8 billion in budget savings in March.</p>
<p>Since the A$7.2 billion was announced in the August budget, they have refused to discuss the remaining A$800 million.</p>
<p>But Howard said this week that if the government got its current programme through the Senate, then he would regard that as achieving his fiscal goal.</p>
<p>(A$=US$0.79)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CANBERRA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
