<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256427" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: Shanghai copper futures end down on LME losses.</title>
<headline>Shanghai copper futures end down on LME losses.</headline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shanghai copper futures ended down on Friday, with most contracts closing below the key 20,000-yuan level due to overnight losses on the London Metal Exchange, traders said.</p>
<p>The most active March 1997 contract ended at 19,900 yuan ($2,397) per tonne, down 260 yuan. It opened at an intra-day high of 20,000 and hit a low of 19,880.</p>
<p>December fell 200 to 19,950, January 220 to 19,890, February 230 to 18,890, April 250 to 19,900, May 270 to 19,910 and June 300 to 20,000.</p>
<p>Combined volume fell to 76,400 tonnes from 76,790.  </p>
<p>Copper opened lower and fell further with most contracts closing at or near their intra-day lows.</p>
<p>Traders said speculative selling and bearish expectations, triggered by the LME losses, pushed most contracts below the 20,000-yuan level.</p>
<p>&quot;Expectations of rises of LME stockpiles hurt confidence of long position holders, with a bout of panic selling in the morning session,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;Copper fell below 20,000 yuan again, indicating that most investors were not optimistic about the future trend,&quot; he added.  </p>
<p>Traders said copper would fall further if it cannot recover its losses next Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;It is very important for long and short position holders to see whether or not copper can hold above the 20,000-yuan level,&quot; a second trader said.</p>
<p>Aluminium ended mostly up. December fell 10 to 13,680, January rose 60 to 13,910 and February rose 50 to 14,050.</p>
<p>Combined volume rose to 2,560 from 500.</p>
<p>($1=8.2990)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M142">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
