<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256495" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China to block imports of 'splittist' art.</title>
<headline>China to block imports of 'splittist' art.</headline>
<dateline>BEIJING 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's cultural guardians have banned imports of art they see are aimed at splitting China or interfering in its internal affairs, the official media said on Friday.</p>
<p>A Ministry of Culture meeting that concluded in Beijing on Thursday had drawn up the policy, which would judge imports of foreign art -- including cultural performances and other forms of entertainment -- based on how it could serve China.</p>
<p>&quot;It is an important task for China to resist the infiltration of decadent culture from abroad, as many developed countries have been shipping their values to developing countries,&quot; the China Daily quoted Li Yuanchao, vice-minister of culture, as telling the meeting.</p>
<p>China would ban imports of &quot;artistic activities with the goal of splitting China and its nationalities&quot; as well as art &quot;with the goal of interfering in China's internal affairs&quot;, Xinhua quoted Yuan Xue, deputy director of the ministry's External Relations Bureau, as saying.</p>
<p>China said last month that U.S.-based entertainment giant Walt Disney Co would be wrong to make a film praising the Dalai Lama, Tibet's exiled spiritual leader.</p>
<p>Beijing accuses the 1989 Nobel Peace Prize winner of creating unrest in the Himalayan region.</p>
<p>&quot;The Chinese government will further encourage foreigners to give performances and hold exhibitions in China, but it will firmly ban decadent cultural ideas and practices from abroad,&quot; Xinhua said.</p>
<p>Also falling under the censor's axe would be art that opposed the socialist system or promoted superstition, pornography, violence or drugs, the news agency said.</p>
<p>In response to Chinese pressure on Disney, dozens of prominent Western film industry figures signed a letter accusing Beijing of trying to impose worldwide censorship on China-related movies.</p>
<p>The letter said China's warning to Disney was the latest step in a continuing effort by Beijing to censor the film industry. They included a list of 12 occasions in which they believed the Chinese government had interfered with productions.</p>
<p>Disney has said it will go ahead with the U.S. release of &quot;Kundun&quot; despite China's objections. Beijing has denied putting pressure on Disney to withdraw backing for the film.</p>
<p>The Dalai Lama fled Tibet in 1959 to India after an abortive uprising against Chinese rule and since then has waged a non-violent campaign for autonomy for his homeland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIJING"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
