<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256584" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Singapore tops HK as regional location - poll.</title>
<headline>Singapore tops HK as regional location - poll.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian business executives prefer Singapore to Hong Kong as the best place to locate a regional headquarters, a regional magazine said on Friday.</p>
<p>The Far East Economic Review poll found 73 percent of 6,000 executives in 11 Asian countries said Singapore would provide a better base for a regional headquarters than the British colony, which returns to Chinese rule at midnight next June 30.</p>
<p>The poll, which will be published in the December 19 issue, also said 42 percent of respondents chose Singapore among major Asian cities for regional headquarters. Only 17 percent were in favour of Hong Kong and four percent for Tokyo.</p>
<p>&quot;Singapore's lower property and labour costs, tax incentives to foreign companies, the growth of its financial services industry and a higher quality of life is tempting many multinational companies away from Hong Kong to Singapore,&quot; the Hong Kong-based magazine's managing editor John Leger said in a statement.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not a case of pre-1997 nerves. Costs and the ease of doing business seem to be the biggest factor,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hong Kong promoted itself as China's window but was facing increasing competition from Shanghai's Pudong area, while Singapore offers access to Indonesia and the rest of Southeast Asia, he said.</p>
<p>The annual survey, Review 2000: Asia's Leading Companies, was conducted in association with Citibank and administrated by Survey Research Singapore, it said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E511">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
