<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256563" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: WTO row places labour standards firmly in spotlight.</title>
<headline>WTO row places labour standards firmly in spotlight.</headline>
<byline>Michael Battye</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>A furious international row over links between bad working conditions and trade this week may not have given immediate help to people, many of them children, toiling in appalling conditions.</p>
<p>But it has put their plight firmly on the international political agenda, officials attending the World Trade Organisation's (WTO) first ministerial conference said on Friday.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue does now have a very high international profile and there's no way any of us is going to be able to hide from it,&quot; said one envoy whose country had fought hard to keep the issue out of the final declaration of the WTO meeting.</p>
<p>&quot;We are already under strong pressure at the ILO (International Labour Organisation) and that is now going to increase sharply,&quot; said the envoy, who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>The debate at the 128-member WTO conference ending on Friday, which often evoked undiplomatic passions in closed-door sessions and in the corridors outside, was not about doing something concrete on the issue.</p>
<p>It was not directly about 250 million children, mostly but not exclusively in the developing world, who work instead of going to school.</p>
<p>It was not about matchbox factories, dangerous fireworks plants, stone quarries, dingy carpet weaving sheds, or baking fields reeking with pesticides. A United Nations Children's Fund report this week said 250 million children aged five to 14 worked in hazardous conditions.</p>
<p>Nor was the debate at the WTO about adults working in factories closer to the standards of the early part of the industrial revolution than the 21st Century into which the world is heading.</p>
<p>For the United States, backed particularly by France and Norway, it was about human rights and getting the WTO to link the issue of basic labour standards and global trade that becomes freer and more competitive by the day.</p>
<p>For many others, mostly in the developing world but backed by several European countries, it was about a major trade power trying to protect jobs at home from cheap Third World labour.</p>
<p>They saw an effort to have the WTO, which has its own court, take over the issue from the ILO, which does not. Rich countries could undermine the low labour cost advantage of the developing world through taking trade disputes to the WTO, they said.</p>
<p>Both sides went away proclaiming victory. Conference sources said the United States was happy that core labour standards were at least mentioned in the final declaration.</p>
<p>Those who had fought against any mention at all said they were content with final wording that placed responsibility for establishing decent working standards and for monitoring them rested with the ILO.</p>
<p>&quot;For us, the language says definitively that this issue is nothing to do with the WTO, that the WTO will do nothing further about it and the issue will not be raised again,&quot; said one senior Asian envoy.</p>
<p>&quot;We are working on the problems, especially child labour, but what we need is help, not coercion,&quot; said another.</p>
<p>But others said they expected the United States and others to come back to the subject because of rising voter pressure at home to do something about the drift of jobs to countries where wages are small and conditions worse.</p>
<p>&quot;There's nothing in the WTO rules that says an issue cannot be raised, and I'm sure the Americans and others will keep coming back to this one,&quot; another Latin American envoy said.</p>
<p>&quot;They've put it on the world agenda and I'll bet you'll see it popping up all over the place.&quot;</p>
<p>The International Confederation of Free trade Unions (ICFTU) called the outcome of the debate &quot;a small but important step&quot; in winning decent working conditions and applauded the WTO for mentioning it.</p>
<p>&quot;The WTO's credibility is undermined when it ensures that Mickey Mouse has more rights than the workers who make toys because it covers trade marks but not labour standards,&quot; said the ICFTU, which claims 124 million affiliate members in 136 countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
