<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256537" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: New Thai finance minister defends economic policy.</title>
<headline>New Thai finance minister defends economic policy.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan on Friday defended the government's economic policy initiatives after political opponents said the package was vague and lacked a time frame.</p>
<p>Amnuay highlighted his proposals to solve the widening current account deficit, maintain fiscal discipline, boost export competitiveness and rescue the depressed property sector.</p>
<p>Opposition politicians have attacked the new government's policy statement, saying it recognised such woes as a slowing economy and sluggish exports but lacked details.</p>
<p>&quot;Thanks for expressing concerns over the economic problems. But I want to tell you that your concerns are my concerns as well. And I'm ready, if need be, to put my life on the line to solve these problems,&quot; he told parliament.</p>
<p>He was winding up a joint parliamentary debate on the policy statement of the new government led by Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh that took office earlier this month.</p>
<p>Amnuay stressed that boosting foreign exchange earnings and cutting unnecessary spending were the keys to solving Thailand's current account deficit, which stood at 8.1 percent of gross domestic product (GDP) in 1995.</p>
<p>The deficit is one of the highest in the region, according to some analysts, and is expected by the central bank to rise to 8.3 percent of GDP in 1996.</p>
<p>On Thursday, Chavalit, who is also defence minister, vowed to curb military spending and shelve planned purchases of two submarines for the navy and a $1.04 billion spy and communcations satellite by the military.</p>
<p>Amnuay said measures to boost foreign exchange earnings included promoting tourism and improving the services sector.</p>
<p>There was also a need to urgently boost the fledgling domestic insurance business and Thailand's shipping fleet.</p>
<p>Although exports have been the major revenue earner of the country for years, the Thai domestic merchant fleet has failed to develop and grab opportunities in the sector.</p>
<p>Freight charges, excluding insurance fees, paid by Thai exporters to foreign shippers to move their goods to overseas market in 1995 totalled nearly 20 billion baht ($800 million), or seven percent of the nation's total payments for services.</p>
<p>Amnuay blamed a very tight monetary policy for a slowdown in the economy, and vowed he would boost liquidity in the market while upholding a disciplined fiscal policy.</p>
<p>&quot;Lots of businesses faced liquidity problems. The drastic slowdown was caused by too tight monetary policy. And when business slowed down, we had problems collecting tax revenue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Thailand's central bank has favoured a tight monetary policy to control inflationary tendencies.</p>
<p>In order to improve liquidity in the market, Amnuay said he would promote the capital markets and let financial institutions pursue wider foreign exchange businesses. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
