<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256602" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Tatung unit in T$15 bln display plant.</title>
<headline>Tatung unit in T$15 bln display plant.</headline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's unlisted Chung Hwa Picture Tubes said on Friday it would invest T$15 billion to build a liquid-crystal display plant in 1997 to make advanced thin-film-transistor LCDs.  </p>
<p>&quot;Seeing the market potential, we plan to step into the advanced TFT-LCD production in 1997, investing T$15 billion,&quot; Chung Hwa vice-president Chien Chen-cheng told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We will invest 100 percent in the project ourselves, but we are seeking technological support from Europe, the United States or Japan,&quot; Chien said by telephone.</p>
<p>The high-technology thin-film transistor displays are a key component for producing notebook computers and monitors.</p>
<p>The plant will be built in the island's northern county of Taoyuan, Chien said.</p>
<p>Other details have yet to be set, he said.  </p>
<p>Chung Hwa's T$3 billion super-twist-nematic LCD plant has recently begun mass-production, expected to turn out 80,000 11.3-inch STN-LCD units a month from December, Chien said.</p>
<p>Chung Hwa, one of the world's leading cathode ray tube makers, is 88.5 percent owned by Tatung Co, one of the island's biggest electronics and electrical appliance makers. Cathode ray tubes are the central component of computer monitors.</p>
<p>Chung Hwa expects to reach a pretax profit of T$10 billion on sales of T$60 billion in 1996, and plans a 1997 pretax profit of T$14 billion on sales of T$72.9 billion, Chien said.</p>
<p>-- Taipei Newsroom (5080815)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
