<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256780" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canada says cannot meet greenhouse gas target.</title>
<headline>Canada says cannot meet greenhouse gas target.</headline>
<byline>Darren Schuettler</byline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada said on Thursday it will fail to meet its goal to stabilize greenhouse gas emissions by the year 2000, but vowed to strengthen its efforts to combat global warming.</p>
<p>Canada was among several countries at the 1992 Rio Earth Summit that committed to reduce greenhouse gases such as carbon dioxide and methane -- the two most common gases which scientists believe contribute to global warming.</p>
<p>But Canadian Environment Minister Sergio Marchi confirmed on Thursday that Canada will fail to meet its goal of stabilizing emissions at 1990 levels by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Canadian emissions of greenhouse gases were 9.4 percent above 1990 levels last year, and are expected to stay 8 percent above 1990 levels by the year 2000.</p>
<p>&quot;If we don't start to redouble the efforts. If we don't recognize that today, we won't even reach (the emission target) by 2010,&quot; Marchi said after a meeting of Canadian energy and environment ministers in Toronto.</p>
<p>Marchi said Canada's higher emissions were due to a growing population and stronger economy which boosted energy consumption.</p>
<p>The federal government unveiled a package of initiatives on Thursday, including plans to strengthen a program which asks industry to voluntarily reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>But environmental groups have said voluntary programs are not enough.</p>
<p>&quot;Rather than introducing a compulsory national program to reduce greenhouse gases similar to those in other countries -- Canada has chosen instead to rely on voluntary corporate program that was flawed from the outset,&quot; said Jim Fulton, executive director of the David Suzuki Foundation, a Canadian environmental group.</p>
<p>Environmentalists have singled out Canada's oil and gas sector as a major offender in the battle against global warming.</p>
<p>The Pembina Institute of Appropriate Development said earlier this week that increased activity in Alberta's oilpatch is playing a large part in Canada's failure to see a reduction in its greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>But Canadian petroleum producers said the industry has made significant progress in stabilizing its emissions.</p>
<p>The Canadian Association of Petroleum Producers (CAPP) said its figures show emissions per unit of production have been reduced by about 10 percent from 1990 to 1995.</p>
<p>While oil and natural gas production has increased by 33 percent over the five-year period, carbon dioxide emissions increased only 19 percent, according to CAPP's data.</p>
<p>Some environmentalists have pressed the government to introduce a so-called carbon tax on the energy sector. But Canadian Natural Resources Minister Anne McLellan said on Thursday that Canada has no plans to introduce such a tax.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
