<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256760" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: Sri Lanka Central Bank sees marked upturn in '97.</title>
<headline>Sri Lanka Central Bank sees marked upturn in '97.</headline>
<byline>Terry Friel</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sri Lanka's Central Bank governor said on Friday he saw a strong economic upturn in 1997, with accelerated growth, falling inflation and interest rates, and a budget deficit reduction strategy back on track.</p>
<p>Governor A.S. Jayawardena told Reuters he expected Sri Lanka, gripped by an ethnic war, to bounce back from a blowout in defence spending and a crippling power shortage that have constrained growth in 1996.</p>
<p>But he cautioned that power generation, heavily reliant on hydroelectricity and hit by drought this year, remained a possible obstacle to growth for this Indian Ocean island.</p>
<p>&quot;We are hopeful that next year we will resume our trend path of growth, which is what we are expecting,&quot; Jayawardena said in an interview.</p>
<p>&quot;But I think that basically after the drought ended and the power cuts ended, I think there have been signs of resumption in economic growth which you see in almost all indicators.&quot;</p>
<p>The government of President and Finance Minister Chandrika Kumaratunga, which has introduced economic reforms, wants to maintain gross domestic product growth around an average 6.0 percent a year.</p>
<p>Growth fell to an estimated 3.7 percent in calendar 1996 from 5.5 percent a year earlier, due mainly to the crippling mid-year power cuts and massive defence spending required to prosecute the war against Tamil separatists in the north and east.</p>
<p>&quot;Four percent is not considered a bad rate of growth, but for the Sri Lanka economy, with a targeted average of around six percent...possibly more than six percent if the war is over, it's not good enough,&quot; Jayawardena said.</p>
<p>Defence spending, the biggest single outlay, has blown out over budget by about 10 billion rupees (US$176 million) in each of the past two years, fuelled by procurement as Colombo modernised its forces.</p>
<p>But the upgrade is finished and Jayawardena said he expects defence spending to fall in 1997, putting Colombo's deficit-reduction strategy back on track and allowing the government to tackle inflation.</p>
<p>Colombo is battling to cut the deficit to 4.5 percent of GDP by 1999 from an average 13 percent over the past 20 years. It is projected at 7.3 percent, or 98 billion rupees, in 1997 from a higher-than-forecast 8.7 percent in 1996.</p>
<p>This strategy would be key to cutting inflation and bringing down interest rates, Jayawardena said.</p>
<p>He said inflation, which is running at 15 to 16 percent, was one of the economy's main problems, but added that &quot;indications are that it will come down to single digits by the middle of next year&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;So, by that time, I think a lot of things will get stabilised. Somewhere by the middle of next year, I think we will be out of the woods.&quot;</p>
<p>Kumaratunga's government sees sound management and a strong economy as essential to attracting vital foreign investment.</p>
<p>The state-owned Ceylon Electricity Board has sought to reassure business that there will be no power cuts in 1997 with predictions of sufficient rainfall and new capacity coming on line.</p>
<p>But Jayawardena said he feared growth in demand for power had been underestimated.</p>
<p>(US$1 = 56 rupees)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
