<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256792" id="root" date="1996-12-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: SOCCER-DUTCH TURN ON THE STYLE TO CONQUER BELGIUM 3-0.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DUTCH TURN ON THE STYLE TO CONQUER BELGIUM 3-0.</headline>
<byline>Bert Lauwers</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>First-half goals by Dennis Bergkamp and Clarence Seedorf four minutes apart steered the Netherlands to a comfortable 3-0 victory over arch-rivals Belgium in their World Cup qualifier on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Dutch, pre-match favourites after their 7-1 demolition of Wales last month, opened up a three-point lead in qualifying group seven over Belgium with the victory.</p>
<p>Bergkamp opened the scoring in the 25th minute when he beat both the offside trap and goalkeeper Filip De Wilde after picking up a long pass from Jaap Stam.</p>
<p>Seedorf then rifled the second into the roof of the net from the left after cleverly slipping the ball between the legs of Belgian defender Eric Van Meir.</p>
<p>Wim Jonk completed the rout when he converted a penalty kick in extra time after Newcastle United's Philippe Albert pulled down Marc Overmars, who had come on just two minutes earlier.</p>
<p>The Belgians' day was further soured four minutes after the break when Pascal Renier was sent off for felling Ronald de Boer just outside the penalty area.</p>
<p>Bergkamp and Seedorf had several clear chances in the last half hour to raise the tally of the Dutch who were almost constantly in command, but De Wilde stopped their efforts with a combination of skill and luck.</p>
<p>Revenge was sweet for the Dutch, who had lost the previous &quot;Derby of the low countries&quot;, in the first round of the 1994 World Cup, 1-0.</p>
<p>&quot;Belgium started strong but we scored at the right time and again right after,&quot; coach Guus Hiddink said. &quot;In the second half we should have finished it off but we were too nonchalant and the pitch was difficult. But we are satisfied that even on this difficult pitch we played very well as a team.&quot;</p>
<p>Wilfried Van Moer, who suffered his first defeat as Belgium coach after two wins and two draws since succeeding Paul Van Himst last year, said: &quot;Of course I'm disappointed but if you look at the Dutch team you know it's never a dishonour to lose against them.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We've moved a step closer to the 1998 World Cup in France,&quot; said Dutch striker Ronald de Boer, adding he did not see a single quality player on the Belgian side.</p>
<p>Belgium were indeed a pale shadow of the team that pulled off the surprise 1-0 win in 1994 and generally had little to offer against the superior Dutch, who have now won 54 of the 118 matches between the two sides against Belgium's 39.</p>
<p>Their best chance came just before Bergkamp's strike when Luc Nilis brushed a fine cross from the right to the head of Brazilian-born Luis Oliveira who just failed to connect.</p>
<p>But the Dutch displayed more flair and firepower and could easily have won by more.</p>
<p>Ronald de Boer fired just wide after beating the Belgian offside trap in the 28th minute and came close again in the 49th. But most of the attacking prowess belonged to Bergkamp and Seedorf, who ran the Belgian defence ragged.</p>
<p>Marc Degryse, Nilis, Stam and Aron Winter were all booked but the game was less heated than corresponding clashes in the past.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Belgium - 1-Filip De Wilde, 2-Eric Deflandre (18-Nordin Jbari 74), 3-Eric Van Meir, 4-Pascal Renier, 6-Philippe Albert, 5-Philippe Leonard (16-Nico Van Kerckhoven 34), 8-Marc Wilmots, 7-Lorenzo Staelens, 9-Marc Degryse (17-Frederic Pierre 62), 10-Luc Nilis, 11-Luis Oliveira</p>
<p>Netherlands - 1-Edwin van der Sar, 2-Michael Reiziger, 4-Frank de Boer, 3-Jaap Stam, 5-Arthur Numan, 7-Aron Winter, 6-Wim Jonk, 10-Clarence Seedorf, 11-Phillip Cocu, 8-Ronald de Boer (14-Marc Overmars 89), 9-Dennis Bergkamp (12-Patrick Kluivert 68)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
