<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256742" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>REPUBLIC OF IRELAND: EU ministers consider new proposal on EMU pact.</title>
<headline>EU ministers consider new proposal on EMU pact.</headline>
<dateline>DUBLIN 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>European Union finance ministers were considering a new proposal early on Friday to break a deadlock over details for budgetary discipline under a future single currency, EU diplomats said on Thursday.</p>
<p>The proposal, put together by the Irish EU presidency, sets a specific figure for the extent of an economic downswing which would save countries with excessive deficits from facing EU fines.</p>
<p>However, it would also leave the last word to the EU council of ministers as to whether to impose fines, the diplomats said.</p>
<p>Emergency finance ministers' talks in Dublin have been stalled by Germany's insistence on the automatic imposition of tough sanctions on countries with excessive deficits.</p>
<p>An earlier Belgian proposal, similar to the Irish plan, had also stressed that even if the ministers agreed on the economic conditions which would allow countries to avoid sanctions, the final judgement would be left up to EU governments.</p>
<p>The ministers are hoping to wrap up details of the stability pact in time to have them endorsed by EU leaders at a two-day summit starting here on Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBLIN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="REPUBLIC OF IRELAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
