<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256785" id="root" date="1996-12-13" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Ovitz steps down at Disney after clashes with chairman.</title>
<headline>Ovitz steps down at Disney after clashes with chairman.</headline>
<byline>Jerry Dubrowski</byline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-12-12</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hollywood powerbroker Michael Ovitz is leaving his post as president of entertainment giant Walt Disney Co. after a year of repeated clashes with Chairman Michael Eisner.</p>
<p>&quot;Michael Eisner has been my good friend for 25 years and that will not change, but it is important to recognise when something is not working. I hope that my decision to leave will eliminate an unnecessary distraction for a great company,&quot; Ovitz said in a statement.</p>
<p>Disney said it did not plan to announce a successor to Ovitz, hired in October, 1995, to help expand Disney's empire around the world, but that it will &quot;continue to operate organisationally as it did prior to his arrival.&quot;</p>
<p>Disney said Ovitz was leaving under a mutual agreement with the company, effective Jan. 31, and will serve as an advisor and consultant to Disney and its board of directors.</p>
<p>Ovitz's departure caps a rocky year in which he and Eisner, Disney's chief executive, struggled unsuccessfully to share power. According to sources, Ovitz told friends he was unhappy at Disney and was looking for another job.</p>
<p>&quot;I will miss Michael's energy, creativity and leadership at Disney,&quot; said Eisner.</p>
<p>&quot;We have been doing business together while being friends for many years and I know that both our personal and professional relationships will continue,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I am proud of the strong creative and management team that we have developed over the past decade,&quot; he said, adding, &quot;Disney will continue to develop new businesses and to maintain its leadership position in its existing businesses.&quot;</p>
<p>Ovitz, Hollywood's leading talent agent, was hired shortly after Disney agreed to acquire broadcasting giant Capital Cities/ABC Inc. for $19 billion in 1995.</p>
<p>Under terms of his five-year contract, Ovitz is entitled to a base salary of $1 million a year and bonus and stock options worth an estimated $100 million.</p>
<p>Industry analysts said it was unlikely Ovitz would receive a settlement package that high, particularly if he went to a rival studio. But it would still be substantial.</p>
<p>Cowen &amp; Co. analyst Harold Vogel said he was not surprised by talk of a rift between Eisner and Ovitz, both strong-willed executives who are used to running their own show.</p>
<p>&quot;The only surprise is the timing,&quot; he said. &quot;I had thought they would stay together a little bit longer.</p>
<p>Indeed, ever since the hiring of Ovitz, Hollywood has been rife with rumours of personality clashes with Eisner, with some reports saying Eisner has complained to other executives about Ovitz' lack of business knowledge.</p>
<p>This is the not first time Eisner has clashed with a top executive. Jeffrey Katzenberg, now a partner in the Dreamworks SKG studio, left Disney in 1994 when he failed to win the president's position after Frank Wells died earlier that year.</p>
<p>The latest incident reportedly involved Disney's plans to go ahead with a controversial film on the Dalai Lama even though it could jeopardise Disney's expansion plans in China. Chinese officials have reportedly expressed concern about the film, but officials in China have denied they threatened to block Disney's plans if the film is released.</p>
<p>Ovitz, who has travelled to China several times in connection with the expansion project, was also responsible for bringing the film's director Martin Scorsese to Disney.</p>
<p>One industry source said Eisner was upset with the way Ovitz handled the situation.</p>
<p>On Thursday, there were rumours Ovitz would take a job at Sony Corp.'s Sony Pictures unit or Viacom Inc., which owns the Paramount film studio and MTV, but officials from both companies denied the rumour.</p>
<p>A spokesman for Viacom confirmed that Ovitz met with Chairman Sumner Redstone earlier this week, but said they didn't discuss Ovitz's employment status at Disney.</p>
<p>Ovitz, co-founder of talent powerhouse Creative Artists Agency, was billed as the perfect partner to Eisner when he was hired last year. His knowledge of technology and talent were touted as key attributes and he was widely expected to lead Disney's expansion efforts overseas.</p>
<p>However, his first few months were rocky. He ruffled feathers at ABC when he became involved in the hiring of former NBC executive Jamie Tarses earlier this year and was rebuffed by Disney studio boss Joe Roth for meddling in movie deals with top Hollywood stars.</p>
<p>Some insiders say Ovitz has had a hard time adjusting to life in a corporation where he is not the ultimate deal maker.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-13"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-12"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
