<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256893" id="root" date="1996-12-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: 12th person dies in UK food poisoning outbreak.</title>
<headline>12th person dies in UK food poisoning outbreak.</headline>
<dateline>GLASGOW, Scotland 1996-12-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A 12th person has died in Britain's worst outbreak of food poisoning, officials said on Saturday.</p>
<p>An 84-year-old woman, who was among pensioners at a church lunch in Scotland where suspect meat pies were eaten last month, has died at a Glasgow hospital, the health officials said.</p>
<p>The 12 people to have died have all been elderly. Most of the cases are linked to two Scottish butcher's shops -- one of which recently won awards for its products.</p>
<p>More than 300 people have reported symptoms of the food poisoning, which can cause kidney failure in vulnerable people such as the elderly and young children. Doctors have confirmed more than 200 cases but say the number has stabilised.</p>
<p>A nurse who worked with hospital patients suffering from the bacteria has also contracted the infection, causing concern among health workers who hope it is an isolated case.</p>
<p>E coli is a bacteria normally found in the guts of cattle, sheep and people. It is usually harmless but one strain, known as 0157, can cause brain damage and kidney failure.</p>
<p>It gets into food via improper slaughtering techniques or through manure used as fertiliser.</p>
<p>Health officials say there has been a marked decline in the number of new cases of infection in the past few days, raising hopes that the outbreak has now been contained. But they say the condition of eight adults is still giving cause for concern.</p>
<p>The deadliest outbreak of E coli was in Canada, where 19 elderly people infected in a nursing home died in September 1985.</p>
<p>Eleven people, mostly schoolchildren, died in an outbreak in Japan in July and 9,500 became ill.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GLASGOW, Scotland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
