<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="256945" id="root" date="1996-12-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Amoco Corp. Mexico pipeline ready early 1997.</title>
<headline>Amoco Corp. Mexico pipeline ready early 1997.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>Amoco Corp.'s joint cross-border, liquified petroleum gas (LPG) pipeline project will be finished in the first three months of 1997, Amoco Oil de Mexico general director Jorge Pinon Cervera said Friday.</p>
<p>The $40 million project with state-owned Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex) will transport the LPG gas, propane and butane used widely in Mexican homes, from Hobbs, New Mexico through El Paso, Texas to Mendez, Chihuahua in Mexico.</p>
<p>Mexico's oil and gas monopoly has worked on the Mexican construction, while Amoco has constructed the U.S. side of the pipeline. Amoco provides about a third of Mexico's LPG gas, Pinon said in an interview with Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;Once the industrial infrastructure is set up, it should be easier and cheaper&quot; for Amoco to distribute LPG in northern Mexico, he said. Currently the gas is shipped by trucks across the border.</p>
<p>Although Mexico's Energy Ministry is encouraging private companies to build infraestructure for natural gas distribution, Pinon said such advances will probably only affect industrial areas and not diminish the high residential demand for LPG gas.</p>
<p>&quot;I think they are a long way off from expanding natural gas use ... that's why Amoco is investing in this project,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>While acknowledging natural gas, or methane gas, is a less contaminating fuel, Pinon said when handled properly, LPG gas can be safer than it is currently.</p>
<p>Amoco in Mexico is the third largest purchaser of Pemex crude oil, mostly Maya heavy crude, Pinon said. The company also supplies 30 to 40 percent of natural gas imports when Pemex imports natural gas, he said.</p>
<p>--Timna Tanners, Mexico City newsroom +525 728 7903</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
