<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257074" id="root" date="1996-12-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Jewell gets probation from state police agency -paper.</title>
<headline>Jewell gets probation from state police agency -paper.</headline>
<dateline>ATLANTA 1996-12-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>A state law enforcement agency has ordered former Olympic bomb suspect Richard Jewell to undergo probation before starting work as a policeman, a newspaper reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>The Atlanta Journal-Constitution said the sanction was approved by the Georgia Peace Officers Standards and Training Council (POST), which charged that Jewell failed to list his 1990 arrest for impersonating an officer on the request for certification he submitted to the agency that same year.</p>
<p>Unless Jewell appeals the decision, the newspaper added, a one-year probation period would begin upon his being hired by a police organisation in Georgia. POST is responsible for certifying all law enforcement officers in the state.</p>
<p>Jewell's attorneys were not immediately available to comment on the report. But the article quoted one of his lawyers as saying Jewell did nothing wrong and would appeal.</p>
<p>Jewell, a former Olympic security guard, became the subject of worldwide media attention as the only named suspect in the July 27 bombing at the Atlanta Olympic Games, which left two people dead and more than 100 injured.</p>
<p>He was cleared of suspicion by the Justice Department in October and has been considering suits against the federal government and the Journal-Constitution. He reached an out-of-court settlement with the NBC television network.</p>
<p>Jewell, who once worked as a sheriff's deputy, would like to return to a career in the private security industry, according to his attorneys.</p>
<p>The POST vote stems from an incident which took place six years ago in an apartment complex outside Atlanta, where Jewell was working as a security guard.</p>
<p>Quoting state records, the Journal-Constitution said Jewell got into a dispute with a local couple whom he threatened to arrest while claiming to be a sheriff's deputy from a nearby county. At the time, however, he was only a county jailer and had not yet been certified as a police officer by POST.</p>
<p>Jewell was arrested on a felony charge for impersonating an officer but later pleaded guilty to a lesser count of disorderly conduct.</p>
<p>The arrest was not listed on his Sept. 12, 1990, request for POST certification.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATLANTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
