<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257163" id="root" date="1996-12-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: PLO asks U.N. stop Israeli housing in E. Jerusalem.</title>
<headline>PLO asks U.N. stop Israeli housing in E. Jerusalem.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Palestine Liberation Organisation called on the Security Council on Friday to prevent Israel from carrying out plans to build 132 housing units for Jewish settlers in Arab East Jerusalem.</p>
<p>In a letter to council President Francesco Paolo Fulci, the PLO's U.N. observer, Nasser al-Kidwa, said Israel was &quot;following an illegal and dangerous path&quot; which violated the Fourth Geneva Convention and U.N. resolutions.</p>
<p>He also said Israel was violating a 1993 accord with the PLO in which they agreed to negotiate the status of Jerusalem, among other things, as part of a final settlement.</p>
<p>Al-Kidwa, who did not request a council meeting, said Israel's plan for the Ras al-Amud neighbourhood, inhabited by 11,000 Palestinians, &quot;is tampering with the sensitive and precarious issue of Jerusalem.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It is completely illegal under international law and relevant Security Council resolutions. It threatens to shatter the Middle East peace process and thus threaten international peace and security.&quot;</p>
<p>He said the council had the responsibility to act on behalf of the international community to &quot;prevent such developments, to protect the peace process and to guarantee respect for the council's resolutions&quot; and for international law.</p>
<p>&quot;Accordingly, we request that the council formally consider the matter and urgently take the necessary measures in this regard,&quot; he added.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
