<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257143" id="root" date="1996-12-14" xml:lang="en">
<title>VATICAN: Pope's clemency plea delivered to U.S. officials.</title>
<headline>Pope's clemency plea delivered to U.S. officials.</headline>
<dateline>VATICAN CITY 1996-12-14</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Vatican's top diplomat in the United States has passed on Pope John Paul's plea for clemency for a death row inmate to the U.S. government and Virginia Governor George Allen, a spokesman said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Chief Vatican spokesman Joaquin Navarro-Valls said the Vatican's nuncio (ambassador) in Washington &quot;has already forwarded the Pope's request to both the governor of Virginia and the federal government in Washington&quot;.</p>
<p>The Vatican had announced on Friday that the Pope had asked his ambassador in Washington to try to save the life of Joseph O'Dell, 55, who is scheduled to be executed in Virginia on December 18.</p>
<p>O'Dell was convicted in 1985 of murdering 44-year-old secretary Helen Schartner and sentenced to death.</p>
<p>Death penalty opponents worldwide have rallied round his case, pleading for a review of the DNA evidence which they say shows that blood found on his shirt does not match the victim's.</p>
<p>O'Dell has asked the U.S. Supreme Court to stay his execution pending a review of the DNA evidence, which his supporters say a court of appeals refused to admit because a submission deadline had expired.</p>
<p>In an encyclical last year, the Pope brought the Catholic Church the closest it has come to calling for a total ban on capital punishment, allowed by 38 U.S. states in murder cases.</p>
<p>The Pope acknowledged traditional Church teaching that allows capital punishment in extremely rare cases, but said such cases were practically non-existent in modern society.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-14"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-14"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VATICAN CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VATICAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
