<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257255" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-DUTCH AND SPANISH PROSPER BUT GERMANY DRAW AGAIN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-DUTCH AND SPANISH PROSPER BUT GERMANY DRAW AGAIN.</headline>
<byline>Gideon Long</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Netherlands and Spain inched closer towards the 1998 World Cup finals with impressive wins against quality opposition on Saturday but European champions Germany were held to a draw for the second match running.</p>
<p>The Dutch chalked up the night's finest scoreline -- a 3-0 win against Benelux neighbours Belgium in Brussels.</p>
<p>Arsenal striker Dennis Bergkamp and Real Madrid's Clarence Seedorf did the damage with two goals in the space of four minutes mid-way through the first half. Wim Jonk completed a comfortable victory from the penalty spot in injury time.</p>
<p>Victory for the Dutch revenged their 1-0 defeat at the hands of their rivals in the U.S. World Cup in 1994, and, alongside their 7-1 thrashing of Wales last month, suggests the Dutch are back to their best after a disappointing European championship in June.</p>
<p>&quot;Belgium started strong but we scored at the right time and again right after,&quot; coach Guus Hiddink said. &quot;In the second half we should have finished it off but we were too nonchalant and the pitch was difficult. But we are satisfied that even on this difficult pitch we played very well as a team.&quot;</p>
<p>Wilfried Van Moer, who suffered his first defeat as Belgium coach after two wins and two draws since succeeding Paul Van Himst last year, said: &quot;Of course I'm disappointed but if you look at the Dutch team you know it's never a dishonour to lose against them.&quot;</p>
<p>The Netherlands are now three points clear of second-placed Belgium at the top of group seven.</p>
<p>Belgium police detained 123 supporters, most of them Dutch, before and during the match and said 13 arrests were likely to result in charges. One Belgian was slightly hurt when he was punched in the face by a Dutch fan.</p>
<p>In Valencia, Spain carved out a fine 2-0 victory against Yugoslavia thanks to Barcelona midfielder Josep Guardiola, drafted into the team at short notice because of injury to Real Madrid defender Fernando Hierro.</p>
<p>Guardiola scored the first goal from the penalty spot and set up teenager Raul Gonzalez for the second.</p>
<p>The result means Spain close the gap on Yugoslavia at the top of the group to two points. It was the first defeat in the qualifying stage for the visitors, who have 12 points from five games.</p>
<p>&quot;We shouldn't forget that we have to go and play in Yugoslavia,&quot; said a cautious coach Javier Clemente, whose side travel to Malta for another qualifying game next week.</p>
<p>In the day's other big match, Germany failed to win for the second World Cup match in a row following their shock 1-1 home draw with Northern Ireland last month.</p>
<p>Portugal, the only side ever to beat Germany in a World Cup qualifier, nearly did it again but had to settle finally for a spirited 0-0 draw.</p>
<p>&quot;I am happy with the result,&quot; German coach Berti Vogts said. We had our chances in the first half but the second half was more exciting and Portugal showed that they are a good side.&quot;</p>
<p>The result leaves Portugal top of European qualifying group nine with eight points from five games, with Germany in third on five points, a point behind Ukraine in second.</p>
<p>The Germans and Ukraine have played two fewer games than Portugal.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BENLUX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
