<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257388" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Belgrade sees biggest opposition rally so far.</title>
<headline>Belgrade sees biggest opposition rally so far.</headline>
<byline>Jovan Kovacic</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>A record 250,000 people marched through Belgrade on Sunday in the 28th day of protests against alleged government election fraud and in an important development a court restored an opposition victory in one city.</p>
<p>&quot;This is bigger than Saturday's protest,&quot; a reporter for independent Belgrade radio B92 radio said of the capital's mass rally. &quot;It's the biggest so far, it's enormous,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>More than 200,000 people had marched on Saturday and opposition leaders were euphoric about Sunday's turnout.</p>
<p>In a breakthrough for the opposition a court in the southern city of Nis ordered the city's election commission to hand back victory won in the elections to leaders of the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition.</p>
<p>Demonstrations spread across the country to 30 towns, 13 more than on Saturday posing an increasingly vocal challenge to President Slobodan Milosevic's rule.</p>
<p>Zajedno leader Zoran Djindjic vowed the daily marches would continue until Milosevic reversed the alleged fraud at November local elections which enabled the ruling socialists to claim victory over Zajedno in 14 out of Serbia's 18 biggest cities, including the capital.</p>
<p>The carnival atmosphere in Belgrade, with music playing, flags waving and firework rockets shooting into the night sky, belied the serious message from Zajedno that it wanted annulled election results reinstated.</p>
<p>&quot;Our protests will last until Serbia becomes a legal state,&quot; Djindjic told Reuters. &quot;Today we have been informed that elections results have been reinstated in Nis,&quot; said Djindjic, adding he hoped this trend would continue.</p>
<p>&quot;We cannot allow ourselves to get a new dictator every five years -- we want full-scale democracy,&quot; Djindjic said.</p>
<p>The Nis district court upheld Zajedno's appeal and ordered the city election commission effectively to endorse the opposition victory, local Zajedno leader Zoran Zivkovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;This shows that we might be after all on the road to justice,&quot; Zajedno leader Vesna Pesic told the Belgrade rally with the British rock group Queen's lyrics &quot;We Are The Champions&quot; playing over the sound system.</p>
<p>A group of 17 students from Nis on Sunday started a 230-km (145-mile) protest march to Belgrade to hand what they said were forged election papers to Milosevic on Tuesday.</p>
<p>After the Belgrade rally dispersed tens of thousands of students set off on a smaller march around the streets of Belgrade carrying lights, torches or wearing miners' torches strapped to their heads.</p>
<p>A student spokesman said their intention was &quot;to enlighten a city in political darkness&quot;.</p>
<p>They were cheered along the route by bystanders and people waving from windows and balconies, switching off and on the electric lights in their homes in gestures of support.</p>
<p>Milosevic has remained largely silent apart from inviting a team of the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) to look into the matter.</p>
<p>Diplomats believe this could be a way for Milosevic to save face, but it remains to be seen whether he would accept its verdict whatever it might be.</p>
<p>Reflecting Washington's concern about the government's handling of the elections and their aftermath, U.S. Assistant Secretary of State for European Affairs John Kornblum was to meet Serbian opposition leaders in Geneva on Sunday.</p>
<p>Kornblum is in Geneva to take part in a meeting on Monday on refugees and other humanitarian issues in Bosnia.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
