<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257333" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FEATURE - Ballymena troubles reveal depth of N.Irish divide.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - Ballymena troubles reveal depth of N.Irish divide.</headline>
<byline>Helen Smith</byline>
<dateline>BALLYMENA, Northern Ireland 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Catholic Church of Our Lady in Harryville is surrounded by a high, spiked steel fence. There are metal grilles on the windows.</p>
<p>This Catholic community has always felt under siege, but never more so than in the past three months.</p>
<p>The 300 worshippers who attend mass at Our Lady's now have to battle their way through an angry Protestant mob, braving abuse and even volleys of fireworks to get to church.</p>
<p>Catholic homes in the area, a suburb of the prosperous Northern Irish town of Ballymena, have been firebombed and one woman was dragged from her car and beaten after she left a Saturday evening service.</p>
<p>A Catholic school near the church has also been set on fire. &quot;It is extremely intimidating,&quot; said Canon Sean Connolly.</p>
<p>&quot;The congregation sits in the church listening to the chanting knowing they have to go out and face it again. It is hardly the background for an act of worship.&quot;</p>
<p>PROBLEMS DATE FROM ORANGE MARCHES</p>
<p>The problems began in September after a Protestant &quot;Orange order&quot; was banned from marching through the Catholic village of Dunloy, some 15 miles (24 km) from largely Protestant Ballymena.</p>
<p>The march was one of several in the province over the summer that were banned or diverted to avoid conflict with Catholic communities, who see the parades as provocative.</p>
<p>The orders take their name and regalia from William of Orange, the Protestant king who defeated Catholic King James II in the 1690 Battle of the Boyne, beginning a long period of Protestant domination of Ireland.</p>
<p>To Northern Ireland's nationalists, the marchers with their English-style bowler hats, orange sashes and pipes and drums, are glorying in Britain's continued rule of the province.</p>
<p>When the marches were banned there was outrage from Protestants, who fear that a peace process spawned by the British and Irish governments could end up going in the nationalists' favour and leaving them under Dublin's rule.</p>
<p>Riots broke out in many towns and villages. In Drumcree, south of Belfast, an Orange march was first banned and then allowed to go ahead after angry protests.</p>
<p>The result was some of the worst violence in Northern Ireland's history. In one night alone, 900 firebombs were thrown and three police were injured.</p>
<p>The cost of the Drumcree standoff, which lasted for several days, has been put at 40 million pounds ($66 million).</p>
<p>INCREASED SPENDING ON SECURITY</p>
<p>Although Protestant guerrillas have been honouring a ceasefire for more than two years and the Irish Republican Army (IRA) has so far carried out only one succesful bomb attack in the province since ending its own truce in February, the government has decided to increase spending on security here.</p>
<p>Britain's Northern Ireland minister, Sir Patrick Mayhew, announced a 120 million pound increase in expenditure on security over the next three years, signalling that Britain has few hopes of an end to sectarian violence in the province.</p>
<p>He called the Drumcree violence &quot;a grievous and wanton self-inflicted wound&quot;, which had detracted funds from areas such as education and welfare.</p>
<p>According to Richard English of Queen's University in Belfast, the peace process has served merely to deepen hostility between Northern Ireland's rival communities.</p>
<p>&quot;The nationalists' hopes that their demands will be met have been raised unreasonably, while the Protestants are afraid that too much has been conceded to the nationalists,&quot; said English.</p>
<p>The growing entrenchment on the unionist side was made plain last week when the Orange orders appointed a right-wing traditionalist as their new grand master.</p>
<p>Robert Saulters was best known for calling Labour Party leader Tony Blair a &quot;turncoat&quot; for marrying a Catholic.</p>
<p>&quot;(Blair) would sell his soul to the devil himself,&quot; Saulters told supporters earlier this year.</p>
<p>MOVES TO DEFUSE MARCHING SEASON TENSION</p>
<p>Last week Northern Irish police announced proposals to try to take the heat out of the annual marching season, but immediately ran into problems with Protestant leaders who saw them as an infringement of their rights.</p>
<p>Under the proposals, a tribunal with representatives from both communities would decide on the route a parade could take and the organisers of the march would have to pay a hefty deposit which would be forfeited if violence broke out.</p>
<p>A third of the report was given over to objections to the proposals from Protestants on the police panel.</p>
<p>In Harryville, one of the biggest problems for police is that they have been unable to identify the organisers of the anti-Catholic protests.</p>
<p>A mysterious, previously unknown group, has issued pamphlets in the name of the Harryville Resident's Association, but police say they could be local people, Orange Order leaders, or agitators from Belfast. They don't know.</p>
<p>Catholics make up only two percent of the population in Harryville and opposite the church is graffiti celebrating Protestant guerrilla groups.</p>
<p>But otherwise there is little evidence that the area -- rows of narrow streets of public housing -- is Protestant and Ballymena's council leaders say there is no history of sectarian violence here.</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, the town's Protestant Mayor James Currie led a vigil outside Our Lady's, which helped to subdue the protesters.</p>
<p>But local Catholics were sceptical. &quot;How come he's only coming now, when the television cameras are here?&quot; asked one. ($1=.6056 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BALLYMENA, Northern Ireland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
