<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257437" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - Dec 16.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - Dec 16.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>Telstra officials are blaming a flat economy for the company's shortfall in sales, as it prepares for partial privatisation. As small businesses disconnect lines and consumers reduce spending on international and domestic long distance calls, Telstra senior management has issued a revenue alert to all the company's business units. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Foreign banks are using different strategies to capture new ground in the multi-billion-dollar Australian market, ensuring the fruitless approaches used by foreign banks in the Australian market in the 1980s are not repeated. Foreign banks are now emphasising alliances, partnerships and strategic acquisitions in what should be a bigger and more successful campaign. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The federal government is under strong pressure from Queensland Federal MPs and the National Party to accept the findings of a report on sugar industry deregulation, which include the abolition of the sugar tariff on July 1 next year and retention of ingle-desk selling - the Queensland Sugar Corp's monopoly over Queensland raw sugar exports. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In talks with the Australian Broadcasting Authority, Canadian media proprietor Izzy Asper is expected to say that his move to lift his stake in the Ten Network to around 76 percent was designed purely to facilitate the A$1 billion-plus stockmarket float of the broadcaster by removing shareholders with differing views on Ten's float from the register. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Highlands Gold Ltd and Placer Dome Inc may meet in the courts this week because of a battle over the level of disclosure in Placer's A$423 million takeover document. Highlands threatened legal action last week if Placer did not supply further details of its share offer and Placer president John Wilson said yesterday that the company had complied &quot;with each and every legal obligation in relation to the conduct of this offer&quot;. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although stockbroker Ord Minnett Ltd remains unaware of the identity of the mystery trader in TNT Ltd options, or how to contact him, the broking house has received written correspondence from the so-called Mark Booth which says he will comply with the Federal Court's orders for the Australian Securities Commission to seize the A$1.98 million profit he made from his A$90,000 investment. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>BHP's interim net profit should be lifted by robust earnings and asset sales within its petroleum division to see it at about A$820 million, which will offset weaker returns from the struggling steel and copper divisions. The half-year results will be released on Friday. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Treasury secretary Ted Evans has declined an invitation to attend a debate between a number of superannuation industry leaders over the Wallis Inquiry in Sydney tomorrow. The superannuation industry is unhappy with Department of Treasury plans which could see a range of protections inside superannuation being dropped in favour of an increased emphasis on product disclosure. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Profit for General Motors Holden's is expected to be stripped by up to 15 percent because of marketing and product investments. Despite the fact that GMH last year hit a record profit of A$260 million on sales of A$3 billion, chairman and managing director Bill Hamel still predicts the company would be Australia's most profitable car maker again this year. Page 17.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australia's information technology industry should benefit from Australia's participation in the information technology agreement negotiated at last week's World Trade Organisation talks. Exports could be boosted by millions of dollars over the next 10 years and there could be further benefits from a commitment by the 127 WTO countries to reach agreement within two months to free up world trade in basic telecommunications products. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In one of the last disposals of assets of Kern Corp, KPMG, as Kern Corp receiver, has sold two Coles Myer distribution centres - one at Somersby to Prime Industrial Property Trust for A$13 million, and another at Goulburn to investment bank Babcock and Brown for A$9.5 million. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Despite the official cut in interest rates last week by the Reserve Bank, earning forecasts for some of Australia's leading companies should remain the same. Austock Brokers research director David Perry says that while retailing and building sectors will benefit the most from the rate cut, the impact on profits this financial year should be minor. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>It is believed Canadian media proprietor Izzy Asper, head of CanWest Global Communications  CWW.TO, plans a A$260 million float of part of the Ten Network to appease the Australian Broadcasting Authority over his controversial share dealings. The proposal would see CanWest sell down from 76 percent back to its original interest of 57.5 percent by setting up a sharemarket-listed unit trust. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>New chief executive of Coles Myer , Dennis Eck, has kept quiet through the company's controversies of 1995, and was rewarded with the announcement of his position to begin on January 1. As former head of Coles' supermarkets division, American-born Eck has been able to use his U.S. experience to improve profitability and expand the supermarket's range of products. Page 35.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>St George Bank will attempt to lift the support of Advance Bank shareholders for its A$2.65 billion takeover offer to ensure any legal challenge that the National Australia Bank may contemplate will not obstruct the merger. As St George's largest sharehlder, NAB does not want the Advance takeover to proceed as it will make its own takeover aspirations for St George more problematic. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Elizabeth Connell, the widow of former Rothwells head Laurie Connell, will be examined in the Federal Court by the lawyers for the trustee for Connell's bankrupt estate, Ross Norgard, about the transfer of assets, including the A$3 million Connell mansion in Peppermint Grove. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following Seven Network's access to confidential documents last week, the television group is considering stepping up the legal attack against its fellow Optus Vision shareholders. The documents relate to a deal between Publishing and Broadcasting, Optus Communications, and Continental Cable Vision in April. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Institute of Chartered Accountants claims the shrinking tax base for consumption of goods and the change in consumption patterns will force a rethink of a goods and services tax. In a report by the ICA, &quot;GST: The Long, Winding Road&quot;, the ICA said that with changes in the Australian lifestyle, Australians are spending more on recreation and entertainment and this is having a serious impact on tax revenue as less tax is obtained from goods. Page 37.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Hoping to end an Australian Broadcasting Authority investigation into CanWest Global Communications'  CWW.TO recent activities on the Ten Network share register, Canadian media proprietor Izzy Asper is expected to outline a proposal to sell down his 76 percent sake in Ten back to 57.5 percent by setting up a sharemarket-listed unit trust. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Recently obtaining injunctions against Matthew Howden and another colleague Mark Pascoe, the Queensland Consumer Affairs office has revealed that credit card company International Credit Card Services holds links to Howden, who was the principal of a failed travel business that left interstate tourists stranded with unpaid accommodation on the Gold Coast. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Dennis Eck's status as an outsider worked well for him when Coles Myer sank into a glut of scandal and intrigue in 1995. Leaving the United States three years ago to join Coles Myer in Melbourne, Eck last week was rewarded by being appointed managing dirctor and chief executive of the group which generates revenue of over A$18 billion a year. Page C2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Nord Pacific and Straits Resources say recent drilling results have improved the development prospects for the jointly-owned Tritton copper project in central New South Wales. The results increased the resource to 9.75 million tonnes grading 3.01 percent copper. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Reacting to Highlands Gold's threat of legal action, Placer Dome president and chief executive John Wilson said yesterday that the company had complied with every legal obligation in relation to its hostile takeover bid of 75 cents a share for the Papua New Guinean gold producer. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After spending A$500,000 in six months coming up with an appealing and different flavour and a catchy name - DNA - accountant Simon Williams launched his own alternative alcoholic &quot;soft&quot; drink in Adelaide last October. Since then, more than 500,000 cases of the clear lime and thyme flavoured drink have been sold in South Australia and Western Australia. Page C3.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2-9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
