<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257498" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam's Kiet says reforms, leadership on track.</title>
<headline>Vietnam's Kiet says reforms, leadership on track.</headline>
<byline>Adrian Edwards</byline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam's prime minister Vo Van Kiet has denied speculation about a looming leadership crisis as the country's president lies seriously ill in a Hanoi hospital.</p>
<p>In a rare official interview ahead of the weekend, the 74-year-old prime minister and proponent of economic reforms, told Reuters that Vietnam remained on track with its Doi Moi (renovation) and open-door policies launched in the late 1980s.</p>
<p>&quot;What I want to stress is that there will in no way be a reverse in our policy of renovation. No matter how the leadership may be in the future that will cause no obstacle in this process,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;In the near future,&quot; he added, &quot;if, because of our president's health condition, he is unable to continue his duties, then we will have a new president because the country cannot exist without a president as head of that country... &quot;</p>
<p>Kiet, who has served as prime minister since 1991, said he too was ready to step down if called upon to do so, and stressed that any leadership changes would be conducted smoothly.</p>
<p>&quot;Many people think of the term 'power struggle',&quot; he said, then asked this correspondent, &quot;(But) since you are based here, since you have been working here, I wonder whether you have noticed any power struggle in our country?&quot;</p>
<p>At 74 years, Kiet looked fit and at ease, and immediately following the interview donned sports clothes for a game of tennis next to Hanoi's prime ministerial White House, the interview venue.</p>
<p>During the 50-minute discussion, however, he spoke at length of the need for politicians to listen to the views of the Vietnamese people, in order to meet their aspirations.</p>
<p>In a written statement issued just before the meeting began he referred to oriental philosophy in which &quot;people are the root&quot; and said the success of Vietnam's reform process would continue to hinge on its ability to tap popular backing.</p>
<p>He conceded, however, that differing views had emerged within the country's communist government about the speed and even the merits of the reform process, but described this as normal and healthy.</p>
<p>&quot;If we do anything which runs counter to the interests of our people the result will be a reaction of the people,&quot; he said. &quot;And that reaction won't be small...&quot;</p>
<p>Vietnam introduced market-oriented reform policies 10 years ago in place of a failed command-led system which had brought the communist country close to economic collapse.</p>
<p>The result, beginning a couple of years later, has been an economic lift-off, new openness, and improved living standards for many.</p>
<p>The country, previously viewed as an international pariah, has also developed new-found diplomatic respect resulting in billions of dollars in aid pledges -- and indirectly in substantial interest from foreign investors.</p>
<p>However, after several years of successes the past year has been clouded by outward appearances of political drift as the country assesses the results, and not all palatable ones, of ten years of capitalist-style reforms.</p>
<p>News last month that President Le Duc Anh, 76, had been hospitalised following a stroke sounded alarms among diplomats and investors concerned about the political ramifications of an unplanned leadership change.</p>
<p>Anh, a general, is a powerful behind-the-scenes operator in a leadership triumvirate which includes Kiet and Communist Party chief Do Muoi. Analysts have said his departure could precipitate broader changes among top-level personnel.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
