<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257522" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan trade groups unhappy with insurance deal.</title>
<headline>Japan trade groups unhappy with insurance deal.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japanese insurance trade groups were less than enthusiastic on Sunday over the agreement with the United States aimed at further opening the domestic market to foreign competition.</p>
<p>They said the United States had taken unreasonable positions in the talks and that more consultation was necessary to ensure any changes did not harm consumers.</p>
<p>&quot;We could not help but feel anger over the very irrational requests by the United States,&quot; said Takeo Iguchi, president of the Marine and Fire Insurance Association of Japan.</p>
<p>He said the U.S. arguments have &quot;totally neglected the benefits to consumers from the current system.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts have said the liberalisation in areas such as auto insurance would offer lower rates for some consumers but push up costs for others deemed to be at a higher risk.</p>
<p>&quot;We hope that liberalisation of the insurance market will be fully discussed at the insurance council (an advisory panel to the finance minister), from the viewpoint of protecting accident victims,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Industry officials were also upset at the delay in the entry of the big Japanese companies into the specialty &quot;third sector&quot; where foreign companies have made some headway.</p>
<p>&quot;It is quite regrettable that the life insurers' non-life subsidiaries will be restricted, as we have always called for completely free entry into the new sector,&quot; said Kenjiro Hata, president of the Life Insurance Association.</p>
<p>Although the specifics of the plan have not been announced, government officials say it will allow Japanese companies into the area of accident insurance beginning in January but will continue to exclude them from such areas as cancer insurance and medical insurance until January 2001.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
