<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257564" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>TUNISIA: By-elections in Tunisia for two parliament seats.</title>
<headline>By-elections in Tunisia for two parliament seats.</headline>
<dateline>TUNIS 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>By-elections were held on Sunday in Tunisia for two seats in parliament, with the opposition certain to win one.</p>
<p>The ruling party the Consititutional Democratic Rallye (RCD) is not running for the Ben Arous seat where four opposition candidates competed to replace jailed Khemais Chammari.</p>
<p>Chammari, Vice-President of the main opposition party Democrat Socialist's Movement (MDS), lost his seat after a court sentenced him to five years in prison last July for disclosing judicial secrets.</p>
<p>The RCD would have won the Ben Arous seat because of the weakeness of the opposition parties, but apparently decided to leave it in the hands of the opposition.</p>
<p>The second seat was in the southern city of Medenine where RCD's candidate Belgacem Bouaouaja is expected to win easily against a candidate of the small opposition Parti Social Liberal.</p>
<p>An amendment to the electoral code reserved 19 of the 163 seats in parliament at the March 1994 general elections for legal opposition parties. The next presidential and parliamentarian elections are due in 1999.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TUNIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TUNIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TUNISIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
