<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257524" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Salomon sets neutral weighting for S'pore market.</title>
<headline>Salomon sets neutral weighting for S'pore market.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Singapore stock market retained its neutral weighting as concerns in the exchange about the near-term growth outlook for the country lingered, the Weekly Pacific Perspective report by Salomon Brothers said.</p>
<p>While the basic fundamentals in Singapore of low inflation, stable interest and exchange rates, and strong external balances remain solid, fixed investment growth has deteriorated and worries over the economy continue to linger, a copy of the report made available on Sunday said.</p>
<p>&quot;Without an end to these concerns, the market's near upside potential is likely to be limited,&quot; the report said.  </p>
<p>On a valuation basis, the Singapore market is inexpensive particularly with regard to domestic interest rates and U.S. long bonds.</p>
<p>&quot;In a regional ranking of markets by valuation, Singapore ranks the third most attractive, after Korea and Taiwan. However, value measures alone are not always a useful guide to prospective market performance. The market's upside potential has been capped by fears of growth deceleration,&quot; the Salomon Brothers report said.</p>
<p>The short-term momentum in the market has improved, but on low volume, the report said.  </p>
<p>The benchmark Strait Times Industrials Index ended on Friday 3.41 points down at 2,179.14. Singapore-based dealers predict the index will move in a narrow range between 2,150-2,200 points until the end of this year.</p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
