<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257629" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Tom Cruise heads U.S. box office with &quot;Jerry Maguire&quot;.</title>
<headline>Tom Cruise heads U.S. box office with &quot;Jerry Maguire&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>LOS ANGELES 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>The new Tom Cruise movie &quot;Jerry Maguire&quot; opened at the top of the U.S. box office over the weekend with $17.5 million, according to studio estimates released Sunday.</p>
<p>The quirky comedy, in which Cruise plays a sports agent who changes his cut-throat ways, is the biggest non-sequel opening in the Christmas period, said a spokesman at TriStar Pictures, which is releasing the film.</p>
<p>The previous record was held by the Julia Roberts drama &quot;The Pelican Brief,&quot; which opened in December 1993 with $16.8 million, the spokesman said. TriStar is a unit of Sony Corp. .</p>
<p>Opening in second was the schlocky alien invasion picture &quot;Mars Attacks!&quot; with $9.7 million, while third place went to &quot;101 Dalmatians,&quot; which had held the top spot for two weeks. &quot;Dalmatians&quot; made $8.75 million this weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;The Preacher's Wife,&quot; a holiday-themed picture starring Denzel Washington and Whitney Houston, opened in fourth with $7.4 million. In its second weekend, the low-end Sylvester Stallone action flick &quot;Daylight&quot; slipped three places to fifth with $4.1 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Jerry Maguire,&quot; which was directed by Cameron Crowe (&quot;Singles,&quot; &quot;Say Anything&quot;) won overwhelming kudos from critics. A Variety poll of reviewers in New York, Los Angeles, Washington, DC and Chicago showed 41 liked it, six did not and 12 were mixed.</p>
<p>The TriStar spokesman said the studio had expected &quot;Jerry Maguire&quot; to open with $12 million to $15 million in sales, and was delighted with the outcome. Despite the sports theme, it was playing to slightly more females than males. It was also cutting across racial and geographic boundaries, he said.</p>
<p>Critics were less kind to the other two new entries in the top 10. The Variety score for &quot;Mars Attacks!&quot; was 14 in favor, 16 against and 19 mixed. &quot;The Preacher's Wife&quot; came in with 15 in favor, 11 against and 13 mixed.</p>
<p>&quot;Mars Attacks!&quot; is released by Warner Bros., a unit of Time Warner Inc., &quot;101 Dalmatians&quot; and &quot;The Preacher's Wife&quot; by Walt Disney Co., and &quot;Daylight&quot; by Universal Pictures, a unit of Seagram Co. Ltd..</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34540">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I42400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LOS ANGELES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
