<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257688" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German tax reform might be gradually phased in.</title>
<headline>German tax reform might be gradually phased in.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Parts of a major reform of Germany's tax system scheduled for 1999 may have to be introduced after the planned start date, leading German coalition government figures said on Sunday.</p>
<p>Michael Glos, parliamentary leader of finance minister Theo Waigel's Christian Social Union, said the core points of a plan for huge income tax cuts would be implemented by 1999.</p>
<p>&quot;But one or other (of the reforms) might not be quite so easily financed as we imagine,&quot; he told German radio, adding that any remaining parts of the plan would be put into effect in 2000 and 2001.</p>
<p>Waigel himself had told journalists on the borders of the European Union summit in Dublin on Saturday that a phased-in approach was &quot;conceivable&quot;.</p>
<p>Neither Waigel or Glos said which parts of the reform might have to wait until after 1999.</p>
<p>Chancellor Helmut Kohl's three-party alliance wants to make income tax cuts to boost Germany's economy in a move which could result in some 100 billion marks of lost revenue.</p>
<p>Tighter controls on tax evasion are expected to offset some of the loss coming from the reform, the full proposals of which are due to be announced early next year.</p>
<p>Waigel favours cutting the entry income tax rate to around 20 percent from 26 percent and reducing the top tax bracket from 53 percent to 40 percent.</p>
<p>Kohl's CDU party wants value added tax to rise by two percentage points, a move which has met with strong opposition.</p>
<p>Rudolf Scharping, parliamentary leader for the opposition Social Democrats (SPD), said in a newspaper interview his party would oppose any increase in value added tax, which is often seen as hitting poorer people hardest.</p>
<p>&quot;We need tax reductions for the wide majority contributors in Germany,&quot; he told the Bild am Sonntag newspaper.</p>
<p>SPD party leader Oskar Fontaine told German radio on Sunday that a tax reform that reduced the burden on low-earners was not only fair but &quot;made economic sense&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
