<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257612" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Major stock movements overnight - Dec 16.</title>
<headline>Major stock movements overnight - Dec 16.</headline>
<text>
<p>NEW YORK - Blue-chip stocks closed slightly higher Friday after jitters over rising long-term interest rates sent the market reeling in the last two days.</p>
<p>Based on early and unofficial data, the Dow Jones industrial average ended up 1.16 points at 6,304.87, steadying from back-to-back losses totalling 170 points. In the broader market, declining issues led advances 14-10 on active volume of 457 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>- - - -  </p>
<p>LONDON - UK shares finished lower on Friday but well above the day's worst levels as Wall Street stocks turned higher after a choppy start in New York. The FTSE, still under the spell of Wall Street after last Friday's sell-off, ended 18.3 points lower at 3,972.4 a gain of 9.4 from last Friday.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>FRANKFURT - German shares close bourse trade just off session lows as uncertainty remains after Wall Street nosedive. Tentative afternoon trade seen with all eyes on U.S. stock market opening for next direction. The DAX index ended down 47.37 points at 2,799.71 a rise of 7.81 since last Friday. In  </p>
<p>post-bourse trade the index fell 31.17 to 2,815.77.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>PARIS - French stocks closed lower on Friday, but above their session lows, after Wall Street appeared to be recovering from the previous day's slide which triggered selloffs in equities markets around the world. The blue-chip CAC-40 index finished down 8.70 points, or 0.39 percent, at 2,203.41 down 37.31 from a week ago.</p>
<p>- - - -  </p>
<p>ZURICH - Swiss shares recovered from a weak bias in late trade but fell off of their highest levels to close lower after Wall Street posted early losses. The all share SPI fell 10.55 points to close at 2,454.68 up 4.01 since last week.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>TOKYO - The Tokyo stock market's key benchmark bounced back somewhat by the end of the Friday session to above the 20,000 threshold, after plunging by nearly 550 points earlier due to weakness on Wall Street overnight. The Nikkei 225 finished 159.81 points or 0.78 percent down at 20,341.39 up 64.69 since last Friday.  </p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>HONG KONG - Hong Kong stocks slid to a weak close on Friday afternoon, dragged down chiefly by nervousness in the outlook for international equity markets. The Hang Seng Index closed down 269.21 points, or 2.06 percent, at 12,784.07 a drop of 318.66 on the week.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>SYDNEY - The Australian share market ended on Friday with its third consecutive fall in response to the overnight plunge on Wall Street, but investors regained some confidence in the afternoon session. The All Ordinaries index closed 23.1 points  </p>
<p>or almost one percent lower at 2,316.5 a rise of 2.6 from a week ago.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JOHANNESBURG - South African shares ended weak in active trade, with the industrial and all-share indices shedding over 100 points in negative sentiment. Golds were softer ignoring a higher rand gold price. Industrial index off 132.2 points to 7,682.5 down 112.7 on the week, all-share loses 124.5 to 6,482.5 down 118.7 from last week and golds off 21.6 to 1,511.6 a fall of 16.4 from Friday week.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
