<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257676" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Creditanstalt battle heats up as deadline looms.</title>
<headline>Creditanstalt battle heats up as deadline looms.</headline>
<byline>Knut Engelmann</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Political infighting over the sale of Austrian sell-off candidate Creditanstalt continued on Sunday, one day before the latest tender in the six-year privatisation was about to close.</p>
<p>The battle for the country's flagship bank took a nasty turn on Friday when the Austrian parliament called on the government to reject a bid by arch-rival Bank Austria, opening a deep rift in the ruling centre-left coalition.  </p>
<p>The motion was whipped through with the votes of the conservative People's Party (OeVP), the Social Democrat's (SPOe) junior coalition partner, and the far-right Freedom Party. The SPOe, together with the opposition Liberals and Greens, voted against it.</p>
<p>&quot;We won't let ourselves be forced into new elections. But on the other hand, you can't reject a good offer just for the sake of (political) peace,&quot; SPOe chief whip Peter Kostelka told Austrian news agency APA. &quot;Our patience has been exhausted.&quot;  </p>
<p>Parliament called for a &quot;speedy and complete privatisation&quot; of both Creditanstalt and Bank Austria.</p>
<p>Bank Austria, which is effectively controlled by the City of Vienna and has close links to the SPOe, last week emerged as a last-minute bidder for the state's 70 percent voting stake in Creditanstalt, traditionally a stronghold of the conservatives.</p>
<p>The bid rivalled a lone offer by an Austro-Italian-German consortium led by insurer EA-Generali, which is openly favoured by the conservatives.  </p>
<p>The group has offered some 10 billion schillings for about two-thirds of the government's 19.9 million voting shares in Creditanstalt and wants to sell the rest on the market. Bank Austria has offered 16 billion schillings for the total.</p>
<p>Finance Minister Viktor Klima over the weekend added a new twist to the seemingly endless sell-off saga, saying he had received a third bid for the bank. &quot;It comes neither from Bank Austria nor from the EA-Generali consortium,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The identity of all three bidders is expected to be released on Monday.  </p>
<p>Klima, the third finance minister in succession to attempt the sale of Creditanstalt, has repeatedly said he wants to wrap up the privatisation before year-end.</p>
<p>Conservatives have balked at the prospect of the flagship bank being taken over by a socialist-controlled rival, supporting Creditanstalt executives and thousands of employees who turned out in force on Friday to protest against a possible takeover by Bank Austria.  </p>
<p>Creditanstalt employees feared they would be more likely to lose their jobs since, by a quirk of Austrian law, employees of Bank Austria are protected from dismissal, effectively putting them in the same league as public servants.</p>
<p>The two banks' combined staff amounts to more than 14,000, prompting analysts to speculate a merger would result in some 4,000 to 5,000 job cuts.</p>
<p>Both banks together, with some 1,300 billion schillings in combined assets, would control 80 percent of retail banking in Austria and dominate trading on Vienna's stock exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
