<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257619" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Doctors believe religious belief beneficial - survey.</title>
<headline>Doctors believe religious belief beneficial - survey.</headline>
<dateline>BOSTON 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Most family physicians believe that religious convictions can contribute to the healing process, according to a survey to be released on Monday.</p>
<p>The survey of 269 family doctors, conducted by Yankelovich Partners at the October meeting of the American Academy of Family Physicians, found that 99 percent of those asked said religion could actually make people healthier.</p>
<p>&quot;Through the ages physicians have witnessed recoveries they can't attribute solely to medical procedures,&quot; said Dr. Herbert Benson, head of The Mind/Body Medical Institute at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Centre in Boston.</p>
<p>&quot;Now, many physicians are beginning to hold that belief can have a profound influence on health and well-being and they see it as an integral part of their traditional treatment plan.&quot;</p>
<p>Some 91 percent of the doctors surveyed reported they had had patients who sought the aid of a spiritial leaders, such as a rabbi, priest or minister, to help with their medical problem.</p>
<p>The survey's results are to be released as part of a three-day conference on Spirituality and Healing at Harvard Medical School.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOSTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
