<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257672" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Mobutu to return home Tuesday, son says.</title>
<headline>Mobutu to return home Tuesday, son says.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zairean President Mobutu Sese Seko plans to return to his embattled country on Tuesday after six weeks convalescing on the French Riviera from cancer surgery, one of his sons said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;He will be leaving on Tuesday morning and fly to Kinshasa,&quot; Mobutu Nzanga, who is also a spokesman for the president, told Reuters from Roquebrune-cap-Martin where Mobutu is staying in a luxury mansion overlooking the Mediterranean.</p>
<p>He said the president, who has ruled Zaire for 30 years, would take off from Nice airport between 7.30 a.m. and 9 a.m. (0630 and 0800 GMT) and make a speech in Kinshasa.</p>
<p>Mobutu was feeling better after convalescing from surgery for prostate cancer in Switzerland in August. However other eyewitnesses have described Mobutu as looking tired and drawn.</p>
<p>In his absence, rebel troops have taken control of a swathe of territory about 500 km (300 miles) long in eastern Zaire, displacing hundreds of thousands of refugees from neighbouring Rwanda and Burundi, many of whom have since returned home.</p>
<p>The rebel coalition has overwhelmed Zaire's ragged army in the east in a two-month offensive, taking several key towns including Goma, Bukavu and Uvira.</p>
<p>Some Western leaders concerned over power vacuum in Zaire have said that only Mobutu has the power to keep his country together, although he is persona non grata in many states because of his aversion to democracy, alleged corruption and widespread criticism of his human rights record.</p>
<p>&quot;There are major things going on in the country, the president will be going back to try to settle the situation,&quot; Mobutu Nzanga said by telephone.</p>
<p>After several false alerts in November, associates and aides said last week that Mobutu would be heading home at the beginning of this week, without giving a precise date.</p>
<p>Mobutu's aides have been packing up baggage, prompting speculation of an imminent departure.</p>
<p>Mobutu arrived at the villa in southern France on November 4 after more than two months' treatment for his cancer in Lausanne, Switzerland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
