<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257731" id="root" date="1996-12-15" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: Mother Teresa dedicates her suffering to God.</title>
<headline>Mother Teresa dedicates her suffering to God.</headline>
<dateline>CALCUTTA 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mother Teresa, recovering slowly from heart surgery in a Calcutta hospital, on Sunday dedicated her suffering to God, doctors treating her said.</p>
<p>&quot;All for Jesus and the poorest of the poor,&quot; a regular medical update quoted the Roman Catholic nun as telling her doctors after they warned that she would have to stay in hospital a few days longer.</p>
<p>There has been an overall improvement in Mother Teresa's condition, said the bulletin issued by Calcutta's B.M. Birla Heart Research Centre.</p>
<p>&quot;Her cardiovascular status is stabilising, heart rhythm remains stable, her pulmonary status today appears somewhat improved and her bronchial pneumonia is clearing,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>Mother Teresa, 86, had heart surgery for the third time in five years to clear two blocked coronary arteries on November 29. Her recovery has been delayed by an irregular heartbeat and long-standing lung and kidney trouble.</p>
<p>Doctors on Wednesday successfully regulated her heartbeat with a mild electric shock, but persistent bronchitis had slowed her recovery.</p>
<p>&quot;I am feeling a little better today,&quot; the bulletin quoted the revered missionary as saying soon after she woke up.</p>
<p>&quot;Mother walked this morning and said she felt a little stronger, and asked when she will be able to go home,&quot; it added.</p>
<p>The 1979 Nobel peace prizewinner was keen to return to her work with the downtrodden which earned her the title &quot;Saint of the Gutters&quot;, doctors said. She renewed her request on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;A few more days of adjustment,&quot; the bulletin quoted her doctors as saying in reply.</p>
<p>A clinic official told reporters: &quot;She is definitely better today and we are hopeful she will be able to return home before Christmas.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-15"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CALCUTTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
