<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="257924" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Global Village sees Q3 oper loss.</title>
<headline>Global Village sees Q3 oper loss.</headline>
<dateline>SUNNYVALE, Calif. 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Global Village Communication Inc said on Monday it expects to report an operating loss of $25 to $30 million, including restructuring charges, for its fiscal third quarter ending December 31.</p>
<p>In a statement, the company said its revenues will fall &quot;significantly below&quot; expectations.</p>
<p>To combat a downturn in business and return the company to profitability, Global Village plans to cut 42 employees, or 20 percent of its workforce and reduce other expenses, specifically in administration, marketing and operations.  </p>
<p>Global Village also said it will take a reserve against anticipated product returns because it expects sell-through of some of its products for Macintosh and Windows computer platforms will not meet expectations.</p>
<p>Lastly, the company will write-down inventory and other assets to better match sales expectations and to refocus its business on core product lines.</p>
<p>&quot;We will have a renewed  emphasis on personal communications products designed to be easy to use and to appeal to home and small-business professionals,&quot; said Neil Selvin, chief executive officer.</p>
<p>The company said it expects to announce fiscal third quarter earnings on January 21.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SUNNYVALE, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
