<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258085" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-WEST INDIES SEND PAKISTAN INTO BAT.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-WEST INDIES SEND PAKISTAN INTO BAT.</headline>
<dateline>ADELAIDE, Australia 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>West Indies captain Courtney Walsh won the toss and sent Pakistan into bat in a World Series limited overs match at Adelaide Oval on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Australia lead the triangular competition with four points from three games, two points clear of Pakistan.</p>
<p>Pakistan named an unchanged side after beating Australia by 12 runs in the tourists' opening match on Sunday.</p>
<p>West Indies called up fast bowler Nixon McLean as replacement for fellow paceman Ian Bishop, who was ruled out with an injured toe.</p>
<p>West Indies have lost their first two matches and prop up the table without a point.</p>
<p>Teams:</p>
<p>Pakistan - Aamir Sohail, Zahoor Elahi, Ijaz Ahmed, Mohammad Wasim, Inzamam-ul-Haq, Moin Khan, Shahid Afridi, Saqlain Mushtaq, Wasim Akram (captain), Waqar Younis, Mushtaq Ahmed, Shahid Nazir (12th man)</p>
<p>West Indies - Robert Samuels, Sherwin Campbell, Brian Lara, Carl Hooper, Shivnarine Chanderpaul, Jimmy Adams, Junior Murray, Kenneth Benjamin, Nixon McLean, Curtly Ambrose, Courtney Walsh (captain), Adrian Griffith (12th man)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ADELAIDE, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
