<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258055" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS TO GO ON TRIAL OVER SENNA DEATH.</title>
<headline>MOTOR RACING-WILLIAMS TO GO ON TRIAL OVER SENNA DEATH.</headline>
<byline>Paul Holmes</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Formula One team chief Frank Williams and five other people will go on trial in Italy next February charged with manslaughter over the death of driver Ayrton Senna, Williams's Italian lawyer said on Monday.</p>
<p>Lawyer Roberto Causo said the trial was scheduled to open on February 20 before a local judge in Imola, where Senna, a Brazilian, was killed in a crash during the San Marino Grand Prix on May 1, 1994.</p>
<p>Causo, who is based in Rome, represents Frank Williams, Williams technical director Patrick Head, chief designer Adrian Newey and Belgian international race director Roland Bruynseraede in the case.</p>
<p>&quot;We deny the charges absolutely,&quot; Causo said.</p>
<p>He would not say whether any of his clients would attend the trial or exercise their right under Italian law to stay away.</p>
<p>Also charged with manslaughter are Imola race track director Federico Bendinelli and a former track official, Giorgio Poggi. They, too, deny the charges.</p>
<p>&quot;We will attempt to show that the race track bore no responsibility for what happened,&quot; one of their lawyers, Roberto Landi, said by telephone from Bologna, central Italy.</p>
<p>Senna, three times world champion, suffered fatal head injuries when his Williams car smashed into a wall on Imola's Tamburello curve during the race in 1994.</p>
<p>An expert report for Bologna prosecutor Maurizio Passarini, who led investigations into Senna's death, concluded that the car's steering column had been modified and snapped as a result of a poor weld as the vehicle took the curve.</p>
<p>The Williams team has argued that the steering column was intact until the moment of impact.</p>
<p>Causo said the only charge which had been open to Passarini under Italian law was manslaughter and argued that it would be heard by a low-level court because it constituted a &quot;minor offence&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that it concerns a personality like Ayrton Senna doesn't make it any more serious,&quot; Causo said by telephone.</p>
<p>Manslaughter carries a maximum prison sentence of five years in the event of conviction.</p>
<p>Causo said that in the vast majority of cases, defendants found guilty of manslaughter in Italy were sentenced to suspended prison terms of less than one year.</p>
<p>The trial will be heard in Imola by a local judge or &quot;pretore&quot;, the equivalent of a magistrates' court under the English legal system.</p>
<p>The judge's verdict will be open to automatic appeal by any of the parties and it could be several years before a judgment becomes definitive.</p>
<p>Senna died a day after Austrian Roland Ratzenberger, who drove for the Simtek team, was killed on the same Imola track in a 300 kph smash during final practice.</p>
<p>Passarini last month won leave from an examining judge to drop proceedings against five people investigated in connection with Ratzenberger's death.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
