<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258038" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Health Power HMO under review by Ohio.</title>
<headline>Health Power HMO under review by Ohio.</headline>
<dateline>COLUMBUS, Ohio 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Health Power Inc said Monday its health maintenance organization subsidiary had been placed under supervision by the Ohio Department of Insurance, effective December 5, after the HMO reported losses in the second and third quarters 1996.</p>
<p>Health Power also said there were questions about whether certain assets included on the HMO's balance sheet were &quot;admitted assets&quot; under statutory accounting principles.  </p>
<p>The HMO expects to maintain normal business operations while under review, subject to the Insurance Department's prior approval of some expenditures and transactions, the company said.</p>
<p>The HMO, which received one-year accreditation from the National Committee for Quality Assurance in 17 Ohio counties, will still try to improve its operating performance, Health Power said. It will also work with the Insurance Department to get adjustments to its balance sheet so that the supervision order can be rescinded, Health Power said.</p>
<p>Health Power said there could be no guarantees the HMO would be successful in having the order rescinded.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLUMBUS, Ohio"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
