<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258072" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: SOCCER-JONES FINED AND APOLOGIES TO TEAM MATES.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-JONES FINED AND APOLOGIES TO TEAM MATES.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wimbledon's Vinnie Jones was fined a week's pay by his Wimbledon club on Monday for writing a mocking newspaper article that offended his team mates.</p>
<p>The rebellious Wales international has also apologised individually to every squad member in the English premier league club and agreed to donate his 2,000 pounds ($3,320) fee from the paper to the players' pool.</p>
<p>&quot;I am also upset that I have upset their families,&quot; said Jones after he was summoned by manager Joe Kinnear and chairman Sam Hammam. His story assessed his colleagues on their abilities at the bar and on the catwalk, as well as in a &quot;ruck&quot; (fight).</p>
<p>Kinnear described the piece as &quot;disgusting&quot; and after his meeting Jones said: &quot;I have explained to the lads that it was supposed to be a joke, a Christmassy, pull-your-leg sort of stunt. But it's gone completely wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;I would like to apologise to the lads and their families for any embarrassment I have caused them.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
