<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258190" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil prices chase higher with cold snapping at heels.</title>
<headline>Oil prices chase higher with cold snapping at heels.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices gained further ground on Monday as traders chose to focus on low heating oil stocks and cold weather forecasts rather than the first tanker loadings of Iraqi crude exports.</p>
<p>At 1730 GMT, London Brent Blend crude futures for January delivery were trading 47 cents up at $24.00 a barrel.</p>
<p>Together with Friday's sharp $1.00 a barrel rally, Monday's gains almost wiped out losses from a ferocious sell-off earlier last week sparked by the resumption of Iraqi exports.</p>
<p>Monday saw the first loadings of Iraqi crude into tankers at the Turkish port of Ceyhan and the northern Gulf port of Mina al-Bakr, but analysts said that the bearish impact of the news had already been factored into prices when exports began by pipeline early last week.</p>
<p>&quot;We're seeing a bit (of Iraqi crude) squeezing out here and there, but the market has already discounted this,&quot; said Alistair Harris of Mees Pierson futures brokers in London.</p>
<p>Industry-watchers said forecasts for cold weather and low heating oil stock levels should at least keep a floor under oil prices and could possibly push them even higher.</p>
<p>&quot;The coldest month is coming up shortly, and stock levels are hardly in overabundance,&quot; said Harris.</p>
<p>Forecasters in the United States, the world's largest heating oil market, on Monday warned of frigid temperatures from the Rocky Mountains to the Appalachians this week, with sub-zero temperatures extending deep into Texas.</p>
<p>The bone-chilling cold was forecast to last into next week which should drive up home heating costs and possibly slow oil refinery operations along the U.S. Gulf coast oil province.</p>
<p>This could hamper refiners' efforts to crank up distillate production to replenish inventories which still languish below 1995 levels.</p>
<p>Analysts noted that markets for middle distillates -- which include heating oil -- are buoyant not only in the U.S. but also in Europe and Asia.</p>
<p>London January futures for gas oil, or European heating oil, gained a hefty $9.00 during Monday trading to close at $222.75 a tonne.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, a tanker carrying Iraqi Kirkuk crude purchased by Turkey's state oil refiner Tupras left the Mediterranean port of Ceyhan on Monday and two other cargoes destined for the United States were loading in the Gulf.</p>
<p>Having been ostracised by world oil markets since its invasion of Kuwait six years ago, Iraq has found little difficulty persuading foreign oil firms to rekindle old trading ties.</p>
<p>Iraqi oil minister Muhammad Rasheed said on Sunday that Iraq has signed contracts with 11 foreign firms.</p>
<p>Those companies which have confirmed they have signed deals include U.S. firms Coastal Corp and Bayoil, France's Elf and Total, and Japan's Mitsubishi Corp. Negotiations are continuing with a range of companies from Europe, Japan, South America and the United States.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>					     Dec 16	    Dec 13</p>
<p>					     1738 GMT	  close</p>
<p> Dated Brent			     23.85	     23.45</p>
<p> IPE London Brent futures (Jan)    24.00	     23.55</p>
<p> NYMEX light crude futures (Jan)   25.23	     24.48</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
