<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258110" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-MALDINI PROMISES TO RESTORE ITALIAN TEAM SPIRIT.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MALDINI PROMISES TO RESTORE ITALIAN TEAM SPIRIT.</headline>
<byline>Chris Endean</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Italy's new coach Cesare Maldini promised on Monday to restore team spirit and stability to the national soccer side in a shift away from the tactics of his unpopular predecessor.</p>
<p>Maldini, addressing a news conference a day after his appointment, steered clear of open dissent from the policies pursued by Arrigo Sacchi, who quit his job on December 1 to return to his old club AC Milan.</p>
<p>But Maldini, who moves to the job after 10 years as under-21 coach, signalled a clear change from the taste for switching players that was one of the chief criticisms of Sacchi's reign.</p>
<p>&quot;You can play in various ways but the important thing is to create a strong group,&quot; Maldini, 64, said. &quot;Italy does not have 95 players all strong enough to play in the national side.&quot;</p>
<p>He praised former national coach Enzo Bearzot, to whom he was assistant when Italy won the World Cup in 1982, as a &quot;maestro&quot; at creating team spirit.</p>
<p>Maldini is set to earn 600 million lire ($390,000) a season, less than 40 percent of what Sacchi was reported to have earned, under a contract that runs beyond the 1998 World Cup finals.</p>
<p>His deputy will be Marco Tardelli, one of the heroes of Italian soccer after scoring in the 1982 World Cup win against Germany.</p>
<p>Maldini inherits a national team still recovering form and morale after last June's humiliating first-round elimination from the European championship.</p>
<p>Since then, Italy have enjoyed two unconvincing wins over Moldova and Georgia in their opening World Cup qualifiers, followed by an embarrassing defeat to Bosnia in a friendly in Sarajevo last month.</p>
<p>The national side's dismal performances and mounting pressure for the removal of the unpopular Sacchi have contributed to falling attendances at Italy's home matches.</p>
<p>&quot;Recently, people have been perplexed about the national side. Our job is to restore the public's affection, to give certain values back to our team,&quot; Maldini said.</p>
<p>Maldini is due to make his last outing with the under-21 side, which he has coached to three European championship titles, in a friendly against Hungary in Budapest on Wednesday.</p>
<p>His first test with the national side will come next February in a World Cup qualifier against England.</p>
<p>Maldini said it was too soon to say whether he would recall striker Gianluca Vialli, dropped by Sacchi after a falling-out, and indicated that while he would consider new talent he would focus on forging a team of regulars.</p>
<p>Maldini's appointment was announced just 24 hours after the Italian soccer federation elected league president Luciano Nizzola as its new chairman in a move designed to restore unity and purpose to Italy's premier game after a year of troubles.</p>
<p>His successor as under-21 coach will be the current deputy coach, Rossano Giampaglia, the federation announced.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
