<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258253" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Busang statement shakes Bre-X, Barrick stocks.</title>
<headline>Busang statement shakes Bre-X, Barrick stocks.</headline>
<dateline>TORONTO 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in Bre-X Minerals Ltd dropped and shares in Barrick Gold Corp rose after Barrick said on Monday the two companies had submitted a joint proposal to operate the massive Busang gold project in Indonesia.</p>
<p>Bre-X was down C$1 to C$20 in heavy trading of 2.2 million shares by mid-morning. Barrick rose C$0.65 to C$39.45.</p>
<p>But the announcement did not dissipate the investor uncertainty that has shadowed Bre-X for months, analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;There are no details,&quot; said gold analyst John Ing with Maison Placements Canada Inc.  </p>
<p>&quot;There are all different kinds of rumors as to how much (Barrick will pay) but I don't think we'll know anything until the Indonesian government responds,&quot; Ing said.</p>
<p>Barrick said the two companies had formed a proposal along lines suggested by the Indonesian government last month. But the proposal still requires government blessing, Barrick said.</p>
<p>While Barrick spokesman Vince Borg said the two companies &quot;have come to mutually acceptable terms&quot; after negotiations this weekend, a matching statement from Bre-X was conspicuously missing, analysts said.</p>
<p>Bre-X was expected to make a statement this afternoon.  </p>
<p>The Calgary-based company did not return calls.</p>
<p>&quot;It's quite possible that they may not have a deal,&quot; said Ing. The announcement from Barrick &quot;almost looks like a trial balloon,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Negotiations between Bre-X and Barrick to split up Busang have been plagued by twists and turns.</p>
<p>While the Indonesian government has clearly favored Barrick to act as Bre-X's partner, Bre-X has made no secret that it wants an open bidding process for its stake in Busang.</p>
<p>And many Bre-X shareholders have said they fear negotiations with Barrick will not be fair since the talks were virtually mandated by the Indosian government. Some of them have threatened legal action if the deal is unfair.</p>
<p>&quot;Barrick has an established track record of being fair,&quot; responded Borg, who said this deal would not be any different.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Indonesian officials have put pressure on Barrick and Bre-X to sort things out quickly. The government extended a November 22 deadline to December 4, and then extended it again to the end of December.</p>
<p>((Heather Scoffield, Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8104))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TORONTO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
