<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258257" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOMALIA: More than 100 dead in battles in Somali capital.</title>
<headline>More than 100 dead in battles in Somali capital.</headline>
<byline>Mohamed Guled</byline>
<dateline>MOGADISHU 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 29 people were killed in a third straight day of street battles in Somalia's capital on Monday, taking the total death toll to more than 100 dead.</p>
<p>Security sources said nine militiamen were killed and 22 wounded in heavy clashes on Monday between forces of Hussein Aideed and Osman Hassan Ali Atto at Mogadishu's airport, closed since last year.</p>
<p>Another 14 were killed and 27 were wounded in fighting over Hosh militia base at the north end of a frontline between Medina district and Aideed's south Mogadishu stronghold, hospital sources said.</p>
<p>They said four people were killed when mortars bombs slammed into the K-5 area of south Mogadishu.</p>
<p>At least two of Aideed's militiamen were killed and two were wounded earlier on Monday when a &quot;technical&quot; four-wheel-drive battlewagon manned by gunmen loyal to Ali Mahdi Mohamed strafed a checkpoint on the Green Line battle zone dividing the capital.</p>
<p>The technical escaped into northern Mogadishu after the hit -and-run attack deep in a wide swathe of war-shattered streets.</p>
<p>More than 80 people died and at least 175 were wounded at the weekend in fighting pitting Aideed's forces against three allied factions and raising fears of a final all-out war for the capital.</p>
<p>Fighting at the airport with mortars and heavy weapons began when Aideed's forces tried to seize territory held by Medina district's Moslem fundamentalist leader Musa Sudi Yalahow at the southern end of the runway.</p>
<p>Aideed's radio station in south Mogadishu said on Sunday night the national army was &quot;cleansing bandits&quot; from Medina.</p>
<p>Hussein Aideed, a 34-year-old former U.S. marine, succeeded his father Mohamed Farah Aideed at his death in August and was elected president of Somalia by his own supporters. But both he and his government are rejected by many other faction leaders.</p>
<p>More than 50 people including 25 women were killed on Sunday when mortar bombs slammed into a busy civilian area full of stalls and shops selling jewellery at south Mogadishu's Bakara main market.</p>
<p>Contacts by elders of Aideed's Habr Gedir sub-clan and Ali Mahdi's Abgal have failed to cool the conflict in Mogadishu.</p>
<p>The airport has been closed to all flights since the last U.N. peacekeepers pulled out of Somalia in March 1995. Even if one faction controlled the whole airport area, it would have to remain closed because it is in range of other factions' guns.</p>
<p>President Daniel arap Moi of Kenya in October mediated peace talks between Somalia's factions and said they had agreed to end hostilities, remove roadblocks and allow the free movement of people.</p>
<p>But the roadblocks were never removed and Aideed's south Mogadishu government stuck to its position that he was president of all Somalia, which has had no central government since the overthrow of dictator and president Mohamed Siad Barre in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SOMAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOGADISHU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOMALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
