<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258274" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Moslem anti-drug protest turns violent in Cape Town.</title>
<headline>Moslem anti-drug protest turns violent in Cape Town.</headline>
<byline>Brendan Boyle</byline>
<dateline>CAPE TOWN 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Five people were slightly wounded and a dozen were arrested by police on Monday when Moslem protesters refused to disperse after a demonstration against drugs and gangsterism.</p>
<p>Witnesses said police fired rubber bullets, tears gas and unleashed their dogs at the defiant crowd demonstrating outside Cape Town's international airport.</p>
<p>The demonstration was organised by the militant Moslem organisation People Against Gangsterism and Drugs (Pagad), who leaped to prominence earlier this year when they publicly shot and burned drug baron Rashaad Staggie to death.</p>
<p>Pagad chief commander Aslam Toefy said before the protest started that his followers would obey police and would disperse when told to do so.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll make our point and then we'll go. Everything is going to be done according to the law of the land,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But scuffles erupted when police gave the 200-strong crowd 10 minutes to disperse, triggering more than an hour of running battles between Pagad members, police and soldiers. Five people were slighlty wounded and a dozen were arrested.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't fight us, fight the gangsters,&quot; one woman in traditional long Moslem robe screamed into the face of a black policeman.</p>
<p>A man near her with his face partly obscured by a Palestinian-style scarf told police pushing the crowd back with plastic shields: &quot;One day we'll pick up guns. Just you wait.&quot;</p>
<p>Justice Minister Dullah Omar, himself a Moslem, has failed in negotiations with Pagad leaders to persuade them to abandon their high-profile campaign, which has included attacks on the homes of alleged drug dealers.</p>
<p>But President Nelson Mandela vowed last week that Pagad would no longer be allowed to demonstrate with guns and with their faces covered. He said they would have to comply with a law requiring seven days notice of any public demonstration.</p>
<p>Transport Minister Mac Maharaj ruled at the weekend that Pagad's planned airport protest would be unlawful and warned them to stay away.</p>
<p>People heading for the airport abandoned their cars in the road when clouds of teargas billowed through the traffic piled up ahead of a police roadblock. Others ducked below window level as police aimed shotguns into the crowd and fired volleys of rubber bullets.</p>
<p>Pagad legal adviser Sharief Khan was hit in the head by a teargas cannister and was arrested while medics travelling with the demonstrators tried to bandage his head. Others arrested included a heavily pregnant woman.</p>
<p>Toefy tried to persuade the crowd to leave after they had handed a petition to airport manager Hennie Taljaard calling for stricter customs controls on drug shipments alleged to be passing through Cape Town.</p>
<p>But when the crowd refused to go, he told them and police:</p>
<p>&quot;The leadership is going. If you want to stay here that's up to you, but the leadership is going.&quot; The crowd dispersed slowly after more than an hour of clashes with police.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAPE TOWN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
