<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258256" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Rwandan human tide trudges home from Tanzania.</title>
<headline>Rwandan human tide trudges home from Tanzania.</headline>
<byline>Mark Dodd</byline>
<dateline>NGARA, Tanzania 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>More than 100,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees ended two-and-a-half years of exile on Monday, streaming on foot from Tanzanian to Rwanda in the biggest human tide since Tanzanian troops and police pushed them to go home.</p>
<p>More than 200 children were by Monday separated from their parents in the crush of refugees and a U.N. official said he feared the total could reach 1,000 by the end of the day.</p>
<p>In the lines snaking towards Rwanda, mothers tied themselves to their children with yellow string supplied by the Red Cross.</p>
<p>In Geneva, U.N. refugee agency (UNHCR) spokeswoman Pam O'Tool said 103,000 refugees crossed into Rwanda on Monday, bringing to 133,000 the number of returnees in the past three days.</p>
<p>She said some 100,000 Hutus in Tanzania were headed for Rwanda and another 50,000 were preparing to leave camps in Kitale area. &quot;This means we have more than 280,000 people who have either returned or on the way home,&quot; she told Reuters.</p>
<p>There had been a total of 540,000 Rwandan refugees in Tanzania but O'Tool said she had no information on the whereabouts of the rest.</p>
<p>Tanzania on December 5 ordered all Rwandan Hutu refugees out by the end of the month and troops intervened when many surged out of their camps and headed away from the Rwandan border.</p>
<p>Many refugees were expected to sleep overnight on the road from the camps in Tanzania, as they have done since they started crossing in large numbers on Saturday, but the border crossing at Rusomo bridge was due to remain open for those still walking.</p>
<p>Another UNHCR spokeswoman said troops on Monday moved into Karagwe camp, the northernmost of Tanzania's 11 Rwandan camps, and refugees from there would arrive at the border by the end of the week.</p>
<p>Trucks, buses and vans were ready inside Rwanda to pick up footsore refugees, whose will to stay out of Rwanda cracked with a brief flurry of blows from stick-wielding Tanzanian troops.</p>
<p>The refugees left Rwanda in 1994 during the genocide by Hutu mobs and militiamen of about 800,000 Tutsis. Many say they fear reprisals from Tutsis for the slaughter if they return home.</p>
<p>A column of refugees estimated by UNHCR at 200,000 on Monday stretched for 90 km (55 miles) inside Tanzania.</p>
<p>Anne Willem Bijleveld of UNHCR said soldiers used force to break the grip of intimidators opposed to the mass return.</p>
<p>&quot;In order to break the grip of the leaders...some sort of force must be used,&quot; he said. &quot;We've never been able to deal with the grip of intimidators. This was the main problem from day one.&quot;</p>
<p>Asked why UNHCR would not protest to Tanzania, he said: &quot;We feel the situation in Rwanda is conducive to return and that the people so far have been totally misled by their leaders.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;What we witnessed is the military and police trying to do it (repatriation) in a most peaceful manner,&quot; Bijleveld added.</p>
<p>UNCHR has been criticised by the human rights group Amnesty International for its stance over the Rwandan refugees in Tanzania, which Amnesty says is at odds with the U.N. agency's commitment to protect refugees from forced expulsion.</p>
<p>Rwandan and Tanzanian authorities barred journalists from the border area for much of the time but most refugees seemed resigned to returning under pressure from troops and police.</p>
<p>Human rights groups have reported no mass killings in Rwanda since an estimated 560,000 refugees flooded back from eastern Zaire last month after fighting forced them out of their camps.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NGARA, Tanzania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
