<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258271" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>COTE D'IVOIRE: New Air Afrique management takes over in February.</title>
<headline>New Air Afrique management takes over in February.</headline>
<dateline>ABIDJAN 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Air Afrique shareholders met on Monday and put back until February 17 top management changes agreed earlier this year to set the struggling multi-national carrier back on its feet.</p>
<p>A statement from the company said that French chairman and managing director Yves-Roland Billecart would continue to run the airline until then.</p>
<p>The 11 member states selected the boss of Air Mauritius, Sir Harry K. Tirvengadum, to run the airline on November 11.</p>
<p>Monday's statement said the shareholders had &quot;put back&quot; the nomination of administrators to their next meeting on February 17 when a new board would formally consider the nomination of the new managing director and elect a new chairman.</p>
<p>&quot;The general assembly (of shareholders) reaffirmed the pertinence of the elements of company's revival plan which must be considered major targets,&quot; the statement said.</p>
<p>A communique in November announced plans to create a special company to take over responsibility for planes at the root of Air Afrique's debt problem before the end of the year.</p>
<p>Each member will provide one billion CFA of the capital with ASECNA-Service, a subsidiary of the multinational Francophone African air safety agency ASECNA, providing 20 billion CFA.</p>
<p>Air Afrique's owners see the airline, which was set up in 1961 during the heady days that followed independence from France, as a symbol of inter-African cooperation.</p>
<p>They cut short Billecart's mandate after staff blamed him for the company's problems.</p>
<p>Air Afrique is majority owned by Benin, Burkina Faso, Chad, Central African Republic, Congo, Ivory Coast, Mauritania, Mali, Niger, Senegal and Togo. Air France is among stake holders.</p>
<p>($1=524 CFA francs)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ICST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABIDJAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COTE D'IVOIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
