<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258279" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ZAIRE: Zaire gears up for Mobutu &quot;Hollywood&quot; homecoming.</title>
<headline>Zaire gears up for Mobutu &quot;Hollywood&quot; homecoming.</headline>
<byline>William Wallis</byline>
<dateline>KINSHASA 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Zaire prepared a tumultuous homecoming for President Mobutu Sese Seko, with state radio urging the populace to turn out in force on Tuesday and his party dishing out transport money or clothes bearing his image.</p>
<p>State radio announced on Monday that Mobutu, who has been absent since having cancer surgery in Europe in August, would return to Zaire's sprawling capital at 3 p.m. (1400 GMT) on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Mobutu will return Hollywood style,&quot; the front page of the pro-Mobutu Soft newspaper said, adding that Zaire's president of 31 years would address the nation for the first time in nearly four months on state radio and television on Tuesday night.</p>
<p>&quot;The entire government will be at the airport to receive the president on Tuesday,&quot; Youth and Sports Minister Kisombe Kiaku Mwisi, who is helping to organise the welcoming ceremony, said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will also be the military high command, every shade of political party and the general population. We are expecting a million people,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>At the headquarters of Mobutu's Popular Revolutionary Movement (MPR) in the working class Kasavubu district, crowds jostled for cash or fabric bearing Mobutu's image.</p>
<p>&quot;I myself had 5,000 new lappas (wraparound skirts) printed,&quot; Kisombe said, adding that security forces would deploy heavily to control the crowds.</p>
<p>Newspapers of all shades of opinion speculated on Monday on the implications of the president's return and the political and military changes it could bring.</p>
<p>Opposition newspapers suggested Mobutu should ensure radical opposition leader Etienne Tshisekedi heads a new national unity government or a whole new crisis would ensue.</p>
<p>&quot;The political crisis will be truly relaunched and the opposition will have to radically reassess its struggle against the dictatorship&quot;, the Potentiel newspaper said.</p>
<p>Most newspapers debated whether the president would favour negotiations to end the conflict in the east of the country or reassemble the defeated army for a counteroffensive against Rwandan-backed Tutsi-led rebels.</p>
<p>Mobutu, 66, has been convalescing in France since undergoing surgery for prostate cancer in Switzerland in August.</p>
<p>During his absence the rebels, with veteran Mobutu foe Laurent Kabila at their head, have taken over a swathe of territory in the east of the country, routing the demoralised and ill-disciplined Zairean army.</p>
<p>Seething political tensions have resurfaced in the capital, prompting speculation that without Mobutu a bitter succession struggle would tear apart the vast central African country of more than 300 ethnic groups.</p>
<p>Allies and even some long-term opponents have pinned much hope for a resolution to the crisis on Mobutu's return.</p>
<p>Members of the presidential entourage say Mobutu symbolises national unity and that once back in Zaire he will solder the country's vast and disparate regions together.</p>
<p>Sceptics and some opponents say that the ailing president is in no position, either politically or physically, to pull magic solutions out of his trademark leopard skin hat. His return, some say, will only complicate the situation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ZAIRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KINSHASA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ZAIRE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
