<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258301" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: Wandering Rwandan refugees herded towards home.</title>
<headline>Wandering Rwandan refugees herded towards home.</headline>
<byline>Mark Dodd</byline>
<dateline>NYAKAHURA, Tanzania 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tens of thousands of Rwandan refugees who last week fled their camps in northwest Tanzania were on Monday heading back towards Rwanda in a massed column stretching 90 km (55 miles), witnesses and aid workers said.</p>
<p>The column was just 10 km (six miles) outside Benaco camp, where Tanzanian troops on Sunday forced out 300,000 Rwandan refugees. It stretched back to Nyakahura, also in northwest Tanzania.</p>
<p>Aid workers expected the first of this batch of refugees to reach the border with Rwanda by Monday evening at the earliest.</p>
<p>The refugees, a composite group from six refugee camps, left their settlements last Thursday moving away from Rwanda. But they were turned around at a Tanzanian military roadblock and sent back towards their homeland.</p>
<p>Another batch that had hoped to walk to Kenya were also being ordered to return to the road leading to their country.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't agree to go to Rwanda. The army of Tanzania will force us to go to Rwanda but we want to go to Kenya. We think it will take two weeks,&quot; said Ernest Kimukama, aged 22.</p>
<p>Kimukama was unaware that the column of refugees in which he was travelling was being diverted by soldiers manning a checkpoint near the village of Lusahugha, south of Nyakahura.</p>
<p>&quot;We have much information that in the Kagera river, there are many, many bodies,&quot; said Batiste Kizimana, another refugee.</p>
<p>&quot;What the people want is to have a place, another place, not Rwanda, not the Tanzanian camps. You are forcing us to go home without security, without representation in the political system. We are not represented, we cannot go back,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>There was no independent confirmation of Kizimana's allegations of the bodies of slain refugees being in the Kagera river.</p>
<p>Kizimana identified himself as a teacher but other refugees pointed to him as a former mayor.</p>
<p>International aid workers based in Nyakahura said the refugee column which included Kimukama's group included hundreds of ethnic Hutu hardliners, the so-called intimidators, mainly Hutu militiamen and former Rwandan troops.</p>
<p>&quot;There's definitely 10,000 or so who can't go back (to Rwanda) and won't go back,&quot; said an official from the Irish charity Goal.</p>
<p>The official estimated the refugee flow through the village at 150,000 over the past three days.</p>
<p>The official said intimidators had pelted a U.N. vehicle in Nyakahura with stones on Saturday. A breakaway group of refugees led by hardline Hutus is believed to be holding out in a thickly-wooded forest area southeast of Nyakahura.</p>
<p>&quot;Don't worry, Msuya knows about them,&quot; said Judith Melby from the U.N. refugee agency UNHCR. Brigadier-General Benjamin Msuya is the Tanzanian military commander for the western zone.</p>
<p>The Tanzanians had ordered out an estimated half-a-million Hutu refugees who fled Rwanda in 1994 in fear of reprisal following the slaughter of over one million Tutsis and Hutu moderates.</p>
<p>Over one million Hutu refugees fled to camps in Zaire and Tanzania in 1994 as the Tutsi-led Rwandan Patriotic Front routed the former Rwandan army and Iterahamwe militia blamed for the massacre.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NYAKAHURA, Tanzania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
