<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258312" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbian unions back anti-government drive.</title>
<headline>Serbian unions back anti-government drive.</headline>
<byline>Peter Greste</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Opposition supporters and students marched into a fifth week of anti-government protests on Monday as a court and trade unions dealt new blows to socialist attempts to keep control of disputed councils.</p>
<p>The municipal court in the town of Smederevska Palanka ordered the local electoral commission to give the municipal council to the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition.</p>
<p>The ruling was a second breakthrough for Zajedno since a similar order was made in the southern industrial town of Nis on Sunday, but opposition parties were still cautious.</p>
<p>Zajedno spokesman Slobodan Vuksanovic said: &quot;This is very good news, but it goes only half way. We still don't know whether the commissions will accept the rulings. But people now see that their demonstrations bring results.&quot;</p>
<p>Protestors gathered on Belgrade's streets again on Monday, although in smaller numbers than the quarter of a million who demonstrated on Sunday in the biggest of the rallies held daily since mid-November to protest alleged socialist electoral fraud.</p>
<p>The country's largest and most influential union organisation also weighed in with backing for another smaller union which has been involved in the daily protests.</p>
<p>The Alliance of Independent Trade Unions of Yugoslavia was pro-government in the past, but its president Dragan Radulovic said it now supported protests by Nezavisnost (Independence) over wages, working conditions and the election dispute.</p>
<p>&quot;Solidarity is a minimum that should exist between trade unions,&quot; Radulovic told a news conference, but stopped short of calling on his association's members to join the protests.</p>
<p>The demonstrations have shaken socialist President Slobodan Milosevic and given the United States a fresh opportunity to press him for democratic reform in Serbia in return for renewed access to international financial institutions.</p>
<p>The Spanish government said former Prime Minister Felipe Gonzalez had been asked to lead an observer mission from the Organisation of Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) which Milosevic has invited to verify the elections.</p>
<p>Nis and Smerderevska Palanka in southeastern Serbia were among towns where commissions disqualified Zajedno for &quot;irregularities&quot; in the local elections on November 17 and awarded control to the ruling socialists.</p>
<p>Vuksanovic said the news from both the courts and unions would maintain the momentum of the daily marches. Zajedno officials said they had a solid and commited base of supporters who would continue to rally day after day.</p>
<p>&quot;We were surprised by the reaction of the people and the number of supporters we got even three weeks ago,&quot; Vuksanovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;Now we understand that the people regard this as a job. They tell us they come every day at three o'clock with their families, and if they can't make it they send their neighbours. This is like a duty for them.&quot;</p>
<p>The coalition claimed victory in 14 of Serbia's 18 largest towns in polling on November 17, but lost most in repeat elections ordered by the authorities.</p>
<p>According to Zajedno, the demonstrations have also spread from 10 towns a week ago to some 27 on Sunday, although it was too early to say how many would continue into the working week.</p>
<p>Vuksanovic said they would maintain the protests until the court rulings were confirmed and Zajedno awarded control of the industrial centres of Kraljevo and Jagodina as well as Belgrade.</p>
<p>Police have so far kept a low profile during the rallies, held in a carnival atmosphere with music and fireworks, but memories of 1991 when Milosevic used tanks to crush the last big street challenge have never been far away.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
