<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25858" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOMALIA: Somali faction leader leaves for Yemen talks.</title>
<headline>Somali faction leader leaves for Yemen talks.</headline>
<dateline>MOGADISHU 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Somali faction leader Ali Mahdi Mohamed and a delegation from his clan alliance left Mogadishu on Saturday for talks in Yemen on preparations for a national conference.</p>
<p>A radio station run by Ali Mahdi's alliance said he would meet Yemeni President Ali Abdullah Saleh in Sanaa and Somali faction leader Ali Hassan Osman Atto, an ally who was already there.</p>
<p>Following the death of south Mogadishu faction leader Mohamed Farah Aideed on August 1, President Saleh invited all Somali factions to Yemen for talks to end their six-year civil war.</p>
<p>Aideed was succeeded by his 33-year-old son Hussein, who was elected by his supporters as president of Somalia. Ali Mahdi also holds he is president and rejects the Aideed government.</p>
<p>Ali Mahdi and Osman Atto have said their alliance will meet on September 10 to prepare for a national reconciliation conference on October 10. It was unclear if both meetings would be held in Yemen.</p>
<p>Hussein Aideed vowed to follow the policies of his father, who ruled out attending a reconciliation conference unless he was invited as president rather than just as a faction leader.</p>
<p>Another Ali Mahdi delegation left Mogadishu on Friday for Addis Ababa for talks on the reconciliation conference. A team from Aideed's government has also gone to the Ethiopian capital.</p>
<p>A series of conferences in Mogadishu and regional capitals have failed to bring peace to Somalia, which has had no central government since the fall of late president Mohamed Siad Barre in 1991.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SOMAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="YEMAR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOGADISHU"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOMALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
