<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258546" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Dec 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Dec 16.</headline>
<dateline>RIO DE JANEIRO 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- WHY BRAZIL IS LOSING MARKET IN THE U.S.</p>
<p>Brazil, the second biggest exporter of shoes to the U.S., is losing market. Brazilian shoes exports to the U.S. have been falling since 1993. The government blames U.S. import tariffs, but the problem is Brazil's difficulties to compete with other countries, China in particular.</p>
<p>-- CULTURAL UNION IS MERCOSUR'S NEW TARGET</p>
<p>The cultural union between Brazil, Argentina, Paraguay and Uruguay is now a priority of the Mercosur's agenda.</p>
<p>-- BBA TO BUY BCN WITHOUT OLACYR</p>
<p>Brazil's Banco BBA Creditanstalt will buy the control of local bank BCN without Grupo Itamarati's owner Olacyr de Moraes as a minority shareholder. In July, BCN and Banco Itamarati announced a merger. But now BCN will acquire Itamarati under a deal worth 150 million reais. BBA, in turn, will purchase BCN after Itamarati's acquisition.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- CONSTRUCTION FIRMS GAVE MORE MONEY TO ELECTIONS IN SAO PAULO</p>
<p>The biggest donations to this year's electoral campaign in Sao Paulo came from construction firms.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>GREMIO WINS BRAZILIAN CHAMPIONSHIP</p>
<p>Gremio soccer team won the Brazilian championship after beating Portuguesa 2-0 on Sunday.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- RAPPORTEUR REJECTS INDIVIDUAL AMENDMENTS</p>
<p>PMDB senator Carlos Bezerra, who is in charge of the federal budget committee, will maintain in the budget proposal only government funds to health, education, agrarian reform and agricultural projects.</p>
<p>--  Reuters has not verified the stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Fatima Cristina, Rio de Janeiro newsroom, 5521 507 4151</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIO DE JANEIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
