<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258662" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan opposes U.S. &quot;open skies&quot; approach -- govt.</title>
<headline>Japan opposes U.S. &quot;open skies&quot; approach -- govt.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A senior Japanese Transport Ministry official said on Monday that Japan is opposed to U.S. efforts to reach &quot;open skies&quot; accords in many aviation markets of Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;This (idea of) open skies will simply invite a domination of international markets by American megacarriers,&quot; said Jiro Hanyu, deputy general of the Transport Ministry's civil aviation bureau.</p>
<p>Hanyu made the remarks ahead of a preparatory unofficial meeting in early January to pave the way for a resumption of negotiations, which have been deadlocked since August.</p>
<p>Hanyu said the U.S. is calling for &quot;open skies&quot; without opening the U.S. domestic market, which accounts for almost 30 percent of the world's aviation market.</p>
<p>&quot;The U.S. market is dominated by four or five American carriers...and is reserved only for Americans,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Mark Gerchick, deputy assistant secretary for aviation and international affairs at the U.S. Transportation Department, said earlier this month that the U.S. would put new emphasis on reaching &quot;open skies&quot; accords in the many closed aviation arkets of Asia.</p>
<p>He said Asia is the world's fastest-growing aviation market, and Japan is the key.</p>
<p>Hanyu called on the United States to open its domestic market to foreign carriers and to agree to a safeguard mechanism to prevent a monopoly by U.S. carriers.</p>
<p>He said Japan has no plans to change its stance in the bilateral aviation talks in January.</p>
<p>Japan argues that there is a substantial inequality over air services into the United States. &quot;The present situation, under which Japan Airlines cannot fly to such cities as Detroit and Dallas, and All Nippon Airways cannot fly to the U.S. mainland...must be corrected,&quot; Hanyu said.</p>
<p>&quot;We would like to know if the U.S. can move towards equality at the meeting. If both sides get a good impression, we will have a formal senior official level meeting very early next year, such as the end of January or in February.&quot;</p>
<p>The bilateral dispute centres on the granting of &quot;beyond&quot; rights to U.S. carriers to operate flights from the United States to Japan onward to other Asian countries.</p>
<p>Washington has argued that a 1952 bilateral aviation agreement allows for beyond rights for U.S. carriers but Japan says such rights have been granted only in exceptional cases.</p>
<p>Japan has refused to approve new flights unless the United States grants extra flights to Japanese carriers.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
