<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258640" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH KOREA: South Korean judge muses on justice and coups.</title>
<headline>South Korean judge muses on justice and coups.</headline>
<byline>Andrew Browne</byline>
<dateline>SEOUL 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>With a line from the ancient Chinese classics -- &quot;a general who surrenders should not be put to death&quot; -- a South Korean judge on Monday spared the life of former South Korean president Chun Doo Hwan.</p>
<p>Judge Kwon Sung's verdict was intended to send a clear message that coup leaders cannot get away unpunished in a new era of democracy.</p>
<p>But in a summing-up laced with Latin metaphors, Confucian logic and modern notions of justice he made clear South Korea should not set a precedent for an endless cycle of bloody revenge.</p>
<p>&quot;Losing political power doesn't necessarily mean death,&quot; Kwon said before setting aside a death sentence for Chun and replacing it with life in jail.</p>
<p>&quot;We must get away from that kind of political culture and establish the principle that death does not follow a transfer of power,&quot; he told the 1979 coup leader and architect of the 1980 Kwangju massacre.</p>
<p>&quot;This is as important as punishing the coup.&quot;</p>
<p>Chun and his successor Roh Tae-woo were convicted of mutiny and treason over the coup that launched Chun's political career and led to the Kwangju atrocity.</p>
<p>Separately, they were found guilty of amassing hundreds of millions of dollars in slush funds.</p>
<p>Current president Kim Young-sam has been accused by opponents of destroying his two predecessors out of personal vengeance, and there are fears he too may be a target of attack after he steps down in 1998.</p>
<p>Kwon's 55-page ruling was eagerly awaited by South Koreans as possibly the final legal word on a courtroom drama that has poked into the darkest corners of South Korea's brutal history and dragged in a Who's Who of politics and business.</p>
<p>But while Kim's intention was to &quot;right the wrongs of history&quot; -- in the words of Kim who launched the national soul-searching -- he only prolonged the agony for Chun's victims.</p>
<p>&quot;This is obviously a prepared script,&quot; sobbed Lee Keum-soon, standing outside the court, after hearing that the most hated man in South Korea had escaped the hangman's noose.</p>
<p>&quot;My son was handicapped during the Kwangju massacre. The people of Kwangju are still living with anger from that incident.&quot;</p>
<p>Several hundred people were killed when paratroopers stormed the southern city of Kwangju to put down a citizens' revolt against martial law.</p>
<p>Defence lawyers had argued a successful coup cannot be legally challenged. But the judge slapped down the logic that might is right.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that an act is legally established does not necessarily mean it is right and unpunishable,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kwon deflected some of the blame from Roh.</p>
<p>&quot;Although Roh is guilty of similar charges, we have to differentiate between a mastermind and a follower. So I give a 17-year prison sentence,&quot; he said, slicing 5-1/2 years off the original sentence.</p>
<p>To five businessmen he allowed to walk free after being convicted of bribing Roh, Kwon offered some solace from the public disgrace and humiliation they have suffered.</p>
<p>The judge suggested the tycoons, who were either acquitted or released on suspended sentences, were caught in the web of corrupt politics where money was power.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not right to put the initial blame on businessmen acting in their company's interests,&quot; he said. &quot;Blame should go to the power that forces the companies to pay these bribes and those who help them.</p>
<p>&quot;It costs money to govern the country and politics cost money.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEOUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH KOREA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
