<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258608" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>singapore: Asian dollar deposits quietly steady in late trade.</title>
<headline>Asian dollar deposits quietly steady in late trade.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian dollar deposit rates were quietly steady in lacklustre trade, dealers said on Monday.</p>
<p>They said most traders were sidelined ahead of tonight's 1415 GMT release of the U.S. November industrial production and capacity utilisation data.</p>
<p>Industrial production for November is forecast to rise about 0.6 percent compared with a 0.5 percent decline reported in October.</p>
<p>November capacity utilisation is expected to rise to 83.0 percent against October's 82.7 percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Rates were steady to higher in the morning on some position adjustments. Some people are waiting for possible direction from tonight's release of the (U.S. November) industrial production and capacity utilisation figures,&quot; a local dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The numbers have been built into the market and most people have squared or are squaring their positions, so I don't think there will be much impact,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In day-to-day rates, Monday/Tuesday, Tuesday/Wednesday and week-fixed were unchanged from last Friday's common 5-5/16 5-3/16 percent, respectively.  </p>
<p>Among longer dates, one-month was unchanged at 5-9/16 5-7/16 percent, three-months rose 1/16 percentage point to 5-9/16 5-7/16, six-months unchanged at 5-9/16 5-7/16 and twelve-months unchanged at 5-3/4 5-5/8 percent.</p>
<p>-- P.Theseira (65-870-3085)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
