<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258669" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Mexico lifting of rice import ban welcomed by Asia.</title>
<headline>Mexico lifting of rice import ban welcomed by Asia.</headline>
<byline>Anchalee Koetsawang</byline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Asian rice exporters on Monday welcomed Mexico's move to re-open its domestic market and lift a blanket 1994 import ban that had blocked all foreign rice, but exempted shipments from the United States.</p>
<p>Mexican rice producers have reacted angrily to the government's action saying that Asian imports could carry disease into the country's own crop and called for the imposition of a 35 percent tariff on rice from Asian origins. Thai exporters hailed the Mexican move, but expressed concerns that high prices will erode Thailand's competitiveness in the  </p>
<p>Latin American market.</p>
<p>They also urged the Thai government to send a team to the country to improve relationships with Mexico's rice importers.</p>
<p>&quot;There's definitely an opportunity there. But our prices are relatively high compared with rice from other Asian origins,&quot; said Vorapong Pichpongsa, president of the Thai Rice Exporters Association.</p>
<p>&quot;However, if Mexico wants quality rice, then I think we can compete. We have a good reputation when it comes to quality and punctuality of deliveries,&quot; he told Reuters.  </p>
<p>But others said the distance between Thailand and Mexico and other barriers such as possible high tariffs will make Thai rice unattractive.</p>
<p>&quot;The freight prices would be costly and substantially reduce the price advantage that we have over U.S. rice,&quot; said a commerce ministry official.</p>
<p>&quot;But it is still a good opportunity to expand the market,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Mexico imposed the 1994 blanket on rice imports, except those from the U.S., after it said some Asian shipments were contaminated with bacteria and insects.  </p>
<p>Thai traders charged, however, that the 1994 decision was politically motivated as cheaper rice from Asia, especially from Vietnam, had seriously affected U.S. rice exports to Mexico.</p>
<p>In the early 1990s, Mexico had bought about 40,000 tonnes of medium grade 10-15 percent white rice a year from Thailand.</p>
<p>But current Thai prices for this grade are much higher than in India and Vietnam, traders said.</p>
<p>Indian traders said they also saw little opportunity to benefit from the Mexican opening, due to India's relative freight disadvantage compared with other closer exporters, adding their prices were higher than those of major competitors.  </p>
<p>&quot;It should be a costly proposition for Mexico to import from India,&quot; said O.P. Mangal, a senior official with Space Group, a leading food grains exporter.</p>
<p>Mangal said that Vietnamese rice prices were currently the most competitive among Asian exporters followed in order by Thailand, Burma and China.</p>
<p>&quot;On top of it our freight will be exorbitant,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Indian analysts said U.S. rice would still work out to be the most competitive, despite its higher price quotes for similar grades than Asian-origin, because of its comparitive freight advantage.  </p>
<p>&quot;We will need to see if the price difference between Asian and U.S. rice would offset the freight disadvantage,&quot; said one analyst.</p>
<p>He said Mexico, with annual average imports of about 250,000 tonnes of rice, was a relatively small market and that, so far, it had not bought rice from India.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
