<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258683" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Coconut Oil - Prices seen steady on tight supply.</title>
<headline>Coconut Oil - Prices seen steady on tight supply.</headline>
<byline>Dolly Aglay</byline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coconut oil prices are expected to stay steady to higher in a generally quiet market this week as some mills in the Philippines have temporarily shut down ahead of the Christmas holidays, vegetable oil traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't see any activity in the last two weeks of the year with most mills closing early to accumulate enough copra for next year's orders,&quot; said one local trader.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who were not covered for the rest of the year may either get it (coconut oil) at current high prices, or pay a little premium, due to meagre supply in Rotterdam,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Coconut oil sellers quoted between $830 to $835 per tonne CIF for November/December shipment on Friday from $820 per tonne on December 9, the trade group United Coconut Associations of the Philippines Inc (UCAP) said.</p>
<p>They asked $780 per tonne CIF for January/February shipments on Friday from $770 to $775 per tonne on December 9, UCAP said.</p>
<p>Philippine traders pegged coconut oil stocks in Rotterdam at 27,000 tonnes as of end of last week from the previous 34,000 tonnes.</p>
<p>Coconut oil requirement in Rotterdam was placed by Philippine vegetable oil traders at 55,000 tonnes a month.</p>
<p>Traders said they only expect one ship, Stolt Sapphire, with a meagre cargo of 3,000 tonnes, to arrive in Rotterdam on December 21.</p>
<p>&quot;Despite prospects of new arrivals in Europe, prices have been holding in the past few days indicating that the cargo of Stolt Sapphire may have been taken up,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>Philippine coconut oil exports from December 1 to 12 reached 65,000 tonnes from 111,466 for the whole month of December 1995, UCAP said.</p>
<p>The state-agency Philippine Coconut Authority said final data indicated coconut oil exports from January to September this year dropped to 590,381 tonnes from 1,050,314 tonnes in the same period last year.</p>
<p>Traders attributed the steep drop in Philippine coconut oil exports to a series of typhoons which ravaged coconut plantations in late 1995.</p>
<p>Philippine coconut oil output is expected to recover in the second quarter of 1997, they said.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
