<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258708" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Mahathir wants higher savings from Malaysians.</title>
<headline>Mahathir wants higher savings from Malaysians.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Mahathir Mohamad said on Monday he wanted Malaysians to achieve a much higher national savings rate than the current 38.8 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to reach 45 percent,&quot; Mahathir said. &quot;Thirty-eight percent, according to most authorities in the world, is fantastic. But we want to be more fantastic.&quot;</p>
<p>Mahathir, speaking after launching a national savings campaign, said he was confident the country could reach the target as many Malaysians still did not plan their savings activities.</p>
<p>In an earlier speech on the same campaign, central bank governor Ahmad Mohamed Don estimated the 1996 national savings rate at 38.8 percent against 36.5 percent the previous year.</p>
<p>But Ahmad said the high savings rate was still below the nation's 1996 investment rate of 45.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;To reduce the gap, the savings rate which we have achieved will have to be raised further,&quot; Ahmad said.</p>
<p>He said to encourage Malaysians to save, new financial products and efficient mechanisms to attract savings will be introduced. He did not elaborate.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-2014813)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
