<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258855" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: World Bank says East Asia economic miracle still alive.</title>
<headline>World Bank says East Asia economic miracle still alive.</headline>
<byline>Alver Carlson</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reports that the East Asian economic miracle that flowered in the 1970s is drawing to a close are highly premature, the World Bank said Monday.</p>
<p>The Bank said that the fundamentals remain in place for the region to continue its economic success into the next century.</p>
<p>&quot;Much of the recent bad news, from the export slowdown to high current account deficits and price falls in some markets, reflects temporary phenomena and does not signal an economic decline,&quot; Bank officials told a briefing for reporters.</p>
<p>The officials said they felt compelled to give their views following various news stories suggesting that the region might at long last be running out of steam.</p>
<p>&quot;Some economies are going through adjustments, but the underlying growth momentum remains extraordinarily strong,&quot; the Bank said in a statement.</p>
<p>At the same, however, it made clear that the region cannot take the stunningly high long-term growth that has been the envy of the world for granted. &quot;The so-called East Asian 'miracle'is not, and has never been, on automatic pilot,&quot; the Bank said, adding that reforms need to continue.</p>
<p>It forecast annual growth in the region of 8 percent for the coming years, with export growth back in the 10-15 percent range beginning next year.</p>
<p>Growth in the region has run at an inflation-adjusted 7 percent annual rate through the 1980s and then, remarkably, accelerated to 9 percent in the current decade.</p>
<p>The Bank also lauded China, which managed to achieve a so-called soft landing for its economy, cooling activity enough to slow inflation, without killing the expansion.</p>
<p>Officials estimated that China could grow as much as 10 percent a year over the next decade if it were to press ahead with needed economic reforms.</p>
<p>Recent events have raised questions about the region's current vitality and its prospects, the Bank said, noting that after years of double-digit growth, exports have been falling in China, South Korea, Singapore and Thailand.</p>
<p>At the same time, deficits in the current account, a measure of economic activity between countries, topped 8 percent of Gross Domestic Product in Malaysia and Thailand in 1995, and could exceed 10 percent in Vietnam this year.</p>
<p>Moreover, the Bank noted that the stock market has fallen 30 percent in Thailand and 20 percent in South Korea this year, while in China, total net profits of state enterprises have fallen to one quarter of their 1995 levels.</p>
<p>But the Bank blamed the problems on the collapse in the market for computer chips, already tightening, some slowing in the economies of the industrial countries, and the depreciation of the Japanese yen, which made Japan more competitive.</p>
<p>&quot;Things are already improving,&quot; the Bank said.</p>
<p>But officials also emphasized that the region still has much to do as it modernizes its economy so that future expansion is guaranteed.</p>
<p>It said a massive amount of infrastrure -- from communications to power generation -- is needed in the region, issues of rising inequality of income distribution in some countries must be addressed, and environmental protection needed a greater role.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EASIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
