<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25887" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CROATIA: Bosnian refugees vote in Croatia ahead of poll.</title>
<headline>Bosnian refugees vote in Croatia ahead of poll.</headline>
<byline>Zoran Radosavljevic</byline>
<dateline>ZAGREB 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Refugees and other Bosnian citizens in Croatia, watched by 260 international monitors, began two days of voting on Saturday in Bosnia's first postwar elections that are likely to shape the country's future.</p>
<p>The in-country election day for Bosnia is September 14. But some 640,000 Bosnian citizens abroad, a vast majority of them refugees from the 1992-95 war, were called on to vote in 55 countries over one week from last Wednesday.</p>
<p>Voting is supposed to lay foundations for the development of democracy in a country torn apart along communal lines, and analysts believe three dominant nationalist Serb, Moslem aand Croat parties were likely to win.</p>
<p>&quot;There is little hope for things to change after this election but still it's better than nothing. It's a step forward,&quot; said Zvonimir Komarica, a Croat refugee from Bosnain Serb northern stronghold of Banja Luka.</p>
<p>Croatian state radio said 117,421 Bosnian citizens in Croatia, over two-thirds of them Croats driven out of north Bosnia during its wartime conquest by separatist Serbs, were eligible to vote at 86 polling stations throughout the country.</p>
<p>Polls opened at 7 a.m. (0500 gmt) and were to close at 7 p.m. (1700 gmt). Voting will be conducted during the same period on Sunday, supervised by 260 OSCE and other international monitors.</p>
<p>Two three-member OSCE supervision teams toured the 18 polling stations, improvised in primary schools and social welfare centres in the Croatian capital on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to make sure that people have secure places to vote, that there are no manipulations, no party posters,&quot; Caroline Katan of one of the OSCE teams, told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We've been to seven polling stations already and we are quite satisfied with what we've seen,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Ballots from all polling places abroad will be sent to the Sarajevo office of the OSCE, which is running the elections, and counted along with those from the in-country voting but final results would not be announced until later in September.</p>
<p>Under the 1995 Dayton peace treaty, Moslem, Serb and Croat citizens of Bosnia living abroad or displaced within Bosnia may vote for representatives in their pre-war addresses.</p>
<p>Three million people in all are called on to elect a three-member Bosnian presidency and multi-ethnic parliament to govern a loose union of Serb and Moslem-Croat entities.</p>
<p>Nationalist Serbs, led by their SDS party, now rule half of Bosnia and a skeletal Moslem-Croat federation the rest.</p>
<p>Analysts say most of the Moslems will probably vote for the Bosnian central government's Moslem nationalist SDA party because of its strong commitment to reintegrating the country and repatriating refugees.</p>
<p>&quot;What we would like to happen most after the election is that we return home but I rather doubt it will be possible,&quot; said Muhamede Huseinspahic, 53, a Moslem from Bosanska Dubica.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect there will still be three separate sides. We'll see whether they will be able to make agreements,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The choice of Croat voters was slightly less certain even though Croatia's ruling nationalist HDZ party dominates most parts of Bosnia where minority Croats still live.</p>
<p>&quot;I've cast my ballot so that in the end Croats get as many votes as possible and we become equal to the other two nations,&quot; said Filip Ivancic, 38, from Tomislavgrad in HDZ-ruled southwestern Bosnia.</p>
<p>But many Croat refugees from Serb-ruled north Bosnia and Moslem-run central Bosnia are embittered by the HDZ's apparent preference to resettle them in depopulated parts of Croatia and west Bosnia rather then return them to their ancestral homes, Western analysts say.</p>
<p>They believe some could vote instead for moderate Croat opposition parties who have accused Croatian President Franjo Tudjman of abandoning refugees from north and central Bosnia in order to consolidate power in the south-west.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CRTIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAGREB"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CROATIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
