<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258869" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Circuit City PC sales weakened sharply.</title>
<headline>Circuit City PC sales weakened sharply.</headline>
<dateline>RICHMOND, Va. 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Circuit City Stores Inc. said Monday that sales of personal computers in its third quarter fell sharply while sales of most consumer electronics products were weak, resulting in lower profits for the period.</p>
<p>Circuit City reported third-quarter earnings of $19.8 million, or 20 cents a share, down from $31.5 million, or 32 cents, a share a year ago.</p>
<p>Overall sales rose 5 percent in the quarter to $1.86 billion from $1.78 billion a year ago, but comparable store sales, which measures results at stores open at least a year, fell 10 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;During the third quarter, sales of personal computers weakened dramatically while sales of most consumer electronic products remained soft, as they have throughout the year,&quot; Richard Sharp, Circuit City's chairman, said in a statement accompanying the results.</p>
<p>Circuit City said a more profitable merchandise mix, including comparable store sales growth in major appliances, digital satellite system and big-screen televisions, offset lower gross profit margins that resulted from an intense promotional climate.</p>
<p>&quot;Our inventory control systems have enabled us to closely manage product supply, placing us in an excellent quarter-end position despite lower-than-anticipated sales,&quot; Sharp said.</p>
<p>&quot;Although the industry climate remains challenging, we are pleased that the Circuit City Superstores are effectively selling a more profitable merchandise mix,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Circuit City opened 36 stores in the third quarter.</p>
<p>For the nine-month period, Richmond, Va.-based Circuit City said profits were $68.2 million, or 69 cents a share, vs. $97.3 million, or 99 cents a share, in the first nine months of last year. Total sales rose 10 percent for the period to $5.25 billion from $4.78 billion, while comparable store sales fell 7 percent.</p>
<p>Its stock fell $1.25 to $29.75 on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C151">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RICHMOND, Va."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
