<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258871" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Cooley pleads not guilty to charge he lied to voters.</title>
<headline>Cooley pleads not guilty to charge he lied to voters.</headline>
<dateline>SALEM, Ore. 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Republican Representative Wes Cooley pleaded not guilty Monday to charges he lied to Oregon voters about his Korean War experience.</p>
<p>Through his lawyer Cooley said he was innocent of two counts of knowingly making false statements to voters in official state pamphlets distributed before his 1994 election to a first term.</p>
<p>Cooley, who is in his last month as congressman, was unopposed in this year's primary and was nominated to serve a second term representing eastern Oregon's vast second district. But he withdrew under heavy pressure from state party leaders over the allegations.</p>
<p>Republican Bob Smith was nominated to replace Cooley on the ballot and easily won election last month.</p>
<p>Cooley could face up to five years in prison and fines of up to $100,000 on each count under the felony indictment handed up last week by a state grand jury.</p>
<p>After the brief hearing before Marion County Circuit Judge Albin Norblad, Cooley's lawyer Walter Todd said his client did nothing wrong when he said in the voter's pamphlet that he served in &quot;Army Special Forces, Korea.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;That is not a false statement,&quot; Todd said.</p>
<p>Cooley has been unable to provide any proof he served in the elite force, known as the Green Berets, and at least one Army officer contradicted him.</p>
<p>Cooley, uncharacteristically reticent since the indictment, offered little comment outside the courthouse in the state capitol, where he was greeted by a handful of sign-carrying supporters.</p>
<p>&quot;My husband hasn't done anything wrong,&quot; said Cooley's wife, Rosemary. &quot;The press has indicted him.&quot;</p>
<p>A separate federal grand jury is investigating whether Rosemary Cooley improperly collected military widow's benefits while the two were living together and presenting themselves as a married couple.</p>
<p>Todd requested a trial by jury. Cooley was released without bail.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALEM, Ore."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
