<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25897" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>CUBA: United States repatriates 15 Cubans.</title>
<headline>United States repatriates 15 Cubans.</headline>
<dateline>HAVANA 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>Fifteen Cubans who were attempting to flee the island in a boat were returned to Cuba on Saturday by a U.S Coast Guard vessel that intercepted the would-be exiles in the Straits of Florida, Prensa Latina reported.</p>
<p>In 1995 Washington and Havana signed an agreement that called for the repatriation of all illegal Cuban emigrants who are picked up at sea by U.S vessels or cross into the U.S Naval Base at Guantanamo in southeast Cuba. At the same time, the Cuban government pledged to prevent all illegal departures for the United States.</p>
<p>The accords put an end to Washington's long-standing policy of accepting automatically all Cubans who fled to Florida.</p>
<p>The Clinton administration signed the accord in order to put a stop to the wave of uninvited Cuban immigrants who set out in rafts and boats for U.S shores.</p>
<p>During the summer of 1994 more than 30,000 &quot;rafters&quot; crossed the Straits of Florida or were picked up by the U.S Coast Guard and sent to the United States Naval Base at Guantanamo in southeast Cuba.</p>
<p>Under the accord with Havana, Washington also agreed to facilitate legal immigration by guaranteeing that at least 20,000 entry visas a year would be given to Cubans. At the same time it allowed virtually all of the detainees at the Guantanamo Base to enter the United States.</p>
<p>Since the accords were signed in May 1995, the United States has repatriated 309 Cubans picked up at sea and another 98 that crossed into the U.S Naval Base at Guantanamo.</p>
<p>Earlier this month Cuba demanded that Washington honour the immigration accords fully by repatriating a group of Cubans who had fled the island in a wooden boat that capsized south of Marathon, Florida.</p>
<p>Eight of the Cubans were given asylum by the United States and three others were sent to the Guantanamo Naval base to await permission to enter a third country. Sixteen passengers on the same boat were sent back to Cuba.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CUBA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAVANA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CUBA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
