<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="258948" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sprint launches PCS, says rollout on target.</title>
<headline>Sprint launches PCS, says rollout on target.</headline>
<dateline>KANSAS CITY, Mo. 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sprint PCS, a joint venture between Sprint Corp and three cable television companies, said Monday it launched its Personal Communications Services (PCS) wireless phone service in four metropolitan areas.</p>
<p>It is on track to hook up 65 cities by mid-1997.</p>
<p>Sprint delayed the launch of its nationwide PCS service and twice lowered its targets for the number of cities on line, after running into problems with the Northern Telecom Ltd (NorTel) software it is using. But the company said it does not feel it is behind schedule.  </p>
<p>&quot;We believe providing Sprint PCS service is not a race to the starting line but rather a race to the finish line,&quot; Andrew Sukawaty, chief executive of Sprint PCS, said in a conference call with analysts.</p>
<p>&quot;...We've always felt that being within months of the other carriers coming into the market was the key target, and we're hitting those,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Sprint PCS today launched its service in Fresno, Calif., Milwaukee, Wis., Portland, Ore. and Spokane, Wash.  </p>
<p>Sprint PCS is a joint venture of Sprint Corp, Tele-Communications Inc, Cox Communications Inc and Comcast Corp.</p>
<p>Last month, PrimeCo, a venture owned by Airtouch Communications Inc and three regional Bell Companies, launched its PCS service in 16 cities.</p>
<p>PCS operates on a different frequency than cellular and is said to provide clear voice quality, fewer dropped calls and more security. Sprint PCS service is digital and based on the code division multiple acces (CDMA) network infrastructure, which was provided by Lucent Technologies and Nortel.</p>
<p>Sprint PCS's new service is part of its entrance in the PCS market nationwide. The venture, which has invested &quot;billions of dollars&quot; in the service, said it will launch up to four more markets by the end of the year and have a total of 65 markets by mid 1997.</p>
<p>&quot;In the first quarter of 1997, the pace of Sprint PCS launches will pick up considerably,&quot; Sukawaty said.</p>
<p>In addition, Sprint PCS said its prices are five to 10 percent lower than cellular phone service.</p>
<p>Sprint said the markets launched today use Lucent CDMA technology.  </p>
<p>In November 1995, Sprint PCS launched its first PCS service in the Washington D.C./Baltimore area through its affiliate Sprint Spectrum. That service uses time division multiple access (TDMA) technology, however, and is incompatible with CDMA.</p>
<p>Sprint PCS originally forecast 20 to 25 markets would be live by end-1996, but now sees at most eight.</p>
<p>Other cities, including New York, San Francisco, Dallas/Ft. Worth, Boston, Miami, Minneapolis/St. Paul, Denver, Seattle and Kansas City, will be started on a market-by-market basis in the first half of 1997, as part of its first phase of Sprint PCS.</p>
<p>During the second phase, Sprint PCS said it will expand existing coverage and fill in service in areas where it currently does not have licenses. It said it is the top bidder in Federal Communications Commission PCS auctions in all areas where it currently  does not have licences. It said it is the top bidder in Federal Communications Commission PCS auctions in all areas currently not covered by Sprint PCS.</p>
<p>Phones for the service have a suggested retail price of $199. They are produced by QUALCOMM Personal Electronics, a joint venture of QUALCOMM Inc and Sony Corp's Sony Electronics Inc.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34410">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I97400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KANSAS CITY, Mo."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
