<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259098" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Farm ministers to tackle veterinary package on Tuesday.</title>
<headline>Farm ministers to tackle veterinary package on Tuesday.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Farm ministers will try to tie up a veterinary package when they resume a two-day meeting at 1030/ 0930 GMT on Tuesday, an EU official said.</p>
<p>Bilateral talks were continuing as the Irish EU presidency tried to carve out a compromise agreement on phasing out veal crates and improving the diet of calves.</p>
<p>But chances of success looked slim, with French and Italian farmers leading protests that the changes would result in crippling extra costs and darken the white meat prized by consumers.</p>
<p>A Commission proposal to ban tissue from sheep, goats and cattle believed to be infected with either scrapie or mad cow disease was likely to be rejected, officials added.</p>
<p>A majority of member states, led by Germany, believe that the measures are excessive given that their livestock is free of either disease.</p>
<p>But Farm Commissioner Franz Fischler, noting that recent British and French research has shown that sheep can be infected with mad cow disease, has argued that no country is risk-free and that public health must be protected at all cost.</p>
<p>British Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg is due to report to the Farm Council on progress in eradicating mad cow disease, on plans to implement a selective cull of an extra 100,000 cattle most at risk and the next step in easing a ban on British beef.</p>
<p>Although Britain will only formally present proposals to the Commission early in 1997, it wants firstly to relax curbs on cattle certified to be free of mad cow disease.</p>
<p>Grass-fed herds in Northern Ireland, where a computerised tracking system has operated for the past six years, would be the first to benefit.</p>
<p>The Farm Council is due to adjourn at 1230/1130 GMT to sign an agreement with New Zealand on the mutual recognition of veterinary standards, the first in a series the EU is negotiating with its main trading partners.</p>
<p>Ministers are then invited to a luncheon to mark the 100th anniversary of the Verona agri-food fair at the Brussels Europa Hotel.</p>
<p>The Farm Council is expected to end by 2000/1900 GMT when the Irish hold a reception to celebrate the end of their six-month presidency.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
