<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259062" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Hearings but no vote seen likely on US tax reform.</title>
<headline>Hearings but no vote seen likely on US tax reform.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. House Ways and Means Committee will continue to hold hearings on major tax reform proposals in the 105th Congress, but further action is unlikely this session, two key committee members said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a long-term journey,&quot; Rep. Bill Thomas, R-Calif., told state legislators meeting here. &quot;We don't know where it's going to end,&quot; he said, noting that the Ways and Means panel held five oversight hearings on the issue last year and plans another &quot;series&quot; this term.</p>
<p>But, even if Congress went no further than hearings, it would be &quot;a very positive process,&quot; Thomas said.  </p>
<p>&quot;When you focus on other ways of doing what you are doing now, what you are doing sometimes doesn't seem as bad.&quot;</p>
<p>Rep. Benjamin Cardin, D-Md., also predicted that &quot;very little will happen on major tax reform in this Congress.&quot;</p>
<p>Cardin said, &quot;The President has no real interest in the subject.  And there is tremendous political opposition to any significant change in the income tax structure,&quot; the former Maryland state legislator added.</p>
<p>But Cardin strongly urged state and local government officials to stay involved in the debate.  </p>
<p>&quot;My message is that, no, we are not going to pass a significant change next year.  But you need to be with us debating this issue, because one day we might do that,&quot; Cardin warned.</p>
<p>Thomas said the Ways and Means panel, chaired by Rep. Bill Archer, R-Texas, a staunch backer of radical tax reform, plans a &quot;series of hearings&quot; in the 105th Congress, which convenes in early January.</p>
<p>Sessions will examine the impacts of major tax reform on individual and families, employee benefits and retirement and personal savings incentives, homeowners and real estate, agriculture, retail sales, banks, service industries and health care.</p>
<p>Ways and Means held five hearings last year on problems with the current system; various alternatives to the system; and impacts on small businesses, state and local governments and tax-exempt entities; international competitiveness; manufacturing; and energy and natural resources.</p>
<p>--Vicky Stamas, 202-898-8314</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
