<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259296" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SRI LANKA: New 51 MW plant boosts Sri Lanka's power plans.</title>
<headline>New 51 MW plant boosts Sri Lanka's power plans.</headline>
<byline>Mohan Samarasinghe</byline>
<dateline>COLOMBO 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>KHD Great Britain, a unit of Germany's Kloeckner- Humboldt-Deutz AG, has signed an agreement with the Sri Lankan government to build a 51 megawatt power plant on the island, company officials said on Sunday.</p>
<p>The $62 million diesel-powered plant, to function on a build, own and operate (BOO) basis, is scheduled to begin generating by mid-1998, David Emmas, general manager of KHD Great Britain Ltd told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;We have signed an agreement, which enables us to generate and sell electricity to the national grid,&quot; Emmas said.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka' state-owned power utility Ceylon Electricity Board (CEB) will purchase the company's total power output at about 6.5 dollar cents per kilowatt hour, he said.</p>
<p>Emmas added KHD's plant, to be located in the Colombo suburb of Sapugaskanda, would add approximately 16.5 percent more power to the Indian Ocean island's grid. The island has a total power generating capacity of about 1,250 MW.</p>
<p>The plant will be operated by Burmeister &amp; Wain Scandinavian Contractor A/S, an equity partner of the project, Emmas said.</p>
<p>Tropical Sri Lanka plans several such thermal power plants to reduce its current dependence on hydroelectricity, after business and industry were crippled earlier this year by a severe power shortage due to drought.</p>
<p>Sri Lanka relies on two monsoons to fill the reservoirs that are used for the production of 84 percent of its electricity. But the winter northeast monsoon failed and the southwest monsoon was delayed, breaking almost two months late.</p>
<p>Now, Sri Lanka says it plans to invest up to $2 billion to more than double its current electricity generating capacity over the next 10 years and that it will switch from hydropower to coal to meet future energy needs.</p>
<p>A CEB official said plans were afoot to add about 1,600 MW of power to the national grid by 2006, but only one new hydroelectric plant.</p>
<p>&quot;Most of it will be done by bringing in private investors who will invest in diesel, gas turbine, combined cycle (a combination of gas and steam turbines) and coal power plants,&quot; said the official who wished to remain unidentified.</p>
<p>Italy's Fiat Avio, a unit of Fiat SpA, is building a 115 MW gas turbine plant at the CEB's Kelanitissa power station to come on stream by mid-1997 while Germany's MAN B&amp;W Diesel AG, part of the MAN AG group, is building a 40 MW diesel plant to be commissioned around the same time.</p>
<p>The CEB will go ahead with plans to build a 70 MW hydroelectric plant in the central hills, but has shelved a 150 MW hydropower plant in that region for environmental reasons.</p>
<p>Officials said foreign investors were also being invited to build a 300 MW coal power plant near the eastern port of Trincomalee, estimated to cost $800 million.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SRILAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020044">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COLOMBO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SRI LANKA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
