<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259230" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - December 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indian newspapers - December 16.</headline>
<text>
<p>Following is a summary of major Indian business and political stories in leading newspapers prepared for REUTERS by Business News and Information Services Pvt Ltd, New Delhi Tel:3324842, 3351006, 3761233 Fax:+91-11-3351006 Internet: biznis@giasbm01.vsnl.net.in</p>
<p>Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>		   -------oo0oo-------</p>
<p>			TOP STORIES</p>
<p>The Hindustan Times</p>
<p>CONGRESS TO REVIEW PERFORMANCE OF GOVERNMENT</p>
<p>The Congress Working Committee will hold a crucial meeting on Wednesday to review the performance of the government.</p>
<p>Announcing this, Congress president Sitaram Kesri said the party would thereafter, if necessary, rethink about its support to the government.</p>
<p>Kesri, however, made it clear that at the present moment the question of withdrawing support to the government did not arise. The party would review its support only if it found that the government was not in the interests of the nation, the Congress chief added.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Times Of India</p>
<p>MINISTER FAVOURS INCREASE IN PETROL PRICES</p>
<p>The country's debt situation would worsen if petrol prices were not increased, railway minister Ram Vilas Paswan said.</p>
<p>If petrol prices were not increased immediately, India's foreign debt would increase by a further 150 billion rupees within six months, he said.</p>
<p>The minister also hinted that there was a difference of opinion among cabinet ministers over the United Front steering committee's decision to provide essential commodities at half price to the poor through the public distribution system.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Financial Express</p>
<p>INFLATION UP AT 6.8 PCT</p>
<p>The annual rate of inflation continued its unabated rise for the third successive week. It gained 0.11 percentage points to touch 6.8 percent for the week ended November 30.</p>
<p>The wholesale price index, however, declined for the second consecutive week. Prior to the upward movement in recent weeks, inflation showed a mixed trend as it moved up and down the price indices ladder.</p>
<p>FOREIGN BORROWINGS FOR TELECOM SECTOR TO BE HIKED</p>
<p>The finance ministry plans to raise the ceiling on external commercial borrowings (ECB) for the telecommunications sector from 35 to 50 percent of the total project cost.</p>
<p>The ministry is also putting together a new set of ECB norms for investments in the ports sector for which a privatisation policy was recently announced. Sources said the highways projects would also be covered by independent ECB norms.</p>
<p>HOECHST TO PUMP 17.6 BLN RUPEES INTO INDIA</p>
<p>The German chemicals giant, Hoechst AG, is exploring new areas of expansion in its Indian operations. These include basic chemicals, engineering plastics, food packaging, polyester films and master-batches.</p>
<p>Sources said the company would invest DM 800 million in the next five years in India. This would be part of the total investment of DM 2.5 billion planned during this period in Asia, sources added.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>Business Standard</p>
<p>MARUTI PLANS $250 MLN RUPEE ISSUE NEXT YEAR</p>
<p>Maruti Udyog Ltd (MUL) plans to float a $250 million issue on the overseas capital markets in the middle of next year.</p>
<p>The proceeds from the issue, which would not be convertible into Indian equity, would be used to fund MUL's capacity expansion and modernisation plans.</p>
<p>However, the company has yet to decide whether to go to the Euro-markets or adopt the American Depository Receipts route.</p>
<p>TAKEOVER CODE TO BE DELAYED</p>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Board of India's (SEBI) new takeover code is not expected to be in place before the next two months. The code is also unlikely to give up the 20 percent minimum public offer clause despite demands for 100 percent mandatory offers.</p>
<p>The new regulations may also stipulate a slab-wise escrow deposit to be maintained by a company making a takeover bid. SEBI officials say the new regulations would be completed only after submission of justice P.N. Bhagwati's report on takeover code.  </p>
<p>LIVESTOCK POLICY DRAFT READY</p>
<p>The country's first-ever live-stock policy's draft is almost ready. The draft policy calls for the continuation of present regulations on milk production and dairy industry.</p>
<p>It also seeks a greater private role in the creation of infrastructure to develop animal husbandry on scientific lines.</p>
<p>The code aims at making India the leading player in the global market for livestock products by exploiting the country's inherent competitive advantages in the export of live animals, meat, milk products and other items.</p>
<p>PYRAMID STRUCTURE FOR RPG TELECOM FIRMS</p>
<p>The R P Goenka group is recasting its telecommunication business into a two-tiered holding company structure.</p>
<p>For the first time in the country, the Calcutta group will put in place holding companies at two levels under which the telecommunication service licensees will be subsidiaries.</p>
<p>The RPG group will control all its telecommunication services projects through an apex holding company - RPG Communications Ltd (RCL). RCL will have two subsidiaries, RPG Telecommunications (RTL) and RPG Mobile Ltd (RML).</p>
<p>In turn, RTL and RML will both be holding companies for the group's fixed and wireless telecommunication service businesses respectively.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Economic Times</p>
<p>IBRD SHRINKS FROM INFRASTRUCTURE AGENCY PLAN</p>
<p>The proposal to set up the Infrastructure Development Finance Company (IDFC) ran into trouble as major multilateral lenders like the World Bank and OECF refused to associate with the agency.</p>
<p>The multilateral agencies had earlier hinted that they would provide credit of more than 30 billion rupees to IDFC. Sources said the World Bank and OECF had hardened their stand in wake of states' inability to effect infrastructure reforms.</p>
<p>They had reiterated their stiff conditionalities including reforms in the infrastructure sector, especially the state electricity boards and the state road transport corporations.</p>
<p>MINIMUM ALTERNATE TAX TO GO AFTER NEW TAX LAWS</p>
<p>Finance minister P. Chidambaram said the controversial minimum alternate tax (MAT) might be removed after redrafting of the Company Law and the Income Tax Act.</p>
<p>He said redrafted tax laws would bring about a better alignment between the two and then MAT might be allowed to disappear. He said MAT had been introduced as a large number of companies had been paying higher dividends but not paying tax.</p>
<p>APEX BANK CLEANS CLOGGED-UP CREDIT TAP</p>
<p>Reserve Bank of India (RBI), the central bank, asked public sector bank managements to allow bank officials at various levels to lend beyond their discretionary limits.</p>
<p>RBI also asked managements to give more powers to bank officials to meet exceptional and emergent requirement of the borrowers. Sources said the RBI move was aimed at easing the credit crisis in the economy.</p>
<p>The central bank also sought half-year reviews of large advances sanctioned by bank chairmen and executive directors to ensure that they were working within their delegated powers.</p>
<p>----</p>
<p>The Observer of Business and Politics</p>
<p>TELECOM DEPARTMENT COMES TO ITI'S RESCUE</p>
<p>Loss-making public sector unit ITI Ltd may not have to go to the Board for Industrial and Financial Reconstruction.</p>
<p>This is because the Department of Telecommunications (DoT) has decided to support ITI's turnaround plan and give it advance purchase orders. A major advance has been the assurance on social costs which had consumed half the company's capital.</p>
<p>A communication ministry panel would look into this. The ITI was also assured advance purchase orders of 119,000 telephone exchange lines of the 1.3-million-line order the DoT is going to place with several vendors, taking the total orders for telephone exchange lines for the year to 370,000.</p>
<p>NEW EXPLORATION POLICY TO END PUBLIC SECTOR FIRMS' MONOPOLY</p>
<p>The new exploration policy is likely to end the monopoly of upstream national oil companies on oil and gas exploration in the country.</p>
<p>The petroleum ministry has proposed alloting a fixed time of five to seven years for the discovery of oil and gas in a particular field or block to companies in upstream sectors where oil and gas reserves have been found to exist after surveys.</p>
<p>According to current policy, the oil and gas fields already discovered can be used for exploration by companies such as the Oil and Natural Gas Corporation and Oil India Ltd for a period of 20 years or even more.</p>
<p>----</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
