<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259335" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Placer may drop Highlands bid.</title>
<headline>Placer may drop Highlands bid.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Placer Dome Inc said it will drop its A$0.75 a share takeover bid for Highlands Gold Ltd if Highlands proceeds with a legal suit against the offer.</p>
<p>Placer Dome has dropped the offer conditions, for all shareholders to ensure that Highlands shareholders can accept the offer with certainty if they wish to do so.</p>
<p>The cash settlement period has been reduced to five business days from 30 days, Placer said.</p>
<p>&quot;The offer is open now, but due to the threat of legal action I can offer no guarantees as to how long the offer will remain open,&quot; Placer Chief Executive John Willson said.  </p>
<p>On Friday, lawyers for Highlands Gold said the company would take legal action in Australia and Papua New Guinea if Placer did not amend alleged defects in its offer document.</p>
<p>Highlands lawyers said in a letter to Placer Dome that the Australian mining concern would take Placer to court if the Canadian miner did not give shareholders information about its involvement in Highlands, including its involvement in the Porgera gold mine in Papua New Guinea and Placer's intentions towards Highlands or intended changes.</p>
<p>((Reuters Toronto Bureau 416 941-8100))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I21000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
