<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259313" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Major hopes to avert Euro defeat in parliament.</title>
<headline>Major hopes to avert Euro defeat in parliament.</headline>
<byline>Gerrard Raven</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major appeared on Monday to be gaining support ahead of the first parliamentary test of his government's unity since it lost its overall majority in the House of Commons.</p>
<p>A vote at 2200 GMT on the government's stance on the European Union's fishing policy will put the new parliamentary position on trial for the only time before MPs begin a three-week Christmas break on Wednesday night.</p>
<p>A defeat would be embarrassing rather than fatal for the Conservatives although it would be open to the opposition Labour Party to put down a confidence motion to be debated on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Labour's senior parliamentary business manager Donald Dewar said before the debate began: &quot;I think we will meet that when we come to it. But it is certainly a possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Fisheries minister Tony Baldry declined to forecast a government win. &quot;I think it is self-evident in the House of Commons now with very tight arithmetic that every vote is going to be very tight,&quot; he told BBC radio.</p>
<p>But there were indications that a vital group of Eurosceptic Conservatives and the nine-strong contingent of Ulster Unionist MPs might give the government enough backing on the fisheries issue, a highly emotive subject for many MPs, for it to win.</p>
<p>Ulster Unionist deputy leader John Taylor said fisheries minister Tony Baldry had written to him pledging moves to give Northern Ireland trawlermen the right to fish more extensively.</p>
<p>&quot;The Labour Party can only get our support if they in turn support our local fishing industry,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>And Teddy Taylor, a member of the faction in the Conservative party against any further integration with the European Union, indicated they might not stage a rebellion.</p>
<p>&quot;We have had some clear indications the government do accept that there is a real crisis facing the British fishing industry because of the (European Union), and that the government has got to do something about it,&quot; Taylor said.</p>
<p>Eurosceptic Conservatives claim Europe's fishing policy is decimating the British industry and allowing foreign-owned boats to scoop up catches which should be theirs.</p>
<p>Major, reporting to parliament on the EU summit in Dublin at the weekend, said he emphasised the need to reform the policy to stop foreign fishermen setting up business in Britain and taking part of Britain's catch -- a practice known as quota-hopping.</p>
<p>But aides said Major was relaxed ahead of the vote, and was planning to attend a Christmas party at Conservative headquarters rather than trying to persuade MPs to back him.</p>
<p>A slip-up in parliament could force Major into an early general election following a by-election last week which left the Conservatives level in terms of seats - 323 - in the lower House of Commons with the combined forces of the opposition.</p>
<p>He has indicated that he has in mind an election on May 1, just three weeks before the last possible date.</p>
<p>Major was defeated by two in an similar parliamentary vote on fishing a year ago. Since then his party's position in parliament has worsened because of defections and by-election losses.</p>
<p>The government is riven by divisions over Europe, and with his party over 20 points behind Tony Blair's Labour in the opinion polls, Major is desperate to avoid an early election.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
