<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259337" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: OECD sees Canada's 1997 GDP growth at 3.3 pct.</title>
<headline>OECD sees Canada's 1997 GDP growth at 3.3 pct.</headline>
<dateline>OTTAWA 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Canada's improving fundamentals should provide enough momentum for stronger growth next year, despite continuing fiscal restraint and a slower than expected expansion in the United States, the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) said in a report released on Monday.</p>
<p>The OECD saw gross domestic product (GDP) at market prices rising 1.5 percent this year and forecast it more than doubling to 3.3 percent in 1997. In 1995 GDP grew 2.3 percent.</p>
<p>The organization pegged Canada's unemployment rate at 9.6 percent in 1996 and at 9.4 percent in 1997.  </p>
<p>The OECD noted Canada's low inflation and continuing fiscal consolidation at both federal and provincial levels which had created the conditions for the lowest interest rates in the country in decades.</p>
<p>The organization said interest rate-sensitive industries have benefitted from this and have stepped up job creation. But declines in public sector employment together with a growing labor force have offset such gains, keeping the unemployment rate at a relatively high 9.5 to 10.0 percent level.  </p>
<p>Inflation in Canada was likely to remain in the lower half of the central bank's 1.0 to 3.0 percent target range, the OECD said, largely due to the slack in the labor market, as well as Canada's widening output gap.</p>
<p>The country's favorable inflation performance, together with its increased competitiveness in export markets and slower import growth have brought about a marked improvement in Canada's current account.</p>
<p>Canada posted current account surpluses in the second and third quarters this year, marking the first such development since 1984.  </p>
<p>The OECD also said that Canada's low inflation, progress in cutting federal and provincial deficits and the reduced threat of Quebec separatism have increased financial markets' confidence in the country and have contributed to a more stable Canadian dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;This has allowed the Bank of Canada to lower short-term interest rates to levels well below those prevailing in the United States,&quot; the OECD said.</p>
<p>Low short-term rates have pulled down interest spreads all along the yield curve and now interest rates on maturities for up to 10 years are below those in the United States.  </p>
<p>Interest rates on longer-term bonds have also declined significantly and are currently at just under 30 basis points, their lowest level since mid-1984, the OECD said.</p>
<p>A basis point is 1/100 of a percentage point.</p>
<p>The OECD said its projections were based on the assumption that the economic fundamentals would allow the Bank of Canada not to follow an eventual modest increase in interest rates in the United States.</p>
<p>This should lead to further declines in long-term interest rates, eventually bringing Canadian rates below their U.S. counterparts.  </p>
<p>The organization said Canada's public debt-to-GDP ratio should begin to decline in 1997 but that it would be a while before it approaches the OECD average.</p>
<p>&quot;With fiscal restraint ongoing and the cyclical component of the deficit declining, general government finances (on a national acocunts basis) are projected by the OECD Secretariat to approach balance by the end of 1998,&quot; the organization said.</p>
<p>				  1997    1997    1998</p>
<p>GDP at market prices	1.5     3.3     3.3</p>
<p>Industrial production     1.4     4.0     3.9</p>
<p>Unemployment rate	   9.6     9.4     9.2</p>
<p>GDP deflator		  1.0     1.5     1.5</p>
<p>Note: All figures are percentage changes from previous period, seasonally adjusted at annual rates. ((Malina Poshtova Zang, Reuters Ottawa Bureau, 613-235-6745))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="OECD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OTTAWA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
