<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259434" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Mallinckrodt to pay Molecular Biosystems.</title>
<headline>Mallinckrodt to pay Molecular Biosystems.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mallinckrodt Inc will pay fees of up to $12.9 million plus 40 percent of product sales to cover royalties and manufacturing to Molecular Biosystems Inc under an expanded marketing agreement, the firms said Monday.</p>
<p>Mallinckrodt's sales and marketing rights for Molecular's second-generation ultrasound imaging agent FS069 have been expanded to include Europe, Africa, India and Russia, they said.  </p>
<p>FS069 is designed to enhance ultrasound imaging by enabling physicians to visualize blood flow and enhance resolution of anatomical structures.</p>
<p>The companies anticipate filing for European market clearance for FS069 in early 1997, they said.</p>
<p>Molecular and Mallinckrodt announced in October that a pre-marketing approval application for FS069 has been submitted to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration.</p>
<p>Mallinckrodt holds extensive marketing rights for FS069 and for Molecular's ultrasound imaging agent Albunex.  </p>
<p>Albunex is the first ultrasound imaging agent to be cleared for marketing in the United States.</p>
<p>The new agreement also covers future ultrasound contrast agents that Molecular has in development.</p>
<p>Of the amount Mallinckrodt will pay to San Diego, Calif.-based Molecular, $7.1 million is payable within 30 days, with the remainder contingent upon certain milestones being met, the companies said.</p>
<p>((-- Chicago Newsdesk 312-408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
