<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259660" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Britain expected to slaughter more cattle.</title>
<headline>Britain expected to slaughter more cattle.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain was expected to announce plans on Monday for a selective slaughter of a further 100,000 cattle in a bid to bring forward a lifting of a European Union export ban on British beef.</p>
<p>Political sources said Agriculture Minister Douglas Hogg was planning to make a statement to parliament on Monday before flying to Brussels for an EU farm ministers meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>A selective cull of 147,000 cattle was agreed by Prime Minister John Major with other EU heads of government at the Florence summit last June as part of a package to end the crisis over mad cow disease.</p>
<p>The EU imposed a ban on British beef exports in March after the British government disclosed that the disease, known medically as Bovine Spongiform Encephalopathy (BSE), could spread to people who ate infected beef.</p>
<p>But Britain said in September it was suspending the scheme after fresh scientific evidence suggested that BSE would be eradicated by the year 2001 under existing measures.</p>
<p>The EU has however made clear there could be no progress on lifting the export ban until the cull was carried out.</p>
<p>Political sources said they hoped that the decision to go ahead with at least part of the cull would in turn pave the way for the lifting of an export ban on so-called &quot;certified herds&quot; -- BSE-free, grass-fed cattle mostly found in Northern Ireland and Scotland.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C312">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
