<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259628" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Euro products outlook - Iraq takes edge off freeze.</title>
<headline>Euro products outlook - Iraq takes edge off freeze.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-13</dateline>
<text>
<p>The resumption of Iraqi oil exports this week may keep a tight lid on product values but forecasts of cold European and U.S. weather could provide a bullish counterbalance to fuel oil and gas oil, traders said.</p>
<p>Baghdad's first crude exports to world markets in six years were being loaded on Monday at the Turkish port of Ceyhan.</p>
<p>Gas oil traders said that, barring severe cold, European oversupply and flat demand would continue to loom large, contributing to a bearish tone set last week by the launch of Iraqi exports and higher European and U.S. stocks.</p>
<p>&quot;If it gets cold, the market could start buying,&quot; one said</p>
<p>But he added that major new German heating oil demand was unlikely because most clients appear covered and reluctant to add big costs to their 1996 figures with the market in backwardation.</p>
<p>Main focus was expected to be an arbitrage to Asia. Heating oil cargo premiums are seen at premiums of around $6 above the January IPE gas oil contract, Russians about $2.50 above and low sulphur diesel at $15 over.</p>
<p>Naphtha prices are expected to hold steady in quiet trade, subject to, but lagging behind, fluctuations in crude futures with little impetus to push the market either way.</p>
<p>&quot;Effectively the market is balanced to long, but it's illiquid with few buyers and no aggressive sellers&quot;, one trader said.</p>
<p>Traders expected to see some buying for top-up parcels but most players are thought covered to year-end. Paraffinic and full range material looked balanced to over-supplied while weak gasoline markets continued to curb demand for N+A grade.</p>
<p>Gasoline direction will depend on continued transatlantic arbitrage activity with European demand staying thin and refiner stocks creeping higher, traders said.</p>
<p>Most prompt cargo avails were cleared up last week.</p>
<p>But the barge market will continue to look for transatlantic arbitrage to balance the dead European inland demand</p>
<p>However, expensive shipping costs with freight space tight may continue to limit arbitrage activity and prices could resume a downtrend that last week saw them tumble around $16 a tonne.</p>
<p>High sulphur cracked fuel oil shed most of its length last week and no sharp losses are anticipated. But end-user demand will stay almost non-existant for Dec barrels with little pressure on buyers to come into the market.</p>
<p>&quot;When prices fell alongside crude (last week) it brought some potential buyers out of the woodwork.</p>
<p>&quot;But they have now gone back in,&quot; said one trader.</p>
<p>Relative to crude, fuel oil had potential to lose ground with much depending on the weather. If it turns colder it will give support and probably herald the end of Russian straight run supplies, traders think.</p>
<p>Low sulphur looked stable. With the main Med buyer relaxed, Dec barrels may prove harder to shift. Low sulphur has potential to fall relative to high -- the spread of about $21 a tonne compares with $14 year-ago. But most dealers feel prices will sit a touch below $130 fob NWE, given steady crude.</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7646</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-13"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
