<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259677" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Former U.S. secretaries of state criticise Israel.</title>
<headline>Former U.S. secretaries of state criticise Israel.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three former U.S. secretaries of state and five other former American officials have urged Israel in a letter to refrain from expanding Jewish settlements in the West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<p>&quot;We write because we are concerned that unilateral actions, such as the expansion of settlements, would be strongly counterproductive to the goal of a negotiated solution,&quot; said the letter, addressed to Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office and dated December 14.</p>
<p>&quot;We, therefore, urge you as Prime Miniser of the State of Israel, just as we also urge all on the Arab side, not to take unilateral actions that would preclude a meaningful negotiated settlement and a comprehensive and lasting peace,&quot; said the letter, a copy of which a Netanyahu spokesman faxed to Reuters.</p>
<p>The letter was signed by former secretaries of state James Baker, Lawrence Eagleburger and Cyrus Vance along with former senior government officials Zbigniew Brzezinski, Frank Carlucci, Brent Scowcroft, Richard Fairbanks and Robert Strauss.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's communications director David Bar-Illan said in response that most of the letter's signatories were not known as friends of Israel.</p>
<p>&quot;These eight people were known as not the most friendly to Israel to say the least...Israel's real friends not only refused to sign this letter but are expressing their support for our policies all the time,&quot; Bar-Illan told Israel's army radio.</p>
<p>He said former secretaries of state George Shultz and Henry Kissinger refused to add their names to the letter.</p>
<p>Around 130,000 Jewish settlers live in the West Bank and Gaza Strip, which Israel captured from the Arabs in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Netanyahu's government, formed in June, has angered Israel's Arab peace partners by approving construction of thousands of new homes in the settlements and reinstating financial benefits for settlers in the West Bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
