<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259607" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WORLD BONDS - EMU pact to refuel high-yield rally.</title>
<headline>WORLD BONDS - EMU pact to refuel high-yield rally.</headline>
<byline>Jacqueline Thorpe</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>High yielding bond markets like Spain and Italy will continue to rally against German debt, emboldened by a pact to enforce fiscal discipline once a single European currency is in place, analysts said on Monday.</p>
<p>The pact, hammered out on Friday, brings a credible European Economic and Monetary Union (EMU), closer to fruition and that should fuel further convergence of high yielders against Bunds.</p>
<p>&quot;The expectations that EMU will happen have been strengthened by this pact. The convergence game goes on,&quot; said Klaus Baader at Deustche Morgan Grenfell in London.</p>
<p>The &quot;stability and growth&quot; pact is designed to discourage countries from straying away from the strict rules of EMU once they are sheltered within a single currency starting in 1999.</p>
<p>Countries will be fined if their deficits slip past the three percent to GDP target spelled out under EMU, unless their economies shrink by a severe two percent.</p>
<p>If their economies shrink by between 0.75 percent and two percent they must be able to prove the downturn was forced on them by &quot;exceptional circumstances&quot; in order to escape being fined.</p>
<p>Analysts said while the Germans had to give up some of their more severe proposals, the pact appears strong enough to allow Chancellor Helmut Kohl's Christain Democrats to convince the public the euro will be a credible replacement for the mark.</p>
<p>&quot;It means the Christain Democrats should not have too much trouble selling this to the German public,&quot; said Baader, a senior economist at Deutsche Morgan Grenfell.</p>
<p>With the Germans behind it, and the French pleased they were able to negotiate some room for political input, the path to EMU becomes clearer, analysts said.</p>
<p>Spreads between benchmark high yielding debt and Bunds shot in when the details were released on Friday but analysts said there was room for further movement.</p>
<p>David Brickman, European bond strategist at Yamaichi International in London, said improving economic fundamentals coupled with EMU enthusiasm should bring the Spanish Bonos/Bund 10-year yield spread in to around 100 basis points in the next three months from 108 now.</p>
<p>His target for the Italian BTP/Bund spread was 150 basis points from 172 basis points now.</p>
<p>Baader said bonds will perform better than currencies from here on under the convergence theme.</p>
<p>&quot;Convergence trades have come and gone for currencies,&quot; he said. &quot;The currencies have converged to within 2.25 percent of their central rate. In fact most currencies are trading stronger than their parity,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ERM narrow bands used to be set at 2.25 percent before a 1993 crisis forced authorities to widen bands to 15 percent.</p>
<p>Phillis Reed, European bonds strategist at BZW in London, said what was good for high yielders was bad for Bunds.</p>
<p>&quot;This increases the chance EMU goes ahead. That's still not good for Germany even though you've got some fiscal discipline in place. There are still plenty of questions about whether the euro will be as strong as the mark,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>She was also more cautious on convergence trades. The whole question of whether Spain and Italy will make it into the first wave was still up in the air.</p>
<p>&quot;People are now starting to concentrate on full credit convergence and that would mean that Spain trades like Belgium so it still looks like quite a good bet,&quot; said Reed. Ten-year Belgian debt currently yields only 16 basis points over Bunds.</p>
<p>&quot;But that presupposes Spain actually gets in and it also ignores the fact that you've got to factor in some sort of break-up premium,&quot; she said. She said such a premium for an EMU crisis could be as high as 100 basis points.</p>
<p>Reed has a 175 basis point target on the Bonos/Bund spread for next year and a 200 basis point target for the BTP/Bund gap.</p>
<p>-- International Bonds Unit +44 171 542 6176</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
