<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259647" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Israel approves regular BA cargo flights.</title>
<headline>Israel approves regular BA cargo flights.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel has given its approval to British Airways World Cargo to start regular cargo charter flights between London Gatwick and Tel Aviv from February, the carrier's freighter manager John White said.</p>
<p>He told Reuters a converted Airbus Industrie A300B4 freighter wet-leased from Channel Express Air Services Ltd, part of UK company Dart Group Plc, would be used for the flights, which would initially start on a weekly basis, rapidly increasing to twice-weekly.</p>
<p>Wet-leasing covers both the hire of aircraft and crew.</p>
<p>BA World Cargo has been trying to win agreement to operate cargo charters to and from Israel for at least two years but the division's managing director Kevin Hatton has repeatedly complained about the Israeli authorities' rejection of these plans.</p>
<p>Objections made by Israel since 1994 have covered BA's proposals to use either ageing aircraft which do not meet modern low-noise levels, or otherwise suggesting planes for use on the route that are not registered by the UK Civil Aviation Authority, said a BA source.</p>
<p>&quot;The Channel Express aircraft will meet all of the requirements, including the latest Stage 3 noise standards,&quot; said White. &quot;It terms of net tonnage, the capacity we will offer on outbound Gatwick-Tel Aviv flights will be about 37 tonnes, with a maximum of 34 tonnes carried in the reverse direction on a direct Tel Aviv-Gatwick routing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A BA World Cargo planning meeting will be held on December 16 to discuss calling at Pisa on the Tel Aviv-Gatwick leg. A BA source said this inclusion was unlikely at the present time.</p>
<p>The initial BA charter contract with Channel Express is for one year, added the source.</p>
<p>The former passenger A300-B4 was operated by Eastern Airlines of the U.S. and Venezuela's VIASA before being &quot;mothballed&quot; in the U.S. desert for more than two years.</p>
<p>Anthony St Hill, director of A300 programmes with Channel Express, said the UK airline acquired the Airbus from Pinnacle, an aircraft trading company, in February this year. It is now being converted into a freighter by British Aerospace Aviation Services at BAe's Filton plant, near Bristol.</p>
<p>St Hill declined to disclose how much Channel Express paid for the aircraft but added: &quot;After completion of the work and subject to receiving the certification by end-January or early-February next year, the market value of the A300-B4 freighter will be around US$15 million.&quot; --Air Cargo Newsroomn Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C22">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
