<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259720" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Ex-Dubai air cargo rates up as surcharge kicks in.</title>
<headline>Ex-Dubai air cargo rates up as surcharge kicks in.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>There has been no pre-Christmas rush for cargo space on aircraft out of Dubai, but the recent introduction of surcharges by many airlines coupled with slightly firmer volumes has seen rates move up off their mid-November levels, a Reuter survey shows.</p>
<p>Volumes have crept higher with some sea-air garment shipments leaving Dubai before the year-end U.S. and European quota cut off, but forwarders and carriers expect the usual drop as the New Year approaches.</p>
<p>They say jet fuel surcharges of 10 U.S. cents, or 35 fils per kg, introduced by a number of international airlines worldwide in mid-November, is helping ease the strain of tight margins in the market.</p>
<p>&quot;At least we are now able to stick to our rates and not drop from them. That's one good thing about the surcharge -- I guess you could call it an indirect surcharge,&quot; said the Dubai cargo manager of a Middle East carrier which has not implemented a fuel surcharge.</p>
<p>Forwarders said some shippers were still trying to use those airlines which have not introduced surcharges.</p>
<p>&quot;But some customers have no choice but to use the surcharge carriers,&quot; an agent said.</p>
<p>One airline official said some carriers which had implemented the surcharge appeared to be rethinking their plans and withdrawing the increase on some sectors in an ad-hoc way.</p>
<p>Despite eight consecutive months of year-on-year drops in sea-air freight shipments through Dubai, agents said that the market was still providing some business.</p>
<p>&quot;A lot of Christmas decorations are transiting Dubai from the Far East. Volumes are okay,&quot; a forwarder said.</p>
<p>&quot;Exports are quite good. Garments are going out to Europe -- the U.K., Amsterdam, Germany, Spain and to the United States -- New York and San Fransico, Los Angeles,&quot; said an agent.</p>
<p>Sea-air freight volumes have fallen sharply this year as cheaper direct services from the subcontinent and Far East encourage shippers there to bypass Dubai and use the quicker all-air movement.</p>
<p>Reuters calculates the average rate on a 100 kg shipment with a six-to-one volume-to-weight ratio to London Heathrow 39 fils firmer at 4.05 dirhams. The same average rate applies to Frankfurt.</p>
<p>After November's marked increase to United States destinations, rates to New York and Los Angeles have this month moved up only by the extent of the surcharge. The average rate to JFK is 6.45 dirhams from 6.10 dirhams a kg a month ago and the rate to Los Angeles is up at 7.50 dirhams from 7.15.</p>
<p>Rates on Far East routes have risen slightly thanks to seasonal demand for space for perishables. The average has moved up to 4.00 from 3.90 to both Singapore and Hong Kong.</p>
<p>&quot;We are carrying at least 10 tonnes a day of green beans and fresh fish from Oman and the UAE and are expecting 600-700 tonnes for the season until mid-March,&quot; Cathay Pacific UAE cargo manager F.A. Baig said.</p>
<p>The cargo is mostly destined for Taiwan, he said.</p>
<p>But a ban on carrying perishable cargo on its new Boeing 777 aircraft is limiting the amount Cathay can carry.</p>
<p>&quot;If this problem was solved my uplift could be multiplied,&quot; Baig said, adding that three of the 15 weekly eastbound flights through Dubai were operated by 777s.</p>
<p>To Nairobi, the average rate on a 100 kg shipment has risen by five fils at 4.00 dirhams a kg.</p>
<p>But the outlook for business is not rosy. As Europe closes down for Christmas, shipments to those destinations will likely fall, operators say.</p>
<p>The start in early 1997 of the Islamic holy month of Ramadan, coupled with the Chinese New Year, should further subdue volumes.</p>
<p>-- Dubai newsroom +9714-626990</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
