<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="25976" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Opposition says Iraqi tanks in Kurd city of Arbil.</title>
<headline>Opposition says Iraqi tanks in Kurd city of Arbil.</headline>
<dateline>ANKARA 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi opposition group said Iraqi tanks on Saturday entered the Kurdish city of Arbil, administrative centre of northern Iraq.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraqi tanks have entered the city in the last hour and nine tanks have been destroyed by Kurdish forces,&quot; a spokesman for the Iraqi National Congress (INC) told Reuters by telephone from London. There was no independent confirmation of the report.</p>
<p>The spokesman said around 60 Iraqi tanks were advancing on the city, which is controlled by the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>He could not say how many tanks had entered Arbil. &quot;They are on the outskirts. They are not in the central parts of the city.&quot;</p>
<p>He said one of the INC contacts within the city, Ahmed Allawi, believed the town would fall in about two hours.</p>
<p>Iraqi forces began an artillery attack on Arbil at 4.50 a.m. (0050 GMT) and heavy shelling has continued since then, the INC said.</p>
<p>The spokesman said the centre of Arbil was under severe bombardment by Iraqi forces and there had been heavy casualties among Kurdish civilians.</p>
<p>&quot;There is severe panic. Everyone who can get petrol for their car is getting out. The hospitals are in pandemonium,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton on Friday ordered the U.S. military to prepare for any possible action in response to the Iraqi troop movements near the Kurdish areas.</p>
<p>U.S.-led air power has been protecting the Kurds in northern Iraq from any attack by Baghdad's forces since shortly after the Gulf War in 1991.</p>
<p>Northern Iraq has been split into rival zones since large-scale fighting broke out between the two major Kurdish factions in 1994.</p>
<p>The PUK said in a statement on Saturday that its rival, the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP), has cooperated with Iraqi forces in the advance of Iraqi military units.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ANKARA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
