<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259737" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Port of Oakland, Calif., rated AA-minus - Fitch.</title>
<headline>Port of Oakland, Calif., rated AA-minus - Fitch.</headline>
<dateline>YORK 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Port of Oakland, CA.'s approximate $262 revenue bonds, consisting of $85 million revenue bonds 1997 series G (AMT), $77 million refunding revenue bonds 1997 series H (AMT), $85 million refunding revenue bonds 1997 series I and $15 million revenue bonds 1997 series J are rated 'AA-' by Fitch Investors Service.</p>
<p>The 'AA-' rating also applies to approximately $232.5 outstanding parity bonds. The issue is expected to be sold through negotiation via a syndicate led by PaineWebber, Inc. during the week of Jan. 6. The rating reflects the port's diverse revenue sources, derived from Oakland International Airport (about 45% of total operating revenues), maritime facilities (45%) and commercial real estate (10%), which is bolstered by a large and healthy service area.</p>
<p>The port's commercial real estate division, which includes Jack London Square, has rebounded from its initial difficulties and is now profitable and contributing positively to the port's cash flow with the vast majority of its office and retail space being occupied. These three revenues sources lend resilience to the port's ability to service its debt -- debt service coverage has been strong, 2.13 times (x) in fiscal 1996 and is projected to remain solid, ranging from 2.09x in fiscal 1997 to 1.70x in 2005 (figures include approximately $611 million in expected revenue bonds issuances between 1997-2002).</p>
<p>Likewise, the port's strong management team is evidenced by its sound operating and financial results, as well as its prospective demand-driven capital planning, which will enable the port to maintain its competitive position. Oakland International Airport is primarily a high frequency, low-fare, short-medium haul airport, which has experienced solid enplanement and cargo growth over the last decade. Additional credit strengths include its high percentage of origination and destination (O&amp;D) traffic of approximately 95%, its accessibility and its significant amount of non- airline revenue, which helps to maintain the airport's low airline fees. Also, the airport's airline use and operating agreements provide it considerable flexibility. These strengths are counterbalanced by the airport's significant airline market share concentration -- Southwest Airlines accounted for 61.2% of total enplanements in fiscal 1996. The port's maritime division has experienced solid and continual container cargo growth: it is the fourth largest container port in the U.S. Furthermore, additional maritime division strengths include its significant percentage of revenue generated from leases and tariffs, its proximity to the Pacific Rim and its ability to adapt to industry changes and shipping alliances. In addition, the port is upgrading and expanding its intermodal capabilities through the development of a joint intermodal terminal, which will benefit the port from a competitive position. Offsetting these credit strengths is the competitive U.S. west coast port environment and the port's dependency on the Pacific Rim for about 76% of its trade.</p>
<p>--U.S. Municipal Desk, 212-859-1650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I76300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
