<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259783" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NYMEX natgas futures called much higher on weather.</title>
<headline>NYMEX natgas futures called much higher on weather.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>NYMEX January Henry Hub natgas futures were expected to open significantly higher Monday, as well below-normal temperatures are forecast for many parts of the U.S. this week, industry sources said.</p>
<p>January over-the-counter trading ranged from as low as $3.98 early to $4.10 per million British thermal units following Friday's settlement to the upside at $3.851.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the arctic cold moving in. If cash gets above index, we don't know how high it (Jan) can go,&quot; one futures trader said.  </p>
<p>Traders speculated that resistance in January was around $4.20. Support was seen in the $3.531-3.565 area, and then $3.19.</p>
<p>In Friday's cash market, Gulf Coast prices climbed 20 cents to near $3.60. Midcontinent prices were 10-15 cents higher in the mid-$3.40s. New York city gate gas was talked five to 10 cents higher at about $4.05-4.10.</p>
<p>Contributing to the rally was news that a few nuclear plants were shut down. The New York Power Authority's 832 megawatt (MW) Fitzpatrick unit, Duke Power's 1,129 MW Catawba 2 in South Carolina, and Southern Co's 822 MW Farley 2 in Alabama, were all shut over the weekend.</p>
<p>Also, PECO Energy's 1,055 MW Limerick 2 unit in Pennsylvania, was reduced to about 15 percent of capacity to correct an exhaust gas problem.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
