<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259830" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Riviera &quot;Godfather&quot; convicted of sleaze.</title>
<headline>French Riviera &quot;Godfather&quot; convicted of sleaze.</headline>
<byline>Bruno Aubry</byline>
<dateline>TOULON, France 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>A court sentenced Maurice Arreckx, a former French Riviera political boss who liked to be called &quot;the Godfather&quot;, to two years in prison on Monday on charges of taking kickbacks on a construction contract.</p>
<p>Arreckx, a 79-year-old former senator who has already spent more than nine months in detention, was also fined one million francs ($200,000) and barred from public office for five years.</p>
<p>The mid-October trial opened a window into the shadowy ties between politicians, business and the underworld along the Cote d'Azur. It was the latest in a string of sleaze cases involving members of France's ruling centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>The court threw out a charge of corruption carrying up to 10 years in prison, convicting Arreckx only on the lesser charge of receiving the proceeds of an abuse of trust.</p>
<p>The court did not immediately order Arreckx to prison, raising the possibility he might be released due to his age and the time he has already served in jail.</p>
<p>State prosecutor Michel Raffin had wanted Arreckx jailed for five years. He accused him of &quot;stuffing himself&quot; by extorting 1.8 million francs in return for a construction contract in the Mediterranean port of Toulon in 1991.</p>
<p>Arreckx, who was mayor of Toulon for 26 years until 1985 and also served as senator and head of the regional elected council for the Var department, said he had not yet decided whether he would appeal against the verdict.</p>
<p>&quot;My honour has been rehabilitated, as has that of my family,&quot; he told reporters after the verdict.</p>
<p>He has denied the charges and argued that the purchase of the land for a planned engineering college had been decided by Toulon's city administration rather than by him personally.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been elected and re-elected and voters made no mistake about me,&quot; he said. Arreckx was a member of the Senate (upper house) for the Union for French Democracy (UDF), the junior partner in the ruling centre-right coalition.</p>
<p>The head of the local building firm suspected of paying the kickbacks, Jean-Louis Germain, was given a suspended 18-month sentence on charges of abuse of trust. Three go-betweens were given suspended sentences ranging from 10 to 12 months.</p>
<p>The Var has been under the spotlight since 1993 when local parliamentarian Yann Piat, like Arreckx a member of the UDF, was killed after she threatened to reveal &quot;Mafia-like&quot; activities in the region.</p>
<p>In a letter made public after her death, Piat told friends that if she were killed, Arreckx should be among the suspects.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOULON, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
