<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259863" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: Greece signs EIB loan for Elefsis highway.</title>
<headline>Greece signs EIB loan for Elefsis highway.</headline>
<dateline>ATHENS 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Investment Bank (EIB) signed over to Greece the first tranche of a 265 billion drachma ($1.08 billion) loan to build a peripheral motorway around Athens, servicing the capital's planned new international airport.</p>
<p>National Economy Minister Yannos Papantoniou and EIB vice-president Panagiotis Gennimatas signed the agreement for the first 45 billion drachma tranche at a ceremony in Athens.</p>
<p>The road is a main element in the development of the new Athens international airport, under construction at Spata east of the capital.</p>
<p>Papantoniou said that a &quot;fruitful co-operation between the government and the EIB on three other major construction projects -- the Spata airport, a natural gas pipeline and the Rio-Antirio bridge -- had already been established.&quot;</p>
<p>The EIB approved a 265 billion drachma loan facility for the Elefsis-Stavros-Spata-Imittos highway in July. The balance of 220 billion drachmas will be arranged with Concessionaire Attiki Odos S.A. and paid in tranches as the highway proceeds.</p>
<p>Gennimatas said that &quot;in 1996 we approved four important construction projects that I consider as the hard core of Greece's construction activity.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;I consider the most difficult of the four projects is the Elefsis-Stavros highway. Its difficulties arise from the very high estimated cost as well as its exceptionally high technical standards and requirements.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Another difficulty is the fact that the highway will be passing through populated areas,&quot; he added. There are 14 Greek companies in the construction consortium, headed by Aktor.</p>
<p>The Elefsis-Stavros project is part of the PATHE axis, a key project in the priority list of Trans-European Network projects (TENs), approved by the Essen European Council.</p>
<p>The Elefsis highway is expected to create 2,000 permanent jobs.</p>
<p>--Margarita Sotiropoulou, Athens Newsroom +301 3311812-4 ($1=244.9 Drachma)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I5020041">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ATHENS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
