<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259874" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Fuel surcharges sour Air France, forwarders links.</title>
<headline>Fuel surcharges sour Air France, forwarders links.</headline>
<byline>Stuart Todd</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The introduction of fuel surcharges at the beginning of last month has soured relations between French air forwarding agents and Air France, the agent's assocation, SNAGFA, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's be clear, we are not contesting the principle of the airlines implementing fuel surcharges but the manner in which it was done,&quot; SNAGFA President, Klaus Pfab, told Reuters.</p>
<p>On this issue, SNAGFA had decided to suspend a joint committee with Air France until further notice. Its members may -- after the end-year rush- also try to avoid using the carrier where possible, he added.</p>
<p>The joint committee discussed such issues as the quality of service in the air cargo industry rates structures on a regular basis.</p>
<p>&quot;When you are supposed to have a &quot;special relationship&quot; with an airline, such as French agents have with Air France, one has a right to expect reasonable prior notice on the changes in the pipeline. However, the lines of communication were very sadly lacking over the fuel surcharge,&quot; Pfab said.</p>
<p>SNAGFA held regular meetings with Air France but there had not been an inkling of what the airline was planning in this respect. Moreover, the airline had shown no indication of changing its position, Pfab added.</p>
<p>SNAGFA was advising its members to bill airlines for fuel surcharges they had paid before November 16 but Pfab admits there is relatively little chance of reimbursement.</p>
<p>He says the move is more a gesture of protest at being badly-treated and warned that in the months ahead SNAGFA members would be &quot;getting the message across&quot; by turning its back on Air France whenever possible.</p>
<p>&quot;At this time of the year, cargo capacity is at a premium and it's hard not to use Air France's services. However, believe me, in January and February when the market has calmed down we will be able to make a choice between airlines and there are those around who can provide just as good a quality of service as Air France.&quot;</p>
<p>The French national carrier would be left to reflect on whether 10 days &quot;revenue&quot; was worth the sour relations it had caused with French agents, all of which could have been avoided if a couple of weeks notice had been given on the introduction of the fuel surcharges, Pfab added.</p>
<p>&quot;Hopefully, it will serve as a salutary lesson.&quot;</p>
<p>--Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax +44 171 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
