<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259828" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: FOCUS - Rheinmetall acquisitions to help earnings.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Rheinmetall acquisitions to help earnings.</headline>
<byline>Douglas Busvine</byline>
<dateline>DUESSELDORF, Germany 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>German defence and engineering group Rheinmetall AG said on Monday that recent acquisitions would boost both group turnover and profits in 1997 after a recovery in earnings this year.</p>
<p>Chief executive Hans Brauner told a news briefing that taking management control of electronics firm STN Atlas and the buyout of Richard Hirschmann &amp; Co GmbH would bring a &quot;quantum leap&quot; in the company's business next year.</p>
<p>He said the acquisitions would boost group turnover in 1997 to 5.5 billion marks ($3.5 billion) from an expected 3.6 billion marks this year. Turnover was 3.4 billion marks last year.</p>
<p>Net profits are poised to rise this year to a double-digit figure, in millions of marks, after 2.6 million marks last year and a loss of 39.6 million the year before.</p>
<p>Pre-tax profits should be &quot;substantially positive&quot; this year, and are forecast at 130 million marks in 1997, after just 9.4 million marks last year, Brauner said.</p>
<p>Brauner said Rheinmetall, founded in 1889, will restructure its business from the start of 1997 into a portfolio of six areas, adding a defence electronics unit based on STN Atlas.</p>
<p>Rheinmetall in November won management control of STN Atlas, sold for 550 million marks by the official receiver of its parent, bankrupt shipyard group Bremer Vulkan.</p>
<p>Via a cascading holding structure, Rheinmetall will own 26 percent of STN Atlas but takes management control. Utility Badenwerk has 25 percent and British Aerospace 49 percent. The deal is subject to cartel office approval.</p>
<p>The group's other divisions -- each with annual turnover of around a billion marks -- will be military equipment, industry electronics, machine-building, automotive equipment, along with a much smaller office furniture systems division.</p>
<p>After the restructuring, the balance of Rheinmetall's business will be 60 percent machine-building against 40 percent military and civil electronics. The last area will be boosted by the takeover of 90 percent of Hirschmann, which was hit by losses in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>Rheinmetall is targeting group turnover of seven billion marks by 2001, and although its workforce will rise to 21,000 from 14,000 by taking on STN Atlas, numbers should then steady.</p>
<p>This year's incoming orders, seen up 16.9 percent at 4.2 billion marks, also offer encouragement for business in 1997, while the group's order book is forecast at 3.1 billion marks at this year-end, up 26 percent.</p>
<p>Cash flow will also jump in 1997, rising to a forecast 370 million marks from an expected 223 million this year -- little changed on last year.</p>
<p>Brauner said Rheinmetall, which is 66.5 percent owned by the Roechling family, would maintain dividend continuity after holding its payout steady while posting recent losses.</p>
<p>&quot;We have a cap on the downside,&quot; Brauner told reporters. The 1995 dividend on ordinary shares was unchanged at seven marks, while the payout on preference shares was eight marks.</p>
<p>Rheinmetall plans to make a rights issue of 30 million marks nominal in preference shares next year, and Brauner did not rule out that cash-rich Badenwerk would cement the two companies' partnership by subscribing.</p>
<p>He said that Rheinmetall shares were near historic lows and dividend yields high even though the company had overcome its losses. &quot;Our share price, which should anticipate these changes, is lagging somewhat,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Rheinmetall ordinaries were up four marks at 206 marks in the last hour of trading on the Frankfurt stock exchange, while preferreds were up 10 at 175 marks. ($1=1.5540 Mark)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I32000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUESSELDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
