<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259892" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: Two suitors for CA seen equally serious.</title>
<headline>Two suitors for CA seen equally serious.</headline>
<byline>Janet McBride</byline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Analysts found little to choose between Bank Austria and an EA-Generali group in the battle for Creditanstalt but said a challenge from supermarket mogul Karl Wlaschek was little more than an interesting distraction.</p>
<p>All three contenders submitted bids for the Austrian government's 70 percent of Creditanstalt ordinary voting shares ahead of a 0700 GMT deadline.</p>
<p>Analysts were divided on the merits of Bank Austria and the EA-Generali group as suitors but they were united in dismissing 79-year-old Wlaschek, former owner of the Billa supermarket chain.</p>
<p>&quot;Wlaschek? I've never heard of him. I don't think this is very serious. He's probably going to be ruled out anyway because of his credentials,&quot; said an international analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously it will be down to the value of the bids to a certain extent but I would have thought the government was unlikely to sell to a private individual,&quot; said Victoria Maxwell, Austria analyst at James Capel in London.</p>
<p>She said a beefed-up bid from the EA-Generali group, which includes savings bank Die Erste Oesterreichische SparCasse, Germany's Commerzbank and Banca Commerciale Italiana might take the day.</p>
<p>&quot;Between them, (the members of the consortium) have got enough money to keep pushing up the bids,&quot; Maxwell said.</p>
<p>By selling traditionally conservative Creditanstalt to the EA-Generali group, Finance Minister Viktor Klima would also avoid the political headaches associated with a takeover by left-leaning Bank Austria, she added.</p>
<p>The EA-Generali consortium said it aimed to take control of 74 percent of the government's 19.9 million Creditanstalt ordinary voting shares and place the remainder over the market.</p>
<p>Union Bank of Switzerland, Commerzbank, Belgium's Bacob, Banca Commerciale and Die Erste (First Austrian) would help find the extra cash needed to the bid for the entire stake.</p>
<p>Bank Austria's offer was also worthy of serious consideration, analysts said. The nation's biggest bank is reportedly willing to pay 16 billion schillings, or 804 schillings a share, for its arch rival.</p>
<p>On Monday Creditanstalt ordinary shares closed at 737 schillings.</p>
<p>&quot;(That scenario) certainly has the most potential but whether that potential will be realised is the question,&quot; said an international analyst.</p>
<p>&quot;The Bank Austria bid certainly offers more in terms of restructuring potential. It is hard to see whether the consortium could achieve as much,&quot; said a banking analyst at Moody's in London.</p>
<p>Bank Austria's bid has aroused opposition among Creditanstalt employees, fearful for their jobs, and conservative politicians, reluctant to cede control of a powerbase.</p>
<p>A tie-up of the two banks would mean up to 5,000 job losses and a wave of branch closures, experts say.</p>
<p>A question mark over Bank Austria's ability to finance the deal and the EA-Generali group's ability to place 26 percent of the state's shares over the market worried some analysts.</p>
<p>But these concerns were not enough to give Wlaschek an edge, they concluded.</p>
<p>-- Vienna Newsroom, 43-1-53112-258</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81403">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
