<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="259907" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: German DAX ends two pct up as dollar aids recovery.</title>
<headline>German DAX ends two pct up as dollar aids recovery.</headline>
<dateline>FRANKFURT 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>German shares closed two percent higher on Monday on the back of dollar and bond market strength, but dealers warned volumes were low and investors still nervous after recent plunges in global share markets.</p>
<p>The DAX-30 index of leading German shares ended bourse trade higher 56.08 points, or two percent, at 2,855.79 as the U.S. currency's rise boosted the numerous export-sensitive German stocks.</p>
<p>The dollar rose on the perception that the monetary union stability pact reached by European finance ministers in Dublin on Friday makes Europe's planned currency union all the more likely.</p>
<p>In as much as EMU undermines the power of the German mark on currency markets, the logic runs that this is positive for the dollar, which traded at close to 1.56 marks compared to last week's end level of around 1.54.</p>
<p>Despite the strong gains, dealers said volumes were still thin. &quot;But volumes are still a bit thin. Investors are still holding back a bit. Some think there is still room for a correction down to 2,750,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>December DAX futures were nonetheless 35 points up at 2,855.0 in early afternoon trade.</p>
<p>The DAX fell sharply on Friday after a 100-point tumble on the Dow Jones index, which triggered memories of the rout in world share markets which took place the Friday before.</p>
<p>German shares were earlier on Monday little changed by the influential research institute Ifo's November survey showing an unexpected dip in business climate perceptions compared to October.</p>
<p>Industrial giant Daimler Benz AG, whose Dasa unit is one of the partners in the Airbus European aircraft-maker, was lower earlier on news that United States-based rivals McDonnell Douglas and Boeing Co were to merge.</p>
<p>But the stock pulled back in late morning dealings to trade at 100.50, 1.70 marks up on the day as initial fears of the impact to Airbus' business were seen as overdone.</p>
<p>Car-maker Volkswagen AG rose 10.7 marks to 614.50 as hopes grew of an out-of-court settlement in the Lopez case of alleged industrial espionage after Friday's announcement of the charges to be faced in Germany by the ex-VW production chief.</p>
<p>Among the few shares to lose ground, printing systems manufacturer Linotype-Hell slumped three marks to 121 after last Friday's news of a 1996 loss forecast and a restructuring plan due to cost some 1,200 jobs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="FRANKFURT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
