<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260078" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>GREECE: FEATURE - SALONIKA TO SHOW OFF BYZANTINE LEGACY IN 1997.</title>
<headline>FEATURE - SALONIKA TO SHOW OFF BYZANTINE LEGACY IN 1997.</headline>
<byline>Dina Kyriakidou</byline>
<dateline>SALONIKA, Greece 1996-12-15</dateline>
<text>
<p>Greece's second city has been delving into its rich cultural history, spanning more than 2,000 years, to come up with some rare gems for its year as Europe's cultural capital in 1997.</p>
<p>An unprecedented exhibition of Byzantine art from the nearby all-male monastic community of Mount Athos, where women are forbidden, is expected to draw more than a million visitors.</p>
<p>&quot;After two years of preparation, the treasures of our Byzantine tradition, which has been kept alive for centuries, will be displayed for the first time outside Mount Athos,&quot; Salonika Mayor Constantine Kosmopoulos told reporters.</p>
<p>A total of 589 items, ranging from gold-leaf icons to rare manuscripts, will be sent from the Byzantine monasteries dotting the Athos peninsula to be shown at the new Byzantine museum from June.</p>
<p>Salonika, founded in 316 BC and named after Alexander the Great's sister Thessalonikeia, is determined to show off both its unique roots and its new air as a vibrant university city.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to project Greek culture as continuing to the present, not a relic of the past,&quot; said Culture Minister Evangelos Venizelos while hosting a tour of the city.</p>
<p>Events will range from ancient Greek drama to plays by Jean Cocteau and Samuel Beckett; from modern jazz to Puccini's La Boheme and Verdi's Il Trovatore.</p>
<p>Exhibitions span the work of Caravaggio to sculptures by the surrealist Max Ernst and a retrospective of Hans Arp; from engravings by Goya to contemporary Yugoslav art.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to promote Greece through a festival of ideas, not by projecting a silly chauvinism,&quot; Panos Theodoridis, the cultural capital's artistic director, told reporters.</p>
<p>ROWS BEHIND THE SCENES</p>
<p>The fourth director since 1992, when Salonika was chosen to succeed Copenhagen, he took over in April only to face chronic delays, public indifference and his predecessors' conflicting visions -- which he quickly overturned.</p>
<p>The initial idea was to promote the legacies of Christian Orthodoxy, Byzantium and Alexander the Great, the Macedonian king who spread the Greek language and ideas as far east as India.</p>
<p>Salonika's intellectual elite decried the concept as nationalist hysteria and said it was wrong to give the top job to Athenians who knew nothing of the city's international past.</p>
<p>They also accused the government in Athens, which earmarked 80 billion drachmas ($328 million) for the cultural capital, of not pushing through the construction needed to make it a success.</p>
<p>&quot;Surely some works have been delayed,&quot; Venizelos admitted. &quot;The Cultural Capital Organisation has management problems. It has become a giant; it should be smaller and more agile.&quot;</p>
<p>Theodoridis, a Salonika native, quickly decided it was never too late and the city's existing facilities would have to do.</p>
<p>&quot;The space is enough and more than enough. What I care about is for the public to come to watch the events,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>HISTORIC COMMUNITIES LEAVE MARK</p>
<p>Theodoridis's vision pays tribute to the medley of religions and ethnic groups that have left their mark on the waterfront city, where St Paul preached in 50 AD.</p>
<p>&quot;We remember and pay tribute to the historic communities of the Armenians and the Jews, who, along with the traditional communities of the Moslems and Christians, helped the city reach its peak,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Dotted with Byzantine churches, Ottoman mosques and bath houses, the city became part of Greece in 1913 during the Balkan Wars. Its streets combine the charm of an eastern marketplace with the grey solemnity of a western industrial hub.</p>
<p>Part of the Roman and Byzantine empires, Salonika was ruled at times by Saracens, crusaders and Venetians until it fell to the Ottoman Turks.</p>
<p>It is the birthplace of Cyril and Methodius, who converted the Slavs to Christianity in the 800s as well as Kemal Ataturk, the founder of modern Turkey.</p>
<p>Salonika got its major economic and cultural boost after the settlement of 20,000 Jews expelled from Spain and Portugal in 1492. The Nazis sent 50,000 Jews from the city known as the Second Jerusalem to the death camps. About 2,000 Jews live here today.</p>
<p>By the 16th century Salonika was a bustling international port city where Jews, Turks, Christians, Armenians and Slavs co-existed and flourished.</p>
<p>About 30 European and Middle East countries are sending artists to perform next year. The United States, Canada, Australia and Japan are also participating.</p>
<p>Salonika fears the year might be such a success that it could have difficulty putting up a huge numbers of visitors.</p>
<p>&quot;Salonika does have a problem with hotels,&quot; Venizelos said. &quot;That's why we made arrangements to have cruise ships docked at the port to cover any such needs.&quot; ($1=243.9 Drachma)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GREECE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-15"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SALONIKA, Greece"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GREECE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
