<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260023" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRIA: PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Dec 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Austria - Dec 16.</headline>
<dateline>VIENNA 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are the main stories from Monday morning's Austrian newspapers:</p>
<p>DER STANDARD</p>
<p>- The Austro-Italian-German consortium around insurer EA-Generali is to hand in a new bid for the government's stake in Creditanstalt worth 12 billion schillings, up from its previous 10 billion offer. The identity of a third bidder remains unknown but speculation is centring on German insurer Deutsche Allianz and German bank Bayerische Vereinsbank.</p>
<p>- The 17 billion schilling bid by Bank Austria for Creditanstalt is causing a severe political rift between coalition partners Social Democrats and the conservative People's Party.</p>
<p>- Insulation materials maker Heraklith expects a drop in net profits to 125 million schilling in 1996 from 160 million schillings last year.</p>
<p>- Austria had a triumphant weekend in the field of sport, with the men's ski team taking the four top spots at the downhill race in Val d'Isere, while Vera Lischka won Austria's first-ever gold medal at the European Swimming Championships in Germany. Austria's women's handball team won the bronze medal at European Championships in Denmark.</p>
<p>DIE PRESSE</p>
<p>- With the deadline for bids for Creditanstalt ending today, all interested parties have tried to beef up their offers.</p>
<p>- Chancellor Franz Vranitzky and Vice-Chancellor Wolfgang Schuessel have said they do not favour a referendum over the introduction of Europe's single currency.</p>
<p>- Economic research institute WIFO expects a decline of real wages from 1997 due to the government's austerity budget and slow economic growth.</p>
<p>KURIER</p>
<p>- Conservative chief whip Andreas Khol says the government coalition could be jeopardised if Bank Austria's bid for Creditanstalt is successful.</p>
<p>SALZBURGER NACHRICHTEN</p>
<p>- Rumours are rife that the unidentified third bidder for Creditanstalt could be German Bayern Landesbank and Austrian bank BAWAG or General Electric Capital.</p>
<p>NEUE KRONEN ZEITUNG</p>
<p>- According to the latest speculation the consortium around insurer EA Generali is to offer a bid of 15.5 billion schillings for Creditanstalt, the paper reports.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUST">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VIENNA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
