<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260127" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australian dollar kills time in dead market.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australian dollar kills time in dead market.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian dollar killed time in a tight band Monday as investors concentrated on keeping out of trouble after a fortnight of wild swings.</p>
<p>Dealers reported a dearth of interest with 15-ticks being the range for the day and often minutes passing between trades in a market where instantaneous was usually considered too long. Most doubted the dollar would stray from the US$0.7890/7950 range that had constrained it since last week's tumble from atop 80 cents, but cautioned that the lack of liquidity meant an impulsive move could not be ruled out and a break of either barrier would see a stop-loss lunge of at least 1/2 cent.  </p>
<p>By 5.00 pm (0600 GMT) the dollar hovering near the day's high at US$0.7930/35 having edged up from a US$0.7918 low, but was not a million miles away from Friday's late US$0.7928/33.</p>
<p>There was a little more life on the crosses where the currency crept up to 90.30/40 yen from 89.62/72 late Friday, largely encouraged by a rally in the U.S. dollar to 113.90 yen from 113.10.</p>
<p>Both the U.S. and local dollars were supported by signs of progress in plans for a single European currency, which tends to diminish the attractiveness of safe havens like the yen, mark and Swiss franc.  </p>
<p>Late Friday the EU clinched a pact on budgetary discipline aimed at paving the way for the single currency and as a result the local dollar climbed to 1.2337/61 marks from 1.2273/88.</p>
<p>This was not enough to impact its trade weighted index, however, where the dollar ended unchanged at 58.9, so neatly encapsulating the general feeling in the market.</p>
<p>The only data out today were partial price indicators little watched by the market, but often cited by analysts as reasons to expect inflation to remain low.</p>
<p>Manufacturing input prices rose 0.7 percent in October, mainly due to oil, but were 2.6 percent down on the year.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, the price of imported goods fell 0.3 percent in October to be 6.1 percent down in annual terms.</p>
<p>In both cases the subdued outcome was largely due to the high Australian dollar, a deflationary force which had actually strengthened through November and was cited by the Reserve Bank as a major factor behind its rate cut last week.</p>
<p>The only release this week with any potential to move the market was merchandise imports on Wednesday, although they would have to be well out of line with median forecasts of a 1.0 percent rise to have even a transitory effect.</p>
<p>-- Wayne Cole 61-2 9373 1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
