<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260185" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>CAMBODIA: Prince's fate shakes Cambodia's fragile coalition.</title>
<headline>Prince's fate shakes Cambodia's fragile coalition.</headline>
<byline>Katya Robinson</byline>
<dateline>PHNOM PENH 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dispute over the return of exiled Prince Norodom Sirivudh has further riven Cambodia's fragile coalition, triggering concerns about the country's stability, analysts and politicians said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Cambodia is facing a real dilemma with a climate of mistrust and suspicion. It's factionalism, and it's not in the national interest,&quot; said Kao Kim Hourn, director of the Cambodian Institute for Cooperation and Peace, a think tank.</p>
<p>On Sunday, Second Prime Minister Hun Sen of the Cambodian People's Party (CPP) said he would forcefully prevent the return of Sirivudh, who was arrested in November 1995 for allegedly plotting to assassinate Hun Sen.</p>
<p>Sirivudh, the half-brother of King Norodom Sihanouk and a member of the royalist FUNCINPEC party, went into exile in France last December to avoid facing the charges in court.</p>
<p>He was sentenced in absentia to 10 years in jail in a trial international observers branded a travesty.</p>
<p>After nearly one year in France, Sirivudh has vowed to return to Cambodia, fuelling tensions between Hun Sen and his coalition partner, co-Premier Prince Norodom Ranariddh of FUNCINPEC , who supports Sirivudh's return.</p>
<p>&quot;This is one more blow for the coalition. There is no doubt it (the coalition) is in serious trouble,&quot; said one diplomat in reference to the uneasy partnership that Hun Sen and Ranariddh formed after U.N.-sponsored elections in 1993.</p>
<p>Parliamentarian Ahmad Yahya agreed that the dispute over Sirivudh shows how badly the two-headed government has faltered.</p>
<p>&quot;The coalition exists only on paper, only in theory. It just doesn't work,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the worst thing I've seen in years,&quot; said one Asian analyst. &quot;Every day here is a battle for power. Cambodia cannot be controlled by cults of personalities -- it's like the country is an individual with emotional problems.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts point to a progressive breakdown between Ranariddh and Hun Sen, who now rarely speak to one another.</p>
<p>In March, Ranariddh threatened to pull out of the coalition over power-sharing issues. In August, deep rifts in the Khmer Rouge guerrilla movement temporarily seemed to bring the two leaders together, but they later ended up competing against each other to recruit the most Khmer Rouge defectors to their own side.</p>
<p>Matters worsened last month when Hun Sen's brother-in-law was killed by an unidentified gunman. Days later, troops loyal to Hun Sen's ex-communist CPP and Ranariddh's FUNCINPEC skirmished in Cambodia's northwest.</p>
<p>Sunday's comments by Hun Sen, who resolved to call out tanks and heavy weapons if necessary to block Sirivudh's return, &quot;are very bad for the relations between the two parties&quot;, said one international observer.</p>
<p>The only good news, said the observer and other analysts, is that even if the coalition is crumbling, violence will probably not erupt over Sirivudh.</p>
<p>&quot;Nothing will happen,&quot; said Ahmad Yayha. &quot;It's just intimidation.&quot;</p>
<p>Analysts say the real problem is foreign investors are getting nervous about Cambodia, a mood worsened by the feeling that local and national elections, scheduled for 1997 and 1998, might not take place on time, if at all.</p>
<p>&quot;It's unfortunate,&quot; said one diplomat. &quot;All parties should learn to exercise some constraint.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="KAMPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PHNOM PENH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CAMBODIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
