<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260103" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: YEAR - Key events in 1996.</title>
<headline>YEAR - Key events in 1996.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>JANUARY saw a resurgence in the conflict in the Russian region of Chechnya, when rebels seized more than 2,000 hostages from the neighbouring republic of Dagestan. After releasing most of the hostages, the rebels' journey home led to a bloody three-day assault by Russian troops on the village of Pervomaiskoye.</p>
<p>Chechen sympathisers also hijacked a ferry in the Turkish port of Trabzon, occupying it for three days and sailing it across the Black Sea to Istanbul before surrendering.</p>
<p>In Sri Lanka, a truck bomb in the centre of Colombo killed at least 55 people and injured nearly 1,400.</p>
<p>France conducted the sixth of a series of nuclear tests in the South Pacific and announced that it was the country's last.</p>
<p>Peace efforts in two long-running conflicts suffered setbacks in FEBRUARY when Arab suicide bombers killed 27 people in Israel and the Irish Republican Army resumed bomb attacks in London, killing three people.</p>
<p>Another intractable political dispute returned to the headlines when Cuban MiGs shot down two small American civilian aircraft piloted by Cuban exiles, reviving tension between Havana and Washington.</p>
<p>In MARCH, tension rose in the Taiwan Strait when China conducted war games designed to intimidate Taipei in the run-up to the island's presidential election.</p>
<p>Unmoved, Taiwan went ahead with the vote and incumbent Lee Teng-hui became its first directly elected president.</p>
<p>Britain unleashed panic among beef consumers with its announcement that a likely link existed between mad cow disease, bovine spongiform encephalopathy (BSE), and its human equivalent, Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease.</p>
<p>In Dunblane, Scotland, an armed social misfit killed 16 kindergarten children and their teacher, provoking an international outpouring of grief and sympathy.</p>
<p>The following month Martin Bryant unleashed modern Australia's worst mass murder when he shot dead 35 people in the southern island state of Tasmania.</p>
<p>APRIL also saw a ceasefire ending 16 days of bombardments between Israeli forces and Hizbollah guerrillas, and the Palestinian parliament-in-exile voted to drop clauses in the PLO charter calling for Israel's destruction.</p>
<p>In Italy, a general election brought the left back to power for the first time in 50 years.</p>
<p>SURPRISE VICTORY FOR NETANYAHU</p>
<p>In MAY Israel's elections for prime minister ended in a surprise victory for right-winger Benjamin Netanyahu by a tiny margin. Arabs feared his hard line could undermine the Middle East peace process.</p>
<p>In India, the Congress party gave way to a BJP government after 40 years in power, but it lasted only 12 days in office before resigning in the face of a no-confidence vote.</p>
<p>South Africa's National Party relinquished a role in government for the first time since 1948, by withdrawing from the ANC-led government of national unity.</p>
<p>Boris Yeltsin failed to score an outright win in the first round of the Russian presidential election in JUNE and faced a July 3 runoff against Communist leader Gennady Zyuganov.</p>
<p>A bomb wrecked a Saudi Arabian military complex, killing 19 Americans and injuring almost 400 people.</p>
<p>PEACE PROCRESS THROWN OFF COURSE</p>
<p>The Northern Ireland peace process was thrown into jeopardy when an IRA bomb attack in the northern English city of Manchester injured more than 200 people.</p>
<p>In JULY, a TWA jumbo jet exploded and crashed into the Atlantic off New York, killing 230.</p>
<p>The 100th Olympic Games, heralded by organisers in Atlanta as the safest ever, was the target of a bomb in Centennial Park in which two people died and more than 100 were wounded.</p>
<p>RENWED BLOODSHED IN BURUNDI</p>
<p>In Burundi, the Tutsi-dominated army seized power in a coup which followed renewed bloodletting, including 300 dead in an attack by Hutu rebels on a camp for displaced Tutsis.</p>
<p>The conflict in Chechnya flared again in AUGUST when rebels stormed the capital Grozny in a five-day offensive that humiliated Russian troops.</p>
<p>Better known for beer and bureaucrats than for death and depravity, Belgium hit the headlines when two sexually-abused girls were rescued from a makeshift dungeon and police unearthed the corpses of four others. The case sparked an international hunt for links to paedophile rings in other countries.</p>
<p>The United States said it had found evidence of life on Mars which President Bill Clinton said held awesome implications if confirmed.</p>
<p>In early SEPTEMBER the United States fired cruise missiles at southern Iraq in retaliation for Baghdad's incursion into the Kurdish north. The Middle East peace process was left in tatters after 75 people died in Israeli-Palestinian clashes.</p>
<p>Islamic Taleban rebels seized the Afghan capital Kabul, imposing their own strict brand of Islam.</p>
<p>Fighting raged between Zairean troops and Tutsi rebels in October leading to the exodus of thousands of refugees. Aid agencies responsible for feeding more than a million Hutu refugees prepared to evacaute.</p>
<p>Hundreds of thousands of Rwandan Hutu refugees returned home from camps in eastern Zaire in NOVEMBER, prompting world leaders to scale down a planned multinational humanitarian force for the region.</p>
<p>CLINTON VICTORY</p>
<p>U.S. President Bill Clinton beat Republican challenger Bob Dole to win a second term.</p>
<p>The world's worst mid-air collision, involving a Saudi Arabian jumbo jet and a Kazakhstan cargo plane, killed 349 people near New Delhi.</p>
<p>Pakistan's President Farooq Ahmed Leghari sacked Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto and her cabinet and dissolved parliament.</p>
<p>In DECEMBER thousands of students gathered in central Belgrade for street protests in what became a daily routine of mass demonstrations against Serbian President Slobodan Milosevic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="WORLD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
