<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260241" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesia holds Singaporeans after drugs found.</title>
<headline>Indonesia holds Singaporeans after drugs found.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesian customs officials have detained two Singaporean traders after 16,527 Ecstasy pills were discovered at Jakarta's international airport, a customs official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The pills were wrapped in packets of M&amp;Ms (multi-coloured chocolate sweets),&quot; Nifsu Chasbullah, head of customs and excise at Soekarno-Hatta International Airport, told Reuters by telephone.</p>
<p>Chasbullah said the two Singaporeans, whose names were not released, had travelled to Indonesia from Amsterdam via Hong Kong on a Cathay Pacific flight which landed on Sunday morning.</p>
<p>&quot;Customs officers became suspicious after the baggage of the two men was X-rayed,&quot; he said, adding there was a strong suspicion the two men were working together as the pills were wrapped in an identical fashion.</p>
<p>There was no immediate estimate of the street value of the drugs. He said the men were due to be handed over to police in metropolitan Jakarta later on Monday.</p>
<p>Earlier this month, two other Singaporeans were caught at the same airport allegedly trying to smuggle 70,431 Ecstasy pills estimated to be worth $1.8 million in the largest single haul in Indonesia.</p>
<p>At the time, customs officials said they had seized 239,048 Ecstasy pills since March this year.</p>
<p>Ecstasy has gained widespread popularity in Indonesia's cities in recent years and the government has recently legislated to increase penalties for trafficking in and using it.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
