<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260317" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - December 16.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Singapore - December 16.</headline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The following are top stories from selected Singapore newspapers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>THE STRAITS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong likely to decide date of Singapore's General Election after his visit to opposition-held Hougang next Sunday.</p>
<p>- Singapore Prime Minister Goh Chok Tong and Senior Minister Lee Kuan Yew urge voters to back People's Action Party teams in Group Representation Constituencies.</p>
<p>- White tiger in popular Indonesian safari park attacks and kills Malaysian woman minutes after she poses for picture with animal.</p>
<p>- Site in Boon Lay is first executive condominium parcel to be tendered out publicly to developers early next year.</p>
<p>- Land set aside for residential development in Jurong West expected to double by 2010.</p>
<p>THE BUSINESS TIMES:</p>
<p>- Prices of hard disk drives shoot up 20-40 percent due to increased demand from systems integrators, computer vendors and retail buyers.</p>
<p>- Wall Street market strategists predict volatile conditions in coming weeks and fear global markets will perform poorly in first quarter.</p>
<p>- Boeing and McDonnel Douglas announce they would merge in stock wrap to create world's largest aircraft company and mammoth in aviation, aerospace and defence.</p>
<p>- Listed transport-based Singapore Bus Service's mega-venture with Malaysia's Renong group to build buses has hit a speed hump.</p>
<p>- Singapore stock market retains its neutral weighting as concerns in exchange about near-term growth outlook for country lingers.</p>
<p>- Analysts say firms may be pushed to list sooner rather than later to match IPOs with their fiscal year.</p>
<p>-- Singapore newsroom 65-8703080</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
