<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260325" id="root" date="1996-12-16" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine bourse gets self-regulatory status.</title>
<headline>Philippine bourse gets self-regulatory status.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Philippine Stock Exchange was granted self regulatory status by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) at a ceremony on Monday.</p>
<p>Granting of this status means the bourse will now police its own activities with the SEC intervening only if necessary.</p>
<p>Brokers said the bourse's new status is expected to make it more efficient as matters relating to approvals of new listings as well as settling of grievances will be handled directly without being referred to the SEC.  </p>
<p>The Philippine Stock Exchange was meant to get self regulatory status a couple of months ago but the SEC had delayed it because of differences with the bourse over market reforms.</p>
<p>The SEC had insisted the bourse should make its dealings more open by introducing non-broker members on the board.</p>
<p>It also wanted the bourse to drop a rule which forced companies making initial public offerings (IPOs) to allocate a certain percentage of the shares to brokers.</p>
<p>The SEC said the IPO allocation rule, meant to ensure distribution to small investors, was abused by brokers who waited to see if an issue became a success before buying it on their own account. If it failed, the brokers would just return it to the underwriter saying the stock did not sell.</p>
<p>The SEC had withheld self regulatory status until the bourse addressed these issues.</p>
<p>Last month the bourse agreed to drop the IPO allocation rule. Brokers have also agreed to let representatives of the public on the bourse's board of directors.</p>
<p>-- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-16"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
