<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260475" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Whittman-Hart can't account for activity.</title>
<headline>Whittman-Hart can't account for activity.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Whittman-Hart Inc said it could not account for the volatility in its shares which fell as much as 3-1/8 to 19-5/8 earlier in the session and recovered to trade in a narrow range Tuesday afternoon.</p>
<p>The company also Tuesday filed with federal regulators for a shelf offering of more than four million common shares. A company spokesman said the shares will be available for future acquisitions, although no deals were pending.</p>
<p>&quot;I have no idea why the stock fell,&quot; said Robert Bernard, Whittman-Hart's chairman. &quot;It has nothing to do with any news from our company or anything related to our business.&quot;  </p>
<p>The shares closed off 1/2 at 22-5/8 on turnover of more than 162,000 shares.</p>
<p>Whittman-Hart, which went public in May at 16 a share, designs and installs computer system projects. It completed an offering of two million shares at 28-1/2 in August.</p>
<p>The sell-off was apparently related to buyers taking profits from small-cap stocks before the end of the year, said one analyst who asked not to identified.</p>
<p>&quot;Given how well they've performed in the market, it's not a surprise they're a little volatile given their high price-to-earnings ratio,&quot; explained Mark Whitcher, an investment banker at Broadview Associates.</p>
<p>&quot;They're experiencing expanding growth in terms of coverage,&quot; Whitcher said, &quot;and the demand for their services is skyrocketing.&quot;</p>
<p>((Chicago newsdesk (312) 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83940">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
