<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26046" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wages for U.S. women fall for first time - study.</title>
<headline>Wages for U.S. women fall for first time - study.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>The pay of working women fell in the early 1990s after rising for more than a decade, reversing a trend that had helped steady family incomes as men's wages tumbled, a study said Sunday.</p>
<p>Pay for most men also fell in the latest period, and the wage declines came as compensation for corporate chief executive officers soared, according to the study by the Economic Policy Institute, a liberal think tank in Washington.</p>
<p>At the same time, business profitability rose to the highest level in 30 years, according to the study, &quot;The State of Working America&quot;, released to coincide with the Labour Day holiday.</p>
<p>&quot;The changes in the economy have been 'all pain, no gain' for most workers,&quot; the authors of the study wrote. &quot;The economy is clearly in transition, but it is far from certain that it is headed to a better place.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;It seems that women who were previously immune have caught a touch of the male wage disease,&quot; said Jared Bernstein, a labour economist at the institute and one of the authors of the study.</p>
<p>He said the decline was the first time that wages for most working women had dropped, according to the institute's research going back to the late 1970s.</p>
<p>The study follows recent reports that have pointed to a modest pickup in wages for American workers. But Bernstein said the recent evidence of rising wages amounted to &quot;a lot of smoke and very little fire&quot; and that wages appear to be stagnating after falling earlier in the decade.</p>
<p>For the period between 1989 and 1995, the typical male worker's hourly wages fell 6.3 percent, after inflation, which was consistent with the pace of decline in the 1980s, the study said.</p>
<p>But the typical working woman's wages fell 1.7 percent over the same period, reversing some of the 5.7 increase experienced in the 1980s.</p>
<p>The decline in wages was not offset by an increase in benefits, according to the study. Total compensation, including wages and benefits, has grown just 0.1 percent faster than hourly wages alone since 1979, the study said.</p>
<p>Not suprisingly, the drop in wages contributed to a decline in family income. The annual income of a median family, which means half earn more and half earn less, fell 5.2 percent, or nearly $2,200, between 1989 and 1994, the last year for which data were available.</p>
<p>The drop in women's wages also meant families could no longer offset men's lower earnings with increased earnings from wives, the study said. Although wages fell for the typical working woman, the highest-paid women have not suffered a decline.</p>
<p>The worst decline in wages came in entry-level jobs. Hourly wages for typical high-school graduates fell almost 7 percent. College graduates also suffered a drop in pay, 9.5 percent for men and 7.7 percent for women.</p>
<p>While wages were falling, corporate chief executives' pay soared to 173 times that of the average worker in 1995, from a multiple of 122 in 1989 and about 60 in 1978, the study found.</p>
<p>It said the rise in companies' return on invested capital, which hit a 30-year high in 1995, came not from greater investment or improved productivity, but rather was fuelled by stagnant or falling wages. Wages are one of a company's biggest expenses, so any reduction would help profits.</p>
<p>&quot;Profit rates are at a 30-year high. That would not be so objectionable if the fruits of growth were being shared equally,&quot; economist Bernstein said by telephone.</p>
<p>While the study painted a picture of continued tough times for most low- and middle-income families, there were some bright spots.</p>
<p>It noted that while job security has dropped, unemployment has dipped to about 5.3 percent, inflation remains relatively low near 3 percent and some tax changes enacted in 1994, especially expanding the earned income tax credit, have helped boost earnings of poor workers.</p>
<p>The other authors were Lawrence Mishel, the institute's research director, and John Schmitt, a labour economist at the institute. All figures were adjusted for inflation.</p>
<p>The fourth edition of the biennial study can be ordered by calling (800) 374-4844. A summary can be found at the institute's Web site (http://www.epinet.org). A final version is due out in book form in December.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
