<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260670" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: SOCCER-&quot;JUST LET ME PLAY&quot;, BAGGIO TELLS MILAN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-&quot;JUST LET ME PLAY&quot;, BAGGIO TELLS MILAN.</headline>
<dateline>MILAN 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roberto Baggio on Tuesday dismissed as a joke media reports he would quit AC Milan for city rivals Inter, but said his future with the Italian champions would remain unclear unless they let him play.</p>
<p>&quot;I categorically deny the joke that I have offered myself to Inter,&quot; Baggio told reporters. &quot;And I haven't had any meetings with Parma.&quot;</p>
<p>But he added: &quot;I don't know yet whether I will stay at Milan or whether I will leave. The only sure thing is I want to play.&quot;</p>
<p>Media reports at the weekend said Baggio, who is suffering from sciatica, had quarrelled with Arrigo Sacchi, the former national coach who returned to his old club Milan two weeks ago.</p>
<p>Nicknamed &quot;The Divine Ponytail&quot; by fans, Baggio missed a penalty in the 1994 World Cup Final in Los Angeles against Brazil and played for Italy only sporadically until Sacchi dropped him from the Italy squad for the European championship in England in June.</p>
<p>Newspapers speculated that was the cause of ill-will between the two men, now working together again at Milan, where Baggio has spent much of the season on the bench.</p>
<p>Sacchi said Baggio had no divine right to play.</p>
<p>&quot;All the players...are the same to me,&quot; he told reporters on Tuesday. &quot;I don't have preferences. I play whoever's most on form...If Baggio stays, I'll be happy but I can't guarantee anyone a place in the team.&quot;</p>
<p>Baggio, 29, joined Milan at the start of last season from current world club champions Juventus but was injured for much of the campaign.</p>
<p>&quot;My physical condition is getting better. I still feel a bit of pain but I'm a lot better than I was last week,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MILAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
