<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260624" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ALPINE SKIING-TOMBA RETURNS TO ITALIAN ADULATION.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-TOMBA RETURNS TO ITALIAN ADULATION.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>MADONNA DI CAMPIGLIO, Italy 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Alberto Tomba finally returned to the Alpine skiing circuit on Tuesday and rewarded his loud and exuberant fans with the eighth fastest time in the first leg of a World Cup slalom.</p>
<p>Austrian Siegfried Voglreiter, who has never finished a slalom higher than sixth place, was well positioned for a remarkable first win after starting 23rd and clocking the fastest unofficial time of 46.40 seconds.</p>
<p>Norway's Ole Christian Furuseth, starting 13th, clocked 45.54 but admitted that he had missed a gate and was disqualified.</p>
<p>France's Sebastien Amiez, who was lucky to escape unhurt from a heavy crash in Tuesday's warm-up, was equal second fastest with Austrian Thomas Sykora over the 55-gate first leg on Madonna's Canalone Miramonti piste in 46.47.</p>
<p>While the Austrians again found themselves leading the field, there was no doubt who was the star on a sunny day with Italians out in force to see their hero return.</p>
<p>Tomba, who celebrates his 30th birthday on Thursday and is sporting a longer, curly hairstyle having left the Carabinieri paramilitary police, started for the first time this season after being sidelined by a knee and wrist injury.</p>
<p>Suitably, for the world slalom champion, Tomba had bib number one and was first out of the starting hut to a cacophany of klaxons from a loyal fan club finally given their first chance of the season to let loose all their energies.</p>
<p>&quot;With Alberto on the piste, its a big party,&quot; read a banner at the finish. &quot;Welcome back, Alberto&quot; said another.</p>
<p>&quot;He needs a few races,&quot; said Furuseth, adding that it was &quot;very good&quot; to see the Italian back again.</p>
<p>Tomba, who clocked a competitive 47.13 seconds, said the piste was not as good as it had been last year -- when he won on his birthday -- but he was pleased with his performance.</p>
<p>He was followed down by Austria's Michael Tritscher, who crashed heavily half way down the piste.</p>
<p>The Austrian, currently fifth in the slalom World Cup standings, lay on the snow while medical staff attended to him. He later reappeared at the finish, limping.</p>
<p>Tritscher said he had fallen when his right knee suddenly gave way and he would be having further checks.</p>
<p>Compatriot Thomas Stangassinger, second in the slalom standings after a second and a third place this season, also fell just a couple of gates from the finish.</p>
<p>The second, 62-gate leg was due to start at 1200 GMT</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADONNA DI CAMPIGLIO, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
