<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260641" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: WEMBLEY NAMED AS SITE FOR NEW UK NATIONAL STADIUM.</title>
<headline>WEMBLEY NAMED AS SITE FOR NEW UK NATIONAL STADIUM.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's Sports Council on Tuesday named Wembley as the site of the country's new national sports stadium.</p>
<p>Wembley, the north London venue which has been the home of English soccer since the 1920s, was chosen in preference to Manchester, the northern English city that will host the Commonwealth Games in 2002.</p>
<p>Some 100 million pounds ($166 million) in National Lottery funds are expected to be provided to help pay for the complete redevelopment of Wembley Stadium, a wholly-owned subsidiary of Wembley Plc .</p>
<p>Architect Sir Norman Foster has unveiled plans for an 80,000-seater stadium. In his design Wembley's famous twin towers would be repositioned to form a new gateway to the stadium area. However a competiton will be held to choose the design for the new stadium.</p>
<p>The English Football Association hopes that the new stadium will boost its chances of staging the World Cup in 2006.</p>
<p>Wembley and Manchester were short-listed from five initial bidders last year. But Wembley emerged as the clear favourite after soccer, athletics and rugby league all threw their weight behind its bid two months ago. ($1=.6027 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
