<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260730" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Security tight for Major visit to edgy N.Ireland.</title>
<headline>Security tight for Major visit to edgy N.Ireland.</headline>
<byline>Martin Cowley</byline>
<dateline>BELFAST 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Prime Minister John Major arrived in Northern Ireland for a high-security visit on Tuesday, his first since IRA bombers struck at the heart of Britain's military presence here in October.</p>
<p>Hours after the United States and Ireland stepped up demands for the outlawed Irish Republican Army to call off violence and revive a shattered peace drive, Major flew in for what officials said was his &quot;traditional Christmas visit&quot; to greet troops, community groups and industrialists.</p>
<p>British sources said troops and police would be on increased alert during his overnight visit following the collapse of a 17- month IRA truce and recent hostilities by a republican splinter group, the Irish Continuity Army Council.</p>
<p>&quot;The security situation means that security forces are more edgy than they would have been in ceasefire times,&quot; a source said.</p>
<p>IRA guerrillas fighting British rule killed a soldier and wounded 30 others in a double car bomb attack at British military headquarters in Lisburn, near Belfast, on October 7.</p>
<p>It was the first IRA attack in Northern Ireland for two years and came nine months after the guerrillas went back to a war footing with bombs on mainland Britain.</p>
<p>Recent explosives and armaments finds have fuelled British fears that republican guerrillas are planning further attacks.</p>
<p>Northern Ireland's 60 per cent Protestant majority strongly supports rule from London, but the Catholic minority, some of whom back the IRA and its Sinn Fein political arm, want an all-Ireland state ruled from Dublin</p>
<p>Major vows he will not permit the IRA to bomb its way into peace talks and says it must call off a 27-year battle before Sinn Fein can enter talks.</p>
<p>Officials said Major, on his first visit since June and accompanied by his wife Norma, would attend functions in several areas outside Belfast on Wednesday. Political analysts said they did not expect him to announce any policy departures.</p>
<p>In Washington, before holding talks on the troubled Northern Irish peace process, U.S. President Bill Clinton and Irish Prime Minister John Bruton called on the IRA to proclaim a truce.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't make peace until we end violence,&quot; Clinton told reporters before the White House talks.</p>
<p>Bruton said that &quot;from every point of view&quot; it would be better for the IRA to declare a ceasefire paving the way for Sinn Fein to enter talks.</p>
<p>Earlier in a BBC radio interview broadcast in Northern Ireland Bruton played down Anglo-Irish differences on when Sinn Fein should be allowed into talks in the event of an IRA truce.</p>
<p>Irish nationalist hopes for a new truce received a setback recently when Major rejected proposals from Catholic moderate leader John Hume aimed at speeding Sinn Fein's access to talks.</p>
<p>Major says his intelligence agencies must determine whether any new IRA cessation is genuine and intended to last, unlike the first which Britain says was a short-term tactic.</p>
<p>Ireland is opposed to a lengthy delay in bringing Sinn Fein to the talks table once it has subscribed to principles of non-violence and an IRA truce is deemed to be credible.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELFAST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
