<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26083" id="root" date="1996-08-31" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Algeria restaurant bomb kills seven -newSpaper.</title>
<headline>Algeria restaurant bomb kills seven -newSpaper.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-08-31</dateline>
<text>
<p>A bomb explosion in a restaurant west of Algiers on Friday killed seven people, an Algerian newspaper said on Saturday.</p>
<p>Algerian security forces said in a statement that two people were killed and six were wounded when a home-made bomb ripped through a restaurant in the coastal town of Staoueli.</p>
<p>But Le Matin newspaper, quoting witnesses, said the bomb killed seven people and wounded 20.</p>
<p>Liberte newspaper said the bomb was hidden in a bag in front of the restaurant and that a booby-trapped car was defused near the restaurant shortly before the bomb went off.</p>
<p>A week ago a home-made bomb exploded in a market in the western coastal town of Bou Haroun, 65 km (40 miles) from Algiers. Newspapers said it killed two women and five children.</p>
<p>Algerian newspapers quoted the Human Rights National Observatory (ONDH), a government-appointed watchdog, as saying earlier in August that about 1,400 civilians had been killed in bomb attacks blamed on Moslem guerrillas in the past two years.</p>
<p>An estimated 50,000 people have died in Algeria's violence pitting Moslem rebels against government forces since early 1992 when the authorities cancelled a general election in which radical Islamists had taken a commanding lead.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-08-31"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-08-31"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
