<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260806" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: Soccer-CAF confident of 1998 Nations' Cup being staged in Burkina Faso.</title>
<headline>Soccer-CAF confident of 1998 Nations' Cup being staged in Burkina Faso.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Confederation of African Football said it was confident the 1998 African Nations' Cup finals would be staged in Burkina Faso as planned.</p>
<p>CAF president Issa Hayatou will travel to the arid west African country in February or March, shortly after an inspection team visits Burkina Faso at the end of January to check on the progress of stadia and accommodation requirements for the 16-team tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;Mr Hayatou's visit will not be an inspection trip but to lend support to Burkina Faso,&quot; CAF secretary-general Mustapha Fahmy said.</p>
<p>Fahmy said the organisation was confident of the Burkinabes' ability to host the tournament, scheduled for February 1998 -- just a few months ahead of the World Cup finals in France.</p>
<p>The host countries of the last two Nations' Cup finals have pulled out of their commitments, leaving Tunisia in 1994 and South Africa this year having to come in as replacement hosts.</p>
<p>There was much speculation that Burkina Faso might also have a change of heart because of the high costs of staging the tournament.</p>
<p>&quot;We have heard good news from the president of the organising committee during our meetings in Cairo last week,&quot; said Fahmy.</p>
<p>&quot;We are satisfied that the accomodiation facilities will be in order, particularly after the recent Francophone summit and the stadium in Bobo-Dialassou is also nearing completion.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UPVOLA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
