<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260981" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: LOT sets up domestic flights subsidary.</title>
<headline>LOT sets up domestic flights subsidary.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's state-owned national carrier PLL LOT SA has set up a fully-owned subsidary  Eurolot to operate its current domestic and regional flights and launch new flights, LOT's president said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jan Litwinski told a news conference the new firm, due to start operations in April, was set in line with LOT's strategy of focusing on its profitable international flights and transfering other non-core operations to subsidiaries.</p>
<p>&quot;In LOT's strategy there is no room for expanding in domestic and regional flights so this moment seems suitable to set up such a firm...the idea was also to lower LOT's deficit (on domestic operations),&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Litwinski said a specialised domestic and regional carrier would be better positioned to develop new connections and win LOT expected the domestic flights would bring it a nine-million-zloty loss in 1996.</p>
<p>Mariusz Tazbir, a member of Eurolot's management, also present, suggested the firm was likely to stay in the red next year and did not say when it could start bringing profits.</p>
<p>The new firm was expected to have 356,000 passengers on domestic flights in the 1997 summer season, and 480,000 passengers on both domestic and short-distance international flights to smaller centres.</p>
<p>LOT carried 203,000 passengers on domestic flights in the summer season this year.</p>
<p>Litwinski did not rule out a sale of a part of Eurolot, but did not give any details.</p>
<p>&quot;There is an interest in the project...and we are open for proposals, but first we want to start operating,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Eurolot would operate renting LOT's aircraft, but Litwinski said the company planned to buy new 19 or 30-seat planes.</p>
<p>&quot;We are negotiating with four aircraft suppliers,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Malgorzata Rzepka +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
