<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="260972" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: Czech PX50 and RPIX indices close higher.</title>
<headline>Czech PX50 and RPIX indices close higher.</headline>
<dateline>PRAGUE 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Czech PX50 index closed higher on Tuesday led by the four most heavily capitalised shares on the Prague Stock Exchange (PSE) which all rose.</p>
<p>SPT Telecom again led the way with a 37 crown gain to 3,128 but dealers said domestic investors had been responsible for most of the buying with foreigners staying on the sidelines.</p>
<p>&quot;I haven't seen much demand from outside the country. Its mainly domestic buying,&quot; said Lubomir Vystavel of ING Barings.</p>
<p>Foreign investors have been put off the Czech equities market because of fears over the lack of regulation in the capital markets.</p>
<p>The Czech government at the weekend said it would take steps to improve the situation early next year and the PSE has said it will try to set up a US style securities watchdog perhaps as early as next July.</p>
<p>Other major issues also rose. CEZ gained five crowns to 977, Komercni Banka rose 11 crowns to 2,091 and Ceska Sporitelna was up three crowns to 316.</p>
<p>In the broader market, glass fibre maker Vertex resumed its sharply downward course with a 159 crown fall to 3,041.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PRAGUE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
