<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261042" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria debates 1997 budget, currency board plan.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria debates 1997 budget, currency board plan.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's cabinet has begun debating a 1997 budget designed to allow implementation of a tough monetary regime but has not yet approved a final draft, a government spokeswoman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Late last night the cabinet debated a 1997 budget draft which involves introduction of a currency board plan but it came to no decision,&quot; a government spokeswoman told reporters.</p>
<p>The budget frame has not yet been finalised, she added, declining to elaborate.</p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund (IMF) proposed the introduction of a currency board to restore confidence in the lev, which has collapsed from 70 to the dollar at the start of the year to 500 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Under the system the amount of levs in circulation must be matched with the central bank's hard currency reserves.</p>
<p>The currency board, whose adoption must be approved by parliament, halts central bank lending to the government, state enterprises and commercial banks.</p>
<p>Bulgaria has yet to debate to which currency and at what rate to peg the lev. The dollar is traditionally seen as a benchmark of stability, but some circles are lobbying for the mark, as Germany is the biggest investor in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;Acceleration of inflation will depend very much on the rate at which the lev will be pegged,&quot; Vice President of Emerging Markets Research at Salomon Brothers David Boren told Reuters.</p>
<p>If the lev is pegged lower than the market rate, Bulgaria will remain competitive for a longer period and the local currency will appreciate, he said.</p>
<p>If the rate is closer to the current market rate it would be less painful when the currency board is implemented, but the lev would not retain its credibility over a longer period of time, he added.</p>
<p>IMF technical missions are currently in Sofia to help prepare the draft budget and the legal amendments needed to make the plan operational.</p>
<p>A preliminary draft prepared by the finance ministry three weeks ago envisaged a budget deficit of 370 billion levs or nine percent of gross domestic product (GDP), which is estimated at 4.054 trillion levs.</p>
<p>Expenditure was assumed at 1.46 trillion levs and revenue at 1.090 trillion levs.</p>
<p>GDP, which fell by 6.2 percent for the first half of this year, is seen falling a further 8.2 percent.</p>
<p>One of Bulgaria's options is to agree on a currency board implementation timetable with the IMF missions this month and make the necessary legal adjustments in the next one or two months and then introduce the currency board.</p>
<p>The alternative is to make the legal adjustments as soon as possible and introduce the plan in January, bankers said.</p>
<p>--  Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
