<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261286" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel dodges Clinton jab on settlements.</title>
<headline>Israel dodges Clinton jab on settlements.</headline>
<byline>Howard Goller</byline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel on Tuesday rejected criticism by U.S. President Bill Clinton of Jewish settlements and vowed to strengthen its hold on the outposts that Clinton called an obstacle to peace.</p>
<p>At the White House on Monday, Clinton toughened his stance against an Israeli settlement revival in occupied Arab lands launched by right-wing Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, who came to power six months ago.</p>
<p>&quot;The policy of this government is to strengthen settlement in places where it exists,&quot; Israeli Defence Minister Yitzhak Mordechai told reporters in the Gaza Strip after visiting Jewish settlers there.</p>
<p>&quot;There are natural needs and necessary growth and I believe this policy is clear and was explained to every national or international element,&quot; Mordechai said.</p>
<p>Clinton on Monday embraced the tough language of his predecessor George Bush on the issue. Asked at the White House if he would call settlements an obstacle to peace, Clinton told reporters: &quot;Absolutely&quot;.</p>
<p>Israeli-Palestinian tensions flared in the last week over Israel's decision to grant financial benefits to West Bank settlements. The cabinet action followed the killing of a settler mother and her son by Arab gunmen.</p>
<p>Netanyahu declined comment on Clinton's remarks when asked by reporters on Tuesday. But his communications chief David Bar-Illan shrugged off the U.S. presidential jab.</p>
<p>Bar-Illan said that Washington, not Israel, had to change its policy and insisted the Jewish state's relations with its close U.S. ally were as excellent as ever.</p>
<p>&quot;The position of the administration on the settlements has been consistent...They are opposed to any activity on the settlements and we have to try to change their minds but obviously we haven't been able to,&quot; Bar-Illan told Reuters.</p>
<p>He voiced astonishment at reaction to the Israeli decision which he said was meant to eliminate discrimination against West Bank settlers by giving them benefits enjoyed by Israelis in other areas captured in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Palestinian officials hailed Clinton's remarks, saying Washington had begun playing an important role in peacemaking.</p>
<p>&quot;President Clinton has realised that settlement activity is fatal to the peace process,&quot; Ahmed Korei, speaker of the 89-member Palestinian legislature, told Reuters.</p>
<p>A White House spokesman said Washington found the latest policy on settlements &quot;a complicating factor&quot; in peace efforts which have been stuck on the long-overdue handover of 80 percent of the West Bank town of Hebron to Palestinian rule.</p>
<p>Ties with Washington reached a 35-year low over an Israeli settlement boom when Likud was last in power in the early 1990s.</p>
<p>At the time President Bush awarded $10 billion in U.S. loan guarantees only after Yitzhak Rabin came to power in 1992 and froze new settlement building. Netanyahu lifted the freeze after winning election in May this year.</p>
<p>In Vienna, Austrian Chancellor Franz Vranitzky said Netanyahu had told him in a phone call on Tuesday to expect an accord on Hebron within days. The sides renewed talks on Monday, prodded by Clinton who insisted the time had come for a deal.</p>
<p>Since a White House summit prompted by bloodshed nearly three months ago, Israel and the PLO have failed to agree on security arrangements which Netanyahu wants to protect some 400 Jews in the heart of Hebron, amid more than 100,000 Arabs.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
