<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261299" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>EGYPT: Egyptian shares rise despite some profit taking.</title>
<headline>Egyptian shares rise despite some profit taking.</headline>
<dateline>CAIRO 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Egyptian share prices reversed on Tuesday the declines of the last three trading days despite some profit-taking, especially in the important milling sector.</p>
<p>The Capital Market Authority (CMA) all-share index closed 0.58 points up at 287.96 on relatively higher turnover of 45.22 million pounds ($13.3 million).</p>
<p>&quot;The profit taking in the milling sector continues,&quot; said Sherif Cararah of brokers EFG/Hermes. &quot;There was profit taking in Medinet Nasr too but the volume was very thin,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Medinet Nasr Housing and Development, one of the most successful privatisations of the year, closed 6.50 pounds lower at 296.00 but there were only 12 deals during the session.</p>
<p>Central and West Delta Mills, one of the three most active shares, ended unchanged at 81.50 but East Delta Flour Mills fell 1.00 to 52.31 and North Cairo Flour Mills slipped 1.75 to 131.25 pounds.</p>
<p>In the cement sector, another pillar of the Egyptian exchange, Helwan Portland Cement slipped 0.25 to 59.75 in heavy turnover while Suez Cement rose 0.50 to end the day at 54.00 pounds.</p>
<p>There was no immediate word on the state's offer to sell 10 percent of Amriyah Cement to one or more stretgic investors. The deadline for bids was Monday.</p>
<p>Cararah said that after a 10 percent rise since the all-share index set a new record in late November it was a good sign that prices appear to have stabilised.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm very happy with the market because it's healthy. It couldn't go up and up without a rest. But I do see it going higher in the first quarter of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said the price rises had pushed average P/E ratios up to between nine and 10 but the average would fall again when many key shares go ex-dividend in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>The CMA index for openly traded firms rose to 434.95 from 433.28 on Monday and the index for rarely traded &quot;closed&quot; firms rose to 202.01 from 201.82.</p>
<p>Of a total 74 shares traded, 27 fell and 14 rose while the rest closed unchanged.</p>
<p>$1 = 3.4 pounds</p>
<p>-- Cairo newsroom +20 2 578 3290/1</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EGYPT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CAIRO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="EGYPT"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
