<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261311" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Blue chips romp higher as Fed keeps rates steady.</title>
<headline>Blue chips romp higher as Fed keeps rates steady.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK</dateline>
<text>
<p>Blue-chip stocks posted large gains Tuesday as the Federal Reserve's decision to keep interest rates unchanged brought back buyers from the sidelines for the first time in a week.</p>
<p>The Dow Jones industrial average ended up 39.98 points at 6,308.33, propelled by the top technology and financial names -- the same stocks that fuelled the fierce November rally.</p>
<p>In the broader market, advancing issues led declines 1,246 to 1,240 on active volume of 519 million shares on the New York Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>&quot;The old leaders are re-asserting themselves,&quot; said Joseph Battipaglia, chief investment officer at Gruntal &amp; Co. &quot;We've essentially had a 5 percent correction without a fundamental change in the economy.&quot;</p>
<p>With the Dow's losses exceeding 200 points over the last four sessions as investors cashed in profits from last month's gains amid worries about corporate profits, analysts said stocks were starting to look like bargains.</p>
<p>&quot;What we saw over the prior three or four days was a pretty significant underperformance,&quot; said Douglas Cliggott, U.S. equity strategist at J.P. Morgan. &quot;We had actually gotten to a point where stocks looked undervalued vs. bonds.&quot;</p>
<p>Indeed, stocks were able to post their rally despite weakness in the bond market.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond was off nearly half a point, raising its yield, which moves in the opposite direction from the price, to 6.66 percent from 6.63 percent at Monday's close.</p>
<p>Although the Fed's decision to hold short-term interest rates unchanged was widely expected, it was viewed as a sign the central bank was satisfied with the economy's performance.</p>
<p>The Fed, which last set the federal funds rate at 5.25 percent and the discount rate at 5.0 percent on Feb. 1, has seen the longest stretch of unchanged rates since 1993.</p>
<p>The central bank has kept interest rates steady as the economy settles down and inflation remains in check as the year draws to a close.</p>
<p>&quot;This was not exactly a roaring surprise,&quot; said Larry Wachtel, an analyst at Prudential Securities. &quot;It was the non-event of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>While the stock market bounce was a welcome sign, the mood on Wall Street was far from exuberant. For the second straight session, a major investment firm -- this time the nation's largest -- voiced caution on the stock market's outlook.</p>
<p>At a press briefing, top  strategists at Merrill Lynch predicted that next year investors might be better served by holding bonds instead of stocks.</p>
<p>Merrill Chief Economist Donald Straszheim said the firm expected operating earnings among companies in the Standard &amp; Poor's 500 index would rise only 2.5 percent in 1997 vs. an expected gain this year of 6.1 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The equity markets are not going to have quite the tailwind of earnings,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Dow's top gainers included International Business Machines Corp., which rose 3-1/8 to 151-3/4, and J.P. Morgan &amp; Co. Inc., up 2-5/8 to 97-3/8.</p>
<p>Frontier Corp. fell 5-5/8 to 20-3/4 after warning that its fourth quarter earnings would be below year-ago levels. Frontier was the NYSE's most heavily traded stock.</p>
<p>General Electric Co. climbed 2-1/2 to 97-5/8, a day after its Chairman John Welch briefed analysts on the company's outlook. A company spokesman declined to comment on Welch's remarks but analysts who attended the meeting described the talk as upbeat. During his remarks, Welch expressed confidence GE would meet Wall Street earnings estimates for the 1996 calendar year, analysts said.</p>
<p>Stanford Telecommunications Inc. rose 4-1/8 to 29-3/4 after Oppenheimer &amp; Co.  raised its rating on the shares.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq Composite index rose 5.34 points to 1,266.32.</p>
<p>The Standard &amp; Poor's composite index of 500 stocks rose 5.06 to 726.04. The American Stock Exchange index was off 2.26 to 570.31.</p>
<p>The NYSE Composite index of all listed common stocks rose 1.92 to 382.77. The average share was up 20 cents.</p>
<p>The Wilshire Associates Equity Index -- the market value of NYSE, American and Nasdaq issues -- was 7,028.131 up 29.508 or 0.42 percent.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
