<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261328" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Shuttle Challenger pieces wash ashore in Florida.</title>
<headline>Shuttle Challenger pieces wash ashore in Florida.</headline>
<byline>Steven Young</byline>
<dateline>COCOA BEACH, Fla 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two large pieces of wreckage from the space shuttle Challenger washed ashore on Tuesday, nearly 11 years after the explosion that ripped the spacecraft apart and killed all seven astronauts on board.</p>
<p>A 15-by-6-foot (4.5-by-2-metre) section of the shuttle's wing came ashore at Cocoa Beach, south of the Kennedy Space Centre, NASA spokesman Bruce Buckingham said. A second piece of wreckage about 5-feet by 1-foot (1.5-by-.3 metres) was found a short distance away.</p>
<p>&quot;It's been years and years since we've recovered a piece like this,&quot; he told a news conference. &quot;This is probably one of the biggest parts that has washed ashore.&quot;</p>
<p>The aluminum wing structure was encrusted with barnacles and had become home to several small crabs but was instantly recognisable as a piece of the doomed shuttle by its distinctive heat protection tiles.</p>
<p>&quot;As soon as I topped the dunes, I knew it was part of Challenger,&quot; said Ron Phelps, the NASA engineer who was sent to investigate Tuesday's discovery.</p>
<p>Challenger exploded 73 seconds after blastoff on Jan. 28, 1986, killing the seven astronauts including New Hampshire school teacher Christa McAuliffe, who was selected through a &quot;Teacher in Space&quot; programme. Other astronauts who died were Francis Scobee, Michael Smith, Judith Resnik, Ronald McNair, Ellison Onizuka and Gregory Jarvis.</p>
<p>A massive recovery operation was mounted after the disaster but only about half of the orbiter was recovered from the ocean. Phelps said the wreckage found on Tuesday had been positively identified as part of the left wing, the first section of that part of the shuttle to be recovered.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know if we've recovered anything this large since we concluded the investigation in 1986,&quot; he told reporters.</p>
<p>The section of wing was spotted by residents in the early morning but officials at the Kennedy Space Centre and Cocoa Beach police were not notified for about four hours. Local residents said a handful of people broke off souvenirs before police roped off the area to keep back the sightseers.</p>
<p>Buckingham warned those who had taken pieces of the shuttle that they could face legal action. &quot;It's government property,&quot; he said. &quot;If you are in possession of it and if you do not readily turn it over then you could be prosecuted.&quot;</p>
<p>The shuttle pieces were taken by truck to the Kennedy Space Centre for official identification. In the new year, they will be placed in a missile silo at Cape Canaveral Air Station, along with more than 200,000 pounds (90,720 kg) of Challenger debris already recovered from the Atlantic.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COCOA BEACH, Fla"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
