<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261481" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Southeast power rises as thermometer dips.</title>
<headline>U.S. Southeast power rises as thermometer dips.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Spot bulk electricity prices in the southeastern U.S. were driven higher again Tuesday by cold weather and the resulting shortage of supply and strong natural gas prices, sources said.</p>
<p>Firm, peak power prices in the northern part of the Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA) territory for Wednesday were sharply higher again after gaining about $8.00 Monday.</p>
<p>Traders said most deals were done around $31.00, as compared with the $21.00-23.00 trading range seen on Monday.</p>
<p>January/February TVA prices were talked in the $26.00-27.00 area.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak electricity in northern TVA was notionally assessed at $15.00-17.00.</p>
<p>At the Georgia/Florida border, prices for firm, peak electricity in 16 hour blocks for Wednesday delivery were widely discussed in the $28.00-32.00 range, as compared with Monday's mid-$20s.</p>
<p>&quot;Prices are pretty much converging everywhere in the Midwest and Southeast,&quot; one market source said.</p>
<p>Firm, off-peak power for Wednesday at the Ga./Fla. border was still notionally assessed at $15.50-16.00.</p>
<p>In Florida, where most daytime highs are in the 70s Fahrenheit and lows are in the 50s, peak power prices on a 16-hour schedule for Wednesday were discussed in the $34.00-36.00 range, as compared with the $23.00-25.00 area seen on Monday.</p>
<p>Temperatures in the region are expected to dip to about 10-20 degrees Fahrenheit below-normal Wednesday through Saturday.</p>
<p>Separately, Southern Co's 822 megawatt (MW) Farley 2 nuclear unit in Alabama, shut this weekend, is expected to restart Tuesday evening.</p>
<p>Entergy's 858 MW Arkansas 2 nuclear unit returned to the grid Tuesday.</p>
<p>Like power prices, natural gas spot values on the Gulf Coast rose by about 40 cents today into the low-$4.40s per million British thermal units.</p>
<p>--H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
