<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261612" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - Dollar consolidates with eye toward upside.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - Dollar consolidates with eye toward upside.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The dollar should remain largely range-bound in coming sessions, but good supports against the mark and yen continue to offer hope for a fresh rally higher, technical analysts said.</p>
<p>Dollar/yen faces a current upside hurdle at 114.25/30, Monday's peak, and will probably require a fresh push upward by mark/yen to retest the 1996 highs near 115, chartists said.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/yen has been moving in a rising channel since early December&quot; after bottoming at 111.73 on December 6, noted Martin Autotte, a technical analyst at CIBC Wood Gundy in Montreal.  </p>
<p>Others were a bit less sanguine, noting the dollar has essentially followed mark/yen's lead for several sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no real dollar story at the moment,&quot; said Darren Spain, technical analyst at Credit Suisse. &quot;Mark/yen generally seems buoyant and is likely to grind higher in the short term toward 73.95,&quot; which is a 50 percent Fibonacci retracement of the decline from late October to early November.</p>
<p>Dollar/mark has been consolidating since it reached a 23-month high at 1.5735 on December 3. Some chartists now see a triangle pattern forming, which would suggest dollar/mark could eventually break higher.  </p>
<p>&quot;Triangles are usually known as continuation patterns, so that favors a break to the upside, but I would wait for that break before initiating any long positions,&quot; Autotte said.</p>
<p>Autotte said he sees good dollar support at 1.54 marks, with resistance at 1.5535.</p>
<p>While Spain agreed that support seems good between 1.54 and 1.5410 marks, and cited solid resistance at the 1.5580/85 area, he rejected readings of a triangle pattern.</p>
<p>&quot;There's no justification for people to be drawing a triangle at this point,&quot; Spain said, adding, &quot;we are certainly seeing some consolidative activity&quot; in dollar/mark.  </p>
<p>Spain sees a dollar test of lows just as likely as a rally higher and cites support at 1.5390 marks and a critical floor at 1.5292 marks.</p>
<p>Mark/yen flirted more than once with a significant support at 73.40 on Monday and chartists said a failure to hold there could bring immediate downward pressure on dollar/yen.</p>
<p>Elsewhere, cable charts look strong having pierced $1.6665 resistance Monday and held support at $1.6630 overnight.</p>
<p>&quot;Cable has a date with fate at $1.68,&quot; Spain mused.</p>
<p>--Chris Stetkiewicz, 212-859-1664</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
