<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261743" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: BoF warns against softening Maastrict criteria.</title>
<headline>BoF warns against softening Maastrict criteria.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bank of France governor Jean-Claude Trichet warned on Tuesday against watering down tough qualifying conditions for joining Europe's planned single currency, saying it would hurt all countries concerned.</p>
<p>Asked at the central bank's annual news conference whether he wanted Italy and Spain to be part of the single currency at its scheduled startup on January 1, 1999, he said he hoped &quot;the largest number of countries possible&quot; could join.</p>
<p>But Trichet, reiterating a longstanding position, said membership should be determined by &quot;respecting the criteria, the spirit and the letter of the (Maastricht) treaty.&quot;</p>
<p>Both Italy and Spain were long regarded as lagging behind frontrunners such as Germany in getting their finances in order to meet conditions for monetary union but have announced tough budget measures in recent months to be part of the first wave.</p>
<p>Trichet, without singling out any countries, said the entire single currency zone would suffer by allowing nations to take part which had not met the economic convergence criteria.</p>
<p>Along with cutting deficits to three percent of gross domestic product, conditions include strict public debt, inflation, interest rate and exchange rate thresholds for membership.</p>
<p>&quot;If a country with high inflation, a high deficit, high costs joins the single currency, it would naturally upset the single currency zone,&quot; he said. &quot;Companies in the single currency zone would see their market interest rates rise.&quot;</p>
<p>Countries which took part without having met the strict criteria would find their hands tied in adjusting their economic policies as they would be bound by the conditions of the European Union stability pact agreed last weekend in Dublin.</p>
<p>The pact is designed to police budgetary discipline after monetary union.</p>
<p>&quot;It is imperative to be well prepared to enter monetary union...to gain the maximum benefit,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>At the same time, he said he &quot;was absolutely confident&quot; the transition to a single currency &quot;will be much smoother than is sometimes forseeen&quot; and that a &quot;nice and appropriate&quot; consensus would be reached on which countries should join.</p>
<p>That decision is due to be made early in 1998 on the basis of 1997 economic and budget performances.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G154">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
