<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261790" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss stocks end lowwer, eyes on Novartis.</title>
<headline>Swiss stocks end lowwer, eyes on Novartis.</headline>
<dateline>ZURICH 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Swiss shares closed lower in sagging volume and nervous trade as investors concentrated on U.S. approval for Ciba-Geigy and Sandoz to merge as Novartis, the world's second biggest pharmaceuticals company.</p>
<p>Profit-taking pushed shares in both companies lower after they had run up on news the companies had scheduled a news conference on the FTC decision.</p>
<p>Sandoz bearer shares closed four Swiss francs lower at 1,525. Ciba-Geigy registered shares shed two to 1,625.</p>
<p>The blue-chip Swiss Market Index (SMI) fell 18.8 points, or 0.49 percent, to 3,850.4.</p>
<p>All-share Swiss Performance Index (SPI) closed down 11.82 points, or 0.48 percent, to 2,459.92.</p>
<p>A rise in U.S. November housing starts pressured shares in late trade, but the indices pulled away from the day's lows after a friendly Wall Street opening.</p>
<p>The market was expected to remain shaky in the next few days, although Wall Street may keep present levels as a U.S. interest rate cuts looks unlikely, one dealer said.</p>
<p>&quot;There will be more stock picking,&quot; he added, pointing out that on Friday alone around 15 shares options will expire.</p>
<p>Alusuisse and Sulzer soared more than one percent each.</p>
<p>Dealers said that Alusuisse was fundamentally strong and Sulzer was propelled by hopes for further spin offs.</p>
<p>Ciba and Sandoz surged when they called a news conference, with Ciba briefly at an all-time high of 1,649 Swiss francs and Sandoz up to 1,540.</p>
<p>But they slipped after announcing U.S. regulatory approval for the Novartis merger. Traders said the decline was due to profit-taking and saisd the approval had been expected.</p>
<p>Among financials, insurer Baloise fell four percent to 2,760 francs.</p>
<p>Dealers cited disappointment that Baloise at a news conference had not announced a partnership or takeover, but instead unveiled a capital repayment, share split and withdrawal from some markets.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZURICH"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
