<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261803" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Metalbank takes Kolbenschmidt stake.</title>
<headline>Metalbank takes Kolbenschmidt stake.</headline>
<dateline>MUNICH, Germany</dateline>
<text>
<p>Metallbank GmbH, the banking unit once part of German conglomerate Metallgesellschaft AG, confirmed Tuesday it has acquired a 24.99 percent stake in car components group Kolbenschmidt AG.</p>
<p>The company said it has already passed the stake, which was formerly held by Commerzbank AG, onward at a discount of around 5 percent to the market value.</p>
<p>It also said British engineering firm T&amp;N has an option on the package.</p>
<p>T&amp;N Plc had an option to buy Commerzbank's former 49.99 percent holding in Kolbenschmidt but was blocked from doing so by German cartel authorities. That option was due to expire at the end of this year and Commerzbank said it had no plans to extend it.</p>
<p>Separately, T&amp;N said it has extended its option on a 24.99 percent stake in Kolbenschmidt until September 1997 and that Commerzbank had passed the stake on to Metallbank, which was acting for a group of European investors.</p>
<p>It said an announcement about its option for the further 24.99 percent in the group would be made shortly.</p>
<p>Metallbank trading division manager Lothar Mark said in a telephone interview the deal with 6.7 million Kolbenschmidt shares had cost some 125 million marks ($80.9 million) -- about 5 percent below the market value of the shares.</p>
<p>Sources in Munich had named Metallbank as the taker for the package, which Commerzbank said it had passed onward.</p>
<p>Kolbenschmidt shares closed bourse trade on Tuesday 21 pfennigs (65 cents) lower at 19.30 marks ($12.49), broadly in line with the market trend.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35300">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MUNICH, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
