<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261999" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>India: Bombay shares end shade higher on fund buying.</title>
<headline>Bombay shares end shade higher on fund buying.</headline>
<dateline>BOMBAY 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bombay shares gained strength by close of trade on Tuesday after a slow start, with pivotals rallying on buying by local funds, dealers said.</p>
<p>The benchmark 30-share index of the Bombay Stock Exchange (BSE) gained 26.56 points, or 0.90 percent, to a provisional close of 2,985.21, the day's highest level.</p>
<p>Some traders said the government's move to drop a non-voting share proposal also helped buoy market sentiments.</p>
<p>&quot;This is good for the markets as it will send a positive signal to local and overseas investors,&quot; said Govind Agarwal, institutional dealer at local brokerage Motilal Oswal.  </p>
<p>He said the 3,000 index level will be a major resistance for the market in the next few sessions.</p>
<p>The Economic Times newspaper on Tuesday reported that the government had dropped its proposal to allow companies to issue non-voting shares.</p>
<p>Foreign funds had been opposed to such stock issues because it diluted the value of their holdings.</p>
<p>Dealers said the Unit Trust of India, the country's biggest mutual fund was a major buyer in a number of shares including Hindustan Lever, Bajaj Auto, SBI and TELCO.  </p>
<p>Short-covering on the last day of weekly trade at the National Stock Exchange (NSE) added to the gains recorded. The NSE index rose 2 points to 849.05 provisional.</p>
<p>TELCO gained 9.50 rupees to 345.0 rupees, ACC 16.0 to 1,116.0, Bajaj Auto 22.70 to 793.0, TISCO 0.50 to 159.25, M&amp;M 3.25 to 323.50 and Hindalco 11.70 to 618.0.</p>
<p>SBI was unchanged at 218.50 while Reliance lost 0.50 rupees to 194.0 and Gujarat Ambuja Cement 3.25 to 235.50.</p>
<p>-- ANSHUMAN DAGA, Bombay newsroom +91-22-265 9000</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOMBAY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
