<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261972" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: PRESS DIGEST - France - Le Monde DEc 17.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - France - Le Monde DEc 17.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are leading stories in afternoon daily Le Monde.</p>
<p>FRONT PAGE</p>
<p>-- Council of State, France's highest administrative court to which the government submits bills for legal vetting, has challenged part of a measure to curb illegal immigration on the grounds that new housing rules would breach individual freedoms.</p>
<p>BUSINESS PAGES</p>
<p>-- In an interview, EU agriculture commissioner Franz Fischler says Britain made serious mistakes in handling the mad cow disease, adding he expects crisis to cost up to 3.5 billion Ecus ($4.4 billion) to the European Union by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>-- Former prime minister Edouard Balladur calls in an interview for increased flexibility in labour laws, as a means to boost employment.</p>
<p>-- CDR structure selling off troubled Credit Lyonnais assets sold 40 billion francs worth of assets in 1996, expects to sell two thirds by the end of 1998. Privatisation Commission agrees to sale of Sligos to Axime before the end of the year.</p>
<p>-- Major commercial banks cut base lending rate to 6.30 from 6.55, its lowest level since 1992.</p>
<p>-- New bank for small and medium businesses BDPME to offer them 10 billion francs in loans from January 1, 1997.</p>
<p>-- Public sale offer on Thomson-CSF, rather than a privatisation by private placement, is not ruled out. Paper says that during the December 16 supervisory board meeting of Thomson SA and Thomson-CSF, the management let it be known that it prefered a market sale over a private placement.</p>
<p>-- Paris Newsroom +33 1 42 21 53 81</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
