<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261994" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>DENMARK: Danish central bank announces new bond issues.</title>
<headline>Danish central bank announces new bond issues.</headline>
<dateline>COPENHAGEN 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Denmark's central bank on Tuesday said it estimated the government's gross domestic financing requirement to be 69.9 billion crowns in 1997 and it announced plans to open two new bond series in January.  </p>
<p>A central bank official told Reuters the 1996 borrowing requirement was 98.3 billion crowns.</p>
<p>A statement said a four percent bond series maturing on February 15, 2000 would open on January 7 1997 and a five percent bond due August 15, 2005 would open on January 14.</p>
<p>Sale of bonds would begin at 1000 GMT on each date through the Copenhagen Stock Exchange match system, it added.</p>
<p>The sale of six percent 1999 treasury notes would continue during the first six months of 1997 and there would be regular issues of short-term paper, it said, but the existing fixed programme of issuing a new note every six months would cease.  </p>
<p>The statement said sales of the six percent 2002, the seven percent 2007 and seven percent 2024 bonds would continue unaltered. There would also be monthly auctions and a new 9-month treasury bill every three months. A new nine-month bill would open on December 20, 1996, it added.</p>
<p>Access would continue to be given to location swaps for a nominal 2 billion crowns in each of the new series, it said. --Steve Weizman, Copenhagen newsroom +45 33969650</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="DEN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="COPENHAGEN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DENMARK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
