<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="261952" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SPAIN: Spain's long-term rates decline almost over - Rojo.</title>
<headline>Spain's long-term rates decline almost over - Rojo.</headline>
<dateline>MADRID 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The decline in Spanish long-term interest rates is almost over, Bank of Spain Governor Luis Angel Rojo said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Spectacular falls in our medium- and long-term rates have come about and we've arrived at a situation where a proportion of reasonable declines is, to a great extent, over,&quot; Rojo told a parliamentary committee.  </p>
<p>Answering questions, Rojo said the central bank had to be cautious in the light of EMU optimism driving financial markets.</p>
<p>Possible changes in the direction of the markets, based on forecasts for monetary union, were &quot;the reason why the Bank of Spain has to be very careful with the evolution of interest rates, because it can't cut them too much while it wishes to leave room for caution,&quot; Rojo said.</p>
<p>On the labour market, Rojo repeated a call for deep reforms to reduce Spain's high unemployment rate. &quot;The Spanish labour market is clamouring for reforms, tough reforms which are difficult to accept, and upon which jobs for young people, who have been so mistreated, depend,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>-- Madrid newsroom +341 585 2160</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SPAIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MADRID"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SPAIN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
