<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262090" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Sweden's Riksbank ends year upbeat on inflation, GDP.</title>
<headline>Sweden's Riksbank ends year upbeat on inflation, GDP.</headline>
<byline>Belinda Goldsmith</byline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM, Sweden</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's central bank Tuesday ended 1996 with an upbeat inflation report that coincided with the 25th cut this year in the key repo rate and positive Gross Domestic Product (GDP) data.</p>
<p>As the Riksbank cut the repo rate by 25 basis points to 4.10 percent, it simultaneously released its final inflation report for the year, saying the outlook for inflation over the next two years was good and even better than three months ago.</p>
<p>The release of GDP figures for the third quarter of 1996 showing a smaller-than-expected rise of 0.8 percent compared to a year ago also buoyed the optimistic mood in the debt market.</p>
<p>The upbeat tone, however, was restrained by a warning from the central bank about wage rises which were seen as the main source of potential inflation.</p>
<p>&quot;The outlook for inflation is somewhat more optimistic than in the report last September,&quot; the Riksbank said in a statement, forecasting inflation rates of 1.5 percent in 1997 and 2 percent in 1998.</p>
<p>It said data since September had brightened the picture.</p>
<p>&quot;The main factors have been strongly rising exports and investment,&quot; the Riksbank said. &quot;Still it is not considered likely that in the coming two years economic activity will rise above the level of resource utilization at which inflation is liable to pick up.&quot;</p>
<p>The lower-than-expected GDP figure was well received as the market had expected to see a rise of 1.5 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;It backs up the inflation report's message that there is no threat by inflation,&quot; one dealer said.</p>
<p>The National Economic Research Institute, KI, has forecast GDP rising 2.7 percent in 1997 and 2.4 percent in 1998 against 1.5 percent this year.</p>
<p>Economists saw the inflation report as indication of further cuts in the repo rate, the key tool for controlling money market liquidity, that started 1996 at 8.91 percent.</p>
<p>Tuesday's cut was widely expected by the markets, especially after figures last week showed a drop of 0.3 percent in November's consumer price index, indicating a negative annualized inflation trend for the second consecutive month.</p>
<p>&quot;The rate cut was expected and market reaction was calm,&quot; said Knut Hallberg, Swedbank analyst.</p>
<p>Economists forecast further cuts early in 1997 although the Riksbank said additional room for cuts was now limited.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the next lowering to be in January and that the Riksbank will then choose to lower the repo rate by 25 basis points again,&quot; said Handelsbanken economist Jan Haggstrom.</p>
<p>Richard Woodworth, European economist at Merrill Lynch, said he saw the repo bottoming at about 3.75 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;There's probably still room left, but given the assessment of the economy and the fact that the recovery should be gaining pace next year, we don't expect dramatic easing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In its inflation report, the Riksbank said the rate of inflation in 1996 was expected to be some tenths of a percentage point below its target's lower tolerance level.</p>
<p>The central bank's target has been for 2 percent with a one percentage point movement in either direction.</p>
<p>&quot;This largely stems from transitory effects of decreased interest costs and lower import prices,&quot; the bank said.</p>
<p>However, the bank warned if wage increases in 1997 and 1998 were as high as in 1996, when wages are expected to rise 6 to 7 percent, the rate of inflation could pass the target.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM, Sweden"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
