<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262088" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Sandoz, Ciba-Geigy cleared to become Novartis.</title>
<headline>Sandoz, Ciba-Geigy cleared to become Novartis.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States Federal Trade Commission on Tuesday agreed to the multi-billion dollar merger of Swiss drug giants Ciba-Geigy and Sandoz to become Novartis, if they meet certain conditions.</p>
<p>The FTC said in a statement that the two companies must license or divest several product areas -- gene therapy, corn herbicides and flea-control markets. The merger would create the world's second-largest pharmaceutical company after Britain's Glaxo-Wellcome.</p>
<p>Combined capitalisation of the two would be nearly $57 billion, with annual sales of nearly $20 billion in the core pharmaceutical, agricultural and nutrition businesses based on 1995 figures.</p>
<p>Analysts said Novartis would have a leading position in generic drugs, a broad range of healthcare products and clear dominance in crop protection products.</p>
<p>The FTC voted 5-0 to announce the proposed consent agreement, now open for 60 days of public comment. Typically, final approval occurs within two weeks after the close of public comment.</p>
<p>The FTC said Sandoz has agreed to license some gene therapy technology and patent rights to Rhone-Poulenc Rorer so that it can compete against the new combined firm.</p>
<p>Sandoz agreed to sell its United States and Canadian corn herbicide business to BASF for about $780 million, which the FTC called one of the largest divestitures it has ever required.</p>
<p>The Sandoz flea control business would be sold to Central Garden &amp; Pet Co. of Lafayette, Calif., or another FTC-approved buyer. The new producer of pet products would be permitted to produce its own methoprene, the active ingredient in the flea products.</p>
<p>Ciba-Geigy and Sandoz said the required conditions would leave the innovative potential of Novartis intact.</p>
<p>&quot;The required divestments and conditions will leave the innovative potential of Novartis intact,&quot; they said in a joint statement after the FTC announcement.</p>
<p>Shares in Novartis  NOVZn.S were to start trading on the Swiss Exchange on Dec. 23.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I25700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
