<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262342" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Bullying could start with poor parenting - study.</title>
<headline>Bullying could start with poor parenting - study.</headline>
<byline>Paul Majendie</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>School bullies may lash out in the playground because they are reacting to neglect and punishment at home, researchers said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>As many as one in three British children say they have fallen prey to bullies and Professor Rowan Myron-Wilson believes parents could hold the key to the soaring figures.</p>
<p>She and fellow psychologist Peter Smith from London's Goldsmith's College established the link after studying 72 school children aged between seven and 11.</p>
<p>&quot;Although bullying begins at school, the roots are in the family and the behaviour the children see there,&quot; Myron-Wilson said at the British Psychological Society conference where the findings were being presented.</p>
<p>&quot;Those who had a high bullying score were more likely to see their parents more negatively. They saw their parents as being more neglectful and punitive,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>The study is now being widened to take in another 200 children and this time psychologists will also elicit responses from the parents in a bid to get to the heart of the problem.</p>
<p>&quot;Perhaps more emphasis can be placed on incorporating parents into any programmes underway in the school,&quot; Myron-Wilson said.</p>
<p>Girls usually prefer mental torture while boy bullies are much more physical.</p>
<p>&quot;It tends to be girls who do the indirect bullying. They are much more socially manipulative at excluding them from the group,&quot; Myron-Wilson said.</p>
<p>Children can be naturally cruel as everyone from actor Mel Gibson to Prince Charles has discovered.</p>
<p>Gibson, mocked at his Australian school for having an American accent, used to fend off bullies by making jokes. Playing the school jester helped develop his acting talents.</p>
<p>Heir-to-the-throne Charles confessed to being miserable at Gordonstoun school where boys would pick on him and then boast: &quot;We punched the future king of England.&quot;</p>
<p>Myron-Wilson said: &quot;I think some experience of falling out within friendship groups is an inevitable part of childhood. Your friends have the power to hurt you. But bullying is more malicious and should not be an inevitable part of childhood.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
