<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262404" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>MOROCCO: Morocco drafts law on telecom privatisation.</title>
<headline>Morocco drafts law on telecom privatisation.</headline>
<dateline>RABAT 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Moroccan parliamentary ccommission has started debating a draft law aimed at partly privatising the telecommunications network to attract foreign investors, a parliamentary spokesman said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;A parliamentary finance commission presided by Prime Minister Abdellatif Filali is examining, for the second day, the draft law related the to privatisation of Morocco's telecommunications network,&quot; the spokesman said.</p>
<p>The government plans to split the telecommunications and postal services (ONPT) into two enterprises, respectively called Ittissalat al-Maghrib and Barid al-Maghrib, an official at the privatisation ministry said.</p>
<p>&quot;With the globalisation of the economy, the government is adapting the country's legislation to technological progress and competition...Therefore it will open its telecommunications network including the GSM mobile telephone network to private investors,&quot; the official said.</p>
<p>Morocco has in recent years extended the GSM network to remote areas in a move aimed at doubling the number of GSM subscribers from the existing 30,000.</p>
<p>Daewoo of South Korea,  AT&amp;T of the U.S. and Alcatel of France have shown interest in the privatisation of the GSM system, the finance ministry has said.</p>
<p>&quot;The draft law which was presented to the commission is vague and has no clear vision for the future development of the telephone network after privatisation,&quot; said a deputy of the old-guard opposition Istiqlal party who is a member of the commission.</p>
<p>&quot;The draft does not say clearly whether the future private investors would modernise this strategic sector and provide consumers with more lines and better services,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Morocco, with a population of 27 million people, has only four telephone lines per 100 people.</p>
<p>Earlier this year, the ONPT said it would invest $1.5 billion over the next five years to expand and improve the telephone network.</p>
<p>According to the parliamentary spokesman the draft law could be adopted in January if the commission members could overcome their differences over the project.</p>
<p>- Rabat newsroom +212-7 726518</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MOROC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RABAT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MOROCCO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
