<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262537" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: AFL-CIO chief reaches out to moderate Republicans.</title>
<headline>AFL-CIO chief reaches out to moderate Republicans.</headline>
<byline>Peter Szekely</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>After doing his best to snuff some of their political careers, AFL-CIO President John Sweeney reached out to moderate Republicans Monday, saying he wanted to discuss his legislative goals with them.</p>
<p>&quot;We are going to be striving for a renewed relationship between moderate Republicans and workers,&quot; Sweeney told a news conference. &quot;I really am confident that we are going to have relationships with moderate Republicans.&quot;</p>
<p>The 78-union federation spent $35 million this year in an unsuccessful effort to oust the Republican majority of the House of Representatives.</p>
<p>Of the total, $25 million went for an advertising campaign that slammed the voting records of Republican lawmakers, including some moderates who voted with labor on some issues.</p>
<p>Sweeney, who has sought to reinvigorate the labor federation since his election 13 months ago, said moderate Republicans had become more conservative in the last session of Congress until many of them joined Democrats last summer in the passage of an increase in the federal minimum wage.</p>
<p>The AFL-CIO's media blitz included television commercials in certain congressional districts that criticized locally elected lawmakers for opposing the minimum wage hike.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that the message that we delivered during the campaign about the agenda of America's working families sends a clear message for moderate Republicans as well as Democrats,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The union effort failed to erase the Republican majority in the House, but succeeded in trimming it to a 20-vote margin over Democrats of 227-207 in next year's session from 235-197. There is one Independent in the 435-member House and there are currently two vacancies.</p>
<p>Sweeney, who had met earlier with the AFL-CIO's policy-setting Executive Council, said the federation would not decide on its legislative priorities for next year until its annual winter meeting in February.</p>
<p>Republican leaders of the House Economic and Educational Opportunities Committee have said that they intend to reintroduce several bills that labor opposes next year.</p>
<p>They include measures that would relax a requirement for time-and-a-half pay for working more than 40 hours a week, ease the federal ban on so-called company unions and beef up the requirement on unions to tell members that they can withhold the part of their dues that is used for political purposes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
