<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262598" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK study finds smell of chocolate relaxes people.</title>
<headline>UK study finds smell of chocolate relaxes people.</headline>
<byline>Maggie Fox</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The smell of chocolate sends brainwaves &quot;wild&quot; and both distracts and relaxes people at the same time, experts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>No other smell tested on volunteers had such a strong effect, Neil Martin, a neuropsychologist at London's Middlesex University, said.</p>
<p>&quot;Chocolate was quite a star performer in this experiment,&quot; Martin said. &quot;It seemed to make the brain go quite, scientifically, wild.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;We found that they found it soothing and they found it pleasing and they found it very relaxing.&quot;</p>
<p>About 20 volunteers were asked to sniff artificial odours including chocolate, spearmint, almond, strawberry and garlic. In a second experiment they smelled real odours, including chocolate again, baked beans, coffee and rotting pork.</p>
<p>They sat in specially designed smell-proof rooms, wore clouded goggles and had earplugs so they had to concentrate on the smells being presented to them, Martin told the annual meeting of the British Psychological Society.</p>
<p>Volunteers were not told what smells they were going to get.</p>
<p>While they sniffed, Martin's group measured their brain activity. Chocolate depressed brainwaves known as theta waves, which are associated with attention, Martin said.</p>
<p>&quot;This seems to be the one involved with attention. The more complex a task you do the more of this brainwave there is,&quot; he said in a telephone interview ahead of the conference.</p>
<p>Martin said it was not clear why chocolate alone should have such an effect.</p>
<p>&quot;One reason is you are thinking about chocolate, maybe baking cakes or sweets, and because of that you don't pay much attention to your environment and it relaxes you,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Or perhaps somehow the emotional centre of the brain is being activated -- but this would not explain why other pleasant odours did not have the same effect.</p>
<p>&quot;The two odours you think might have been alerting -- coffee and rotting meat -- had no effect at all,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Chocolate also increased alpha and beta brainwave activity, which Martin could not explain.</p>
<p>&quot;Alpha is most commonly seen in a relaxed but waking adult, while beta is seen when people are doing something like mental arithmetic,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GHEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GODD">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSCI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
