<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262675" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: Canadian avalanche kills three German skiiers.</title>
<headline>Canadian avalanche kills three German skiiers.</headline>
<dateline>VANCOUVER 1996-12-16</dateline>
<text>
<p>Three German skiiers died in an avalanche on Monday in the mountain wilderness near the Canadian resort of Whistler, British Columbia, officials said.</p>
<p>Royal Canadian Mounted Police spokesman Peter Montague said three Germans -- two men and one woman -- were known to have died in the accident.</p>
<p>They were in a group of 11 European tourists who were heli-skiing on the Phalanx Glacier in Garibaldi Provincial Park just outside the bounds of the Blackcomb Mountain ski area in the Coast Mountain range.</p>
<p>&quot;We can confirm three dead. They were from Germany,&quot; Montague said. The other members of the group have been located and a search has been called off, he said. Another member of the group was injured but not seriously, he said.</p>
<p>The police will not release the names of the victims until their families are notified.</p>
<p>Jason Roe, manager of Tyax Heli-Skiing, said his company was involved in the incident but had few details of what happened. The group was skiing with a local guide when the avalanche struck at 2:45 p.m. PST/5:45 p.m. EST (2245 GMT), he said. The deaths were the first in the company's 10-year history.</p>
<p>In heli-skiing, skiers are taken by helicopter to remote areas unreachable by lifts. They ski down the mountain, usually with a guide. Conditions can be treacherous in the back country where, unlike on developed ski runs, no avalanche control measures are taken. Skiiers usually carry locating devices which emit a signal to help rescuers in an emergency.</p>
<p>The weather in Whistler was clear with a light wind on Monday with temperatures around 16 degrees Fahrenheit (minus 9 Celsius) in the late afternoon, Whistler resort said.</p>
<p>The town of Whistler, about 75 miles (120 km) north of Vancouver, has consistently been rated one of the top ski resorts in North America and attracts many visitors from Europe, the United States and Asia.</p>
<p>Montague said the avalanche was rated Class Two, which is considered &quot;major&quot; and heavy enough to bury people. Alan Dennis, manager of the Canadian Avalanche Centre in Revelstoke, British Columbia, said avalanches are rated on a scale of one to five with five being the most serious.</p>
<p>The centre had rated the danger of an avalanche in the Whistler area as moderate on Monday. Dennis said this meant that a natural avalanche was unlikely but a human-triggered avalanche possible. &quot;That could mean the weight of the skiiers set it off,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In an avalanche, a torrent of snow and debris can bury a person within seconds. Injury or death can result from suffocation or a blow to the body. Avalanches commonly occur where fresh or loose snow sits on top of frozen, packed snow.</p>
<p>An average of seven people are killed each year in Canada by avalanches, most of whom are heli-skiers, Canadian Press said.</p>
<p>The previous worst avalanches each killed seven heli-skiers.</p>
<p>Seven people on a tour operated by Mike Wiegle Helicopter Skiing were swept to their deaths the Monashee Mountains near Blue River in British Columbia in 1987. Seven skiers also died in an avalanche near Golden, British Columbia 300 miles (500 km) northeast of Vancouver in 1979, Canadian Press said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-16"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VANCOUVER"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
