<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262722" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>CHINA: China stock crackdown said spurred by politics.</title>
<headline>China stock crackdown said spurred by politics.</headline>
<byline>Graham Earnshaw</byline>
<dateline>SHANGHAI 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>China's crackdown on stock markets this week is partly fuelled by fears in Beijing that the volatility of the exchanges could lead to social instability, analysts said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>They said the move was also aimed at avoiding disruption caused by foreign and domestic speculators planning to pump money into the markets up to the mid-1997 handover of Hong Kong from London to Beijing and then pull it out again.</p>
<p>&quot;In a transitional period when the ailing leader Deng Xiaoping is gradually moving out of polical arena, social stability is the primary concern of the leadership,&quot; said one executive with a Chinese brokerage.</p>
<p>&quot;Stock boom and bust cycles do not fit in with the aim of social stability,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>A Shenzhen-based broker said there had been many rumours that the surges on the Shenzhen market were supported by overseas funds from Hong Kong and Macau.</p>
<p>&quot;Some rumours said that foreign funds wanted to push up the Chinese markets before the (Hong Kong) takeover and depress them afterwards,&quot; the broker said.</p>
<p>The People's Daily newspaper, mouthpiece of the Communist Party, said in a harshly-worded commentary on Monday that China's stock markets had overheated on widespread speculation. It warned that if the markets crashed, the government would not step in to support them.</p>
<p>In anticipation of the response to the commentary, the stock exchanges last Friday evening introduced a 10 percent limit on movements of prices for individual shares.</p>
<p>On Monday and again on Tuesday, most shares on both the Shanghai and Shenzhen stock exchanges plunged to the 10 percent limit-down level.</p>
<p>Shanghai's domestic A share index lost 100.964 points or 9.64 percent to 946.716 points after falling 9.92 percent on Monday. The B share index shed 1.431 points or 2.39 percent to 58.498 points.</p>
<p>In Shenzhen, the A index plummeted 9.99 percent to 375.51 points while the B index dived 9.51 percent, to 121.64 points.</p>
<p>Most shares hit the daily limit-down of 10 percent shortly after the opening, as on Monday, and stayed there for the whole session, brokers said.</p>
<p>Since April, both domestic and foreign currency share prices on the two markets have surged on average by well over 100 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;The central government has chosen the right time,&quot; said one political analyst. &quot;There are still a few months to go before the Hong Kong takeover and stock prices had not surged so far that falls would push investors out on to the streets (to demonstrate).&quot;</p>
<p>Some stock traders said that by talking down the markets, Beijing had effectively prevented heavy fresh liquidity flowing in.</p>
<p>&quot;The inflow of hot money (speculative funds) has been cut off with retail investors frightened away and institutions taking heed of the warning,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;It seems now that the markets will be stable around the date of the Hong Kong takeover,&quot; he added. &quot;Prices are expected to move little after the impact of the crackdown is gradually digested.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SHANGHAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CHINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
