<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262702" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Australia enterprise wage deals plateaued - RBA.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Australia enterprise wage deals plateaued - RBA.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The pace of Australian wages growth in enterprise bargaining agreements appears to have plateaued, and seems likely to remain consistent with the Reserve Bank of Australia's inflation objective, the RBA said.</p>
<p>However, the RBA also said in an article in its December Bulletin entitled &quot;Measuring Wages&quot;, the Australian Council of Trade Union's (ACTU) full 'Living Wage' claim &quot;would imply a marked acceleration of wages growth.&quot;</p>
<p>The RBA estimated the claim would add 1.6 percentage points to current growth in the average weekly ordinary time earnings (AWOTE) series.  </p>
<p>The bank said that adjusting the Department of Industrial Relations figures on enterprise agreements for recent bank wage increases, &quot;the pace of wages growth seems to have plateaued.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Given this, whilever those workers on the awards stream are receiving the sorts of modest increases of recent years, the aggregate outcome seems likely to remain consistent with the two to three percent (underlying) inflation objective,&quot; it said.</p>
<p>The difference between wages under awards and enterprise bargains may be normal as the labour market becomes more market orientated, and to the extent that wage flexibility rewards skill it should help employment growth, the RBA said.  </p>
<p>However, whether this greater dispersion of wages was sustained, depended on a number of factors, one of which was the ACTU's 'Living Wage' claim.</p>
<p>The RBA said it estimated &quot;the direct effect of the Living Wage claim would be to increase the economy-wide wages bill by close to two percentage points.&quot;</p>
<p>As the group covered by the claim accounted for around 0.4 percentage points of the annual AWOTE increase, the RBA said this would add a net 1.6 percentage points overall, taking aggreagate wage growth to over five percent.  </p>
<p>&quot;Furthermore, flow-on effects to the wages obtained in other streams of bargaining would mean that the full effect of the Living Wage claim would be considerably higher than the above estimates,&quot; the RBA said.</p>
<p>The RBA said its estimates were &quot;necessarily imprecise&quot;, and based them on the assumptions that workers on award wages made up around one-fifth of the nation's wages bill, and Stage 1 of the ACTU's claim would see these workers' wages rise by 8.75 percent. There would also be some effect on the wages of those who receive small over-award payments.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
