<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262792" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai central bank defends baht fixing policy.</title>
<headline>Thai central bank defends baht fixing policy.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Thai central bank official on Tuesday defended the policy by which the baht is fixed daily against a basket of currencies, heavily weighted in the U.S. dollar.</p>
<p>&quot;We stick by the integrity of the basket of currencies against which the baht is fixed. We will do whatever is neessary to defend the role of this system,&quot; an official in the Bank of Thailand's banking department told Reuters.</p>
<p>He made the comments when asked about reports by forex dealers of a speculative attack on the Thai currency by offshore investors early on Tuesday and that the central bank had spent up to $500 million to defend the currency.  </p>
<p>&quot;I cannot comment about interventions,&quot; the official said when asked about the reported central bank defence of the baht in the Singapore market.</p>
<p>The baht fell sharply earlier in the day after the offshore speculative attack which came on the back of year-end demand for rising dollars by companies preparing to close their books, dealers said.</p>
<p>Statements by the Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan that the baht was undervalued, contrary to some views that it was overvalued, also helped shore up the currency.</p>
<p>At 0839 GMT, the baht stabilised at 25.595-25.600 to the dollar, after sliding to a day's low of 25.612.</p>
<p>Amnuay said any change in policy to make the system of baht-fixing more flexible or to change it would be considered later, only when it was necessary.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
