<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262707" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-ABARE sees Australia wheat crop at 21.3 mln/t.</title>
<headline>RTRS-ABARE sees Australia wheat crop at 21.3 mln/t.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Australian Bureau of Agricultural and Resource Economics (ABARE), said on Tuesday it was maintaining its forecast for the Australian wheat crop at 21.3 million tonnes for 1996/97 to June 30.</p>
<p>The forecast by the government's official commodities forecaster is below the 21.8 million tonnes expected by private forecaster Wheat Forecasters Pty Ltd and the 21.5 million forecast by the Australian Wheat Board (AWB).</p>
<p>Good rains and mild conditions through the late winter and early spring meant that yields would be above average across most of Australia, ABARE said in its December outlook.  </p>
<p>However, there have been isolated crop problems, it said.</p>
<p>Rain and strong winds disrupted harvests in central and western Queensland, resulting in downgrading and the loss of some crops, ABARE said. Also, frosts in Queensland and the Mallee regions of Victoria and South Australia in September caused severe but isolated reductions in yield in some areas.</p>
<p>Upward revisions of both northern and southern hemisphere harvests, which have pushed world wheat prices lower, combined with a big Australian crop, meant that the likelihood that the Australian crop would need to be sold on lower priced markets over a longer period had increased, ABARE said.  </p>
<p>Also, with some buyers possibly holding back on some forward purchases while prices were declining, opportunities for forward sales of Australian wheat will have been constrained, it said.</p>
<p>As a result, the current forecast average pool return of Australian Standard White (ASW) wheat in 1996/97 of around A$185.00 a tonne may need to be revised as marketing of the new crop proceeds, ABARE said.</p>
<p>ABARE sees Australian wheat exports at 13.340 million tonnes in 1996/97 versus 12.057 in 1995/96.  </p>
<p>The figure only partially takes into account a planned one million tonne sale of Australian wheat to India for Jan/Feb delivery announced last week, an ABARE analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;It will lift the forecast, but not by a million tonnes,&quot; the analyst told Reuters.</p>
<p>On a global scale, wheat production is forecast to rise in most major wheat exporting countries in 1996/97, ABARE said.</p>
<p>With exportable surpluses rising and imports forecast to fall to the lowest in a decade to around 90 million tonnes, price will be well down on last year, it said.  </p>
<p>The world indiator price of wheat (July/June) is forecast to average in the range of US$163.00-to US$205.00 a tonne, with a most likley outcome of around US$180.00 a tonne, some 14 percent below the 1995/96 average, ABARE said.</p>
<p>World wheat production is forecast to rise by 7.8 percent to 579 million tonnes in 1996/97, the second highest on record, ABARE said. Record or near-record yields are expected to occur in Australia, the European Union and Argentina, it said.  </p>
<p>The Argentine wheat crop is estimated to be 14.5 million tonnes in 1996/97, 58 percent higher than in 1995/96, ABARE said. &quot;As Argentina does not have the infrastructure to to store such a large crop, Argentine traders are attempting to ship wheat as soon after harvest as possible,&quot; ABARE said.</p>
<p>To achieve this, Argentine wheat has been sold at discounted prices, it said. &quot;Even though Argentina is the smallest of the major exporters, the heavy discounting has contributed to rapidly falling world prices,&quot; ABARE said.  </p>
<p>Improved seasons have also been experienced in importing countries, particularly China, Russia, Morocco, South Africa and Turkey, ABARE said. Chinese imports in 1996/97 are forecast to be five million tonnes lower than in 1995/96, it said.</p>
<p>The lower imports in some countries are expected to be partially offset by increased imports by eastern European countries, such as South Korea and Algeria, ABARE said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
