<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262770" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Arianespace to launch 70 satellites in next 4 years.</title>
<headline>Arianespace to launch 70 satellites in next 4 years.</headline>
<byline>Josephine Ng</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>European satellite launch company Arianespace will launch 70 satellites over the next four years, chairman and chief executive officer Charles Bigot said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Arianespace has decided to further increase its launch capabilities by 50 percent -- 70 satellites will be launched within the next four years,&quot; he told a news conference at the opening of a regional office in Singapore.</p>
<p>He said the increase was to meet growing demand for telecommunication satellites. He said 50 to 60 satellites were expected to be launched over the next eight years for the Asia-Pacific region alone.</p>
<p>Arianespace had orders to launch 42 satellites over the next 2-1/2 years, 10 of them for Asia-Pacific customers, Bigot said.</p>
<p>&quot;In 1997, we hope to launch 18 to 20 satellites,&quot; of which six will be for Asia-Pacific customers, he added.</p>
<p>Arianespace is the leader in the heavy satellite launch market and company officials said it aimed to maintain its 60 percent global market share.</p>
<p>Between 1998 and 2000, Arianespace would use a combination of its existing Ariane 4 rocket and its new Ariane 5 to launch satellites, Bigot said.</p>
<p>Ariane 5, expected to be qualified for commercial use from 1998 after two test flights in 1997, would launch 32 to 34 satellites in 1998-2000.</p>
<p>The rocket, developed at an estimated cost of US$5 billion, was designed to carry two three-tonne satellites at one time and had a reliability rate of 98.5 percent, Bigot said.</p>
<p>Ariane 4's reliability rate was 96 percent, he said.</p>
<p>He said that over the longer term, Arianespace would raise its capacity further and adapt Ariane 5 for changing market conditions.</p>
<p>&quot;First, the satellites to be placed into GTO (geostationary transfer orbit) will become heavier and larger starting from 3000 to 3,500 kg...approaching five or six tonnes,&quot; Bigot said.</p>
<p>This was due to strong demand in mobile communications and direct to home television broadcasting needs.</p>
<p>There was also increasing demand for small and medium-sized satellites at lower orbits of 1,000 to 10,000 km.</p>
<p>Bigot said the company was considering using other launchers as Ariane 5 might not be suitable for all new missions.</p>
<p>A first step in this direction was its partnership with Russian Space Agency (RKA) and Samara Space Centre from Russia and Aerospatiale to form Starsem.</p>
<p>Starsem would operate the Soyuz family of low and medium orbit launchers.</p>
<p>Bigot said Starsem had won a contract to launch 12 satellites as part of the Globalstar satellite telecommunications network formed by 56 satellites.</p>
<p>Globalstar is owned by U.S. company Space Systems Loral, part of Loral Space &amp; Communications Ltd.</p>
<p>Starsem would launch the 12 satellites in 1998, Bigot said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
