<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262729" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan envoy in new mystery mission overseas.</title>
<headline>Taiwan envoy in new mystery mission overseas.</headline>
<byline>Alice Hung</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan's foreign minister dropped from sight on Tuesday to embark on what local media said was yet another overseas mission cloaked in secrecy to evade rival China's tightening diplomatic embargo.</p>
<p>The Foreign Ministry, adopting the tight-lipped policy seen during previous secret sojourns by Taiwan leaders, said minister John Chang had left the country for &quot;official business&quot; but would not comment on a report he may have gone to west Asia.</p>
<p>&quot;Minister Chang left for official business. He'll be back in a few days,&quot; Vice-Minister Cheng Chien-jen told reporters. &quot;Because of other considerations, we can't provide other details before (his return).&quot;</p>
<p>It would be inconvenient to name Chang's hosts, he said.</p>
<p>State television said Chang's plane was bound for Rome but that he stopped in Abu Dhabi, a member of the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>It was not clear if Abu Dhabi was Chang's destination or a waystation, as a visit to neighbouring Jordan also was possible, the television said. President Lee Teng-hui visited the United Arab Emirates and Jordan in 1995.</p>
<p>The Liberty Times, quoting unidentified sources, said Chang left Taiwan late on Monday for a three-to-four-day visit to some foreign nations that have no diplomatic ties with the island but which nonetheless maintain &quot;secret and close&quot; links.</p>
<p>He was bound for west Asia and perhaps Europe, it said.</p>
<p>Other media said the possible stops on Chang's mysterious tour included Israel, Russia and Ukraine.</p>
<p>Chang and Vice-President Lien Chan have followed a similar pattern for numerous overseas trips in the past year, simply dropping from sight for days at a time as international and Taiwan media scurried to track them down.</p>
<p>Lien managed such a secret visit to Ukraine in August, triggering a minor row between Kiev and a furious Beijing.</p>
<p>Similarly, Chang dropped from sight after his December visit to South Africa, where had sought in vain to reverse Pretoria's November 27 decision to switch diplomatic recognition to Beijing from Taipei by the end of 1997.</p>
<p>Chang surfaced in Belgium on December 7 but failed to win access to Belgian leaders or other European or African officials there as Beijing diplomats mounted what Taiwanese officials and media said was a concerted drive to prevent such encounters.</p>
<p>Communist China, Taiwan's arch rival since a civil war split them in 1949, regards the island as a rebel province ineligible for sovereign ties. It has tightened a diplomatic squeeze on Taipei in its quest to bring Taiwan under mainland rule.</p>
<p>Chang nonetheless said on Monday he would visit diplomatic ally Guatemala for the December 29 signing of a peace pact between its government and leftist rebels.</p>
<p>The trip is one of four damage-control missions planned by top Taiwan officials since South Africa, Taipei's largest ally, declared it was switching ties.</p>
<p>Beijing refuses to recognise any country that recognises Taiwan's exiled Republic of China government, but has stepped up efforts to win over the 30 states that still do.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
