<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262851" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: Thai finmin sets moderate economic targets. [CORRECTED 07:43 GMT]</title>
<headline>Thai finmin sets moderate economic targets. [CORRECTED 07:43 GMT]</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Thai Finance Minister Amnuay Viravan on Tuesday unveiled moderate economic targets for the next few years, saying he would pursue balanced economic growth and stability.</p>
<p>Amnuay said in a prepared policy statement obtained by Reuters that he targeted gross domestic product (GDP) growth of 7.0-7.5 (corrects from 7.0-7.25) percent for the next two to three years. He also set the targeted 1997 inflation rate at 5.0 percent.  </p>
<p>Amnuay was due to make his keynote policy speech at the finance ministry later this afternoon.</p>
<p>The new finance minister and deputy premier said he would adopt more fiscal measures than the previous government in stabilisin the economy which slowed this year and is set to sustain zero-growth for exports.</p>
<p>He said, however, that Thailand's practice in the past several years of adopting deficit-free, balanced national budgets would be maintained.  </p>
<p>Amnuay also said in the statement that he had targeted Thai exports to grow by between 7-10 percent in 1997 after zero-growth expected for 1996.</p>
<p>He put the target for the 1997 Thai current account deficit at 7.5-7.9 percent of GDP versus 8.2 percent in 1995.</p>
<p>Thailand may exceed his moderate near-term targets if economic recovery in major industrial countries was conducive to world growth, he added.</p>
<p>He said in his policy outline that the government would take measures to help an ailing Thai property sector by easing central bank restrictions on foreign borrowings by condominium and residential project developers.</p>
<p>Amnuay told reporters before his scheduled press conference that the Thai economic slowdown should bottom out this year and he expected key indicators, including investment and industrial outputs, to show improvement from 1997.</p>
<p>He described his 7-10 percent export growth target for 1997 as realistic, saying that both the Bank of Thailand and the Thai commerce ministry agreed it was achievable.  </p>
<p>The minister said the government would help boost domestic housing demand and assist property developers facing financing problems.</p>
<p>On government efforts to rehabilitate the ailing Bangkok Bank of Commerce Plc, Amnuay said in his policy outline that he would speed up measures to revive the bank without hurting or weakening the overall banking sector.</p>
<p>-- Bangkok newsroom (662)-2529950-3</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
