<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262866" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: Indonesian oil contracts down in 1996 - minister.</title>
<headline>Indonesian oil contracts down in 1996 - minister.</headline>
<dateline>JAKARTA 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Indonesia said on Tuesday the number of exploration contracts signed by state oil company Pertamina had fallen to 15 in 1996 from 20 the previous year.</p>
<p>But despite the fall, Mines and Energy Minister Ida Bagus Sudjana stressed that the country was still attractive to foreign companies investing in the oil and gas sectors.</p>
<p>&quot;The total number of oil contracts that have been signed in 1996 is lower than the 20 contracts in 1995. However, the interest in exploration in Indonesia from foreign and local investors is still high,&quot; Sudjana said. &quot;I am optimistic the investment climate in our country is still attractive.&quot;</p>
<p>Sudjana was speaking after the signing of two production sharing contracts and four technical assistance contracts, including one production sharing deal between Pertamina and Santa Fe Energy Resources Inc of the United States.</p>
<p>Sudjana said Pertamina had signed nine production sharing and and six technical assistance contracts in 1996, compared with 10 of each in 1995.</p>
<p>Pertamina exploration director Prijambodo Muljosudirdjo said the company was processing around 15 oil contracts, including both kinds, but they would not be signed this year.  </p>
<p>&quot;The negotiations on seven contracts are complete but we will not sign the contracts until next year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The contract with Santa Fe covers a 8,595-sq-km area both onshore and offshore near Pagatan in South Kalimantan. Santa Fe will invest $25.7 million over 10 years to explore the area, he said.</p>
<p>In another contract signed on Tuesday, locally-owned PT Risjad Salim Resources Asahan will explore a 4,200-sq-km offshore area in the Asahan Block in North Sumatra. It will invest more than $73.6 million in exploration over 10 years, he said.</p>
<p>Pertamina also signed four technical assistance contracts with local and joint-venture companies.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JAKARTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
