<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262841" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Handover already factored into HK market - Merrill.</title>
<headline>Handover already factored into HK market - Merrill.</headline>
<byline>John O'Callaghan</byline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The handover of Hong Kong to China next June will not cause headaches for investors as political risk has been a constant in the territory's investment equation, Merrill Lynch said on Tuesday.</p>
<p>The transfer of the British colony to China had moved down a &quot;reasonably bumpy road&quot;, but the outcome had already been taken into account by the market, Merrill political analyst Richard Margolis said at a presentation on the firm's regional outlook.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a constancy about our political risk and vulnerability,&quot; he said. &quot;Politics, in a sense, is irrelevant.&quot;</p>
<p>Margolis said there was nothing in the handover or the transfer of leadership to change Merrill's predictions, which see the economy growing 5.2 percent in 1997, corporate core earnings recovering and the stock market rising.</p>
<p>&quot;Merrill Lynch is pretty optimistic for the Hong Kong market in 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The worst-case scenario was that Chinese leaders would withdraw their support for the large measure of autonomy the territory has been promised after the handover, but Margolis said a change in the territory's &quot;separate status&quot; was unlikely.  </p>
<p>The former British diplomat said Sino-British relations in the run up to the handover have been characterised by &quot;problems, a degree of mistrust, delays in resolving issues&quot;.</p>
<p>But political factors had relatively little effect on the market other than causing short-term interruptions, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The Hong Kong market is a lot less political than it is given credit for,&quot; he said. &quot;This is part of the backdrop and you just have to learn to live with it.&quot;</p>
<p>Two of the biggest questions facing Hong Kong in the seven months before the transfer were the formation of the China-appointed provisional legislature and the debate over an anti-subversion bill proposed by the colonial government.</p>
<p>Beijing plans to replace Hong Kong's elected legislature with a 60-member appointed council to be picked on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;The provisional legislature is part of the transition and not the end of the road,&quot; Margolis said, but added it was important to watch the preparations for elections promised by Beijing for 1998.</p>
<p>Margolis said he saw the subversion law as the last major point of disagreement between London and Beijing, adding that parameters for the law were already set by international covenants on political and human rights.  </p>
<p>The subversion bill, which defines sedition, treason and subversion, sets legal markers against China-style jailings of dissidents after the handover.</p>
<p>But Beijing slammed the bill as an unacceptable intrusion into the future administration's affairs, raising concern that the law, if passed, would be scrapped after July 1.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
