<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="262996" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWEDEN: Swedish Riksbank cuts repo rate to 4.10 pct.</title>
<headline>Swedish Riksbank cuts repo rate to 4.10 pct.</headline>
<dateline>STOCKHOLM 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Sweden's central bank, the Riksbank, on Tuesday cut its key interest rate, the repo rate, by 25 basis points to 4.10 percent as widely expected in the market.</p>
<p>As announced by the bank, the reverse repurchase operation will run for three weeks from December 18 to January 8 to cover the holiday period.</p>
<p>It was released at the same time as the Riksbank's last inflation report for the year which painted a bullish picture for the next two years.</p>
<p>This was the 25th cut this year to the repo, which is the Riksbank's main tool for controlling money market liquidity.</p>
<p>The repo rate, the central rate in a three tier system, started the year at 8.91 percent but the central bank has pursued an aggressive monetary policy.  </p>
<p>The cut was expected by the financial markets, especially after a fall of 0.3 percent in consumer price figures released last week showed Sweden was in a negative annualised inflation trend for the second consecutive month.</p>
<p>In a Reuters poll, all 14 economists questioned expected a repo cut. Nine forecast a lowering of 25 basis points, two a cut of 20 basis points and one a 35 basis points drop. The others forecast ranges between 15 to 35 basis points.</p>
<p>This is the third time the Riksbank had lowered the repo rate by 25 basis points.</p>
<p>The last move was on November 26.</p>
<p>The Riksbank last lowered its two other key rates, the deposit and lending rates, on December 5 when the bank trimmed both by 50 basis points to 3.75 percent and 5.25 percent respectively.</p>
<p>-- Belinda Goldsmith, Stockholm newsroom +46-8-700 1017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SWED">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="STOCKHOLM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWEDEN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
