<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263055" id="root" date="1996-12-17" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks close down on lower turnover.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks close down on lower turnover.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks closed down on Tuesday, with the upcoming U.S. central bank policy meeting on interest rates providing the reason to take some gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>&quot;The FOMC (Federal Open Market Committee) meeting is just an excuse to take profit,&quot; said Peter Lai, associate director at OCBC Securities. &quot;U.S. inflation is under control and we won't see a rise in rates.&quot;</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index closed down 122.11 points at 12,815.37, after bouncing off a low of 12,747.91. Turnover declined but remained healthy at HK$5.71 billion, down from Monday's HK$6.54 billion</p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve's policy setting FOMC will meet later on Tuesday but is expected to leave rates unchanged.</p>
<p>Hongkong Bank said it saw U.S. rates rising just 25 basis points by the end of next year, a view on which it bvased its forecast that Hong Kong's economic growth w3ould rebound to 5.2 percent in 1997 from an estimated 4.6 percent this year.</p>
<p>Brokers said as the market's turnover declined, prices were more vulnerable to single large orders and large players.</p>
<p>&quot;There are not a lot of natural buyers around at this time of year,&quot; said one broker with a large U.S. house. &quot;And there aren't any shorts either.&quot;</p>
<p>The market's near-term direction was likely to be dictated by Wall Street, he added.</p>
<p>Properties came in for selling in the morning, but utilities were the worst performing over the day.</p>
<p>HongKong Telecom slipped HK$0.30 to HK$12.90. China Light lost HK$0.50 to HK$33.50, while Hongkong Electric added HK$0.05 to HK$25.75.</p>
<p>In the property sector, Sun Hung Kai tumbled HK$2.00 to close at HK$91.00 on heavy turnover of HK$357.74 million.</p>
<p>Cheung Kong closed HK$1.25 lower at HK$64.50</p>
<p>Brokers said the odd transactions at Tuesday's open that saw Cheung Kong trade at HK$56.25 were probably human error, with a trader keying in the share price of Cheung Kong associate Hutchison, which ended the day at HK$56.25.</p>
<p>The stock exchange said it is investigating the &quot;suspected erroneous&quot; transactions amd changed Cheung Kong's day low to HK$60.00</p>
<p>Most heavily traded HSBC Holdings lost HK$1.50 to HK$155.00.</p>
<p>The China Enterprise Index managed to hold onto good gains following a loss on Monday, rising 0.72 percent to 896.79. Qingling Motors led the sector with a gain of HK$0.20 to HK$3.825.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-17"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
