<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263111" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: America Service Group, Wexford to merge.</title>
<headline>America Service Group, Wexford to merge.</headline>
<dateline>NEW CASTLE, Del. 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>America Service Group Inc and Wexford Health Services, a privately held correctional health care provider based in Pittsburgh, PA, said they have signed a letter of intent to merge Wexford with units of America Service Group.</p>
<p>Under the terms of the deal, Wexford shareholders will receive 1,500,000 shares of ASGR common stock, representing almost 30% of the proforma ownership of the combined company.</p>
<p>The transaction is planned as a pooling of interest, and completion of the merger is anticipated in the first quarter of 1997.  The merger is subject to the execution of a definitive agreement, ASG shareholder approval, and various regulatory approvals.  </p>
<p>Upon completion of the merger, the combined company, which will operate under the name of Wexford Health Sources, will provide healthcare services to more than 120,000 inmates in twenty-two states.</p>
<p>Officers of the combined company will include:</p>
<p>-- James Roddey, current chief executive of Wexford, will serve as chairman of America Service Group.</p>
<p>-- William Eberle, current chairman of America Service Group, will serve as chairman of the executive committee.</p>
<p>-- Scott L. Mercy, will remain as chief executive of America Service Group.</p>
<p>-- Jeffrey Bairstow, newly appointed chief operating officer of America Service Group, will continue to serve in that capacity.</p>
<p>Corporate services will continue in both Nashville, Tennessee, and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I95100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW CASTLE, Del."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
