<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263213" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Celeritek warns about future results.</title>
<headline>Celeritek warns about future results.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA CLARA, Calif. 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Celeritek Wednesday said several factors will affect the company's  financial performance through the first quarter of 1998.</p>
<p>In a statement, the company said the factors include later than expected placement of several key orders, a slower than anticipated ramp up in certain of our manufacturing areas and a gradual shift in product mix as demand for semiconductor products increases.  </p>
<p>To address these factors and to capitalize on opportunities in the semiconductor area, the company said it will be making significant investment in its Gallium Arsenide operations. The company did not offer specific forecasts for the future.</p>
<p>The company, a manufacturer of products for the wireless communications market, also said it reached an agreement with a major Very Small Aperture Terminal network provider to produce VSAT transmitters. The agreement is currently expected to result in $5 million of shipments beginning in mid-1997.</p>
<p>Celeritek announced a development contract for this product in October. Celeritek also announced it has received an $8 million order from P-COM Inc to produce 38 GHz outdoor units for use in P-COM's high density, high volume, point-to-point data transmission radio systems. The company said the order represents an expansion of a manufacturing contract Celeritek received in April.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34531">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA CLARA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
