<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263384" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>NETHERLANDS: SOCCER-FEYENOORD NARROW GAP AT TOP WITH 10 MEN.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-FEYENOORD NARROW GAP AT TOP WITH 10 MEN.</headline>
<dateline>AMSTERDAM 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ten-man Feyenoord narrowed the gap with PSV Eindhoven at the top of the Dutch first division to three points after beating Roda JC Kerkrade 1-0 in an incident-filled match on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Feyenoord skipper Ronald Koeman scored the only goal in the 36th minute from the penalty spot after striker Gaston Taument had been brought down in the box .</p>
<p>Six minutes later defender Henk Fraser was sent off for a bad tackle.</p>
<p>One of the linesmen was hit by a lighter thrown from the stands as he went off at halftime.</p>
<p>The referee extended the halftime break by 20 minutes before returning for the second half, having made sure security in the Feyenoord Stadium was stepped up.</p>
<p>In the second half Roda tried in vain to take advantage of having an extra man but the woodwork and goalkeeper Ed de Goey stood in the way of an equaliser.</p>
<p>Fraser will miss at least Feyenoord's final match before the winter break on Sunday against NEC Nijmegen. So will Koeman, who received his fourth yellow card of the season, which means a one-match suspension.</p>
<p>Feyenoord now have 42 points from 19 matches.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NETH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMSTERDAM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NETHERLANDS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
