<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263338" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: NORDIC SKIING-NORWAY TAKE TOP FOUR PLACES -- TWICE.</title>
<headline>NORDIC SKIING-NORWAY TAKE TOP FOUR PLACES -- TWICE.</headline>
<dateline>OBERSTDORF, Germany 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Norway's cross-country skiers made World Cup history on Wednesday by taking the top four places in both the men's and women's races in a World Cup meeting in Oberstdorf.</p>
<p>In the men's classical-style 30 km race, the Norwegians' domination was even more complete as Bjorn Daehlie led a block of eight Norwegians who finished in the top 10.</p>
<p>For Daehlie, the most successful cross-country skier in World Cup history, the victory in one hour 20 minutes 13.3 seconds was the 33rd of his career.</p>
<p>It stretched his lead over Italy's Fulvio Valbusa in the overall standings to more than 100 points after just four races.</p>
<p>Daehlie was followed home by compatriots Erling Jevne, Sture Sivertsen and Vegard Ulvang.</p>
<p>In the women's 10 km classical race, Trude Dybendahl led home another Norwegian quartet in 29 minutes 23.1 seconds to notch the seventh victory of her career but her first for three years.</p>
<p>She was followed home by Bente Martinsen, Anita Moen-Guidon and Marit Mikkelsplass.</p>
<p>Italy's Stefania Belmondo did enough to defend her overall World Cup lead by finishing ninth.</p>
<p>The meeting was marked, however, by continuing allegations of blood doping among male athletes.</p>
<p>&quot;I think there is manipulation going on,&quot; said German team doctor Ernst Jakob.</p>
<p>The medical committee of the International Ski Federation (FIS) is so concerned about the allegations that the chairman of its medical committee, Ernst Raas of Austria, announced that it would begin carrying out blood tests in January.</p>
<p>&quot;There are certainly going to be tests at the next World Cup races,&quot; he told the German sports agency SID from Innsbruck.</p>
<p>&quot;I have set up a procedure and informed my colleagues that they can carry out the tests.&quot;</p>
<p>In particular, he mentioned a cross-country skiing meeting in Nagano, Japan, and a Nordic combination meeting in Saalfelden, Austria, both to be held on January 11 and 12, as events where tests would be carried out.</p>
<p>Raab collected the blood haemoglobin values of 90 percent of the skiers before the start of the season to allow a comparison to be made.</p>
<p>Haemoglobin in red blood cells transports oxygen around the body and its level can be boosted through blood doping, a technique in which blood is taken from an athlete's body and pumped back just before competition to enhance the distribution of oxygen to the muscles.</p>
<p>Values are typically around 15 to 18 and Raab said an increase of three units was highly dangerous and would be considered suspect. He said the committee would ask the FIS to ban athletes who were found guilty.</p>
<p>&quot;In Belgium alone 12 cyclists are supposed to have died from blood doping,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="NORW">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="OBERSTDORF, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
