<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263317" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Anheuser to boost stake in Grupo Modelo.</title>
<headline>Anheuser to boost stake in Grupo Modelo.</headline>
<dateline>ST. LOUIS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Anheuser-Busch Cos Inc said Wednesday it will increase its ownership in Grupo Modelo S.A. de C.V. and its subsidiaries to 37 percent for an investment of about $550 million.</p>
<p>Grupo Modelo, the No. 1 brewer in Mexico, is known for its Corona brand.</p>
<p>In 1993, Anheuser-Busch acquired a 17.7 percent direct and indirect interest in Grupo Modelo and its subsidiary, Diblo, for $477 million, with options to increase its holdings at any time between mid-1995 and the end of 1997.  </p>
<p>The transaction is expected to close in late January 1997.</p>
<p>As a result of the investment, the number of seats Anheuser-Busch holds on the Modelo board will rise to 10 from the current three.</p>
<p>The total number of seats on the Modelo board will increase to 21 from the current 14. Grupo Modelo vice chairman Carlos Fernandez G. is a director of Anheuser-Busch. Antonio Fernandez R. is an advisory member of Anheuser-Busch's board.  </p>
<p>Modelo is the exclusive importer and distributor of Budweiser and other Anheuser-Busch brands in Mexico.</p>
<p>Modelo brands are brewed at seven breweries throughout Mexico.</p>
<p>Anheuser-Busch, the world's largest brewer, sold 87.5 million barrels of beer in 1995. Through the first three quarters of 1996, it sold 70 million barrels of beer, representing a 44.8 percent market share, according to the Beer Institute.</p>
<p>		  ((-- Chicago newsdesk 312 408-8787))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ST. LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
