<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263381" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: BASEBALL-TIGERS, PADRES DEAL AGAIN.</title>
<headline>BASEBALL-TIGERS, PADRES DEAL AGAIN.</headline>
<dateline>DETROIT 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Detroit Tigers completed another trade with San Diego on Tuesday, sending pitchers Joey Eischen and Cam Smith to the Padres for catcher Brian Johnson and pitcher Willie Blair.</p>
<p>For Detroit, it is the sixth trade of the off-season and third involving a starting catcher in the last week.</p>
<p>The Tigers had dealt Brad Ausmus, who was acquired from San Diego last season, in a nine-player trade with Houston a week ago, and acquired Matt Walbeck from Minnesota a day later.</p>
<p>The 28-year-old Johnson has played all three major-league seasons with San Diego. In 82 games last year (59 starts), he recorded career bests of a .272 average, 66 hits, eight homers, 35 RBI and 13 doubles.</p>
<p>Blair went 2-6 with one save and a 4.60 ERA in 60 relief appearances, spanning 88 innings in 1996. He owns a 25-41 career record with four saves and a 4.73 ERA with Toronto, Cleveland, Houston, Colorado and San Diego.</p>
<p>Eischen began last year with the Los Angeles Dodgers, but was dealt to Detroit on July 31 in a three-player trade. The left-hander was 0-1 with a 4.78 ERA in 28 relief appearances with the Dodgers before posting a 1-1 mark and 3.24 ERA in 24 outings with Detroit.</p>
<p>Smith has compiled a 26-30 record and 4.84 ERA in four minor league seasons. Last year, he went 5-8 with a 4.59 ERA in 22 games (21 starts) in Class A Lakeland.</p>
<p>General manager Randy Smith came to Detroit from San Diego and has engineered three trades in less than a year with his former team. These teams also completed a major trade last June, as catcher John Flaherty and shortstop Chris Gomez were sent to San Diego for Ausmus and shortstop Andujar Cedeno.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DETROIT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
