<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263369" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ABU DHABI: SOCCER-SAUDI ARABIA TO FACE UAE IN ASIAN CUP FINAL.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-SAUDI ARABIA TO FACE UAE IN ASIAN CUP FINAL.</headline>
<byline>Nadim Ladki</byline>
<dateline>ABU DHABI 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Favourites Saudi Arabia won a penalty-shootout 4-3 against triple champions Iran on Wednesday to book an Asian Cup final showdown with hosts the United Arab Emirates who beat Kuwait 1-0.</p>
<p>Defender Ahmed Madani scored the decisive goal to silence the 15,000 Iranian supporters and send the Saudis to their fourth final in a row.</p>
<p>The final will be played on Saturday.</p>
<p>Iran striker Ali Daei, the tournament's top scorer with seven goals, missed the target with the first kick of the shootout and left the field in tears.</p>
<p>The score was 3-3 after five kicks each. Mohammad Al Daeyea then saved Mohammad Khakpour's attempt before Madani hit the winner.</p>
<p>The Saudis went close to winning the game in the second half of normal time, hitting the crossbar twice, the second time in the 89th minute.</p>
<p>A superb save by Iran keeper Nima Nakisa from a header by substitute Abdullah Al Dossary denied the Saudis a ''golden goal'' in the 24th minute of extra time.</p>
<p>It was sweat revenge for the Saudis who were hammered 3-0 by the Iranians in a group phase tie last week.</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia won the title in 1984 and 1988 but lost to Japan in the final four years ago. Iran won the title three times back-to-back between 1968 and 1976.</p>
<p>Thousands of locals took to the streets after the final whistle of the UAE-Kuwait match to celebrate their team's surprise qualification for the final. The UAE had never previously reached the final in the competition's 40-year history.</p>
<p>Striker Hassan Ahmed rose to head in a corner 21 minutes from time against the run of play to give the hosts victory.</p>
<p>The match was marked by two controversial decisions by Japanese referee Okada Masayoshi who twice booked UAE players for off-the-ball incidents against Kuwaiti players.</p>
<p>Kuwait on both occassions protested that the offenders should have been sent off.</p>
<p>A controversial refereeing decision against Kuwait had also marked the meeting between the two teams 10 days ago in the group stage. The UAE also won that match 3-2.</p>
<p>UAE captain Adnan Al-Talyani was lucky to stay on the field in the 56th minute when he elbowed Jamal Abdulrahman as the players waited for a Kuwaiti corner.</p>
<p>The Japanese referee, who did not see the incident, produced only the yellow card to Talyani after consulting his linesman.</p>
<p>The referee had also showed the yellow card to UAE's Hassan Mubarak for another off-the-ball incident in the 44th minute.</p>
<p>The two losing teams take part in a playoff for third place on Saturday ahead of the final.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ABDBI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="IRAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="KUWAIT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
