<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26344" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News- Sept 2.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News- Sept 2.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In its fifth successive year of decline, Australia's market share in Japan in 1995 slipped from five per cent to 4.3 per cent. Australia is one of the few countries to have a trade surplus with Japan, yet the four biggest exporters to Japan - the US, China, South Korea and Taiwan - have either improved their market share or held their ground. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>After a court decision in May abolished an old restriction on third parties paying for legal action undertaken by others in return for a share of damages awarded, company liquidators are discovering a new weapon to use against the heads of failed companies - insurance company funding for legal actions. Page 2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In an attempt to recover losses and improve its position in the interstate market, Ansett Australia  AIRa NZ is considering dropping first class on its domestic flights, after a 45 per cent fall in those tickets over the past two years. Corporate customers and Government departments are being sounded out this week over the move, which would see Australia move in line with the rest of the world, as it is one of the few countries where a domestic first class still exists. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Mining and forestry group North Ltd has settled a long-running legal action in the Industrial Relations Court in which it was seeking more than A$250,000 in damages from unions involved in a strike at a Tasmanian paper mill four years ago. An out-of-court settlement was negotiated with the ACTU and the unions. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>MIM Holdings Ltd shareholders have been asked to accept their lowest annual dividend payment in ten years, despite a big bounce back into profit for 1995-96. The final dividend has been halved to A$1.25 a share to help the company fund its billion dollar commitments to new projects over the next three years. Page 20.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The National Mutual Holdings senior management team have finalised the retail price, as well as the indicative institutional price, for the company's sharemarket listing on October 8, after determining the exact number of shares sought by NatMut's 1.2 milion policy holders. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>United Kingdom telecommunications carrier Cable &amp; Wireless plc  CW.L, a 24.5 per cent shareholder in Optus Communications, has supported a move to align Optus Vision with the Australis Media Ltd  ALM.AX satellite pay-TV business. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Multinational JR Simplot acquired some of Australia's most famous food brands, including Four'n Twenty Pies, Edgell Birdseye and Nanna's when it paid A$1.3 billion to Pacific Dunlop Ltd  PDP.AX for its Pacific Brands Food group, and the results have been rewarding. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Building and construction materials company CSR Ltd CSR.AX, will attempt to get itself out of trouble with a sale of A$506 million in debt securities to fund the expansion of its growing United States operations.  The funds will be used by subsidiary CSR America, a concrete group, and CSR Finance, the company's finance arm. Page 29.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>In the lead up to the Sydney 2000 Olympic Games, Puma Australia, the best performing subsidiary of the international Puma AG sportswear group, will launch a fresh assault on the A$450 million wholesale sporting footwear market. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Richard Sheppard, executive director of Macquarie Bank Ltd MBL.AX, believes medium-sized business are set to reap significant rewards from increased competition within the financial sector. Sheppard claims the current outlook is good for medium-sized businesses looking to borrow. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>As former Amcor Ltd  MAC.AX managing director Stan Wallis retired from his position to head the banking inquiry, the new managing director of the paper and packaging giant, Don Macfarlane, must today face the market to report the company's first profit decline. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>A bumpy ride is expected for financial markets this week as concerns in the United States over inflation is fuelling ideas of an interest rise there. Meanwhile, the Reserve Bank is meeting tomorrow, yet an adjustment of interest rates is not expected and National Australia Bank chief economist Alan Oster believes that post-Budget local interest rates are more likely to go up than down. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Many in Australia's banking industry are speculating over the findings of the Wallis Inquiry into Australia's financial systems, with expectations the market may head for another round in the bank mergers game that shook the industry 10 years ago. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Film and Production company Southern Star, maker of Blue Heelers, Police Rescue and Water Rats, is to be floated on the stockmarket. The A$134 million public float, underwritten by Bain &amp; Co involves the issue of 43 million Southern Star shares at A$1.40 apiece, which comprises 14.65 million new shares and the vendor's sale of 28.4 million shares. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Australia's resources sector faces a dismal six months as pressure on commodity prices and a strong currency threaten to wipe out efficiency gains. A number of profit reports have come with sombre predictions about the direction of prices for the rest ofthe year. Page 31.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>ABN Amro Hoare Govett chairman Dr John Hewson has been appointed to chair multimedia company Network Entertainment as it prepares for a stockmarket float in early November. As a former division of Shomega, Network is raising about A$12 million and will be capitalised at A$30 million on listing. Page 33.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Uncle Tobys managing director Peter McLoghlin said new Uncle Tobys products - Uncle Tobys Nut Feast and In-Cred-I-Bites - were being promoted to take advantage of the new demand for healthier foods. The company will benefit from the return of its Olympic stars Kieran Perkins and Samantha Riley, who are now available for more promotional work. Page 33.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>Greenpeace is alarmed at the increasing production rate of PVC in Australia and believes the substance is so dangerously toxic that it should be banned. PVC is a fine white substance that manufacturers buy at $1100 a tonne to produce everyday items like gumboots, catheters, guttering and car trim. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The patent to two 'air' labels of Nike is coming to an end after 17 years. The air label has given Nike a 36 per cent share of the athletic shoe market and has sold more shoes in this area than any of its competitors since 1987. Page C1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Prime Minister John Howard's trip to the South Pacific has been overshadowed by the region's report that at least a half of its 16 members are suffering some form of economic crisis. The report claims that many of the South Pacific nation economies are runing large trade deficits and the Australian Government has recently cut $3.5 million worth of aid to this region. Page C2.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Communications Minister Richard Alston yesterday said the Fairfax newspaper group  FXJ.AX, whose three main papers are The Age, The Sydney Morning Herald and The Australian Financial Review could be split up and sold to different parties, possibly to Kerry Packer and Rupert Murdoch becoming its new owners. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Having suffered a downturn in advertising dollars from local services, real estate, motoring and employment, country newspapers are beginning to feel the pinch of financial constraint. When Australia's rural account was strong, these newspapers were healthy, and their readership is still there, but without crucial advertising dollars, the future for country papers will not improve. Page C3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Anaconda Nickel's A$900 million Murrin Murrin nickel project is under strong fire after scenes at the WA Supreme Court on Friday. In a complete turn around of the company's plan to seek orders for dismissal of action, Anaconda has now supported the decision to quit the action. Page C3</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
