<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26356" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>NEW ZEALAND: Mt Ruapehu eruptions hint at new round of activity.</title>
<headline>Mt Ruapehu eruptions hint at new round of activity.</headline>
<dateline>WELLINGTON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Two minor eruptions at Mt Ruapehu on Sunday hinted at a new round of volcanic activity, the Institute of Geological and Nuclear Sciences (IGNS) said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;Further minor eruptive activity is expected from Ruapehu and further larger events are a possibility,&quot; IGNS spokesman Brad Scott said.</p>
<p>After some early evening grumblings, the central North Island volcano belched back to life about 11.30 p.m. on Sunday with ashfall forcing the closure of the snow-laden Turoa skifield.  </p>
<p>Scott said yesterday's activity was consistent with the current alert level.</p>
<p>The level was downgraded recently after a decrease in eruptions and seismic activity.</p>
<p>&quot;Eruptive activity consistent with level 2 (continued minor eruptive activity) has occurred at Mt Ruapehu over the weekend.</p>
<p>&quot;There were two short lived periods of activity on Sunday evening. The latter activity caused minor ashfall over the Turoa skifield area,&quot; Scott said in a statement.</p>
<p>The eruption plume trailed about 50km.  </p>
<p>&quot;The institute will continue to monitor the activity at Ruapehu and advise... as the level of activity changes,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Turoa management said its skifield would be closed for at least.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not looking too pretty. It's black and grey,&quot; a spokesman said this morning.</p>
<p>The mountain's other commercial skifield, Whakapapa, was not affected by last night's eruption and was likely to be open for skiing today, a spokeswoman said.</p>
<p>-- Wellington newsroom 64 4 4734 746</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WELLINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NEW ZEALAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
