<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263531" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: North Sea, West African crude firm, Med depressed.</title>
<headline>North Sea, West African crude firm, Med depressed.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>North Sea and West African crude markets were firm on Thursday, but the Mediterranean sour market was seen under pressure from the onset of Iraqi exports.</p>
<p>Several North Sea grades traded at steady to firmer numbers with two Forties cargoes, loading Jan 4-6 and Jan 6-8, fetching Dated Brent +28 cents.</p>
<p>After four cargoes were sold on Tuesday, traders said that the first decade Forties programme was virtually sold out and some expected differentials for second decade cargoes to command a premium of more than 30 cents to Dated Brent.</p>
<p>A Statfjord cargo for Jan 8-10 sold at Dtd Brent +28 cts.</p>
<p>That was 10 cents above the price of a December-loading cargo traded late last week. A Jan 10-12 Statfjord traded at Dated +26 cents.</p>
<p>Other Norwegian grades also fetched stronger prices, with a Dec 7-9 Troll sold at Dated Brent +40 cents and a Dec 7-9 Gullfaks C traded at Dated +37.5 cents.</p>
<p>A Dec 27-29 Brent was sold early to a Wall Street trader for Jan Brent -18.5 cents, but late Dec and early Jan barrels were assessed at or above Jan -12/13 cents later in line with next week's cfds which made further gains to talk around Feb Brent +40 cents.</p>
<p>The sole Brent cargo nominated from the paper chains was kept by Shell UK, traders said.</p>
<p>Feb Brent paper fell back sharply after trading at $23.73 and $23.66 a barrel to talk some 35-40 cents down at $23.30/$23.35 in line with IPE screen levels at 1840 GMT.</p>
<p>The forward paper curve also shed earlier gains. Jan/Feb talked either side of +50/54 cents after trading at +55 cents and Feb/March was discussed at +58/62 in late trade.</p>
<p>West African grades were firm, with arbitrage opportunities to both the U.S. and Asia, traders said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
