<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263660" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MAURITIUS: Mauritius index up after fin min unveils policy.</title>
<headline>Mauritius index up after fin min unveils policy.</headline>
<dateline>PORT LOUIS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Stock Exchange of Mauritius share index, semdex, gained 2.34 points to 338.18 on Wednesday after new Finance Minister Vasant Bunwaree unveiled plans to restore investor confidence in the island.</p>
<p>Turnover rose to 14.20 million rupees on 594,170 shares from 7.34 million rupees on 257,951 shares on Monday.</p>
<p>Bunwaree told parliament on Tuesday that his economic policy would seek to shrug off a &quot;pervasive wait-and-see attitude&quot; in business by stimulating investments and savings and placing the fight against inflation on top of government priorities.</p>
<p>Bunwaree pledged to reach a set of macroeconomic medium term targets with economic growth of 5.5 to 6.5 percent over the next three years and inflation below 5.0 percent by the year 2000.</p>
<p>Bunwaree's speech was seen as a good start for the new finance minister who took office three weeks ago.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a first step in the right direction and we look forward to seeing the Minister continuing on the good signal which he has just sent,&quot; one broker said.</p>
<p>Stocks were in buoyant mood and most moving shares were on an upside trend, bourse officials said.</p>
<p>All three hotel stocks gained ground after Bunwaree said he would not carry out a hotel and restaurant tax increase sought by his predecessor Rundheersing Bheenick in the 1996/97 budget.</p>
<p>Sun Resorts was 50 cents higher to 36.50 rupees on 8,943 shares, New Mauritius Hotels rose 50 cents to 30 rupees on 32,600 shares and Grand Baie Hotel climbed 60 cents to 37.20 rupees on 200 shares.</p>
<p>Mauritius Commercial Bank was one rupee higher to 75.50 rupees on 97,246 shares and State Bank of Mauritius edged up by 10 cents to an all time high of 9.40 rupees on 203,000 shares.</p>
<p>British American Insurance gained 10 cents to 7.60 rupees on 63,288 shares. Conglomerate Rogers rose 50 cents to 94.50 rupees on 3,200 shares and commerce concern Happy World Foods was stable at 17.20 rupees on 30,500 shares.</p>
<p>National carrier Air Mauritius fell by 2.50 rupees to 50 rupees on 800 shares.</p>
<p>--Port Louis ++230 211-9555.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MAURTS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PORT LOUIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MAURITIUS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
