<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263601" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>CANADA: CanAmera Foods switchs Hamilton to soybean crush.</title>
<headline>CanAmera Foods switchs Hamilton to soybean crush.</headline>
<dateline>WINNIPEG 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>CanAmera Foods last week switched its largest crushing plant in Hamilton, Ontario, from a dual canola and soybean processing facility to exclusively crush soybeans, Saskatchewan Wheat Pool chief executive Don Loewen told Reuters.</p>
<p>&quot;This is not permanent. There's a soybean plant and a canola plant. We changed the canola plant into what we call a swing plant and we're able to swing it either onto canola or soybeans depending on the crush margins and we just started that (crushing soybeans) last week,&quot; Loewen said.</p>
<p>Low profit margins on canola crush forced plant slowdowns.</p>
<p>Three of Canada's five canola crushers, including CanAmera, announced reduced production runs in October.</p>
<p>CanAmera's canola plant in Hamilton crushed between 600 to 700 tonnes of canola each day, Loewen said.</p>
<p>&quot;When we switched over to beans, the 700-tonne canola plant became about a 1,500-tonne soybean plant so it's a significant switch,&quot; Loewen said.</p>
<p>&quot;The other soybean plant is larger,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>CanAmera is 50 percent owned by Saskatchewan Wheat Pool, Manitoba Pool Elevators and 50 percent by Central Soya, a unit of private French company  Eridania Begain-Say.</p>
<p>((Gilbert Le Gras 204 947 3548))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I41600">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WINNIPEG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CANADA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
