<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263702" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Dec 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Bulgaria - Dec 18.</headline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the main stories in Sofia newspapers today. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>STANDART</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria can gain some $5.8 billion net revenue over 30 years from a pipeline concession for transiting Russian gas through its territory, if the government grants the concession, visiting Russian Deputy Prime Minister Oleg Lobov said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's state monopolist cigarette maker Bulgartabak holding is expected to submit a proposal to the Trade Ministry by December 20 for a 40 percent rise in cigarette prices, a company official said.</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Health Ministry said prices of Bulgarian-made medicines would be raised by some 50 percent effective from Monday as a result of a rise in fuel prices.</p>
<p>PARI</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet debated the 1997 draft budget envisaging an introduction of a currency board system in the country but no decisions were taken.</p>
<p>The Finance Minister Dimitar Kostov said a government commission would discuss the final version of the draft with representatives of the International Monetary Fund.</p>
<p>-- The ruling Socialist party is not able to introduce succesfully a currency board system in Bulgaria because it has the support of only 13 to 16 percent of Bulgarians, the main opposition Union of Democratic Forces leader Ivan Kostov said.</p>
<p>TRUD</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria had signed a preliminary protocol for grain imports from Russia and details of the deal are yet to be discussed by the two governments, a senior Russian government official said.</p>
<p>24 CHASA</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's Telecommunications Company (BTC) will submit a proposal to the cabinet to raise telephone charges by 40 percent effective from January 1, a BTC senior official said.</p>
<p>KONTINENT</p>
<p>-- Bulgaria's cabinet has decided to peg fuel prices to the central bank's daily fixing for the German mark, the newspaper said without quoting sources.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, (++359-2) 981 8569</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
