<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263766" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria agency sees rate fall to 30 pct in 1997.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria agency sees rate fall to 30 pct in 1997.</headline>
<byline>Elisaveta Konstantinova</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria's Agency for Economic Forecast and Development expects annual interest rates to fall to 30 percent after the introduction of a currency board, the agency's director Gancho Ganchev said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Our forecast is that annual interest rate next year will average around 30 percent,&quot; Ganchev, who is also deputy minister of economic development, told a news conference. The central bank's main interest rate is currently 180 percent.</p>
<p>The rate is expected to slide gradually and hit low levels by the end on a one-year operation of the currency board, said Ganchev.</p>
<p>Bulgaria's central bank raised the main interest rate to a record high of 300 percent annually in September in a bid to support the collapsing lev by curbing panic withdrawals of savings and their conversion into dollars.</p>
<p>The lev's chronic instability prevented the central bank from reducing the rate lower than 180 percent in the past two months.</p>
<p>Bulgaria is now discussing the introduction of a tough currency board regime proposed by the International Monetary Fund to boost confidence in the crumbling financial system.</p>
<p>Under the system, the central bank will not be able to print levs it cannot cover with hard currency reserves, which is expected to remove political pressure from monetary policy.</p>
<p>The bank will also be banned from lending to the government and commercial banks.</p>
<p>&quot;With restricted or banned refinancing of commercial banks by the central bank, the current interest rate structure will change under a currency board system,&quot; said Ganchev.</p>
<p>The main interest rate set by central bank will be replaced by different rate levels -- the interbank market rate, the lending rate of commercial banks and the deposit rate, said Ganchev.</p>
<p>Interest on deposits will be lower than the market and lending rates, said Ganchev.</p>
<p>Currently the market rate is several points higher than the main interest rate and the rate on deposits is up to 10 percent lower.</p>
<p>Annual inflation next year is seen at between 20 and 30 percent, depending at what rate the lev will be pegged, said Ganchev.</p>
<p>&quot;It will be best to fix the rate at the market rate of the day the currency baord is launched,&quot; said Ganchev.</p>
<p>The lev traded at around 450 to the dollar on Wednesday, down from 70 in the beginning of the year.</p>
<p>The agency predicted economic growth at zero next year. The Economy Institute of the Bulgarian Academy of Sciences expected an eight percent decline of the economy.</p>
<p>&quot;It (growth) depends very much on when the currency board plan is introduced,&quot; said Ganchev.</p>
<p>The system will be introduced after the parliament passes next year's budget and a package of legal amendments which would make the currency board operational.</p>
<p>The cabinet has not approved the 1997 draft budget so far, but officials said that the budget frame is based on assumptions of the agency.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
