<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263765" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Zloty up vs basket, NBP raises 14-day revrepo rate.</title>
<headline>Zloty up vs basket, NBP raises 14-day revrepo rate.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish zloty extended yesterday's gains to well above three percent from the trading band centre on the back of client-based currency sales, dealers said.</p>
<p>They said the central bank, which said earlier this year it did not want furhter zloty appreciation, did not intervene, limiting itself to asking for for quotings, which could encourage some players to drive the Polish unit up.</p>
<p>&quot;The zloty is gaining 0.05 to 0.1 point against the parity rate a day and traders, sitting on short currency positions, are happy to make profits,&quot; said Krzysztof Mordes from BIG SA.  </p>
<p>The zloty closed at 3.19/3.16 percent from the trading band centre, up from yesterday's 3.08/3.01 percent. It closed at 2.8545/55 to the dollar, down from 2.8530/50 on Tuesday and at 1.8388/95 to the mark, up from 1.8430/45.</p>
<p>Dealers said that the client-fuelled currency selling trend combined with a trend to sell currencies in spot deals on a Wednesday to sit on higher yielding zloty instruments over the weekend.</p>
<p>They said these two factors kept the Polish unit from falling on Wednesday despite the dollar's rise against the mark on world markets.  </p>
<p>At its drainage today the NBP kept its one-day rate flat at 21.50 percent, set a four day rate at 21.59 percent and raised its 14-day rate by 2.54 point to 21.70 percent, which dealers said established a new short term money market yield curve.</p>
<p>Banks wanted to place 2.423 billion zlotys with the central bank which drained 1.969 billion.</p>
<p>Overnight rates were at 21.15/21.65 percent, up from opening's 21.10/21.50 percent, tomorrow/next rates were at 21.25/21.75 percent against opening's 21.25/21.60 percent.</p>
<p>-- Krzysztof Wojcik +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
