<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263874" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>COSTA RICA: Costa Rica privatisation plan faces hurdles.</title>
<headline>Costa Rica privatisation plan faces hurdles.</headline>
<byline>John McPhaul</byline>
<dateline>SAN JOSE 1996-12-17</dateline>
<text>
<p>One day after President Jose Maria Figueres announced Costa Rica's ambitious privatisation programme to reduce the national debt, questions remained as to how much of the package would pass congress in 1997, an election year.</p>
<p>On Monday Figueres proposed privatising the country's second largest bank, the Banco de Costa Rica, the government's offshore bank Banco Internacional de Costa Rica (BICSA), the government-run communications company Radiografica Costarricense SA and 40 percent of the state insurance monopoly, the National Insurance Institute.</p>
<p>The country's powerful public sector unions wasted no time in denouncing the plan and vowed to oppose it.</p>
<p>&quot;The policies of this government are uniting the public sector unions,&quot; said Fernando Masis of the Telecommunication Engineers' Union.</p>
<p>Even private sector groups which supported the plan in principle, though not in all its details, recognised the tough road ahead.  </p>
<p>&quot;The battle is hard and it's just begun,&quot; said Chamber of Industries President Marco Vinicio Ruiz. &quot;We support the plan because it provides a basis for discussion.&quot;</p>
<p>The proposals were part of a package aimed at cutting the country's $3.4 billion internal debt, blamed by private and public sector officials alike for interest rates of over 25 percent, which are dragging down the economy.</p>
<p>This year the government spent 35 percent of its budget on servicing the debt.</p>
<p>The private sector complained that although the country was posting record export figures and most other macroeconomic figures were balanced, Costa Rica's otherwise healthy economy would barely register growth this year because of the effects of the debt burden.</p>
<p>Other parts of the Figueres plan included selling off the country's beachfront, currently government property only leased under concession; delaying a scheduled reduction of duties on luxury items and issuing $200 million in government bonds on the international market to take advantage of lower interest rates in 1997.  </p>
<p>&quot;The president made an effort to please everyone and unfortunately pleased no one,&quot; former President Rodrigo Carazo, a leading opponent of privatisation, told the daily La Nacion.</p>
<p>Although some economists and private sector leaders had urged a more aggressive privatisation plan, including the sale of the power and telecommunications monopoly Instituto Costarricense de Electricidad (ICE), Figueres conceded in his nationwide address to announce his plan that ICE was off-limits to privatisation.</p>
<p>&quot;This institution is a national symbol and the country has given clear signs that it wants it to remain public,&quot; he said. &quot;I respect and support this national feeling.&quot;</p>
<p>--San Jose bureau +506 224-2949))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COSR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-17"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAN JOSE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COSTA RICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
