<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263888" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: INTERVIEW-Avantel set to take on Telmex.</title>
<headline>INTERVIEW-Avantel set to take on Telmex.</headline>
<byline>David Luhnow</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Officials at upstart Mexican telephone company Avantel show visitors a cartoon of a jogger labelled Avantel racing around a track while other would-be rivals of ex-monopoly Telefonos de Mexico sit on the sidelines in their warm-up suits.</p>
<p>Dan Crawford, president of Avantel, says the message is clear: Avantel is way ahead in the run up to January 1, when Telmex loses its historic grip on Mexico's telephone market.  </p>
<p>And practically every third spot on Mexican television is an Avantel ad trying to coax customers into leaving long-time provider Telmex.</p>
<p>One ad shows a businessman trying to make sense of the different rates he has been charged on his bill. After a confusing explanation by a Telmex clerk, who asks, &quot;Is everything clear?&quot;, the man responds, &quot;Perfectly: I'm switching to Avantel.&quot;</p>
<p>By the end of 1997, Avantel will have spent $600 million in capital and another $300 million in human resources, marketing and other non-capital spending, Crawford said.  </p>
<p>&quot;They went ahead with their investment plans even before all the rules were set for the market, so now they are more prepared than anyone else to compete with Telmex,&quot; said Leslie Marcus, an analyst at Santander Investment in New York.</p>
<p>Avantel started placing long-distance calls for corporate clients in August, but come January it will be able to connect, for a fee, to Telmex's local network and go after thousands more corporate clients and residential customers.  </p>
<p>At stake is a $4 billion a year market in long-distance alone -- a market expected to double in five years. Crawford said he expects long-distance minutes growth of at least 17 percent a year, nearly twice the U.S. rate.</p>
<p>Avantel aims to have 20 percent of the market within five to seven years. Officials are wary of predicting how fast they will gain market share, however, saying much depends on how well the government regulates the market and if Telmex plays by the rules.  </p>
<p>One early problem has been government delays in sending out ballots that allow potential customers to pre-subscribe to Avantel as their long-distance company. If customers do not choose a carrier ahead of time, they can pick a long-distance company for each individual call by dialing a prefix.</p>
<p>If customers do not return ballots or dial a prefix, their call will automatically go to Telmex.</p>
<p>&quot;We don't think its particularly fair, but we've accepted it. Having said that, we think it's incumbent upon the government to ensure there is a strong turnout (in the pre-subscription process),&quot; Crawford said.  </p>
<p>He also said Telmex is using its role as a local service provider to gain advantage in its long-distance business.</p>
<p>&quot;We order services from Telmex on behalf of our clients, and clients who may never have seen a Telmex salesman see a long-distance salesman the next day,&quot; Crawford said.</p>
<p>&quot;They'll make promises to get a circuit to them in two weeks. We had been waiting six months to get it for them. Now they are offering them a much shorter time,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Telmex officials have consistently denied charges the company is using its local services as an advantage.  </p>
<p>Crawford said new competitors will be keen to see if the government chooses a carrier other than Telmex, which is seen as maintaining strong ties to the government.</p>
<p>&quot;If Telmex wins the government contract in an auction, that's fair. We just want all the business put on the table so that we can participate and win,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Avantel says its long-distance rates will be on average 10 percent lower than Telmex. But officials play down the possibility of a damaging price war.</p>
<p>&quot;I wouldn't rule it out. We need to be careful we don't take it for granted. (But) the pricing that's been in the marketplace so far is reasonable...we're seen some improved pricing for the consumer, but in a rational range,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((-- Mexico City newsroom, +525 728-9565))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
