<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263838" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Russia 1997 securities yields under 20 pct - Dubinin.</title>
<headline>Russia 1997 securities yields under 20 pct - Dubinin.</headline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Yields on Russian state securities will likely fall below 20 percent next year from an average of 38-40 percent, the head of the central bank said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;The situation will normalise next year when, with inflation at about 12 percent, we intend to pay 17, 18 or maybe 19 percent on state borrowings,&quot; Sergei Dubinin told a meeting of Russia's top financiers.</p>
<p>He said he saw yields on securities by the end of 1997 at four to five percentage points above the level of inflation, which he predicted would be 11-12 percent for the year.</p>
<p>Dubinin said that M2, a broad measure of monetary supply, would grow in 1997 at a rate similar to 1996.</p>
<p>&quot;The growth of M2 was 35 percent in 1996, and we expect the same in 1997, 34-36 percent,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>He said securities yields were expected to start slipping already by the end of this year, but said there would be no government orders for this to happen.</p>
<p>&quot;We do not plan any government resolutions ordering quarterly yield cuts next year, but the fact is that the trend will be towards lower yields,&quot; Dubinin said.</p>
<p>In summer this year the government issued a resolution, ordering gradual cuts in T-bill yields.</p>
<p>The 1997 draft budget provides for a fall in the issue of government securities, which, combined with a yield fall, is part of the govenrment's efforts to tempt cash away from T-bills and bonds into the production sphere of the economy.</p>
<p>--Moscow Newsroom, +7095 941 8520</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
