<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263924" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia's Samper backs reelection of cenbank head.</title>
<headline>Colombia's Samper backs reelection of cenbank head.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's President Ernesto Samper backed the re-election of Miguel Urrutia as the head of the central bank in a statement issued Wednesday.</p>
<p>The central bank's board of directors is due to hold an election for the institution's top job Friday. The statement said the goverment fully respected the central bank's autonomy and said it had developed good relations with Urrutia.  </p>
<p>Urrutia is a known supporter of the opposition Conservative Party, but is not politically active.</p>
<p>His continuation in the post appeared in doubt earlier this year when the central bank was criticized by the ruling Liberal Party and key export sectors for allowing the peso to strengthen. The central bank had set a 13.5 percent devaluation target for the peso this year, but so far has devalued by less than 3.0 percent.  </p>
<p>Analysts have explained the central bank's passivity on the peso as due to the unexpectedly high amount of dollars that entered the country this year. The dollar purchases necessary to meet the devaluation target would have boosted the money supply and fueled inflation, they believe.</p>
<p>The central bank does not comment on its actions.</p>
<p>However, in recent weeks supporters have rallied around Urrutia, and with Samper's backing today, he looks to be in a shoo-in at Friday's vote.  </p>
<p>&quot;The government has found Dr Urrutia to be a good interlocutor when discussing its concerns. We think it is important to maintain a healthy continuity in the administrative consolidation of the bank,&quot; the statement from the presidential office said.</p>
<p>&quot;The government has been profoundly respectful of the autonomy of the central bank and its directors, but it is desireable that the bank consider the impact of its decision on other economic variables such as inflation, jobs, production and exchange rate stability,&quot; it added.  </p>
<p>Urrutia was elected to a four-year term in February 1993.</p>
<p>The central bank fears some of its independence may be eroded by two bills currently in through Congress. However, no action will be taken on them until Congress recovenes in March 1997.</p>
<p>-- Karl Penhaul, Bogota newsroom 571 610 7944</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C411">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
