<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="263980" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil's Bozano sees Banerj sale by Dec 27.</title>
<headline>Brazil's Bozano sees Banerj sale by Dec 27.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The manager of Rio de Janeiro state bank Banerj said it expects the bank's privatization auction to take place by December 27.</p>
<p>Paulo Ferraz, president of private bank Bozano, Simonsen, said he expects to set a new date for the auction shortly after a court injunction which blocked Tuesday's scheduled sale is lifted.</p>
<p>&quot;We expect to have the injunction repealed today and set a new date for the auction tomorrow,&quot; he said.  </p>
<p>Banerj was due to be auctioned off Tuesday at 0900 local/1100 GMT but the sale was postponed indefinitely after the court granted an injunction to the Association of Banerj's Employees, an opponent of the sale.</p>
<p>Bozano has been administering Banerj since early January on behalf of the Central Bank, which took over the state bank in December 1994.  The Central Bank's special administration period expires on December 27.  This date sets the stage for Banerj to be liquidated, returned to state hands or taken over by the federal government if it is not privatized.  </p>
<p>Rio de Janeiro state government has said it does not plan to have the bank returned to its control and does not see strong possibilities for transferring it to the federal government.</p>
<p>Ferraz said that if Banerj were not privatized, it would end up being liquidated.</p>
<p>The Bozano chief also downplayed talk that weak interest among investors could prevent Banerj from being privatized.</p>
<p>On Monday, only one of the bidders who signed up for the auction, Banco Itau, presented financial guarantees to bid on the sale.  </p>
<p>The other investor, Bradesco, failed to present the guarantees, raising speculation that the bank was dropping out of the running.</p>
<p>Ferraz said Bradesco decided not to present the guarantees because of the court injunction.</p>
<p>&quot;The main reason is the judicial battle,&quot; he said, adding he has been in touch with Bradesco and Itau to keep them aware of the government's action to lift the court injunction.</p>
<p>((-- Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo Newsroom 55-11-2485412))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C183">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
