<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264014" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - Dec 19.</title>
<headline>RTRS-PRESS DIGEST-Australian Business News - Dec 19.</headline>
<text>
<p>(Compiled for Reuters by Media Monitors)</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN FINANCIAL REVIEW</p>
<p>In a major embarrassment for the Wallis inquiry and the Federal Government, Federal Treasury has said there had been &quot;gross misrepresentations and exaggerations of the Treasury position as outlined in the department's submission to the Financial System Inuiry&quot;, and accused the Wallis inquiry and others of misrepresenting its position. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although not initially rejecting the merger, the Australian Securities Commission may block the A$2.65 billion St George Bank merger with Advance Bank after receiving legal advice raising concerns about the structure of the deal. The ASC will decide whether to act on the merger this week. Page 1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Sugar Industry Review Working Party has recommended the scrapping of the sugar tariff from July next year, a plan which working party member Harry Bonanno says will save the single desk selling for exports for the A$2 billion industry. The tariff is imposed on all sugar imports at a specific rate of A$55 a tonne and is worth A$26.7 million a year to the industry. Page 3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Although the speculation has been denied by both companies, rumours abound that CSR Ltd managing director Geoff Kells and Boral Ltd managing director Tony Berg will be replaced before the expected upturn in the industry towards the end of next year. With rivals James Hardie Industries Ltd and Pioneer International Ltd experiencing strong share rises in the past two months, the two chief executives are under pressure over their companies' static and uninspiring share prices. Page 13.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>While Ten Network shareholders have yet to agree on the best mechanism to float the A$1 billion-plus group, CanWest Global Communications head Izzy Asper said yesterday he was more confident of floating the Network after meeting with Communications Ministr Richard Alston. Meanwhile, 6.5 percent shareholder AMP Society said a &quot;simple&quot; float would be a better option than other shareholders' plans. Page 13.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Following Highlands Gold Ltd's threat to take legal action over a perceived lack of information provided by Placer Dome Inc, Placer has revealed that it would review Highlands' exploration programme and consider the best options for its Nena gold/copper and Ramu nickel deposits should its A$423 million takeover offer deliver total control. Page 14.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AUSTRALIAN</p>
<p>An agreement between BHP, Australia's biggest coal producer, and the Japanese steel mills, where BHP accepted price cuts of up to US$2 a tonne for some categories of coking coal, has been criticised by Australian coal producers, who warn the industry will be forced to chase higher export volumes at discount prices to maintain revenue. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>WMC Ltd's Duchess phosphate deposit near Mt Isa in Queensland looks set to go ahead, with the company expected today to announce an agreement with the Queensland Government over the supply of gas and sulphuric acid and efficient rail freight arrangements. The development of the A$650 million project will see WMC's wholly owned HiFert subsidiary lead the booming fertiliser industry. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Bankers Trust Australia, the third largest shareholder in John Fairfax Holdings Ltd, said yesterday it was not interested in selling its strategic 13.5 percent stake in the group as part of a takeover play. BT Australian head Rohan Hedley has added that the company is yet to express its position on voting against Brierley Investments Ltd moving to 24.9 percent of the publisher. Page 19.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>RTZ-CRA is expected to make A$20 million on the sale of Southern Copper's defunct New South Wales smelter and refinery to a five-member consortium led by Japanese metals giants Furukawa Electric Co Ltd and Nissho Iwai Corp. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>New Metway Bank Ltd chairman John Lamble has confirmed, in a letter to shareholders, that an extraordinary meeting will be held next year to approve the issue of an option incentive scheme to new managing director Steve Jones, and a rise in directors' fee to support the greater workload as a result of the merger with Suncorp and the QIDC. The letter also said a name change for the bank was being contemplated. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>An independent Government-appointed planning committee has lodged findings with the relevant Victorian Government Minister, Rob Maclellan, over whether Amcor Ltd can clear company-owned land in Gippsland to establish plantations for its expanded Maryvale aper mill. A decision is expected early next year. Page 21.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE SYDNEY MORNING HERALD</p>
<p>The Advance Bank is concerned that the National Australia Bank has bought a stake of just below five percent in an attempt to agitate against St George Bank's A$2.6 billion takeover offer at Monday's crucial Advance shareholders' meeting. However, with AB unlikely to be able to block the takeover on Monday, it is expected any holding would be used as a launching pad for a legal challenge to the deal early next year. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Bankers Trust Australia, a key John Fairfax Holdings institutional shareholder, has yet to decide whether to vote against Brierley Investment's proposal to purchase the remaining 4.99 percent of Conrad Black's shareholding at an extraordinary shareholder' meeting. BIL needs shareholder approval to move above 19.9 percent of Fairfax under takeover laws. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>AMP Society has written to Communications Minister Richard Alston, opposing Izzy Asper's plan to float Ten Network. The letter, by Australia's biggest institutional shareholder, which owns 6.45 percent of the voting stock in the network's parent Ten Group, was sent as Asper met with Alston to discuss the recent share dealing by Asper's CanWest Global Communications. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Up to seven advertising agencies, including DDB, John Singleton Advertising, and Mojo Partners, are lining up for a slice of the huge Telstra advertising account - valued at A$100 million, the second largest in Australia behind Coles Myer - as the telecomunications giant has placed its entire advertising account under review. Page 25.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A survey conducted by outplacement specialist Davidson &amp; Associates, has found sacked executives and managers are going interstate, and even overseas, to find a job, with some moving between industries. The survey of 6,000 managers between 1992 and 1996,also found the trend towards self-employment has more than doubled in the past five years. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>A survey by accountants Coopers and Lybrand shows NRMA Insurance has moved into top position in the general insurance premium growth stakes, with the number of premiums lifting by 23 per cent to A$1.53 billion in the year to June 30, and a A$70 million profit turnaround. Page 27.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>THE AGE</p>
<p>The Productivity Commission will deliver its draft proposals on the future of car tariffs today, with Mayne Nickless chairman Ian Webber, appointed to the inquiry as an outside expert, expected to deliver a split report dissenting from the views of the in house commissioners Bill Scales and Jeffrey Rae. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The Federal Government is to introduce a credit facility, underwritten by the Commonwealth Bank and Hongkong Bank, to allow Chinese buyers of Australian wool access to a revolving line of credit offering up to A$600 million a year. Other schemes for wheat, iron ore and sugar may also be introduced. Page B1.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>The current account deficit is expected to continue to climb over Christmas with the release of Australian Bureau of Statistics figures that show seasonally adjusted imports have risen in November for the fourth month in a row. Qantas and Ansett contribued to the rise in imports of 1.2 percent to A$6400 million by buying a plane each. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Aussie Homes Loans, the National Australia Bank, and the ANZ Bank have joined together to attack the new consumer credit code, which the companies believe have created chaos in the industry and will end up costing consumers increased fees. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Bryan Grey's Aussie Airlines should pass a major hurdle today, as the airline begins negotiations with Qantas over terminal access. Efforts to reach today talks have gone through two years of legal stalling, with Qantas twice going to court to try to proe Aussie Airlines did not constitute a new player in the domestic airline market. Page B3.</p>
<p>--</p>
<p>Federal Finance Minister John Fahey has announced the Federal Government will finally try to sell its underperforming investment house AIDC. Calling for expressions of interest yesterday, Fahey said he was confident of completing a sale by the end of the next financial year. Page B2.</p>
<p>-- Reuters Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
