<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264095" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Centennial says share suspension unfair.</title>
<headline>Centennial says share suspension unfair.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Centennial City Inc said on Wednesday that a Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) order suspending trading in its shares was unjustified.</p>
<p>The suspension would prejudice the investing public and cause panic to both domestic and foreign investors, a Centennial statement said.</p>
<p>The SEC ordered on Wednesday the suspension of trading in Centennial shares for possible violation of full-disclosure rules in connection with a reclamation project being undertaken along Manila Bay.</p>
<p>The award of the project to the Amari consortium, of which Centennial is a part, was questioned by a Senator saying the government had got a lower price.</p>
<p>Centennial holds 20 percent in the Amari consortium. Thai construction firm Italian-Thai Public Development Plc is one of the partners in the waterfront development.</p>
<p>The SEC said Centennial had not disclosed certain material information regarding the company, including the existence of other apppraisal reports bearing different valuations on the Amari properties.</p>
<p>The SEC said it has set a hearing with Centennial City on Friday for the company to prove why it should not be sanctioned, which may include the revocation of an approval to increase its capital stock. -- Manila newsroom (632) 841-8937</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
