<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264163" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Oman approves 360,000-tonne sugar refinery.</title>
<headline>Oman approves 360,000-tonne sugar refinery.</headline>
<byline>Hilary Gush</byline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Oman has allocated land in the Mina Qaboos port for a sugar refinery with a capacity of 360,000 tonnes a year.</p>
<p>Sugar trader Ali Redha Darwish, one of eight businessmen setting up the $70 million plant, said on Wednesday: &quot;The land has been allocated to us by the Ministry of Communications in the port, so basically it's all systems go now.&quot;</p>
<p>Speaking by telephone from Muscat, Darwish said the final study into the feasibility of the refinery had been completed, and the &quot;results were extremely positive&quot;.</p>
<p>He said 40 percent of the National Sugar Refinery (NSR) would be floated on the Muscat stock exchange once the company had completed its formation, probably in February.</p>
<p>&quot;Sixty percent of the funds are already committed by the original founders,&quot; Darwish said.</p>
<p>After flotation, NSR will start tendering for refinery equipment and construction.</p>
<p>&quot;The basic idea is that the equipment will come from Germany, or Italy or South Africa, or a mix of the three,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The plant, expected to come on stream in late 1998, will compete in the region with Al Khaleej refinery in Dubai, which aims at annual capacity of 720,000 tonnes, and a 500,000-tonne refinery in Saudi Arabia, which is due to start production in early 1997.</p>
<p>But the Arabian peninsula, with annual sugar consumption among the world's highest at an average 30 kg per head, is likely to remain a net importer of refined sugar, brokers say.</p>
<p>They say the six Gulf Arab states and Yemen consume about 1.6 million tonnes annually. Iran is another big consumer, with International Sugar Organisation figures showing consumption of 969,000 tonnes last year.</p>
<p>Brokers have said European exporters will be hardest hit by the new refineries.</p>
<p>Darwish said neighbouring Yemen will be an important market for its sugar, even though the Oman refinery will produce sugar of a higher quality, equivalent to 45 ICUMSA grade, than that which Yemen usually buys 100 ICUMSA.</p>
<p>&quot;Yemen buys a lower quality than this, but there is no harm in buying better quality,&quot; Darwish said.</p>
<p>When asked about the affordability to impoverished Yemen, he said: &quot;The price differential (between the two grades) is not that huge. Right now the price differential is only $8 a tonne and we have the advantage of proximity.&quot; -- Dubai newsroom +9714-626990</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="OMAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
