<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264143" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israel says PLO trade curbs to be met &quot;in kind&quot;.</title>
<headline>Israel says PLO trade curbs to be met &quot;in kind&quot;.</headline>
<dateline>JERUSALEM 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Israel's treasury warned the PLO on Wednesday the Jewish state would respond &quot;in kind&quot; to plans to impose restrictions on foreign-made goods imported by Israeli agents into the self-ruled West Bank and Gaza.</p>
<p>Treasury Director-General David Brodet said at the end of two days of meetings with senior Palestinian economic officials the restrictions -- due to go into effect on January 1 -- were in violation of an Israeli-PLO accord which established a free trade area between the sides.</p>
<p>&quot;Israel will be forced to respond in kind,&quot; the treasury quoted Brodet as telling the meeting. It did not elaborate on what steps Israel would take in response.</p>
<p>Since August Palestinian trade officials have announced a number of trade restrictions to be implemented at the new year, including barring Israeli importers from selling certain brands of vehicles and cigarettes in self-ruled Gaza and the West Bank.</p>
<p>The measures are aimed at bolstering Palestinian firms.</p>
<p>The Treasury said in a statement the Palestinian self-rule Authority (PA) had turned down a request by Brodet to delay implementation of the restrictions.</p>
<p>The PA had no immediate comment.</p>
<p>On Tuesday Palestinian Minister of Trade and Industry Maher al-Masri told Israeli businessmen the trade regulations would be imposed gradually and with flexibility.</p>
<p>The Authority, which took over parts of the West Bank and Gaza under a 1993 self-rule deal, has eased dependence on the Israeli economy, fostering trade with Jordanian and Egyptian firms.</p>
<p>The Wednesday statement said the sides did agree that Israel would transfer to the PA tax revenues levied on Palestinians from May-December 1994.</p>
<p>In return, the PA agreed to pay debts it owed to seven Israeli hospitals, to Bezeq Israel Telecom, and to Israel's Mekorot water utility, the statement said.</p>
<p>The Authority also agreed to reach a formal accord on settling debts between Israeli and Palestinian businesses.</p>
<p>The Federation of Israeli Chambers of Commerce has estimated that Palestinian firms owe companies in the Jewish state hundreds of millions of dollars.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JERUSALEM"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
