<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264104" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippine sugar prices seen sliding due to glut.</title>
<headline>Philippine sugar prices seen sliding due to glut.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippine sugar prices are expected to slide further as the milling season starts this month, officials of the Sugar Regulatory Administration (SRA) said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Local sugar prices are expected to shed 20 pesos from its current price of 500 peso per 50-kilo bag with the start of the milling season this month until February next year, the officials who declined to be identified told reporters.</p>
<p>Domestic sugar was pegged at 750 to 800 pesos per 50-kilo bag early this year.</p>
<p>The officials said they expected some 1.2 million tonnes of sugar to be added to the current inventory of around 400,000 tonnes by March 1997 when the milling season ends.</p>
<p>Sugar industry sources in Hong Kong and China told Reuters on Wednesday that China was facing a similar situation.</p>
<p>China's domestic sugar prices had dipped even lower as the crushing season began full tilt, they said.</p>
<p>Rumours that a cargo of sugar from Thailand and another from Australia totalling about 50,000 tonnes arrived earlier this month at one northern and one southern Chinese port had also weighed on prices, a China-based sugar trader said.</p>
<p>Sugar price weakness in the Chinese market would continue until the middle of February, after the Chinese New Year, but would firm if the government did not allow imports in the first half, a Beijing-based trader said.</p>
<p>In October, the Philippine government imposed a ban on sugar imports until March next year.</p>
<p>-- Dolly Aglay (632) 841-89-36, fax 817-62-67</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
