<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264265" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</title>
<headline>Export Business - Grain/oilseeds complex.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Grain and oilseed exports reported by USDA and private export sources.</p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Philippine firms on Wednesday sought tenders for 35,000 tonnes of U.S. wheat, traders said. Traders said they have received tender invitations for the supply of 28,750 tonnes of dark northern spring wheat and 6,250 tonnes of western white wheat for January 1997 delivery.  </p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Algeria seeks 100,000 tonnes of French, Argentine or U.S. milling wheat, or any combination of the three, for shipment in February and March, European grain traders said. Exporters offers were due Monday, but the tender runs until Thursday, they said.</p>
<p>WHEAT TENDERS - Pakistan issued separate tenders for 270,000 tonnes of U.S. No. 2 or better soft white wheat and Australian white milling wheat for Jan 8-31. Offers are to be opened at 1100 Pakistan Standard Time December 22 and remain valid until 1800 PST December 23. U.S. grain would be under GSM 102. On the same date, it seeks 270,000 tonnes of Australian white milling wheat.  </p>
<p>RICE TENDER - The Japanese Food Agency will hold an import tender for 7,000 tonnes of rice on December 25, agency officials said on Friday.</p>
<p>CORN AND SOYBEAN TENDER - Taiwan importers could hold one tender for 54,000 tonnes of U.S. corn and soybeans this week, Taiwanese traders said.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - The Indian government will release 912,000 tonnes of wheat in January 1997 to its states and union territories for sale under the public distribution system, the United News of India said Wednesday...The European Commission opened the door on Wednesday for the sale of gene-altered maize in the European Union, following the advice of its own experts but defying opposition from consumer and environmental groups.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - The draft limit on vessels navigating the Mississippi River near New Orleans was raised to 42 feet Wednesday and could be increased to a normal level of 46 feet if no problems occur, Coast Guard officials said. Draft restrictions have been in place since Saturday, when a grain freighter lost control and plowed into a waterfront shopping complex near the city's French Quarter.  </p>
<p>MARKET TALK - Mexican grain imports are seen dipping to 5.2 million tonnes in 1997 from the 9.8 million tonnes expected to be brought into the country in 1996 and the 6.4 million tonnes imported in 1995, the National Farm Council (CNA) said Wednesday. In a year-end report, the CNA said grains output is set to rise to 29.3 million tonnes next year from the 28.4 million tonnes produced in this calendar year and the 28.1 million tonne output of 1995, the CNA added.</p>
<p>((CHICAGO NEWSDESK 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
