<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264209" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US condemns Peru hostage-taking, offers assistance.</title>
<headline>US condemns Peru hostage-taking, offers assistance.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States on Wednesday condemned the taking of hundreds of hostages at the Japanese embassy compound in Peru, offering to help but declining to confirm that any Americans were being held.</p>
<p>&quot;We call upon the terrorists who are holding these hostages to release them quickly and safely and unharmed,&quot; State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said. &quot;There can be no justification for this shameful act of violence and terrorism. Our concerns are with the hostages -- who are numerous -- and our concerns are with their families.&quot;</p>
<p>Burns said U.S. Ambassador Dennis Jett and his deputy chief of mission, who was not named, had been at the Lima reception on Tuesday evening. &quot;They left about half an hour before the terrorists took over the compound,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Citing U.S. policy, Burns refused to give any information about Americans who might be among the hostages.</p>
<p>Reports from Lima said as many as 490 people could be being held by the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) guerrillas who stormed the reception in a bid to win the release of jailed comrades.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton was being kept updated on the situation by his national security advisers. He sent messages to Peruvian President Alberto Fujimori and Japanese Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto, the White House said.</p>
<p>Burns and White House spokesman Mike McCurry made public offers of assistance to the Peruvian government, and Burns noted that two task forces had been established -- one at the State Department in Washington and one at the U.S. embassy in Lima -- to field inquiries and offer aid where appropriate.</p>
<p>The United States has been aware of the MRTA group for years, Burns said, adding that it was founded in 1983 and was blamed for an attack at the U.S. embassy in Peru in 1990.</p>
<p>While Burns would not as a matter of policy say whether Americans might be involved in the incident, he noted that about 10,000 U.S. citizens live in Peru.</p>
<p>Burns declined to link the hostage incident to the life imprisonment in Peru of American citizen Lori Berenson, who was convicted by a military court of treason for association with MRTA, a violent group known for attacks and kidnappings.</p>
<p>The State Department has voiced concerns about the circumstances of Berenson's trial, and would have preferred that her case be heard in civil court, and about the conditions of her imprisonment, which Burns called &quot;very harsh&quot;.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
