<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264538" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU says postal liberalisation not before 2003.</title>
<headline>EU says postal liberalisation not before 2003.</headline>
<byline>Suzanne Perry</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Telecommunications Council reached a common position on Wednesday on a plan for opening up postal services to competition that will delay significant liberalisation until at least the year 2003.</p>
<p>The accord represents a victory for France, which had lobbied heavily against setting an early deadline for abolishing state postal monopolies over direct, or &quot;junk&quot;, mail and cross-border mail.</p>
<p>The ministers set a target date of January 1, 2003 for liberalising those two sectors, agreeing to take a formal decision before the start of 2000. Only Sweden, Finland and the Netherlands voted against, EU officials said.</p>
<p>The ministers also agreed that the Commission could use its powers under Article 90 of the EC treaty to open up competition on its own if governments had not done so by the end of 2004.</p>
<p>Industry Commissioner Martin Bangemann called that a &quot;fallback position&quot; that he hoped would put pressure on EU states to curtail the postal monopolies.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a kind of encouragement to member states to be liberal,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>The ministers were under pressure to break a deadlock over the dossier after EU leaders at the weekend Dublin European Council ordered them to strike an accord before the end of 1996. The European Commission had threatened to act on its own to open up postal services in the absence of a deal by then.</p>
<p>The Commission, under pressure from private operators that want to compete with state post offices, had pushed for a shorter liberalisation timetable, proposing in COM(95)227 that direct and cross-border mail be opened up by 2001.</p>
<p>The EU executive argues that the sector has to become more competitive to survive in an era of electronic mail and faxes.</p>
<p>It was supported by Britain, the Netherlands, Denmark, Finland and Sweden.</p>
<p>But France, wary of producing big job losses that could incite further public unrest there, pushed hard for a go-slow approach and won the other countries to its side.</p>
<p>Even Germany, which plans to liberalise its own postal sector, supported Paris out of a sense of solidarity. Those backing France argued that too abrupt liberalisation could lead to a deterioration of public service.</p>
<p>Bangemann acknowledged that the sector is a more sensitive one than telecommunications, where the EU has set a January 1, 1998 deadline for full liberalisation.</p>
<p>&quot;There's much more of a social question,&quot; he said. &quot;They have much more impact on regional services and services citizens actually have first-hand contact with. That's what we've taken account of in today's decision.&quot;</p>
<p>The ministers, whose accord must be approved by the European Parliament before final adoption, agreed without controversy to begin quickly to allow competitors to deliver mail weighing more than 350 grammes and costing more than five times that of a standard letter.</p>
<p>The Commission says that covers only about two percent of all mail carried in the EU. By contrast, direct mail represents about 17 percent of the volume.</p>
<p>The Commission plans to publish a notice outlining how it plans to apply competition rules to the postal sector that will take account of the Council's common position. It originally said it would publish the notice by the end of 1996, but Competition Commissioner Karel Van Miert told a news conference on Wednesday it would now be at the beginning of next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79010">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
