<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264537" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Wife of jailed Peru guerrilla fears for his life.</title>
<headline>Wife of jailed Peru guerrilla fears for his life.</headline>
<dateline>NANTES, France 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The wife of a jailed Peruvian guerrilla leader said on Wednesday she feared for his life after comrades seized at least 200 hostages at the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima to demand his release.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel distressed and I'm awaiting news fearing that it won't be good either from the Japanese embassy or from the prison where my husband is held,&quot; Victor Polay's wife Rosa told Reuters.</p>
<p>She said she feared reprisals from the Pervian authorities and was very worried for her husband's life.</p>
<p>The rebels are threatening to kill their hostages at the residence unless the Peruvian government frees 400 to 500 jailed comrades, including their leader Polay, and gives them safe passage to an Amazon jungle hideout.</p>
<p>Rosa Polay, who has lived with her three children in the western French city of Nantes as a political refugee for seven years, said she was stunned to hear of the action by the Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA).</p>
<p>She said the media had been her only source of information about the hostage-taking. &quot;I never imagined that an operation could be carried out on this scale and now I wonder what the outcome will be,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;The lives of a lot of people are under threat and I also think about my imprisoned husband who risks suffering the consequences of this hostage-taking. I fear reprisals.&quot;</p>
<p>She said she did not want to make &quot;political statements&quot; in exile but she nevertheless saw little hope for her husband and herself unless there was a change of government in Peru.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NANTES, France"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
