<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26452" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>IRAQ: Kurdish group says many Iraq troops quit Arbil.</title>
<headline>Kurdish group says many Iraq troops quit Arbil.</headline>
<byline>Hamdi Istanbullu</byline>
<dateline>ZAKHO, Iraq 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Baghdad has withdrawn many of its troops from the main Kurdish city of Arbil in northern Iraq, an Iraqi-backed Kurdish group said on Sunday.</p>
<p>&quot;About 40,000 Iraqi soldiers had entered. A large portion of that -- more than half of them -- have withdrawn,&quot; Husameddin Mohammed, a senior official for the Kurdistan Democratic Party (KDP) in the northern Iraqi town of Zakho, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Iraqi troops backed by armour and artillery intervened on Saturday in inter-Kurdish fighting in northern Iraq on the side of KDP leader Massoud Barzani to recapture Arbil from Jalal Talabani of the Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (PUK).</p>
<p>&quot;Talabani joined with Iran, and in response, we came closer to Iraq. We got their support,&quot; Mohammed said.</p>
<p>He said Talabani's troops had withdrawn to Sulaimaniya, in the south of the Kurdish-controlled region.</p>
<p>Mohammed said the tanks used in the assault on Arbil -- captured in December 1994 by the PUK -- did not belong to Baghdad, but had been bought from Iraq by the KDP.</p>
<p>Iraq earlier pledged to withdraw from northern Iraq, but has not set a date. Washington expressed scepticism over Iraq's intentions.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton put U.S. troops in the Gulf on high alert after the attack on Arbil. Iraq warned the United States to keep out of its Kurdish north and vowed to turn it into another Vietnam if Washinton intervened.</p>
<p>All was quiet in the towns of Zakho and Dohuk of the Kurdish-controlled northern Iraqi region on Sunday.</p>
<p>KDP officials say they have told the people of Arbil to return to their jobs and continue life as normal.</p>
<p>The two Kurdish factions have a history of bloodshed and shifting alliances with Iraq and Iran. The fighting in Arbil derailed the latest in a series of peace talks, which had been scheduled to take place in London.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDEF">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ZAKHO, Iraq"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="IRAQ"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
