<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264602" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: EU Commission keeps shipbuilding aid ceilings.</title>
<headline>EU Commission keeps shipbuilding aid ceilings.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission decided on Wednesday to maintain EU shipbuilding aid ceilings until the end of 1997, if an international deal to scrap most support to the sector has not come into force before then.</p>
<p>The rules allow for construction aid of nine percent of contract value for large vessels and 4.5 percent for smaller vessels.</p>
<p>The Commission move follows a recent decision by EU industry ministers to prolong the rules of the EU's current shipbuilding aid directive until entry into force of an agreement forged by the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD).</p>
<p>The issue is a problem for the EU because the United States has so far not ratified the 1994 OECD accord to slash the amount of aid which may be granted to shipyards.</p>
<p>&quot;The EU continues to attach great importance to the early entry into force of the OECD agreement and will continue to work with its other OECD partners to encourage the U.S. to complete ratification as soon as possible,&quot; the Commission said.</p>
<p>The Commission said Wednesday's decision was consistent with the aim of the EU directive that there should be a progressive reduction in the level of the aid ceiling, since the extent to which it covers the price/cost gap has decreased.</p>
<p>This is because the gap between construction costs at EU yards and world market prices have widened. So even if the aid ceilings remain unchanged in terms of percentage of the contract value, the relative importance of aid in relation to costs would decline for some ship types, an EU official said.</p>
<p>As soon as the OECD agreement comes into force, the EU's rules will lapse automatically.</p>
<p>The OECD agreement would eliminate all direct shipbuilding subsidies except social aid and, within certain ceilings, aid for research and development.</p>
<p>But the deal, which was originally due to enter into force last January, faces ratification problems in the United States.</p>
<p>The Republican-controlled House of Representatives endorsed it on June 13, but adopted amendments that would delay key sections by 30 months, leading the Clinton administration to warn that the agreement might not be ratified.</p>
<p>U.S. shipyards argue they have not had enough time to adjust to the commercial era after the loss of military contracts at the end of the Cold War.</p>
<p>The EU, which represents about 20 percent of the world shipbuilding market, ratified the OECD agreement in December last year, saying it would help improve market access for its shipyards. -- Brussels Newsroom 32 2 287 6800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
