<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26460" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>LEBANON: Bribery charges sour Beirut's parliamentary poll.</title>
<headline>Bribery charges sour Beirut's parliamentary poll.</headline>
<byline>Haitham Haddadin</byline>
<dateline>BEIRUT 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Allegations of bribery soured voting in Beirut in the third stage of Lebanon's parliamentary elections in which billionaire Prime Minister Rafik al-Hariri hoped to win an overwhelming endorsement.</p>
<p>Witnesses said they saw Hairi representatives bribing voters during Sunday's polling in the capital. Hariri's office accused supporters of rival candidates of making the payments.</p>
<p>The charges were the latest in a series of complaints about electoral malpractices during the month-long elections, which are being held in five regions on five successive Sundays.</p>
<p>Interior Ministry officials said about 30 percent of Beirut's 377,000-strong electorate voted to choose 19 deputies for the 128-seat parliament. Results were expected on Monday.</p>
<p>Hariri, who has been in power since late 1992 and was standing for parliament for the first time, headed a 17-man list of candidates against a 13-member list led by ex-premier Selim Hoss, a well-respected non-partisan politician.</p>
<p>Both men were expected to win easily, but it was unclear how many of the candidates on their rival lists would also be elected. Najah Wakim, a firebrand Christian deputy and a sworn foe of Hariri, headed a separate eight-man list.</p>
<p>Hariri, a 51-year-old tycoon.who won popularity by spearheading Lebanon's reconstruction drive after the 1975-90 civil war, rolled out a powerful election machine in his efforts to secure a wide electoral base.</p>
<p>The bribery allegations followed charges of widespread electoral malpractices during the earlier voting in Mount Lebanon and north Lebanon. People in south Lebanon and the eastern Bekaa valley have yet to vote.</p>
<p>Dozens of voters at a Hariri election office in Beirut told a Reuters reporter they were paid or promised 100,000 Lebanese pounds ($64) each after they swore on the Koran, Islam's holy book, to vote for the prime minister.</p>
<p>The reporter saw Hariri representatives hand out money to a man at the head of a crowd of voters demanding payments for voting for Hariri.</p>
<p>The handouts ended abruptly when a dozen Lebanese soldiers arrived, told the crowd to disperse and seized the cameras of television reporters filming the event.</p>
<p>Hariri's office denied any involvement in bribery, saying supporters of other candidates were posing as Hariri's representatives and paying voters.</p>
<p>Paul Salem , head of the Lebanese Association for Democracy of Elections (LADE), an independent watchdog, said there were hundreds of electoral malpractices during the Beirut voting.</p>
<p>But he said the abuses were not as bad as in polling in Mount Lebanon or north Lebanon when pro-government candidates swept aside all but three opposition candidates.</p>
<p>Salem and opposition candidates said electoral lists were manipulated on Sunday, opposition delegates were barred from monitoring the vote at some stations and the Interior Ministry illegally gave stamped voting envelopes to Hariri's campaign team.</p>
<p>Interior Minister Michel el-Murr said judicial authorities were investigating the allegations concerning the envelopes.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LEBAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BEIRUT"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LEBANON"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
