<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264719" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>PAKISTAN: Pakistan sees hard times ahead after IMF accord.</title>
<headline>Pakistan sees hard times ahead after IMF accord.</headline>
<byline>Ovais Subhani</byline>
<dateline>KARACHI, Pakistan 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pakistan will have a tough time sticking to targets agreed with the International Monetary Fund, which is likely to suspend the lending programme if any slippage occurs, analysts said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;Pakistan will find it difficult to relax as the IMF will now be monitoring Pakistan on a monthly basis with monthly targets,&quot; analyst Amir Peracha of ING Baring Securities said.</p>
<p>The IMF said on Tuesday it was resuming lending to Pakistan with an extended and expanded stand-by credit.</p>
<p>An IMF statement said it had agreed to Pakistan's request to extend a stalled $600 million standby loan to September from March and to increase it by $231 million.</p>
<p>Analysts said the loan re-activation was a victory for the caretaker government of Prime Minister Meraj Khalid installed on November 5 after the dismissal of the government of Benazir Bhutto on disputed charges of misrule and corruption.</p>
<p>But most were uncertain if the next government would be able to meet ambitious IMF-set targets after February 3 elections.</p>
<p>Peracha said the IMF remained sceptical on Pakistan's economic performance.</p>
<p>He said the loan had been reactivated on the basis of 1996/97 macro-economic targets that include total revenue collection of 368 billion rupees, a build-up of forex reserves to $1.6 billion or equivalent to 6.4 weeks of imports, slashing bank borrowing from around 70 billion to 61 billion rupees and a budget deficit target of four percent of gross domestic product (GDP).</p>
<p>&quot;Under the commitments given to the IMF the government has proposed further budgetary cuts to ease pressure on borrowing, interest rate increases to slow down the economy, tax increases to improve the tax/GDP ratio and further rupee depreciation to boost exports,&quot; Peracha said.</p>
<p>There was no official confirmation that these were the targets contained in the latest agreement with the IMF.</p>
<p>Abid Naqvi, research head at Taurus Securities, said meeting the deficit target would require a &quot;Herculean fiscal effort&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Since the present government will not exist beyond February, the new political government will have to meet this ambitious commitment,&quot; Naqvi said.</p>
<p>Failure at the first quarterly review after disbursement of the second tranche would trigger another suspension, he said.</p>
<p>Uncertainty on the fate of the agreement coupled with the IMF decision to release only two $80 million tranches before the first review expected in February depressed the Karachi Stock Exchange, where the 100-share index dropped 13.54 points, or 0.97 percent, to 1,382.21 points at the close on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The caretaker government said earlier it was hoping to get at least $160 million of the standby loan up-front.</p>
<p>&quot;This shows that while international creditors support the general direction of measures being taken, they are unconvinced that the next elected government will deliver on the commitments that the caretakers are promising,&quot; Naqvi said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KARACHI, Pakistan"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PAKISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
