<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26479" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>SYRIA: Iraqi Shi'ite opposition condemn attack on Arbil.</title>
<headline>Iraqi Shi'ite opposition condemn attack on Arbil.</headline>
<dateline>DAMASCUS 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>An Iraqi Shi'ite Moslem opposition leader on Sunday condemned an Iraqi attack on Arbil, the Kurdish stronghold in northern Iraq, and urged the United Nations to oust Baghdad forces from the Kurdish area.</p>
<p>Ayatullah Mohammed Taki Mudarisi, head of the Islamic Action group, said in a statement in Damascus the regime of Iraqi President Saddam Hussein &quot;will always be a source of tension and anxiety for the Iraqis and peoples of the region&quot;.</p>
<p>&quot;Northern iraq should be kept as a safe haven for the Kurdish people according to the decisions implemented after the (1991) Gulf War, and the Security Council should take the initiative to oust the forces of Saddam from this region,&quot; Mudarisi said.</p>
<p>Iraqi troops and tanks supporting Kurdish rebel faction of Masoud Barzani stormed Arbil on Saturday, ousting rival rebel faction of Jalal Talabani.</p>
<p>Iraq has announced it would withdraw its forces from the region which the United States, Britain and France declared an exclusion zone shortly after the 1991 Gulf War.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DAMASCUS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SYRIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
