<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264707" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>AFGHANISTAN: Three contenders to build Afghan pipelines.</title>
<headline>Three contenders to build Afghan pipelines.</headline>
<byline>Tim Johnston</byline>
<dateline>KABUL 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Taleban official in Kabul said on Wednesday there are three contenders to build multi-billion dollar oil and gas pipelines through war-ravaged Afghanistan to Pakistan.</p>
<p>The pipelines would start in the neighbouring former Soviet republic of Turkmenistan.</p>
<p>Mullah Sher Abbas Stanakzai, acting deputy foreign minister in the Taleban administration, told Reuters the three contenders were a consortium of Unocal of the United States and Delta Oil of Saudi Arabia, Daewoo of South Korea, and Bridas of Argentina.</p>
<p>He said that no contract had yet been signed.</p>
<p>&quot;We have not finalised which company is to build the pipeline. We will see which company takes the initiative and who can fulfil the contract,&quot; Stanakzai said.</p>
<p>He said that the Unocal/Delta consortium had agreed to set up an office in the southern Afghan city of Kandahar, where the Taleban are based, and start a survey.</p>
<p>The Taleban, whose Islamic warriors swept into the Afghan capital on September 27, have agreed in principle to the pipelines going ahead.</p>
<p>&quot;In principle we are ready for the pipeline and we want it to go through Afghanistan,&quot; according to Stanakzai.</p>
<p>The proposed pipelines will run from the gas oil and gas fields of Turkmenistan to the Sui gas fields in Pakistan. The proposed route runs close to the Taleban-held city of Herat, which is itself close to a bitterly contested front line between the Taleban and the opposition.</p>
<p>The Taleban currently control almost 75 per cent of the country, including all the territory through which the pipelines are expected to pass.</p>
<p>However, their administration has yet to be recognised as the legitimate government of Afghanistan, and the country is still represented by members of the ousted administration of President Burhanuddin Rabbani on most international bodies.</p>
<p>The Taleban have vowed to take the rest of the country and impose their strict vision of Islamic law on the entire nation.</p>
<p>The proposed route for the pipelines runs close to the road between the Pakistani border near Quetta and the Turkmen border in the north of the country.</p>
<p>The road has suffered extensive damage during the 17-year-old civil war in Afghanistan. Stanakzai said a contract to repair the road was expected to get under way in the near future.</p>
<p>He said the Pakistani government was a partner in the contract.</p>
<p>&quot;A contract was signed between the Afghan government and the Pakistani government a few months back. Pakistan was supposed to deliver some equipment and some money to repair the road.</p>
<p>&quot;I think that within a few days our side will receive the equipment from Pakistan and soon we will start to repair the road.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AFGH">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SKOREA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TURKM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I13000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I1300002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C33">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KABUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AFGHANISTAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
