<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264977" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French stocks close up, supported by Wall Street.</title>
<headline>French stocks close up, supported by Wall Street.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>French shares closed higher on Wednesday, supported by strength on Wall Street, and traders were moderately hopeful about further progress.</p>
<p>&quot;If New York finishes higher, if the dollar holds steady in around 5.25 francs and rates stay steady, we have the grounds to move a bit higher,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>Erasing Tuesday's losses, the blue-chip CAC-40 index finished up 25.19 points or 1.15 percent at 2,218.89 while the CAC-40 futures settled at 2,221.0 against 2,195 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>Volume totalled 6.1 billion francs.</p>
<p>Insurer Axa climbed 1.54 percent to 309.50 francs after the expiry of its share exchange offer for rival UAP. The companies announced a new executive lineup for the merged group bearing Axa's stamp with 10 of the 16 members of the executive committee from Axa.</p>
<p>Shares in luxury goods group LVMH soared 8.37 percent to 1,375 francs after a U.S. arbitrator cleared its bid to buy U.S. duty free chain DFS. LVMH forecast the deal would boost operating profits by some 30 percent.</p>
<p>Bank Credit National climbed 7.5 percent on a press report speculating it could be bid target, saying its share price was undervalued. But analysts were uncertain about who might bid.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
