<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="264999" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FINLAND: FINNISH PENSION FUND EQUITY INVESTMENT SEEN RISING.</title>
<headline>FINNISH PENSION FUND EQUITY INVESTMENT SEEN RISING.</headline>
<byline>Veera Heinonen</byline>
<dateline>HELSINKI 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Proposed changes to rules governing Finland's employment pension funds, due to take effect in 1997, look set to liberate substantial funds which could boost trade and curb volatility on the small Helsinki bourse.</p>
<p>Finland plans to relax pension funds' stringent yield requirements, enabling them to increase their solvency capital and to venture into riskier sectors -- like equities.</p>
<p>A committee chaired by pension insurer Ilmarinen's CEO Kari Puro has proposed a longer-term total reform of the system, including a near-term change to let pension funds boost capital without raising pension contributions.</p>
<p>It has proposed that pension insurers' minimum required rate of return on investment be lowered to about 5.5 percent in 1997 from six percent now, while the rate at which funds are allocated to future pensions temporarily cut to three percent.</p>
<p>Later that would return to match the return requirement.</p>
<p>The temporary 2.5 percentage point difference between the funding rate and the required return would be in force for two to three years, so pension insurers' solvency capital would be boosted to work as a buffer for increased portfolio volatility.</p>
<p>Pirkko Alitalo, investment director at insurer Vakuutusosakeyhtio Pohjola , said the plan would enable work pension funds to roughly double within five years their investments in equities, from about seven percent of their current portfolios.</p>
<p>&quot;The goal of the proposal is to double employment pension companies' present solvency capital of about seven billion markka within the next couple of years,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>&quot;This would improve the companies' risk-carrying capacity to the extent that they would be able to double their stock market investments in about five years,&quot; she added.</p>
<p>She said it was impossible to give a figure, but most of the new liquidity would probably flow to the Helsinki bourse.</p>
<p>NEW LIQUIDITY TO REDUCE FLUCTUATIONS</p>
<p>&quot;The clue of the whole reform is that pension contributions would decrease and they (work pension funds) would get more profits from their investments,&quot; said Jukka Huuskonen at Arctos Securities.</p>
<p>Last year, investments by Finnish work pension companies totalled 124 billion markka, of which shares accounted for seven percent or 9.5 billion markka. That compares with around nine percent in Sweden and 16.3 percent in Denmark.</p>
<p>Shareholdings relative to the Helsinki bourse's market capitalisation -- 273 billion markka at end-November -- average about four percent.</p>
<p>The target is to double pension funds' equity investments, so about 10 billion markka could flow into stocks over five years triggering a potential annual inflow of some two billion markka of new liquidity to the Helsinki stock exchange.</p>
<p>For Helsinki, where daily trading volumes typically average 390 million markka, that is a significant sum, analysts say.</p>
<p>&quot;Two billion markka is a considerable amount of money, it would certainly bring a buffer (against volatility) and more stability,&quot; said Jukka Huuskonen analyst at Arctos.</p>
<p>&quot;The new flow of liquidity would also rationalise the pricing of shares,&quot; said Matti Ahokas market analyst at Postipankki.</p>
<p>HELSINKI BOURSE NOT ONLY GAINER</p>
<p>Although analysts expect the bulk of the extra funds to target equities rather than bonds, they note it is unlikely that Helsinki-listed companies will be the sole beneficiaries.</p>
<p>&quot;The problem is that big investors are already heavily invested in the large companies,&quot; Huuskonen said.</p>
<p>Investors could start seeking alternative investments among small and medium sized companies on the OTC- and Brokers' lists.</p>
<p>&quot;The new liquidity would not be channelled only to the Helsinki bourse, small and medium sized companies would also get their share,&quot; Postipankki's Ahokas said.</p>
<p>Some of the money could be widely dispersed abroad, particularly if the single European currency becomes reality in the next millenium.</p>
<p>&quot;A wide single market area would add new exchange-rate risk-free investment objects to the domestic offerings,&quot; Pertti Pylkkonen, economist at the Bank of Finland wrote in October.</p>
<p>&quot;The risks associated with securities investments would be easier to spread more widely than is possible in the Finnish capital markets alone,&quot; Pylkkonen added.</p>
<p>The Puro proposal was approved by parliament on December 17 and is scheduled to take force at the start of 1997.</p>
<p>-- Helsinki newsroom + 358 - 9 - 680 50 240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FIN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81502">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150214">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HELSINKI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FINLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
