<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265175" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Israeli shekel rises against dollar and basket.</title>
<headline>Israeli shekel rises against dollar and basket.</headline>
<dateline>TEL AVIV 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Israeli shekel rose moderately against the dollar and the basket of key foreign currencies on Wednesday despite the rise of the dollar overseas, dealers said.</p>
<p>&quot;Activity was low today and the session opened with a rise of the shekel. When the dollar fell to 3.2730 shekels investors started buying dollars and the U.S. currency recovered,&quot; said one dealer.</p>
<p>&quot;The dollar is stabilizing at a range of 3.27 to 3.29 shekels. It now appears that the dollar will not rise against shekel before the end of the year because investors expect a minimal (interest) rate cut of only 0.3 percentage point in December,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The Bank of Israel is due to decide on January interest rates next week. The current base rate is 15.2 percent.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rise of the dollar in Europe had no impact on local trading.</p>
<p>The representative rate for the dollar was fixed at 3.2770 shekels against 3.2800 shekels on Tuesday. The basket composed of the dollar, mark, pound sterling, French franc and yen, was fixed at 3.6612 shekels against 3.6648 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>On the crosses the shekel traded against the yen at 2.8839 shekels per 100 yen against 2.8792 on Tuesday and against the mark at 2.1107 shekels against 2.1178 on Tuesday.</p>
<p>In late afternoon the dollar continued to trade at 3.2760 shekels.</p>
<p>(See page ILS= for latest commercial bank shekel/dollar rates, ILS1= for a list of commercial bank shekel/dollar rates, ILS2 for a list of commercial bank shekel/basket rates. Bank of Israel announcements appear on BOIJ).</p>
<p>- Dan Gerstenfeld, Tel Aviv newsroom, 972-3-537-2211</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TEL AVIV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
