<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265286" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS-EU rejects calls to end tobacco subsidies.</title>
<headline>FOCUS-EU rejects calls to end tobacco subsidies.</headline>
<byline>Suzanne Perry</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission refused on Wednesday to seek an end to European Union tobacco production subsidies, saying it was not prepared to put 200,000 tobacco-related workers out of jobs.</p>
<p>Despite criticism that the subsidies compromise the EU's efforts to curb smoking-related deaths, the Commission said it preferred to reform the programme by targeting aid to higher quality tobacco and paying growers who quit the sector.</p>
<p>&quot;Given that approximately 77 percent of tobacco consumed in the EU is imported, the regime's abolition would merely lead to 100 percent of EU tobacco demand being met by imports,&quot; it said in a statement.</p>
<p>Health and Social Affairs Commissioner Padraig Flynn, who waged an unsuccessful campaign to phase out the more than $1 billion in annual subsidies, told a news conference he was unhappy with the decision, calling smoking the biggest single preventable cause of death in the EU.</p>
<p>But he won support from the Commission for a separate report outlining options EU governments should consider implementing to curb smoking and its damaging health effects.</p>
<p>These included strengthening cigarette label warnings, reducing the tar and nicotine content of cigarettes, regulating additives and agreeing a code of practice on children's right to a smoke-free environment.</p>
<p>It said governments should also consider increasing taxes on tobacco and restricting access of young people to cigarettes.</p>
<p>The package, while not including specific legislative proposals, was condemned by Europe's tobacco industry.</p>
<p>&quot;The Commission is proposing measures which would be costly to implement and which would limit consumers' choice without offering any evidence that they are either necessary or will achieve the desired effect,&quot; Robert Toet, chairman of the Confederation of European Community Cigarette Manufacturers (CECCM), said in a statement.</p>
<p>The group said the Commission had disregarded the interests of a sector employing 1.5 million people and generating 52 billion Ecus ($64.5 billion) in annual tax revenue in the EU.</p>
<p>The Association of European Cancer Leagues expressed disappointment, on the other hand, that the proposals did not include stronger measures such as requiring all cigarettes to be sold in plain generic packages.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a stepping stone in the right direction, but it doesn't go anywhere near as far as we would have preferred,&quot; Andrew Hayes, the group's EU liaison officer, said.</p>
<p>The EU already has rules requiring tobacco product labels to carry health warnings, banning television tobacco advertising and limiting the tar content of cigarettes. But the Commission has so far been unsuccessful in getting EU ministers to adopt a total ban on tobacco advertising.</p>
<p>Flynn said the Commission would submit new anti-smoking legislative proposals only if it won support after consulting interested parties.</p>
<p>The proposed tobacco subsidy reforms, which must be approved by EU ministers, include a doubling of the one percent levy on tobacco subsidies that is used to finance an EU tobacco public health programme.</p>
<p>Agriculture Commissioner Franz Fischler said the Commission had no choice but to continue aiding farmers who had no way to diversify since their plantations were on average barely more than one hectare.</p>
<p>Eight EU countries produce tobacco, but 76 percent of the production comes from Italy and Greece. Much of it is low-quality tobbaco that is exported to third countries.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100145">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G153">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
