<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265345" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: French Communists open renewal congress.</title>
<headline>French Communists open renewal congress.</headline>
<byline>Paul Taylor</byline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>France's Communist Party began its first post-Marchais congress on Wednesday seeking to cast off the remains of its Stalinist past and set out a credible left-wing alternative to the opposition Socialists.</p>
<p>A central issue of the five-day congress is the Communists' attitude towards a future single European currency, which may determine whether they can join a broad left alliance for the 1998 general election.</p>
<p>For the first time since the 1950s, veteran former leader Georges Marchais was not attending. Marchais, 76, who announced recently he would retire from the politburo at this 29th party congress, was recovering from a heart attack last week.</p>
<p>His handpicked successor, Robert Hue, who took over from Marchais as national secretary in 1994, has worked hard to transform the party, which still claims 300,000 members.</p>
<p>He has jettisoned the remnants of &quot;democratic centralism&quot;, accepted the principle of the market economy and belatedly acknowledged that, contrary to Marchais's dictum, Soviet communism was not &quot;globally positive&quot;.</p>
<p>The jovial, rotund Hue, a familar figure with his cropped beard and round spectacles, has also succeeded in halting the Communists' electoral decline. He won 8.6 percent in last year's presidential election.</p>
<p>An independent CSA poll published on Wednesday said nine percent of voters would cast their ballot for a Communist candidate, and another 17 percent would not rule it out.</p>
<p>For the first time, the policy document to be approved by the congress was drafted in conjunction with grassroots party cells and the congress will vote on amendments offered by both liberals and hardliners.</p>
<p>The key test will be the Communists' position on a single European currency.</p>
<p>Hue has demanded a referendum before France joins monetary union, but hardliners have put down amendments condemning the euro. That would make it harder for the party to team up with the Socialists if the Left wins the 1998 general election.</p>
<p>In his first inaugural speech as national secretary, Hue called on the Communists to &quot;rise to their responsibilities&quot; and be willing to join a Socialist-led government in 1998 on the basis of a common platform.</p>
<p>&quot;Important differences remain between us on the question of money and of the single currency. Above all the Socialist Party persists in its old approach of ignoring pluralism by presenting its own programme as representing 'the Left',&quot; Hue said. &quot;We are not resigned to this situation. We want unity.&quot;</p>
<p>He added: &quot;Our party has a duty to participate in government to ensure the implementation of a policy of change. We consider the action of Communist elected officials -- and of possible Communist ministers -- will relay citizens' demands to France's institutions and rulers.&quot;</p>
<p>The Communisty party had four ministers in a Socialist-led government formed by the late president Francois Mitterrand in 1981, which carried out sweeping nationalisations. It withdrew in 1984, accusing Mitterrand of betraying the Left.</p>
<p>Hue warned Communists against the temptation of joining a &quot;radical pole&quot; -- including ecologists, Trotskyists and leftist pressure-groups -- to the left of the Socialist party.</p>
<p>&quot;This approach contains the risk, albeit involuntary, of dividing people more than it unites them,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>In one sign of the times, the general-secretary of the Communist-dominated CGT trade union, Louis Viannet, is to give up his seat on the politburo, renamed the national bureau, although he will remain on the central committee.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
