<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265305" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: FOCUS - Clabecq rescue plan rejected - radio.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - Clabecq rescue plan rejected - radio.</headline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The European Commission has rejected a rescue plan for Forges de Clabecq, in essence condemning the ailing Belgian steel firm to bankruptcy and a possible re-start in a slimmed-down form.</p>
<p>Belgian radio BRTN, quoting Belgian news agency Belga, said on Wednesday the decision had been taken, but gave no details.</p>
<p>Belga said the Commission had ruled the 1.5 billion franc plan broke European Union rules on aid for the steel industry. It would demand the company pay back 700 million francs in advances already received within two months.</p>
<p>Analysts said this sounded the deathknell for the bourse-listed steel firm, which has been struggling to survive in a volatile market marked by overcapacity and has failed to find a partner to improve its competitive position.</p>
<p>&quot;This is the end for Clabecq, it seems neither of the other two steel companies (Dutch Hoogovens and Belgian Usines Gustave Boel) are interested in taking over any part of Clabecq,&quot; said steel analyst Patrik Geldermans at Kredietbank.</p>
<p>Instead, Hoogovens is taking a 50 percent stake in UGB. It says UGB's activities complement its own business better.</p>
<p>Analysts have said the firm was saddled with high labour and product costs, poor operational margins and low-quality products.</p>
<p>In slimmed-down form, with debts restructured, Clabecq might re-start, but not without a severe impact on 1,700 people directly employed at Clabecq and on the 3,500 whose jobs are linked to the steel firm, they said.</p>
<p>Clabecq workers plan to demonstrate outside the European Parliament building in Brussels on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The European Commission noted that under the plan Clabecq was only receiving regional government aid without calls being made on its private shareholders.</p>
<p>Belgium's southern region of Wallonia owns a large majority in Clabecq and under the plan would be the only provider of aid for the company.</p>
<p>Quoting Commission sources Belga said the company was being aided at a time when, technically, it was already bankrupt. The Commission had strong doubts about the viability of the company, even if large amounts of cash were invested, in view of the overcapacity in its market.</p>
<p>The Brussels bourse said shares in Clabecq would trade as normal. &quot;There will be no suspension of Clabecq shares,&quot; a bourse source said.</p>
<p>Clabecq closed at 91 francs on Tuesday, but indicative bid and ask prices on Wednesday were sharply lower at 20 francs at 0940 GMT. The share has been falling steadily since June when it was at 380 francs.</p>
<p>Indicating the trouble the firm is in, its book value per share stands at a negative 850 francs. By contrast, Belgium's largest steel firm profitable Cockerill Sambre has BVPS of 980 francs.</p>
<p>Clabecq stock is traded on the cash market where shares are normally subjected to two price fixings a day. But the bourse has imposed a 10 percent maximum markdown per day after an excess of sellers.</p>
<p>-- Brussels Newsroom +32 2 287 6810, Fax +32 2 230 7710</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G157">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
