<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265467" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: 2,000 Polish workers march to demand govt action.</title>
<headline>2,000 Polish workers march to demand govt action.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>About 2,000 Solidarity trade union members marched in Warsaw on Wednesday to demand more backing from Poland's leftist government for workers' jobs.</p>
<p>The protesters, chanting &quot;Down with Commies (communists)&quot; and &quot;We want work&quot;, hurled firecrackers and paint jars at the government headquarters, smashing windows and smudging the refurbished building with red, eyewitness said.</p>
<p>Police looked on but did not intervene.</p>
<p>Among the protesters were workers from the energy sector, the bankrupt Gdansk shipyard, the Ursus tractor factory, coal miners and employees of the Swidnik aircraft plant.</p>
<p>The shipyard workers want the government to extend credit guarantees so that the bankrupt enterprise can finance an order for the construction of five ships from a German shipowner.</p>
<p>The crucial loan, of between $120 and $150 million, would keep part of the yard's 5,000-strong workforce busy building the vessels while the government and management find an investor to save the business. @</p>
<p>The shipyard has operated under bankruptcy regulations since August with debts of 415 million zlotys ($148 million).</p>
<p>The left-wing government of the Democratic Left Alliance (SLD) and the Polish Peasant Party (PSL) has said it would guarantee the loan if the yard found a bank to give the credit.</p>
<p>Workers of the Swidnik aircraft factory want the government to buy at least 10 of its &quot;Sokol&quot; helicopters.</p>
<p>Energy sector workers demand the abolition of energy price differences depending on the region of the country and also protest against third-party access to the energy industry, now monopolised by the state-owned PSE energy distribution firm.</p>
<p>The protesters handed petitions to government and parliament representatives.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C42">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
