<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265520" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: FOCUS - BA seeks to end rocky USAir ties.</title>
<headline>FOCUS - BA seeks to end rocky USAir ties.</headline>
<byline>Tony Roddam</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>British Airways Plc said on Wednesday it planned to sell all of its shares in USAir, bringing their troubled three-year relationship to a close as it prepares for a strategic alliance with another U.S. carrier, American Airlines.</p>
<p>BA said in a statement it would offer its stake, currently at 24.6 percent, to USAir and its three directors on USAir's board would resign once the share sale was completed.</p>
<p>&quot;British Airways has taken this action with regret. But it has become inevitable. It would clearly be unwise to pursue an alliance with an unwilling partner,&quot; chief executive officer Bob Ayling said in the statement.</p>
<p>BA's link with USAir, which included a code-sharing deal and cooperation on frequent flier programmes, has been overshadowed by the British airline's proposed alliance with American Airlines, a bitter rival to USAir.</p>
<p>Incensed by BA's planned linkup with American, USAir is suing BA in a U.S. federal court and has said it would end its code-sharing pact early next year.</p>
<p>Airlines worldwide have rushed to strike low-cost code-sharing alliances, notably to tie up the lucrative U.S. market and transatlantic routes. BA said earlier this year its link with USAir generated around 70 million pounds ($117 million) annually in additional operating profits.</p>
<p>But code-sharing, which enables carriers to extend their reach to destinations too expensive to serve with their own networks, has often generated friction as different corporate cultures are thrown together and new rivalries generated.</p>
<p>Ayling said the decision to shed the USAir stake was not related to the lawsuit, which he said British Airways still believed was groundless. A spokesman for the airline said American Airlines had not pressured BA into the move.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a British Airways decision alone,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>BA, which said it paid $400 million for the 24.6 percent stake in 1993, did not disclose the price it would offer USAir for the shares. The U.S. airline has 60 days to decide whether to accept. After that period, BA is free to sell the stake by private transaction or by public offering.</p>
<p>British Airways shares in London leapt on the news of the proposed share sale, rising 11-1/2p to 603p in early dealing although dealers warned momentum was likely to fade.</p>
<p>&quot;The shares have had a good run...People figured British Airways was going to do it some time and from the looks of things the sale will only make a small profit,&quot; one said.</p>
<p>--London Newsroom +44 171 542 4367 ($1=.6003 Pound)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I75000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
