<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26551" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Wall Street braces for July redux.</title>
<headline>Wall Street braces for July redux.</headline>
<byline>Richard Melville</byline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wall Street braces for a critical test this week, with markets sharply focused on a report many feel will dictate near-term interest rate policy.</p>
<p>On Friday, the Labour Department will report August employment figures, which include the nation's unemployment rate, new payrolls and average hourly earnings growth.</p>
<p>&quot;The key to the week is Friday,&quot; said Philip Orlando, chief investment officer at Value Line Asset Management. &quot;The employment report is one of the last pieces of key data the Fed will see before its Sept. 20 meeting.&quot;</p>
<p>Markets will be closed Monday for Labour Day and September's first session Tuesday brings the closely watched National Association of Purchasing Management index.</p>
<p>A robust regional report in the Chicago index on Friday triggered a sharp bond market sell-off and put analysts on alert for a strong NAPM reading.</p>
<p>However, the upcoming employment report carries extra baggage because of the shock wave it sent through markets in July, when stunning increases in payrolls and hourly earnings raised the specter of wage-driven inflation and stoked fears of a Federal Reserve move on interest rates.</p>
<p>A month's worth of tame economic data had seemingly quelled the jitters and most of August saw a somnolent market content to bide its time until the fall.</p>
<p>But late last week, a hefty upward revision to second-quarter Gross Domestic Product and the Chicago manufacturing index awakened slumbering bears and sent the Dow on a 95-point two-day slide, dashing hopes for new highs.</p>
<p>&quot;There are a lot of people who thought the bull market had another strong leg in it,&quot; said Robert Stovall, president of Stovall/21st Advisors. &quot;The bulls are definitely on the defensive now.&quot;</p>
<p>Many are now convinced the Fed needs little prodding to pull the trigger this month, in contrast to just weeks ago, when most counted on steady rates through the elections.</p>
<p>&quot;Because the data has been so strong, you might say the markets are making the Fed's decision for it,&quot; Stovall said. At this point it could be viewed as political if they didn't raise rates.&quot;</p>
<p>One buffer could be in place, because unlike two months ago, when the jobs data hit an unsuspecting market, this time the Dow has sold off ahead of the report, while the Nasdaq Composite has yet to recover from July's correction.</p>
<p>&quot;In May and June people were still not afraid of the market,&quot; said Marshall Acuff, portfolio strategist at Smith Barney. &quot;It could be that people have gotten so cautious that (a strong report) is priced in already.&quot;</p>
<p>However, as Acuff noted, timing may exacerbate the outcome because &quot;September and October traditionally have not been particularly good months for the market.&quot;</p>
<p>Also, analysts noted, a further potential threat looms at just about this point in the corporate third quarter.</p>
<p>&quot;You now have a double-edged sword with concerns about an over-heated economy around the same time you might expect to start getting cautionary comments about earnings,&quot; Orlando said. &quot;Those two events in conjunction may serve to roil the market at a time when it seems of a bent to correct.&quot;</p>
<p>Economists forecast a 244,000 increase in payrolls and a 0.3 percent rise in average hourly wages. Unemployment is expected to fall to 5.3 percent from 5.4 percent.</p>
<p>The August NAPM index is expected to rise to 52.9 from 50.2 in July. Any reading above 50 indicates an expanding manufacturing sector and some economists have raised their forecasts in light of the almost unheard of 60.0 reading in the Chicago index last Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
