<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265677" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia Rating Corp assigns AAA to Cagamas.</title>
<headline>Malaysia Rating Corp assigns AAA to Cagamas.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian Rating Corp Bhd (MARC) said on Wednesday it has assigned a AAA long-term issuer rating to national mortgage corporation, Cagamas Bhd.</p>
<p>In a statement, MARC said it has also assigned Cagamas with a short-term rating of MARC-1.  </p>
<p>The ratings apply to all outstanding long- and short-term debt securities issued by Cagamas, the rating agency said.</p>
<p>The ratings &quot;reflect its strategic role in the financial system, strong shareholder support, excellent portfolio quality, prudent asset and liability management policies and strong earnings and internal capital generation capacity,&quot; MARC said.</p>
<p>The AAA rating indicates that the ability to repay principal and pay interest on a timely basis is &quot;extremely high&quot;, MARC said.  </p>
<p>It added that the short-term MARC-1 rating, the highest rating issued by the agency, indicated a &quot;very high likelihood&quot; that principal and interest will be paid on a timely basis.</p>
<p>Cagamas is the sole issuer of debt securities for the purpose of funding the purchase of mortgages. It was established with the aim of promoting development of a secondary mortgage market in Malaysia.</p>
<p>Its key shareholder is the central bank, Bank Negara Malaysia, with a 20 percent stake, while the rest of the equity is divided amongst other financial institutions.  </p>
<p>Nearly 99 percent of Cagamas' assets are mortgage-purchased.</p>
<p>The balance are invested in government-issued papers and private debt securities -- which are bank guaranteed and/or AAA rated -- or in other high quality assets, MARC said.</p>
<p>MARC is the country's second rating agency after Rating Agency Malaysia Bhd.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81501">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I8150103">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C174">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
