<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265633" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>SINGAPORE: Vietnam coffee trade slows ahead of Christmas.</title>
<headline>Vietnam coffee trade slows ahead of Christmas.</headline>
<byline>Rene Pastor</byline>
<dateline>SINGAPORE 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Trading in Vietnam's robusta coffee appears to be slowing ahead of the Christmas holiday period and while the Indonesian crop is over for 1996 next year's crop, due to arrive in the market early in 1997, is looking promising, regional traders said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There's not much physical business going on now. Most of the traders are trying to get their shipments out before Christmas,&quot; a senior dealer for a European commodity house said.  </p>
<p>The market will be very quiet next week as markets in London and New York shut down while the majority of traders in Europe and the U.S. go on long holidays, dampening business sentiment across the board, the traders said.</p>
<p>Concerns in the trade about mould affecting part of Vietnam's robusta crop lingered among some dealers. The country is the second largest producer of robusta beans in Asia after Indonesia.  </p>
<p>One trader said fears over mould increased in November after heavier-than-expected rains pounded Dak Lak province, which produces about two-thirds of the estimated 250,000 tonnes of robusta beans Vietnam exports each year.</p>
<p>&quot;This will only be settled after we hear from the roasters after Christmas. That's when you'll possibly hear of any moans or groans,&quot; the dealer said.</p>
<p>But the chief coffee dealer of another European trading house said the reports have been exaggerated.  </p>
<p>&quot;We have not had any call backs (from the roasters),&quot; the trader said. &quot;The mould issue is overcooked, overdone and oversold.&quot;</p>
<p>Vietnam's state coffee corporation, Vinacafe, said last week the reports about mould were false while urging local producers to focus on quality.</p>
<p>Total coffee exports from Vietnam in December will probably reach 30,000 tonnes, almost unchanged from the same month last year, the traders said.  </p>
<p>Vietnam's benchmark Grade 2 coffee was being quoted by regional dealers at around US$930-950 a tonne FOB Saigon port for nearby shipment against last week's price of around $950-$970 a tonne FOB.</p>
<p>The Indonesian coffee crop, on the other hand, appears to be in fine shape with heavy rains helping the development of the crop, which is due to begin in earnest in March, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's coming along fine,&quot; a trader said. &quot;The rains have been good for the crop.&quot;  </p>
<p>Indonesia's Grade 4 coffee was priced at around $1,150-$1,180 a tonne FOB Panjang, slightly lower than last week's quote of around $1,150-$1,200 a tonne FOB Panjang, traders said.</p>
<p>LIFFE futures may open lower with front-month January expected to test the floor of $1,300 a tonne. The January contract fell $14 to close at $1,314 a tonne.</p>
<p>&quot;It's due about $10 lower. The short-term floor is around $1,300,&quot; one dealer said. &quot;The market took a real pounding last night.&quot;  </p>
<p>Active cross-trading and shortcovering perked up the normally moribund coffee market on the Singapore Commodity Exchange (SICOM), traders said.</p>
<p>Some 4,000 tonnes were traded in the front-month January, second position March and third-position May contracts compared to the usual average of less than 50 tonnes a day.</p>
<p>On Friday, only 200 tonnes were traded in SICOM's coffee market.</p>
<p>&quot;Those are just some local houses churning out their trading quotas as we approach the end of the year. I don't think it will last,&quot; one dealer said.  </p>
<p>-- Singapore Newsroom (65-8703305)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SINGP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SINGAPORE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
