<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265796" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>THAILAND: PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Dec 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Thai newspapers - Dec 18.</headline>
<dateline>BANGKOK 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are some of the leading stories in the Thai press on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>TOP STORIES</p>
<p>- A protest by 2,000 employees of Sanyo Universal Electric Plc, over their annual bonus and a planned factory relocation, escalated into a riot last night during which workers set fire to the company's warehouse and office building. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Four people were killed and 24 others injured yesterday when a powerful explosion blew out a three-storey factory building at a chemical plant in Samut Prakan province. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- Sweeping changes are expected when the Police Commission meets today to name the new police chief, who is most likely to be deputy director-general Pracha Promnok. Pol Gen Pracha was named acting police chief last Friday after Pol Gen Pote Boonyachinda was unceremoniously removed from the top post and transfered to Government House in the wake of a series of scandals that have tarnished the image of the Police Department. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>	 + + + +</p>
<p>BUSINESS</p>
<p>- Top Thai banking and finance officials yesterday hailed the 18-measure economic package announced by Deputy Premier Amnuay Viravan as one with credibility due to its specific intentions and timeframe. They also expressed confidence that the policy details and action plans will restore foreign investors' conficence in Thailand's capital and money markets, as well as in the government's ability to address the immediate issue of the hard-hit property sector and Bangkok Bank of Commerce. (THE NATION)</p>
<p>- The baht endured another hectic day of trading against the dollar yesterday as the central bank intervened twice to counter a slide as rumours of devaluation and government incapabilities circulated through the market while offshore bankers unwound their positions before the year's end. (BUSINESS DAY)</p>
<p>- Unnecessary spending must be cut, Prime Minister Chavalit Yongchaiyudh told cabinet ministers yesterday. State agencies were also told to restrict imports in a bid to lower the burgeoning current accound deficit. Funds not used for allocated purposes could not be switched to other projects. (BANGKOK POST)</p>
<p>- Bangkok newsroom (662) 652-0642</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="THAIL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BANGKOK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="THAILAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
