<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26572" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN delays Iraqi oil plans; fears for staff safety.</title>
<headline>UN delays Iraqi oil plans; fears for staff safety.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali on Sunday put off plans to implement an oil-for-food deal that would allow Baghdad to re-enter oil markets for the first time in six years.</p>
<p>&quot;He decided to hold off,&quot; said chief U.N. spokeswoman Sylvanna Foa. &quot;Security for the staff is the main problem.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;The situation in northern Iraq right now is extremely tense and he doesn't feel he can send people into a situation like that,&quot; she said</p>
<p>The oil-for-food programme, signed on May 20 between Iraq and the United Nations, permits Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months in order to buy food and medicine for its people, hard-hit by six-years of U.N. trade sanctions.</p>
<p>The embargoes were imposed in August 1990 shortly after Baghdad's troops invaded Kuwait.</p>
<p>She also said that Iraq's deputy prime minister Tareq Aziz had assured Boutros-Ghali in a telephone call that Baghdad's troops had been told to withdraw from the Kurdish areas where they captured the city of Arbil on Saturday.</p>
<p>Aziz reported that the situation was calm in Arbil, an &quot;assessment that has been confirmed by U.N. headquarters in Baghdad,&quot; Foa added.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton has already called several world leaders to discuss a &quot;course of action&quot; in response to the Iraqi military onslaught against one faction of rebel Kurds in norther Iraq, the White House said.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali, in a statement issued by Foa's office, said he had &quot;decided to delay the deployment of certain personnel who will supervise the implementation of Resolution 986,&quot; a reference to the document that sets out the oil-for-food plan.</p>
<p>The programme had been expected to be implemented within the next two weeks, presumably after the arrival of 14 oil monitors sent by the Dutch-based Saybolt company and 32 customs officials fielded by the Britain's Lloyd's Register.</p>
<p>An advance team to make arrangements for the oil monitors arrived in Baghdad late last week, but the 14 had been expected to leave this week, U.N. officials said.</p>
<p>In order tor the plan to be implemented, Boutros-Ghali must assure the Security Council that all arrangements are in place, including the first group of monitors to be stationed in the north as well as the rest of the country.</p>
<p>Said one key Security Council envoy: &quot;He has put the thing on ice for the time being, which is very sensible on prudency and political grounds.&quot;</p>
<p>But diplomatic sources said one other detail was still open -- arrangements for an escrow account to be set up at France's Banque Nationale de Paris. Arrangements for this have to be approved by a Security Council committee and the United States could delay approval, they said.</p>
<p>The United Nations eventually intends to send a total of 260 foreign monitors to Iraq for the deal, with about 900 Iraqis hired as support staff.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
