<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26574" id="root" date="1996-09-01" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN Chief delays arrangements for oil-for-food plan.</title>
<headline>UN Chief delays arrangements for oil-for-food plan.</headline>
<byline>Evelyn Leopold</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-09-01</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali said on Sunday he would delay arrangements to implement the oil-for-food plan until he could assess the situation in nothern Iraq.</p>
<p>The U.N. chief, in a statement, said he had &quot;decided to delay the deployment of certain personnel who will supervise the implementation of Resolution 986,&quot; a reference to the Security Council document that sets out the plan.</p>
<p>The oil-for-food programme, signed on May 20 between Iraq and the United Nations, permits Baghdad to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months in order to buy food and medicine for its people, hard-hit by six-years of U.N. trade sanctions.</p>
<p>The embargoes were imposed in August 1990 shortly after Baghdad's troops invaded Kuwait.</p>
<p>In order tor the plan to be implemented, Boutros-Ghali must assure the Security Council that all arrangements are in place, including the first batch of oil monitors and customs officials to be stationed in the north as well as the rest of the country.</p>
<p>Diplomats and U.N. officials said last week they expected his report to be ready shortly, perhaps within a week.</p>
<p>A statement attributed to a U.N. spokesman said that &quot;the secretary-general is very much concerned about the deterioration of the situation in northern Iraq.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;In light of developments there, he has decided to delay the deployment of certain personnel who will supervise the implementation of Resolution 986.</p>
<p>&quot;He is following the situation closely, and he is in continuing contact with the United Nations Coordinator in Baghdad,&quot; the statement said, adding that he had been informed that all U.N. personnel in northern Iraq were safe.</p>
<p>Iraq, according to U.S. officials, amassed 30,000-40,000 troops this week in northern Kurdish provinces and captured the city of Arbil, expelling one Kurdish faction and installing a rival group more favourable to Baghdad.</p>
<p>The United Nations since the 1991 Gulf War has had a large humanitarian programme to aid the Kurds, who were no longer under the control of the central government. The oil-for-food deal makes special arrangements for assistance to the Kurds, separately from the rest of the country.</p>
<p>But the plan cannot be implemented before 14 oil monitors are in place as well as 32 customs officials, who would be supervising borders between Iraq and its neighbours, including those in the north. U.N. officials said earlier that some of the oil monitors had already arrived in Baghdad but the bulk of the customs group was not in Iraq yet.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-01"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-01"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
