<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265797" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>VIETNAM: Vietnam to sell 50 bln dong T-bills on Wednesday.</title>
<headline>Vietnam to sell 50 bln dong T-bills on Wednesday.</headline>
<dateline>HANOI 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Vietnam will offer 50 billion dong ($4.49 million) worth of six-month Treasury bills at an auction on Wednesday, an official at the State Bank of Vietnam said.</p>
<p>At the last sale of government paper, on November 27, the central bank issued 2.5 billion dong worth of six-month notes to domestic institutions at an annual rate of 8.20 percent.</p>
<p>There have been 17 such sales so far this year, through which a total of 906.4 billion dong worth of Treasury stock has been issued.</p>
<p>The Bank has been aiming to hold one auction roughly every two weeks to lay the ground for a future secondary market.</p>
<p>Rates have fallen sharply in the first half of this year, partly due to a dong surplus in the banking system. At the first sale of the year, on March 1, the state bank sold six-month bills at a rate of 15.00 percent.</p>
<p>However, rates have bottomed out in recent weeks due to tighter liquidity, and bids for stock have come in at rates far higher than the Ministry of Finance was prepared to accept. As a result, much less stock has been allocated at recent auction than the central bank had orginally offered. (US$1 = 11,037 dong)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="VIETN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HANOI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="VIETNAM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
