<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265760" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>TAIWAN: Taiwan's BES targets China construction market.</title>
<headline>Taiwan's BES targets China construction market.</headline>
<byline>James Peng</byline>
<dateline>TAIPEI 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Taiwan general contractor BES Engineering Corp says it is planning to enter China's huge construction market with two industrial-zone development projects.</p>
<p>BES is promoting the plan despite the government's go-slow stance on investment in China, Taiwan's diplomatic rival.</p>
<p>&quot;We set up a Beijing representative office in July and plan to join ventures there to develop industrial zones in Shenyang and Nanjing,&quot; BES chairman Yao Che-shen told Reuters on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;If our shareholders' meeting on December 30 authorises the board to launch China investments, we will finalise the venture details and seek Taiwan government approval,&quot; Yao said.</p>
<p>Taiwan's investments in China need special approval by the Economics Ministry's Investment Commission.</p>
<p>Taipei said in December the commission and other agencies would take no new steps to boost economic links with China. The move was in retaliation for Chinese pressure which resulted in South Africa announcing it would sever diplomatic ties with Taipei and recognise Beijing beginning in 1997.</p>
<p>Some 25,000 Taiwan firms have poured over US$20 billion into China investments, making Taiwan one of the top overseas investors there -- and China one of Taiwan's most important markets.</p>
<p>BES vice-president Cheng Chih-ta said the planned ventures &quot;are aiming at the huge, potential China market.&quot;</p>
<p>Only five percent of BES sales are from overseas projects, a ratio that should swell rapidly in coming years, he said.</p>
<p>&quot;Entering 2000, our overseas projects -- mainly in mainland China and southeast Asia -- are expected to account for 40 percent of our total sales,&quot; Cheng said.</p>
<p>Yao said Taiwan's construction industry is only now beginning to emerge from years of recession.</p>
<p>&quot;The domestic construction industry has reached the bottom and has begun to recover,&quot; he said. &quot;You can take our rising rate of undertaken projects since July as a good example.&quot;</p>
<p>In the July-November period alone, he said, BES had undertaken projects worth T$10.96 billion (US$399 million) -- more than it undertook in all of fiscal 1995/96 (July/June), which itself was a BES record of T$10.19 billion (US$371 million).</p>
<p>For all of 1996/97, BES expects to undertake T$20.41 billion (US$742 million) in new work, Yao said.</p>
<p>It has set a 1996/97 pretax profit target of T$479 million on sales of T$19.56 billion, up from actual 1995/96 pretax profit of T$392 million on sales of T$16.5 billion.</p>
<p>Vice-president Cheng said that because general contractors like BES benefit from economic recovery up to 30 months before construction firms and other property sectors, &quot;we can expect the construction and real estate market to recover soon&quot;.</p>
<p>Cheng said the government's crackdown on organised crime in public construction projects should bolster the construction and property sector's long-term recovery.</p>
<p>The cabinet repeatedly has pledged to speed infrastructure projects so as to boost the slowing economy.</p>
<p>BES said T$610 billion worth of public construction projects would be executed in fiscal 1996/97, including a budgeted T$410 billion in fiscal 96/97 and T$200 billion in delayed projects.</p>
<p>BES was privatised in June 1994 after the government's stake in the firm fell to 40 percent from 91.5 percent through a public share offer. The state's shareholding was finally eliminated through a December share offering.</p>
<p>(US$1=T$27.5)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CHINA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TAIWAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I50200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TAIPEI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TAIWAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
