<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265845" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Dec 18.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Dec 18.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Manila newspapers on Wednesday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>- The Senate ratifies the bicameral conference committee report on proposed amendments to the expanded value added tax, exempting several sectors starting January 1 (MANILA BULLETIN)</p>
<p>- Government prosecutors will seek the death penalty for Zamboanga del Norte Congressman Romeo Jalosjos on charges of raping an 11-year old girl. (PHILIPPINE DAILY INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- President Fidel Ramos reiterates his decision to oppose moves to extend his term beyond 1998. (PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>- Former communist guerrilla chief Romulo Kintanar joins the ruling Lakas-NUCD party. (ALL PAPERS)</p>
<p>				 +++++++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>- The Securities and Exchange Commission chairman Perfecto Yasay says he is set to suspend trading of Centennial City Inc for allegedly bloating the value of its acquired property along Manila Bay. (INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- A wage dispute between the Airlines Pilots Association of the Philippines and Philippine Airlines was resolved after 19 hours of negotitations. (MALAYA)</p>
<p>- Budget secretary Salvador Enriquez says the government had agreed to acknowledge the oil firms' claims from the oil buffer fund as a liability of the national government. (TODAY)</p>
<p>- Three groups have been prequalified by the Central Bank to bid for the 60 percent equity of the Philippine National Bank's subsidiary PNB-Republic Bank. (MANITLA TIMES)</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
