<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265816" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan 97/98 real GDP growth forecast at 1.9%--EPA.</title>
<headline>Japan 97/98 real GDP growth forecast at 1.9%--EPA.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Japanese government is expecting real gross domestic product growth for the 1997/98 fiscal year of about 1.9 percent in real terms, Economic Planning Agency Minister Taro Aso told reporters on Wednesday.</p>
<p>The government has kept its official forecast of 2.5 percent GDP growth for the current fiscal year.  </p>
<p>&quot;Economic growth may slow in the first half of 1997/98 due to an increase in the consumption tax, but Japan can achieve sustainable economic recovery in the whole fiscal year,&quot; Aso said.</p>
<p>The following are the official forecasts released by the EPA on Wednesday:</p>
<p>		97/98 forecast  revised 96/97  original 96/97</p>
<p> GDP (real)     +1.9 pct     +2.5 pct	  +2.5 pct</p>
<p> GDP (nominal)  +3.1 pct     +2.5 pct	  +2.7 pct</p>
<p> C/A surplus     6.9 trln yen 7.0 trln yen    9.7 trln yen</p>
<p> CPI		+1.6 pct     +0.3 pct	  +0.5 pct</p>
<p> WPI (domestic) +1.3 pct     -0.7 pct	   N/A</p>
<p> Unemployment    3.3 pct	3.4 pct	  3.1 pct</p>
<p>Industrial</p>
<p>    output	+3.3 pct     +3.5 pct	  +3.5 pct</p>
<p>Note: Figures are approximate. More details and exact forecasts will be released at an extraordinary cabinet meeting on Thursday.  </p>
<p>A senior EPA official said the government will likely forecast private consumption growth of 1.5 percent for the fiscal year starting from April 1.</p>
<p>He added that private housing spending would likely be forecast to fall by about five percent while capital spending would likely be forecast to grow about 7.0 percent.</p>
<p>The forecasts were drafted on an assumption of an average exchange rate of 112.74 yen to the dollar, the average for the past month, the official said.</p>
<p>A rate of 110.49 yen to the dollar was used when making the forecasts for the current fiscal year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
