<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265955" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: New U.N. chief calls for a leaner world body.</title>
<headline>New U.N. chief calls for a leaner world body.</headline>
<byline>Anthony Goodman</byline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Kofi Annan, a 58-year-old U.N. career official from Ghana, called for a leaner, more effective United Nations after he was sworn in as secretary-general until the year 2001.</p>
<p>Appointed by acclamation by the 185-nation General Assembly on Tuesday, Annan said nations should &quot;make this organisation leaner, more efficient and more effective, more responsive to the wishes and needs of its members.&quot;</p>
<p>Mindful, however, of both Washington's $1.3 billion debt, which is bankrupting the United Nations, and its demand for reform, he said in his acceptance speech:</p>
<p>&quot;Applaud us when we prevail; correct us when we fail; but, above all, do not let this indispensable, irreplaceable institution wither, languish or perish as a result of member state indifference, inattention or financial starvation.&quot;</p>
<p>Change, he said, was necessary for the United Nations as well as the rest of the world. &quot;Let us make change our ally, not our enemy, seize it as an opportunity, not a threat; recognise it as a necessity, not an imposition.&quot;</p>
<p>The gray-bearded Annan, currently undersecretary-general for peacekeeping operations, will be the seventh secretary -general in U.N. history when he takes office on Jan. 1.</p>
<p>He will also be the first from sub-Saharan Africa and the first to have risen through the U.N. bureaucracy.</p>
<p>Annan lost no time appointing a transition team, composed entirely of his former colleages in the peacekeeping department. It is headed by Iqbal Riza of Pakistan, the current U.N. representative in Bosnia, tipped to become Annan's Cabinet chief.</p>
<p>The 15-member Security Council nominated Annan to the $205,809-a-year post last Friday, making his endorsement by the Assembly a formality and gala event.</p>
<p>He succeeds 74-year-old Boutros Boutros-Ghali of Egypt, who probably would have been re-elected if the United States had not vetoed his candidacy last month, saying he had not done enough to carry out reforms.</p>
<p>Annan praised the &quot;vision and energy&quot; of Boutros-Ghali, switching to French during part of his speech to display the fluency that France has made a requirement for anyone aspiring to the top U.N. post.</p>
<p>He departed from his prepared text when he saw Boutros-Ghali's predecessor as secretary-general, Javier Perez de Cuellar of Peru, in the blue-and-gold assembly hall. Turning to him, he said, &quot;Welcome home, sir.&quot;</p>
<p>Sitting side by side in the hall were Annan's Swedish artist wife, Nane, and Boutros-Ghali's wife, Leia.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali, in a farewell address, delivered a thinly veiled jab at the United States for its arrears to the world body and stressed the need for a secretary-general to be totally independent.</p>
<p>The U.N. financial crisis was &quot;not the result of mismanagement,&quot; he said, rejecting an often leveled charge.</p>
<p>&quot;It is the refusal to fulfil a treaty obligation. Now that a new secretary-general is being appointed, all arrears should be paid at once, as has been promised so often in the past few months,&quot; he said pointedly. U.S. Ambassador Madeleine Albright, seated at the head of her delegation, looked on stonily.</p>
<p>Appearing to contradict a U.S. assertion that a U.N. chief's first thoughts should be of reform, he said, &quot;Throughout the past five years, the first thing I thought of when I awoke in the morning were my responsibilities as secretary-general to the ideal of the Charter and independence and credibility of the organisation.&quot;</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali, speaking in English, French and Arabic, said that during his five-year term, coinciding with the end of the Cold War, the United Nations passed through periods of enthusiasm, disillusion and realism.</p>
<p>&quot;Now let us look to the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;The holder of this office must never be seen as acting out of fear of, or in an attempt to curry favour with, one state or group of states. Should that happen, all prospects for the United Nations would be lost.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GHANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
