<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="265974" id="root" date="1996-12-18" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: Hong Kong stocks end weak, led down by properties.</title>
<headline>Hong Kong stocks end weak, led down by properties.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Hong Kong stocks closed on a weaker note on Wednesday, led down by losses in the property sector as a lack of incentives prevented share prices from retaining some early gains.</p>
<p>The Hang Seng Index shed 49.35 points to 12,766.02 after rising to a session high of 12,942.63. Turnover was HK$6.29 billion compared with HK$5.71 billion on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;At current levels there are not any good reasons to convince investors to buy blue chips substantially so people are just laying off a bit and seeing which direction the market will go,&quot; said Henry Lui, research analyst at Mansion House Research.</p>
<p>Lui said investors were divided about the future course of interest rates. The U.S. Federal Reserve decided to leave monetary policy unchanged at a meeting on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;I think some people expect rates to go up again in the first quarter of next year while others expect stable rates for the whole of 1997,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>ING Barings sales director James Osborn said while Wall Street stocks made gains overnight, &quot;the bond market went the wrong way for equities&quot;.</p>
<p>The Dow rose 39.98 points to 6,308.33 on Tuesday but the U.S. long bond slipped 15/32 to yield 6.66 percent.</p>
<p>&quot;Hong Kong is probably not going to wander far from the 12,800 level. There is no reason to,&quot; said Osborn. &quot;Hong Kong has done very well this year. There is no reason for people to be window dressing in the market towards the end of the year.&quot;</p>
<p>In the property sector, Henderson Land fell HK$0.50 to HK$72.00 and Cheung Kong was down HK$0.50 at HK$64.00.</p>
<p>Hysan Development dropped HK$0.85 to HK$27.60 and Sun Hung Kai Properties slipped HK$0.25 to HK$90.75.</p>
<p>Satellite services provider APT Satellite Holdings made its trading debut on Wednesday and closed at HK$13.50 per share compared with an issue price of HK$13.40 per share.</p>
<p>Shares in Kwong Sang Hong rose HK$0.70 to HK$3.925.</p>
<p>Peregrine Investments Holdings said it would privatise Kwong Sang Hong, offering 200 Peregrine shares plus HK$1,700 cash for every 1,000 Kwong Sang Hong shares.</p>
<p>Peregrine fell HK$0.80 to HK$12.45.</p>
<p>The H-share index of China-incorporated companies listed in Hong Kong fell 1.92 points to 894.87.</p>
<p>December Hang Seng Index futures fell 10 points to 12,820.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-18"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
