<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266087" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Redhook sees Q4 sales, EPS below forecasts.</title>
<headline>Redhook sees Q4 sales, EPS below forecasts.</headline>
<dateline>SEATTLE 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Redhook Ale Brewery Inc said sales for the quarter ending December 31, 1996 will be below expectations.</p>
<p>Disappointing shipments in November and December, primarily in Western states, combined with the start-up impact of the new brewery in Portsmouth, New Hampshire will cause the company's earnings for the quarter to be significantly below expectations.  Redhook will report its fourth quarter results as scheduled on February 4, 1997.</p>
<p>Analysts have been forecasting Redhook to report about $0.11 a share for the quarter versus $0.12 a share last year.  </p>
<p>The company cited lower than expected sales of some products on the West Coast.</p>
<p>Redhook expects its total fourth quarter shipment volumes will increase only 15-20 percent over the quarter ended December 31, 1995. Total barrels sold by Redhook in 1996 are expected to be up approximately 40 percent over 1995.</p>
<p>Its Portsmouth brewery began operations in October and the expected effect of certain operating costs will increase the cost of goods sold as a percentage of net sales. Due to lower than expected sales volumes in the fourth quarter, this impact will be more significant than previously anticipated, it said.  </p>
<p>It also said the delay in the City of Portsmouth water service direct connection to the brewery will increase the adverse effect on gross margins of the brewery start-up through higher water costs.</p>
<p>The Portsmouth City Council recently approved the direct connection to the water-line and Redhook expects to complete the connection in the first quarter of 1997, construction logistics and weather permitting.</p>
<p>It said freight savings on shipments from Portsmouth to Eastern markets will begin to have an impact in the first quarter of 1997.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I42700">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SEATTLE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
