<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266115" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Arterial Vascular sees Q4 EPS $0.14 - $0.16.</title>
<headline>Arterial Vascular sees Q4 EPS $0.14 - $0.16.</headline>
<dateline>SANTA ROSA, Calif. 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Arterial Vascular Engineering Inc said on Thursday it expects fiscal second quarter earnings per share of $0.14 to $0.16 a share, well off the previous quarter's $0.25.</p>
<p>In a statement, the company cited higher-than-expected expenses in the second quarter ending December 31 and pricing pressure on its products as reasons for the earnings decline.</p>
<p>&quot;Legal expenses have increased significantly as we continue to vigorously defend and pursue claims brought in connection with (our) purchase of technology from Endothelial Support Systems,&quot; John Miller, chief financial officer, said.  </p>
<p>Though physician response to its GFX Stent product is encouraging and it remains excited about prospects for entering new markets, Vascular Engineering said recent increases in costs and pricing pressure will continue to affect earnings in the foreseeable future.</p>
<p>&quot;Until the (Endothelial) litigation is resolved, or regulatory approval is obtained for the U.S. market, earnings for subsequent periods will likely be in line with those expected in the quarter ending December 31,&quot; Miller said.</p>
<p>Legal expenses, coupled with costs for terminating some distributorships, will total over $1.0 million in the December quarter, he said.</p>
<p>Moreover, Arterial Vascular recently formed a direct sales force in several European countries and that has contributed to higher costs, while sales in those countries have been &quot;significantly slower than anticipated.&quot;</p>
<p>The company is boosting research and development costs and taking a charge of $400,000 in the quarter for a postponed stock offer. Those two factors also will contribute to the earnings shortfall.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I37200">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SANTA ROSA, Calif."/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
