<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266389" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: FRENCH, GERMAN, POLISH MINISTERS FIRM TRIANGLE TIE.</title>
<headline>FRENCH, GERMAN, POLISH MINISTERS FIRM TRIANGLE TIE.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The French, German and Polish foreign ministers met in Warsaw on Thursday to keep up the momentum of their cooperation in the so-called Weimar Triangle, an understanding Poland views as a key to European integration.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a meeting which I hope will add impetus to contacts within the Weimar Triangle,&quot; Polish President Aleksander Kwasniewski told a news conference after receiving the ministers briefly in his Warsaw palace.</p>
<p>He said French minister Herve de Charette and Germany's Klaus Kinkel had confirmed the three heads of state would hold a summit next year, although a date had yet to be decided.</p>
<p>The ministers also met Polish Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz, but their main business was later due to be conducted through a working lunch, which diplomats and officials said would be too short to allow very detailed talks.</p>
<p>Poland's Foreign Minister Dariusz Rosati said earlier that they would examine how to apply and extend the model of good-neighbourly Franco-German ties to Warsaw-Bonn relations.</p>
<p>They would discuss European security, including the planned expansion of NATO, which Poland expects to join fast, and ways of involving countries which could not or would not enter the Western alliance soon, he told a Wednesday news briefing.</p>
<p>Poland wants to be more involved in discussing the pattern of future economic and monetary union in the European Union, which it also aspires to enter rapidly, especially in view of controversies and decisions at this year's EU Dublin summit.</p>
<p>&quot;It is our goal to build a joint position of the three countries around these matters,&quot; said Rosati, whose country aims to enter monetary union not long after joining the EU.</p>
<p>This is the sixth meeting of the three countries' foreign ministers under the informal triangular relationship, since an inaugural gathering in Weimar, Germany, in August 1991.</p>
<p>Poland views the axis, which France has backed with greater enthusiasm since President Jacques Chirac visited Warsaw in September, as an important symbol because it straddles former World War Two and Cold War divisions.</p>
<p>Kwasniewski said that although the Weimar Triangle framework had not so far been spectacular, it had advanced lower-profile contacts that had smoothed Poland's progress.</p>
<p>&quot;I think these are important events which allow us not merely to believe, but to be sure that France and Germany are very effective advocates of Poland in entering the European Union and NATO&quot;, the Polish president said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="EEC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E51">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E512">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="G158">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
