<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266355" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: GERMAN COURT THROWS OUT SELES CLAIM FOR DAMAGES.</title>
<headline>GERMAN COURT THROWS OUT SELES CLAIM FOR DAMAGES.</headline>
<byline>Susanne Frank</byline>
<dateline>HAMBURG, Germany 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tennis star Monica Seles failed on Thursday in a bid to win damages from the German Tennis Federation (DTB) for a knife attack by a spectator which kept her out of the sport for more than two years.</p>
<p>A Hamburg court rejected her claim that the DTB's security measures at the Hamburg Open in April 1993 were inadequate, allowing her attacker to jump from the stands and plunge a kitchen knife into her back.</p>
<p>Lawyers for Seles, who was not in court, had claimed 24.4 million marks ($15.75 million) for damages and lost earnings from her 27-month layoff after the attack.</p>
<p>The 23-year old U.S. star had charged that the players' bench in the stadium was too close to the spectators' stand, from where lathe operator Guenter Parche leapt to stab her.</p>
<p>The court did not give an immediate explanation for its decision but said Seles, the number-two ranked player in women's tennis, would have to pay the costs of the hearing.</p>
<p>&quot;We'll discuss in peace and quiet whether we want to appeal after we receive the judgment in writing,&quot; said Seles' lawyer Wilhelm Danelzik.</p>
<p>He said he was inclined not to accept the court's verdict but it was up to his client whether she wanted to pursue the case further. He had informed Seles of the decision by fax but had not yet received a reply.</p>
<p>The DTB welcomed the court's ruling. &quot;This is a verdict for sport,&quot; said Juergen Tietjen, the head of the DTB subsidiary which organised the Hamburg event.</p>
<p>&quot;It ensures direct contact between spectators and players will also be possible at sports events in the future,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>&quot;If the verdict had been different we would have had to think about whether we could continue to stage tournaments. Tennis lives from the directness of the game. We don't want tennis in a cage.&quot;</p>
<p>Parche was given a two-year suspended sentence in October 1993 for grievous bodily harm. He had jumped from the stands and stabbed Seles in the back during a changeover in a match against Bulgarian Magdalena Maleeva.</p>
<p>He said his fascination with Graf drove him to wound Seles -- then ranked number one in the world -- to help the German player regain the top spot.</p>
<p>The trial judge ruled he was emotionally retarded and may not have been entirely responsible for his actions.</p>
<p>Prosecutors had asked the court to jail Parche for attempted murder. A subsequent appeal by Seles for a tougher sentence failed. She told that hearing in a written statement the attack had &quot;ruined her life.&quot;</p>
<p>Seles, suffering from fear and depression, postponed her comeback to the international tennis circuit several times and finally returned last year. But she has not taken part in any tournaments in Germany since her return.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HAMBURG, Germany"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
