<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266424" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Med oil products steady to a touch easier.</title>
<headline>Med oil products steady to a touch easier.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mediterranean oil products were broadly steady, but some showed a softer tone.</p>
<p>Naphtha held steady in quiet activity. Traders said the market looked fairly balanced with bids scarce and cargo offers into the Med thin, although several cargoes of Egyptian and Algerian material, of 25-30kt, were offered into NWE.</p>
<p>Physical barges were notionally valued around $218 a tonne fob Med.</p>
<p>Gasoline was steady with most December business done and a good deal of first half January programs already completed due to the year-end holidays.</p>
<p>Premium unleaded cargoes were around $221 a tonne cif Med.</p>
<p>Gas oil slipped $1.50 a tonne but premiums in the Med were stable at around high cif quotes +0.50 basis Genoa.</p>
<p>Heating oil supply was healthy but availability of vessels meagre and demand thin. A cargo of 0.2 percent sulphur heating oil was offered at high cif +0.50.</p>
<p>The main focus was on efforts to obtain a vessel to work an arbitrage to Asia, but movements have slowed since last week. Pakistan and India are seen as the likely destinations for heating oil, with suppliers sending 0.2 per cent sulphur in place of the 0.5 percent material requested by both countries.</p>
<p>Low sulphur diesel remains long with two Algerians due to load at Skikda in late December and early January.</p>
<p>Fuel oil drifted sideways amid a weaker tone backed by a low sulphur cracked deal done at $124 fob NWE.</p>
<p>The main Med buyer continued to remain out of the market with little obivious interest being shown for January barrels.</p>
<p>Romania remained a focus of attention amongst the high sulphur cracked fuel fraternity. Traders said large cargoes were done into the country.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8980</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
