<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266526" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>NIGERIA: Nigerian democracy campaigner, unionist detained.</title>
<headline>Nigerian democracy campaigner, unionist detained.</headline>
<dateline>LAGOS 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Nigerian democracy campaigner and a trade unionist have been detained by security forces, a local human rights group said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;We call for the immediate and unconditional release of Mr Anselm Akele and Dr Frederick Fasehun who were illegally arrested on December 17 and 18, respectively,&quot; the Committee for the Defence of Human Rights (CDHR) group said in a statement.</p>
<p>It did not say why the two men were arrested and there has been no confirmation of the arrests by the authorities.</p>
<p>The independent Guardian reported on Thursday that Fasehun, a medical doctor, was taken away on Wednesday morning after a police search of his house and private hospital.</p>
<p>Fasehun took over as chairman of the umbrella Campaign for Democracy from Beko Ransome-Kuti who in 1995 was given a 15-year prison sentence for his part in an alleged coup plot.</p>
<p>Akele is chairman of a wing of a public workers' union.</p>
<p>Nigeria's commercial capital, Lagos, is in a state of high tension following two bomb explosions in less than a week which have seriously injured over a dozen soldiers.</p>
<p>Nobody has claimed responsibility for the attacks but police in November accused opponents of the military government of being behind a bungled car-bomb which killed the three would-be bombers.</p>
<p>CDHR condemned the bomb blasts but said only democracy could restore peace in the country.</p>
<p>&quot;In so far as the military remains in stolen power, general insecurity, violence, crime, terrorism and political assasinations will continue in Nigeria,&quot; it said, adding that ... &quot;enthronement of a genuine democratic setting is an imperative condition for the resuscitation of peace and tranquility.&quot;</p>
<p>Dozens of opposition figures are detained in Africa's most populous nation, which has become a pariah state for alleged human rights abuses and lack of democracy.</p>
<p>Among the detainees are Moshood Abiola, the presumed winner of a 1993 presidential poll, whose annulment plunged Nigeria into turmoil.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="NIGEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LAGOS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="NIGERIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
