<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266572" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: FNB rises on sale of troubled FirstPref.</title>
<headline>FNB rises on sale of troubled FirstPref.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shares in First National Bank Holdings Ltd (FNB), one of South Africa's four biggest banks, rose on Thursday on news of the sale of troubled instalment credit unit, FirstPref, dealers and analysts said.</p>
<p>By 0915 GMT, FNB shares on the Johannesburg Stock Exchange had added 1.72 percent or 35 cents to 20.75 in fairly brisk trade of 146,700 shares.</p>
<p>&quot;The sale is very, very positive for FNB,&quot; one banking analyst said.</p>
<p>&quot;They should not have got into it (FirstPref) in the first place and then there was a huge administrative and systems mess in running it,&quot; the analyst said.</p>
<p>FNB said on Wednesday it had agreed to sell FirstPref back to McCarthy Retail Ltd with effect from April 1, 1997 as the financing of McCarthy's business had not worked out to the mutual benefit of both companies as originally envisaged.</p>
<p>FirstPref, which FNB bought in July 1995, was last month fingered by the bank as being partly responsible for its 69 percent surge in bad debts and poor earnings performance in the 1995/96 financial year.</p>
<p>Analysts said despite the sale, FirstPref's bad debt problem would still cut into FNB's first half 1996/97 earnings, but the effect would be smoothed over for the full year.</p>
<p>&quot;FNB will assess the quality of the book at the time of the transfer back to McCarthy and make additional provisions. They will be up on the first half of last year as some (debts) still have to work through the system. But they will not be too onerous,&quot; an analyst said.</p>
<p>Dealers said the shares, which touched a year low of 19.90 rand this week, had more upside potential.</p>
<p>&quot;There is some genuine buying...It should go up a lot more than that (35 cents),&quot; one said.</p>
<p>-- Nicole Mordant, Johannesburg newsroom 27 11 482 1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I65400">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
