<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266596" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Serbia gives guarded welcome to polls inquiry.</title>
<headline>Serbia gives guarded welcome to polls inquiry.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>disrupt city, protest size)</p>
<p>By Peter Millership</p>
<p>Serbia's government gave a guarded welcome on Thursday to an international mission which is to rule on vote-rigging accusations while the opposition threw a huge festive street party in the capital.</p>
<p>Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic said Serbia would not be bound by any findings made by the OSCE, which arrives on Friday, saying its recommendations must be confirmed by Serbia's own institutions.</p>
<p>The Organisation for European Security and Cooperation (OSCE) was called in by embattled President Slobodan Milosevic in response to a storm of Washington-led criticism from abroad and mass rallies at home over annulled November local polls.</p>
<p>The Zajedno (Together) coalition says it was robbed of victory in 15 of Serbia's main towns and cities, including the capital, as the ruling Socialists, former communists, had annulled the votes. It demands reinstatement of its triumphs.</p>
<p>&quot;The regime will yield, either under our pressure or from its own weakenesses,&quot; Zoran Djindjic, an opposition leader told the Belgrade rally of more than 200,000 people, one of the biggest in 32 straight days of protests.</p>
<p>&quot;We are persevering in our demands; the monolith is slowly cracking,&quot; the minister added.</p>
<p>Milutinovic's decision to comment publicly on the crisis after a month of silence follows a statement by Milosevic on Tuesday in which he suddenly dropped his aloofness and promised to investigate vote-rigging allegations.</p>
<p>Political sources said that Milosevic, who had hoped the opposition cause would run out of steam, had now abandoned his sit-it-out strategy and was working out concessions and how to distance himself from any voting irregularities.</p>
<p>&quot;Various officials of the regime are saying things which are straying somewhat from the official line -- but individual concessions are not acceptable -- we must be given back our election results,&quot; Djindjic said.</p>
<p>In another bitter blow to their morale, Socialists in two Serbian towns had to scrap their rallies in support of Milosevic due to dismal attendance, Zajedno officials said.</p>
<p>As part of an official damage limitation exercise, Milutinovic played down the discontent and rejected foreign intervention in Serbia.</p>
<p>Milutinovic said the government would need to consider the OSCE recommendations. &quot;They are here to establish the facts. Naturally whatever the OSCE mission concludes, our competent institutions will have to assess within the organs of the system,&quot; he told a news conference.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that all this should be resolved within the institutions of the system,&quot; he said. &quot;The reaction is totally out of proportion to the issue,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Zajedno and its supporters have surprised themselves with their massive displays of people power which have brought memories of the 1989 revolutions which rocked Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>Security forces have kept a low profile during the peaceful protests which regularly draw families with children. In stark contrast Milosevic crushed 1991 street protests with tanks.</p>
<p>Student leaders said on Friday they would mobilise their supporters to blockade three bridges over the Sava River to snarl up traffic going into Belgrade with the aim of paralysing the city for 30 minutes.</p>
<p>The streets of Belgrade were packed once again on Thursday as young and old went on their daily protest march around the capital then celebrated St Nikolas's Day with a festive feast of fried fish, cakes and wine serenaded by celebrity singers.</p>
<p>In the main body of the crowd were United States, French, Canadian and British flags in tribute to democracy. Others carried banners with phrases such as &quot;Better Dead than Red&quot;.</p>
<p>Fireworks sent showers of sparks into the night sky as protesters waved torches and tucked into the feast.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
