<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266613" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SLOVENIA: PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Dec 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Slovenia - Dec 19.</headline>
<text>
<p>DELO</p>
<p>- President Milan Kucan is due to make a statement following the end of talks with party leaders to select a prime minister for the new government. Kucan should name his candidate by January 3.</p>
<p>- December pensions rose by 2.8 percent from November in reaction to an increase in salaries, the pensioners' fund said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>- Slovenia on Thursday beat Macedonia 87-61 in a qualifying match for the European basketball Championship in Spain next year.</p>
<p>- Milan Kucan met parents, wives and children of soldiers and policemen killed in Slovenia's independence war in 1991.</p>
<p>- Slovenia's Defence Minister Jelko Kacin said on Thursday Slovenia was the NATO applicant to complete bilateral talks with the organisation successfully and that it could soon expect to become a full member.</p>
<p>DNEVNIK</p>
<p>- Trading activities constitute 10.5 percent of Slovenia's GDP, compared to developed countries where the figure is between 15 and 20 percent. The Chamber of Economy said 9.6 percent of all Slovenian workers are employed in trade.</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>- Prime Minister Janez Drnovsek on Thursday arranged a traditional new year meeting with foreign diplomats working in Slovenia.</p>
<p>- The Slovenian Development Fund, the state's restructuring agency on Wednesday closed the tender for stakes in 152 firms and accepted a joint offer by 23 Slovenian investment funds.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SLVNIA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SLOVENIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
