<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266692" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Bucharest bourse turnover up at last '96 session.</title>
<headline>Bucharest bourse turnover up at last '96 session.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turnover at the Bucharest stock exchange's last session of the year rose by 14 million lei but remained low at 40 million in thin demand.</p>
<p>Two independent indices fell to new year lows.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's turnover level was quite good considering that both investors and brokers are already in a holiday mood,&quot; said a trader.</p>
<p>Six prices picked up, six touched new lows, one was unchanged and three had no trade.</p>
<p>Investors once again focused on the bourse's most liquid company fertiliser maker Azomures SA, which took more than half of turnover, as well as on Artrom SA engineering company, in which more than half the total 8,192 shares traded changed hands.</p>
<p>Both Azomures and Artrom closed stronger. The fertiliser maker picked up 500 lei to close at 12,100 and Artrom ended the session at 2,050, up from 1,960.</p>
<p>Syringe maker  Sanevit SA remained suspended pending an announcement, while the suspension of Electroceramica SA insulator maker was lifted during trading after the company had released details of its last shareholders' meeting.</p>
<p>Electroceramica said its shareholders had discussed contracts for 1997, unrecovered receipts and new products.</p>
<p>The exchange said on Thursday it was closing down for the winter holidays and would resume trading on January 7.</p>
<p>Two unofficial indices -- the VAB, computed by  Vanguard SA, and  Bucharest Investment Group 's BIG -- fell to year lows, slipping by 1.7 percent from the previous session. The VAB was 262 points and the BIG 261.36 points compared with a 1,000-point base last November.</p>
<p>		DEC 19  DEC 17   Week's change  1996 high  1996 low</p>
<p> VAB-Index  262.0   266.6	-4.0 pct	879.29   262.0</p>
<p> BIG-Index  261.36  265.8	-4.1 pct	820.9    261.36</p>
<p>($=3,795 lei)</p>
<p>-- Luli Popescu, Bucharest Newsroom 40-1 3120264</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
