<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266640" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Polish PZU limits motor liability insurance rise.</title>
<headline>Polish PZU limits motor liability insurance rise.</headline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's largest insurer, Powszechny Zaklad Ubezpieczen SA (PZU), on Thursday reduced a rise in motor liability insurance premiums to 33 percent from earlier announced 43 percent, PAP quoted PZU's president as saying.</p>
<p>&quot;PZU lowered the motor liability insurance by 10 percent from earlier proposals. Currently the average increase amounts to 33 percent,&quot; PAP quoted Jan Monkiewicz as saying.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Wlodzimierz Cimoszewicz earlier this week suggested he might dismiss the management of state-owned PZU if it failed to limit the scope of the increase.</p>
<p>Second largest insurer Warta, which earlier raised its premiums by 33 percent, said it would consider the PZU move and did not rule out a change in its own rise.</p>
<p>&quot;The decision over a possible change will be taken after we know details about PZU's premiums,&quot; Warta's spokesman told Reuters.</p>
<p>Polisa officials were not immediately available for comment. Polisa earlier raised its motor liability premiums by 50 percent.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
