<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266614" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>CZECH REPUBLIC: PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Dec 19.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Czech Republic - Dec 19.</headline>
<text>
<p>HOSPODARSKE NOVINY - Petr Pithart was elected the first chairman of the newly-formed Czech Senate. He received 41 of 81 votes in the second round of voting. Pithart, a member of the Christian Democratic Party, was the Prime Minister of Czechoslovakia before the split with Slovakia.</p>
<p>- Even though Czech banks are posting multi-billion crown profits, their productivity pales in comparison with local daughter companies of foreign banks. While one worker in the Prague branch of Citibank earned an average net profit of over three billion crowns for the bank, a worker in the best Czech bank in this respect, Ceskoslovenska Obchodni Banka, earned 610 thousand crowns for the bank.</p>
<p>- Metalimex a.s., a trading company specialising in non-renewable resources, has requested a license from the Ministry of Trade and Industry to import natural gas. &quot;We do not know whether we will get it or not, but we will check it from all legal angles. We will definitely not fight against the governemnt's interests,&quot; Petr Paukner, the general manager of Metalimex, stated.</p>
<p>- A majority of financial experts expect a decrease in the number of leasing companies as well as a gradual stabilisation of the market.</p>
<p>- While the completion date for the construction of the Temelin nuclear power plant is still not clear, according to CEZ, the investor of the project, it could be as early as the end of next year. In this case, the reactors would begin operations in the spring of 1999.</p>
<p>- Investicni a Postovni Banka a.s. will not take part in the government's plan to increase Aero Vodochody's basic capital, according to the bank's spokesman Jan Rezek. Ceskoslovenska Obchodni Banka has not ruled out the possibility.</p>
<p>- The Skoda Automobile factory increased its output by one quarter this year. The company sold 238,000 automobiles abroad and more than 79,000 automobiles domestically in the first 11 months of 1996.</p>
<p>- ZVVZ Milevsko a.s. will exceed sales of two billion crowns for the first time. The company posted sales of 1.956 billion crowns and a gross profit of 82 million crowns in the first ten months of 1996.</p>
<p>- The largest domestic producer of paper, Sepap a.s., will lay off the largest number of empoyees by the end of this year since the beginning of the decade. By the end of December, 600 employees will be laid off, a decrease of about one quarter from last year's total of 2360.</p>
<p>MLADA FRONTA DNES - Ceska Banka clients will not receive their deposits this year. The Ministry of Finance and the Czech National Bank have not yet decided on the exact procedure they will use to pay the outstanding deposits in the bank.</p>
<p>-- Prague Newsroom, 42-2-2423-0003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CZREP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="CZECH REPUBLIC"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
