<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266749" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BOSNIA: Bosnia's vital winter gas supply in doubt.</title>
<headline>Bosnia's vital winter gas supply in doubt.</headline>
<byline>Sabina Cosic</byline>
<dateline>SARAJEVO 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bosnians may shiver through the winter unless the government and a local gas company reach agreement with a Russian gas supplier on an outstanding $11 million debt, a company manager said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Gas is an important source of heating in a country striving to recover from a 43-month war but haggling over payment of the debt has put the winter gas supply in doubt.</p>
<p>In addition to the $11 million dating from October last year, Bosnia accumulated a $105-million debt during the war, which was put aside for separate negotiations with London and Paris debt clubs.</p>
<p>The Russian supplier &quot;Gas Export&quot; says it will only provide gas until the end of the year unless Bosnia presents a plan to pay the existing debt and for future supplies, said Mensur Causevic, deputy-director of the country's gas importer, Energoinvest.</p>
<p>Energoinvest, which describes itself as a Bosnian engineering group, has requested the government's help in solving the debt problem but Causevic said it has received little help so far.</p>
<p>&quot;We organised a meeting on Saturday, but none of the government officials who could solve the debt problem showed up,&quot; Causevic told Reuters.</p>
<p>Bosnian officials say the gas problem comes at a time when a post-war government is still being formed, with newly-elected officials just taking up their jobs.</p>
<p>&quot;My government is no longer responsible for that, you should speak to the (Moslem-Croat) federation's government,&quot; Bosnia's outgoing Prime Minister Hasan Muratovic said.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no need to dramatise the situation, we shall not freeze this winter.&quot;</p>
<p>Muratovic has proposed alternatives to gas heating, saying local resources such as electricity and coal should be used more often.</p>
<p>&quot;I've always said gas should be a substitute, not a primary source of power,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But critics say such a solution could hit people's wallets severely. Bosnia's war-ravaged electricity system is not to be trusted either and could collapse with a sharp rise in power consumption, they say.</p>
<p>A cold November spell increased gas use, creating shortages and also underlined the need to arrange a long-term agreement with the Russian gas company.</p>
<p>One Western official said he did not believe the Russians would cut the gas supply off altogether and viewed their tough stance as &quot;payment posturing from Moscow&quot;.</p>
<p>Muratovic said two proposals were being considered. One plan involved equal payments from the state budget, foreign donors and users and the other proposal would draw on the World Bank's $90 million of transitional credit for reconstruction.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, Bosnia's electric company offered special discounts to people opting for electric heating.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BSHZG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I16000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C311">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SARAJEVO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BOSNIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
