<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266717" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Bulgaria seeks funds to reduce coal pollution.</title>
<headline>Bulgaria seeks funds to reduce coal pollution.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Bulgaria is seeking funds to develop a sulphur reduction project to curb pollution from its biggest coal mining and thermal power complex, Maritsa East, an energy official said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Bulgarian Atomic Energy Committee chairman Lachezar Kostov said Japanese experts were helping Bulgaria work out a pilot project using electronic technology to reduce pollution from the high-sulphur lignite coal.</p>
<p>Kostov said the International Atomic Energy Agency will extend aid of some $1.5 million for the project and Bulgaria must provide some $1 million.</p>
<p>&quot;Japan is giving us the installation, worth $4 million, free,&quot; Kostov told a news conference. &quot;We are seeking another $700,000.&quot;</p>
<p>Environmental officials say lignite from Maritsa East has one of the highest sulphur contents in Europe and Bulgaria's outdated thermal power stations are among the worst polluters in the country.</p>
<p>Maritsa East, 250 km south-east of Sofia, has only lignite coal and its reserves of some two billion tonnes are expected to feed the country's coal-fired power stations for another 80 to 100 years.</p>
<p>Bulgaria relies on Maritsa East for 30 percent of its electricity needs and the nuclear power plant at Kozloduy meets more than 40 percent of the country's power demand.</p>
<p>-- Liliana Semerdjieva, Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I11000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GENV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
