<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266898" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: YEAREND-Brazil tames inflation, eyes bright future.</title>
<headline>YEAREND-Brazil tames inflation, eyes bright future.</headline>
<byline>John Miller</byline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>When Central Bank director Gustavo Franco sees gay marriages and crime topping Brazil's evening news these days, he knows he is doing his job.</p>
<p>For a country whose recent past saw inflation rates of 2,000 percent and where finance ministers were as well known as soap opera stars, just keeping the economy out of Brazil's headlines is a victory for policy-makers.  </p>
<p>Officials admit that much remains to be done to put Brazil's economic house in order following a decade of debt crisis, subsequent bouts with hyperinflation and political turmoil. But they say the nation has hit a milestone as it enters the midway point of President Fernando Henrique Cardoso's four-year term.</p>
<p>For the first time in recent memory, people are using words like &quot;boring,&quot; &quot;predictable&quot; and &quot;monotonous&quot; to describe the Brazilian economy.  </p>
<p>A wave of bank failures triggered by the Real Plan's attack on inflation has subsided, ending worries about an imminent banking crisis.</p>
<p>And there are growing signs that Brazil's poor are actually getting richer, countering a regional trend toward growing income inequality. Private and official studies show low-income Brazilians eating more meat and making first-time purchases of toasters, washing machines and other hitherto &quot;luxury&quot; items.  </p>
<p>President Cardoso even named the chicken a &quot;national hero&quot; because its affordability under the Real Plan has helped increase meat consumption dramatically among the poor.</p>
<p>Even though Brazil still has one of the worst income distributions in the world, economists say the trend is promising. Leading newsweekly Veja devoted a cover story to the phenomenon this week, calling it &quot;Brazil's New Economic Miracle&quot;, in a reference to the fast-paced growth Brazil achieved in the 1960's-70's.  </p>
<p>The fact that Brazil's president, for example, has kept the same economy minister since he took office two years ago sharply contrasts with the virtual musical chairs game between 1990 and 1994, when six different people occupied that post.</p>
<p>&quot;There is no more news about the economy important enough to find space on the eight o'clock news,&quot; boasts Central Bank director Gustavo Franco, one of the main architects of Brazil's Real Plan, a successful inflation slashing drive that began in July 1994.  </p>
<p>The stable environment has also freed Brazilian policy-makers from day-to-day worries over the economy, allowing them to think about Brazil's future in a way they have not been able to do in more than 20 years.</p>
<p>&quot;We are now discussing things that we were last talking about in the 1970s, such as what role should Brazil play in the world economy and developmental issues,&quot; Franco told Reuters in a recent interview.</p>
<p>&quot;The simple fact that we are talking about this says a lot.&quot;  </p>
<p>Still, the financial markets are keeping a cautious eye on the country's widening trade gap, a stubborn budget deficit and mounting internal debt -- seen as the three biggest challenges to the government in 1997 and beyond.</p>
<p>Trade worries have even caused markets to speculate that the Central Bank could speed depreciation of Brazil's real currency to slow the heavy tide of imports.</p>
<p>But Franco, who often refers to policy-making in military terms, said Brazilian economic policy had moved beyond knee-jerk reactions to new problems, which characterized the country under &quot;wartime.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have a foreign exchange policy appropriate for peace time. If there is a war OK, but if not then there is no reason to change anything and I don't see anything emerging,&quot; Franco said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E131">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
