<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266871" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: Brazil grants automakers controversial incentives.</title>
<headline>Brazil grants automakers controversial incentives.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Brazil, brushing off complaints by Argentina, has approved a decree granting tax cuts and lifting import duties to draw automobile industry investment to its impoverished north and northeast, a government decree said.</p>
<p>The decree was signed into law Thursday by President Fernando Henrique Cardoso despite protests over the planned incentives earlier this week by Argentine President Carlos Menem.</p>
<p>Menem said the move would draw badly needed auto investment away from his country.  </p>
<p>Brazil and Argentina are partners in the four-nation Mercosur customs union, which also has Chile and Bolivia as associate members.</p>
<p>However, conservative lawmakers from Brazil's poor, rural north and northeast have been pressuring the government for tax breaks and other incentives for their region in exchange for siding with Cardoso on important issues before Congress.</p>
<p>According to the decree, the main incentives offered to auto firms moving to Brazil's north, northeast and central-west are:</p>
<p>* Exemption from tax on company profits.</p>
<p>* The lifting of all import duties and value-added tax on machinery and equipment.</p>
<p>* A 90 percent cut on import tariffs on raw materials, auto parts, components, assemblies and sub-assemblies.</p>
<p>* A 45-percent tax exemption on raw materials, auto parts, components, assemblies and sub-assemblies.</p>
<p>The incentives are valid until December 31, 1999 and the government could extend the measure until December 31, 2010, according to the decree.</p>
<p>(( -- James Craig, Sao Paulo newsroom 5511 248 5413))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I35101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
