<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266897" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia minister sees vigorous growth in 2H 1997.</title>
<headline>Colombia minister sees vigorous growth in 2H 1997.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombia's economy should return to vigorous growth in the second half of 1997 at the latest, Finance Minister Jose Antonio Ocampo said Thursday.</p>
<p>And while Ocampo predicted the strongest growth of 1997 would come after June, he repeated Wednesday's comments that signs of recovery were already visible and that business optimism was on the rise.</p>
<p>&quot;I expect the economy will take off midway through next year. The first half of 1997 will be a period of recovery and that optimism is already being seen in business surveys,&quot; Ocampo told the Caracol radio network.  </p>
<p>Although the 1996 growth in gross domestic product was just 3.0 percent, he said the economic slump had not been as bad as some critics had first feared. GDP growth was down from 5.28 percent in 1995 but not as low as the 1991 result -- the worst of the decade so far -- of 2.0 percent.</p>
<p>Ocampo's predictions coincide with those of private business analysts who are forecasting a general upturn in the economy, spearheaded by growth in the recession-hit construction industry, from July 1997.</p>
<p>Private analysts still have doubts, however, about the prospects for key exports sectors next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
