<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266826" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ARGENTINA: Argentina may decree more labor laws - minister.</title>
<headline>Argentina may decree more labor laws - minister.</headline>
<dateline>BUENOS AIRES 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Argentine government may decree more labor market flexibility legislation if Congress continues to balk at approving its controversial plans, Labor Minister Armando Caro Figueroa said Thursday.</p>
<p>President Carlos Menem late Wednesday signed decrees cutting union wage negotiating power and eroding their health plan monopoly. He took the decision, which provoked unions to say they will consider a general strike, after talks with unions ended in stalemate and the government was unable to push its measures through Congress.</p>
<p>But Caro Figueroa said more decrees may be on the way, according to the state-run Telam news agency.</p>
<p>&quot;It should be understood that these decrees do not exhaust the part of the reform which can be carried out by decree,&quot; he said. &quot;The government is analyzing other subjects which are important for the reform, which go further than the bills sent to Congress and so we are studying two or three regulations more.&quot;</p>
<p>Apart from Wednesday's decrees, the government had tried to prod Congress into passing laws to establish an unemployment insurance fund to replace compensation payments for dismissal and make work contracts much more flexible.</p>
<p>Union anger at the government plans led to a 36-hour general strike in September.</p>
<p>-- Jason Webb, Buenos Aires Newsroom +541 318-0655</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E41">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GJOB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUENOS AIRES"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ARGENTINA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
