<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="266905" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>MEXICO: Snowfall outside Mexico City, rain in coffee belts.</title>
<headline>Snowfall outside Mexico City, rain in coffee belts.</headline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Snow fell on the mountains outside Mexico City Thursday while coffee growing belts saw temperatures above freezing and recorded light rains, meterologists said.</p>
<p>The cold front edging slowly southward from the United States brought frosts to much of northern Mexico. Central Mexico went largely unscathed, except on mountain tops, the National Meterological Service reported in an update.</p>
<p>&quot;There is a possibility of more snow in the mountains of the central plains above 3,600 meters (12,000 feet),&quot; it said.  </p>
<p>TV network Televisa showed images of snow falling on the Ajusco mountains to the north of the capital, which are around 3,600 meters high.</p>
<p>Temperatures given in coffee growing regions were all above freezing.</p>
<p>At Jalapa in Veracruz state, the maximum-minimum for Thursday were predicted to be 15-10 degrees celsius, the service said.</p>
<p>At Oaxaca in Oaxaca state, they were 23-05 degrees, at Tapachula in Chiapas state, they were 32-18 and in Puebla in Puebla state they were 10-16 degrees.  </p>
<p>Rains was falling in most southern states, the service said, predicting between 50 and 70 millimeters would fall in the next 243 hours in Veracruz and Chiapas states.</p>
<p>Further north in non-coffee growing regions, temperatures were largely below zero celsius.</p>
<p>The sevrices said Ciudad Juarez saw an overnight minimum of -8 degrees celsius, Chihuahua -9, Durango -3, Monterrey -4, Matamoros -1.</p>
<p>((--Chris Aspin, Mexico City newsroom (525) 7289530. E-mail at chris.aspin@reuters.com))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I01001">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I0100137">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GWEA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MEXICO"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
