<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267013" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: PWE says going alone with pulp mill.</title>
<headline>PWE says going alone with pulp mill.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>PWE Industries Bhd said on Thursday its proposed joint venture with an Indonesian partner to establish a pulp mill in eastern Malaysia would be aborted.</p>
<p>The company would, however, &quot;proceed on its own to undertake the setting up of...the mill&quot;.</p>
<p>In a statement to the Kuala Lumpur Stock Exchange, the company said it would subscribe to a 100 percent stake in Sarawak Pulp &amp; Paper Sdn Bhd to set up the &quot;high-technology&quot; pulp mill in the Bintulu district of Sarawak on Borneo island.</p>
<p>Sarawak Pulp &amp; Paper was orginally supposed to have been 45 percent owned by PWE and 55 percent by the undisclosed Indonesian partner, PWE said in March.</p>
<p>The company said it would also carry out the &quot;development, reforestation and management&quot; of a plantation to ensure continued wood supply for the proposed mill.</p>
<p>The projected cost of establishing the mill and carrying out a reforestation program is estimated to be 3.5 billion ringgit ($1.2 billion)</p>
<p>Output from the mill would be about 1.2 million tonnes a year, the company said.</p>
<p>PWE executive chairman Ting Pek Khiing said in April the project was expected to be launched by 1998 and annual income derived from it was estimated at 200 million ringgit or 60 percent of earnings.</p>
<p>-- Kuala Lumpur newsroom (603-2307509)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I34000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C24">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
