<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267090" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JORDAN: Iraq still evaluating sugar offers - Jordan trade.</title>
<headline>Iraq still evaluating sugar offers - Jordan trade.</headline>
<dateline>AMMAN 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Iraq was evaluating over 120 offers from international sugar houses for supplies of two to four cargoes of sugar, but there were no signs of an imminent decision, Jordanian traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;They took the offers and are evaluating those who are offering from origin or reliable sources, but so far nothing has been negotiated,&quot; said a Jordanian agent of a well-known sugar supplier who has submitted a bid.</p>
<p>European traders said this week Baghdad will buy on December 17 between four and six cargoes of lower quality white sugar for arrival between mid-February and early March.  </p>
<p>Jordanian traders say Iraq was seeking to buy between two and four cargoes of sugar of between 12,000-14,000 tonnes each, with the extent of Iraqi puchases dependent on prices.</p>
<p>&quot;We are not sure how much the Iraqis are going to buy, whether one cargo, or two or whether they will buy at all,&quot; said another trader who said he did not expect the Iraqis to decide before early next week.</p>
<p>&quot;The Iraqis are not being specific in their needs and this is causing confusion in the markets while prices are firming up,&quot; said another commodities trader.</p>
<p>Iraq said recently it could import some 300,000 tonnes of sugar over a six-month period when it will be selling oil in exchange for food under a $2 billion deal approved by the U.N. --Amman Newsroom +9626-623776</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="JORDAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="AMMAN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JORDAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
