<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267050" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: Japan unveils sweeping forex deregulation plan.</title>
<headline>Japan unveils sweeping forex deregulation plan.</headline>
<byline>Tatsuo Ito</byline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Japan, faced with a &quot;hollowing out&quot; of its financial markets, on Thursday announced a sweeping plan to deregulate its foreign exchange market in 1998 in a bid to put the Tokyo market in the same league as London and New York.</p>
<p>Officials said the plan will accelerate the pace of a planned loosening of control over tax systems and securities transactions and will intensify competition among Japanese financial institutions and with foreign companies.</p>
<p>&quot;The main purpose of the liberalisation is to revive the Tokyo financial market and make it internationally competitive with those in New York and London,&quot; said Tomomitsu Oba, subcommittee chairman of the Committee on Foreign Exchange and Other Transactions, an advisory panel to the finance minister.</p>
<p>The panel, in its final report, called for full deregulation of participation in Tokyo's foreign currency markets by scrapping the current rule which limits forex transactions to authorised foreign exchange banks.</p>
<p>The panel also called for freer cross-border capital transactions and settlements by individuals and corporations with their overseas counterparts.</p>
<p>Tight regulations, which had in the past protected Japanese financial institutions from foreign competition, have left Tokyo far behind other money centres in terms of volume of transactions and foreign participation.</p>
<p>Daily foreign exchange transactions averaged $167 billion in Tokyo in April 1995, compared with $477 billion in London and $266 billion in New York.</p>
<p>And only 77 foreign companies are listed on the stock market in Tokyo compared with 531 in London and 247 in New York.</p>
<p>&quot;The hollowing out of Japan's financial markets will accelerate unless the Japanese market is liberalised,&quot; said Eisuke Sakakibara, director-general of the Finance Ministry's International Finance Bureau.</p>
<p>Japan's financial markets are hollowing out because foreign securities and financial institutions refuse to come here or are leaving Tokyo for other areas where they face fewer regulations and lower costs.</p>
<p>Sakakibara warned that Japanese financial institutions are going to face intensified competition as a result of the deregulation. &quot;I hope Japanese financial institutions will be well prepared for severe competition in the future,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Katsuhito Sasajima, a financial analyst at Nikko Research Center, said the deregulation will increase competition among banks as new participants enter the foreign exchange business.</p>
<p>&quot;Without expanding their business areas, banks will not be able to survive,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Some analysts showed reacted coolly to the deregulation package. &quot;They just made a framework, and to make it successful participants in the market must change their traditional way of thinking and behaviour,&quot; said Taisuke Tanaka, market strategist at Credit Suisse in Tokyo.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Ryutaro Hashimoto has vowed to carry out &quot;Big Bang&quot; financial reforms to implement substantial deregulation by 2001.</p>
<p>The report contained several main points:</p>
<p>It urged that any participant be allowed to engage in currency transactions and settlements. Currently, only authorised banks can handle foreign currencies.</p>
<p>It said the system of having to get permission and give prior notification for cross-border capital transactions must be abolished.</p>
<p>It added that all market participants should be allowed to conduct foreign exchange business, such as the sale and purchase of foreign currencies, currency futures contracts, currency swaps and options.</p>
<p>It also said the current system in which currency transactions are made only at designated securities firms and money exchangers should be abolished.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
