<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267048" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>MALAYSIA: Malaysia rubber market ends mixed on holiday mood.</title>
<headline>Malaysia rubber market ends mixed on holiday mood.</headline>
<dateline>KUALA LUMPUR 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Malaysian rubber prices ended mixed after weak interest shown by players distracted by the approach of year-end holidays, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;It's the holiday mood,&quot; said a trader. &quot;There's no real buying or selling going on, except maybe some hand-to-mouth short-covering.&quot;</p>
<p>At the close, the Malaysian Rubber Exchange and Licensing Board quoted January RSS1 buyer at 318.50 ($1.26) a kg, down half cent from Wednesday's close. January SMR 20 buyer was quoted half cent down at 308.50 cents.  </p>
<p>Traders said business in December was usually slow, with the Christmas and New Year festivities distracting players.</p>
<p>Producers were, however, trying to hold to prices because rains in recent weeks have drastically reduced supply of raw materials into the market, said traders.</p>
<p>Trading houses were quoting the SMR 20 at 307 cents, SMR CV at 362, SMR L at 343, SMR 10 at 308, and drum latex at 236.</p>
<p>The INRO five-day moving average rose to 242.78 Malaysian/Singapore cents per kg on Dec 18 from 242.18 on Dec 17. The daily indicator price fell to 243.30 from 243.87.</p>
<p>-- Barani Krishnaan (603-230-7509) ($1=2.5250 ringgit)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MALAY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KUALA LUMPUR"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="MALAYSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
