<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267166" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. sends security advisers to tackle Peru crisis.</title>
<headline>U.S. sends security advisers to tackle Peru crisis.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United States sent security advisers to Peru on Thursday to assist U.S. officials dealing with the hostage crisis in Lima as President Bill Clinton said he was &quot;very concerned&quot; about the captives.</p>
<p>&quot;Obviously we are keeping up with it very closely and we're very concerned about it,&quot; Clinton said of the hostage drama involving about 400 captives, including many high-ranking diplomats and businessmen.</p>
<p>&quot;We're concerned about all those held hostage,&quot; Clinton told reporters while posing for pictures at the start of a meeting in the Oval Office.</p>
<p>Secretary of State Warren Christopher made clear that Washington's concern for the captives should not be viewed as pressure to bow to the demands of the leftist rebels.</p>
<p>&quot;The United States has a strong policy against making any concessions and we advise all those involved to follow that policy,&quot; Christopher told a news conference.</p>
<p>State Department spokesman Nicholas Burns said Washington did not wish to &quot;micromanage&quot; the hostage drama, but told reporters: &quot;We don't make concessions to terrorists and our advice is that other governments not make concessions either.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;Terrorists win if you give in to them. Terrorists win if you meet their demands,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Hundreds of people are being held in Lima by Tupac Amaru Revolutionary Movement (MRTA) guerrillas who stormed a reception at the Japanese ambassador's residence on Tuesday evening in a bid to win the release of jailed comrades.</p>
<p>Burns said the U.S. government had just sent to Lima &quot;a group of American security advisers who will be advising ambassador (Dennis) Jett on ways that we can help to protect American citizens.&quot;</p>
<p>They had been sent &quot;as a precaution and to basically help ambassador Jett,&quot; he said. The security advisers came from a variety of U.S. government agencies, he added, refusing to give further details.</p>
<p>Jett and his deputy chief of mission were at the reception but left before the guerrillas struck. Burns refused to comment on reports that six U.S. officials were among the hostages.</p>
<p>Burns said a key task for the U.S. embassy was to ensure protection of about 10,000 Americans living in Peru. &quot;You have to prepare yourself for any kind of eventuality,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Attorney General Janet Reno said separately the FBI and Justice Department have been working with Clinton's National Security Council staff in reviewing the Lima hostage standoff.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
