<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267216" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US FCC unveils plan to drive down int'l call rates.</title>
<headline>US FCC unveils plan to drive down int'l call rates.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. Federal Communications Commission (FCC) proposed on Friday measures to try to force foreign carriers to reduce the rates they charge for international calls and drive down the cost for U.S. users.  </p>
<p>In its proposal, the FCC set target ceilings for settlement rates, the amount the phone company in the destination country charges the originating phone company to complete a call.</p>
<p>The upper limit would be 15 cents per minute for high-income countries, 19 cents per minute for middle-income countries and 23 cents per minute for low-income countries.</p>
<p>U.S. carriers would negotiate the reciprocal rates with foreign phone companies. The FCC proposed a one-year schedule for developed countries, two years for middle-income countries, and four years for developing countries.  </p>
<p>A cut in settlement rates, which account for only a part of the total cost paid by the user, would bring the price of an international phone call closer to actual costs, the FCC said.</p>
<p>The measure would also lower net outpayments from the United States to foreign carriers -- almost $5 billion in 1995 -- and expand the $50 billion global market for international calls, the FCC said.</p>
<p>U.S. consumers currently pay 99 cents a minute for an international call, compared with 16 cents a minute for domestic calls, even though the actual cost is similar, the FCC said.</p>
<p>The FCC called for initial comments on its proposal by February 7 and for reply comments by March 10.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I79020">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
