<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267303" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. Midwest power up about $20/MWh from week-ago.</title>
<headline>U.S. Midwest power up about $20/MWh from week-ago.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Wholesale spot electricity prices for the U.S. Midwest were steady to higher Thursday, gaining about $20 on week-ago levels, but the market was beginning to show some stability, sources said.</p>
<p>Temperatures throughout most of the Midwest are expected to be much below normal Friday but then moderate slightly for the weekend.</p>
<p>However, another cold front is expected to arrive early next week, weighing temperatures down about 15-25 degrees Fahrenheit below-normal.</p>
<p>In the Mid-Continent Area Power Pool (MAPP), peak non-firm power prices for Friday delivery were in the $40.00-42.00 per megawatt hour (MWh) range, as compared with Wednesday's $41.00-43.00 trading range.</p>
<p>Off-peak non-firm MAPP power deals were assessed at $16.00-17.00.</p>
<p>In the Mid-American Interpool Network (MAIN), peak, non-firm power prices for Friday delivery were about $1 higher in the $40.00-41.00 range.</p>
<p>Next-week peak prices in MAIN were talked significantly lower in the $27.50-28.50 range.</p>
<p>MAIN off peak power was notionally assessed in the $15.00-16.00 range.</p>
<p>Peak, non-firm electricity prices in the East Central Area Reliability Coordination Agreement (ECAR) for Friday were in the $40.00-42.00 range, as compared with Wednesday's $36.00-37.00 trading range. Some deals were reported done as high as $45.00.</p>
<p>Peak prices for next week in ECAR were talked around $28.00.</p>
<p>January/February ECAR prices were steady in the $25.50-26.00 range, while March business was still talked in the $21.40-22.00 area.</p>
<p>Off-peak, non-firm next-day ECAR power was notionally talked up at least a $1 at $16.00.</p>
<p>In the Southwest Power Pool (SPP), peak non-firm power for Friday delivery was quoted mostly around $42 per MWh, up about $2 from Wednesday's trading range.</p>
<p>January/February peak prices in SPP were talked up about 20 cents to the $27.80-29.10 range, while March prices were around $23.75-24.25 range, traders said.</p>
<p>Off-peak prices throughout SPP were notionally around $17.00.</p>
<p>Kansas City Power and Light Co's 670 megawatt (MW) Iatan coal-fired unit, shut early Tuesday, was set to return to service around 1200 CST Thursday, the company said.</p>
<p>Also, Omaha Public Service's 585 MW coal-fired unit in Nebraska City, Neb., is expected to resume operating early Friday.</p>
<p>Contributing to the stronger electricity prices were the still higher natural gas prices. In the Midcontinent, gas for Friday delivery amid pipeline freeze-offs traded anywhere from $4.60 to about $4.80, with the bulk of the deals done in the high-$4.60s.</p>
<p>((H McCulloch, New York Power Desk +212-859-1628))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
