<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267489" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Pressure eases on German parliament speaker.</title>
<headline>Pressure eases on German parliament speaker.</headline>
<byline>Kevin Liffey</byline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's embattled parliamentary speaker Rita Suessmuth got preliminary backing on Thursday from a probe into alleged misuse of official aircraft as Chancellor Helmut Kohl denied party leaders wanted to discredit her.</p>
<p>Deputy speaker Hans-Ulrich Klose of the opposition Social Democrats (SPD) issued a statement saying that &quot;an initial review of Mrs Suessmuth's flight schedule has not provided indications of an inappropriate use of official aircraft&quot;.</p>
<p>The comment was the first piece of good news this week for Suessmuth, the &quot;Mrs Clean&quot; of German politics, who has been under pressure over allegations she regularly used official aircraft to visit her daughter in Zurich.</p>
<p>Although Suessmuth is a member of Kohl's Christian Democratic Union (CDU), she is not well-liked within the party because of her advocacy of women's issues and what many conservatives see as her moralising stand on social questions.</p>
<p>The liberal views of Germany's most successful woman politician, ranked second only to the president in the state hierarchy, have also more than once put her at odds with Kohl.</p>
<p>But Kohl denied speculation on Thursday that the CDU wanted to discredit Suessmuth.</p>
<p>His spokesman Peter Hausmann told journalists the CDU's silence so far did not imply any plot to harm her image.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Schaeuble, the powerful CDU parliamentary leader, also publicly defended Suessmuth, who denies the charges and says her Swiss trips were all on official business.</p>
<p>&quot;Chancellor Helmut Kohl wants to make clear that there are no efforts in the CDU leadership to damage the reputation of the parliament speaker,&quot; said Hausmann.</p>
<p>Schaeuble told a news conference: &quot;I don't have the slightest reason to doubt what Mrs Suessmuth said, namely that, when she flew with the Bundeswehr (armed forces) as we all do, she did it for official reasons.&quot;</p>
<p>Suessmuth has asked Klose to produce a detailed report on behalf of parliament's Council of Elders. His statement said a final evaluation would only be possible after a point-by-point examination which could not be unduly hurried.</p>
<p>Speculation has been mounting in the German press that Suessmuth, who has declined to deny that there might be a smear campaign against her, might be forced to step down.</p>
<p>The popular daily Bild, which has run front-page charges against Suessmuth for the past five days, said on Thursday she had taken 31 flights to or from Switzerland since January 1993, most of them at weekends.</p>
<p>It printed a detailed list of all the flights and details of several recent visits to see her daughter.</p>
<p>But Suessmuth on Thursday secured an interim court injunction against Bild's publisher, Axel Springer Verlag AG, preventing it accusing her of using official aircraft for private purposes in the last two years.</p>
<p>Suessmuth, 59, said on Wednesday she had made nine trips to Switzerland in the past two years, not including return flights, and all were official.</p>
<p>The SPD said the lack of public support for Suessmuth from her own party showed the CDU might be considering dropping her.</p>
<p>Wilfred Penner, the SPD head of parliament's domestic affairs committee, called the silence from her fellow party members &quot;the most intensive form of backing away&quot; and said it appeared the leaks to Bild could have come from CDU sources.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
