<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267504" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>SWITZERLAND: Swiss not compensated with Holocaust funds - report.</title>
<headline>Swiss not compensated with Holocaust funds - report.</headline>
<byline>Felix Bauer</byline>
<dateline>BERNE 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>An official Swiss report said on Thursday that Switzerland returned the unclaimed wealth of Holocaust victims to Poland and Hungary after World War Two, but denied Berne used the funds to pay Swiss for communist-seized property.</p>
<p>Two independent historians commissioned by the government declined to back up charges by Jewish groups and a senior U.S. senator that Berne used assets left dormant because their owners perished in Nazi death camps to settle Swiss claims over assets nationalised in Eastern Europe.</p>
<p>But their report said Berne should consider &quot;concrete compensation measures&quot; for years of mistakes in handling dormant bank accounts that may have come from victims of Nazi terror.</p>
<p>It also urged Switzerland to use its comprehensive federal archives to hunt belatedly for any East Europeans, including Holocaust survivors, whose Swiss wealth was declared ownerless after the war and who fell victim to Cold War politics.</p>
<p>Switzerland has faced a flood of criticism from world Jewish groups about the way it handled accounts left ownerless by murdered Jews and other victims of Nazi oppression.</p>
<p>The historians' report said Switzerland assigned funds from dormant accounts to communist-ruled Poland and Hungary under postwar compensation accords on confiscated Swiss property, in line with principles of international private law.</p>
<p>It confirmed that Switzerland had paid Poland 16,000 Swiss francs in 1960 from accounts the Poles claimed should revert to them since the missing owners had last lived in Poland. Berne paid Warsaw another 464,000 francs in 1975.</p>
<p>But it said this was not tantamount to paying off Swiss.</p>
<p>&quot;Transferred wealth from dormant accounts did not flow back to the dispossessed Swiss, but rather increased the Polish government's general leeway to use hard currency,&quot; co-author Peter Hug told reporters. He noted the larger payment came only after Warsaw had finished compensating Swiss claimants.</p>
<p>Switzerland also paid Hungary 325,000 francs in 1975 based on the same home-country claim. This -- like the second payment to Poland -- came from a 1960s fund of unclaimed bank accounts left ownerless by Jews and other victims of Nazi persecution.</p>
<p>The payment to Hungary stememd from a confidential amendment to a 1973 treaty under which Switzerland deducted Hungary's claims for dormant accounts from Swiss claims for compensation.</p>
<p>&quot;Hungarian counterclaims for a total of 400,000 francs were directly netted off against the sum of 1.8 million francs in compensation owed Swiss property owners,&quot; it said, but both governments announced only the net 1.4 million figure.</p>
<p>Similar claims from other eastern European countries behind the Iron Curtain were rejected and the report said Poland and Hungary had signed agreements to recognise the claims of rightful heirs if they turned up.</p>
<p>The report confirmed that the search for survivors or heirs was restricted to the West by a Swiss policy that barred research behind the Iron Curtain, on the assumption that enquiries could endanger residents of communist countries.</p>
<p>&quot;We recommend that the Swiss Federal Archive's wholly preserved and well-ordered dossiers on East European accounts declared ownerless be reviewed and any surviving contact persons be sought quickly,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>The historians also said the Swiss government had made repeated mistakes in handling the issue of ownerless accounts, including paying Hungary in secret without notifying parliament.</p>
<p>&quot;Considering the decades of omissions, it is recommended that further steps be considered in order to fulfil today's perception of justice,&quot; the report said.</p>
<p>It said those measures would include further research as well as &quot;concrete compensation measures&quot;, but did not not specifiy them or say who should be compensated.</p>
<p>Berne is setting up a broad historical enquiry into Switzerland's wartime role as a financial centre.</p>
<p>The cabinet on Thursday named Swiss historian Jean-Francois Bergier to head the nine-member panel. It has four foreigners, including former Polish foreign minister Wladyslaw Bartoszewski.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HUNG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SWITZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BERNE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SWITZERLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
