<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="267574" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>BELGIUM: Clabecq says to file for bankruptcy.</title>
<headline>Clabecq says to file for bankruptcy.</headline>
<byline>Lorrayne Smith</byline>
<dateline>BRUSSELS 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Belgium's Walloon region, majority shareholder in Forges de Clabecq, has decided to withdraw its support for the steel firm and the company will file for bankruptcy on Friday, a Clabecq spokeswoman said on Thursday.</p>
<p>She was confirming a report on Belgian news agency Belga, which said the Walloon government Minister-President Robert Collignon announced to the Walloon Parliament that the region had decided to support Clabecq no longer.</p>
<p>The report said the company's management would go to a commercial court on Friday to file for bankruptcy, which the spokeswoman also confirmed.</p>
<p>Collignon said the court could decide to appoint an expert, a liquidator or a trustee. It could also decide that activities should carry on at Clabecq, in part or in their entirety.</p>
<p>The fate of the loss-making steel firm, which employs 1,700 people, was sealed on Wednesday when the European Commission rejected a rescue plan by the Walloon region for Clabecq.</p>
<p>The project involved an offer of 1.5 billion Belgian francs of capital, 700 million francs of credit already granted, the writing-off of debts worth more than 800 million francs and the rescheduling of other borrowings.</p>
<p>But the Commission said the subsidies went against EU rules which only allowed steel sector aid for environmental reasons, for research and development or for company closure.</p>
<p>At the same time it pledged to help the region with reconversion and to attract other investment which was &quot;more likely to bear fruit.&quot;</p>
<p>Collignon was quoted by Belga as saying a decision had been made in favour of working wholeheartedly towards a reconversion.</p>
<p>The Walloon government would adopt a standpoint at the start of 1997 on the structure of a reconversion programme and the means with which it would be carried out.</p>
<p>It also reserved the right to appeal against the European Commission's decision to reject its rescue plan, he said.</p>
<p>Collignon hoped a certain amount of activity could be preserved at Clabecq, notably the blast furnace to supply near-by privately-owned small steel firm Usines Gustave Boel.</p>
<p>Clabecq has struggled to survive in a volatile market marked by overcapacity and cheap imports from eastern Europe, and had failed to find a partner to improve its position.</p>
<p>A report on Clabecq commissioned by the Walloon region earlier this year showed its costs were 20 to 30 percent above the average of its competitors. The company has also been saddled with poor operational margins and low-quality products.</p>
<p>Illustrating the firm's problems, its book value per share stands at a negative 850 francs. By contrast, Wallonia's biggest steel maker Cockerill Sambre has a book value per share of 980 francs.</p>
<p>Clabecq shares were last traded down seven francs at 76 on the Brussels bourse cash market on Thursday, where they are subjected to twice daily fixings, but the bid/ask prices were indicated at 12 francs.</p>
<p>Because of an excess of sellers, the bourse imposes a maximum daily markdown of 10 percent on the stock.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BELG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I22100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BRUSSELS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BELGIUM"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
