<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26782" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>ANGOLA: ANGOLA'S NATIONAL BANK HALTS COMMERCIAL ACTIVITIES.</title>
<headline>ANGOLA'S NATIONAL BANK HALTS COMMERCIAL ACTIVITIES.</headline>
<dateline>LUANDA 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Angola's national bank halted all of its commercial activities on Monday and transferred them to the state-owned Caixa de Credito Agro Pecuaria e Pescas (CAP), the daily Jornal de Angola said.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the move had been approved by the Council of Ministers in July 1996 and was part of the restructuring of the central bank which began last year.</p>
<p>&quot;The National Bank of Angola (BNA) ceases as of today its commercial activities and assumes only the functions of the central bank, within the framework of modernising the finance sector of the country,&quot; the newspaper reported.</p>
<p>Previously, the BNA was involved in commercial activities such as providing loans to the agricultural sector through its 18 regional branches.</p>
<p>These functions would now be passed on to CAP -- an investment bank involved in credit operations in the agriculture, fishing and coffee sectors.</p>
<p>The newspaper said the process of reorganising the central bank was aimed at restricting its activities only to the issuing and control of the monetary system.</p>
<p>A meeting of the Committee of Governors of the Southern Afircan Development Community (SADC) recommended at a meeting in March this year in South Africa that Angola abandon its &quot;commercial slope and attach its monetary functions to the central bank&quot;, the newspaper said.</p>
<p>-- Luanda newsroom, +2442 393-341</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ANGOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81401">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LUANDA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ANGOLA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
