<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="268091" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>DUBAI: Mideast Gulf oil outlook - bullish despite Iraq.</title>
<headline>Mideast Gulf oil outlook - bullish despite Iraq.</headline>
<dateline>DUBAI 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>Gulf crude and refined oil product markets have shrugged off Iraq's return to the market and prices should consolidate in current ranges as winter temperatures grip main consumer markets, Gulf oil traders said on Thursday.</p>
<p>Iraq's first exports of crude in six years under a United Nations &quot;oil-for-food&quot; deal has failed to check further gains in outright refined product prices or dent premiums for Gulf crudes loading in February.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq has not been a factor in this market...It's more focused on the weather,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>Middle distillates, naphtha and fuel oil prices have all risen in the Gulf catching and outpacing gains in crude.</p>
<p>Naphtha has rallied to post-Gulf War highs of $225.90 a tonne fob Gulf while gas oil and jet kerosene have gained over $1.50 a barrel to $31.90 and $32.35 respectively without the aid of major additional buying from India and the completion of scheduled refinery maintenance work.</p>
<p>Gulf gas oil was $22.05 a barrel on December 19 last year.</p>
<p>Gulf markets did find support from Pakistan's award of 480,000 tonnes of diesel in eight cargoes for delivery in the first quarter, Gulf traders said.</p>
<p>It was not yet clear when, how much or which grades of refined products Iraq will export under the U.N. deal.</p>
<p>Before its 1990 invasion of Kuwait, Iraq was exporting mainly gas oil (diesel) and fuel oil.</p>
<p>Gulf firms have entered product contracts with Iraq's State Oil Marketing Organisation (SOMO) and at least one has had talks on securing product storage facilities at the port of Jebel Ali in Dubai in the United Arab Emirates.</p>
<p>&quot;Iraq has an export capacity of 12,000-14,000 tonnes a day of fuel oil and around 2,000-3,000 tonnes a day of gas oil from the north; and 4,000 tonnes a day of fuel oil and 1,500 tonnes a day of gas oil from the south,&quot; the Cyprus-based Middle East Economic Survey (MEES) newsletter reported this week.</p>
<p>Gulf crude premiums have been resilient despite the prospect of up to 600,000 barrels per day (bpd) of Iraqi crude with Abu Dhabi light grades commanding a 70 to 80 cents premium.</p>
<p>-- Steven Swindells, Dubai Newsroom +971 4 671255</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="IRAQ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="DUBAI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
