<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="268081" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish shares edge up 0.16 pct to new record.</title>
<headline>Turkish shares edge up 0.16 pct to new record.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-12-18</dateline>
<text>
<p>Istanbul shares firmed slightly in highly selective activity on Thursday despite profit-taking which erased most of the early morning gains, brokers said.</p>
<p>The IMKB-100 closed 146.74 points, or 0.16 percent higher at a new all-time high of 94,451.17, compared to a previous high of 94,407.21 on December 6. It fell from an early high of 96,480.</p>
<p>In dollar terms, the index stood at $0.89, down from $0.92 on December 6 and a $1 record on April 8.</p>
<p>Trade volume jumped to 31.19 trillion lira ($294.8 million) from Wednesday's 25.15 trillion ($238.3 million) with the help of fresh cash influx.</p>
<p>&quot;The market may revive the old index target of one dollar. Such profit-taking waves are normal. Strong volume confirms the current rise and the index may exceed 95,000 if activity spills over to the whole market,&quot; said Nazmi Sarikaya from Disbank.</p>
<p>The index had lost 5.37 percent last week amid rumours ahead of the S&amp;P's rating cut and negative sentiment after a failed attempt to overcome stiff resistance at 95,000.</p>
<p>Three-day gains totalled 8.37 percent since Monday's 2.44 percent fall prompted by the S&amp;P's dowgrading of Turkey's long-term foreign currency debt rating last Friday.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-18"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
