<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="268290" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>GERMANY: Kohl denies plot against top German woman leader.</title>
<headline>Kohl denies plot against top German woman leader.</headline>
<dateline>BONN 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>German Chancellor Helmut Kohl on Thursday denied that his Christian Democratic Union (CDU) wanted to discredit embattled parliament speaker Rita Suessmuth with charges of misusing official aircraft.</p>
<p>Kohl's spokesman Peter Hausmann told journalists the CDU's silence so far over the affair, which blew up this week with charges Suessmuth used official planes to visit her daughter in Zurich, was not a plot to harm her image.</p>
<p>Wolfgang Schaeuble, the powerful CDU parliamentary leader, also spoke up and publicly defended Suessmuth, who denies the charges and says her Swiss trips were all on official business.</p>
<p>&quot;Chancellor Helmut Kohl wants to make clear that there are no efforts in the CDU leadership to damage the reputation of the parliament speaker,&quot; said Hausmann.</p>
<p>At another press conference, Schaeuble said: &quot;I don't have the slightest reason to doubt what Mrs Suessmuth said, namely that, when she flew with the Bundeswehr (armed forces) as we all do, she did it for official reasons.&quot;</p>
<p>Suessmuth, whose &quot;Mrs Clean&quot; image has made her Germany's most popular politician, is not well-liked within the CDU itself because of her advocacy of women's issues and what many conservatives see as her moralising stand on social questions.</p>
<p>CDU backbenchers have been grumbling since the Bonn public prosecutor said on Tuesday he was considering bringing a charge of misuse of the official planes against her.</p>
<p>Speculation has also been mounting in the German press that Suessmuth, who is second to President Roman Herzog in the state hierarchy, might be forced to step down.</p>
<p>The popular Bild daily, which has run front-page charges against Suessmuth for the past five days, said on Thursday she had taken 31 flights to or from Switzerland since January 1993, most of them at weekends.</p>
<p>It printed a detailed list of each flight and details of several recent visits with her daughter.</p>
<p>Suessmuth, 59, a prominent member of the CDU's small liberal wing, said on Wednesday she had made nine trips to Switzerland in the past two years and all were official.</p>
<p>The opposition Social Democrats (SPD) said the lack of public support for Suessmuth from her own party showed the CDU might be considering dropping her.</p>
<p>Wilfred Penner, SPD head of parliament's domestic affairs committee, called the silence &quot;the most intensive form of backing away&quot; from her and said it appeared the leaks to Bild could have come from CDU sources.</p>
<p>Suessmuth, who has often travelled abroad on parliamentary business since becoming speaker in 1988, survived a 1991 scandal about her husband's use of her official limousine.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BONN"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GERMANY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
