<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26846" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Oil price jumps a dollar as Iraqi sale delayed.</title>
<headline>Oil price jumps a dollar as Iraqi sale delayed.</headline>
<byline>Richard Mably</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>World oil prices jumped on Monday after the United Nations put on hold an Iraqi oil-for-food exchange in response to Baghdad's military incursion into its northern Kurdish region.</p>
<p>October futures for international benchmark North Sea Brent blend ended a sharp $1.21 higher at $21.99 a barrel.</p>
<p>Oil traders had been expecting Iraq to make its first oil sales on world markets for six years since the Gulf War in the next few weeks.</p>
<p>But U.N. Secretary General Boutros Boutros Ghali on Sunday responded to Baghdad's military move into a U.N. safe haven in Iraqi Kurdistan by delaying the deployment of U.N. personnel to supervise aid distribution under the oil exchange plan.</p>
<p>Iraq massed 30,000 to 40,000 troops in its northern Kurdish provinces and captured the city of Arbil at the weekend, expelling one Kurdish faction and installing a rival group.</p>
<p>By Monday Iraqi troops, along with heavy armour and artillery, were reported by U.N. personnel to have evacuated the Iraqi Kurdistan capital.</p>
<p>But the United States dismissed the Iraqi redeployment saying troops still were arrayed around Arbil. The White House said President Bill Clintion had a &quot;defined course of action,&quot; but declined to elaborate.</p>
<p>Turkey, which provides a pipeline link for Iraqi oil exports, said it expected to see the first Iraqi oil sales delayed &quot;for some time.&quot; They had been been expected this month.</p>
<p>&quot;The question may be not when will Iraqi oil sales start but whether they will start,&quot; said energy analyst Geoff Pyne at Swiss finance house UBS.</p>
<p>&quot;This is a real kick for the markets,&quot; said Oystein Berentsen, international crude trading manager for Norway's Statoil.</p>
<p>&quot;With demand so strong and oil stocks so low the market was looking as if it could quite easily have absorbed some Iraqi exports.&quot;</p>
<p>The Kurdish Democratic Party invited Iraqi President Saddam Hussein to intervene in the Kurdish-ruled region after it said the rival Patriotic Union of Kurdistan received backing from Iran in recent fighting. Iran denies involvement.</p>
<p>The U.N. oil-for-food deal would allow Iraq to sell $2 billion worth of oil over six months to purchase food, medicine and other goods for its people suffering sanctions imposed after Iraq invaded Kuwait in August 1990.</p>
<p>The deal signed on May 20 and renewable every six months under a U.N. review, was expected to supply tight world markets with about an extra 550,000 barrels a day (bpd) of crude at current prices.</p>
<p>Under the U.N. plan, dozens of monitors must be deployed across Iraq to make sure aid is fairly distributed among rebel populations. Plans to begin deployment of personnel have been halted for the moment.</p>
<p>Delays to the oil sale deal come at a time when oil prices were already running some $4 higher than at the same time last year and Middle East tensions are helping keep oil on the boil.</p>
<p>The United States, the world's biggest oil consumer, is still investigating a truck bomb that killed 19 Americans at a U.S. military complex in Saudi Arabia in June.</p>
<p>Saudi dissident Osama bin Laden, said to have influenced the Saudi nationals who carried out the attack, called last week for a holy war against U.S. troops in the region.</p>
<p>Low stocks of heating oil and diesel (distillates) in Europe and the United States helped drive European heating oil futures on Monday to five-year highs. London heating oil futures finished trading up $11.00 at $207.50 a tonne.</p>
<p>A strong demand outlook for industrialised consumer countries and a delay in some new North Sea oilfield projects have also added to the bullish market sentiment.</p>
<p>&quot;We can't expect Iraqi oil in the near future and distillate demand is still there for the winter,&quot; said Alastair Harris at brokers Mees Pierson Derivatives in London.</p>
<p>Crude oil prices in dollars per barrel:</p>
<p>						    Sep 02	 Aug 30</p>
<p>						    (close)	(close)</p>
<p>    Dated Brent				 $22.24	 $21.03</p>
<p>    IPE London Brent futures (Oct)	$21.99	 $20.78</p>
<p>    NYMEX light crude futures (Oct)	 ---	  $22.25</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
