<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26849" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: LCE coffee awaits NY reaction to new US funds long.</title>
<headline>LCE coffee awaits NY reaction to new US funds long.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Robusta coffee futures ended a quiet session softer on Monday, but the market was nervous ahead of New York's reaction on Tuesday to a substantial buildup in U.S. fund long positions, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;The (U.S.) funds are pretty heavily loaded now,&quot; said one London-based trader.</p>
<p>Traders said they were surprised and shocked by the large increase in U.S fund long positions of some 6,500 lots in the two weeks to August 27.</p>
<p>The increase, as reflected in the latest U.S Commitment of Traders Report, takes the total fund long postion to between some 10,500 and 10,739 lots, traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;At some stage these guys are going to have to get out of those positons,&quot; said one London-based broker.</p>
<p>The market is wary the increase in the fund long position could spark a sharp sell-off in the New York coffee futures when the market re-opens after Labour Day on Tuesday.</p>
<p>&quot;There is potential for a washout...The market is very nervous and there could be a bloodbath when New York re-opens,&quot; said another trader.</p>
<p>At the close on Monday the benchmark November robusta contract was off $15 at $1,620 a tonne.</p>
<p>On the spot September contract, unchanged at $1,670, traders said tenders reached 207 originals, which could encourage a widening of the Sept/Nov spread.</p>
<p>&quot;The market is waiting to see who will take delivery of the tenders,&quot; said another dealer.</p>
<p>But thin volume at 946 lots at the close, however, reflected the fact that many key players are still away for summer holidays and the absence of the key arabica market.</p>
<p>--Julia Meehan, London newsroom +4471 542 79 28</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
