<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26872" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK to seek ICAO support over Ukraine plane seizure.</title>
<headline>UK to seek ICAO support over Ukraine plane seizure.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>UK-based cargo airline Coyne Aviation said the UK government will ask the International Civil Aviation Organisation (ICAO) to investigate the seizure of a Coyne chartered Ilyushin-76 freighter aircraft by Ukraine customs on August 20.</p>
<p>The company's chief executive, Larry Coyne said in a statement: &quot;The action of the Ukraine authorities has serious implications for any operator making technical stops in Ukraine in the future.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;We have issued a formal complaint through the British government, who will ask the international Civil Aviation Organisation to investigate the matter fully,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The freighter was seized at Ukraine's Lvov airport on August 20, and detained for 10 days without formal explanation, the statement said.</p>
<p>The plane was only freed after obtaining a special permit, which effectively placed the aircraft under Ukrainian jurisdiction - as opposed to international law which normally governs aircraft making technical stops during international flights, it added.</p>
<p>The Ukraine-registered IL-76 freighter was making a fuelling stop at its home base of Lvov, during a flight from Maastricht to Baku in Azerbaijan.</p>
<p>The flight was one of some 800 similar movements which Coyne Aviation has operated between Europe and the CIS in the last two years, mostly using Ukraine-registered aircraft, the statement said.</p>
<p>The general cargo included 3300 kilos of explosive drilling charges and 229 kilos of measurement equipment containing radioactive material, destined for oil industry use.</p>
<p>The drilling chargs were originally shipped by air from Houston to Amsterdam, while the measuring equipment originated in Manchester, and was also flown to Amsterdam. Both shipments were then transferred to Maastricht, where they were loaded onto the aircraft by Maastricht Handling, it added.</p>
<p>Managing director of Maastricht Handling, Hans Peeters, said &quot;This was a totally legal and well-organised flight. The papers and packing were checked by us and by &quot;Dangerous Goods Management&quot;, who are one of only a very few specialists with the necessary licence to conduct such checks.</p>
<p>&quot;If anything had been wrong, these shipments would not have been given clearance to fly by us,&quot; he added</p>
<p>Coyne Aviation's chief executive Larry Coyne said: &quot;We have received no explanation for the Ukraine authorities' arrest of this aircraft. The aircraft and its load were typical of the regular flights which we operate into Baku and other points in the region. Ukraine customs made a serious mistake in detaining this aircraft and its urgent cargo.&quot;</p>
<p>When Coyne Aviation's enquiries persistently met with no response, the company was forced to take the matter to the highest levels in the Ukraine, the company added.</p>
<p>Coyne's pROtests were supported by government representatives of the U.S., Netherlands, UK and Azerbaijan.</p>
<p>Larry Coyne said &quot;If we had done anything wrong, I doubt that we would have received such high-level backing.&quot;</p>
<p>On August 30, Coyne Aviation was fully informed that the aircraft would be granted special permission to leave Lvov, provided the company accepted that the flight was subject to Ukraine jurisdiction as opposed to International law.</p>
<p>Coyne complied with this exceptional procedure, and the aircraft was finally released and departed Lvov ay 06.56 hrs on August 31, the statement said.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe this procedure may simply have been a means for Ukraine to clear itself of any accusation that it had acted unlawfully...... We complied with their proposal only as a means</p>
<p>of obtaining the aircraft's early release, and we informed the Ukraine authorities that we fully reserved out rights under international regulations,&quot; Larry Coyne added. -- Air Cargo Newsroom Tel+44 171 542 7706 Fax+44 17 542 5017</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I77002">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
