<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26881" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: Late bond market prices.</title>
<headline>Late bond market prices.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>This is how major world bond markets were trading in late European business on Monday.</p>
<p>GERMANY - German Bund futures recouped losses late in the session to finish in positive territory after a day of dull trade, traders said dealings were light with the U.S. market on holiday and a lack of news about German economic fundamentals. The September Bund future on the London International Financial Futures and Options Exchange (LIFFE) was trading at 97.29, up 0.11 from Friday's settlement price.</p>
<p>BRITAIN - UK gilts notched up respectable gains in a quiet session as players wait for U.S. market to re-open after the Labour day holiday, most see scope for T-bond bounce after Friday losses, which should help gilts edge higher ahead of Wednesdays UK monetary meeting. The September long gilt future on LIFFE was trading at 107-06/32, up 06/32 from Friday's settlement price.</p>
<p>FRANCE - French bond and PIBOR futures closed higher after a calm session of very light volume, flows were light in the absence of U.S. markets which were closed due to the Labor Day holiday. The September notional bond future on the MATIF in Paris settled at 123.16, up 0.02 from Friday's settlement price.</p>
<p>ITALY - Italian bond futures ticked up and held on to slightly higher levels by late afternoon helped by the firmer lira and dollar, trading volumes were moderate with no lead from Treasuries with the U.S. market closed for the Labour Day holiday. The September bond future on LIFFE was trading at 115.78, up 0.27 from Friday's settlement price.</p>
<p>UNITED STATES - The U.S. Treasury bond market is closed today for the Labor Day holiday, trading will resume on Tuesday. On Friday the key 30-year bond ended sharply lower as fears of a Fed credit tightening surfaced after the release of a new batch of stronger-than-expected economic data.</p>
<p>JAPAN - Key December 10-year Japanese government bond (JGB) futures closed easier as profit-taking emerged to inhibit cash bond rises. &quot;The market was quiet in the afternoon,&quot; said a long-term credit bank dealer. &quot;The rally in the morning from last week's firmer tone was dampened when profit-taking emerged (in cash bonds),&quot; he said. In after hours trading the December future on LIFFE was trading at 120.50, down 0.33 from Friday's settlement price on the Tokyo Stock Exchange.</p>
<p>EUROBONDS - New issues activity was at a standstill with today's U.S. holiday putting a cap on mainstream business after last Friday's shake-out in U.S. Treasury prices. The only item of note was Turkey's announcement that it will raise up to 200 million marks via a Eurobond in the near future.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
