<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="268864" id="root" date="1996-12-19" xml:lang="en">
<title>ISRAEL: Palestinians reject U.S. demand on Israeli talks.</title>
<headline>Palestinians reject U.S. demand on Israeli talks.</headline>
<byline>Taher Shriteh</byline>
<dateline>GAZA 1996-12-19</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Palestinian Authority rejected on Thursday a demand by Washington they reciprocate Israeli gestures in troubled talks over giving Palestinians self-rule in the West Bank town of Hebron.</p>
<p>A statement faxed from Albania, where Palestinian President Yasser Arafat was on a visit, rejected a U.S. State Department assessment on Wednesday that Israel had made some concessions in talks on Hebron and that Palestinians should respond in kind.</p>
<p>The State Department spokesmen did not specify the Israeli concessions in his statement.</p>
<p>&quot;Such statements don't give expression to the core and the reality of the Israeli stubborn position which does not want to reach any understanding,&quot; said the Palestinian Authority statement issued by the official WAFA news agency.</p>
<p>It accused Israel of trying to change the agreement signed at the White House in September 1995 under which Israel must hand over 80 percent of the West Bank town to self-rule.</p>
<p>Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu, elected in May, has sought to modify the deal to bolster security for the 400 Jews who live and study in the heart of Hebron among 100,000 Arabs.</p>
<p>Israel Radio and army radio reported meanwhile that the United States had sent Israel a sharply worded message critical of Netanyahu's announced plans to expand Jewish settlements.</p>
<p>Israel's tabloid Yedioth Ahronoth reported Washington was threatening to cut drastically or eliminate loan guarantees to Israel if Netanyahu's government carried out its plans.</p>
<p>Netanyahu adviser Dore Gold, speaking to army radio, denied the newspaper report.</p>
<p>President Bill Clinton this week toughened his stance against an Israeli settlement revival in occupied Arab lands, characterising them as an obstacle to peace.</p>
<p>&quot;The president's view is that settlement activity at this time, to expand the settlements or to encourage more people to go and live in the settlements, is not helpful to moving the peace process forward,&quot; U.S. Ambassador to Israel Martin Indyk said on Wednesday.</p>
<p>Netanyahu has come under growing international criticism since he scrapped a four-year freeze on settlement construction shortly after ousting Israel's centre-left government in May.</p>
<p>Some 130,000 Jews live in settlements scattered among more than two million Arabs in the West Bank and Gaza. The areas, where Palestinians hope to establish an independent state, were seized by Israel in the 1967 Middle East war.</p>
<p>Under terms of five years of loan guarantees that the United States promised Israel in 1992, Washington deducts from an annual $2 billion allotment a sum equivalent to Israel's investment in Jewish settlements.</p>
<p>According to U.S. figures, Washington deducted $60 million from the sum this fiscal year and last, $217 million the previous year, and $437 million in the year before that.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ALB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ISRAEL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-19"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-19"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GAZA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ISRAEL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
