<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269067" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: SOCCER-MONACO WIN, OPEN FOUR-POINT LEAD.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-MONACO WIN, OPEN FOUR-POINT LEAD.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Monaco scored three times in the first half to beat Lens 3-1 away on Friday and open a four-point lead in the French first division.</p>
<p>Challengers Paris Saint-Germain lost ground when they were held 1-1 at home by Montpellier.</p>
<p>The leaders, who scored through Nigeria's Victor Ikpeba, Gilles Grimandi and Brazilian Anderson, have 48 points, PSG 44 and Bastia, 3-1 winners over Bordeaux on Thursday, 42 in third place.</p>
<p>Champions Auxerre crashed to their second successive defeat, 1-0 at home to Strasbourg.</p>
<p>Rennes striker Stephane Guivarc'h hit a hat-trick as his side came from behind to beat Marseille 4-2 and took his tally as the division's top scorer to 17.</p>
<p>Former Marseille striker Tony Cascarino of Ireland also scored three as relegation-threatened Nancy won 3-1 at Le Havre. But they remained one place from bottom.</p>
<p>Four players were sent off in nine matches, while Lyon's goalkeeper Pascal Olmeta punched team mate Jean-Luc Sassus after their 1-0 home loss to Nantes and the defender was taken to hospital with concussion.</p>
<p>The league now goes into winter recess until the last weekend of January when Monaco and PSG clash in a top-of-the-table encounter in the principality.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MONAC">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
