<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269007" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL-KOTITE WILL STEP DOWN AS COACH AFTER SUNDAY'S GAME.</title>
<headline>NFL-KOTITE WILL STEP DOWN AS COACH AFTER SUNDAY'S GAME.</headline>
<dateline>HEMPSTEAD, New York 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Rich Kotite announced Friday he will step down as coach of the New York Jets after the team's nightmarish 1996 season comes to an end Sunday against the Miami Dolphins.</p>
<p>&quot;I was not fired, I am not quitting, but I thought this was the best thing to do for the organisation,&quot; Kotite told a news conference at the Jets' training centre at Hofstra University.</p>
<p>&quot;I wanted to do this today because I wanted the opportunity to talk to all of the players.&quot;</p>
<p>Kotite's two-year reign as Jets coach has been a disaster. He has compiled a 4-27 record, and the Jets are an NFL-worst 1-14 this season.</p>
<p>&quot;I'm a bottom line guy and 3-13 and 1-14 doesn't cut it,&quot; said Kotite. &quot;I hold myself accountable. A change has to be made. I feel so disappointed about not getting the job done. Not so much for me, but for (owner) Leon Hess and the whole Jets family.&quot;</p>
<p>Jets owner Leon Hess complimented Kotite for his work ethic, and said both sides recognised a change had to be made.</p>
<p>&quot;He (Kotite) handled the adversity this season with class and dignity,&quot; Hess said in a statement. &quot;Rich is stepping aside by mutual understanding.</p>
<p>&quot;For whatever reason, his two years as head coach of the Jets didn't work out. We both knew the record. We both knew the inevitable. He will always be a part of the Jets family. Now we have to decide on a new course for the football team.&quot;</p>
<p>Kotite previously served four years as head coach of the Philadelphia Eagles and was fired after the Eagles lost seven straight games to cap the 1994 season. Kotite has lost 34 of his last 38 games as a head coach.</p>
<p>After being fired by Philadelphia, Hess named Kotite to succeed Pete Carroll as head coach in January 1995. The Jets struggled to an NFL-worst 3-13 record in Kotite's first season.</p>
<p>Hess opened his checkbook in the off-season to try and upgrade the team, spending more than $60 million in free agent contracts.</p>
<p>The big prize was quarterback Neil O'Donnell, who left the AFC champion Pittsburgh Steelers for a five-year, $25 million deal. New York also signed receiver Jeff Graham, tackles Jumbo Elliott and David Williams and selected Southern California receiver Keyshawn Johnson with the top pick of the NFL draft.</p>
<p>But the new cast failed to improve the Jets, who again own the first pick in the draft.</p>
<p>&quot;I really thought we would be very respectable this year,&quot; said Kotite. &quot;But this happened under my watch. Sometimes that's the way life is. You can work your tail off and things still wouldn't work out.&quot;</p>
<p>O'Donnell played in just six games this season due to a separated right shoulder and a pulled right calf muscle.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HEMPSTEAD, New York"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
