<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269021" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: ALPINE SKIING-BOYD STILL GOING STRONG 10 YEARS ON.</title>
<headline>ALPINE SKIING-BOYD STILL GOING STRONG 10 YEARS ON.</headline>
<byline>Alan Baldwin</byline>
<dateline>VAL GARDENA, Italy 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>There are few places in the world where Rob Boyd receives the sort of reaction that he commands in Val Gardena.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't know why it's always here that I do so well but it seems like a lot of people know me from this area,&quot; the Canadian skier said.</p>
<p>&quot;I walk down the street and its almost like being at home -- 'hey, Boyd number one. Go for it. You win, you win'. It's really neat, it's comfortable here,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>A glance at Boyd's downhill race record shows why.</p>
<p>The Saslong piste was the scene of the first two victories of his World Cup career, including a remarkable win in 1986 when he was 20 years old and in his second season.</p>
<p>He won again in Val Gardena in 1987, was second in 1990, third in 1988 and fourth twice in two races in 1993.</p>
<p>Val Gardena stands out in a three-win career -- the other was at home at Whistler Mountain in 1989 -- with only one more rostrum place when he was third at Kitzbuehel in 1991.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a course where I have been on the podium four times and I have been in the top 10 nine times,&quot; said Boyd.</p>
<p>&quot;I have been asked why so often and I guess the answer to that is that I feel really comfortable on the course. I just like it. Nothing really scares me on it.&quot;</p>
<p>The lanky Canadian said his early triumphs had much to do with his ability to use his long legs to absorb the piste's famed bumps and glide over them rather than flying.</p>
<p>&quot;The first two years that I won, some people were jumping the &quot;Camel Humps&quot; but you had to jump so hard to make it and I didn't believe that I had quite enough &quot;explosiveness&quot; and so I would absorb them instead,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>The results were staggering for his rivals.</p>
<p>The mighty Austrians and the Swiss had won all but two of the races held at Val Gardena since 1969 when Boyd came along 10 years ago and gatecrashed their party.</p>
<p>So confident were the established powers that Italian Michael Mair, Germany's Markus Wasmeier and Switzerland's Franz Heinzer were already on the podium celebrating for the photographers when Boyd set off down the 3.4 km piste.</p>
<p>Boyd soon rewrote the script, crossing the line in a time of two minutes 01.76 seconds -- 0.14 faster than Mair.</p>
<p>&quot;Here comes this young kid down with number 26 -- and at that time when the top 15 were finished that was pretty much the race -- and these guys were on the podium doing preliminary photographs for the press,&quot; recalled Boyd.</p>
<p>&quot;Number 26 wins the race, Michael Mair steps down, Wasmeier goes over a step and I step up in the middle.</p>
<p>&quot;I go 'Sorry guys, I won I guess'. It was a pretty neat feeling, a big surprise for me and a big surprise for a lot of other people. Especially the guys on the podium.&quot;</p>
<p>Since then the course has changed in subtle ways, with the bumps moved forward slightly, forcing skiers to jump.</p>
<p>The falls and injuries over the years have also taken their toll on Boyd, whose last top 10 finish was in 1994.</p>
<p>But the Canadian is still full of optimism.</p>
<p>&quot;I know that I'm stronger than I ever have been before,&quot; he said. &quot;I think technically I'm also skiing better than I have but I think that skiing better than ever and racing better than ever also involves the mental aspect of it.&quot;</p>
<p>That means convincing himself that he can avoid mistakes, or can handle the consequences if he does go wrong.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel I'm close to being back to when I skied really well,&quot; he said after clocking the seventh fastest time during the final training for two Val Gardena downhills.</p>
<p>That in itself was impressive. With Austrians filling the top four places and Italians the next two, Boyd's time was faster than anything the Swiss or French managed.</p>
<p>Now, as when he was just starting out, the pressure of expectation created by his wins has dimmed with the Austrians -- particularly newcomer Fritz Strobl -- taking the limelight.</p>
<p>&quot;I was young. I jumped a lot of steps and just went boom right to the top. Maybe that's because I felt very comfortable with how I was skiing, with the course and speed,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I felt like I could handle anything that came at me. That's why I think I was able to just go and win.&quot;</p>
<p>Strobl, winner of the opening downhill of the season in Val d'Isere last weekend, shares a similar confidence, but Boyd warned the Austrian it might not last. &quot;What will be hard for him will be to keep going at that level,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;I think quite possibly throughout the year he'll be a threat at every race. But next year? You might see something totally different. You might see him way down in the 20s and going 'What the hell, what's going on?'&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;I know so many racers that have done the same thing. (Canada's Cary) Mullen. One year he was first, second and second. And the next year -- like, what's going on?&quot;</p>
<p>Ten years from his first World Cup win, Boyd is still having fun. Val Gardena may see further glory.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="CANA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="VAL GARDENA, Italy"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
