<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269076" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: OLYMPICS-ITALIAN GROUP SAYS 'NO' TO ROME OLYMPICS.</title>
<headline>OLYMPICS-ITALIAN GROUP SAYS 'NO' TO ROME OLYMPICS.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A group of Italian intellectuals and environmentalists launched a campaign on Friday to prevent the 2004 Olympics coming to Rome, saying the Games would only harm the traffic-choked city.</p>
<p>Some 100 intellectuals, writers and environmentalists signed a petition urging the international community and Italians to protest against Rome's bid to host the summer Games.</p>
<p>&quot;The singular historical and artistic nature of the centre and the horrible state of transport and services in the entire metropolis would ensure the city is damaged by the presence of millions of people,&quot; the petition said.</p>
<p>Among its signatories were economist Luigi Spaventa, writer Raffaele La Capria and art critic Federico Zeri.</p>
<p>It said Rome and the Vatican were already gearing up for a massive influx of people to celebrate the year 2000, which Pope John Paul has declared a jubilee, or Holy Year. Millions of people are expected to flock to the city.</p>
<p>&quot;Personalities from every field have begun a national and international campaign to stop a calamity -- the Olympics -- four years after another inevitable calamity, the Jubilee,&quot; the petition said.</p>
<p>&quot;It is also highly probable that the expenses for the Games would not contribute to the modernisaton of the city,&quot; said the petition, adding that Rome should concentrate on improving its infrastructure and restoring its art treasures.</p>
<p>It urged the city council, whose Greens Party mayor Francesco Rutelli has spearheaded Rome's Olympic bid, to demonstrate to the public how the capital would benift.</p>
<p>&quot;The waste, the useless 'public works' and squandering of public money during the 1990 (soccer) World Cup are all too fresh in the public's mind,&quot; it said. Rome hosted the final.</p>
<p>Rome, which also hosted the 1960 Olympics, is considered one of the front-runners for the 2004 Games.</p>
<p>The other candidates are Cape Town, Rio de Janeiro, San Juan, Buenos Aires, Stockholm, Athens, Lille, Seville, Istanbul and St Petersburg. The decision is expected next year.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
