<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269054" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ABU DHABI: SOCCER-UAE LOOK TO HISTORY TO DENY SAUDI.</title>
<headline>SOCCER-UAE LOOK TO HISTORY TO DENY SAUDI.</headline>
<byline>Nadim Ladki</byline>
<dateline>ABU DHABI 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The United Arab Emirates hope a sense of history will prevail when they seek to prevent favourites Saudi Arabia from winning the Asian Cup for a record-equalling third time in the final on Saturday.</p>
<p>The UAE stage the final and hosts have won six of the previous 10 titles. Never has a host nation reached the final and lost.</p>
<p>The UAE are the surprise team of a tournament that saw the early exit of the continent's two football powerhouses, 2002 World Cup co-hosts Japan and South Korea. While the Saudis have produced some of the finest football at the tournament, the hosts have shown great strength, stamina and determination to reach the final.</p>
<p>Backed by a vocal home crowd, they hung on in matches they were outplayed in to come from behind to draw or win and they are the only unbeaten team in the competition.</p>
<p>UAE Croat coach Tomislam Ivic acknowledged after the 1-0 semi-final win against Kuwait that the hearts of his players were a key part of their success.</p>
<p>''Tonight...I had 11 comandoes, not 11 players,'' he said.</p>
<p>His key players are midfielder Bakhit Saad and strikers Adnan Al-Talyani and Hassan Ahmed, the UAE's top scorer in the tournament with three goals.</p>
<p>Saudi coach Eduardo Vingada of Portugal tried to ease some of the pressure on his players, seen as hot favourites to win.</p>
<p>''I think we have a 50-50 chance of winning,'' he told reporters. ''The UAE are a very physically strong side backed by a fantastic atmosphere. They are not spectacular but are very well organised and very difficult to beat.''</p>
<p>Saudi Arabia won the title in 1984 and 1988 and lost the 1992 final to Japan. They -- along with other Arab countries -- first took part in the competition in 1976 after Israel stopped participating and joined the UEFA.</p>
<p>The Saudis have a number of fine players and strong finishers.</p>
<p>Playmaker Khalid Al-Muwalid showed real class at the beginning of the tournament but struggled a bit in the knockout stage. Fahad Al-Mahalel is a quick and strong striker who has four goals to his name in the tournament so far.</p>
<p>Goalkeeper Mohammed Daeyea and defender and 19-year-old Hussain Sulaimani have been in fine form at the back.</p>
<p>Iran and Kuwait, the losing semi finalists, will play for third place on Saturday before the final.</p>
<p>Iran, beaten by the Saudis on penalties, won the Asian Cup three times in 1968, 1972 and 1976.</p>
<p>Also on Saturday, the Asian Football Confederation will reveal the hosting nation for the Asian Cup 2000 with China and Lebanon the front-runners.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ABDBI">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="SAARAB">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UAE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ABU DHABI"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
