<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269057" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-REDSKINS PLAY FINAL GAME AT RFK STADIUM.</title>
<headline>NFL AMERICAN FOOTBALL-REDSKINS PLAY FINAL GAME AT RFK STADIUM.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Washington Redskins end a 35-year era Sunday when they play the Dallas Cowboys in their final National Football League game at Robert F. Kennedy Stadium.</p>
<p>The team is scheduled to move next season to a 78,000 seat stadium being built in nearby Prince Georges County, Maryland. The new field will have over 20,000 more seats and more amenities than the current stadium, but the Redskins will be hard-pressed to match the success they enjoyed there.</p>
<p>Washington won all five National Football Conference title games played at RFK and three of the five Super Bowl games following those victories.</p>
<p>The Redskins sold out all their home games at the 55,000-seat stadium for the past three decades and expect to do the same when they move since the waiting list for season tickets is greater than the number of additional seats.</p>
<p>Tickets to Redskin games are a Washington status symbol and national and local political figures vie for coveted seats in team owner Jack Kent Cooke's private box.</p>
<p>The field opened in 1961 as District of Columbia Stadium. It was renamed for Robert Kennedy in 1969, several months after the New York senator and former attorney general was assassinated in Los Angeles on the night he won the California Democratic presidential primary.</p>
<p>The stadium was also the home field of the Washington Senators Major League Baseball team until the franchise was moved to the Dallas-Fort Worth area in 1972, where it was renamed the Texas Rangers.</p>
<p>RFK has hosted a number of other events including college and high school football games, World Cup and Olympic soccer games and rock concerts.</p>
<p>The District of Columbia owns RFK stadium and will continue to operate it for various events including home games of D.C. United, Washington's Major League Soccer team.</p>
<p>Former Redskin stars who will be honoured at the game Sunday include quarterback Sonny Jurgensen, linebacker Sam Huff, wide receivers Bobbie Mitchell, Charlie Taylor and Art Monk and fullback John Riggins.</p>
<p>Some of the most memorable games at RFK have come against the Dallas Cowboys, the Redskins' biggest rival. But this Sunday's contest will only be for pride since the Redskins have been eliminated from the NFL playoffs with an 8-7 record while Dallas has clinched the NFC's Eastern Division title.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
