<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269047" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: CRICKET-TASMANIAN COX HAMMERS PAKISTAN.</title>
<headline>CRICKET-TASMANIAN COX HAMMERS PAKISTAN.</headline>
<dateline>HOBART, Australia 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Tasmanian opener Jamie Cox hit a career-best unbeaten 191 on Friday to give his side a healthy lead over Pakistan on the second day of their four-day match at Bellerive Oval.</p>
<p>Tasmania were 392 for six at stumps after resuming on 73 for one, a lead of 93, against a spin-dominated Pakistan attack led by Mushtaq Ahmed and Saqlain Mushtaq.</p>
<p>The pair sent down 60 overs between them, with Mushtaq claiming four for 97, but could not prevent Cox establishing several personal milestones as he recorded his 14th first-class century.</p>
<p>His previous best score was 175 against New South Wales six years ago and he now tops the Australian domestic totals with 652 runs, 142 clear of injured test opener Matthew Elliott.</p>
<p>Pakistan captain Wasim Akram, who did not bowl during the second day, experimented unsuccessfully with number three batsman Ijaz Ahmed, who was hammered for 18 runs from his single over which contained four no-balls.</p>
<p>Australia test batsman Ricky Ponting gave a hesitant performance ahead of next week's third test against West Indies, falling to pace bowler Mohammad Zahid for 35, Tasmania's second highest score of the innings.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="PAKIS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GSPO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HOBART, Australia"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
