<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269294" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ROMANIA: Romania raises fuel prices as IMF head arrives.</title>
<headline>Romania raises fuel prices as IMF head arrives.</headline>
<dateline>BUCHAREST 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Romanian Prime Minister Victor Ciorbea ordered price rises for fuel on Friday as the head of the International Monetary Fund arrived to discuss resuming of credits for the Balkan country.</p>
<p>The independent Mediafax news agency said Ciorbea told parliament the increases would be introduced in the New Year to meet IMF recommendations and bring prices up to world levels.</p>
<p>Ciorbea gave no figures but promised the increases would be balanced by compensation for consumers already hard hit by inflation running near annual rates of 50 percent.</p>
<p>One Bucharest daily reported that the National Oil Company had proposed a rise to 1,700 lei per litre, almost double the current price. Energy prices were last increased in July, triggering a 7.5 percent blip of the monthly inflation.</p>
<p>In a separate statement sent to heads of banks, the prime minister asked for vigilance in protecting against the transfer outside the country of &quot;significant sums of money&quot; he suggested were obtained illegally.</p>
<p>The IMF's Managing Director, Michel Camdessus, was arriving for a 24-hour visit which Fund representatives say is intended to get acquainted with Romania's new administration under reformist president Emil Constantinescu.</p>
<p>He was due to meet Constantinescu, Ciorbea, opposition leaders, trade unionists and even Romania's Orthodox patriarch in what officials say is an attempt to come to grips with realities since his last visit in 1994.</p>
<p>He will undertake no formal talks on a new loan accord. Those are due to begin in mid-January.</p>
<p>The Fund suspended a $460 million three-year accord this year after criticising foreign exchange market restrictions and overspending by the leftist government ahead of the election that brought Constantinescu to power.</p>
<p>A week-long mission by Fund experts this month revealed a grimmer economic situation than had earlier been believed.</p>
<p>In addition to asking ministers to raise energy prices and postpone promises of increased child benefits, the IMF sought budget cuts, a liberalised foreign exchange market, higher discount rates and reduced central bank funds to farmers.</p>
<p>Recent indicators have highlighted the dire state of the Romanian economy.</p>
<p>Year-on-year inflation was 47.4 percent in November, more than double the IMF-directed target of 20 percent for 1996, and the budget deficit surged to 5.7 percent of gross domestic product from initial pledges of 2.2 percent.</p>
<p>($=3,912 lei)</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ROM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I14000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E212">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BUCHAREST"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ROMANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
