<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269288" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: OSCE to discuss Serbian crisis with opposition.</title>
<headline>OSCE to discuss Serbian crisis with opposition.</headline>
<byline>Peter Greste</byline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>A pan-European delegation opened talks in Serbia to try to defuse a crisis over electoral fraud allegations that has provoked daily anti-government street protests by tens of thousands of people.</p>
<p>The mission from the Organisation for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) arrived in Belgrade late on Friday to investigate opposition claims that the government robbed it of victory in local elections last month.</p>
<p>The delegation leader, former Spanish prime minister Filipe Gonzales, went straight into talks with President Slobodan Milosevic after arriving ahead of the rest of his group.</p>
<p>Mass demonstrations erupted after committees dominated by Milosevic's ruling socialists overturned opposition victories in 15 of Serbia's largest towns and cities, including Belgrade, in the November 17 elections.</p>
<p>The opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition accused the authorities of blatant fraud and boycotted many of the repeat polls which handed control of most centres to the socialists.</p>
<p>Gonzales told reporters the OSCE had not come to mediate but to &quot;speak to all sides and find out the facts about the elections as quickly as possible.&quot;</p>
<p>He and the rest of the OSCE delegation later met leaders of the opposition Zajedno (Together) coalition and a Zajedno leader, Zoran Djindjic, told reporters the talks would continue over a working breakfast on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;These are not political talks. The commission has the mandate to find the facts and not to mediate politically nor to give a political decision but to find facts,&quot; Djindjic said.</p>
<p>&quot;We want to cooperate and we will be glad to give all the facts that we have to the commission.&quot;</p>
<p>Milosevic invited the OSCE's intervention in the face of the mounting street protests by up to a quarter of a million people in Belgrade at home and rising criticism from abroad led by the United States.</p>
<p>Both sides in the dispute emphasised the importance of the high-powered OSCE team, with its legal and electoral experts, in helping to resolve the crisis.</p>
<p>But, while they welcomed the opportunity to put their cases to independent arbitrators, they also built in escape routes, declaring that the OSCE's verdict was not binding.</p>
<p>The opposition has said it will continue its protests until its election victories are recognised regardless of what the OSCE finds. Foreign Minister Milan Milutinovic has said the mission's rulings must be processed through local institutions.</p>
<p>But, with the anti-gevernment demonstrations entering their 34th day, the pressure on the OSCE to find a peaceful way out was intense and rising.</p>
<p>About 40,000 students blockaded bridges over the Sava River in Belgrade on Friday. A tense standoff with riot police was resolved after 30 minutes when the students left without any violence but the ensuing traffic jams took hours to clear.</p>
<p>The anti-Milosevic marches have spread to dozens of towns across Serbia, but the authorities have started to organise counter-demonstrations, dividing local communities and raising tensions still further.</p>
<p>About 3,000 people attended a rally in Pozarevac, Milosevic's home town in southern Serbia, organised by the embattled socialists.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVOTE">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
