<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="26929" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>SOUTH AFRICA: S.African rand/bonds closing report.</title>
<headline>S.African rand/bonds closing report.</headline>
<dateline>JOHANNESBURG 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>The South African rand ended more than one-and-a-half cents stronger on Monday as local fund managers, exporters and London players sold dollars.</p>
<p>At 1428 GMT the local unit was quoted at 4.4680/4730 from 4.4845/4895 late on Friday.</p>
<p>Dealers said the rand initially drifted weaker on the back of demand for dollars around the 4.4900/4950 levels.</p>
<p>However, heavy dollar sales from local fund managers, exporters and London players saw the currency move rapidly firmer to a morning best of 4.4690 bid where it hovered for much of the day.</p>
<p>&quot;Fund managers, exporters and London banks sold dollars and there are still a lot of long positions out there...the impetus is to carry on selling,&quot; one trader said.</p>
<p>&quot;At the rate we are going we could see the rand breach the 4.45 level this week,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Another dealer said the rand hovered around the 4.47 level in the afternoon amid good two-way flows.</p>
<p>&quot;Sentiment improved after the rand breached the psychologically important 4.50 level last week and the next target is 4.45. We've broken important levels and the guys are nervous to be caught sitting long on dollars,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Reserve Bank deputy general manager of international banking Allan Buckland said the bank had not been active in the market.</p>
<p>&quot;The bank has not been in the market at all today,&quot; Buckland told Reuters.</p>
<p>Another dealer noted that the rand was unlikely to &quot;race down&quot; to the 4.45 level despite the turn in market sentiment: &quot;It will probably take its time in getting there as there is good dollar demand at the lower levels.&quot;</p>
<p>Currency and bond market dealers were awaiting the release on Friday of South Africa's gold and foreign exchange reserves. A Reuters consensus poll of economists forecast August reserves to come in at 10.1 billion rand from 10.37 billion rand in July.</p>
<p>Against the crosses, the rand was last at 6.9701/9801 on sterling from 7.0096/0210 on Friday and at 0.3322/3328 marks from 0.3286/3295 marks previously.</p>
<p>Bond yields ended slightly higher after a lacklustre day dominated by jobber activity.</p>
<p>However, bond traders said underlying sentiment was bullish, cheered by the stronger rand, improved money market conditions and an unexpectedly positive trade surplus last week.</p>
<p>&quot;The market moved in a ten point range on the day and we are currently seeing some consolidation but expect further strength later in the week,&quot; a trader said, adding that 15.03 percent was the next target on the downside on the R150 bond.</p>
<p>At 1429 GMT the R150 was quoted at 15.25 percent from 15.20 percent on Friday, while Eskom's 168 was trading at 15.39 percent from 15.35 previously.</p>
<p>Bond Exchange figures showed foreigners were net sellers of 89.73 million rand of South Africa bonds on Friday after selling 8.42 million rand of South African bonds on Thursday. Nominal cumulative volumes were pegged at 7.16 billion rand on Friday after 43.91 billion rand on Thursday, a settlement day.</p>
<p>On the money market, three-month NCDs were slightly lower at between 15.90 to 16.05 percent from 16.05 to 16.20 percent on Friday, while 90-day BAs were also lower at between 15.30 to 15.50 percent from 15.50 and 15.70 percent previously.</p>
<p>The Reserve Bank put the money market shortage at 8.183 billion rand on Saturday from 7.903 billion rand on Friday.</p>
<p>-- Vera von Lieres, Johannesburg newsroom, +27 11 482-1003</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SAFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="JOHANNESBURG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="SOUTH AFRICA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
