<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269382" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Latvia says to meet 1996 deficit target.</title>
<headline>Latvia says to meet 1996 deficit target.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Latvian finance ministry said on Friday that the Baltic state would meet its planned budget deficit target of 40 million lats this year.</p>
<p>The country set the deficit after as part of its agreements with the International Monetary Fund (IMF). It came after the 1995 deficit ballooned to 90 million lats in the wake of a serious banking crisis</p>
<p>&quot;The budget of 1996 holds has no surprises in store for us,&quot; finance ministry state secretary Valentina Andrejeva told a news conference.  &quot;We are sure to stay within the legislated 40 million deficit.&quot;</p>
<p>She said that the central government budget deficit could even be lower than planned at 35 million lats.</p>
<p>The finance ministry said that by December 19, the state deficit was running at 28.81 million lats, consisting of 425.23 million lats of income and 471.47 million lats of spending.</p>
<p>It said that total internal debt came to 181.299 million lats, of which 121.189 million lats was funded by government Treasury bills.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
