<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269389" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>LATVIA: Latvian share trade buoyant, Unibanka bounces.</title>
<headline>Latvian share trade buoyant, Unibanka bounces.</headline>
<dateline>RIGA 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share trade on the Latvian bourse was buoyant on Friday as it traded for the first time on a fourth day of the week.</p>
<p>The market has until now had three sessions a week.</p>
<p>Overall market turnover came to 64,572 lats and Unibanka was the most traded on 16,752 lats. Its price rose to 2.33 lats from 2.20 lats.</p>
<p>Fellow official list shares Riga Transport Fleet (RTF) and Staburadze were also well traded, turning over 10,000 lats and 7,322 lats of stock respectively.</p>
<p>RTF rose to one lat from 99 santimes while Staburadze maintained its recent rise to climb to 2.15 lats from 2.09 lats.</p>
<p>On the secondary market, Daugavpils chain and Riga Yeast were the most traded on 8,899 lats and 8,920 lats respectively. Both shares rose, Daugavpils hitting 1.10 lats from 1.07 lats and Riga Yeast rising three santimes to 2.50 lats.</p>
<p>Fish cannery Kaija was also active on trade of 7,986 lats and it added one santime to 1.20 lats.</p>
<p>Drinks firm Veldze and Salacgriva both dipped as they traded 1,983 lats and 1,969 lats each. Veldze slipped to 65 santimes from 73 and Salacgriva lost five santimes to 2.10 lats.</p>
<p>-- Riga Newsroom, +371 721 5240</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="LATV">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="RIGA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="LATVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
