<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269424" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: Gdansk shipyard applies for $100 mln loan.</title>
<headline>Gdansk shipyard applies for $100 mln loan.</headline>
<dateline>GDANSK, Poland 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Poland's bankrupt Gdansk shipyard has applied to a local bank, Bank Gdanski SA, for a $100 million loan to build five ships for a German investor, Bank Gdanski's spokesman said on Friday.</p>
<p>Adam Grzybowski said the shipyard wanted the project to be carried out by a company it carved out from its own assets after filing for bankruptcy in June, called New Gdansk shipyard.</p>
<p>&quot;New Gdansk shipyard has applied for a credit of about $100 million to build five vessels,&quot; Grzybowski told Reuters.</p>
<p>The new firm, now existing only on paper, is not burdened with the shipyard's debts which exceed 415 million zlotys.</p>
<p>The yard's administrator Wieslaw Szaj said he wanted to start construction of the ships in February.</p>
<p>A source in Bank Gdanski, which asked not to be named, said the bank was analysing the application and had not started to look for partners in a possible consortium that would extend the loan, as the yard administrator suggested on Thursday.</p>
<p>Late on Thursday, the government confirmed it was ready to offer a partial guarantee for the loan, which would keep some of the yard's 4,800-strong workforce busy while an investor to save the whole business is sought.</p>
<p>But government spokeswoman Aleksandra Jakubowska said the guarantee could be given only if the shipyard's trade unions, which have launched various protests to demand that their jobs be saved, refrained from further actions.</p>
<p>She said financial risk involved in the construction of the five ships should be divided among the treasury, banks and the company ordering the vessels, German-owned and Cyprus-based shipping group Schoeller Holdings.</p>
<p>The government says the shipyard -- where 17 years ago Lech Walesa set up the Solidarity, the first free trade union in the then Soviet bloc -- plunged into troubles because its previous management signed a number of unprofitable contracts.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I36101">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GDANSK, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
