<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269467" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>COLOMBIA: Colombia stocks rise led by cement producers.</title>
<headline>Colombia stocks rise led by cement producers.</headline>
<dateline>BOGOTA 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Colombian stocks edged up on Friday, led by gains in shares of cement manufacturers Cemento Argos and Cementos Caribe, and reinsurer Reaseguradora de Colombia.</p>
<p>Bogota's IBB price index gained 0.26 percent to 841.37 amid a heavier-than-average volume of 11.3 billion pesos. Medellin's IBOMED general price index rose 0.39 percent to 13,319.51 as shares worth 22 billion pesos changed hands.</p>
<p>Volume in Medellin was bloated by a 16 billion peso cross-deal in chocolate manufacturer Nacional de Chocolates, which held steady at 8,300 pesos a share.  </p>
<p>In Bogota, Cemento Argos edged up 1.44 percent to 5,275 in trading of shares worth 2.9 billion pesos.</p>
<p>In Medellin, 1.2 billion pesos worth Cemento Argos shares changed hands, as the stock rose 0.96 to 5,250. Cementos Caribe gained 1.72 percent to 4,323 in trading of 3.3 billion pesos.</p>
<p>A Medellin broker said the cross-deal in Nacional de Chocolates probably involved shareholders in the company's parent, Sindicato Antioqueo, adjusting their portfolios in aniticpation of year-end tax breaks.</p>
<p>((Juan Guillermo Londoo, Bogota newsroom 571 610 7944))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="COL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BOGOTA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="COLOMBIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
