<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269532" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>GUATEMALA: After peace, Guatemala must resettle thousands.</title>
<headline>After peace, Guatemala must resettle thousands.</headline>
<byline>Fiona Ortiz</byline>
<dateline>GUATEMALA CITY 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>After signing a historic peace treaty with leftist rebels on Dec. 29, Guatemala will face the expensive job of resettling hundreds of thousands of people forced from their homes by army violence during years of civil war.</p>
<p>The problem of the internally displaced will dwarf the work and money Guatemala has spent repatriating thousands of refugees who fled to Mexico during the war.</p>
<p>On paper the government has made huge and costly promises for aid to displaced people, but specific programmes have yet to be decided and no one even knows how many displaced there are.</p>
<p>&quot;There's little I can say about displaced people because at this point we still don't know what the population will want to do,&quot; said Jose Luis Gandara, director of the National Commission for Attention to Repatriated, Refugees and Displaced People (CEAR).</p>
<p>The government guaranteed the right to collective reparation for damages suffered during the war. Demands will probably flood in.</p>
<p>&quot;I don't believe the government can bring back to life our dead but it should resolve the damages that it did to us,&quot; Catarina Mejia, a displaced woman who lives in a squatter settlement outside the capital, told Reuters.</p>
<p>Mejia was seven years old when she fled the highland town of Totonicapan in the early 1980s after soldiers accused her father of supporting the guerrillas and beat him badly. Years of wandering brought her family to the capital.</p>
<p>Mejia belongs to a group of 160 displaced families living with hundreds of other landless families in the Santa Isabel squatter settlement on a dusty hill south of the capital.</p>
<p>Mejia, her construction worker husband and two children live in a stifling, two-room, dirt-floor shack built of corrugated metal walls and roof and a plastic sheet door.</p>
<p>The displaced of Santa Isabel were pushed out of their former homes in rural areas during the army's counterinsurgency campaigns directed by military governments in the early 1980s.</p>
<p>&quot;These are families that were victims of repression, of big massacres, of scorched earth,&quot; said Manuel Perez of the National Council of Guatemalan Displaced People (CONDEG).</p>
<p>Government officials and advocates for the displaced believe they may number 250,000 to 600,000. No one knows how many live in slums and squatters settlements ringing the capital.</p>
<p>In tentative budgets for spending for post-war programmes, resettlement funding for the displaced is the largest budget item - $617 million out of $2.5 billion.</p>
<p>Officials have told refugees still living in Mexico that after June 1997 there won't be any more money for repatriation programmes because the priority will be for the displaced.</p>
<p>The promises are contained in one of 11 peace accords signed between the government and the leftist rebels, the Guatemalan National Revolutionary Unit, during years of peace negotiations.</p>
<p>The 1994 Accord for Resettlement of People Displaced by the Armed Conflict says the government will provide legal aid so people can recover land they lost in the war.</p>
<p>Under the accord the government will do everything short of buying land to help resettle displaced people: provide job training, promote community business projects, and build roads, clinics, schools, and other infrastructure.</p>
<p>When CONDEG was formed in 1989 the first battle was to get the government to admit they existed at all. Suspicious of paper promises, now CONDEG wants officials to make the displaced a priority.</p>
<p>&quot;The government must define a priority attention to the displaced population. It is the most vulnerable,&quot; Perez said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="GUAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="GUATEMALA CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="GUATEMALA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
