<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269569" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>BRAZIL: PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Dec 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Brazil - Dec 20.</headline>
<dateline>SAO PAULO 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the highlights of the main Sao Paulo and Rio de Janeiro newspapers this morning.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>GAZETA MERCANTIL</p>
<p>-- 1997, CONSENSUS AMONG ECONOMISTS GROWS</p>
<p>Brazil's economy will grow moderately, the stabilization process will continue and inflation rates will keep falling in 1997. But the fiscal outlook is still gloomy and the trade deficit is likely to continue growing. This is the point of view of tens of economists, bankers and businessmen interviewed by the paper.</p>
<p>-- GALICIA TO REPLACE BCN IN BARCLAYS</p>
<p>Banco de Galicia, Argentina's largest private bank, is entering the Brazilian banking sector with the purchase of a 31.39 percent voting stake in universal bank BCN Barclays belonging to local bank BCN. The deal, worth 28 million reais, would put an end to a 23-year partnership between BCN and Barclays. It still depends on approval of Argentine and Brazilian authorities.</p>
<p>-- FOREIGN BANKS INCREASE STAKE IN BRAZIL</p>
<p>The National Monetary Council (CMN) approved on Thursday measures reducing restrictions on foreign banks in Brazil. Foreign banks' affiliates will be allowed to expand activities as full service banks. The CMN also authorized foreign investors to include ADRs issued by Brazilian banks in their locally held investment portfolios known as Annex Four.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>FOLHA DE SAO PAULO</p>
<p>-- RADIO CONCESSIONS NEGOTIATED UNDER SCHEME</p>
<p>Radio concessions are being traded for between 50,000 and 150,000 reais under a scheme involving lawmakers to sell concessions which will be offered by the government in a bidding process.</p>
<p>-- MOTTA SAYS WILL INVESTIGATE</p>
<p>Communications Minister Sergio Motta denied any possibility that radio concessions have been sold without a bidding process. He said he will investigate the case.</p>
<p>-- PERUVIAN GOV'T STUDIES GUERRILLAS' DEMANDS</p>
<p>The Peruvian government and the guerrillas who stormed the Japanese ambassador's residence in Lima began on Thursday to negotiate the release of hundreds of hostages.</p>
<p>- - -</p>
<p>O GLOBO</p>
<p>-- HOUSING, CEF ALTERS RULES FOR FINANCING THE MIDDLE-CLASS</p>
<p>Federal bank Caixa Economica Federal (CEF) decided to alter rules for financing the purchase of houses by middle-class Brazilians.</p>
<p>-- FH, COUNTRY IS MORE IMPORTANT THAN RE-ELECTION</p>
<p>In an speech on his two years of government, President Fernando Henrique Cardoso said Brazil is more important than the re-election amendment, adding that the political parties should vote on the proposal as they wish.</p>
<p>-- Reuters has not verified these stories and cannot vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>-- Fatima Cristina, Sao Paulo Newsroom, 55-11-2485412</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BRAZ">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SAO PAULO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BRAZIL"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
