<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269679" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. corporate market sees lackluster trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. corporate market sees lackluster trade.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The U.S. corporate bond market experienced a day of very little activity on Friday, as many Wall Street players had their minds more on the upcoming holidays than on corporate bonds, traders said.</p>
<p>In the high-yield market, however, investors showed some interst in the supermarket and the telecommunications and cable sector early in the day.</p>
<p>Supermarket bond from Ralphs Supermarkets, Brunos Inc and Grand Union Co closed 1/2 a point higher on Friday. In the telecommuncations and cable sector, traders said Nextel Communication Inc bonds also saw better bids.  </p>
<p>Analysts suspected that much of the buying came from accounts looking to stock portfolios with liquid, higher-coupon bonds as the new year approaches.</p>
<p>New issue activity was also quiet on Friday. A unit of Mellon Bank was one of the only issuers to tap the primary market, selling $500 million in capital securities with a 7.995 percent coupon at a spread of 137.5 basis points over Treasuries.</p>
<p>The deal, rated A2 by Moody's Investors Service and BBB-plus by Standard &amp; Poor's, was priced via a Merrill Lynch &amp; Co-led syndicate.  </p>
<p>Spreads on both high-yield and investment-grade bonds ended the day largely unchanged to Treasuries, traders said.</p>
<p>The 30-year benchmark Treasury dropped 8/32 to close at 98-20/32. The yield rose to 6.61 percent.</p>
<p>-Douglas Brown, 212-859-1662</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
