<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269732" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Argentina's Fernandez says court system to improve.</title>
<headline>Argentina's Fernandez says court system to improve.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Roque Fernandez, Argentina's economy minister, said the country's judiciary system will improve over time though he acknowledged some existing problems.</p>
<p>&quot;We believe that the economic and political system for Argentina is working very well,&quot; Fernandez told Reuters after a news conference sponsored by Chase Manhattan Bank. &quot;Over time, that is going to be the same for the courts,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>Fernandez's predecessor, former economy minister Domingo Cavallo, has vociferously accused members of President Carlos Menem's court system of corruption.  </p>
<p>On Thursday, Cavallo burst into an Argentine television studio in an attempt to confront Menem on the air with some of his allegations. Many government officials have denied the accusations and some, including interior minister Carlos Corach and at least one court judge, have sued Cavallo for slander. The lower house of congress leader Alberto Pierri has said he also plans to sue Cavallo.</p>
<p>Many Argentines believe convictions on these counts could land Cavallo in prison.</p>
<p>In addition to those officials, Cavallo has accused Menem's chief of staff, Alberto Kohan, of turning a blind eye to corruption and justice minister Elias Jassan of manipulating judges.</p>
<p>When asked whether or not his former boss might end up serving a prison sentence, Fernandez said he is unsure.</p>
<p>&quot;I hope not, but I couldn't tell you,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>((Scott Gerlach, 212-859-1868))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ARG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
