<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269755" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CSCE coffee ends higher after see-saw day.</title>
<headline>CSCE coffee ends higher after see-saw day.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CSCE coffee prices ended higher in volatile trading Friday after the USDA appeared to lower its estimate for Brazil's 1996/97 coffee crop, traders said.</p>
<p>In what initially seemed to be a downward revision of figures released a week ago, the U.S. Department of Agriculture's attache in Sao Paulo pegged Brazil's 1996/97 crop at 25.8 million 60-kg bags, down from 27.0 million put forth a week ago.</p>
<p>The attache's report, dated November 5, was only made available on Friday. Prices shot up more than three cents per lb following its release, with buy stops triggered near 112.50 and 113 cents.</p>
<p>&quot;There was nothing going on until the report came out,&quot; said one trader. &quot;The run-up was all on the (USDA) news.&quot;</p>
<p>But the market staged a quick retreat when a USDA crops analyst reiterated the department's 27.0 million bag forecast, explaining that the attache's report, now seven weeks old, had since been revised.</p>
<p>USDA specialty crops analyst Edmond Missiaen said there were no plans to revise the 27.0-million-bag estimater put forth last week until next June.</p>
<p>Having pared around half its gains by the close, March ended at 112.15 cents, up 1.95 on the day. Trades were posted from 109.30 to 113.90. Second-position May rose 2.15, to 109.60.</p>
<p>Technically, dealers said the market would next encounter resistance at 114.25, with 115 seen as a key psychological hurdle. To the downside, 109.30-108.50 was seen as an important support area.</p>
<p>An estimated 8,986 lots were exchanged on the day.</p>
<p>-- Wendy Pollack, New York Commodities Desk +1 212 859 1640</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
