<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269862" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: East Asia to raise funds via shares sale.</title>
<headline>East Asia to raise funds via shares sale.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philippines' East Asia Power Resources Corp said on Friday it would sell new shares at a minimum price of 8.50 pesos apiece to raise funds to cover its capital requirements.</p>
<p>East Asia closed at 8.50 pesos on Friday.</p>
<p>Assistant corporate secretary Ildebrando Ambrosio told the Philippine Stock Exchange it needed to raise $65 million to finance projects to be undertaken by the company and its subsidiaries.</p>
<p>The power firm has appointed Philippine National Bank as its lead underwriter for the shares offering.</p>
<p>Ambrosio said East Asia had bought into Asia Pacific Power &amp; Light Co Ltd which owns 51 percent of Taixing Huangquiao Pacific Power Co Ltd, operator of a 30-megawatt coal-fired power plant in Jiangsu province in China.</p>
<p>It had also acquired 100 percent of East Asia Power Services Inc, a firm engaged in providing operations and maintenance services to power plants.</p>
<p>East Asia is partly owned by Van der Horst Ltd of Singapore and Filinvest Development Corp of the Philippines. - Manila newsroom 63 2 8418938 Fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C171">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
