<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="269997" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. crudes end weak, Jan grade business moves out.</title>
<headline>U.S. crudes end weak, Jan grade business moves out.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. crudes ended weaker Friday, closing out a hectic week in the cash markets as refiners attempted to fill out January business ahead of the Christmas holiday week.</p>
<p>January pipeline scheduling plans forced domestic grades in all directions the previous two days, as refiners attempted to play off the January NYMEX crude futures expiration on Thursday, then Friday cleared desks ahead of the short week.</p>
<p>Gains on Thursday evaporated in most sweet grades, but the sour side of the business was well-supported by the production problems in the U.S. Gulf.  </p>
<p>Mobil's Green Canyon platform will be out of commission for two to three months, curtailing sour crude supply.</p>
<p>Sweet barrels were squeezed on the open arbitrage window for bringing trans-Atlantic barrels to the U.S. Gulf.</p>
<p>Traders said West African and North Sea cargoes were on their way to American markets, &quot;loosening&quot; the stranglehold Light Louisiana Sweet/St. James has held over the market in recent weeks.</p>
<p>LLS/St. James drifted to a discount against the January West Texas Intermediate/Cushing, selling at 15 cts under the marker, after tracking to nearly a $1.00 premium early on Thursday.</p>
<p>&quot;Selling just took off after the short covering rally Thursday morning. We saw deals getting done all over the place,&quot; said one Texas trader.</p>
<p>January West Texas Intermediate/Cushing ended at around $26.00-10 a barrel, about $1.00 better than the February WTI/Cushing end at $25.00-10 a barrel.</p>
<p>West Texas Sour hovered around the $1.00 discount level to the Jan WTI/Cushing, and Eugene Island at 80 cts below WTI.</p>
<p>Late Friday, the United Nations said it had approved three more contracts under the oil-for-food accord, bringing the total to 16 since the program began on December 10.</p>
<p>Additional contracts have been signed by Iraq's State Oil Marketing Organization (SOMO), but have not been forwarded to the U.N.-appointed oversears at this time.</p>
<p>--Patrick Connole, New York Energy Desk, +1 212 859 1828</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
