<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270037" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: CBOT corn ends mixed amid delivery stopper, cold.</title>
<headline>CBOT corn ends mixed amid delivery stopper, cold.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>CBOT corn futures closed mixed with nearby months firm on strong stopping of deliveries on the expired December contract and on cold weather in the U.S., traders said.</p>
<p>&quot;Cargill stopped all the corn this morning and that helped the bull spreads,&quot; a trader said.</p>
<p>There were 2.14 million bushels of corn posted Friday for delivery on the December and the Cargill Investor Services house account stopped all of it, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>But volume was thin and trading was quiet with the market settling into a holiday trading atmosphere, traders said.</p>
<p>Some support came from bitter cold weather in much of the U.S. which was boosting livestock feed consumption and slow farmer selling also was mentioned as a supportive influence.</p>
<p>Nearby March was boosted by Refco Inc's purchase of six million bushels and LIT America bought five million bushels of March, traders said.</p>
<p>Smith Barney sold 8.5 million bushels of July and Barney also was a featured buyer of 1,500 December $2.80 puts at 31-1/2 to 32 cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn closed 3/4 cent per bushel higher to 1-1/2 lower, with March up 3/4 at $2.66-3/4.  </p>
<p>Corn futures volume was estimated at 40,000 contracts, below the 41,272 contracts traded Thursday, according to the CBOT.</p>
<p>In addition to the Smith Barney moves in corn options, Term Commodities bought 1,000 March $3.00 calls at 7/8 cent and Refco Inc sold 500 March $2.70 puts at nine cents, traders said.</p>
<p>Corn options volume was estimated at 7,000 contracts, above the 6,822 traded Thursday.</p>
<p>((Sam Nelson 312-408-8721))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
