<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270082" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Prudential faces larger loss estimate on problems.</title>
<headline>Prudential faces larger loss estimate on problems.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Florida insurance regulators contend in a filing that  Prudential Insurance Co of America policyholders nationwide may have lost as much as $5.6 billion as a result of the insurer's alleged improper sales practices.</p>
<p>That figure is sharply higher than previous estimates of Prudential's potential exposure and well above the compensation policyholders can expect to receive under a proposed class action settlement.</p>
<p>Under the settlement, Prudential has agreed to pay at least $410 million to as many as 10.7 million policyholders.  </p>
<p>The settlement could cost Prudential as much as $1.2 billion and have a value to policyholders of nearly $2 billion.</p>
<p>&quot;What it mainly shows is how far out of whack the settlement figures are,&quot; a Florida insurance department spokesman said.</p>
<p>But two major rating agencies criticized the methodology used by Florida, saying the state has probably overestimated the potential losses.</p>
<p>Even so, A.M. Best said the ultimate cost to Prudential may indeed exceed earlier projections.  </p>
<p>Prudential said it has not officially seen the filing, but also questioned Florida's methods as described to it.</p>
<p>The estimate, which was in a filing with the U.S. District Court in Newark, N.J. on Thursday, was reached by estimating the losses in Florida from certain improper sales practices and then extrapolating nationwide from 1982 to 1995.</p>
<p>But Prudential's sales practice problems were apparently more serious in Florida than in other states and therefore the $5.6 billion estimate may be too high, A.M. Best senior vice president Larry Mayewski said.  </p>
<p>&quot;To throw a number out like that based on using Florida as the base and expanding that nationwide has some basic flaws,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>But, he said, &quot;we're not quarreling with the fact that the cost to the organization could exceed the projections that are out there. Only time will tell.&quot;</p>
<p>The Florida estimate also assumes that policyholders lost all the value of their policies in these transactions, Standard &amp; Poor's analyst David Havens said.  </p>
<p>In these transactions, policyholders drew down from their old policies the exact amount needed for premiums on new policies.  This drained the value of their old policies and people then were unable to keep up with the payment of premiums on new policies.</p>
<p>Florida said data provided by Prudential showed there were about $205 million of such &quot;exact match&quot; disbursements in Florida in that 14-year period.</p>
<p>But, Havens said, policyholders did not always lose the entire value of those policies.</p>
<p>&quot;They were not trading in $205 million of value for something worth nothing,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Havens said Standard &amp; Poor's continues to expect the ultimate cost to Prudential to be somewhere in the $1 billion range.</p>
<p>&quot;It's not surprising that there's wild numbers being thrown around.  There's a lot of money at stake and there's a lot of motivations that are fueling people at this point,&quot; he said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I82000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C15">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C152">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
