<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270042" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: US Midco spot prods off with NYMEX, but diffs firm.</title>
<headline>US Midco spot prods off with NYMEX, but diffs firm.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>U.S. Midcontinent spot product prices were sharply lower around midday Friday, especially in the case of gasoline as NYMEX product futures headed downward, traders said.</p>
<p>But differentials were firm, particularly in the case of &quot;1-oil&quot; or &quot;Y-grade&quot; low sulphur jet fuel, which in Group Three have soared to 10 cents over &quot;X-grade&quot; or low sulphur diesel by dint of the cold snap gripping the midcontinent.</p>
<p>&quot;Y-grade is just flying,&quot; said one trader, noting just a week ago, he closed a deal for 50,000 barrels of Y-grade at 4.25 cents over prompt Group Three low sulphur diesel.  </p>
<p>Low sulphur jet fuel is mixed with diesel in cold temperatures to prevent the motor fuel from becoming too gummy to burn properly.</p>
<p>Group Three low sulphur diffs perked up a bit amid talk some players were interested in closing a few deals before the weekend, with prompt and any month barrels talked from 6.50 to 7.00 cents under January NYMEX, the latter a done deal.</p>
<p>Diffs in Chicago were a bit more stable, with unleaded gasoline talked at around 5.50 cents under the January print, and prompt and low sulphur diesel diesel pegged about unchanged at 8.00 under NYMEX.</p>
<p>-- Oliver Ludwig New York Energy Desk +1 212 859 1633</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M143">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
