<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270095" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Pena brings wide experience to top energy job.</title>
<headline>Pena brings wide experience to top energy job.</headline>
<byline>Sonali Paul</byline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Federico Pena will bring to his new job as Energy Secretary four years of experience in the Clinton cabinet and the support of a key political constituency -- Hispanics.</p>
<p>Pena, 49, has a long history of public service as mayor of Denver and Secretary of Transportation, but he has limited hands-on background in some of the complex aspects of energy policy, ranging from utility deregulation to managing the nuclear weapon stockpile.</p>
<p>&quot;Pena is very intelligent and very able to grapple with some of the toughest issues,&quot; said David Nemtzow, president of the Alliance to Save Energy.</p>
<p>After an unusually long tenure at Transportation of three years and nine months, Pena had resigned and planned to leave Washington.</p>
<p>He emerged relatively late in the game as a choice for Energy, and was picked over Federal Energy Regulatory Commission Chairmwoman Elizabeth Moler partly in response to the demand of Hispanics for greater representation in Clinton's cabinet.</p>
<p>Saying he was ready to go home, Pena resigned the Transportation post and put his house up for sale. But Vice President Gore called and sounded him out about staying in the cabinet two weeks ago, Transportation officials said.</p>
<p>&quot;Yesterday afternoon the president and vice president called and asked if he would accept the energy position,&quot; one official said.</p>
<p>Pena's record on energy efficiency and alternative fuel boosted his star with some groups because Denver was one of the first cities to require cleaner-burning gasoline to combat pollution.</p>
<p>&quot;As transportation secretary he is very familiar with the whole nexus between transportation, energy and the environment,&quot; said Carol Werner of the Environment and Energy Study Institute.</p>
<p>Pena's biggest accomplishments in the transportation post were to boost the nation's investment in infrastructure such as roads, mass transit, rails, by 22 percent or $2 billion a year, raise safety standards for commuter airlines up to the levels of big jets, and negotiate 40 new international aviation agreements, official said.</p>
<p>Elected in 1983 as Denver's first Hispanic mayor after a stint in the state legislature, Pena, a Texas native, saw the go-go years of the late 1970s and early 1980s turn sour, sparked by a decline in oil prices.</p>
<p>But he remained popular even as he spent most of his eight years in office battling tough economic times.</p>
<p>He played a crucial role in getting Denver International Airport, a controversial $2.7 billion facility with state-of-the-art equipment.</p>
<p>He left office in Denver in 1991 and established a financial consulting firm, Pena Investment Advisors Inc.</p>
<p>In 1995 the Justice Department cleared Pena of allegations that his investment firm had benefited from his cabinet position.</p>
<p>Pena, born March 15, 1947 in Laredo, Texas, earned his law degree from the University of Texas at Austin in 1971 and worked briefly at a legal services clinic.</p>
<p>He is married to Ellen Mary Hart, a lawyer and world-class marathon runner. They have two daughters.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
