<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270128" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: U.S. cash hog prices melt as Midwest warms - trade.</title>
<headline>U.S. cash hog prices melt as Midwest warms - trade.</headline>
<dateline>CHICAGO 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A combination of increased hog supplies and light holiday meat packer demand pushed cash hog prices lower Friday, with further declines of $2.00-$3.00 per cwt seen by the end of next week, cash sources and some livestock analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;The thinking is, that as the weather warms up, all those hogs that were backed up this week by the weather will be available to the market,&quot; said Dave Maher, analyst with Securities Corp of Iowa.  </p>
<p>A blizzard in the Dakotas, northern Iowa and southern Minnesota earlier this week, along with bone-chilling cold temperatures and dangerous wind chills in the Midwest restricted hog movement.</p>
<p>Interior Iowa and southern Minnesota top cash hog prices through Thursday rallied on the weather, with top values climbing $2.50 to $56.50 per cwt, according to USDA.</p>
<p>The severe weather delayed hog marketings and will exacerbate a seasonal cash price decline when the animals do finally come to market, cash sources and analysts said.  </p>
<p>&quot;It's not unusual to have a substantial break in hog prices between Thanksgiving and Christmas,&quot; Maher said. &quot;What will be unusual will be the severity of the break because of this week's weather,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>As temperatures and wind chills moderated Thursday, producers shipped some of the backed-up hogs.</p>
<p>Interior Iowa and southern Minnesota hog receipts Thursday came in at 115,000 head, 10,000 over the estimate, USDA said. Friday's Iowa/southern Minnesota run was estimated at 110,000 versus 97,000 a week ago.  </p>
<p>Interior Iowa/southern Minnesota hog prices Friday fell $1.00 per cwt to a top of $55.50 paid on hogs delivered to plants, USDA said.</p>
<p>&quot;There won't be many hogs killed next week,&quot; said a buyer for an Iowa packing plant.</p>
<p>Several meteorologists agreed early Friday that the weather will warm over the weekend in the Midwest, with high temperatures rising into the 30s or 40s degrees Fahrenheit before more frigid weather hits the Midwest early next week.</p>
<p>However, price declines could be blunted not only by another round of cold weather but by demand for hogs for delivery against the December Chicago Mercantile Exchange hog futures contract, said Dale Benson, analyst with Dean Witter Reynolds.</p>
<p>Although December futures expire Friday, deliveries can be made against the contract up to January 3rd, Benson noted.</p>
<p>&quot;What if we have to make 200 deliveries the next two weeks?&quot; Benson asked. &quot;There will be a lot of scrambling for hogs at the terminals, which can also raise direct cash hog prices,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Benson said that retail pork demand for mid-January featuring could further temper a hog price slide the next two weeks.</p>
<p>&quot;Beef will be featured early in the month (January) but I expect that to change to pork by mid-month,&quot; Benson said.</p>
<p>((Bob Janis 312-408-8720))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="CHICAGO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
