<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270129" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: INSIGHT - One last dollar thrust seen by year end.</title>
<headline>INSIGHT - One last dollar thrust seen by year end.</headline>
<dateline>NEW YORK 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Following the lead of its cousins in the U.S. equity and bond markets, the dollar seems to be gearing up for one final push to 1996 highs before the dawn of 1997, technical analysts said on Friday.</p>
<p>With solid supports galvanizing the downside and recent resistance breaks pointing the way higher, the greenback should make a serious run at the 42-month high at 114.92 yen and the two-year high at 1.5735 marks in coming sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;Today's consolidation is just a pause. It's only a matter of time before we take out those highs,&quot; said Jim Chorek, director of currency research at Elliott Wave International.  </p>
<p>The break on Thursday of 1.5585 marks resistance suggests the dollar will retest interim resistance at 1.5630 and edge higher, chartists said.</p>
<p>&quot;We're still very bullish on the dollar, with a target of 1.59 marks,&quot; said Keith Raphael, president at Crosscurrents Investment Advisory.</p>
<p>Raphael cited the climax of the dollar/Swiss rally at 1.3410 as a temporary cap on dollar/mark's advance.</p>
<p>&quot;That took the wind out of dollar/mark in the very short term, but dollar/mark has a chance to play catch-up over the next two weeks,&quot; Raphael said.  </p>
<p>Against the yen, the dollar has had difficulty pushing past resistance at 114.25/30, but the rising support line, which offers a solid floor at 113.55, should act as a springboard for continuing gains, chartists said.</p>
<p>&quot;Dollar/yen is in a bull channel stretching back to the December 6 low at 111.78,&quot; said Chorek. &quot;It doesn't have a very steep ascent, but it is slowly grinding higher.&quot;</p>
<p>Yet dollar/yen appears to have somewhat less upward momentum than dollar/mark, with analysts seeing tough sledding after the greenback pierces 115 yen.  </p>
<p>Meanwhile, mark/yen seems more and more susceptible to a pullback, despite the dogged support near 73, chartists said.</p>
<p>Near-term resistance at 73.60 should allow mark/yen to push toward support at 72.55 in coming sessions.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a little bothersome that we haven't gotten any follow-through selling below the 73 support. But I doubt we'll go above 73.60 and the next big move will be to the downside,&quot; said Chorek.</p>
<p>--Chris Stetkiewicz, 212-859-1664</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NEW YORK"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
