<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270177" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UNITED NATIONS: UN chief, Council call for Somali ceasefire.</title>
<headline>UN chief, Council call for Somali ceasefire.</headline>
<dateline>UNITED NATIONS 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Secretary-General Boutros Boutros-Ghali and the U.N. Security Council on Friday called on Somali factions to stop fighting and restore their ceasefire.</p>
<p>In separate but similar statements, the U.N. chief and the 15-member council said they supported all countries in the region attempting to negotiate a settlement in the civil war that shows little sign of abating.</p>
<p>More than 130 people have been killed and 1,500 wounded and admitted to Mogadishu hospitals during fierce fighting in the Somali capital over the past week.</p>
<p>Boutros-Ghali said the fighting could deal &quot;a fatal blow&quot; to the recent agreement signed in Nairobi by three Mogadishu-based faction leaders under the mediation of Kenyan President Daniel arap Moi.</p>
<p>He called &quot;for an immediate cessation of hostilities and urges the Somali leaders to demonstrate political wisdom and patriotism.&quot;</p>
<p>The Security Council, in a statement read at a formal meeting, also reminded states of an arms embargo in place against Somalia and said all factions should &quot;cease immediately all hostilities and restore an effective ceasefire.&quot;</p>
<p>Shooting and shelling since last Friday has pitted militiamen loyal to Hussein Aideed against forces of his rivals -- Hassan Ali Osman Atto in south Mogadishu, Ali Mahdi Mohamed in north Mogadishu and Moslem fundamentalist leader Musa Sudi Yalahow.</p>
<p>Hussein Aideed, a 34-year-old former U.S. marine, succeeded his father Mohamed Farah Aideed on his death in August. He was elected president of Somalia by his supporters but both he and his government are rejected by most other faction leaders.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="SOMAL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UNITED NATIONS"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
