<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27027" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>YUGOSLAVIA: Bonds account for most of Belgrade bourse volume.</title>
<headline>Bonds account for most of Belgrade bourse volume.</headline>
<dateline>BELGRADE 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turnover on the Belgrade Stock Exchange (BSE) rose to 60.912 million dinars in the week ending on August 30 from 44.064 million in the previous week, the bourse said on Monday.</p>
<p>The number of transactions rose to 184 from 169.</p>
<p>&quot;National bank bonds accounted for most of the turnover, with 37.23 million dinars traded in 10 transactions, compared to the previous week's 20.27 million in five deals,&quot; Slavko Stimac of the BSE told Reuters.</p>
<p>A total of 20.547 million dinars worth of commercial paper was traded in 159 deals, up from 17.234 million in 135 transactions in the week ending on August 23.</p>
<p>Interest rates on these securities ranged from 44 to 971 percent per year and maturity from seven to 31 days.</p>
<p>The most actively traded commercial bills were those issued by chemicals producer Hipol (2.59 million dinars), pharmaceuticals company Hemofarm (2.05 million) and food processor BIM Slavija (1.88 million).</p>
<p>-- Amra Kevic, Belgrade newsroom +381 11 2224305</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="YUG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="BELGRADE"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="YUGOSLAVIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
