<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270423" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Fed votes to raise U.S. banks' underwriting limit.</title>
<headline>Fed votes to raise U.S. banks' underwriting limit.</headline>
<dateline>WASHINGTON 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System voted Friday to allow U.S. bank section 20 subsidiaries to derive as much as 25 percent of their revenues from the underwriting and dealing of securities, up from the current limit of 10 percent.</p>
<p>The vote, on a proposal released for comment July 31, marks another strike against Depression-era laws that separated banking from other financial service industries.</p>
<p>Section 16 of the Glass-Steagall Act generally prohibits banks from engaging in non-banking activities but the Fed found a loophole in section 20 of the act.</p>
<p>In 1987, the Fed first allowed bank affiliates to engage in underwriting activities as long as the revenue generated did not exceed five percent of the subsidiary's total revenue. In 1989, the revenue limit was raised to 10 percent.</p>
<p>The Fed's action also follows a recent move by Comptroller of the Currency Eugene Ludwig to allow nationally-chartered bank affiliates to engage in a wide variety of non-banking activities.</p>
<p>Congress is expected to take up the issue next year as it attempts once again to overhaul the 1933 Glass-Steagall Act. Rep. Jim Leach, chairman of the House banking Committee, said in a speech this week that he favored allowing banks into a limited array of non-bank fields.</p>
<p>--Aaron Pressman ((202-898-8312))</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="USA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WASHINGTON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
