<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270543" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: OPTIONS-Sell coffee calls to protect downside risk.</title>
<headline>OPTIONS-Sell coffee calls to protect downside risk.</headline>
<byline>Clelia Oziel</byline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Coffee players maintained a cautious stance on options this week while robusta futures set new lows as they searched for firmer ground.</p>
<p>But interest on rangebound cocoa has dried up, traders said.</p>
<p>January robusta options expired peacefully on Wednesday with no threat of mobilising the hefty open interest on $1,400 but some out-of-the-money puts were exercised, possibly to avoid further losses if these were sold into the futures market.</p>
<p>Selling crept in to March puts at $1,200 and $1,250 strikes and traders also cited some buying interest on calls at suspiciously distant strikes of $1,450, $1,500 and even $1,650.</p>
<p>&quot;If you need cover, it's not a lot of money,&quot; commented one market maker.</p>
<p>Volatilities eased back to around 27 percent after last week's firmer 28 for March puts and calls, he said.</p>
<p>Scattered activity reflected the blurred direction in futures after the market took a pounding this week on increasing supply concerns while key Mexican coffee areas escaped frost damage from a cold airmass.</p>
<p>March coffee slipped through support at $1,231 and hit a new contract low of $1,225 a tonne on Friday. But some analysts said the market was likely to head lower towards $1,205 on continuation basis. In rangebound markets with a downside risk a good strategy singled out was to sell a strangle on March $1,400 call and $1,150 put. This would limit the losses if the market skidded to new low ground. Another possibility was to buy one $1,350 call and sell two $1,400 calls at a net credit of $2-3. This would protect the downside and generate some premium. Traders said the same deal could be applied to $1,300 and $1,350 for a more aggressive approach.</p>
<p>Cocoa options were wobbly with no appetite emerging for the few put sales that were on offer this week from players who thought the market may had bottomed out.</p>
<p>&quot;There were some at-the-money put offers for March 900 and May 925, but we couldn't find any buyers,&quot; said one.</p>
<p>May 1,000 calls traded up to 18 stg with implied volatility at 20.5 percent.</p>
<p>March cocoa futures set a nine-month low of 899 stg where it encountered support. But technical analysts say 899 remains a threat while the market seems to have no stamina to rally.</p>
<p>In white sugar, the March contract dominated options activity, mainly on $320 calls, although some interest was also noted in out-of-the-money May puts.</p>
<p>Despite the bearish sentiment on the futures market, traders said underlying support was relatively solid although upside scope was probably limited.</p>
<p>&quot;Everyone in the market is still a bit bearish,&quot; said one, adding that one strategy might be to sell a March strangle between $310 and $300.</p>
<p>March volatilities were quoted at between 12 and 13 percent, compared with a range of 10 and 11 previously.</p>
<p>-- London Newsroom +44 171 542 8072</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M14">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M141">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
