<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27068" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Germany's WAZ settles Bulgarian Pressgroup debt.</title>
<headline>Germany's WAZ settles Bulgarian Pressgroup debt.</headline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Germany's WAZ Group, publisher of the Westdeutsche Algemeine Zeitung, has settled a 23.5 million mark debt of Bulgaria's 168 Chasa Pressgroup owed to First Private Bank (FPB), a bank official said on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;The German Westdeutsche Group WAZ settled on Friday the 23.5 million marks debt of the 168 Chasa Pressgroup to First Private Bank, thus clearing all of its outstanding payments to the FPB,&quot; central bank sequestrator of the FPB Stefan Chipilski told Reuters.</p>
<p>The FPB was one of five banks slated for bankruptcy by the Bulgarian central bank as part of a reform package aimed at reducing loss-makers. FPB's management was dismissed and central bank sequestrators appointed to investigate its financial state.</p>
<p>&quot;The Westdeutsche Algemeine Zeitung is expected to acquire around 70 percent of the cash-strapped 168 Chasa Pressgroup,&quot; said Chipilski.</p>
<p>The deal, due to be officialy announced in mid-September, has yet to be registered by the courts. The Group's president Petar Blaskov declined comment.</p>
<p>The 168 Chasa Pressgroup, set up in 1990, publishes four magazines and five newspapers, including the widely circulated daily 24 Chasa (24 Hours).</p>
<p>An ambitious printing house project launched last year produced financial difficulties for the Pressgroup.</p>
<p>Long-term credits were extended to the Pressgroup by the the Frankfurt-based Kreditanstalt fuer Wiederaufbau (KfW), the World bank and the European Investment Bank and were guaranteed by the government, said Chipilski.</p>
<p>Under the deal signed on July 31 by the two press groups, the first tranche of 500,000 marks was paid to FPB on August 8 and the remaining 23 million marks on August 30.</p>
<p>Chipilski said the 29 million german marks debt of the 168 Chasa Pressgroup to FPB was reduced by 19 percent after negotiations with the German buyers to the current 23.5 million marks.</p>
<p>-- Sofia Newsroom, 359-2-84561</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GFR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I47500">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C16">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C173">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
