<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270618" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>UK: UK curbs Natl Express buses after rail deal.</title>
<headline>UK curbs Natl Express buses after rail deal.</headline>
<dateline>LONDON 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Britain's trade ministry said on Friday it had decided to regulate some coach services offered by transport group National Express Plc following its acquisition earlier this year of the Midland Main Line railway franchise.</p>
<p>In a statement, the Department of Trade and Industry said it had accepted a monopolies panel study, which recommended caps on coach fares and service levels, and saw the rail purchase as potentially operating against the public interest in relation to coach services offered on parallel routes by National Express.  </p>
<p>Ian Lang, secretary of state for trade and industry, said in the statement that the group's acquisition of Midland Main Line (MML) could lead over time to higher coach fares and possibly higher rail fares too and a lower quality of services on certain routes from central London.</p>
<p>The competition watchdog, the Monopolies and Mergers Commission said that MML's rail services between central London and five other destinations showed overlapping areas.</p>
<p>Therefore, Lang said he had agreed with the MMC's recommendaiton to demand a number of conditions.</p>
<p>First, coach fares must not outstrip inflation growth.  </p>
<p>Second, National Express is not allowed to make &quot;restrictive changes to the terms and conditions applicable to coach tickets&quot; and must maintain different categories of services.</p>
<p>Coach capacity must be maintained to adequate levels to meet demand, with no cuts in frequency unless there is a &quot;significant reduction in passenger numbers.&quot;</p>
<p>The group must provide service quality which is equal to other transport divisions and agree to monitoring of its performance by the Office of Fair Trading.</p>
<p>Lang said if these undertakings are not agreed to by March 20, &quot;I would then have to consider using my powers to make an order to enforce these remedies.&quot;</p>
<p>-- London newsroom +44 171 542 7717</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="UK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I72102">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C31">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C34">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LONDON"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UK"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
