<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270662" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>TURKEY: Turkish central bank sells dlrs for lira - bankers.</title>
<headline>Turkish central bank sells dlrs for lira - bankers.</headline>
<dateline>ISTANBUL 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Turkish central bank sold dollars for lira to banks towards the close on Friday in an attempt to restrain the U.S. currency's rise which was fuelled by persistent demand, bankers said.</p>
<p>The lira firmed to 106,000 against the dollar on the central bank's dollar sales from previous 106,180. It had opened at 106,100, weaker than Thursday's 105,780.  </p>
<p>Bankers said dollar demand picked up in the last few days as several banks tried to close their year-end currency positions and importers' foreign currency demand also rose, as usual at end-year.</p>
<p>A lack of sellers in the currency market in recent days also buoyed the dollar, they added. &quot;A few private banks bought dollars heavily in the last two days in addition to existing demand and this pushed up the dollar sharply,&quot; said one banker.</p>
<p>Bankers said the downgrading of Turkey's long-term foreign currency rating to &quot;B plus&quot; from &quot;BB minus&quot; by European rating agency IBCA did not affect the market much as the lira had already weakened to 106,170 at midday.</p>
<p>The central bank carried out two minor bouts of dollar selling intervention earlier this week, on Monday and Thursday, bankers said. The central bank declined to comment.</p>
<p>-- Istanbul newsroom +90-212-2750875.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="TURK">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M13">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="M132">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ISTANBUL"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TURKEY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
