<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270844" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Press rights group asks Ethiopia to free newsmen.</title>
<headline>Press rights group asks Ethiopia to free newsmen.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>A Paris-based international press rights group called on Ethiopia on Friday to release several jailed newsmen, saying prison was not the right answer to media offences.</p>
<p>Reporters Without Borders (RSF) said in a letter to Prime Minister Meles Zenawi that it failed to understand why Sinteyehu Abate, editor-in-chief of the weekly Remet, had not been released though several weeks ago he ended a year's jail term for publishing material and a photograph thought pornographic.</p>
<p>RSF said four other newsmen were also being held in prison for reasons which were not known. It said &quot;prison sentences are never an appropriate response to press offences&quot;.</p>
<p>The group identified the jailed newsmen as Wesson Seged Mersha, publisher of the weekly Kitab; Goshu Modus of the weekly and monthly Tobia and acting manager of the weekly Tikuret; Tilahun Bekele, editor-in-chief of the weekly Ruhama, and Tefera Kitila, editor-in-chief of the weekly Tikuret.</p>
<p>All the publications are in Amharic.</p>
<p>RSF said nine other journalists, which it did not name, were also in jail in Ethiopia, some for more than a year awaiting trial.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ETHPA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
