<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270878" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>FRANCE: Jailed French cancer fund chief released on bail.</title>
<headline>Jailed French cancer fund chief released on bail.</headline>
<dateline>PARIS 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The former head of France's leading cancer research association was freed on bail on Friday after spending six months in detention for suspected fraud, justice sources said.</p>
<p>Jacques Crozemarie, 71, former president of the Association for Cancer Research (ARC) was released on bail of 500,000 francs ($100,000) pending possible trial.</p>
<p>He was forced to resign in January after a Court of Auditors found ARC spent little more than 27.2 percent of its funds, or 124 million francs ($24 million), on research aid in 1993 while its top officials lived in grand style.</p>
<p>Legal proceedings were then opened for suspected breaches of fraud laws in connection with ARC's finances.</p>
<p>ARC admitted it paid 13 million francs ($2.5 million) to an advertising agency that fed funds to Socialist politicians in the mid-1980s, when the party of the late president Francois Mitterrand was in power.</p>
<p>But ARC officials said there was no proof that the association had knowingly funded the party. The Socialists denied receiving cash from the association.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="FRA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCRIM">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="PARIS"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="FRANCE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
