<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270823" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Pope encourages Timorese Nobel winner.</title>
<headline>Pope encourages Timorese Nobel winner.</headline>
<byline>Philip Pullella</byline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Pope John Paul on Friday encouraged Nobel peace laureate Bishop Carlos Belo to continue his work promoting peace in disputed East Timor.</p>
<p>&quot;Congratulations on the Nobel Prize. I hope it will be a shield for you to work more for peace in Timor,&quot; Belo quoted the Pope as saying during a brief private audience at the Vatican.</p>
<p>&quot;The Holy Father was very pleased to receive me,&quot; Belo told a news conference. &quot;He understands our situation very well.</p>
<p>&quot;He told me to continue working for the people with the same enthusiasm, the same faith and same loyalty,&quot; Belo said.</p>
<p>It was the first meeting between the Pope and Belo since the bishop received the Nobel Peace Prize in Oslo on December 10.</p>
<p>Belo, the Vatican's administrator in Dili, East Timor, won the $1.1 million prize jointly with Jose Ramos Horta, a self-exiled East Timor independence campaigner.</p>
<p>East Timor, with a population of more than 800,000 people, was invaded by Indonesia in 1975 and annexed the next year in an act not recognised by the United Nations, which still regards Portugal as the territory's administering power.</p>
<p>The Jakarta government has condemned the Norwegian Nobel Committee's decision to include Ramos Horta in the prize.</p>
<p>Belo refused to answer what he termed political questions but repeated calls for a dialogue over Timor and the release of political prisoners.</p>
<p>&quot;Let's all sit down and talk,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&quot;All that needs to be said is that the people want to see their cultural, religious, ethnic and historical identity respected, as the Pope always says. That's all&quot;.</p>
<p>The 48-year-old bishop said his relations with the Indonesian government have not changed because of the prize.</p>
<p>&quot;We're there. We serve the people. We try to have good relations and when people come to me and tell me of abuses of human rights I try to talk about it to improve the situation,&quot; he said.&quot;</p>
<p>&quot;But these relations (with the Indonesian government) are not stellar,&quot; he joked.</p>
<p>In October senior members of the Indonesian government attacked Belo for reported remarks in a German magazine that the Indonesian military treated East Timorese as &quot;scabby dogs&quot; and &quot;slaves&quot;.</p>
<p>Last month Belo denied he had used the word &quot;scabby&quot;.</p>
<p>Asked if he was afraid of being killed, Belo said: &quot;Afraid of what? We only die once. An important part of every bishop is dying for the people.&quot;</p>
<p>Belo said in his acceptance speech in Oslo that the people of East Timor wanted peace and respect for human rights.</p>
<p>&quot;It is high time that the guns of war are silenced in East Timor, once and forever. It is high time that tranquillity is returned to the lives of the people of my homeland. It is high time that there be authentic dialogue,&quot; he said in Oslo.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TIMOR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="VCAN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GREL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
