<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270959" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: POLISH BOURSE SEEN UP IN WAIT FOR JANUARY RISE.</title>
<headline>POLISH BOURSE SEEN UP IN WAIT FOR JANUARY RISE.</headline>
<byline>Steven Silber</byline>
<dateline>WARSAW 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The Polish bourse should rise during brief two-session, pre-Christmas trade next week, analysts said, as investors seemed to be buying in anticipation of a repeat of last year's January rise.</p>
<p>&quot;In newspapers they're writing that the bourse should rise around January 5, and it seems many people would rather not sell before then,&quot; said Pawel Dmytryk, a trader at Bank Staropolski brokerage.</p>
<p>But Dmytryk said demand could slow in lighter pre-holiday trade on Tuesday, the last day before trade resumes on Monday December 30.</p>
<p>Analysts said a good sign was that the market was rising despite the week's negative signals such as the central bank head's statement that interest rates could rise to hamper fast credit growth and firms' mediocre November earnings results.</p>
<p>Analysts said Hanna Gronkiewicz-Waltz's statement might have already been priced in as the bank had long said it wanted real rates to rise.</p>
<p>Analysts said another good sign was that large-cap stocks such as BPH and Elektrim achieved slight gains on Friday in heavy trade.</p>
<p>They said their rises, and the 7.9-percent Friday jump by large-cap Agros , showed large investors were buying.</p>
<p>&quot;The fact that Agros rose that much for no apparent reason signals buying by foreign investors, who traditionally like the stock,&quot; said Pawel Tarnowski, an analyst at Raiffeisen Capital and Investment.</p>
<p>Analysts said one of the year's top stories materialised late on Thursday when Poland's two listed paintmakers, Polifarb Cieszyn and Polifarb Wroclaw , announced they planned to merge.</p>
<p>The move, which led to 9.7 and 9.4 percent surges by the two stocks on Friday, would represent the first friendly takeover in Warsaw bourse history.</p>
<p>Wroclaw and Cieszyn rose 14.4 and 13.6 percent on the week.</p>
<p>Swarzedz , the main market's top gainer this week, surged 24.2 percent, most of it after it announced a 200- million-mark contract on Wednesday. Wroclaw, Cieszyn and Swarzedz were all seen extending gains next week.</p>
<p>Analysts said Mostsostal Zabrze , up 16.8 percent on the week, was rising since announcing in November its issue of 2.6 million shares at a discount was oversubscribed.</p>
<p>Staropolski's Dmytryk said the main market's biggest loser this week, Rolimpex down 5.9 percent, might be scaring some investors buy piling up significant debts.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="WARSAW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
