<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="270919" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>ITALY: Italy to review 97 budget by March - Prodi.</title>
<headline>Italy to review 97 budget by March - Prodi.</headline>
<dateline>ROME 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Prime Minister Romano Prodi said on Friday that the Italian government would review its 1997 budget in late February or early March to assess whether supplementary measures were needed to keep the public deficit down.</p>
<p>He told an end-of-year news conference that any mini-budget next year, if needed, would be formed entirely from spending cuts and would not raise revenue.  </p>
<p>The 1997 budget, now before the lower house of parliament for final approval, aims to cut next year's deficit by 62.5 trillion lire ($41 billion) to help Italy meet the terms for membership of Europe's planned single currency.</p>
<p>Prodi acknowledged that the measures would not quite meet the single currency target of a deficit equal to three percent of gross domestic product but said interest rate developments could change that.</p>
<p>Many economists and the opposition say a mini-budget will be inevitable but Prodi said the centre-left government could not decide until full 1996 accounts were available in late February or early March.</p>
<p>The full budget has been criticised as over-heavy on revenue raising measures, including an unpopular one-off &quot;Euro-tax&quot; levy. Prodi said the cabinet had decided that a possible mini-budget &quot;must touch only reductions in spending&quot;.</p>
<p>-- Rome newsroom +39 6 678 2505</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="ITALY">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="ROME"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="ITALY"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
