<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271090" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>AUSTRALIA: RTRS-Advance says ASC won't stop meeting.</title>
<headline>RTRS-Advance says ASC won't stop meeting.</headline>
<dateline>SYDNEY 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Advance Bank Ltd said on Friday the Australian Securities Commission (ASC) had indicated that it would not interfere with s shareholder meeting being held on Monday to vote on the bank's proposed merger with St George Bank Ltd.  </p>
<p>&quot;The Australian Securities Commission (ASC) has informed Advance Bank's legal advisors today that it does not intend to interfere with the scheme meetings on Monday, 23 December 1996,&quot; Advane said in a statement.</p>
<p>However, Advance said the ASC had indicated that it intended to appear at a second hearing of the Supreme Court of New South Wales on January 6, 1997, which must also approve the scheme of arrangement for the merger to proceed.  </p>
<p>Advance's statement followed a notice from National Australia Bank Ltd (NAB) on Thursday which said the bank was concerned with one aspect of the scheme, namely the deemed power of attorney device which allows Advance directors to vote abstaining shares in favour of the proposal.</p>
<p>NAB has an eight percent stake in St George and has blocked attempts to expand, buying converting preference shares in Metway Bank Ltd earlier this year to block St George's unsuccessful bid for the Brisbane-based bank.  </p>
<p>NAB has said its St George stake is strategic, but many banking analysts see the stake as a launch-pad for a potential takeover bid if the St George-Advance deal does not go ahead.</p>
<p>Advance said in convening the scheme meetings, the Supreme Court had before it detailed submissions from Advance about the scheme and the deemed power of attorney arrangement.</p>
<p>&quot;The Court did not raise any concern about the deemed power of attorney arrangement in convening the meetings,&quot; the bank said.  </p>
<p>Advance said it was confident that the deemed power of attorney arrangement was valid and entirely proper and was in the interests of the shareholders of the bank.</p>
<p>NAB revealed on Thursday that it was holding a 3.03 percent stake in Advance and said Advance was aware of this holding.</p>
<p>National Australia Bank managing director Don Argus said NAB was considering all its options in deciding how to vote its shares, including abstaining from voting at the Advance meeting on Monday.  </p>
<p>At 1.20 p.m. (0220 GMT), Advance shares were seven cents weaker at A$6.68, St George shares were 20 cents higher at A$8.00, while NAB stock was 24 cents firmer at A$14.40.</p>
<p>-- Sydney Newsroom 61-2 9373-1800</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="AUSTR">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C18">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C181">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SYDNEY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="AUSTRALIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
