<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271116" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>INDONESIA: PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Dec 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Indonesian newspapers - Dec 20.</headline>
<text>
<p>The following are the leading stories in the Indonesian press on December 20. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>Telephone: (6221) 384-6364. Fax: (6221) 344-8404.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>KOMPAS</p>
<p>President Suharto said Indonesia's history showed that national flare-ups could occur together with economic difficulties if it was felt that development was not evenly spread and unjust.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>JAKARTA POST</p>
<p>President Suharto has made obiligatory a requirement for individual and corporate taxpayers to donate two percent of their after-tax incomes to help the poor. The presidential decree, issued on December 4, did not say if it applies to all taxpayers or only to those whose after-tax incomes exceed 100 million rupiah a year as Suharto once suggested.</p>
<p>Independent labour leader Mucthar Pakpahan and nine members of the left-wing People's Democratic Party (PRD) who are standing trial for subversion and spreading hatred against the government have proclaimed their innocence, describing the charges as a government attempt to silence its critics.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>MERDEKA</p>
<p>The government-backed leader of the Indonesian Democratic Party (PDI) has reported to police the action of PDI members who chained the gate of his official residence and sprayed graffitti on its walls in a demonstration in support of ousted leader Megawati Sukarnoputri.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>REPUBLIKA</p>
<p>The second prototype of the Indonesian-designed N-250 passenger aircraft has made its inaugural flight after numerous delays.</p>
<p>- - - -</p>
<p>BISNIS INDONESIA</p>
<p>Bank Indonesia has founded a private company, PT Star Warkat, to provide clearing services between commercial banks and the central bank.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="INDON">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="INDONESIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
