<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271200" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: Philippines enacts tax amendments into law.</title>
<headline>Philippines enacts tax amendments into law.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>Philipine President Fidel Ramos on Friday signed a bill on amendments to the expanded value-added tax (E-VAT), the presidential palace said.</p>
<p>The E-VAT law, which replaces more than 80 indirect taxes on a wide range of goods and services, was passed early this year but was opposed by some sectors which claimed that they were unfairly taxed while others were spared.</p>
<p>In a speech after the signing ceremony, Ramos said that non-food agricultural products, marine and forest products, cotton and cotton seeds, copra, fertiliser seeds, fish, prawn, livestock and poultry were exempted from the ambit of the law.</p>
<p>Other items exempted include coal and natural gas and petroleum products, including raw materials for their manufacture, except lubricating oil, processed gas, grease, wax and petroleum.</p>
<p>Medical, dental, hospital and veterinary services, except fees charged by doctors, and educational services will not be covered.</p>
<p>Sales by agricultural and electrical cooperatives, by artists and sale of houses and lots and other residential dwellings, and leases of residential units with monthly rentals lower than 8,000 pesos are also exempted.</p>
<p>Sale, import, printing or publication of books and other periodicals will not be covered by the E-VAT.</p>
<p>&quot;Rather than viewing these amendments as constricting the base of the VAT, these should be seen at improvements aimed at making the VAT system a fairer system,&quot; Ramos said.</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom 63 2 8418939 fax 8176267</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="E21">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="E211">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="ECAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
