<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271241" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>JAPAN: JGB futures end higher ahead of long weekend.</title>
<headline>JGB futures end higher ahead of long weekend.</headline>
<dateline>TOKYO 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>The key March Japanese government bond (JGB) futures contract ended Friday's Tokyo session higher, but well off its earlier high of 126.41.</p>
<p>The March closed up 0.10 at 126.02, an intraday low. Volume was 43,904 contracts.</p>
<p>&quot;The March gave up much of its gains on position-adjustment selling ahead of the long weekend,&quot; said a trader at a trust bank's securities unit.</p>
<p>Tokyo markets will be closed for a holiday on Monday.</p>
<p>Traders, however, said a solid support was confirmed near 126.00.  </p>
<p>&quot;The March looked heavy above 126.30 while looking solid around 126.00, as people were eager to square their positions before a three-day break. Next week, however, the March might test record highs,&quot; said a brokerage house trader.</p>
<p>The all-time high for any benchmark JGB futures contract is 126.58 recorded on November 28.</p>
<p>The recent weakness in Tokyo stocks is lending support to JGBs, as it underscored the likelihood that the Bank of Japan (BOJ) would need to maintain a low interest rate policy.</p>
<p>Tokyo's Nikkei 225 average ended up 119.79 points or 0.61 percent at 19,690.46 on Friday.  </p>
<p>Traders said the Nikkei's failure to post bigger gains after a 126 point overnight jump in New York's Dow Jones industrial average suggested the weaknes in Tokyo stocks would continue for a while.</p>
<p>Some traders noted that the BOJ's monthly economic review was partly responsible for JGB selling in late afternoon.</p>
<p>The economy is continuing its gradual recovery, with private demand becoming increasingly firm, the central bank said in the report.</p>
<p>It also said the pace of the rise in industrial output is increasing.  </p>
<p>Next week, market participants will be focusing on whether the BOJ will conduct an outright JGB purchase operation on Tuesday, traders said.</p>
<p>The BOJ currently conducts outright JGB purchase operations twice a month.</p>
<p>-- Kanta Watanabe, Tokyo Treasury Desk +81-3-3432-9780</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="JAP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M12">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="TOKYO"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="JAPAN"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
