<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271356" id="root" date="1996-12-20" xml:lang="en">
<title>PHILIPPINES: PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Dec 20.</title>
<headline>PRESS DIGEST - Philippine newspapers - Dec 20.</headline>
<dateline>MANILA 1996-12-20</dateline>
<text>
<p>These are the leading stories in Manila newspapers on Friday. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy.</p>
<p>GENERAL NEWS:</p>
<p>- The Senate and the House of Representatives fail to break a deadlock over the proposed 476.2 million peso budget for next year prompting the government to revert to the 1996 National Appropriations Act for funds to keep operations running until the new budget is passed. (INQUIRER/MANILA TIMES/PHILIPPINE STAR)</p>
<p>- President Fidel Ramos signs into law a 15-year plan to modernise the armed formces appropriating 331 billion pesos for the programme. (TIMES JOURNAL/BULLETIN)</p>
<p>- Constitutional experts in the House of Representatives say the petition filed by a senator at the Supreme Court to stop the Commission on Elections from hearing a petition seeking amendments to the Constitution, will not prosper. (CHRONICLE).</p>
<p>				 +++++++++</p>
<p>BUSINESS STORIES</p>
<p>- A finance official says the recent oil price rollback will adversely affect the government's budgetary position next year since it could end up assuming additional deficits in the Oil Price Stabilisation Fund. (MANILA TIMES/BUSINESS DAILY)</p>
<p>- The National Telecommunications Commission plans to slash the proposed fees for the use of scarce slots in the radio frequency spectrum used in the operation of various telecommunications services such as the lucrative personal mobile telephone service. (INQUIRER)</p>
<p>- The Department of Environment and Natural Resources issues new rules for mining companies aimed at strengthening environmental laws and protecting tribal landowners. (CHRONICLE)</p>
<p>- The Philippines will unlikely import rice next year as total buffer stock is expected to hit 1.997 million tonnes by year-end, about 40 percent higher than last year, the Bureau of Agricultural Statistics said. (MALAYA)</p>
<p>- The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) clears Centennial City Inc from violations of disclosure rules and suspension will be lifted today. (JOURNAL/MALAYA)</p>
<p>- The national government borrowed twice as much from its foreign creditors than it should with foreign borrowings from January to November this year reaching 20.32 billion pesos, or 119 percent more than the full-year programmed level of only 9.28 billion pesos. (TODAY)</p>
<p>- A regional trial court issues order indefinitely suspending the National Power Corp's evaluation of the bidding proposal for the $450 million Caliraya-Botocan-Kalayaan hydroelectric power project on grounds that the state-run power firm issued strict guidelines for the civil works that prevented other companies from joining the bidding. (BULLETIN)</p>
<p>- Manila newsroom (632) 841 8934</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PHLNS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-20"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-20"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MANILA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PHILIPPINES"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
