<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271576" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>POLAND: STALEXPORT APPROVES $50 MLN EUROBOND ISSUE.</title>
<headline>STALEXPORT APPROVES $50 MLN EUROBOND ISSUE.</headline>
<dateline>KATOWICE, Poland 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Shareholders of Polish steel trader Stalexport SA on Satursday approved an issue of 50,000 five-to-seven-year convertible eurobonds at a par value of $1,000 to foreign and domestic investors.</p>
<p>&quot;The issue will probably take place in the first half of 1997,&quot; Stalexport's president Ryszard Harchala said after the shareholders meeting.</p>
<p>The issue's lead manager, British investment bank Robert Fleming, will seek listing for the bonds in London or Luxemburg stock exchange.</p>
<p>The shareholders also approved an issue of 4,000,000 new shares, with a 10-zloty nominal value, for which the bonds could be exchanged. Currently Stalexport has 8,833,826 shares outstanding.</p>
<p>Harchala said that Stalexport, which originally planned to sell the bonds only to foreign investors, would direct them also to domestic buyers.</p>
<p>He said state-owned Pekao SA bank, the Polish Development Bank (PBR), BIG bank were interested in the bonds. &quot;The management will also offer the bonds to other banks, such as BPH bank and BRE bank,&quot; he added.</p>
<p>The bonds' redemption date will be subject to the lead manager and Stalexport's management decision before the issue.</p>
<p>The management will also determine the date of conversion and the bond's interest, which will not be higher than five percent of the bond's nominal value annually.</p>
<p>The bonds could be exchanged for the shares six months after the issue at the earliest. The shares would be converted at the average price of the shares during three sessions before the issue plus a premium of at least 15 percent in dollar terms.</p>
<p>Stalexport also said the bonds would be callable after three years at par value plus a coupon equal to the interest on comparable five or seven year U.S. treasury bonds plus 125-175 basis points.</p>
<p>Harchala said Stalexport would use the revenue from the issue to invest in Ostrowiec, Labedy and Szczecin steel mills and to set up a warehouse and service network in southern Poland.</p>
<p>-- Warsaw Newsroom +48 22 653 9700</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="POL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I61000">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C17">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="C172">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KATOWICE, Poland"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="POLAND"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
