<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="27163" id="root" date="1996-09-02" xml:lang="en">
<title>PERU: Lima shares end down, foreign investors absent.</title>
<headline>Lima shares end down, foreign investors absent.</headline>
<dateline>LIMA 1996-09-02</dateline>
<text>
<p>Share prices on the Lima stock exchange closed down Monday because local players were cautious in the absence of foreign investors, brokers said.</p>
<p>Prices were expected to pick up Tuesday as foreigners return to the market after Monday's holiday in the United States, they added.</p>
<p>Monday, the General Index, dipped 0.60 percent to 1,419.97 points, while the blue-chip Selective Index fell 0.89 percent to 1,934.44 points, according to preliminary stock figures.  </p>
<p>Volume was a meager 15.6 million soles ($6.3 million). In a total of 1,433 operations, 15 stocks rose, 25 fell and 39 were stable.</p>
<p>Amid the quiet activity, the electricity sector dominated. Generating utility Edegel, which rose 3.80 percent to 6.01 soles, was the most heavily traded stock, accounting for 14.5 percent of the day's volume.</p>
<p>&quot;If it had not been for the trade in the electricity shares, the session would have been dead,&quot; said Luis Calderon of local brokerage Acciones y Valores.</p>
<p>Luz del Sur edged down 0.56 percent to 3.58 soles on volume of 245,000 shares.  </p>
<p>Among other leaders, benchmark Telefonica del Peru dropped 1.56 percent to 5.68 soles on unusually low volume of 385,000 shares and brewery Backus y Johnston fell 1.21 percent to 2.44 soles on 266,000 shares.</p>
<p>-- Eduardo Orozco, Lima newsroom, 511 221-2134</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="PERU">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-09-02"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-09-02"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="LIMA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="PERU"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
