<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271622" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>BULGARIA: Party factions battle after Bulgarian premier quits.</title>
<headline>Party factions battle after Bulgarian premier quits.</headline>
<byline>Thalia Griffiths</byline>
<dateline>SOFIA 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Reformists and hardliners are battling for supremacy in Bulgaria's ex-communist government after the surprise resignation of Prime Minister Zhan Videnov at a weekend congress.</p>
<p>Reformist delegates met late into the night to discuss who would replace the 37-year-old premier. Videnov's supporters said they would ask him to run again.</p>
<p>The communist-style congress, which must also name a new cabinet, is expected to continue until early on Monday.</p>
<p>&quot;If the declaration made by Zhan Videnov is not a tactical manoeuvre then I welcome it. I think it has been delayed too long,&quot; said respected former party chairman Alexander Lilov.</p>
<p>Videnov said he had submitted his government's resignation to parliament on Saturday and expected it to be voted before the end of the year.</p>
<p>&quot;It's a ploy,&quot; said one reformist delegate. &quot;There's no one in parliament to accept it apart from the security guards.&quot;</p>
<p>U.S.-born Georgi Pirinski, who resigned as foreign minister last month saying the government lacked public support, had been tipped as a possible successor to Videnov but delegates said his star seemed to be waning.</p>
<p>Videnov became prime minister after parliamentary elections in December 1994 and his government is half way in its four-year term. Criticism became more vocal after the Socialists' defeat in last month's presidential election.</p>
<p>Speakers at the congress painted a bleak picture of an economy wrecked by seven years of delayed reform. Bulgaria has the lowest level of foreign investment in the region.</p>
<p>Acting foreign minister Irina Bokova said an increasingly isolationist Bulgaria no longer had the confidence of international financial or political institutions.</p>
<p>&quot;Our foreign partners do not believe in our honest desire to integrate Bulgaria into European structures,&quot; she said.</p>
<p>Leading members of the Bulgarian Communist Party renamed themselves Socialists after the end of one-party rule in 1989.</p>
<p>The government's failure to meet reform targets, including closing or restructuring loss-making state enterprises, has led the World Bank and the International Monetary Fund to  suspend funding.</p>
<p>A party plenum last month gave Videnov only narrow backing in a confidence vote and he is also under fire over his links to a shady group of companies known as the Orion Group.</p>
<p>The deputy head of parliament's commission against corruption, Edvin Sugarev, wrote to the chief prosecutor on Thursday asking him to investigate Videnov's links to Orion and its bank, the Bulgarian Agricultural and Industrial Bank, which Sugarev said had caused significant losses to state and private financial institutions.</p>
<p>A quarter of Bulgaria's numerous and illiquid banks are in receivership. Loss of confidence in the banking system caused a run on the lev, which has fallen from 70 to the dollar at the beginning of the year to 485 now.</p>
<p>Former prime minister Andrei Lukanov, who was shot dead outside his home on October 2, was about to reveal high-level government corruption when he was killed, according to his party colleagues.</p>
<p>The government has not yet finalised the 1997 budget and is also preparing to introduce a fixed exchange rate mechanism to halt the collapse of the lev.</p>
<p>IMF technical experts left on Friday after helping the government to prepare the legal measures for setting up a currency board and to draft the 1997 budget framework.</p>
<p>IMF mission head Anne McGuirk said she hoped to be back in the New Year for final negotiations, but much depended on how long it took to resolve the political situation.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="BUL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="SOFIA"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="BULGARIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
