<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271623" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>RUSSIA: Yeltsin to move Sunday to suburban Moscow home.</title>
<headline>Yeltsin to move Sunday to suburban Moscow home.</headline>
<byline>Adam Tanner</byline>
<dateline>MOSCOW 1996-12-22</dateline>
<text>
<p>Russian President Boris Yeltsin was scheduled to return to his suburban Moscow home on Sunday a day before he plans to resume working in the Kremlin, his spokesman said.</p>
<p>Since undergoing heart surgery last month, Yeltsin has slowly resumed working and meeting top officials during his recovery, but has not visited the Kremlin.</p>
<p>On Saturday, he started working at the Rus residence about 100 km (60 miles) outside Moscow at 6:30 a.m., his press secretary Sergei Yastrzhembsky told a briefing later in the day.</p>
<p>Among his tasks was to sign a decree approving new passports to replacing Soviet-era documents still used by Russians who travel abroad, the spokesman said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin had multiple heart bypass operation on November 5, and has stayed in several residences outside Moscow since then. On Sunday, he is due to return to his home in Gorky-9, a wooded area 20 km (12 miles) from the capital occupied mainly by government officials.</p>
<p>On Friday, in his first television interview since his operation, Yeltsin said he was ready to resume active work at his Kremlin desk.</p>
<p>&quot;I feel that the recovery period is over. I am returning to the Kremlin on Monday... I will be there at nine a.m. The doctors have done their job and now it is up to the president,&quot; he told the nation.</p>
<p>&quot;The country needs an active and energetic president, especially now,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin, who looked much thinner than before his surgery, spoke in a firm and decisive voice throughout the interview though he appeared to be moving stiffly.</p>
<p>Highlighting the drama of the president's return, his press office on Saturday gave Reuters and Russian television stations a rare tour of his Kremlin office, which is lined with wood paneling and bookcases, and is illuminated by two ornate chandeliers.</p>
<p>Among the problems Yeltsin said he is anxious to address were workers' unpaid wages, the peace process in the breakaway region of Chechnya and reform of the army and military doctrine.</p>
<p>In his remarks on Friday, the president also warned he will crack the whip on government officials who have not worked hard enough in his absence, and said managers of business who do not pay taxes should lose their jobs.</p>
<p>The president's first order of business on Monday morning will be meeting top aides and government officials, Yastrzembsky said.</p>
<p>Yeltsin will also be able to review initial results from Sunday's gubernatorial and other local elections in 15 Russian regions, where Communists and other opposition candidates are opposing candidates supported by the government.</p>
<p>The elections are important not only for their regional impact, but also because Russian governors serve on the upper house of parliament, the Federation Council.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPOL">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-22"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MOSCOW"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="RUSSIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
