<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271610" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>TANZANIA: UN expects 500,000 Hutus to quit Tanzania by Dec 25.</title>
<headline>UN expects 500,000 Hutus to quit Tanzania by Dec 25.</headline>
<dateline>NGARA, Tanzania 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>At least 500,000 Rwandan Hutu refugees in Tanzania will have returned home by Christmas, the U.N. refugee agency UNHCR said on Saturday.</p>
<p>&quot;At the present rate of repatriation, at least half a million refugees will be spending their first Christmas in Rwanda since 1993,&quot; UNHCR spokeswoman Judith Melby told Reuters in the northern Tanzanian town of Ngara.</p>
<p>By nightfall on Friday up to 280,000 Rwandans had crossed the border from Tanzania over the past week and there was a 50-km (30-mile) -long column of some 100,000 Hutus edging towards the border.</p>
<p>&quot;It's one long continuous straggle of people. They are going over today and tomorrow,&quot; Melby added.</p>
<p>The bulk of an estimated 125,000 refugees from five camps in the Karagwe zone were expected to cross by December 25.</p>
<p>Over half a million Rwandan Hutus fled to Tanzania in 1994. Tutsi rebels drove them out of the country after putting an end to the genocide of minority Tutsis by the Hutu majority.</p>
<p>Tanzania told its 540,000 unwanted guests to leave by the end of the month, encouraged by the mass repatriation of some 600,000 Rwandan refugees from eastern Zaire last month.</p>
<p>Hardline Hutu militiamen, who played a leading role in the genocide and refuse to return to a Tutsi-ruled Rwanda, are being rounded up and put in a special camp by Tanzanian forces.</p>
<p>On Friday, senior UNHCR official Anne Willem Bijleveld asked for an explanation from Tanzanian authorities about an incident on Wednesday in which refugees were beaten and a church in which they were sheltering was burnt down.</p>
<p>UNHCR workers alleged that Tanzanian security officials carried out the attack. The human rights group Amnesty International protested against the incident.</p>
<p>Tanzanian soldiers have manned roadblocks and wielded sticks to force the refugees to return to Rwanda but there have been few reports of violence.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RWANDA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="TANZA">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GVIO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="NGARA, Tanzania"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="TANZANIA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
