<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271629" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>UKRAINE: Ukraine's Kuchma hails healthy Yeltsin.</title>
<headline>Ukraine's Kuchma hails healthy Yeltsin.</headline>
<byline>Elaine Monaghan</byline>
<dateline>KIEV 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Ukrainian President Leonid Kuchma on Saturday hailed President Boris Yeltsin's recovery from surgery and said it meant relations with Moscow -- soured by years of fighting over the Black Sea Fleet -- would improve in 1997.</p>
<p>Kuchma, speaking at an end-of-year news conference, portrayed himself and Yeltsin as two men facing difficult parliaments and said deputies in Kiev were holding up reforms.</p>
<p>&quot;We must not waste time. Losing a day means losing a month and losing a month means losing a year,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>Kuchma, trying to satisfy the economic demands of donors like the International Monetary Fund and World Bank, is locked in a row with deputies over how to reform taxes which are so crippling they are almost impossible to collect.</p>
<p>International donors have pledged well over $5 billion in aid over the next three years -- if Ukraine stays on course.</p>
<p>Monetary sources have suggested aid partly hinges on how the left-dominated parliament, which gave the budget a first reading on Thursday, receives ambitious reform and budget plans.</p>
<p>They called for bigger revenues, a lower deficit, continuing benefits to victims of the Chernobyl nuclear disaster and war veterans, and more money for industrial and agriculture sectors.</p>
<p>But after economic problems, Kuchma's biggest headache is relations with Russia, where politicians like Moscow mayor Yuri Luzhkov -- seen as a potential successor to Yeltsin -- are apt to play the nationalist card over Ukraine's port of Sevastopol.</p>
<p>Luzhkov has said Sevastopol could be taken by force, while parliament said Ukraine had no right to rule the city, transfrerred from Russia to Ukraine in 1954. The city is home to the former Soviet Black Sea Fleet.</p>
<p>Kuchma said Yeltsin completely opposed such territorial claims and that the Russian leader would fulfil a promise to visit Kiev and sign a Friendship Treaty once he recovered.</p>
<p>&quot;The political situation will change as far as Ukrainian-Russian relations are concerned when Boris Yeltsin starts work in the Kremlin,&quot; Kuchma said.</p>
<p>Kuchma was speaking a day after Yeltsin gave his first television interview since multiple bypass heart surgery last month and promised to return to work at the Kremlin on Monday.</p>
<p>Yeltsin had cancelled six trips to Kiev over the row, which centres around how and if Russia should pay to keep its share of the fleet in Sevastopol.</p>
<p>Many Ukrainians are very sensitive about their five-year-old state which rose from the ashes of the Soviet Union.</p>
<p>Their language and culture declined as a result of Moscow's 300-year rule over the territory which is split between the Russian-speaking, industrialised east, and the west, marked by strong national sentiments and European cultural influences.</p>
<p>Kuchma wants to maintain strong but equal links with Moscow, but takes every chance to stress Ukraine's future is in Europe.</p>
<p>In 1996 he declared his aim was to join the European Union and obtain a special partnership in the NATO Western alliance.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not want Ukraine to be in Russia's shadow or to be sidelined in world history,&quot; Kuchma said.</p>
<p>&quot;They are not waiting for us. We must push our way into Europe because that is where our future lies.&quot;</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="RUSS">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="UKRN">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="GCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GDIP">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="GPRO">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="KIEV"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="UKRAINE"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
