<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271769" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>USA: Petrochemicals exception to smooth Mexico selloffs.</title>
<headline>Petrochemicals exception to smooth Mexico selloffs.</headline>
<byline>Timna Tanners</byline>
<dateline>MEXICO CITY</dateline>
<text>
<p>Mexico's rush of privatisations scheduled for 1997 should proceed smoothly and draw a tidy sum for the government, although the petrochemical industry will be a hard sell, economists said Friday.</p>
<p>Next year Mexico is hoping to place on the auction block operating rights to the remaining railroads and ports, airports, satellites, radio spectrum, natural gas distribution rights and stakes in 61 petrochemical plants.</p>
<p>While economists said the assets were seen as extremely attractive, restrictions in the once coveted petrochemical industry have put a damper on investment plans.</p>
<p>The government decided amid anti-privatisation pressure to allow only a minority stake in existing plants and full ownership of new ones.</p>
<p>Once considered likely bidders for the plants, companies such as conglomerates Grupo Alf and Desc Sociedad de Fomento Industrial, have cautiously said they do not want to be minority partners with state-owned oil and gas monopoly Petroleos Mexicanos (Pemex), analysts said.</p>
<p>&quot;These companies have said that if they make the investment, they want to bring in their own CEO, they want the ability to manage as they deem appropriate,&quot; said an analyst who asked not to be identified.</p>
<p>Although companies can build their own petrochemical plants, still using Pemex supplies, the cost of constructing an independent complex will often be unprofitable, economists said.</p>
<p>&quot;The worst thing that can happen for an investor is for things not to be clear. The petrochemical sale all depends on the clarity of how the sector will be disincorporated,&quot; said an economist who asked to remain unnamed.</p>
<p>With the entry of new companies in the other privatisations, however, economists expect lower prices and greater efficiency.</p>
<p>&quot;It has all the ingredients for taking the government out of the economic process, reducing the role of the Mexican government as a direct actor in the industry. It means more new partners for investment, a lower deficit and greater social spending,&quot; said Abel Beltran-del-Rio, director of Ciemex-Wefa consulting group.</p>
<p>President Ernesto Zedillo's expected $14 billion from privatisations appears achievable, economists agreed. They clashed, however, on whether the government will use the windfall to fund social development programmes, pay back government debt or reduce the debt.</p>
<p>Economists cited recent competitive privatisations as evidence that Mexican assets will be in demand in 1997.</p>
<p>The 50-year operating concession of key Mexico-U.S. rail route, known as the Northeast Railway, was recently granted to a partnership between Transportacion Maritima Mexicana (TMM) and Kansas City Southern Industries Inc.</p>
<p>Although the companies' $1.4 billion bid for the route was considered excessive by many brokerages, they said the competitive bidding proved that buyers find Mexico attractive.</p>
<p>In bringing out-dated infrastructure into the modern age, companies are expected to invest in improvements, develop synergies with U.S. partners and slash traditionally excessive payrolls.</p>
<p>As a consequence, Mexico's unions have been the loudest opponents of the government's privatisation scheme, begun in the previous administration and continued ploddingly under Zedillo.</p>
<p>&quot;International experience indicates that in the first year (after a privatisation) employment falls, then returns to previous levels with more skilled people,&quot; said Isaac Katz, economics chair of Mexico's Autonomous Technical Institute.</p>
<p>He said improvements needed on the Northeast Railway track, for example, may require a boosted labour force in initial years.</p>
<p>Political factors could be another roadblock to 1997 privatisations, as mid-term elections could stir up nationalist, anti-privatisation sentiment, economists said.</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="MEX">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="M11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="MCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="MEXICO CITY"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="USA"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
