<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?>
<newsitem itemid="271722" id="root" date="1996-12-21" xml:lang="en">
<title>HONG KONG: HK fund managers in talks over consortium - paper.</title>
<headline>HK fund managers in talks over consortium - paper.</headline>
<dateline>HONG KONG 1996-12-21</dateline>
<text>
<p>Four of Hong Kong's largest fund managers have discussed forming a consortium to tap into the territory's proposed Mandatory Provident Fund (MPF), local newspapers reported on Saturday.</p>
<p>Jardine Fleming, Schroders Investment Management, LGT Asset Management and Invesco were in talks over ways to crack the lock insurance companies are expected to have over the new pension market, the South China Morning Post said.</p>
<p>The name of the proposed consortium would be the Mandatory Provident Fund Co, the newspaper said, adding that senior management of the fund management groups confirmed talks had been held but provided no details.</p>
<p>LGT Asset Management is a unit of private bank and fund manager Liechtenstein Global Trust AG  BLSTp.Z. Schroders Investment Management is a unit of British investment bank Schroders Plc.</p>
<p>The MPF could contribute US$5 billion annually to a fund that is exepected to top US$150 billion by 2015.</p>
<p>Known for their lack of enthusiasm for unit trusts, Hong Kong people could be required to contribute 10 percent of their monthly salaries to approved retirement funds under the scheme.  </p>
<p>Hong Kong's fund industry is now dominated by foreign institutional funds dedicated to Asian investment.</p>
<p>A survey by the Investment Funds Association showed foreign funds accounted for about 70 percent of an estimated US$94 billion under management.</p>
<p>Hong Kong's Legislative Council has passed framework legislation allowing the creation of the MPF but subsidiary legislation and regulations are still being drafted.</p>
<p>The MPF office in Hong Kong has said the regulations should be ready by April, leaving only a few months before the British colony returns to Chinese rule at midnight on June 30.</p>
<p>It is not clear whether Beijing will support the MPF plan, which is a cornerstone of controversial reforms in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>-- Hong Kong Newsroom (852) 2843 6441</p>
</text>
<copyright>(c) Reuters Limited 1996</copyright>
<metadata>
<codes class="bip:countries:1.0">
  <code code="HKONG">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:industries:1.0">
  <code code="I81402">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83100">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="I83960">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<codes class="bip:topics:1.0">
  <code code="C11">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
  <code code="CCAT">
    <editdetail attribution="Reuters BIP Coding Group" action="confirmed" date="1996-12-21"/>
  </code>
</codes>
<dc element="dc.date.created" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.publisher" value="Reuters Holdings Plc"/>
<dc element="dc.date.published" value="1996-12-21"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.creator.location.country.name" value="HONG KONG"/>
<dc element="dc.source" value="Reuters"/>
</metadata>
</newsitem>
